Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Curtsey Fried
and my partner in Sound Audio crime. Josh Pressers. That's right. We have spent
longer than I want to admit trying to figure out
why my audio while talking to Kurt was messing.
Would you like to tell the audience why it was messed up? Kurt?
Well, the suspicion is, it's my USB port. It was Kurt's fault, not mine.
And I was the one
trying to sort all this out on my side
assuming there was something wrong with my microphone.
And then you had the brilliant idea of listen to some audio on your computer.
And I'm like, oh,
yeah. No, that's broken too.
Well, that's because I recorded myself. And then, and what makes it even more fun
and more tragic
is my first thought was I will reboot
and I was in Windows to do the recording
and then when it came back up because I dual boot
this computer every now and then something happens to like the
boot loader and windows makes me go to a website and
type in a hilariously long key to prove I am me
because a bit locker stuff and that popped up.
So, I'm recording on Linux now, which I probably should have been doing anyway.
But I was lazy and I didn't want to make it all work. But anyway, anyway,
I also have another hilarious story to tell
in my
interesting life, I guess. Well, I have two things.
So, first of all I started a new job last week, which is very exciting.
I'm the vice president of Security at Encor, which is awesome.
Yeah, I had to,
I had to update all my contact list
for you because it keeps default because alphabetically.
Right.
Oh. Right. Right. Yes. Well, and I don't have your new one.
So, obviously a comes before e
uh, yes, that's true. That's true.
And, and I've, it's been three whole days at this point. So
that, that's cool. I'll, I'll, I'll have more to say at some point, I'm sure.
And then the other thing that happened, this is hilarious is, uh,
it was actually exactly one week ago today at the time of recording
the pickup truck I've owned for 21 years. Finally gave up the ghost. It is done.
Well, no, my understanding is something broke on it.
That's ok to live without if you don't care about the environment.
Well, no, it's not ok to live without. It will murder you.
So, what happened was the exhaust manifold.
The thing that comes off the engine that all the exhaust goes into,
there's three pipes on each side because it's a V six engine,
all of the exhaust goes through these pipes and then it goes
through the catalytic converter and the muffler and all that jazz.
Uh,
basically one of my pipes broke
and it's going to cost more than the truck is literally worth to replace.
Assuming nothing terrible goes wrong in the process,
which could increase the price to infinity as they're working on a 21
year old engine or considering what else they find wrong with it.
Well, there's everything is wrong with this thing.
In fact,
I even like the mechanic and I have an agreement that if it isn't going to kill anyone,
don't worry about
it.
Like the check engine line has been on for probably
a decade at this point and the door lock doesn't,
the, the electronic door locks don't work anymore.
Uh, the passenger side window doesn't roll down anymore like it has many,
many problems.
So anyway, anyway, what I did actually, truck dies,
whatever I expected that I knew it was coming.
I'm sad. It happened now because buying a new car is really hard actually.
So I ended up with
a Nissan Leaf electric car.
It was the literally the only electric car I could find that was actually in stock,
but
I, I was like, I want an electric car and so I found one, I bought it and
it is a cool little car. I'm really happy with it.
Well, and so, and apparently they won't burn down your house when you charge it,
I guess.
Look, I would have bought a Chevy if they would have sold me one man.
I mean, I'm kind of glad they did it because I think
I bought a used Nissan leaf that's a year old, didn't have a ton of miles on it.
And it, it has all like the weird, like, level two driving auto,
whatever they call that stuff,
I
think.
Yeah. Yeah, it's got whatever.
But anyway, so it could do, like, basically it can drive on the highway by itself.
Right. Which I still have to touch the wheel occasionally or yells at me. But,
and, and the, the Chevy wouldn't have done that.
So, but still, like, 66 Chevys exploded.
That's not bad out of however many what, hundreds of thousands they sold.
Like, well,
it reminds me of when those Mercedes smart
cars kept catching fire and Mercedes of course,
is like, well, it's your fault and then, no,
it turned out to be like a manufacturing defect.
Yeah. Right. Right. Because as I understand it, cars are, um,
not supposed to catch fire, I mean, I guess.
But, but anyway, anyway, it's, uh, no, it's fun.
And then, and then, so what makes it even more fun is I had to,
I had to put a 220 volt outlet in my
garage to charge it because it comes with the charger for
like just 100 and 20 volt, you know, crappy us power.
It's like plugging your ipad into those one AMP chargers
while you're using it. And you can just see the battery dying less slowly.
Yeah. So it would take 48 hours to charge it
with a, a regular plug, which I will say is unacceptable.
But now that I have like a proper outlet and all that jazz, I'm curious, what,
how many amps does that thing draw?
Like? Is it a 40 amp circuit or 50? So the, the charger I have can do 36 amps at 220 volts.
But when you plug it into
20 I was plugged into a 15 amp outlet. So, so you're limited to about 12. Like, yeah.
So anyway, anyway,
that's kind of my story.
It's been a very, it was a very hectic end of the week,
last week because it was the end of my work at Elastic which I,
I'm very grateful for and I still love elastic.
It was a very
amicable parting but truck dies,
leave my job, go buy a car. It was funny because I went to the auto dealership.
I'm like,
I, I don't have any money right now because it's being transferred.
Can I get a loan and I'm unemployed? Technically,
it all worked out in the end,
which is really funny. But
yeah, every time anybody asks me my employment history apart. From those.
Out of the last 20.
Oh, my. Out of the last 23 years I've technically only been employed for seven of them
because you work for yourself. Right. I'm a contractor
in
Canada.
We have a real topic that isn't just Josh's life.
So. 01 quick thought. I'm just curious.
Have you figured out how much time you're gonna save on not having to gas up your car?
Because I just had the random thought, like, if you save five minutes a week,
not gassing up your car that adds up.
I mean, I'm, I don't gas up my car once a week. I'm, I'm skeptical it will be a number
of any significance. I'm more excited to just not buy gas
because I think electricity is cool.
Yeah, I'm aware with you on that
and, and I've got a little app so it's like starting to track
my use. And, like, yesterday I drove 15 miles.
I don't, I don't drive a lot, obviously pick up my kids mostly at school
and it used 50 cents worth of electricity,
which I don't know if that is in kilometers.
That's,
uh, I
don't know. It is times 1.6. So it's about 2023. There you go.
So 23 kilometers, 50 cents, 50 us cents worth of electricity.
That's actually a lot cheaper than gas.
Uh, it is.
They, well, they, I mean, yeah,
they're way cheaper than gas and the price of
gas is going up and the price of electricity is
pretty much the same.
I drive a smaller car and I, my last tank, Philip was almost 60 bucks. Canadian.
Right.
And, and you like your, your, your petrol is expensive.
I live in the United States where it's
comically cheap and people still complain about it.
I've, I've lived in Europe. So when you say expensive money
expectation is about,
yeah.
Right. Right. Yeah, because in Europe it's like double the price per liter.
And anyway, this is a security podcast. We're done. We're done.
We are going to talk about the U A parser,
debacle. We'll call it. It was
OK. I'll go with that. Maybe I
should say debacle. I think,
I think actually it's a debacle but not so much on the sense of the U A parser,
but on the response to it.
Um And, and not for the reasons, I think a lot of people think we're going to take,
well, well, first let's kind of explain
what's going on.
There's a, a node Js library called the U A parser. It's a user agent parser.
And the idea is when you connect with the web browser to a thing,
it,
your web browser sends a user agent and then depending upon what your user agent is,
things might be different because obviously,
like if you're coming from a chrome machine
or a Firefox machine,
it's not a machine.
Um
But you know what I mean? Like you can kind of show things in a different way. Right.
And this is just a library to help with that. And basically
it looks like an attacker
managed to
insert a backdoor
and upload new
packages. Yeah, packages to know N PM.
And then they were there for about four hours.
People found them, they got it all pulled down.
And what amuses me is somebody immediately was like, why,
why is my antivirus triggering on this?
Right. Right. I mean,
it was not subtle if I was going to
describe a, a
ideal scenario of malware,
you know,
going into the pipeline being found and
removed like this actually went really well,
it was four hours.
It wasn't a long time,
but
everyone
I've,
I've seen is now talking about how it's unacceptable that N PM doesn't enforce
two factor off and we need to be signing everything with keys and we need
better supply chain policies and tracking and all this and the thing I,
I keep thinking every time I read this is
I don't think you're wrong,
but none of this is free
and most of most of N PM is literally
a person who does it for fun. You know what I mean? Like this is
you can't ask a volunteer
to jump through these hoops. Well, it's worse than that because
you can make the hoops easier.
So a great example of two factor authentication is at the strongest end.
You've got hardware tokens like UB hes and, you know, Google Titan,
you know, where you have to physically hunt me down and steal my physical key for me.
Right.
And then,
you know, on the, on the really, still pretty good end you got like an app on a phone,
like Google Authenticator or free OTP or
Microsoft, uh, whatever it's called with a little stupid looking icon.
And
those are pretty solid, right?
Like, again, you'd have to hack my phone or steal my phone and
yeah, that's,
yeah, on a modern phone, hacking the phone remotely,
it's doable as we've discussed.
Yeah, this is a good example because two factor authentication you can.
So at the, at the top end of the kind of gold standard we've got hardware tokens,
you know, like UB keys, Google Titan.
I don't know any other brand names and you know,
those are great because you have to physically mug
me and steal my physical keys to get in.
And then
pretty good.
Like I would say 95 to 99% as good is,
is the software app on your phone because a modern phone kept up to date,
you know, unless a state level attacker attacks you, in which case they're,
they're gonna win.
Sorry,
again, pretty good.
But, oh man, setting those things up, that could be tricky. And then
on the easy side,
you've got a
phone based like,
sorry, I should say phone number based
so S MS or a voice call.
But those cost money to send.
Uh, but,
but even ignoring that the amount of work that has to
be done by a package maintainer to support this stuff is,
is quite significant.
And then, well, and you've got the simple one which I hate,
but also kind of makes sense is that the email based
two fa which honestly if you do account recovery via email,
it's the same thing because somebody attacks your email,
they can hijack your account regardless.
Right. You've got to get people to actually set this up and, like, not
lose their token or not,
you know, accidentally wipe their phone or buy a new phone
or,
you know, all
it's a hassle because as soon as you add stronger,
uh, account security,
the chances that people have to do account recovery increase.
That's right.
And then that shifts cost into something like the N PM
project because now you have to have a way for people to
update their stuff.
And it's,
I mean,
the thing I keep thinking about all this is so
supply chain is a hugely popular topic right now
and
we've seen a handful of problems here and there pop up and,
and generally speaking in the open source world,
I think most have been dealt with very quickly, which is really good.
And I think that is,
I, I won't say it's expected,
but we'll say I'm not surprised the reality is number one,
we only know of a few big private
closed source hacks because they were so bad that they made the news,
they had to make the news
and when you look at the timelines on them,
like I'm gonna pick on solar winds because they're a big company with a lot of money.
So we're gonna punch up at them
and, uh, like,
they literally could not have handled it much worse other
than just completely ignoring it and letting it go.
Well, I, I will say though, after the fact
they've been owning this pretty well
and
talking about it, I
want to continue to exist and have government customers.
Yeah, that's probably true. But regardless. So there's,
I, I feel like if you're dealing with a corporate entity,
you could easily make these requests.
But when we're dealing with open source
there,
you can say we should be signing things, we should be enforcing true factor.
We should be doing all this stuff and some of it is getting easier.
Like if you look at the work happening in
cigar,
the ability to sign artifacts while it doesn't quite exist yet, it's really,
really close.
Well,
but that leads to one challenge where for example,
instead of having say N PM provide really good account security,
you can just sort of outsource the whole thing by using single sign on and say,
for example, requiring a Facebook or a Google login.
But then the problem becomes, you know, which providers do you pick?
How do you anoint them?
How do you get enough coverage of providers so that everybody's happy because,
you know, some people don't want to use Facebook
Microsoft owns N PM now.
Right. Let's see.
Windows
log
in.
Yeah, exactly.
Yeah.
And I suspect that might be a bit of a
bridge too far for some of these open source developers.
And then the second problem is
as much as I love Sig Store.
My fear is kind of like, let's encrypt. I, I'm really happy to see that.
Let's encrypt has competitors now. And so is let's encrypt because
uh like let's encrypt could theoretically go away someday,
right? It's unlikely.
But it's possible and I it would be really bad if Lets
and Crip was the only game in town and then suddenly went away
and, and Looks Star is an open source project.
Anyone could run their own registry and their own infrastructure if they wanted to.
There's no reason. And, and I don't think that's,
that is too theoretical. Like we don't even have the meat
on the bones
in, in the Siga
universe today to have that conversation.
I think you're, you're getting way ahead of yourself.
The question becomes we have all these open source developers
and now there are people saying we, you should do more
and the thing I want you to do, you don't want to do.
You know what I'm going to disagree with you.
I don't think a lot of them don't want to do this.
It's just that they have an infinite pile of fires to deal with.
And this is not
that important, to be honest. Does that count as, don't want to do?
I mean, you, you're right. I think we're, I think
they would,
I think it kind of boils down to like last week's episode uh with uh Chris Weiss.
So
in that a lot of these developers
don't understand the benefit of security education.
And once they
like, my experience is when a lot of people actually kind of get security,
they're like, 00, I actually do want to learn this,
you know, and same thing with
uh password manager is a great example.
I remember my mother
saying and I quote,
so wait, I only have to remember like two passwords now,
like my phone password and my password manager, password. And I'm like, yeah,
that's the, I'm like, exactly. And she's like,
oh, I like that. I'm like, yes, yes, yes, you will.
But ok, so I think you bring up a really important point that I was,
I thought we'd get to later, but now is fine,
like
making the secure option, the easy option,
the better is the important thing.
But, but today, things like two factor authentication
and signing of artifacts
and having multiple sign offs on commits
and having a release process. And like, none of that
is the easy.
Well, all requires work
well and worse. It's not
only hard, it's not better.
Like,
now that I've actually gotten into using a password manager quite religiously,
I basically have memorized four passwords.
Right. Two work ones and two personal ones. That's it. And I, I love it,
you know,
the, the problem with release signing and two fa and so on is it doesn't
generally make life that much better.
Like
it just doesn't really like
how does it make life better for the developer?
It, it kind of doesn't and even for so on on both both developers,
the developer building the package and the developer receiving the package,
it doesn't technically change that relationship in a meaningful way.
What signed artifacts do
is they allow somewhere upstream to do some verification or you know what I mean?
Like
tunnel from A to B like as long as it was secure, then
it doesn't matter what happened between A and B because I checked the signature.
It's correct. OK.
I mean, yeah, kind of, that's a good way to look at it. And I think
this again creates this weird dynamic where
a lot of developers,
I I'm not saying they don't care about security but they want to develop,
they don't want to spend
hours verifying things and checking things and making sure it's OK.
And you could argue, oh, we'll just build some tooling and stuff,
but that's also a huge job.
You know, it's hard to do, but we've done that, like,
look at how much better it has made the world.
Like
I remember the time before
and it was bad.
Well, this is like
III, I work at anchor now. This is literally one of the things they're doing, like
the tooling is getting better. And I think,
I, I think it is the future, but there's still,
there's always that aspect of friction
that
whatever you do, if, if you increase friction,
people find ways around it.
You know what I mean? And that's the challenge.
A lot of historical security friction. Not only are we creating friction,
but then we're saying you have to learn about
the friction and spend more time doing the friction
and,
and users are like,
no,
yeah, I mean, I agree like my favorite example is always phishing.
OK? So we're going to tell you not to click on emails not to open links.
I literally just got an email from my Adobe sales contact with a link to his calendar,
right?
And you know, like, what am I gonna check it to make sure it's all correct?
And then how would you check it?
You know, like, so I click show original. Ok. SPFD Kim and D marker. I'll pass it.
Is adobe.com I'm gonna cut and paste it into notepad to make sure it's not, you know,
a homo
homo
glyph attack, you know, using like some Cyrillic letter D or something.
And OK, it actually does appear to be from adobe.com correctly.
Now, let's see, the link goes to,
I've never seen that domain before.
I have no
idea
what that is.
You clicked it, didn't you?
I'm right. Clicking. Copy link address it is.
Or
mimas.com. What the heck is or
meas.com?
See, but look at this like you have an audience listening to you now,
verify a link and 00, the site cannot be reached seriously.
The root level domain doesn't have a website
but does the subdomain
a dopey
Adobe?
Noy
A SMB dot What?
Like I thought it would be Adobe on something.
OK. OK. That's enough. And
if I, if I just put the, the full Adobe
uh host name in
again, airs out to an error page.
I have to put the full link in with like slash C slash
the user name to get to this guy's calendar to make an appointment.
So basically, it's Paul.
OK.
Yes. Also, I'm just gonna hit unsubscribe.
This is, this is the finest segment we've ever done in this podcast.
But that's the point. I can't even safely click a link. And II, I tried really hard.
We'll say hard enough
like yes. And, and so this is the point is
we want to tell open source,
these are the expectations we have of you.
But we don't, if you're going to say that we need to somehow fund this,
this can't just be talk of people saying, oh, you should do this, you should do that.
You should sign things who is going to pay for this. None of this is free.
It needs funding, it needs sponsorship, it needs accountability
and I feel like that's the piece of the conversation. So
a package in N PM gets back doored.
Everyone is like, oh my goodness, look at this, look at this.
You need to fix everything you do.
Why can't N PM just throw every file upload through virus total dot com's API is it?
No, it's not free at that scale. Well, I'm sure,
you know, Microsoft can probably afford
or Microsoft can just chuck it through theirs.
I mean, I, I don't know, like come on,
I think Microsoft can do virus scanning if they can't do virus scanning at scale.
Well, they have Defender, right? They, they, they literally have a virus scanner.
Well,
like virus total was set up by that Spanish University department and then they,
you know, sold to Google,
like
Microsoft's almost a trillion dollar company.
If they can't do this, then that's on them. I mean,
I,
I
don't know, I don't know if
saying
N PM should be responsible. Well, here's the question.
Why shouldn't they scan it for viruses?
Because it would have caught this,
it would have caught this immediately and
they could have flagged it and immediately,
you know.
Yeah, I mean, you're right. This is scanning scanning package uploads for viruses.
Seems like a no brain
like red hat scans all the RP MS before they go to customers.
And thank goodness we do because remember that, um, for a while,
Ali
A V had that stupid rule. If a file was double zipped, it was flagged as suspicious.
And there was a product that had a double zipped file because it had,
what was it? It was like
Ruby or Java Based or something and it included some component that then
got zipped into a thing to be delivered to the client or whatever.
Anyway,
so it flagged this component and I had to write a
knowledge based article and put it on the website because,
you know, customers are freaking out.
Right. Right.
You know,
and so one of the things I've historically done is
I've scanned artifacts through virus total before releasing them.
Not because I'm worried about them having a virus,
but because I'm worried about them having a
false positive that then customers freak out.
Yeah, I've, I've been through that more than once.
And so if, if for that reason, if nothing else,
I virus scan stuff so that I don't have to deal with people freaking out.
But uh there's, you shipped me a virus. I, I think you're right.
But now if we look at it from like the N PM perspective,
I'm not paying them any money.
No. What, what is my expectation from N PM
if I'm just doing N PM, install
$0 are exchanged.
I think the expectation in general is that when you release software to the web,
even for free, that it's not a virus ridden pile of garbage.
I feel like you're right,
but I, I'm not willing to
put my myself behind that statement yet.
I, I feel, I mean this
in the world of open source
to be backdoor
free. Well, well, here's the question. Let's say
I create an open
source package and I purposely put a virus in it.
I put in the release notes,
I have put a virus in this package which no
one will read and then people start to use it.
I would say it's ethically wrong. It's
maybe, is it, is it illegal? I don't know. But you know what I mean? Like
it actually, well, in some jurisdictions,
it absolutely would be illegal but part of it would be, there's the,
so there are intentional, like there's like web goat,
like there's web servers and applications with
intentional security flaws for training purposes,
but they're, you know, clearly labeled as such.
Now, if I create an N PM package,
unless it's like,
you know, uh this is for example, this N PM package sends the
icard.com string
so that you can test if your stuff catches viruses,
right?
Iar.com being, you know,
a harmless text string that we've all agreed
is quote unquote virus for testing purposes.
But if I actually include like, say a crypto minor or some ransomware in it.
Um, ignoring the damage aspect. Let's say I include a back door.
Well, there's that aspect of damage, but let's ignore that for a moment.
So let's say there's some malware in there that's quote unquote harmless,
but say it impacts system performance. Well,
yeah, we expect like let me put it this way.
If somebody's handing out free samples at Costco,
it better be actual food.
I mean
like if I'm out on the street handing out. Oh, perfect.
So I'm out on the street handing out flyers,
you expect them not to be covered in poison?
I I would expect that although I would also not take your flyer because I hate,
I hate taking those.
Ok.
Ok, you made me think of something and we're, we're getting kind of close to the end.
So maybe, maybe we'll wrap this up and, and think of it this way.
So there's like the whole open source universe, right?
And I think today there's a lot of unfettered use
of open source where people aren't just pulling it in
and there's maybe some misunderstandings and what it
is or what's happening or what not.
But if you think about in the context context of like Red Hat, back back in the day,
people didn't trust open source,
but they were willing to trust Red Hat because Red Hat was like,
we will do everything we can to make this trustworthy and
I think our circle of trust is now expanded to include open source generally.
Now, if, if I'm a person making a thing for free and I pull an open source and I, I think
that you can make a reasonable expectation that I'm not
going to do a ton of due diligence on that.
Right? I, I think that's fair.
But if I'm a company and I'm making a product,
I think there are certain expectations
that and in the contracts as well, it's going to spell out a lot of this. So I think that
the, the trust is still has to be in the companies. I just think the companies have
maybe, maybe they're not doing the due diligence they should be doing.
Maybe I'm starting to feel like
if you are worried about an N PM package,
how are you going to do some verification?
Well, let's take a step back too because there's for example,
github.com/company name, like Facebook or whatever, where they release stuff,
open source for free, you know,
and again, I would expect that that stuff's virus free.
I would expect that stuff to not have backdoors in it.
Right.
And I, I, no amount of like, oh,
we put it in the change log that it has this backdoor so that we can do, you know,
performance testing whether you like it or not.
No, that I wouldn't be shocked if Facebook stuff
had some sort of phone home mechanism
and that's different, like there's,
there's lots of phone home mechanisms that are legit, like we want to report,
you know,
um like what your system uh type is so that we can see, you know,
are people running this on Linux or Windows or whatever, right?
The reality is I would also expect Facebook wants to protect their brand,
for example, like any major company would want to protect their brand typically.
Uh
and as such, I would then expect them to,
to do some minimal effort to make sure that they're not
shipping, complete flaming open source garbage.
I mean,
yeah, it's,
I feel like this is such, I I I've been thinking about this all week and I think there's
still a lot of unanswered questions because you're right, there's the,
the the aspect of companies and their brands and their, their open source,
their usage of open source.
There's the open source, I guess here's what,
here's what I would kind of boil it all down as
I think, expecting
open source developers
whose stuff you're using
for? Probably free, expecting them to follow your rules is not realistic.
So the question becomes, how, how do we incentivize?
How, how do we start maybe boiling some trust up into open source?
Because I think that's what this is.
I think things like signing packages and multi factor off for
uploading artifacts and whatever it's all just about
starting to, to put trust in place, but it's not free So how are we gonna pay for it?
How are we gonna add accountability? And I don't think anyone knows that today.
Honestly, this is probably
a new business opportunity. I suspect it needs to be
or not needs to be, but I suspect it will be much better
and more effective if it's cooked into the
underlying platforms like gith Lab and github.
And it's just
there as a thing. And
again,
Github's a company and not only a company, but it's been acquired by Microsoft.
So they have a little bit of money behind them. And
I would
like to think that Microsoft,
they keep saying that, you know, we're open source friendly, blah, blah, blah,
we've changed no more Halloween memos,
no more cancer,
you know, of open source.
And
I think it's on Microsoft to do some of the work here.
If they want people to continue to trust github,
right? Because right now github
is in a fair, it's a golden era of trust, right? Everything is in github.
No. And, and I mean, this is part of my point, right? Like let's say Git
lab starts incorporating all this stuff. I think that is,
that is a differentiator. Now, if github
isn't doing it and Git Lab is doing it,
you could, you know what I mean?
That, that,
that gives us an incentive to do more open
source with Git lab or if there's some other,
I know there's other hosting
or source control whatever we call, get up and get lab. You know what I mean?
I, I feel like there's a huge opportunity here and I think part of it too is also
what do people expect and want and what are providers actually doing and,
and that speaks to, you know, the, the,
like the Linux Foundation badges program and stuff because
for example, has this repo
scan for viruses?
Well, I have no idea.
Right.
Does this repo
enforce two fa for the developers?
I have no idea. And there's no way you can tell for the most part
without having some sort of external source.
Verify. I mean, it's kind of the same thing with compliance. Right. Where
I know you and I have talked at length in private about like sock two compliance where
it's one of those things getting, it isn't particularly difficult.
It says a lot if you can, you have to get it. You know what I mean?
It's one of those, like
you wash your hands after you use the toilet sort of things.
Oh, yeah.
No, I,
I just found out one of my favorite restaurants in
a small town is completely anti vax and it's like,
well, I can never go there again because they don't follow health code.
So
that sucks because they had really good hot dogs.
And what else are you doing? You know,
I mean,
that's the question
and, and I think,
yeah, and maybe, maybe the scorecard
is
the first step in the right direction, I guess.
So, the problem again, the scorecard comes back to is ok.
So we're scoring open source and if they want to take the next step, how,
how like who's doing the work, how is it being paid for, what's going on, you know,
and that's why I think it,
it really the best bang for the buck will come in when like github
does this and just, it's a switch that you either.
Well, ideally have to opt out of if it's actually better security and not, you know,
a privacy issue or whatever or has like a relatively easy opt in switch.
And that's just it, maybe it'll be github,
maybe it'll be someone else. I don't know the answer, but I do think you're right.
I think
somehow
we need an easy button
to, you know, steal the trope where it's basically like
secure my project. Click. There we go. We're all set everybody.
Well,
you know, if you go into github,
I, I don't think there's a dashboard.
Ok.
Better example,
Wordpress has a security dashboard built into it now since quite a while.
And for example,
mine keeps nagging me to upgrade my version of PHP because I'm running on a Buntu 18
LTs. So it's like,
you know,
technically it's out of date, but it's back port of patches,
but the security dashboard in wordpress
is great because it's like, here's a bunch of stuff that's wrong.
Click here to fix it and it like takes you to the
plug in screen where it's like here's a punch out outdated plugins,
hit that update button or you know, you need to upgrade PHP
like a
get update PHP or you know,
it actually has either actionable advice or a link to directly.
Like click here, click here, click that to enable this.
And so github
for example, could have a thing where like it could have an egg screen saying, hey,
you know, you don't enforce two fa on your organization or projects,
please do or you know, click here to ignore because you just don't want to.
Again,
I think a lot of people just don't think of it
or they just don't get around to it because you know,
do you want your project fixing bugs or turning on two of a?
No, I, I agree and that's just my point, right?
Like no developers want to develop, they don't want to manage all this crap. So
I don't know the answer
to
all this crap. They would not be in github.
Yeah, that's true. That's
true.
All right. I need to call this one. I again,
I guess more questions and answers.
But it's
if, if someone listening has the answer, let us know.
I think part of this feedback loops and capturing those desires and wants and
you know,
I would actually love to see from 100 developers like why haven't you
enabled tu of a and I suspect 20% of them would be like,
oh, shoot.
Yeah, I should do that. Click, click can be done in five minutes. Maybe. I don't know.
I don't know. All right, calling it. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. Go to preserve
Security podcast.com,
Susie Pounds
his podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the.