Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in scoring crime.
Josh Pressers.
Yeah, we'll get to that. I have a funny story to tell first. So
-- in my recording studio,
-- isn't it a closet with a big crack behind
your head?
There's no crack anymore. I fix that. But yes, it is a closet.
I
have a large walk in closet. It's like 3 m by 3 m with the Slanty roof behind me.
-- Kind
-- of, I am so proud of you for saying that.
Well, I know
the vast majority of our listeners are not in the United States and I would
say anyone in the US who listens to us knows what a meter is.
So I'm comfortable using,
we'll say not crazy units, whatever possible temperature,
I still struggle with sometimes.
Anyway. Anyway. So in my recording studio slash closet,
I, I
was thinking, I don't like the amount of echo I'm getting.
So I had a bunch of foam panels in the basement and I thought
I'm going to melt them to some boards and hang them on the walls,
right.
So over the weekend
I get out the contact cement. I start doing my thing
and I thought I had an enormous amount of ventilation
in the garage while I was working on this.
No, you don't. I was high as a kite when I left that garage and I didn't even,
and the thing is you don't realize it until like,
you step in the fresh air and it's like,
whoa, we,
we have to put a link in the show notes to like one of
those uh us Air Force training videos on hypoxia where like the guy,
you know, it's like, what,
like they have a deck of cards and they're supposed to
pull the top card and say what car it is.
Show it to everybody and he's like four spades
and he pulls in,
it's like
four spades
and he just gets
like, he, he gets to the point where they put the mask on him or he's going to die.
Yeah. Right. Right.
It's, yeah, it's like being drunk, it sneaks up on you. And
the problem is by the time you can realize
you're drunk or hypoxic or messed up on solvents.
-- Yeah, your forebrain is gone.
-- It was, it was, I was like, holy cow.
And then I just went in the house and I told my wife I'm like,
I need to go sit down for a little while
and
she's like, are you OK? I said
I just inhaled a lot of contact cement and then of course,
everyone started laughing at me because
I, and I, I, like I even said, she's like, you should use ventilation.
I was like, go look at the amount of ventilation I have going right now in that garage.
-- Like go look and I, she goes out and looks, she comes back and it was like, holy
-- cow,
you gotta open the garage
and just run box fans and do this in summer.
I,
I have a room above my garage and I open all the windows and I actually
had three fans sucking air out the window and it still wasn't enough like it was.
Anyway. Anyway, valuable lesson learned, not dead.
And now I have a bunch of foam padding on the walls, which makes me very happy.
So that's my, that's my story.
Anyway,
scoring open source,
I guess we'll have probably the show notes will be
like the judge is holding up the 9 to 10,
whatever.
I don't know. We'll see. I've gotta, I gotta think about that anyway.
So the reason we're talking about this is there's the open SSF which uh open
source Security Foundation I think it's in for if you don't know who they are,
like, just go look them up.
It, it's, they have many projects they do
and one of them is they're calling the,
the open score cards, I think.
And basically they released version 3.0 of this.
And so Kurt and I started kind of chatting on signal. And I,
this would be a fun topic because here is the first question that comes to my brain.
Is it acceptable to be measuring an open source project
-- that you say have no relationship to?
-- Yeah, of course it is.
Yeah. Well, we look at cars whose ratings do you trust about a car?
More Ford's ratings or consumer reports where consumer reports goes and
buys a car and smashes it to make sure it's safe.
So here's the thing I keep thinking about on this though is there,
there's measuring like, say
the Apache software foundation projects which I'm perfectly ok with.
But then there's like
some stuff a guy wrote
the score is going to be terrible
because they don't want to do this. Now, what does
you're telling someone your baby is ugly because
you're not following these rules we made,
-- but
-- we're supposed to give everybody a free pass and open.
Let me put it this way.
We don't hang children's art in the Louver just because they put their heart into it.
So
I don't, I don't want to use open source that somebody really cares about.
I want to use open source. That's really good. I,
and the reality is in a lot of open source.
The one that is even not very good is still better than any other option,
right? Like my favorite thing to pick on is Lib J peg because
LJ Pig started out life as a thesis defense. Right. Straight up somebody at U BC
was wrote Lib J peg for their thesis and then, because it was open source licensed,
everybody else used it.
I tried tracking this human being down. I was unable to.
Wow.
Well, it's lib J
peg. Like it's trust me. If you have a device with AC pu in it,
there's a copy of lib J peg floating around somewhere on the storage attached to it.
-- You
-- know, this reminds me of a story from a long time ago is the the folks
Z if that do
OG
Vars
the sound and they do like BP eight I think, and they've got a bunch of codex, right?
They're like really smart people and the guy who kind of runs it all.
His name is Chris Montgomery. He's really cool.
He's got some really good youtube videos talking about this stuff.
I will dig up and put in the show notes because there he
was called the Bob Ross of audio at one point and they're phenomenal.
Anyway, anyway, I remember there was some security issues in I think it was,
it was the, I
think it was Lib Vor
at the time
and I was talking to him and he's like, oh, this is meant to be a reference library.
No one should be using this in production.
I was like, Chris,
this is in everything like this is literally one
of the most used libraries on the planet today.
We need to worry about this.
Well,
here's the thing is there even a remote second place contender to something like Lib
Forbis or Lib Jpeg
that is even 50% as functional
open SSL like, oh, you mean you mean direct competitors to those libraries?
OK. So liv
vs is, here's arguing. Liv
Forbis is supposed to be the reference implementation is like saying we're
going to build a prototype and then build it for real.
No, if you build a prototype that even works 50% bam that's production.
-- Why the heck did you rewrite it?
-- No, I agree. I agree.
Well, it's just that if we haven't figured that out in the last 50 years of software,
then there's, there's no hope like that.
That's just how it is.
I
won't lie to you when I say I've done this more than once where I do
something and I know it's exceptionally poor quality
and I think it's just an experiment.
That's my justification to myself of why it sucks so hard anyway. Anyway. OK.
So scoring. OK. So
I,
I guess you're not wrong is if I'm a company and I'm doing something with open source,
even if it's the kids' picture on the refrigerator,
at least I know it's a kid's picture on the refrigerator and it's not a work of art
that I'm, I'm dealing with. And I guess just knowing that
is probably acceptable,
I would say this is part of the artistic and software process is it's OK.
When you give somebody a gift,
you give them a gift and they get to do with it as they wish.
That's kind of how gifts work, right?
And I would say if you release art or you release software or you release literature,
you are now open to critique.
That is how that works.
If you do not want your work critiqued, don't show it to anybody.
I guess that's probably fair
you
up and down both buttons.
They
do and a comment section that is a toxic.
And so I, I would argue
now that's not to say people should be mean and rude and terrible. Like
there's a big difference between constructive
criticism and helpful feedback then.
Well, yeah, the youtube comment section.
Well, and I guess with these scores,
some projects will release a score and they will take it to heart and say
-- I could do better with this. Some projects won't.
-- Well, some projects
can't.
Well, yes and, and that's so that's my next point is
I think one of the missing pieces to all this
is
so the open ssf has all these projects.
They're doing things like measuring open source.
They've got the salsa framework now like this is
cool work and I think this is very important.
Like don't get me wrong. None of it's perfect. I'm not gonna say it's perfect,
but this is all a good start down a very long road that we have in front of us. However,
I think one of the pieces missing is, I feel like, so you just scored a project.
They didn't do great.
Now what?
You know what I mean? And I don't think there's any follow through that I'm aware of.
Well, and that's the thing though. It's, it's not up to the open ssf to decide.
Now what, because now what might be, it doesn't matter or now what might be?
Somebody sees that score and goes, oh, this is,
I actually use this and maybe they need
some help because one thing that drives me nuts
is I think we can both agree that the vast majority of open source that gets used
like actually used like not somebody's pet, you know,
project with like three users but something like
and I, I like left, I was it left pad, right.
But companies use that and they,
they use it heavily and they rarely if ever contribute anything meaningful back.
And this might be a good signal for companies to go.
Oh, like this thing that we rely upon heavily, we need to maybe
-- help keep it healthy.
-- I think you're, you're halfway there.
Here is the better example I would give is when we
were at Red Hat and working heavily with open source projects,
we would never just show up with a vulnerability and say here you go, fix it.
We would always show up with help and say we found this.
If you want us to help you with this, we will, here is what we can do to help you be it.
We can work on patches, we can review patches, we can write advisories for you.
We can get you CV ES.
-- We can
-- coordinate,
you can't score a like you can't score 10,000 open
source projects and then offer all of them help.
No, no, I I agree. I'm not saying the Linux Foundation needs to
specifically do this themselves,
but I feel like
the thing that scares me to death
is we're going to score all this stuff and people are going to start freaking out
and they're going to do dumb things like say, oh, we'll just write that ourselves,
which is like
that
if their process and, and management is that immature,
they're, they're gonna do dumb things regardless. I mean,
that could be
like no offense, but
I, I don't buy that as an argument.
The like this is like saying, oh, if we, you know, if,
if consumer reports gets the score on a car wrong, people won't buy that car.
That,
that is true though.
If they fail a car based on faulty assumptions, no one is going to buy that car.
In that case,
there's a car manufacturer with a lot of money who should then help correct that,
you know,
-- so the dynamics are different.
-- But if I'm a person with the github
project,
you're
not
my project wrong.
So what, what now,
I mean, and maybe, I don't know,
and there have been open
source projects in the past that have become pariahs for a variety of reasons.
Like the maintainer was a jerk or
the,
the project was very, oh, I mean,
we've seen cases where the project is a nightmare to work with and so people fork it
and it is true. You know,
again, what, like why is there some, why is there this expectation
that I wrote a piece of open source software? And now the world owes me something
-- and
-- I don't think they necessarily do and I agree with that.
I think if you open source, your project,
you owe the world nothing and they owe you nothing.
I pretty sure that's explicitly in the license
pretty much like
on the
source bits, right? Obviously,
I want to give a shout out to Tide Lift right now.
I don't know if anyone else doing this,
if there's other companies doing this sort of work, like, let me know,
but Tide Lift is a company that's working on basically funding open source work.
And so they're doing some really cool stuff if
you're a company using lots of open source,
like go check them out.
-- It's totally worth it.
-- I look at Patreon and at first I was like, oh
yuck, but
there's actually some really,
really good content creators now that are getting funded through
Patreon that are doing some really good work and,
and some, you know, a lot of it is,
I guess it would be like hyper niche kind of
knowledge or hobbies, you know,
like
which,
yeah,
it turns out there's like 1000 people globally that will
pay a dollar or $2 or $5 a month.
And
well, now that's your full time job.
Yep. Yep.
Yeah. Totally. Totally. Alright. Alright. Before we,
I want,
I want to talk about some of these scores
because I think there's like the criteria they're using.
I think there's some interesting stuff here. So let me pull up the list.
Here it is. Alright. Alright.
So I'm just going to start at the top. I'll put a link to this list in the show notes.
You can, you can look it up and follow along if you like.
Uh All right. So the first one here says binary artifacts
is the project free of checked in binaries. This is where
let's say a project checks in an executable file,
which is obviously a terrible idea into their github
repo.
I
I don't I don't think anyone's going to complain about this one, right?
Um Well, binary objects. What about artwork or MP threes?
I wouldn't if they if they're I haven't read the long description
of this one because I felt like it was too obvious.
I
there is no way
they count that as a binary
would in general
99.999% agree with.
I'm sure there's one or two valid corner cases,
which is basically you're going to need like a phone book size disclaimer.
So, it basically is true. I think the biggest thing about
the, the lack of binary would be
of
every time I've seen a binary pulled in,
it's because of an immature process and it
indicates a whole pile of other problems basically.
Right. Right.
You know, it's like,
let me put it this way when you find a rotten floor in a house,
it's not just a rotten floor in a house, the water came from somewhere.
Yeah, I just looked this up. Uh, specifically they call it compiled.
We're good. We're good. I don't want to dwell on this one.
It's too obvious, too obvious.
Uh, brand protection. Does the project use brand protection. No brainer.
-- Here's
-- if you have like a single developer project, it doesn't really matter.
-- I mean,
-- no, no, it doesn't.
But I think for any project of any reasonable size as say, two or more developers.
Yeah. Sure, great idea.
Yeah, it's a coordinating tool.
Well, not only that, this helps you not screw things up.
You hear about these horror stories where people accidentally do like a
forced merger or something and they blow away all of their github
repo.
This protects you from that
use
it.
That was,
that was easy.
Uh C I test does a project run tests and ci I feel like
this one is, I don't have huge complaints about this one. Really.
When we interviewed Danny pointed out that
you need to have a testing framework,
even if you have zero tests because once you
have a testing framework then you can have tests.
Right. Exactly.
And now I will say so
I recently I, I'll put a link. I, my son
is learning Python.
He's on the robotics team for his school and they're going to use Python.
And I'm like, good idea.
What's the alternative?
Well, well, so the supported languages we'll put them in quotes is A C++
and I'm like,
there's nothing wrong with those. But if
-- there is for Python, that's better.
-- Do you love your child?
And is he under the age of 18,
-- Python is
-- the choice anyway. Anyway, the point is
I,
I stood up like a Python skeleton framework that has the unit test and it has
like how the modules should be laid out and stuff for these kids because I'm like,
look, just check this out and use it.
This is going to save you for someone who doesn't know how Python works.
This is probably
a
week's worth of work for these kids.
-- And I'm like, I did this in a couple of hours, just take it and go.
-- Is it in github?
Because I know in github
there's like a github.
Ignore repo that has all the
get
ignores for, say Python or emacs or all these other things.
Yeah.
Yeah,
they do. They do. I, I didn't add that. But anyway, anyway, doesn't matter.
All right.
No, no. I mean, did you, did you put your Python stand up thing in Github?
-- So that other people can just grab it?
-- Oh, yeah, it's in,
I'll put them on.
It's not very exciting.
Um, anyway, anyway, anyone,
anyone moderately competent can do this in a couple of minutes.
I'm not moderately competent. So it took me two hours.
All right. Uh, ca I best practices.
We talked to David Wheeler about ci I in like,
I think it was one of the single digit episodes of this podcast.
I'm not going to link to the show because we sucked back then.
But we should probably bring David back at some point
and talk about what CI I is doing today.
I feel like
I like ci I because it is an opt in program.
So if a program is, or if a project is mature enough,
they can opt to ci I and say these are
the things we're doing and ca I provide some guidance.
I think maybe the scorecard and salsa might,
will say encapsulate ci I at some point. But for the moment,
it's a great program.
If you have a project, you should go look at it.
Yeah, I would agree.
I mean,
CIA actually has some good actionable advice and
generally has goals that are consistent with sanity.
-- Yeah.
-- Absolutely. Absolutely.
Alright. Uh code views.
Does the project require code reviews before code is merged?
Yeah, that's, well,
and the thing is as much as I want to say that's absolutely required.
It should be. But
my concern is code reviews.
Always my eyes glaze over and I just smash that like button.
Well, that's just it, I mean
the
lyrics
-- incident, right?
-- If you're a one person show you who's going to review your code.
You actually, it's funny I have AAA repo at work. I do some things in that
I'm the only committer to but I still have my own branch
and I approve my own commits.
So it's like this is stupid, you know.
Well,
but the thing is you've now set it up so that when
a second person comes along and wants to help you with it,
there's
ok. Click.
There's nothing to set up. There's no friction.
-- This
-- is the ultimate forever alone meme because it
was like people will come and help me.
Nobody came in
here.
It's just me approving my own commands. Like do do do.
Yeah,
I would say it's one of those things. It's like shoulder checking. I always
always shoulder check,
even when I'm merging into a lane that like starts like
there's a curve that winds out and the lane starts.
I still shoulder check because my rule is I always shoulder
check and I always signal my lane changes so that it's just
physical mechanical habit
Yep. Yep.
And I, because I've caught myself almost merging into people when I'm tired but,
because it's just like an ingrained reflex.
Oh,
-- there's a car
-- there. We got to keep going. We're going to run out of time
contributors.
Does the project have contributors from at least two different organizations?
It's, it's one of those health of the project issues
and it's also
like,
what if the guy wants to go or the girl or
the whoever wants to go on sabbatical or take a vacation?
I mean, that's fair. I,
and there's like a critical security flaw in it.
Yeah, I'm not going to argue this 11 way or the other.
I feel like there's lots of projects that might have
a handful of people from the same organization like is that
and
a
perfect example.
I was looking at the smart health card standard and so of course,
went and grabbed the Python library for it,
which is actually really simple and noticed somebody had
cloned the Python library
kind of removed a bunch of the
uh history and then published it on um on one of the sites essentially
under their name with a sort of a more search engine optimized name.
And
you know, that that library is probably gonna
become widely used now,
but it's just sort of one person who I'm not
sure they have the expertise to actually fix the library.
So I would say that this is important because it's a red flag.
It's, it goes back to, you know,
y Combinator where they will not take a pitch from a single person
company because if you cannot convince another person to work on your idea,
-- we're not giving you money for it. Yeah, that's
-- fair. OK. OK. I think we're in
agreement. Dependency update tool.
-- Does the project use tools to help update its dependencies?
-- Yeah.
-- If you don't do this and it's 2021. Yeah,
-- I agree. I mean
github
has depend,
aot depend
aot is free, right?
There's other, if you're a company, you can pay another organization to,
there's a bunch of scanning vendor like, yeah, this is,
this is the world we're in today and you can make arguments about how,
oh the scanners have a lot of false positives and some of
these don't really matter and whatever and some of that is true.
But I think generally speaking,
these scanners have become pretty good at what they're doing.
Well, more to the point.
If you're using any modern language that has
built independency management and you're ignoring it,
then
what else are you doing wrong? And I will use the word wrong very clearly. Yep.
Yep, 100%. Uh All right.
Fuzzing. Does the project use fuzzing tools like Os S Fuzz?
Um I'm OK with them not fuzzing because some
tools are uh not,
they don't really. OK. Perfect example. I remember American Date. It converts
normal sane rational dates into that
month, day, year format.
If you were to fuzz it, in theory,
you should find all the edge cases pretty quick and fix it.
Fuzzing is complicated.
Some languages,
strongly typed languages lend themselves well
to fuzzing weekly type languages don't.
So for example, Fuzzing a node library is
nontrivial generally, but fuzzing say a Java library is usually pretty easy.
So this one, I think
I'm OK with this score but they, I don't, they don't put a ton of weight on it,
which I think is right.
I would
put it more fuzzing
the interfaces that accept user controlled input,
be it network or files or whatever.
I mean,
yeah, but like the problem you get is
you have to, there's, there's a lot of heavy lifting if it's a weekly type language.
But anyway, um yeah, I it's fair.
-- I mean, fuzzing is boring now, but
-- the thing is fuzzing will get better.
It, well, it, it's been getting better for like two decades now.
Uh maintained is the project maintain.
This one's where they basically say like has it
received an update in the last 90 days?
Like
this is a no brainer. I think
I feel like quarterly code commits are not asking for a lot.
Uh
And look there are projects that don't need updates but a couple of times a year,
those are rare
and you can easily pick those out
and say this is OK.
But if I'm using
a html parsing library from 2014.
Holy crap. What have I done? You know what I mean?
All right. Uh, pin dependencies. Does the project declare in pin dependencies?
I don't know about this one.
We, we discussed this the other day actually and I think we're in the same boat.
So I'll let you go first.
I'll be a jerk and say it's complicated.
It's a
-- jerk.
-- This
is true.
Yeah.
I
the, the upside of pinning dependencies is you actually know what's in there
and
it's more stable, right?
You're not going to get some random update that then break stuff on the flip side
in a perfect world and we are nowhere near a perfect world.
Everybody runs current and has tests and knows the moment something
changes and breaks and is able to quickly rectify it.
And the majority of us do not live in that world.
The majority of us don't even floss.
I,
I do floss here is the way I would describe
this is I think when you have a release build,
you should pin your dependencies because
if I,
if I say do a build
and then I hand you the source repo and tell you to build it also
and there's no pin dependencies,
you're going to get whatever's latest and a bunch of libraries could have
-- changed from the time I built it to the time you built
-- it.
Well, it becomes increasingly nondeterministic.
Right. Right.
And in fact, in some cases,
if you're using latest and you wait like six months and then do a build,
it's just going to explode because like the
API is different or something in your dependencies.
So I think from the perspective of having like stable branches,
I like pin dependencies.
But from the perspective of having like your main branch,
I feel like pin dependencies could potentially be holding you back and
you can end up in situations where things start to rot.
However, however, there's one big caveat to this.
If you are using a scanning tool,
then that will catch some of this.
So it's like
-- a, this is a big part of confusion.
-- Here's a stupid question.
Does any language that does dependency management
allow you to have the concept of
an unpinned dependency with a suggestion of saying, for example,
this absolutely works with 3.5 0.0
but we're going to suggest that you use current
and thus if it blows up, you know, you can go back to 3.5 0.0
uh you sort of, you can do
something
greater
-- than like they'll do like equal to or greater than a version
-- they have.
Uh uh it's common in I think node and Ruby do this where you
can basically say like version three or greater only in the version three,
like version four won't be met by this,
this dependency, you know what I mean?
And so like for example, I'll, I'll keep yanking the latest version three
and while version three might still be alive, version four just came out.
-- I'm not going to automatically download that one
-- because it
seems to me if you had the concept of,
OK, we'll try it with the latest and then if it blows up,
we'll walk it back to the ones we know,
work that might help kind of get the best of both worlds.
Yeah, maybe, I don't know. Anyway. All right. This one's kind of complicated.
This could probably be a show on its own.
So we're just going to keep moving because we're in and out of time. Good packaging.
Uh No packaging is next.
There's, there's actually two lists and the one,
the short list has packaging after independenc season
and the long list has packaging before.
So,
all right. Does the project project publish,
does the project build and publish official packages from C I CD?
Like using github publishing?
Um
No,
I think it makes sense.
Well, I can't think of any language,
any modern language where that's not really appropriate.
Um If it's, if it's written in C or C++,
I could totally see doing a source only release and just, you know,
the standard dot slash configure
dot Smash,
make install.
But
-- anything written in Python or Java or Rust or anything and
-- these are,
these are dependencies we're talking about.
You're right. Like this is a no brainer, right? We're not talking about it.
Um Keep going.
SAS. Does the project use a static code analysis tool?
I don't agree with this one at all because I think the vast majority of
SAT still sucks rocks.
And I think if you're an open source project, this is a huge burden to put on them.
Well, that also assumes there's a good SASS tool available
-- which
-- they kind of aren't. I mean, there's like code QL from
github, which is cool, but that is a lot of heavy lifting too.
What is, what is the one for ruby called? That's pretty decent,
man.
Yeah,
man. Like break man is good,
but I've run it and there's all. Yeah, it's, oh
man.
Anyway,
like
you're going to get a whole pile of
false positives and then what do you do?
Like teach to the test and fix those or do you just write a big list of exceptions?
So,
I like the,
I think the
SAT should be left in there if nothing else to encourage SAT to get.
That's fair. That's fair. I'll agree with that.
Um Let's keep going. Security policy. Does the project contain security policy?
No brainer. All right. Keep going.
Does the project cryptographically sign releases,
the signed releases?
I would have actually six months ago even, I would have said, you know,
it's nice to have, but not that important because
key management and everything for devs is such a chore and nightmare.
But now with things like SIG store. Let me put it this way.
It's like http s now that you have let some crypt,
there's no excuse not to.
Well, I mean, using
store is still a little hard but I think,
I think this is good to put on the list though so
people can think about it and get ready because I think,
I think at the moment
this is still really hard to do.
But I think once SIG store is, we'll say slightly more mature and more available.
This will be my suspicion is github
is just gonna incorporate this right into
github. And it's gonna be like, ok, we're done. Thanks.
They might have. I just don't know
who knows if they haven't. I'm sure it'll come.
Let's see. Token permissions. Does the project declare github
work full of tokens? It's read only.
I don't know how you test for this one. Can you see that? I don't know.
So I, I just looked here, it says uh the check cannot detect if read,
only permission setting is enabled as there is no API available.
So basically, it sounds like this is a,
you have to tell them you're doing it. Maybe
like, I mean, this is a no brainer anytime you are accessing an API
use the least privilege possible to access it. If read only works,
you don't want, right? Because if someone gets your token, you have a problem.
Well,
and also you want to be using tokens that are
sort of handled by some sort of management system.
So that, oh, I don't know
if there's like some sort of theoretical flaw in your, you know, build system. Say
that kind of exposes all your tokens
that you can maybe rotate them,
that happens all the time, right? Or my favorite show. So
you and I talked about this not too long ago
where you stood up a virtual machine for me.
And I was like, here are all of my SSH keys. And back in the day, I had like one SSH key I
share among
machines.
Now every machine gets its own key because you know what,
if one of my machines gets stolen or lost or compromised,
I just delete that line from my authorized keys and there we go.
I'm good, you know.
All right. All right, we got one more here. Vulnerabilities.
Does the project have unfixed vulnerabilities?
I mean,
this kind of goes back to the scanning service. I think using a dependency scan,
-- the whole clean CV E scan thing.
-- Here is
this one I think needs an enormous amount of education
and I don't want to dwell on it today.
But here is my explanation.
If you have a scan
with no results,
that is worse than a scan with 1000 results because
it either means you're doing something to trick the scanners,
right?
Like with. And the classic example is the Debian Openness cell oopsies
-- Yes.
-- Exactly. Exactly. That and, and so like
the the challenge now is we need the ability to interpret a scan
and say
the results of this scan
fall within. Imagine it's a sliding scale, right? We like nothing is bad.
Too many is bad and you have this sweet spot in the middle.
More to the point are these vulnerabilities
explained or somehow accounted for.
So like the web development team at the CS A, you know,
Ruby on rails and they quite commonly will have a CVE sitting in the code for
maybe one or two or three weeks because
fixing it and updating it just breaks everything.
-- Yeah, it depends what it is
-- exactly.
And they'll do a review of it and be like, OK, well, we're not
actually, you know, my favorite is Jackson Data bind and satellite six, right?
Satellite six use Jackson data bind and did not and probably
hopefully cross my fingers will never use the Jackson Data bind Java
-- XML, whatever deserializing routines,
-- polymorphic deser
and the number of discussions let's call them discussions
uh because they absolutely were not arguments
but the discussions I had with people about we're
not going to update this right away because like,
yes, that CV exists in the code,
but we don't use that code and provably we don't use that code.
Like if you search for that, not
there
and it got to the point where at
some points it was just OK.
No, we're actually going to fix this because man,
it's just going to be easier than arguing with people.
I agree.
And II, I get there sometimes, I mean, the challenge is,
these are critical vulnerabilities.
If you're using it,
no one is using it.
So,
and it's not just that we're not using it, it's not possible to use it,
sort of rewriting the product.
And I was like, and that's not like that's out of support.
-- Like, if you rewrite the product, then we can't support that.
-- Right. Exactly.
Exactly. And, and not only that, look
when you are in a Java environment,
it is often difficult to update certain jars because multiple things can depend
on them and you end up in these weird situations where like,
I would like the new version,
but this other thing over here is using the old
version and so I can't update it yet and it's,
and, and you could say, OK, well, let's just make this, this dependency,
use that jar and I'll use the new jar and now I have two copies.
So yay for me. And it's, it
is difficult to say the least. So anyway,
I think this one, we,
let's just plan on doing a show about this in the near future because
I think there's so much confusion on this topic and I it is the,
well, I wouldn't even say it's a future like it's here today.
-- It's just, it's not well
-- understood.
Here's the thing I like that it's included because we're exposing
the pain point and forcing people to do something about it.
Even if it is,
this is, this is broken and we're intentionally ignoring it,
but you're aware of it.
Now, the,
the one thing I want to end on because we're out of time and I think this is a cool list.
But now the challenge is going to be
using these tests,
understanding the data and completing the loop,
which I'm not,
I'm not connected enough to this project to understand how they're,
how they're measuring and and feeding that back into the process.
But if
that is how things get better, right?
And if if no one's feeding the data back into the other end of the machine,
this will eventually die because it will be on, it will not be useful, right?
Well, the other thing to realize too is the world has changed in that, for example,
github
could look at this list and go oh you know what
like, yeah, we can fix the the signatures thing, we can just support
six
and make a button in the interface
and
it's done.
And, and I think that's part of the magic of the modern world is
literally every single one of these tests.
There are companies that do this and make you know,
money doing this and also quite often provide kind of a free version or free
whatever for the open source world. Or, you know, some light version
and, and that's the future because I think
we come from a world where we would have had to build
all of this ourselves because it didn't exist a lot of it.
I built my own
servers back in the day.
Exactly.
And so I would say if you're looking at
this scorecard and you're interested in implementing it,
I mean, same thing for things like salsa or ci I
is,
don't do it yourself, find a way to automate it
and it's not your problem.
You know what I mean? That is the answer to all of this stuff.
And I think that is the mindset
that is making a lot of this truly successful is it's no longer NIH,
it's how do I solve this problem without creating more work for me?
And that's cool.
Well, and the reality is you're not going to do as good a job as they did.
-- No.
-- Absolutely. You're not an expert
-- like you're just not
-- right.
And I,
and I include in that statement like fortune
100 companies with massive piles of security people.
You have other work to do.
You're managing email and a SQL database. You're going to suck at one of them,
you know, or both. You're not going to be good at them both.
Anyway, I'm calling it. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you all for listening. Go to home
security podcast.com at Russia.
Not su
pound.
Oh, it says podcast hashtag Do hit us up on social media.
-- Kurt have a marvelous rest of your
-- day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye
that.