Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner clicking on random stuff.
Josh Pressers. It wasn't a click. You had to scan a QR code. So did you scan it? Yeah.
And then you have to tap on it. Did you scan it? I scan QR codes all the time.
But did you scan the QR code?
Which? Oh, you mean the one from the Super Bowl? I
don't watch TV. Does Canada get the Super Bowl? I don't know if you pay for it.
Oh, it's not like just broadcast. I don't know these things. It's,
I'm also not a football fan.
Well, neither am I but the commercials are funny.
All right. So let's explain
what just happened.
So what the latest championship of which owl is the most superb,
the world championship I might add of American football,
which is also the wrong thing.
Well, it is American football. You're right. Sorry,
you got it right. Sorry, I'm supposed to talk about the commercials.
I've never seen the damn thing. Whatever. No, the QR code. What was the QR code?
You're not.
No, you're cut off. I'm telling the story.
I
didn't
see
it.
I read
on
Twitter.
So, in the United States, for anyone who doesn't know
there is American football and the, like,
the championship for American football is called the Super Bowl and it's
held on a Sunday and a lot of people watch it.
I usually watch it because the commercials are funny.
I usually don't care about the game happening at all and I didn't this time either.
Uh, we eat a lot of terrible foods because it's fun.
And that's, that's pretty much it.
Well, and I forgot that we don't get the good commercials up here. Oh, really?
Oh, you have like knockoff Canada commercials basically. Yeah, people pay
for their commercials.
So we don't see commercials for like, Comcast and stuff, which we can't buy up here.
Thank God.
Anyway, we'll, we'll talk later. I, we can maybe make that work. But anyway, anyway,
the Super Bowl has all these commercials and
there is a commercial that's just a QR code bouncing around the screen, like,
you know, those DVD player screens where like the little DVD logo bounces around
that
because I was like, looking at the screenshot and I'm like,
what? Like I didn't under, ok.
Yeah. And it looked like that. Right?
And it's a QR code and the thing comes on and I just said, I bet that's a crypto
ad. And then my son says the QR code goes to Coinbase and I'm like, called it and then
security Twitter lost its mind.
And that's the story
like, because obviously scanning QR codes is dangerous and it could get you pump.
I mean,
no, it can't. Like here's the thing,
the whole premise of pretty much every
modern compute device that people interact with
is that you, like you click on links and look at stuff,
I mean.
Right. Like, especially in a web browser. That's kind of a thing I heard since.
Oh, I don't know, 9998 don't click on links in untrusted emails, right?
Good advice.
Or don't open emails from untrusted sources.
It's like, but until I open the email, I can't see
my job is reading emails from people. Oh, no. How do I do?
Ok. Ok.
Before we go all full on old man complaining mode here,
I want to start by saying
this was a brilliant ad
on behalf of Coinbase no matter what you think of crypto,
no matter what you think of Coinbase, didn't there site crash?
There's site crash because so many people visited the link
and we're all talking about it.
Like we're,
we're making a whole podcast about this one ad which
is good job marketing team like you did it.
Well, I hope you get a nice bonus.
It's one of those sort of if you do the minimalist
thing and you're the only person doing the minimalist thing.
It really stands out.
Like my favorite example of this is Apple stores and apple packaging.
Right. There's a really great youtube video of like taking an apple product in a box
and like, basically turning it into what, like Microsoft would put on that box.
Right. And it's just like tons of text and pictures and it's just,
it's, it's a horror show. It's like clip art threw up on the box
and, but that's the thing. Like, so,
uh, I think I've talked about this before. But locally at the West
Monton Mall, there is an Apple store and it's, it's an Apple store,
you know what it is.
And there's, there was past tense,
a Microsoft store and it was comical in that the
Microsoft store clearly tried to copy the Apple store,
but Barfed Microsoft all over it.
And so like the walls instead of being calm were
like video displays with crap on them all the time.
And I remember I literally walked in there once just to see what would happen and try.
And I'm like, hey,
I'm actually looking for a windows computer.
This is back when I was all max no Windows.
And
I want a Windows computer kind of like an IMAC format with a touchscreen, you know,
kind of an all in one touchscreen that my kids can easily use.
And I want multitouch
and he started looking at and telling me about the
different CP US and amounts of ra M they had,
I mean,
and like as a technical person I'm like, I don't, I don't care, they're all fast.
I don't care,
doesn't have multitouch
and he didn't know and he couldn't answer. And it's like,
you know, and it's just the whole experience was so hysterically Microsoft
and, and that's how I feel like, so this, this minimalist ad is brilliant because,
yeah, it's,
it's just a moment of calm with a QR Code.
It's not a moment of calm at all. Everyone lost their minds.
Now here is where I think it's really funny is there's a QR code.
A bunch of people on Infosec Twitter are complaining about don't,
don't scan random QR codes because your phone can get
POed and your dog will get kidnapped or whatever.
But here's the thing if you were paying
attention to the Super Bowl prior to that ad,
I bet there were no less than 20 QR codes that appeared in various other places,
other commercials
on the screen is just in the background of the game and kind of crap like that.
But this is the one everyone loses their mind over.
Here's the two things that boils down to for me. Number one,
it is safe to click a QR code.
If it's not safe to click,
click it, you got to scan it, man.
Come on, you scan it and click it whatever you're young and hip.
I'm not,
I I am hip and that they pop when I get off the couch. But um
so here's the thing if, if clicking a link or scanning a QR code or, or some
to put it bluntly, if some
interaction of your web browser and a web server is dangerous,
then your web browser is broken. I agree.
Like it has a zero day or it's so out of date, it's a problem, right?
Number one and number two,
if you go to a website
and you, it's like not your bank for sure or not something that, you know, for sure.
And you start plugging all your personal information
into it without kind of a second thought
then.
Well, yeah, kind of sucks to you. Like one story.
I just actually going through this,
uh Alberta Treasure branch is a bank I actually use
here in Alberta
and they have like,
apparently a sort of think tank venture cap kind of technology arm
and I got a piece of like,
spam because apparently I think from the show we're on some marketing list now.
Hey, like, are you getting this stuff too?
I get so much junk. It's not even funny.
Ok. Yeah, because I've been getting a ton of weird stuff, especially blocked
anyways. And it's an identity provider. Kind of like that one the IRS
using
with the face scanning. I forget what the name was. Something dot ID. Do me. Yeah.
And this one was some random four letter combination dot ID.
So Indonesia dot id though. Clever.
And I'm like, ok, cool.
And I replied to the press release saying, yeah, I'm kind of interested in this but,
but
I, I need basically proof that this is from Alberta Treasure Branch like that.
This is actually
because the person emailing me is from some random media company
and she doesn't know what I'm talking about. So it's,
I love that you have this website talking about
identity management and like giving us all your information.
And as best I can tell,
the only mention I could find that it's related at
all to Canada is that in their terms of use,
they say if you go to court with them that it will be in Calgary, Alberta, which is
where A TB is located out of.
Right? OK.
But there's no like contact us page.
There's,
they don't have an entry and done in Brad Street because it's not like a company.
It's like AAA
some sort of effort from a TB. That's not like a fully separate company yet.
And it's so it's supposed to be this identity
provider that can't prove to you who it is.
Yes. Exactly. Right. I find it very funny
and,
and
so like,
am I gonna give this site my info so I can have like
a self sovereign digital Blockchain based identity with the A TB blah,
blah, blah thing.
A
lot
of words. Exactly. It's word soup. But that's the thing is normal.
People would look at that and go oh yeah, it looks legit.
It says it's associated with a TB.
It probably is. Oh, it's absolutely legit.
I can't prove it.
I mean, but how much can you prove? Look? OK, simple.
They could have a page on the ETB website saying here is this thing,
this is not going in the direction I expected
this conversation to which I think is fine.
But I think, look, if you look at how
modern society function, even society for probably the last couple of 100 years
is there is an enormous amount of just implied trust
everywhere we look when a police officer pulls you over,
how does he prove he's a police officer,
you know, call 911.
Well, you can but no one does.
Well,
they do now locally a bit because there were some
people Impersonating police officers pulling women over on the freeway.
So like
that, I mean, that's an example where there was a solution but like that,
that's terrible, obviously.
But you know what I mean? There's so many things that happen. If we had to
go out of our way to verify trust with
every interaction we we have throughout our day,
we would accomplish nothing
well, even better. So I just saw this on the CBC marketplace.
You know what you have to do to register a lien on a property here in Canada.
And I bet it's comically simple.
You go to a website and you say that you want to register a lien on it and,
but you have a commercial interest on it and you fill out a little form and click.
Yes.
I'm not even a little surprised.
And for the person on the receiving end of that lien,
they are hooped
if it's,
you know what I mean?
Because, yeah, everybody's discovering that when you like rent a furnace or,
you know, have a security system installed that you pay for monthly,
they put a lien on your house to make sure you pay for it.
So you don't like sell the house and
the bill doesn't get paid, right? Which is fair. But
the people don't realize the lien is being registered
and also the amounts of the lien are like,
pretty crazy in some cases,
you know, like $20,000 on a $5000 water tank or whatever.
But anyway, you, you get my point right?
Like this is we, we're off in the weeds, but fundamentally,
there's just all this implied trust that has to exist and I think it's no different.
Well, because it usually doesn't get abused.
Well, it, it usually doesn't.
And I think like this Coinbase thing is another example of it didn't get abused.
There was nothing wrong with the QR code.
Well, the other thing, people forget QR Codes often have a context.
Like I sit down at a restaurant,
there's a QR code like taped to the table and they're like,
scan that to get the the menu,
like, and
they don't even have to tell me anymore because I'm,
I'm pretty sure if I see a QR code taped to a table in a restaurant,
it's probably the menu.
So we just need to start taping QR codes to tables at restaurants
that send you to the Rickroll web page.
And that already happened with the parking thing.
Remember where, uh, the, the, some place in the US has like QR codes where
you scan and go to, you know, pay or whatever
and somebody replaced those QR codes. And so people were
paying somebody else for parking, you
know.
Interesting. So,
and so like what they do here locally is they just have signs and the,
the sign has a number like you're in zone 2004 or 1968 or whatever inherently,
trusting a QR code in public.
Yeah, they're pretty easy to swap over cover with a sticker
and again, it kind of boils down to,
well, this is why, I mean, this is one of the biggest reasons TLS exists is
not to encrypt your connection,
but to have a certificate that says you're actually at walmart.com,
not walmart.com, but like Walmart with one l.com,
you don't check the certificate and no one really checks the
URL bar that closely and anyone can get a certificate now.
Well, for any website. But yeah, so,
so I wanna,
I wanna realist all the way back now because this conversation has gone
off into a weird place to a tweet you put on the internet.
I put on the internet. Don't? I sound like an old person today
that basically points out a bunch of just bad security advice that won't die.
And one of them is, don't scan QR codes. Why don't you tell us what the others are?
Let's see if you remember. Uh,
so the one was, I originally,
they said password length when I meant password complexity.
Close
enough. Well, no password length is great. Password complexity is stupid.
We know
what you mean? Clicking on links slash scanning QR codes.
And then the other one which I just,
I want to always eye gouge people is don't use public Wi
Fi.
That's right. That's right. And I agree. Yeah,
I live in Canada. Do you know what I pay for data? I don't, I know it.
I have to use public Wi Fi. It's, it's a lot like I, I have unlimited free data.
I could do whatever I want. I can buy unlimited data
except when you get to eight gigs, they cap you to like 256 K percent. It's
not unlimited data. No, it's unlimited
time use.
I,
I
swear this is the argument they made, especially also with the, um,
with all the cable modems and stuff was that it's, you're allowed to be on 24 7.
What,
what
do you mean?
It's unlimited, you can be on 24 7.
But that was their definition of unlimited, not unlimited.
When they said unlimited use, you can use it 24 7. Not unlimited data. Like, holy cow.
That's some grade a weasel right there
again.
Like, as a Canadian, I can probably say,
I hate all the internet and data related companies up here and
I'm pretty sure every Canadian is going to be like, uh huh.
Yeah, it's, it's hard to have worse cell service than the US.
But like, Canada pulled out all the stops on this one. So well done. Canada.
Ok. Anyway, anyway,
bad security advice. So you asked the question, why doesn't this stuff die?
And I've been thinking about this since you put that tweet up? Because
I think that's a valid question. There's,
and there's a ton of stuff.
It's not just these three, the thing I keep thinking of is there's kind of,
I think two aspects to this.
There is the security people who spout this nonsense.
And I think
some of it is they, they, they've let their skill set wane.
They haven't maybe kept up with the modern knowledge.
But then there's also the other side is the people, like,
we hammered this into their brains for so long
that I don't know if we can undo the damage at this point.
You know, the thing I was thinking about, it's like, why, why is that advice?
Bad and advice?
Like,
always look both ways when you cross the street
is good because that's a timeless piece of advice.
But I think part of it is
the downside of all
looking both ways. When you cross the road,
you don't have an opportunity cost, you don't lose something.
Whereas if you don't use public wi fi or you don't open emails from strangers,
you lose something, especially for example, if you're in sales, like,
if you're in sales and you don't open emails from strangers,
but you're not going to be in sales for very long.
Yeah, exactly. Right.
And
you know, like I remember, oh my God,
I did the stupidest thing once about a year ago is we
were getting a ton of spam and fishing via office files.
And so I floated the idea of, hey,
what happens if we block office files from being sent to us?
Whoa. Yeah, I walked that back real fast after marketing sales research and
everybody at the CS A yelled at me
like
I apologize like I straight up was like,
I am so sorry, like
uh
I don't usually make mistakes this bad but like
yeah,
I'm sorry, please don't set me on fire.
So here's where I think we should kind of, let's take your three things. Right.
Don't scan QR codes. Has that ever actually been a threat? I don't think so.
I think that's movie plot in super limited situations with people who
really aren't paying attention to what they're then ending up on.
But I mean, these are the kind of people where
you could probably just
tell them to do it or whatever, you know,
and they're just gonna do it because they're not paying attention or something.
Like it's, it's enough of a corner case that I'm not going to worry about it.
I, I agree the same thing with public wi fi like, can you get
a, no,
no, no, no, no. That one will get to that one's,
that one's a little special
now. Password complexity.
Nist gave out this advice.
They've said they were wrong
but I think
the damage was done. Not just said they were wrong but they like
amended the standard, like straight up, they rewrote 80, what is it?
800-63 or something? I
don't remember which one. It is 53 maybe. I don't know. It has a three in it
that narrows it down.
Good job anyways. It starts with 800 probably.
And actually that I would say even that advice is
wrong in the sense of the correct advice is
use a password manager and machine generated passwords.
But those didn't exist, but
they do now back then they do now. And I agree. I think, I think that the lesson here
is that
any security advice,
any security best practices need to be revisited on a constant basis because
whatever was true
at some point in time probably won't be true
later just because that's the nature of progress.
Yeah, perfect examples.
The White House actually came out and said if you're going to do multi,
well, they said that you have to do multi factor authentication
and it cannot be S MS anymore
because
yeah, like S MS fishing and blah, blah, blah.
It's or man in the middle, blah, da, da, da, da.
Yeah, it s MS is dead.
Gotta go.
Yeah.
Yeah, I mean, it's still better than nothing, obviously, but not much.
Well, but here's the beauty in some cases,
it's actually worse because by popping your phone number and then most of
these sites have used your phone number for recovery and you get the code
and so you just,
the Attackers are doing like industrial fishing here.
They don't care what ends up in the net just that they get something.
And so in a way S MS actually makes that a lot easier for them to accomplish.
So it actually makes things worse in some ways. All right. Anyway. Anyway.
But, yeah, so onto. Ok.
So the public wi Fi thing now,
I think public wi fi is special because do you remember back in the day
when
there were actual tools that would like spy on public wi Fi?
I was going to say the defcon or was it the wall of sheep?
Right.
And what was, wasn't there another tool called it?
Was it fire Sheep that was designed to spy on web, web requests of public wi Fi.
Yeah, I did like art shenanigans and no Ds intersection or something.
I don't remember anymore. But you get the idea is this was a legitimate concern.
My favorite was, oh, I don't even, I was, I was at a little
local hacker con. This is like a decade ago probably.
And someone basically just set up a sniffer on the public wi Fi
looking at URL S and anytime there is a URL with an image,
it would put the image up on the big screen.
And of course,
it's always funny because someone ends up looking up at porn or something. But
you know, it, it was,
it was hilarious because people are like doing
stuff and it's appearing and they're like,
oh, but the picture of my house is up there.
It's like, yeah, that
yes,
yeah, I mean, this is a perfect example
like on my list of essentially um I have a list of
criteria for evaluating cloud providers for the cloud security lines to use.
And one of them because the list is very, very old is do they do HTTP S
not like, do they do it all the time? But do they even support it at all?
And then that morphed into
do they require HTTP S for the login?
Because remember for the longest time banks would have like an HTP
Yeah, login page that then went to an HTPS site
and it was like, well, no, that doesn't work because
you can just rewrite the HTP to go wherever, right?
And then
it morphed into OK. Everybody, most everybody is doing htps. Are they doing hsts?
That is required like saying that you have to use HTTP S to get to me.
And if you can't, don't come here, right?
With the gold standard being is do they go into the HSTS preload
list which is an actual like file with URL S like for example,
cried.org is in there and it's in about almost the
top 100 because I was in there pretty early.
You talk about it a lot. And so yeah,
and
you know paypal does it a bunch of banks, do it, yay.
But like, yeah, back in the day, 10 years ago,
do they even do HTTP S at all? Was
like maybe, but nowadays,
it's all 10 years ago, you could make the plausible argument
that using public Wi Fi is dangerous.
Now, I would say that 99.9% of the time you're using public Wi Fi,
it's probably fine unless you're at a hacker conference or something.
But if you're just at Starbucks and you're checking your email,
you're probably going to be ok.
So obviously advice was handed out saying be careful when you do this, you know VPN.
Sure, whatever,
but now
VPN providers sure as heck aren't shady and monitoring traffic.
We know that now, I mean,
that was always the suspicion
they didn't exist back then. It was a lot of corporate VPN back then. And now
we've reached a point where people are still saying don't use public wi Fi.
But the reality is
there's not a lot happening on the internet that isn't encrypted these days.
And so public wi fi
really,
someone looking over your shoulder is probably a far bigger
threat than the public wi Fi at the coffee shop.
Yeah,
I think the other problem is sort of orthogonal to this is that
a lot of this advice was meant for people who are like,
worried about a targeted attack.
So if you're worried about a targeted attack, there is some stuff you should do.
Like, yeah, like not use public Wi Fi or other things, right? Because just, even
just kind of the traffic analysis might be enough for your adversary to
learn stuff about you that you don't want them to know about you.
But that's not a problem for us.
And by us, I mean, everybody on the planet who's not a journalist,
I will find the document that's Massad versus not mossad for
kind of threat situations. And that's what we're right.
Like the, the, the, the best example is the, if, if you're dealing with
a situation where you're a target of like an international group,
the security group,
like the,
the joke in it was that Massad changes out your cell
phone for a brick of uranium gives you brain cancer,
you die and then they buy you a state like
that's basically what would happen.
They, they can wait, you know, they, they, you know,
they buy the NSO product with the, uh,
with the zero days and send you a text that pops your phone open.
Right. And, and so,
and I think that's the, you know what, I think that's what a lot of
it is, is I think a lot of security people,
we love thinking about the targeted attacks. The
movie
plot,
we love thinking about the movie plots.
We want to believe that we're special and we're going to be attacked.
And so we need to tell all our friends that they also
need to act in a special way when the reality is like,
I used to be really, we'll say bizarre about a lot of my security practices.
And then one day I'm like, honestly
none of this matters,
but the way I protected my SSH key was
I could tell like a half hour story of all the steps I took,
but I guarantee I had better protection on my SSH
key than most corporations had on their signing keys.
Like for real, it was completely bananas. What I did.
I remember like running workloads in Amazon EC2,
but not trusting them to enough to use the elastic load balancer with
their SSL certs. And then I realized like, hang on,
that's no,
let's just use the LB it's easier,
you know,
like
uh yeah,
I think that's,
I think that movie plot aspect is part of it because yeah, we want infosec to kind of,
we want to sex it up because the majority of infosec is
literally inventory all your systems and patch them up to date.
Once you've done that, then we can discuss maybe buying a firewall.
Although in the modern world, probably not
like literally the only reason we have a firewall at
CS A is because to run a wireless network,
you have to
stick on that box in front of it. Well, they're all firewalls and
ubiquity makes a really nice what is called the Security Dream or something.
And like,
it's just an all in one box and it was cheap and reliable. So we went with that.
But otherwise,
like the only reason I have a firewall here is
because that's what my wi fi does by default.
Like, no, because I actually have I PV six controlling.
They have like, like these are live I PV six. Like they are internet
attach. Like my, my ISP actually hands me a proper,
what's it like a slash 56 or 64? I
can't even keep track of I PV six. So like,
yeah, like literally if you have an inventory,
like if you can't conclusively tell me what all you have
for systems and hardware and that they're up to date.
Yeah. Come back when you have and then we can talk about security.
I mean, I think that's an overly simplistic view
but
I, I think
what you're on to is that
there are things we can do
that have real and direct consequences for our business or lives or whatever.
And then there's the crap that doesn't matter and
obsessing over QR codes being worried about password complexity,
telling your employees not to use public wi fi
none of that matters. If you stop doing that tomorrow,
nothing would change.
And, and I think that now of course, getting this advice to die
is one of the next challenges.
And I, I don't,
I don't know what's funny to me is that this advice has already largely died
for everybody under the age of 30 just by virtue
of the fact that they have a cell phone.
And that's kind of one of their primary platforms,
I guess.
I mean, maybe that that could be
on a cell phone. You can, you, it just stuff kind of just works.
And for example, like it's really, it's actually difficult to see
um here. Yeah, like,
oh, interesting. Yeah.
So like if I go to CBC dot C A,
it's actually http S like I have to click on the thing and kind of like wait
for the URL to come up and I have to scroll around a bit to see it.
But
that's the thing.
Like on the modern internet with a modern device, it's all http S it's all encrypted.
It's all like,
we're getting to the point where DNS over HTTP is, is,
is a thing and it's becoming more widespread.
So even the whole argument of like all the,
the Attackers can see your DNS traffic and know that you, like,
like to go buy bananas from banana.com or whatever.
Like, nope, that's going away.
I, I think what drives me nuts is,
it's not just the focus that we lose by telling
people these silly things that sort of the operational cost.
Like, again, like that whole, like,
don't open emails from untrusted people. Well, but
a big part of my job is talking to strangers. We're hiring my replacement again.
Third time's a charm.
And, um, although this time we're smart, we're hiring a manager and a team
to replace my operations.
So, yeah, that we finally figured it out. What can I say? I'm really good at it.
I'm old school.
But the thing is like, I have to open up a bunch of resumes and like about
15% of them are doc files. I'm like, whatever. I, I,
you're kind of already sorted to the bottom of the
pile mentally for me if you can't make a PDF.
But whatever, I'll give you a fair chance
and like,
you know, I,
I chucked them through virus total just to be on the
super safe side because I'm opening them up on my desktop.
Like I'm not getting a burner system to read resumes.
You know,
and I truck these files through virus total and then I open them and I'm sure there's,
people are like, oh my God, Kurt opened a doc file.
I can, like,
target and attack them. Well, yeah.
And if you can get your vi, like,
if you can get your hostile payload through an up to date
windows 11 system and I'm chucking this stuff through virus total.
Cool. Go sell that exploit to Mossad,
right?
Like
you're gonna make a lot more money than popping me. That's right.
You know, and that's my strategy with like, the cloud security stuff is like, yeah,
we're in Google if you can pop us in Google,
but you're gonna go take over that bank next door to us. I mean, you'd help.
But it, it's fair anyway. Anyway. So, and I think that's part of it is just
like, yeah, I, I, maybe,
maybe a lot of this is just infosec kind of has to get over itself and
get rid of the movie plot thinking.
Uh, there's some of that, I think some of it as well is there was a very historic,
I guess a view of hackers as the superheroes, which, I mean,
I think there's a lot of amazing things they do.
But the reality is, I mean, when you're in infosec,
I would say it should be a lot more similar to accounting than to like fighter pilot,
you know. What I mean?
I mean, I, I like my favorite example is, is the cake, what is it?
The, the CIA Q document from the CS C
Assessment initiative questionnaire?
Oh Caiq, I always get those screwed up anyway.
Like basically it's just what like 300 controls you go through and answer it
and then instead of having to fill out a new questionnaire for everyone,
you just be like
a little cake. Take this
and 99% of the time people are like, oh, thank goodness a cake,
I'll just take this from you so you can compare them. I know they're amazing.
But the point is like,
that's really boring though. You know what I mean?
Like filling it out isn't exciting.
Reviewing, it isn't exciting comparing them isn't exciting, but
it's an example of where you can do some work,
reuse the work and it's not just like pointless questionnaires
you're filling out and passing around for no apparent reason.
I, I actually, I, I gave that talk today and
that was one of the points I made especially I
can't say I gave that talk today because literally no one knows what today is
that
anyway, it doesn't matter because the point is one of the points I made
link in the show notes. Kurt just gave a talk
anyways. One of the uh the points was that
the security needs to,
the security needs to be automated and these emails being sent out like,
what are you doing about log for J are you blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
And it was all like,
it wasn't even a, there wasn't even a spreadsheet.
It was just an email with a bunch of text and you're supposed to reply with,
I guess free form text
to. It was like security compliance at the vendor name.com.
And you know, I make the point that this is all human generated human process.
Like, it's just garbage
and it was three days late. It was a lock for Jane.
They sent this email to us on a Monday and I was like,
we've had 72 hours of log for Jay. Like, if you haven't fixed it too
late. Yeah,
you're done.
And
that kind of stuff needs to go
away because, like, it,
it doesn't work, it's too late. It's not effective. It's inefficient
like
that effort that they put into that they should have put into like, oh,
we need to do some automation.
Like,
maybe we need to get cakes from all our vendors.
I mean, yeah, that's a good start.
You know, and again, it's a, it's a sign of maturity as well.
If you filled it out, you kind of have a clue.
You know, this is like, anyway,
major quote, un, quote, serious security vendor.
Like you, you use them every day kind of thing. I'm not surprised at all.
I, I, I've seen many things, I've seen it all more than once. Right.
We should, we, we need to wrap this one up.
I guess my parting thought on this whole thing is that
there is an enormous amount of security best practices.
I'm doing air quotes right now, but no one can see.
And
that's the beauty of radio.
There's best practices and I think it is important.
We review them on a regular basis, but I know we almost never do.
And there is an enormous amount of advice we hand out.
There's an enormous amount of steps we take today
that probably don't really matter.
And
it's hard to find out some, it's, it's hard to realize what those are sometimes.
But, you know, after the fact it seems easy. But
anyway, I, I think that's the thing. It's just,
like, constantly pay attention to what you're doing, constantly ask, like,
what is this actually accomplishing?
Yeah, there's a good story of, you know, for example, when you leave the harbor,
you turn the ship 360 degrees around in a
circle before you leave the harbor for good luck.
And somebody points out that maybe it's, you know, it's a way of testing the rudder.
So if the rudder is gonna break it snaps off and you, you break in harbor, not
out in the middle of nowhere, right?
I don't know.
And so, well, anyway, the point is, like you said, I think that's,
it's not just reassessing are these security practices working.
But
what are these security practices meant to do because
there's a whole bunch of security practices that I don't do anymore
because I'm, I'm cloud based.
Like, there's just a whole bunch of physical security stuff that
doesn't apply to me.
Like, I, it's,
you know,
I
hear you. And so I think maybe, like you said, it's, it's that step of,
look at what you're actually trying to accomplish and, and make sure that, that
like
makes sense
before then you look at how you're doing it because
like a lot of people spend a lot of time. Let's chop down trees more efficiently.
But it's like, are we in the right forest?
Nobody knows
it.
Kurt,
thank
you all for listening to open
source security, podcast.com. Head up the show,
Suzy Pound
says podcast. Hashtag do hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.