Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Gunk
-- experiment. Josh Pressers.
-- What does that even mean
-- thought
-- experiment?
It's from Einstein where he came up with
the theory of relativity through thought experiments because
he didn't have the budget to build like
the large Hadron
-- Collider
-- to build a spaceship that can travel at the speed of light.
Yeah, exactly. Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. Yeah.
To, to put a bunch of clocks in orbit and like, oh they're off by a few milliseconds.
So,
no, I, I, we're going to do it because you wanted to talk about the,
the security vulnerabilities in g lipsy and curl.
And I wanted to maybe try a bit of a new approach. So a thought experiment,
-- I'm so partially terrified and partially interested in what's going to happen.
-- OK.
So
we have a security flaw in
Gipsy.
That's uh uh my understanding is it's,
it's local to full exploit like it's you get relaxes
and then the thing in curl is a heap overflow under um
let's say a more specific set of circumstances.
You got to be using the Sox five proxy and some DNS shenanigans and
not impossible. And actually a lot of people,
like, I've even used the Sox five
set up when I was traveling because the hotel
Wi Fi was wonky and wouldn't let me out and
did some tunneling and blah, blah, blah. So
it's not
zero, it's more than zero, but it's not obviously everybody.
Right.
Right. Basically.
Uh So this thought experiment works, we're going to do it with curl in mind,
but it literally is the same words, just replace curl with g lipsy and replace
like web requests with like running software.
And basically, it's the same thought experiment. OK. So number one,
we got these like super bad vulnerabilities in this commonly used
software that like you basically have to use by default.
Sure, like you can't not use GPS
C realistically unless you go to something very specific like say alpine Linux,
right, which I think they use something different than
Glips. I want to say, yeah, they use
Mucil,
that's the one, the cereal, one, breakfast,
breakfast cereal. That's how I remember it.
Right.
Anyway, you don't even want to know where you're filed in my brain
next to sauerkraut.
Probably best not to know.
-- I mean,
-- actually, you know, you're next to processed cheese because
I love processed cheese.
So,
so OK, so number one
simple solution,
stop making web requests. I mean, this works for Gopher.
-- It's how we solved all the security problems in
-- Gopher.
No, that's not realistic. Right.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Ok. So we,
-- to eliminate that, just
-- don't use electricity. Right.
-- Like, oh, problem solved.
-- Yeah, exactly. So we can eliminate that one real quick.
Ok. Cool.
Number two,
stop using curl. Use a different better library.
There's no different, better libraries.
There are different libraries but not better
and certainly not compatible
without a ton of work and certainly not gonna handle.
Like, my favorite thing is everybody's like, oh,
I could write a web client in a weekend and then they do and then they're like,
everybody's like, what about this super common corner case?
And they're like, oh, what about this one?
You know what I mean? And it just,
and then you end up reim implementing Curl, but it takes you like two decades.
It amuses me that you said that because in Daniel's blog post
that da da da da,
we're gonna get there, we're gonna get there.
So,
but this is part of the thought experiment where
we're going through some obvious cases and like,
we can't do that.
Like, it's just not a realistic solution.
Right. Right.
OK.
Next one, this is where we were headed.
All right. Let's take Curl and rewrite it,
you know, memory safe language
and you and I are not even gonna answer this question because Daniel already did
rewrite it. Question mark. Yes.
This family of flaws would have been impossible if Curl had been written in a memory
safe language instead of c but hoarding curl
into another language is not on the agenda.
I like how it just,
it's like, no, that's not on the menu.
This amused me because when I saw it all I wanted to
do was reply to him on Mastodon with what do you mean?
-- You can't rewrite curl in a weekend in rust
-- pretty much.
Um, actually no, the correct way to do it would have cha
GP t do it. But anyways,
it would probably just steal Carl SARS
code and feed it to you.
Yeah.
So I am sure the news about this vulnerability will trigger a new
flood of questions about and calls for that and I can sigh,
roll my eyes and try to answer this again.
The only approach in the direction I consider viable and sensible is
to allow and uh use and support more dependencies written in memory,
safe languages and potentially and gradually replace parts of
curl piecemeal like with the introduction of Hyper.
So basically like what the Linux kernel is doing
where you just sort of maybe the public facing
or more internal nasty sensitive bits, kind of get a bit of a tidying up.
Well, and that's what the whole, I mean, we talked to Josh Oates
and that's what the prosal
project is basically trying to do is just slowly move these tools into Rust.
And like, remember when Mozilla
rewrote their web browser and almost died because
as it turns out rewriting a major piece of software.
-- It's gonna take you a few years
-- who knew who could have possibly predicted that?
Weirdly, people are still going to expect you to support the old one.
So it's not like you get to just stop
doing curl, rewrite something clean and ship it right. Like,
because I'm, I'm sure he has a lot of spare time.
-- So,
-- you know what this reminds me of is when we were at Red Hat, I'll never forget
the security team. I always joked, we don't celebrate
like product releases. We celebrate product end of life.
Finally don't have to support this thing anymore,
-- man. When we finally killed off Sam,
-- which one was Sam? Even?
I remember that
-- account
-- manager, I want to
say
-- that. I think that's right. It
-- was like sat
light but
terrible
like
it obviously filled a need at a time. But
regardless anyways. So going back to this.
So such development is however,
currently happening in a near glacial speed and shows with painful clarity,
the challenges involved.
That's the other thing, right? Is people seem to think, oh, take curl.
It's a known hunk of
software, reasonably high quality and we'll just rewrite it and rust,
what could go wrong?
And
the answer is
a lot that we don't know because part of this is
like,
we don't have a lot of people and a lot
of knowledge about rewriting big chunks of Seaco and Rust.
And that's
what that all means. So a part of this is exploratory
to the point of even being like, is this possible?
Like this isn't Hearts of Iron Four where you just pour money
into your research budget and like out pops up a jet plane,
that's not a guaranteed outcome.
Here's what happens every time someone says, oh, we're going to just rewrite
whatever any feature
you will introduce
new bugs and probably all of your old bugs as well, depending upon how you rewrite it.
Because there's different ways to rewrite software.
And if you're basically trying to do like a uh like function for function,
photocopy from one language to another, you're probably going to reim implement
-- those bugs that already exist.
-- And you also just made a massive classical mistake,
which is that you assumed, you know what the software does.
Yeah.
So the software, like a lot of software does stuff, but we're not
like TCP is always my favorite where the software does TCP
and then we encounter some problem and everybody's like, well,
what does the RFC say?
And the RRC says like,
nothing or it's ambiguous or it's not really
well defined.
And it's kind of like, well, you know,
these people did it this way and these people did
it this way and it's kind of sort of compatible.
-- So we kind of really never noticed that.
-- Oops.
So I have a fun story about that actually.
So I have, I, I put it on math and I'll put a link in the show notes, but
I have been working on like a very cheap,
like conference badge project for a couple of groups that
will say have an interest in having such a thing
in my intent. I had two, well, three goals in mind. Really?
When I did it, first of all, I wanted it to be $5 or less. Right.
Second goal was it had to run for more than eight hours on AC R 2032 battery.
And the third goal was that I want like normal people to be able to like,
put it together and hack on it and do stuff.
They're soldering, but it's all true. Whole soldering.
It's no surface mount, right? Because surface mount soldering is
if you've never tried it before, you are not doing it. Right. Exactly.
And so anyway,
it runs this processor called an a tiny 85.
It's like the, the, the world we live in now is like, blows my mind.
This is a, a, this is a supercomputer,
$1 microprocessor that can run at 16 megahertz.
I only run it at eight because the power use is cut in half at eight.
But
the
megahertz
it has
what? Eight pins on the thing. I can use five of the pins for data and stuff.
And so I, I built this bad, I just got an eight by eight led matrix display.
It scrolls and stuff and it's very fun, right? But here's the thing,
there is a ton of it is what are the undefined,
just like stuff in C++ you don't realize
that I've never hit before. Like one example is, did you know
a Y loop that never completes is considered undefined behavior in C++
-- OK.
-- I'm gonna,
here's my answer to this is this is why I basically only write code and bash and
Python.
But here's my
point,
here's my point
is I'm writing software, right to make this thing work.
And at one point, I'm like,
I just need it to basically loop through this thing and like print
dots on the screen so I can figure out what's going on.
I, I turn on a Y loop
and literally nothing works. I'm like, what the heck is going on.
And so I'm like, I'm reading documentation and trying to understand, I'm like,
holy crap.
Like a wire loop that never returns is undefined in C++
so the compiler,
I don't even know what it did because nothing
-- you
-- fix the halting problem,
right?
But it's, it's one of those things, right? Like there's,
I have learned about so much undefined behavior working
on this project that you never really think about.
But all of a sudden, I'm in this like super resource constrained environment
and the compiler is doing like horrible, horrible things to make the code fit.
I'm like, oh my goodness, this is bananas.
That's one of the fascinating things I find is when 40 or 50 years ago,
resource constrained environments were the default.
That's it.
That's
right.
And so
you and I have some idea of what
working in a resource constrained environment works uh means
sort of at a fundamental level.
And watching people rediscover this, for example,
with smart contracts in Blockchain where
oh you want to write some software? Cool, except it is
very expensive to run this code.
So you literally have to pay gas to run the code and to see them just
run into a brick wall because they're used
to like building an electron app that's like
displays a flashing button,
eight gigs of ra M
people aren't used to this anymore and they run into it like a brick wall
and there's so much
institutional knowledge here that's never been properly written down or
documented
or if it is, people are like, oh, that's like
old timey, you know, getting tuberculosis. We have hospitals now. Who cares? Well,
that works until you encounter some new technology where
like A I with your A K token limit
and to watch these people like reinventing sharding.
And I'm like, oh like splitting your data up into chunks and process. And it's,
but it goes to this thing.
It's the same thing as the rewriting curl
where unless you've actually even sort of attempted it
at some point like refactoring your own code,
just refactor your own code. A function
no, seriously. And that will, and a lot of people will come back and we can be like,
with, you know, the 1000 Yard Stern, just like I had no idea.
-- It's
-- my, what did, what did, what is a quote? There's a funny quote.
I read one time that was like,
I'm only, I,
I wrote this code a year ago and pass me was an idiot or something like that.
And like, I totally get that. There's so much code I've looked at I wrote
in the past and I'm like,
I can't even explain why. I thought this was a good idea.
There's no excuse,
I forgot to comment it.
-- So I'm like staring at it and I'm like, no, it's self commenting.
-- It's fine.
It cleverly does something and it produces the correct output. I have like why?
And then I'll eventually maybe re invent the wheel and understand what I did.
-- Yeah. Anyway. All right, back to your thought experiment
-- to continue on
and then he's actually got some data
every oh yeah, everyone not happy about this is of course,
welcome to roll up their sleeves and get working
like
fair. Including the latest two CV ES reported for Curl 8.4 0.0.
The accumulated total says that 41% of the security vulnerabilities
ever found in Curl would likely not have happened.
Uh Should we have used a memory safe language?
But also the Ross language was not even
a possibility for practical use for this purpose
during the time in which we introduced maybe the 1st 80% of sea related problems.
For sure. For sure. Right.
This is like, let's replace all the cars with self driving electric vehicles. I wish
like,
yeah, it
sort of will kind of happen eventually in 10 or 20 years, but certainly not tomorrow.
-- No, that for sure for sure.
-- So, I think we've established
just with our discussion and backed up by
Daniel rewriting curl in a memory safe language.
Even piecemeal is not gonna happen anytime soon.
-- No,
-- not without an enormous effort funded by someone
resourcing. Yeah.
Right.
Unless someone is willing to spend like literally
tens of millions of dollars on this project,
it's probably going to take more than 20 years at the current pace that I'm aware of.
Well, especially with how fast the web is
like quick, http two, the whole, like the whole http two reflection ddos
attacks, things that came out last week.
Right. And all the a lot of the web servers are like whoopsy doodle.
Yeah, because people forget you can't.
It's not just refactoring the code,
it's not some static accounting toilet system that sits in isolation and doesn't,
you know,
-- curl literally talks to everything on the planet
-- and off the planet like
Yeah. Yeah.
So OK,
so
then the question becomes, what can we do now,
we can obviously continue to play whack a
mole with security vulnerabilities that works 100%.
Which is what we'll do. That's exactly what's going to happen.
Yeah. And, and it's affordable and it's honestly, it's kind of what we got.
It's working. All right. I mean, look, let's face it.
-- It's all in all society functions.
-- Yep.
But here's the question. Are there any new things we could do?
And I would pause it but there is,
there is a new capability
in the form of A I in the last
year coming available
and I would pause it.
This is something that curl can do and a lot
of software projects can and I think should do which is
using A I
to
explain the code and maybe have people walk through the code and
maybe something like this heap overflow will kind of pop out.
Maybe not. I don't know.
Uh number two,
maybe using A I to help write test cases and
number three using A I to help write fuzzing cases.
So having the A I for example, process and go through all the um options,
the command like fuzzing all the command line options for example,
but maybe a bit more intelligently with A I.
So instead of just feeding at random garbage, it's like
you could have like a test suite of Wonky DNS names
like long, too many dots, not enough dots
like every time now, Google links to their blog and it's like blog dot Google.
My brain is like uh huh blog dot google dot what and no dot Google is a TLD. Now,
your, it, your, your suggestion is as ridiculous as writing curl on a weekend
also because who's going to do the work, Kurt,
who's gonna do it?
Interesting is gonna do it?
Well, see, here's an interesting aspect I think of using A I is that
a
person who is not overly familiar with the curl code base
can do this. Now, I don't know that they're going to get a useful result,
but there is at least the possibility of them dipping
their toes in the water and participating to some degree.
-- Here's
-- what's going to happen and this is why
maybe someday, but I think the reality is today. It's ridiculous.
So first of all, doing what you just described would be pretty expensive.
So someone's got to pay for it. It's not free.
Let's say someone donates A I time to do this right
now. You're gonna have brand new people
going through code and either adding ridiculous comments that are wrong
or filing bugs that are wrong and incorrect.
And what's going to happen is the
curl maintainers who are already overworked and probably
just in general grumpy at poorly worded commits are going to say f this.
If you bring any A I crap to this project ever again, I ban you forever.
That's what's going to happen
in my world. They're explicitly not touching the curl code base.
They're explicitly touching test cases and
fuzzing and staying away from touching,
but they have to commit them eventually, right?
Where do you know
the test cases in the fuzzing in a
separate repo?
But then no,
this is a ridiculous story because if you have
test cases and fuzzing in a separate repo,
how do they get applied to the primary curl repo? I assume they're going to generate.
-- But
-- you don't
-- have
-- to,
how do,
how do security researchers research software?
-- They do no
-- security researchers,
research software and then they have to take
their research and do something with it.
Be it file bugs
-- or write a paper or something or
-- file a bug bounty.
But,
but that's the problem
is if enough people do this with A I and I think it is no surprise that at the moment,
the quality of what would come out of this project would not be particularly high,
which would put all of the burden on the crow maintainers to deal with
the heap of garbage that's going to end up being the result of this.
Right? And
-- so how do we get better at this unless we start doing it?
-- Not with Carl.
Look, you can say we have to do better.
And I agree and I think people who would want to work on something like this and,
and experiment with it and learn
100%.
But what, what you just said
is probably
years in the future at this. Point of being practically applicable.
-- So, but we can't, that's not helpful to curl today actually.
-- No, there's,
there's already been some results with people using
A I to fuzz stuff and find things.
That's, that's a done deal that's happened months ago.
Whatever fuzzing is well understood though. And, but you still,
you're not going to give a fuzz or an A I fuzz to a Noob.
-- It's a go fuzz curl because,
-- well, we did that with a FL
American fuzzy
-- loop
-- but
you're not. No,
they weren't noobs though. Kurt like
when uh look if you're an open source project or a company
and someone,
and I remember this happening where someone would show up and be
like I ran this fuzz here are 36,000 files that crash it.
And we're like,
and,
and they'd say, well, we didn't do any more work. You figure it out.
-- We're like, no, I'm not doing this, but
-- here's
-- the
-- problem.
We need to start doing something new, right?
This whole, for example, how many people are still banging on about,
we need to train developers, people are still banging on about,
we need to train developers to write code securely and it's like, no that will never,
it was like saying we need to train people
to drive cars better to reduce the collision that
work.
-- Like no, this is peak humanity as far as driving and writing code goes.
-- Look, I think
A I isn't the answer either.
The answer is to have tool sets that don't
let you stab yourself in the leg repeatedly.
But that ignores the fact that
like we have the existing technical debt of
all the C code and 100%.
-- And
-- this is a
problem. But A I, Kurt, like you have to get off the A I will solve everything,
it
will solve everything. But I'm saying it's a new capability.
No, I'm saying it's a new capability
and I'm already seeing good security results with it.
I for example,
have been using it to do threat modeling and it's come
-- up with actually correct results
-- and it's probably good at that.
It's probably not good at writing curled test cases by suspicion.
There's
some
out there
maybe, maybe someday look, I think this is exactly one of the instants
of extraordinary claims require extraordinary
and so not right now,
but you send me the extraordinary evidence because I would love to see it
and I want it specific to curl, not some like random paper,
you find an archive that talks about how A I could maybe do this thing
in the lab that we made it do with interns or grad students or whatever.
But anyway. All right. All right.
So is that your thought experiment or is there more to it?
OK. Perfect example. Can we educate the curl developers trade code more securely?
-- Um Not really, I mean,
-- look, here's, here's my comment on all of this,
I think the way Curl works
is acceptable.
All things considered, you can argue like we should have better development,
we should have safer tools, we should have whatever.
But the reality is we have what we have and Curl does a pretty good job, like full stop.
The way I'm approaching this is I'm looking at this and it's,
it's sort of similar to when I tried to push mod security
for web server stuff at Red Hat uh for the products.
With the idea being, for example,
a cross site scripting vulnerability pops up in satellite version six.
And it's instead of having to fix satellite version six,
we just deploy a mod security role
and deploy that to customers and it blocks it. Boom done.
I've done that.
Like for example, the, the, the CS A has a really old PHP app running. It's
like just a data visualization thing. There's no like
user data even log in or anything.
And it's got a reflective cross site security vulnerability
in it because it's a really old PHP framework.
And so I just,
yeah,
so I just wrote a cloud flare rule that blocks
every request that has a ankle brackets in it.
-- There
-- you
go.
-- I mean, that probably catches most
-- of
them
and it doesn't break the app and it basically fixes
like 99% of my security related X SS S reflection,
whatever attacks
done
because I can't fix the underlying act because it's so old.
See, but what you've just described that's a mitigating control.
And that's what I'm saying is we need to start maybe thinking of using
A I as a mitigating control as helping us write Fuzzs and test cases.
And if you just Google it,
there's a whole bunch of examples here where people have successfully used chat
PT
to
do better.
No,
no, you don't get to get away with that easily.
I'm gonna, I'm gonna put your feet to the fire here.
A I is not the mitigating control.
You can use A I to help you create mitigating controls. I would accept that.
And that's what I'm saying.
We have a new capability, let's use it instead of saying for 50 years, hey, let's,
but people have to show how it works.
You can't just say A I will fix it and then run away
like that's not how this works.
Someone needs to do the work to show this is how we do this.
So I've, for example, I've literally used
chai PT
to like explain this code to me,
-- explain where there might be security flaws and it
-- has
it absolutely can do that for simple code base.
I want you to do that with curl, do it with curl and then I will be impressed
as cart
starts typing.
No, it's and obviously it's not gonna work perfectly now.
But I want,
I've spoken with people at Microsoft and they're doing stuff internally where
they have the A I with the other thing you're gonna remember is
we have the A I with guardrails where you can't ask it to hack for sure.
And there is like,
there's a form where you can essentially ask Microsoft to give you access to the pest
A I.
Here's my comment on all of this and this is we're going to
end this conversation now because I'm not turning this into A A I podcast
A I has potential to help with many problems.
But today there's too many A I fan boys running around screaming
A I hitting you in the face and then running away.
-- And that's not helpful.
-- Do you not remember the web in 95 to 2000?
I do
and remember how hard it was to convince certain people that it was a really good idea
right now. People claiming A I will solve everything
are going to set A I backwards by years in many instances. And that is a huge problem.
-- Same with the web, same with Blockchain, but that doesn't
-- make it OK.
But what's the alternative? We're going to do this perfectly and safely.
The alternative is to be sane
and
screaming about it.
But seeing
poop KT,
-- that's the answer.
-- But until we try and
experiment with this, we don't know what is sane or insane
if you had told me
10 or a year ago, some of the use cases I now daily use
A I for I would have been like, that's completely bonkers.
Like I'm reminded of when I used to
not use Amazon web
services load bouncing because I didn't want them to
have my SSL certificates and they have them all.
And then I realized there
and then I realized they're running all my work
on because I'm not turning this into an
answers.
I want to talk about G
lipsy because we have a few more minutes. And the G Lipsy bug
is
the one reason I want to talk about it
is because this is one of the only instances I know of where secure
boot stopped a security vulnerability and I am ecstatic by that.
Well, exactly what what's going on this amuses me to no end.
So there's this GLC bug
which is the, the the details are mostly irrelevant. It's a buffer overflow in
this weird
performance environment.
Variable GLC supports that you can use with a set U ID application
to overflow, the heap and gain root, right?
Very typical set U ID functionality, no surprises there.
But
when you turn on secure boot.
So and to be clear, what do you mean what is secure boot here?
Like the UEF I blah blah blah stuff,
right? Like when you in your bios, you say like secure boot on, right?
When secure boot is on,
there are environment variables set in the kernel and
G Lipsy checks them and it disables certain functionality in
this particular environment variable.
That is the result of, I also need to say, what was the name of it? Lo
looney tunable. They named it, which is very amusing to me.
The environment variable is not red
if, if secure boot is on.
So I saw that I was like, oh my goodness, secure boot actually did something good
that only works on hardware now in V MS or containers. Correct?
Well, containers,
you know,
I don't know if the secure boot magic makes it into a container running on a system.
That's a good question. But it's from the kernel. I don't know.
People are kind of working on that, all that attestation stuff, right. But it's not
their
V MS support this like crap too, for sure, for sure.
It's
the g lipsy thing is really wild to me because,
ok, back in the day we had multi user systems for one very simple reason. What was it?
It's because we could only afford one
computer cost
-- and like,
-- right for build a room,
like,
like
I had a mail server and FTP and web and login server running on
a single box because really simple reason is I only could afford one box.
You
know what?
You know what I think is funny is I remember in the early two thousands
where UNIX people would brag how one UNIX system can basically do.
Like a data center's worth of work of a windows.
You know, environment where you need like Microsoft was like,
if you have a web server, you run the web server on one computer.
Like you don't put all this crap.
And us UNIX people were like, we can run everything on this one system.
And then of course, leads to
the problem is between those different system components.
There's a lot of interconnection points to talk to each other that there
shouldn't be.
But what really blows my mind is to this day, for example,
my web browser basically I wanted to be able
to like read and write its config directory,
arguably write to my downloads directory.
And that's kind of all I wanted to do to my system
and maybe be able to print once in a while.
-- But
-- instead your web server prints.
No, my web client. Sorry,
sorry.
Did I not say web client? Sorry. So my web browser,
my
brain
is
like I said, I want my web browser basically to view web pages
maybe print once in a while.
Yeah,
but like not poop all over my system unless I like
tell it to save a file to a very specific spot.
But
the world we live in
unless I do some like crazy se links policies or something.
My web browser has fundamentally access to everything.
If I write a Python script and I import a single library,
what can that single library do?
The answer is
-- everything,
whatever it wants
it can be me,
-- it can write to the file and
-- you're totally
checking the code in all your Python libraries,
right?
And so
of course,
well, the honestly the solution to this is kind of containers, which one?
Because also it just makes stuff work. Sure. Sure.
And so
what do you remember when we had those kind of thought experiment discussions
at Red Hat about Red Hat Nine and what we wanted to see?
And a bunch of us were proposing,
we want Red Hat Nine
to be basically a very
like
the hardware.
Uh Basically,
we wanted to re invent nt version 351 with the hardware abstraction layer
with like a like with a VM slash container level.
And so like literally, if you ssh into the system is root, spins up a container is root
and,
and then you would be allowed to maybe with special circumstances,
talk to the underlying system,
but that underlying system would be like very tight and clean
and, you know, unless you're doing high frequency trading,
you run everything in a container or on a VM.
And so, right, the idea was that we had,
we could stop trying to make Se Linux actually keep people
from touching each other and just have containers do it.
And
for the
the majority of apps like, oh, I need to talk to a database. OK.
Here's your, you know, port 5432 for Post Grass or whatever,
here's your web server. Here's your thing. And of course, that didn't happen.
Red Hat version nine was just Red hat version eight. But with more up to date software
distribution, it was architecturally identical.
But
what gets me is, well, my web servers do that now. Like we use Hiroko,
we have a bunch of containers and
I think it's a Buntu
based, I don't even know anymore or care. And that's the point.
Most of this stuff just works.
And
that's, I think is an example of
how do I put this nicely. The solution to this g lipsy security flaw
is like, yeah, we'll play security whack a mole with the bugs as they come up.
But fundamentally how do we fix something like that? And it's
not rewriting it in rust.
That's probably not gonna work.
I
mean, it's
possible but I, I imagine if you try to rewrite g lipsy and rush,
you're gonna encounter some weird corner cases or
-- undefined behaviors
-- it can't take but a weekend.
-- Yeah,
-- exactly. I really like Linus wrote Linux
in like a few weekends, didn't he? Yeah, a couple days probably,
you know,
get mi
level functionality.
But
that's the thing.
I'm, I'm looking at again, kind of back to this compensating control.
I think we need to kind of go to this bolt on security because
we can't
fix the underlying system.
It's just, it's like trying to fix all the roads in Edmonton.
No, I mean,
look there's lots of organizations that don't have
to care about this because so here,
here's a great example when I was at Elastic,
they have a cloud service and at one point there
was some sort of set U ID bug or something.
I remember it was, I think it was a bug in Pseudo
and our solution was
to upgrade Pseudo. It was to remove Pseudo
from all of our containers.
We're good now, We don't care and we never have to care again.
And they were like, wait a minute, why should we stop with pseudo?
Let's remove every set U ID thing on these containers.
I used to do that as a security thing on the web services,
remove all the set U ID junk because
it's probably just gonna cause me problems
like it's already a container. You're not like ss
-- hing in and doing stuff. I
-- was doing this like 20 years ago,
right?
Like it, it, but that's the thing is,
I
think that's, this is an example where we'll use our A I threat model, right?
To tell us like, let's look at this. Oh, set U ID stuff is a potential problem.
Let's just get rid of it because we don't need it and we're done
and we don't even have to care about this bug even a little bit.
And that's awesome.
Well, the offset being is you have to sell, getting rid of set U ID and part of that is.
Well,
what if we move to an environment where we
just don't need it like containers where we have one
privilege set or whatever you want, call it per container.
They talk through well-defined network sockets.
They could even talk over shared, you know, volumes if they really want to.
But fundamentally
you chunk it up into nice discreet chunks
and they're,
well, you don't have like 20 kids with one has a cold in a classroom equivalent of it.
We're all gonna get sick
and see.
And that's what I'm talking about is because
every time I see somebody say something like,
oh, we just need to train developers to write code securely.
I'm like, yeah, we,
-- it's been 50 years. Let me know when that's going to work.
-- No, it, it doesn't work.
It doesn't work.
In fact, was it, I'll,
I'll try to find uh Bob Lord had a really nice too the other day that basically said
fishing training is inhumane.
It's, it's mean
because you're basically trying to trick your employees
into clicking a link and when they do,
you're punishing them like that's bananas.
Well, and more to the point if, if one of your employees clicking a link
-- like down like, yeah,
-- your security team is terrible. The
MGM.
If truly what happened to MGM is basically
one or two phone calls resulted in 100 million
dollar claimed claimed loss, then your, it is bad for sure, for sure.
But I think the problem is we have to start looking at new
capabilities and new ways of doing things because this whole thought experiment,
we, we can't rewrite stuff in rust.
We can start nibbling at it like the Linux kernel and windows. Absolutely.
But
that requires resources that not everybody has. Like
curl, curl
doesn't have a pile of magic resources.
And if they had a pile of magic resources, they probably have a pile of bugs that are
-- need to be fixed like sooner rather than for
-- sure, for sure. And, and I think
this is the perpetual problem and we've been talking
like this for decades at this point of using
compensating technology to deal with certain vulnerabilities.
And as much as I'd love to say, yeah,
we should all start doing this like this is not new thinking
and I don't think it's going, here's the reality and this is what I'm going to end on.
We have the security, the market demands. That is it.
Well,
we, that was also true for cigarettes and cars with no seatbelts.
How did that get changed?
Yeah. Well, through regulation and through people making a sting.
-- And
-- so today we have the security of the market demands.
If we want to make security better,
we have to change the environment,
the external environment, we can't fix the software,
we can't bolt on security unless the market
somehow demands it and regulation can create demand.
Consumers can create demand.
But fundamentally that has to come from outside. It can't come from us.
Yeah. Well, and we're seeing that like the White House released their um,
open
source security paper
did. And so I feel like we're starting to move a little bit,
but at the end of the day,
that is where the change comes from,
not from
people like us complaining on a podcast.
That's it.
All right.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to Social security podcast.com. Find the show notes.
Here's a pando
podcast. Hashtag on Mastodon. Kurt. You have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye bye.