Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast
episode, the 41st Prime with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime Josh Bresser.
So,
-- gonna make me redo this intro.
-- No, I'm not.
So, it's episode 179 which anyone listening to,
I put the episode number in the title which I, I'm like, constantly every time I do it,
I think I need to stop.
But
anyway,
so 179 is the 41st prime number.
That seems, I feel like it should be farther along,
I guess 100 and 79 and there's only 40 prime numbers before that.
And I'm sure that counts the fake primes, which is what, 12 and three.
Well, think about it,
like you can immediately eliminate half the numbers because they're even.
That's true.
And then you can eliminate one more sixth of the numbers every third number.
Right? And there's a bit of overlap with the, the evens.
Ok.
Yeah. Yeah.
And the thing is like in the 1st 100 prime numbers,
there's actually not that many prime numbers, like looking at this.
It goes, you know, well,
like here starting sort of towards the middle 31 37 41 43 47 53 5961.
So, like there's about two or maybe three prime numbers out of every 10,
that's not a lot.
-- Uh,
-- no, no, no, I, I agree.
And it's, uh, this is what,
this is a special prime too because it's a Sophie Germain prime.
And I believe the number,
the Sophie domain prime that gets us here is also
it, it, it's,
I forget what they call that where a Sophie
domain prime gets you to the prime you're on.
And then this one is also a Sophie domain prime,
which means if you take two times the number plus one.
So two times, what is it like 49 I think
89. So 89 times two plus one is 179 and 179 times two plus one is a number. That's also,
yeah.
There you go. I like
my kids laugh at me. I cannot do math in my head.
Like at all, you can give me a very simple math problem.
And basically, once you exit like the single digits, I'm lost.
It's embarrassing anyway,
right?
So, you know, it's not prime though, Kurt
9090 days isn't prime. That's right.
So
I will let you explain to our dear listeners what the
number 90 means and why we're going to talk about it.
So,
uh Google Project Zero has been doing a lot of good work
finding really bad security flaws and getting people to fix them.
Yeah, definitely.
And back in the beginning of this, I mean, and this goes back, I was going to say,
back in the olden days,
but I realize now the olden days according to this are like 2015
and I have, like,
I'm literally probably wearing a pair of jeans that I bought that year.
Um,
I definitely have shoes older than that.
So
basically when they started project zero,
they didn't really give or force any deadlines.
And so like in true classic fashion,
they
had,
they had 90 days.
No,
no, no, no,
no. Originally it was just kind of a best effort thing. Right.
-- Right.
-- And so some of these vendors would take, you know,
six months
or, well, you remember back in the bad old days, right?
People would disclose vulnerability with a
timeline that indicated that the vendor had
it for like two or three or sometimes four or five years.
-- Yeah. Oh, I remember years. It was embarrassing and bad stuff
-- too.
Not like, like, oh, there's a cross site scripting vulnerability.
No, like, like you type in the letter seven
and it gives you root access,
right?
And these were the days also that like if you,
if the vendor said we need two years to fix this and you said
no way
they'd say, well, we're going to sue you if you say anything.
So you better not talk like, well, crap.
I don't think that ever actually happened, did it,
or at least not successfully. Although it
doesn't have
to
mess up your life.
Right.
I don't feel like I remember anything substantial but there could,
it wouldn't shock me if there were private matters as well because
obviously not everything that happens in a court of law becomes public.
There's ways to keep things secret. So I would,
I, I,
without question, there was intimidation.
Did anyone go to jail for it?
I don't think so, but I wouldn't, I wouldn't bet a coke on it either.
-- So
-- then Google came up with 90 days and we
-- go public with it and
-- everyone lost their mind.
It was literally the end.
It was just like when, you know, Dan Farmer came out with Satan, you know,
security analysis tool for networks,
which it's now like a required thing to do by
almost every security standard from
every government professional organization.
But back when Dan Farmer came up with Satan, I mean, I remember like, like son kind of
held on to him for a few days and then like, booted him out.
He, he basically was, he, he had literally caused the end of the world as we knew it,
you know,
turns out not really.
Yeah,
but
those were different days.
So, yeah.
So one thing Google Project Zero did basically when you release their patch,
they would release the information right away.
You know, again, this is one of those things where
we need, we need to clarify this.
You have 90 days, which means if you take 100 days to release an update,
then Google probably released the details 1010 days before you do.
And a long time ago, that was a huge deal today.
I
think most organizations can pull off 90 days.
I mean,
there's every now and then you'll hear stories about like
Microsoft asked for a two day extension or something and,
-- and there are
-- legitimately like some of the you
have intel hardware bugs.
It's like, yeah,
we're definitely going to need more than 90 days on this or some of the Linux,
oh, not Linux
stuff. But the uh like those g lipsy bugs,
you know,
they definitely needed more than 90 days because, you know, I remember
did all that awesome work and they're like,
and we have this cool solution that should be pretty flawless.
A red hat engineer who all all
anonymity basically went.
No, that, that will only work if we use like four gigabyte card pages.
And then you can have like three processes on a 32 bit system,
it
won't work as a solution.
So some vulnerabilities are such that legitimately, they take more 90 days right
now
at the same time, let's say you take two weeks to fix your issue,
then you would tell Google we're releasing our
update in two weeks and they'd say great.
And then as soon as you release your update with your details,
they would hit publish on their details.
And now their new policy is that they will publish their details at the 90 day mark.
Full stop,
whether there's an update out or there's not an update out.
The 90 day mark is when the details go public,
which I think is great because if you fix your vulnerability relatively quick,
quickly say 30 days or 60 days, you know, that gives you a month or two of leeway.
Well, sort of,
if you would have asked me about this a year ago,
I would have said this is a terrible idea
and I changed my mind in some strange ways for a variety of reasons just because
I've been actually dealing with some very similar
problems in the last six months or so.
But here's the, I guess here's how I would explain this.
So let's say I release version 1.1
and it fixes a terrible security issue that Google project zero reported to me
and I just say here's version 1.1 and that's it right
now, what people say over 1.1 came out. Uh No security issues. I don't care.
I'll wait for the one that has security issues, right?
Why are you publishing 1.1 and not telling people there's a security fix in it.
Why? Because Google is keeping it quiet for 90 days.
So version 1.1 was released. And now, let's say, in
30 days,
all the security information becomes public and now I say, oh,
there was a security issue in 1.1.
So the issue I, I used to have and I, I still sort of do, sort of not is basically
if someone saw 1.1 and they saw no security issues, are they going,
how do you again communicate that?
Ok. 1.1 actually did have security issues.
You actually need to update to that thing. Right.
And I think a couple of years ago, upgrading on a constant basis was uncommon.
I think it's becoming more common,
but there's still a lot of organizations that can't upgrade every
week or every month or every however often you're released.
Well, there's a lot of use cases where upgrades are, are actually restricted,
like medical devices, you got to certify this stuff or,
you know, I run an oil and gas plant. I'm not just gonna like,
do a, you know, a rolling update of Windows,
seven to Windows 10 on the control system and kind of hope for the best.
That's right. That's right.
I, I guess here's,
here's the way I look at it now just because I still struggle with this
in my mind on a constantly and I saw this from Google and I just,
I like, had flashbacks to everything I've been through over the last year.
And
so my kind of view on this is
when you release something,
even if it has security updates,
there are always going to be people who can't upgrade
in a timely manner and that's just that.
So this is why good security advisories are
really important because then they can review the security
advisory and say I'm not using this functionality or I'm not doing it in this way or,
hey, here's how I can just turn off that feature so I'm not vulnerable,
I'll do that instead.
-- Yeah,
-- or add some compensating controls or whatever.
Right. Exactly. Exactly.
That,
so we're in a situation where not everyone can upgrade. Right.
There's some people who do,
who like literally like you hit publish and five minutes
later they're running your new version and that's cool too
for other reasons. I mean, maybe it has other problems but whatever,
there, there's that story
and I feel like how do people
receive and interpret this information? And I think the,
a couple of years ago,
the idea of people looking at a release,
looking at the security issues and then deciding whether they should upgrade or not
was a very point in time event.
But I think we are changing the way all of
this works because now there's so much more automation,
there's so much more microservice architecture magic
that I don't think it's as important
if you're not stuck in 1995 which some, some people are and I'm sorry.
-- Yeah,
-- the challenge is,
there's a lot of people running a lot of
software and it's not necessarily even old software,
10 or 20 or 30 years old, but it's software that's,
they don't have the source code for and they can't fix it.
So they're beholden to the vendor.
And it's typically the kind of software where you can't be like, oh, well,
we'll just stop using that, you know,
because it's like an accounting system or something or payroll
and, you know, you upgrade something else and it breaks,
you know,
and that's
in fairness.
You know, my one thought is, well, hopefully those vendors go out of business,
right?
Because for example, if you write software that runs on Red Hat,
Linux or Windows 10 or whatever,
it should basically run on those platforms, right. That's it. That's all I got.
You know, I understand like on ipad,
you know, my kids ipads, some of the apps they have, have died.
And it's really sad because there's this one Disney drawing app that was really nice
and it stopped working around I OS version 12.
I'm still bitter that I can no longer play.
What Mini Death Star it was called. There was, there was a game
that before Disney had bought Lucas Arts
that they paid like some third party publisher,
I think it was called Mini Dust Star or Tiny Dust Star it was called.
And anyway, I really enjoyed it.
It was kind of a silly game but I liked it and
then it disappeared and I can never get it back now.
So
I'm better.
Yeah. So, you know,
I mean,
the Enterprise world is a little different but
there's also like the normal people world of,
you know,
somebody has a piece of photo editing software that
they've learned and been using for 20 years.
Why, why should they have to, you know,
it's a,
it's a complicated problem because most of the real world we don't
make changes to devices that make them break or totally incompatible,
right?
Like there's, it's not like my car,
somebody's going to say, oh, this spare part
or, you know, this part of your car has some flaw in it.
So, here's a new one that fixes it and then my radio breaks.
Uh, that's true because every time I've ever gone in for recall work,
it has basically been the same as before I brought it in.
Yeah.
So, you know, and then that's something interesting with software is that most,
a lot of software is very brittle
in the, you know, you, you look at it funny and it falls over and
-- back. But
-- how does this relate to Google's 90 day policy change?
A lot of people can and don't want to upgrade because
if I don't upgrade, my system keeps working, if I upgrade, there is a
larger than zero chance it breaks.
Now,
offset by the security risk of there's a security risk
there's a bigger than zero chance it gets exploited,
but potentially that larger than zero number is so small, it might as well be zero.
But now if you're a person who never upgrades
Google's policy change effectively has no effect on you.
-- Well, exactly.
-- I mean, it doesn't matter in that case really.
This basically,
I think only affects people who lag slightly who might
say only take security upgrades that they need to care about
and they're probably already paying closer attention than most.
And I think this is just going to slightly change the way people need
to interact because before it was just uh I would check every
release to see if I need to care about something and now
I need to watch
it at different times, right?
Releases aren't necessarily the thing I need to look for.
And my one other complaint though, I must say that could make this very confusing
is so
you could have a situation where I report a security issue to
say Microsoft and then Google reports a security issue to Microsoft.
And
when are they going to publish details? Right? Are they going to just tell me,
please, let's just wait for 90 days because we have this other issue.
I'm like, oh, you have another issue, ha ha
you know what I mean? And so there's gonna be some complexity there.
Well, at scale though, every vendor always has a train of security flaws
and
like that's the thing, right? Like,
you know, if you have a, like
even a good and relatively small code based security product
typically has more than one flaw at a time
without question.
So I don't think that's a real problem. I think I, like,
I get the sense that what Google is trying to do here is to incentivize people.
You have 90 days and if you take less than 90 days,
your customers will hate you less and you will have done a better job and
people will be happier
and they're trying to incentivize that good,
correct behavior of fixing it quickly and efficiently and clean.
How does this incentivize that outside of the way they already handle things?
Well, for example, in the past, if I fixed it quickly at 30 days,
Google still released the information at 30 days and why, why is this now?
Buy me 60 days
to do what to
tell people. Look, this is a security release, you better install it right away.
Uh oh, before they release, say like a working exploit, I suppose.
Well, before Google releases uh details, right?
-- They, as far as I know Google project here doesn't release exploit code,
-- don't they?
I thought they did. I don't remember.
-- I'm pretty sure
-- they don't because the legality of that gets kind of
we'll say reproduction code, right?
Not weaponized, nobody should
weaponized exploits.
We can argue about that
-- security tools that
-- are like meta,
I love
metas
play
anyway,
that's just don't release weaponized exploits for things I have to work with.
Ok.
That I have to upgrade. Right.
That's my request. Everything else is fine.
The
thing I have to deal with you don't mess with that because they,
and I
bet.
But um no, so this way with the new project zero timeline,
if I release my security patch at 30 days and tell people, I basically can say, look,
you have 60 days to upgrade, there's a security flaw and you know, 60 days from now,
the details will become public
as a customer.
I would kind of prefer that because I have
now I don't have to immediately upgrade and panic.
Hang on. I'm gonna, I'm gonna break this apart into a couple of pieces.
Uh You are wrong and I'll explain to you why.
But additionally, Google said that they don't want people rushing patches.
And I, I've been through that too where someone, someone reports a security issue
and everyone was like, oh my goodness, security issue,
like let everyone light on fire and run around like crazy people.
And it's like holy cow, you know,
poster
child for that started with 12
G I think we ended up with five.
Uh I remember that. I think Redhead only did two and
they're hilarious for that. But
anyway,
that is a
bizarre and crazy story in its own right.
But yes, exactly where you don't want people rushing to release things,
but they have 90 days with Google.
So you don't have to rush,
you have 90 days,
you have 90 days either way with this or without it. So,
and plus up to a 14 day extension.
Right.
Which you probably need a really good reason for which my guess is if you
believe
the reason is Christmas.
Right. Exactly.
Or, you know.
-- Yeah, Christmas.
-- And
that's right.
Yes.
Anyway, anyway,
but here's why you're wrong saying you should be able to
say this is a security update and in 60 days,
the details will come out.
Microsoft used to do that
and did it actually prevent anyone from reverse
engineering their patches and coming with exploits?
No,
but that takes a bit of time.
That's not, you know, the details being dropped 15 minutes
later.
I agree with you that it might delay exploit
by a week or more.
You're assuming that people care about these security flaws enough to try. And
that is true.
There are probably only a dozen applications that
people care enough to actually reverse engineer.
You know, basically all the things that people will pay bounties for,
like not the companies but third parties will pay boundaries for.
I would also say that
-- you are wrong because there's a lot of software now that auto updates
-- and there is,
and that's great.
But again, if you're auto updating,
then it, it, it's a moot point,
but this gives the fleet time to upgrade because it's not like, you know,
an auto update happens overnight. Like I'm guessing, even with the best of
uh systems, it takes, you know, 24 to 48 hours plus,
you know,
there's the case of like systems that are offline and then come back online.
You know, because they're turned off,
that's irrelevant to alerting Attackers is that there
is a security bug in this update.
-- They just have to find it.
-- Well, the alternative too is you just ship the update.
Say you ship your version 1.1 you say there's no,
you don't talk about a security update.
You try and get it across the fleet, you know,
and then maybe you retroactively say it's a security flaw or a security update or,
or maybe you say release a 1.1 0.1 and say that's the security update.
I've done all of these things in the last year and at the beginning,
I had the attitude of we need to like first release.
We should publish the advisory
and eat some crow
because we should have done it all. At the same time when you have multiple version,
-- you know, crows best eaten when it's young and fresh.
-- Exactly.
Exactly.
But here's the thing after talking to many customers,
mostly customers and developers and
anyone I could find
it became apparent to me that this was hurting people because
they knew they were running bad versions
and there was literally nothing they could do
because we hadn't released the new version,
right? And they, they don't like being in that situation. And so
what, where I,
where I've ended up landing and I think is the
right thing to do here is you say nothing,
you say nothing until everything is released and ready to go.
And then
like, yeah,
like let's say I've got three versions and they
come out over the course of three weeks,
nothing is said the last one lands and then the advisory comes out and
part of this is treating advisories kind of separate from releases which I think is
what's going to happen with the way Google is treating, this is
releases and advisories have historically been bolted together and I think they
need to be separated in order for this to actually work.
And I think it's ok though
because I think it gives people an opportunity to better
control what's happening in terms of releasing all the software.
But additionally, I think for something like project zero,
part of the power in this is going to be
when you have say Debian in Red Hat. And so
all releasing software
and, and I have to say Muntu,
I forgot about them. But anyway, there's like a million distro, right?
And I remember it was very common for Debian to be first and then Muntu
might come next and then Red Hat come next and then Debian might re release again
because they screwed up the patch the first time and it's like that was messed up.
Yeah,
I remember crunching a bunch of numbers on that one time because somebody
was basically picking on red hats and you guys are too slow.
When you looked at the re releases, it was like, yeah,
we look good because like we were testing this stuff.
One of the specific goals of this is faster patch development. We can all agree.
That's the goal, but more importantly, thorough patch development.
So not just like how many times have people fixed
that
specific,
you know, aspect of that security flaw and the underlying flaw is left, right?
And
number three, which and I mean, I keep coming back to this is that improved patch
adoption, right? Because
you know, if a patch falls in the forest and nobody installs it, does it
anybody hear it or care?
I'm skeptical the improved adoption is going to be a part of it.
But I do think that in the open source ecosystem
giving multiple people time
to deal with this stuff, I think has the potential to be a game changer.
Now, the other part of it though is again,
if you release version 1.1 of library
X and I look at the, I don't see any security issues in it. I'm like, great.
I don't need to care about this release.
We'll just update the next time, you know, kind of still back in that position.
Whereas
obviously when there was
the nation in the Linux distro world
say, oh, hey, I, you know,
library X is coming out in two weeks and it has a security issue and here's a patch.
So it's,
I mean, it's complicated. I feel like
they're doing the right thing,
but I do think it's not
exactly easy to explain right now because I think there's a lot of nuance.
Well,
I would say the biggest thing for me is they're doing it relatively transparently.
So we know what the rules are.
That's, I mean, a huge step forwards
because like, literally there's a lot of security researchers out there where,
you know, they tell you something and it's kind of like, so like what,
like, what's the timeline of the rules or do you have rules? Like, do you care?
You know,
and that's one of the things they talk about here specifically is trying to
um blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah.
Uh Well, anyways, and part of the blog posting, they talk about how
they're sort of trying to just standardize things a bit and kind of, you know,
-- some consistency, I guess maybe would be the word I want to use.
-- I, I mean, that
seems fair. It's, this is, this is a really hard problem. And
I think Google has done more specifically Google
project zero has done more in this space
than
probably anyone else to date with their 90 day policy.
And I mean, they were the, they were the demon at, at the beginning.
I remember I didn't even like the 90 day policy. I was like, this thing sucks,
but it was, I think it was important. And so
I don't know, I guess we will see where this goes next.
I'm very curious to see how this all shakes out and where we land.
-- I
-- mean, the good news is we're seeing a couple of other factors,
pushing
generally good behavior with respect to security for it.
So like automatic updates because
if I ship a piece of software and I only have to uh support the most recent version,
man, my life is a whole lot simpler.
Yeah.
Um
You know,
so there's a lot of other factors coming to
play now that I think will help security improve,
not because there's security issues but because
they just make everybody's life easier.
Like,
so
I think it's, I
think the reality is that we're moving to a
world where it's continuous integration and continuous development of software
and if your software randomly breaks when something changes and you
can't fix it and the vendor won't fix it then
-- um Yeah, you need to stop using that software.
-- I mean, that's completely fair
and I, I
don't think that I don't see that too often anymore.
Yeah, like I've been talking with my devs about this because, you know,
we're looking at changing how we do some stuff and basically, it boils down to
the further the delta of like what we use and
kind of what we deploy is from sort of upstream,
the bigger the cost gets and the cost isn't linear. It's
like, I believe it's more algorithmic because, you know,
instead of dealing with one change at a time,
you're dealing with five changes that all sort
of interlink and like really break things,
you know, versus
upgrading from 1.1 to 1.2 to 1.3 to 1.4 to 2.0 is a
lot different than going from 1.0 to 2.0 and hoping for the best.
Uh
Yeah,
yeah.
Well, let me put it this way.
There's a video out there of a guy who installs, what is it like Windows 1.0 or do
-- something and upgrades it all the way to like Windows 10.
-- That's a cool video.
You know, you can do that sequentially, you can't go from D OS to Windows 10.
Uh That wouldn't make sense necessarily.
Now, I will say I've jumped a surprising number of fedora versions
and some
vendors do a really amazing jobs
like that.
Amazingly,
my intent was to just wipe the disk and I think I went
like five Fedora versions once and it actually worked and I was like,
wow, that's amazing.
Well, and that's the thing.
Like there are some software vendors that do that where they literally, you know,
maintain ridiculous levels of backwards compatibility
-- updates,
-- which was definitely an accident though, right?
The fedora developers were not like we should maintain five versions
backwards. No, not at all.
This was just Josh did something really dumb
that no one's ever done before and it happened
like that's all.
No, I, I hear you.
I look at it from the lens of, for example, the logistics world, right,
the logistics world has gone from,
I need to have a big warehouse with enough stuff
that I can ship it out and have it, you know, like arrive there eventually to,
you know,
literally like UPS has commercials that basically boil down to
let us be your warehouse just in time delivery.
It's awesome.
And when it works, man, it's efficient and it works great. And you think about
how much money people have tied up in stuff,
sitting in warehouses versus the people that don't,
that's a huge thing.
And I feel the same way kind of with software in that
the amount of money to have tied up
in supporting older versions or dealing with this.
You know,
the good vendors now, like
I haven't
really had
a Microsoft or Apple or even a major Linux vendor
update
really break anything
-- in a long time. Like you don't run
-- Linux enough.
Uh I run quite a few Linux
-- or we have a mix of sent off seven every time
-- I upgrade it.
I'm like, I wonder what's gonna break this time.
But I mean,
like I remember back in the day when I was running
fedora and there was this one version where they were DP
and around with Se Linux policies and like
it broke NTP and then it,
yeah, and then it broke and I,
I literally stopped upgrading Se Linux because it's like, I, you know,
this is becoming like
-- unusable.
-- You just turn it off, kids.
E Linux
off and
that's actually what I ended up doing.
Yeah,
I'm sorry.
No, actually in all seriousness,
I've been running it on my desktop now for more than a year
and it has not gotten in the way once I was impressed,
they do
the job.
So like, yeah, shout outs to us C Linux des, you guys, you're pretty awesome.
But I mean, that's in general,
the mature software vendors are becoming quite mature with respect to,
here's an update.
It's probably not going to host stuff.
Well, that, I mean, that's some of them, obviously my guess is this,
this project zero change is probably not targeted at Microsoft.
And
I, yeah, I don't know. I mean, I guess
I feel like there's more to this story than we understand and they ever understand,
which I'm sure is true.
It makes sense that, you know,
if I bust my butt to release my patch at 30 days and then Google drops immediately and I
don't have like under this new policy they can
with mutual agreement release earlier than the 90 days.
So, for example,
I could release my patch for 30 days and they release a 35 days or 40 days
instead of a 90 days. Right.
-- Yeah.
-- And I wonder
also if they had some issues where
an open source project might patch something in a public get
repo.
And then is that, is that public?
And now again, a couple of years ago I would have been like, yes,
that's 100% absolutely public.
And now I'm like,
you know what I mean? It really isn't. And if, if someone finds it on accident, like
you can ask him nicely and maybe there's some bad guys looking for it, but honestly,
it's really not that big of a deal.
So
monitoring that stuff with a INML the volume is just way, way too much.
Not necessarily.
I mean, look, man, if I was going to do something nefarious,
I would pick on a sensitive library and there's many like pick on G
lip C,
you could watch the g
lipsy and I, I think they do private bugs still.
I don't think they do everything in public. But
uh I'm sure there's something,
nothing's coming to my mind at the moment that I want to say the name of because
there's certain things I know that do this and I don't want to rat them out.
But
like
there's certain things you could watch
and you knew what you were looking for like an easy example actually. Is
there is,
oh,
crap. I don't even remember now. There, there's, there's a no Js library that
I use
that. I know who the security people are
and I watch for their commits.
I know when they commit something I need to
pay attention because stuff's coming down the pipe.
And so
it's like I'm clearly cheating
and granted I'm doing it for a little,
you know,
to automate and do yourself.
Right. Well, yeah, basically I just follow their commits. Right. And
anyway,
-- not
-- exactly like some,
-- I'm
-- not
-- hacker,
-- I'm not elite hacker.
I use the
button.
That's right. Exactly.
But anyway, anyway,
I feel like this is a,
one thing I like about this is it's a change
and that's, that is enough. They're trying something new
and I like that.
Right. Because how many security vendors are trying new things upscale?
-- I mean,
-- and I think that's
that right there, I think is
potentially the most important thing of all.
And I know that this is an argument I have with people
constantly that sometimes change for the sake of change is bad.
But I especially feel like in the security industry
shaking things up every now and then is really good because I
-- think some of us get the thing
-- is you can't simulate this.
See, that's the biggest problem
with information security is you can't simulate most of this.
-- Uh,
-- right.
Especially when it comes to software fixes and updates and bug handling.
You can't run like
a B control tests without actually doing it.
-- It's just that simple.
-- Uh Yeah. Yeah. Yeah,
you're right. Absolutely. I agree. I agree.
All right. So we're, we're nearly out of time here. So I guess
I will.
I like it. I guess that, that is my, that is my brief description of all this is
I'm glad they're trying something new.
I'm, and they're even calling it an experiment which I, you know,
so they're not saying like,
this is the way we're doing it from now on and no questions.
I mean, it's an experiment. Let's see what we get out of it. I, I'm excited.
I can't wait to see what happens.
So, all right, man. Last word that we're, we're wrapping it up.
I find it sad that we have to have some
private companies holding the rest of the industry to account,
but it's better than nobody doing it.
Thank you,
Google
Project.
-- Right. Exactly. I was like, do you remember what it was like before?
-- Oh Yeah,
I do.
Mm
I'm not gonna go into that. I'm not
whatever,
whatever. That's right. That's right. Anyone right. Make security great again.
So, thank you, Kurt. Thank you for listening. You can go to open
source security podcast.com, hit up the show notes,
you can use the Pound
podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media
and Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the.