Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
and my partner in crime.
Josh Pressers joining me the day after the real Thanksgiving,
the real Thanksgiving.
Oh, man, Kurt, I'm,
I'm not even gonna get into this argument with you because I don't think
either of us are gonna win for those of you who don't know.
Kurt lives in a country called Canada
which celebrates a holiday they call Thanksgiving in the month of October, which
that's all I'll say.
All right, I will, we will let the audience decide and, and by all means,
let us know on Twitter, what you think of celebrating Thanksgiving a month early?
So, what's new Kurt?
Well, uh my favorite
back to something I've looked at before is
where do prime numbers come from?
I, I think they're the stork brings them.
Yeah, I, what,
what gets me is even when I generate prime numbers on my own computer in a way that I
am told is correct.
I, I'm, I'm still not entirely correct. Right.
Because that's part of the beauty and the magic of this prime number based crypto is
the definition is that these things are so hard to determine their factors.
That's the whole security property of them to some degree. Right.
And so we can't really prove if these numbers
are prime or not because they're so dang big.
I mean, unless they end in like a 20.
Right.
We, well, it, it, ok, so that's something really important you just said is,
it is very easy to prove something
isn't prime because you just find something that
it can be divided into, right? No big deal.
And for those of you who don't know which I'm, I'm not gonna lie.
Anyone who listens to this podcast, I would expect to know what a prime number is.
But essentially it's a number that is only divisible by one in itself, right?
So you, for example, can't divide it by two or three
and get a whole integer of the other side of that.
Now, that said
it is
something that keeps coming up in the news lately is the fact that
prime numbers which are the cornerstone of cryptography today
are increasingly coming under attack. Historically speaking,
we've been far more interested in
the algorithms themselves, but now that we have research going on into
the fact that some of these algorithms like Diffie Hellman, for example,
relies on having a large good prime number.
Well, when we did a bunch of this work, 1024 bits, what's considered large and,
and good is questionable at best, but we'll get to that
1024 bit primes are no longer big enough.
And
did you read the paper, Kurt?
-- Honestly, I don't really read crypto papers because you don't know
-- how to read.
Well, usually by about the second or third paragraph, I'm, I'm lost,
I've read about the first. It's 29 pages and I read probably 15 of them so far.
I, I won't lie.
I don't, I don't delve into the math very deeply now that, you know, I,
I don't do that sort of thing very often.
But,
but fundamentally, these guys have done some pretty solid work. And for those of you
out there who listen,
the fundamental problem here is that
when you have an algorithm like Diffie
Hellman,
which relies on essentially having a good prime
number that both parties know and share,
then you do some,
some math and there's plenty of videos on the internet that
discuss how Diff Helmet works and it's an ingenious algorithm.
But the problem is that if you have an attacker
that has significant amounts of computing power at their disposal,
they can do a bunch of pre computations around
these prime numbers
and then they can essentially so there, well, there's kind of two attacks here.
There's one where you do a bunch of pre computation and you store the data
on
understanding what all the possible
numbers are that I, this is, this is tough man to not go too crazy
and so
alienating everybody.
But essentially what you end up with is
you've got a prime number, you're doing some math with another number
and you can pre comput a whole bunch
of this math in advance. And then you can use that to your advantage to
essentially break the diffie Hellman
results that are expected to be secure. But now this new attack
is essentially talking about how you can have prime numbers
that are known bad.
And this is fascinating to me because historically speaking,
the idea that we were always afraid of was having a number that wasn't really prime,
whereas you have a number that's mostly prime,
we'll say which I know sounds hilarious.
But
the way we check prime numbers is we don't go through every possible integer,
multiplying them and dividing them and saying, you know,
does this give us our prime number?
We have various algorithms
that we think
are correct for determining prime this?
We don't, I don't, I don't believe they're proven.
Well, actually, it's worse than that.
I, I did some research into this last year and all of the stuff that those um
those tests and those algorithms are based on is
math that is essentially at this 0.30 years old.
And I was unable to find,
I was unable to find any recent work on it,
right? The work was done 30 years ago and that's it.
And it was,
these algorithms
definitely do work for testing the primal
of prime numbers
up to a certain size.
And back then
like 30 years ago, a 1024 bit prime was like magic, let alone a 4000, you know,
96 bit prime or something.
And so I wasn't able to find anybody that
could even say with any certainty that these algorithms
will work well on large prime numbers.
And nobody as far as I can tell has done the research publicly.
That's,
that's really interesting because the answer to having
essentially weak back door 1024 bit primes is using
2048 bit primes
because in, in the research, I don't have the number in front of me right now.
But basically, they said that in, in a couple of weeks of compute time,
given the fact that the cloud exists, which is
really makes some of this research crazy because in the past,
there were a few organizations that could literally have, you know,
thousands of computers at the disposal.
I know anyone can do it for, you know, $4 and a credit card.
So the answer here though is to use large primes.
When I say large primes, we're talking 2048 bits,
which is still not super huge. But
that's really interesting if you say that there isn't a ton of good math
deciding if our old ways of determining prime.
Well, yeah. Well, that's fair,
but
it might not be good. And the problem is though, we don't
uh there hasn't, as far as I can tell, there hasn't been a lot of research into this,
you know,
I was looking for.
Um,
because two of the things I've always wanted to
find is a good test suite for prime numbers
that is
mathematically,
you know, has had some research done into say larger primes, like 4, 4000 bit primes,
8000 bit primes
and a second test suite for randomness and cryptographically secure randomness.
-- And there's
-- some really good random test suites.
Actually, I don't remember the name of it. I should look for this.
Yeah, there were one or two that were pretty decent. But
part of what frustrates me is that there's, you know, the,
the math to understand this stuff, let's face it when you read one of these papers,
unless you have a degree in math,
you kind of have to trust what they're writing because it's, it's, you know,
you have to devote a few years to understanding this and
let's face it.
Your average developer or even your average security
person doesn't have the time for that.
I mean,
but that's fair with any industry.
Kurt is the fact that you have experts and most other people rely on those experts.
I mean, I don't know how to build a silicone chip,
but Intel sells them, I buy them from Intel and I assume everything is fine, right?
Uh But,
and then the other thing that really gets me about a lot of
these primes is let's assume for a moment that these prime numbers,
you can generate them safely and correctly.
What's interesting to me is there's a lot of prime numbers
in use and people aren't really sure where they came from.
Like some developer
created them, I guess at some point and put them into the code base and
back in the depths of time.
And, you know, we literally don't know where some of these prime numbers came from.
Well, all right.
So there's, I think a couple of important things we should clarify here is,
first of all,
there are a significant number of cryptographic
algorithms and operations that rely on having
a large prime number. All right.
Second of all, generating a large prime number
is a nontrivial task.
Given the fact that we are essentially dealing with randomness,
it might take 10 seconds, it might take 10 minutes.
So you don't want to generate these large primes on the fly.
All right.
So we've got that because obviously,
if you're connecting to a website and it
takes 10 minutes to generate the prime number,
you need,
you're, you're gonna find somewhere else to go. Right.
So, and additionally, there's the fact that
these large prime numbers have been pre generated,
we don't necessarily know where they came from,
but they're often shared
amongst various things in use on the internet.
For example, I think the,
the top million websites or top 1000 websites are one of those,
this is actually in that, that paper,
they all share a handful of primes
that are the same, which is kind of crazy when you really think about it. That,
and this again comes back to that pre computation attacks and the, the back door is
if, if someone decides your prime number is one of the blessed primes and, you know,
it's back doored.
Yeah, I mean, you're in right.
Yeah.
it's actually a bit worse than that.
I mean, even on a, on a modern PC, sure you can generate a prime number and then,
you know,
a few seconds, uh,
a few tens of seconds if you're unlucky because
literally the way these things generate these large primes
is they pick a randomly large number and then test it for primal, right?
You know,
and using like, what is it? Um, I think it was the number of something, like if you do 50
tests on this number, like the chance of it being not a primer vanishingly small,
um, like two to the negative 80th or something, you know,
which for the majority of us is fine.
But,
yeah, when you start using that prime number for like 60% of the world's websites,
then, you know, that is,
that is something worth attacking for a bad guy.
And what really
the reality too is like on a phone, for example, generating prime,
it's gonna kill your battery.
And if you had to generate new primes, right.
Every time you connect it to a website because
not only does the server have to generate primes, but the, you know,
the client needs primes as well.
Right.
And the reality is if, if we had everything generating primes on the fly, I mean, the
honestly, the battery drain alone a week of that,
regardless of battery, it takes too long to do
to generate suitably large prime numbers. Now, that said,
even though
you have a certain amount of shared primes across these
various applications and various websites and whatever you want to do
there is
these algorithms are designed
with the concept of shared primes in mind.
Diffie Hellman relies on having shared prime numbers
right
now.
At the same time, you also want some amount of shared primes because for example,
if, if I'm connecting to a malicious website
and it hands me a number and says here's a prime number,
is it prime?
It takes a long time to check that. And so
there's value in having some of this pre shared. I'm not saying
that we should all just be automatically doing this stuff on
our own and trusting whatever the server is giving to us.
Now,
when we put all of that together,
the fundamental takeaway here is stop using small primes, right?
We need to use large primes and this is true of encryption keys in general,
we now have so much computing resources available to us
that you need to be using large keys.
And actually, that was one of the things I looked into was, was there any,
was there any cryptographic software on the client
side that was verifying the prime numbers,
uh, that it was being handed?
And I did find one and it was really, it was some bizarre oddball library for, like,
-- uh, music or something.
-- Lib Tinfoil hat.
Yeah, it was, it was totally strange because it actually did call,
uh,
the thing to check if this number was a
prime and then it would error out and literally,
but the key thing is it would air out with rather a
generic error message and not something like this number is not prime,
you probably need to panic a bit.
I
mean,
none of the crypto libraries return good error messages.
I mean,
you're lucky if it says can't connect,
right? That's,
it's terrible.
Yeah.
So
one thing I, I would love to see is a project to generate some good primes
and test them, you know, widely.
Now you started a github
repo or something, didn't you to capture prime?
So, the idea was to basically have I wanted to see,
uh, you know, when you, basically,
because there's a variety of tools to generate these primes, uh like open SSL has a,
you know, uh uh there's a command line switch to do it and there's some other things.
Um, part of it was to see how long these things take, right? Because I was,
it's non deterministic, right? It's not like it.
You want a 1024 bit prime? It'll take a minute. You want 2048 it'll take two minutes.
It's literally the way we generate these primes is give me a random number.
Now, I'm gonna test it for primal
and you might generate like I've had uh occasions where
generating a large prime took like less than a second and
I think my record was just over 10 minutes.
-- What, what do you, what, what, what is a large prime in this
-- context?
I think it was like 4096.
So,
yeah.
Um and I tried doing some larger ones like eight K
and 16 K and that didn't work out so well.
Um
And
just to put it bluntly, they're, they're just to test them properly.
I mean, they're so big that, you know, it's,
it's gonna take hours if not days on a fast machine.
The good news is this kind of testing parallelize is beautifully.
The bad news is as far as I know there's no good software for it,
but here's the thing you say, it parallels beautifully,
but
you have a trust issue because let's say Kurt generates some primes and
Kurt decides to make some backdoor primes that can be easily cracked.
Now, how do I verify that one?
It is prime, which we can do that easy enough.
It,
it will take time but I I would assume there has
been remarkably little verification done on many of these prime numbers
in things like open ssh and Apache.
In fact, we should, um,
one of us should do that just to,
just to make sure because that would be entertaining.
It would be even more entertaining and sad if, if
something wasn't prime there.
But anyway, so there's that.
But then
how do we trust this stuff? Right. You generate this stuff. Where did you get it?
Did you find the prime and the park
or, or what's going on here? Right. That's the challenge.
Well, I mean, for example, the uh the DNS se people have already done that, you know,
they have these elaborate key signing ceremonies,
um which, you know, they, they pull these uh
encryption cards and stuff out of a locked safe and the locked
safe is kept in a room made out of like plexiglass.
And I remember halfway through the key signing, somebody was commenting that the,
the front of the safe was a bit shiny and that they might want to like,
make sure it's not shiny in future because you might be able to see a reflection
of the person entering the safe and like, you know, the code to enter the safe.
Um
And so they basically just have this elaborate key signing ceremony,
you know, to make sure that nobody like nothing up my sleeves
and
yeah, but it boils down to at some point,
we have to have a computer involved that we trust because, like,
you can't generate these primes using like dice rolls or, you know,
one D 2016. Ok. Well, that's not prime 17. Hey, we got a prime number
we're
in,
you know,
um,
I think a lot of it will have to
ultimately rely on testing and, you know,
having somebody generate the prime that
maybe has an incentive to not
generate an even number, like maybe the eff you know,
the electronic Frontier foundation, right?
They have a good, strong uh history of working for people's privacy.
Um Because the reality is if you hand me a number generated on a computer that are,
as far as I know,
there's no real way I can truly verify that number and that computer are, you know,
safe to generate a prime.
And there's,
you know, there's some incredibly subtle stuff you could do to monkey with it.
Yeah.
Well, and so that's kind of the point to this research in this paper is the fact that
they have found a way to generate a number that is prime,
right? It is prime. If you test it,
nothing
will come up as being shenanigans.
But then due to the way math works with Diffie
Hellman,
you will easily be able to crack data that is encrypted using the Diffie
Hellman algorithm.
And so
that's crazy. Now, at the same time, they do say that a 2048 bit prime
would take some insane number of years
for them to es essentially crack, be it, be it.
Once you, let's say you generate a weak 2048 bit prime
or back door, whatever we want to call it,
the computational power to still crack that
software or not software, but
to crack the math is significant. Now, granted, it's still
magnitude lower than it is expected to be.
But that's, that's important because let's face it today.
It is thousands of years,
but at some point,
it's not gonna be thousands of years, right?
It's going to be something between, you know, probably weeks to days
just because the amount of compute power that is available to
us continues to increase and continues to get much cheaper.
I just think about in, in
50 years, how much,
you know, cloud are you gonna be able to buy for five bucks? It's gonna be crazy.
Well, and part of what I mean, the, the good news here,
TLS uh version 1.3 the spec is almost finalized.
They've essentially embraced uh perfect forward secrecy, right?
So the idea behind perfect forward secrecy
is that rather than, you know,
use the same sort of set of prime numbers for all your connections
you generate,
you know, new prime numbers, new keys for each session. So
even if an attacker, you know, sniffs all the data and collects all the data,
that's not how it works
at
a
high
level
EFS
is
you still use Diffie Hellman for the initial key exchange,
which is where the weak primes comes in.
But then what happens is every connection
or every client, it depends how you, how you put it together.
But essentially, then you have a different
key, be it RS A or ECC or whatever.
Because the way
the older tlss work is a server would literally have one key and every client used it.
So if you broke that one key,
you could unlock all of the data
right
now. We still have the weakness in Diffie Hellman though,
because in many instances,
the server and client are probably using a small number of primes.
So if you have a small prime, it doesn't matter how big your key is,
you're going to have problems.
Well, yeah,
but the workload for an attacker goes up,
right?
And that is basically the whole point of cryptography, right? Is, is
there is nothing to prevent you from brute
forcing this with the exception that it's so
much work currently that you just can't do it in a reasonable amount of time,
right?
Uh I mean, the reality is, you know, you
would get fantastically lucky when trying to break a 2048 bit
key and guess the right one on the first try,
you know, it's theoretically possible.
It's just vanishingly improbable.
Fire up your Bitcoin mining rig, right?
Yeah.
So I think the the part of it is we need better primes.
We need to know where they're coming from.
Uh And yeah, like you said, the, the test ability is even with good test ability,
we still have the problem of, you know,
do you really trust the guy and the computer generating this prime number?
Sure. Sure. Sure.
And, and there's some,
I forget, I forget who did this, but
there, there's basically some,
I think it's one of the ni standards defines
how to explain where your primes came from.
But of course, it's not must, it kind of falls under one of those optional,
you know. Yeah, you can do this if you feel like it
definitions and hopefully
that will be adjusted in the future
to make sure we understand where this stuff came from.
Well, it's, yeah,
it strikes me as insane because it's like if you inserted a line of code into open SSH
and refused to say where it came from, like
everybody would be in an uproar.
You know what I mean?
You've clearly never tried to add anything to open SSH,
like getting anything
put in there is, is very difficult.
But
yeah, you know, and that's the thing, right? We would never accept random code from.
Well, when you know, where did this come from, why, why, why did you write it this way?
You know, it's trust me, it's good code
and yet we take these prime numbers and
part of it is, you know,
a lot of projects just go to say open SSL and grab their primes and copy them out
straight up, you know, because what else are you going to do?
Well,
I think the assumption is that open SS SS L
has done some level of due diligence on their primes.
I don't know if they have, I would assume they have just given the project,
but I probably don't want to really know the answer.
Do I?
You know, that's one of the things that's even if they've done due diligence.
Uh
you know,
is that enough?
Because like I said,
I looked into the research and there's just not a lot of recent research,
there's not a lot of people with expertise in this publicly.
Now,
I'm pretty sure the NSA has a bunch of guys in
a room that could tell us one way or the other.
-- Uh And
-- if you are one of those guys, you know, you can,
you can email us,
we'd be happy to,
I
don't want to disappear. My family needs me.
But yeah, I mean, that's, that's part of the problem with these, you know,
with these crypto systems is the, the level of knowledge required to even
understand it, let alone do it properly
is, is quite daunting
it. It is, it is, it's man, this is such crazy stuff.
It makes my head hurt even thinking about it.
And
well, the good news is Attackers don't really attack crypto because let's face it.
Why bother. Right.
Uh I was reading a recent thing. Um, this guy found 6900
card skimming websites.
So basically what the Attackers had done is broken into the website
and essentially installed a software skimmer for the credit cards being entered.
So, you know, like a hardware skimmer. It
your main
lo
well, no.
So what this is basically, it's like, it's like a, for example,
it's basically a script plug in for um one of the common
ecommerce packages was uh I think it's called Magenta or Magenta,
something like that.
And it's used by some large retailers and essentially it just inserted a bit of code
that was labeled uh
ups shipping code
and then it was like script
and then a whole bunch of
gibberish,
you know,
and essentially what it does is as, as a person enters, you know,
their credit card number and Magenta or Magneto or whatever it's called processes.
It,
it was sending a copy of all of that data off to. Well, God knows where Russia China,
some dude in like Texas, who knows.
And
like, yeah, the guy found this on like 6900. We like big websites.
And the reality is, you know,
Attackers aren't going to like record
the data stream and then run decryption algorithms on it.
They're gonna like break into the server and install this little, you know,
one kilobyte shim of code that then sends them every
bit of data they want in future for the next,
you know, six months until somebody notices.
It's that, that XK CD Comic where,
you know, the guy says, oh, this is how I imagine it.
Oh, no, he's using 4096 bit crypto.
We, we can't break his stuff and they're like, no,
like take this wrench and hit him until he tells you his password.
Right. Like that's
it. It's so true. And I think
that is always going to be the story of crime.
Crime will naturally take the easiest way in
and breaking crypto is never the easiest way. But that said now that said though
this kind of research is fascinating and I think it's super important.
So
by all means, even though we're going to talk about how, you know, ha ha,
no one's ever going to do this, it is still
super important to the universe that people do this kind of stuff.
Oh, I agree. I mean,
the reality is, if you know, this stuff is important, this data will, you know,
we don't know if anybody's recording it or how long for, uh,
the reality of storage is getting so cheap.
Like I just picked up a four terabyte external drive.
Um, because quite frankly, it was,
it was just cheap. So why not?
And uh
never throw anything away.
Yeah, pretty much.
Right.
Yeah.
The reality is we don't want to make it too easy for Attackers.
You know, like with the, like, I don't know if you remember, um, oh,
what was it called?
Http S Sheep or the, the one that would basically,
if you had a http unencrypted login page
would intercept it on the fly.
And so when you logged in, normally you would go to a secure site.
Well, this would strip it and send you to an insecure site so that it could, then,
you know, sniffle your user name and password.
Fire, sheep, fire sheep. That's the one. Yeah, I knew sheep were involved
in,
of course. And, uh,
you know, and so, and, you know,
so the response to that is simply people
put all their login pages as being encrypted,
secure web pages.
You know,
we need these fundamentals,
you know, these building blocks.
Otherwise there's, there's really no point, you know,
if it turns out all the primes we're using are actually divisible by seven,
-- then
-- they're not prime.
Yeah.
Well, when I say these prime
because, yeah, like I said,
we don't know with a guarantee that they are
prime until we know that they're not a prime.
Yes, I'm going to hope none of them are divisible by seven.
But if something is, I'm blaming you now.
Yeah.
Yeah, that was me.
So,
that was me. I did it
all right. Anyway,
let's bring this one home. Here's what I'm going to say to everybody listening is
all of the mistakes
we have made discussing crypto
in randomness in primes. And I'm sure there were many,
I want you to tell Kurt.
Ok. So Tweet Kurt on Twitter all about the mistakes we made
and he would be happy to address your concerns in
a future episode of the open source security podcast.
Well, that's what I love is,
we could be completely wrong and 99% of people wouldn't notice.
I, I suspect a handful of the people who listen to us, they know
and
so be sure to tell Kurt.
So I, I guess that leads us now into the most exciting news of October
is. It's cybersecurity month.
I'm
super
excited.
Oh, sorry Awareness Month. Right? Because we, we need
plenty more awareness. I'm super excited.
I've, I've had just nothing but a party for the last, you know, 11 days going on here.
I, uh, I didn't find out about this until accident through my feed.
I, you know, I don't even remember how I found out about it,
but it's clearly ridiculous and I'm skeptical anyone cares about this.
It's a good,
I think it's
done with good intentions,
-- but I
-- just,
-- everything is done with good intentions.
-- Well,
yeah. No, this is true. Sadly.
But, yeah, fundamentally, I don't understand like
what this reminds me of is, it was funny.
I was actually talking to somebody who works for the FDA, the, um,
the US Food and Drug administration
and the topic of security came up and she's like, oh, you know,
are, things are not so bad, they're getting better.
And I'm like, no, it, it's terrible. Everything's terrible. What do I mean?
I'm like, well, for example, I'm like, you work for the FDA, correct.
She's like, yeah. And I'm like, well, do you know, what's your policy on
taking data off of your network and putting it onto removable devices?
She's like, oh, we're not supposed to do that.
I'm like, ok, that's, that's good.
How do they prevent you from doing it? And she's like, well, they told us not to,
that's probably
better prevention than 99% of the organizations on the planet.
Which is the best part.
Yeah.
And so, I mean, that,
you know, there's nothing I'm like, well,
is there anything technological preventing you, like, did they,
you know, is there software that controls what you can copy data off of or is,
did they hot glue the ports, shut,
you know, whatever, right. She's like, no, they just told us not to,
you know, so cybersecurity awareness I think is a great idea. But the problem is
part of it, like you said is, you know,
what can we actually tell these people that's helpful,
we can tell them to
cry quietly under their desk
and that's probably the best advice we can give.
You know, like I'm always reminded of the whole email thing, you know, it used to be.
Oh, you know, you can open up email safely.
Like you can look at an image in your email, you would never get a virus from that.
Just don't run the dot exe.
Well, of course, that change and now it's like, don't, you know,
my favorite all time piece of security advice is because it's so useless.
Don't open data from untrusted sources.
-- I, I don't trust you, Kurt. What do I do now?
-- Yeah,
exactly. You know, except, well, an email shows up in your inbox from your mom.
You trust your mom.
I do not.
So, you know, so that's the thing, right?
Is, is every time all,
pretty much every piece of advice of security advice we've ever given people,
you know, Attackers have found a way around.
Uh, and so essentially we're at the point now where basic human nature of like, oh,
I found a USB key.
I wonder what's on it.
-- There's no safe way to find out,
-- you know,
Schneer
just had a post about this not too long ago where he talks about the fact that
we
cannot fix the users.
That is,
I, I, it's an impossible task to do.
And so in security we do this all the time where we're like, oh, don't do that,
don't do that, don't do that.
Don't do that.
And nobody ever listens to us.
You might have one or two people who sort of take you seriously, but even then
it, they're certainly not going to do it 100% of the time.
And so the only solution
is to fix the products the users use,
which is
easier said than done.
Oh, I agree.
I mean, there's, I,
I'm a somewhat security conscious user and I still make mistakes all the time.
Like,
uh, you know,
I've entered my password when my kid was watching and so
I had to change the pin number on my phone.
You know, because I
figure it out,
-- right? Because he wanted to play games on
-- my phone.
That's what the fingerprint meters for.
-- That's why I
-- got the new one.
Don't nap because they're gonna hold the phone up to your hand.
It's fed
-- off the side of the couch
-- and just don't touch anything
in my house where they can lift a print from it,
you know? Right.
So, you know, that's the thing, right? We, we definitely, I mean,
the other thing that drives me nuts about fixing the users is that,
that presupposes that we have
something safe and useful to tell them,
which quite often we don't like because advice
like don't open data from untrusted sources is,
is useless.
It's meaningless, right?
Especially when viruses are sending out an email, using your address book
-- or, you know,
-- people
I wrote about this in my blog. Uh What, what did I title? It?
Don't Eat Food delivered by Zebras and I forget who I had this discussion with.
It may have been you,
but it was the fact that
we give people advice that they consider to be ridiculous.
And so
if you give someone ridiculous advice,
they'll probably nod and smile because they think you're crazy
and then they just do whatever they want anyway.
And that is basically the history of computer
security summed up into two sentences right there.
No,
I think quite frankly that the general solution is
to where possible remove humans from the equation.
You know, much like driving, right?
People, we can't even get people to reliably use their turn signals, let alone,
you know, driving sober or
driving while, you know, eating and texting and doing, you know, a
crossword puzzle.
Um
But the problem becomes, you know,
is we've got all these existing systems that
were not really designed with security in mind.
Um And the other problem too is we want these systems to be useful
and to do things that are useful, you know.
Yeah, I mean, so,
and part of it too is do we, do we really need perfect security?
And the answer is obviously not because we don't have perfect security in the world,
in the
-- world.
-- No
such thing as perfect,
right? That's the reality of it. You just need to,
it's kind of like the old saying of I don't need to be faster than the bear.
I just need to be faster than you.
Right.
And that used to be true except now, you know,
Attackers will target everything online.
Like that
recent denial of service where they, you know, captured and took over 100 and
some 1000 digital video recorder systems or whatever. Right.
The problem is now, if you plug it into the internet, you're not
an anonymous fish in a big school of fish, you're just a fish.
You know, that the bad guys will find at some point.
Yeah. I mean, that's fair. That's fair. It's,
this is complicated. I suppose you can't always use the,
the argument of, I just need to be slightly more secure than the other guy because
it's not even being more secure than the other guy.
You have to have your security bar at a point where it is more inconvenient
for the bad guys to attack you than to find something else to do.
Yeah.
The problem is that's all been automated now.
So as soon as they find something that you are not secure against then, you know,
-- you're gonna get popped.
-- Right.
Well, and, you know,
that's actually a good point too because if you imagine security as a graph,
the graph goes down over time where the amount of security you have essentially
decreases
as time goes on.
As security vulnerabilities come out as research like
this crazy prime number stuff comes out as
people find new ways to attack TLS and we find new ways to attack, you know, you know,
I PV six is coming, I PV six is insanely complex.
I am terrified of the security flaws
that are going to come out in the I PV six stacks.
It's, it's horrifying to me.
Yeah. Well, and this is also,
and that's for the people that apply patches for the people that don't apply patches
or don't do change.
Yeah, exactly.
You know,
I mean,
I already have devices in my house that I cannot apply patches to, uh,
my nest smoke alarms.
For example, they get over the air updates. I am told by the company I
trust us. Everything's,
yeah,
uh same with my bathroom scale, you know,
Tavis arm and he found a flaw in it that you can use to remotely
hijack and compromise my bathroom scale.
I'm told it was fixed.
Well,
just
hack
it. I
asked Tavis for the exploit.
Yeah.
So you know, it's getting to the point rapidly,
especially with the internet of things.
Not only am I going to have a large number of internet connected devices in my house,
but it's going to be from a huge number of vendors and you know, each,
every single one of them, it's not like there's some unified control panel.
So you, you know what I do for this actually is I I I'm well aware of this problem
and I additionally don't trust my Children or wife
to use my network.
So I have a guest network essentially for devices and guests and my my kids and wife
because I know whatever devices they have,
are almost certainly crawling with malware
and rather than trying to clean it, I've just segregated all of this stuff.
And so there's, there's Josh's friendly network
and then there's everyone else's stuff
and,
I mean, that, that's easy for me to do
but
for normal people that's probably out of the question, unfortunately.
Yeah.
So, I, I don't know what the answers to this are but, um,
it's, it's, you know, it's, it kind of reminds me actually of the, uh,
I hate to bring this up but the Samsung Galaxy seven
thing, you know, where, like,
right now there's all these people with this phone that, like,
literally might catch fire and, or explode,
but
once it explodes it's totally secure.
So Samsung has solved the security problem
for us.
But, I mean, you know, there was a guy on the radio calling in on his, you know,
Samsung seven or Note seven or whatever the heck it's called
and they're asking him. So, like, what are you gonna do? Are you gonna, like, go
in or whatever, like
the fing
phone,
you know?
Yeah, I mean,
and
even something, you know, where the, the course of action should be pretty clear,
like you're supposed to turn this phone off and go swap it for one that doesn't burn,
um,
ignoring
the
fact that
apparently
did you
hear, I think it was,
they
said they're discontinuing the line completely. They've given up trying to fix it.
And it's done.
They, they, they, they've given up,
-- which
-- is, I think from a branding perspective, they've killed it regardless.
That's
-- right.
-- I mean,
and,
and honestly they can just shut the line down and
then restart it with a new sticker on the phone
and
probably the intent. Right. Like,
but, uh, you know,
people need their phones.
I
also need to
not just
burnt.
Yeah. Exploded.
Yeah.
Well, apparently, uh,
and I didn't even know this was a thing but you
can get these essentially fireproof bags for your phone for recharging them
for people who are like, worried about
their phones catching fire firewall charging.
And what's even more amazing is if you read the fine print on most of these devices,
they specifically say they should not be charged while unattended.
That doesn't surprise me. Well, and so
I remember a long time ago there was a guy named Alan Cox who
worked on the Linux kernel and he worked for Red Hat and I,
I remember dealing with him on a fairly regular basis and at
1.1 of his laptops lit on fire while he was charging it,
which in,
in his story was comical in Ha Ha. That's funny. Right.
W which, but it's very serious because people don't realize that
lithium ion batteries had the energy density of TNT.
So like these are i it's a big deal.
I mean, I if lithium ion is going to explode, you're going to get hurt.
It's not like, oh ha ha, the battery leaked a little bit of something out of it,
you know, look, it ruined my video game.
No, no. Like this is,
you're going to be seriously injured by this thing.
Well, like those houses that burned down because of those, uh,
hoverboard thing, of the jigger with those bad batteries,
you know, that
have now been banned.
Exactly the same thing.
Exactly the same.
Yeah.
I, part of me wonders if this is back to,
I don't know if you remember the whole uh Japanese Chinese capacitor
shenanigans that happened about 1510, 15 years ago
where apparently what happened is some company uh broke into another
company's uh computer network and stole some of their design stuff
and started producing capacitors, uh
you know, very cheaply that were supposed to be very high quality.
And it turns out they, they didn't get enough information or they didn't do it.
Right. And basically they, they made,
you know, literally billions of capacitors that ended up uh popping and leaking.
Right. And
like my mom had a deal with this where they, they sent a guy.
They're like, oh, yeah, we know exactly what that is.
Uh, you know, we'll, we'll schedule a guy to come over and swap the motherboard,
you know, and he did it in like 30 minutes and,
you know,
there were millions of these motherboards and
other devices affected by these bad capacitors.
You know, due to this industrial espionage that didn't go quite right.
And part of me kind of wonders if that's
the case with some of these battery situations because
I mean,
obviously it's in Samsung's best interest to make a phone that doesn't catch fire.
Like,
from a branding perspective alone, let alone, you know,
ignoring the whole legal issue.
And I can't help but wonder like, how, how did this become such a big,
like this isn't like a single bad batch of batteries,
right?
This is,
I don't know, it's interesting and it also kind of brings us back.
I'll tie this into IOT as well is
who's verifying the safety of all this stuff?
You look at like an automobile and
you know, they, they crash cars into each other
to figure out is this car
safe or is this car dangerous
and kind of with all this consume consumer products going on?
Who's paying attention to this?
But in, but additionally, the other crazy aspect of that is you and I talk about this
when, when something costs a dollar,
does anyone even care
or can you justify the cost of verifying the safety of something?
I mean, it, it's crazy stuff, man.
Yeah.
And, and I'm really curious is how much of the IOT is gonna have a built in battery?
I assume
some of it because you know, you want it to retain settings.
I would
expect most of it to have built in batteries. I can't think of any iot devices
that don't come with batteries.
Yeah, I mean, I mean, thinking about it, nothing comes to mind and,
and they put batteries in freaking everything, man.
It's crazy.
Yeah. And so, I mean, this, this is, you know,
do we end up with a situation 20 years from now with like, you know,
houses just randomly catching fire and it's normal.
I hope not,
you know, because part of it too is
getting, you know, once people get used to this.
So it's like, it reminds me of texting and driving, right?
Texting and driving was not a problem 20 years ago
-- because
-- people didn't text 20 years ago,
right?
And you know, with this iot everybody's like, and, and myself,
I put myself in this camp of, you know, this iot stuff at home,
you know, what do I care? Right. It's kind of
the thing that
is
the solution to texting and driving
isn't
telling people not to text because we know that doesn't work.
The solution is going to be self driving cars
totally. So
where does IOT end
on this machines taking over the world scale?
So
best case scenario, I think we're going to have to see regulation because Schneer
talks about this actually in a recent essay
where where you have market failures, you know, like
in theory, like the market
doesn't want people's houses to burn down because it's bad for their brand,
you know, like Samsung, right?
And so in this case, you know, Samsung is now
hopefully eventually doing the right thing of recalling
all these phones and not selling them anymore.
And
for what it's worth as much as we made fun of them,
they're totally doing the right thing
and they're, they're eating their poop pie here.
It, it's as bad as it gets,
but I will give them immense credit for making the
correct decision in this instance because a lot of organizations,
they will let stuff like this drag out for years. So, I mean, Kudos to Samsung here.
And so I think with the IOT,
we're going to have to see regulation because part of it is,
yeah, I mean, with a $1 light bulb,
there's no way they can afford a security guy to vet the design.
I mean, I, I think best case scenario
will have sort of reference software
that they can use, you know, like probably Linux based
uh that's hopefully secure, but even if it is, you know, what about the updates,
what about the management piece?
You know,
companies are going to are going to want to put value add on
top of this and they're probably not going to do so securely.
So
I'm beginning to think at some fundamental level, the IOT cannot be truly secure,
at least for a few decades until,
you know, houses start burning down.
We get regulation
be secure.
Well, and here's the worst part, I was talking with somebody about this.
He's like, well regulation is the answer.
And I'm like, well, in theory, yes. But I'm like, what are we regulating?
He's like, what do you mean?
I'm like, well, you know, so this, this guy, uh,
works for the Canadian government and did some stuff with arms control.
So there, it's relatively simple, you know, this is a missile technology.
This is not a missile technology.
Well, except, you know,
what about the PS four or these accelerometers that go into smartphones or,
you know, all these other things, right?
And so he's like, ok, fair enough, you know, it's hard to regulate that stuff.
And I'm like, well, but with, you know,
with this software and stuff, how do we ha
we don't even know what to measure in security right now.
Like, how do we measure software security
defects per line of code?
I can't answer that, but we don't even really know that.
I mean, we, we kind of do but we don't have any hard numbers.
Well,
we don't even have a vocabulary or a proper
ontology that identifies all the types of flaws,
let alone measures them.
We, we do have CWE but it's not complete
and, and it's already huge.
Um So, you know, that's the thing.
First of all, we don't even have good ways to describe and measure this.
So let's assume for a moment we magically
find good ways to describe and measure this,
we then need the resources to do that, you know?
And obviously it's gonna have to be automated because there's so much code.
And even then,
so then let's say you find something that arbitrarily scores 5.0 out of 10.
Well, then what
do we ban it? Do we make them fix it? Do we put a tax on it?
I, I don't know.
Right.
Oh, my goodness. I wonder if this is how the discussions went
back when automobile safety
was becoming a thing
or a
various consumer product safety?
I would love, I should try to find some history, uh,
listeners if you know of any sort of good history about safety
and in kind of this topic, by all means, let us know because this is,
this is a fascinating thing to think about. I'm
part of me thinks
we're certainly not the first industry to have to think about this stuff.
And another part of me thinks this universe we exist
in today is unlike any that has come before us.
-- So
-- it's interesting, you mentioned that, uh, I,
I think a really sad example of this is, um,
the whole positive train control system that
has been deployed across a lot of Europe
and is being deployed across North America
and has been delayed. Right? They've said it's, it's expensive.
It takes too much time, blah, blah, blah.
And they're shooting,
I believe it is for 2018 to have this idea of what's called positive train control.
So the idea is that the train is under positive control.
So you don't get situations like that train going
into that train station at full speed and,
and, you know, destroying the place
in New Jersey.
Um, or like those, you know, trains that have taken bends too fast and, and derailed.
And
so it's,
you know, there's a situation where you have the technology, you,
you even have regulations saying you have to go do this soon
and it's
not happening terribly, you know, some would say it's not happening fast enough,
right?
Based on the fact that we still have these hor, you know,
horrifying accidents that are entirely preventable.
And that's a relatively well and I, when I use the word simple,
I'm making finger air quotes here,
you know, but that's a relatively simple security problem.
You know, at least they have defined the problem.
They've defined the solution, they've actually got a working solution.
They just now have to get it deployed.
You know, we're
in the software world where
that
we don't
know what
is
man.
And train signaling systems are a great example of safety systems that have,
you know, evolved over, over 100 years because like,
let's face it when you smash trains together, it's expensive.
-- But
-- I, I would also counter that with the fact that
anyone can understand
how trains work
and
the concept of crashing a train is bad
is crashing your computer bad is crashing your website bad.
And the there's no yes or no answer to that.
It could be bad depending upon what's going on.
Well, with the IOT, I mean, for example, if I crash your fridge,
does it then stop chilling your food and you lose all your food in the fridge.
You know that, that clearly is bad
in my case. No,
because
I will never buy, I say that
right. I, I have one in two years now, but I will never buy a fridge
that is connected to the internet because I don't
want it to be connected to the internet.
I, I would say the same thing about TV.
S but I'm rapidly approaching a point where I'm not sure I'll be able to buy a dumb TV
-- in my
-- TV is connected to my crappy guest network because it has Netflix on it
and I can watch it and I know it's a terrible mistake and I don't care because
the,
the convenience of having Netflix built into my
TV outweighs all of the potential security nightmares.
I can imagine. It doesn't have a microphone that I'm aware of.
So I have that going for me
and let's face it if somebody hacked my TV,
I, I can't imagine a scenario
that doesn't involve me just unplugging it, throwing it away and buying a new one.
Right.
Well, you know,
there was a real good comic talking about the um the evolution of ransomware and
essentially it showed a picture of a house with all the devices in the house.
You know, saying, for example, I'll make you a cup of coffee for 0.01 bitcoins
or I'll let you open the fridge for 0.01 bitcoins or, you know, I'll make toast. And
to me that's a really fascinating
possibility is, you know, what,
what do you do someday when your fridge says basically I've been hacked, you know,
deposit $5 or
I will do something bad. I mean, let's face it.
You can't get your fridge fixed for less than $5.
And, and that's kind of how ransomware works today.
It is in the best interest of the ransomware.
I,
I guess operators because I won't even say authors because like you
can buy these things and run them on your own now.
But it is in the best interest of the ransomware operators to
ensure that removing the ransomware legitimately
costs more than paying the ransom.
And I think we talked about this at some, some point in the past, but
it's man, everything is on fire literally in some cases.
So,
oh my goodness.
I,
that's all I can handle today.
Kurt, my, my brain doesn't wanna wanna deal with any more than that. So
I'm gonna tell
all of our fans out there that at all the show notes,
all the interesting things we've talked about as well as how to
contact us and tell Kurt all about the mistakes we made,
talking about prime numbers.
You can, you can catch that at open source security, podcast.com.
Hit us up on Twitter. Let us know what you think. We'd love to hear it. And
with, with that, let's, let's just climb back under our desks and,
and continue weeping on the current state of security.
Yeah, I'm gonna go buy some canned food.
That's right.
That's right. Do
the basement?
All right, folks have a great day until next time. Thanks for listening. Goodbye.
All.