Happy December 7th, Kurt. How's, how's your, how's your December going?
Uh,
knowing 2020 probably stuff is
on.
Say everything's great. Everything is great.
I'm actually,
I am actually putting a little skating rink in the backyard for my kids and myself.
Right on, man.
That's fun.
You kill
all the grass. You won't have to mow next year.
You know what? That's true.
-- Yeah, it'll all be dead.
-- It will all be dead.
I've done this before
-- anyway. Maybe I should just flood the entire backyard.
-- There you go.
And you'll just have weeds. It'll be perfect.
No.
Uh, green drop. They kill all the weeds.
I spent like last year
pulling all the weeds and then I hired green drop
and two sprays later. Boom. All the weeds are dead.
-- Better living through
-- chemistry. I don't want to talk about that.
-- So seven
-- is the best prime number.
And this is actually proven when you ask people to pick a number between one and 10,
-- they pretty much overwhelmingly pick
-- 77 is a lovely number.
I feel like it is the most real prime. But the, the real point.
Well, because you can't roll it on ad six. It's magic, it's secret.
That's true. You can't, you can't. But if you roll two it is the most likely number
two D six
s
-- correct. Because that bell curve.
-- That's right. Ok.
So the real purpose of this episode is just prime numbers. Why do we care?
What are they, we talk about?
People talk about prime numbers and security all the freaking time.
-- Yeah, because
-- crypto and Rs A and blah,
blah, blah.
That's true. Public key cryptography which, which may be behind a future door.
Yeah, prime numbers are a huge part of it.
Well, actually there's a number of, I mean, in math, in general,
prime numbers are often magic but the point
is prime numbers in crypto are hugely important.
And actually prime numbers on computers are one of those things that
they, it, it, it's become simple to us because we're very used to it.
But calculating large primes has historically been a very difficult problem.
Well, and here's what I love is zero prime.
Uh
No one isn't prime either, dude.
What about two?
Two is a prime number sort of, but it is the dumbest prime
two is prime but is it the dumbest prime is
three is unquestionably a prime number?
-- And
-- I like, like, I love that like 01 and two. It's kind of like
-- those
-- are 00 is not a prime number.
So I've, I watch a lot of math youtube zero is not prime one is,
most mathematicians will tell you it's not prime but there's some contention.
There
-- two is definitely prime. But it's dumb.
-- Google says it's not prime.
-- So it's not prime. Does
-- Google say two is prime.
Uh
-- Google says two is not prime.
-- It says it's not prime. OK.
There you go.
I'll take it. I'm not gonna complain.
So three is the first prime.
Pause.
It says two is prime.
Oh, ok. I thought so.
It's just the worst prime because it's even like
prime numbers shouldn't be even two is even,
you suck too.
I know when I, when I come up like that, you know, like it's like ends in 246805,
not prime except when it's a 24 or a five or
-- uh
-- whatever, whatever, whatever.
So what,
OK. So here's the deal and this is why prime numbers matter. OK?
Is because
when we have a number, let's say it's an odd number.
That was weird. You laughing was funny.
So
in math, right?
You can obviously multiply certain numbers together and come up with a new number.
Yes.
Yeah, that's kind of the point of math is adding
multiplying
multiplication is just fancy edition.
And the point is, is true
when you're doing your math, right? And let's say you have an even number and
you can divide it by multiple things.
Two being one of them and get whole numbers as the result, right?
-- Unless it's 22 can be divided by two. I
-- am so glad you can't hit me from out there.
Whatever. I don't care. It's all good. You're keeping me on my toes. So,
and in December 7th, after all right, the world may have ended by now.
-- It is,
-- oh, a day to remember. Right.
Right.
Yes. So anyway, the point is
prime numbers are incredibly important because what you end up
doing in cryptography is basically multiplying two prime numbers together,
-- two gigantic prime numbers
-- together.
Well, right. And the result you get
is a number that only has two possible solutions if you were to divide it out, right?
Being the one of the two prime numbers.
Whereas if you had a number that was two even numbers,
let's say multiplied together,
there's actually going to be more than
two possible solutions to that division problem.
Oh, pretty much
-- there's going to be potentially a lot,
-- probably seven or eight solutions or more.
It depends, right?
-- Some even like 12 is a great example where 12 has like six divisors.
-- Right.
-- Well, and that's why we use it for clocks and Sumerians. Right.
-- Exactly. Exactly.
-- That 60 is ridiculously dividable.
-- Yeah, exactly.
-- And so this is why prime numbers matter.
-- Oh my God.
-- Can you imagine a clock system based on prime numbers? Oh, sweet
-- Germany.
We should make one up. I feel like this has this has legs cart, we could do this
anyway, it has, it has no purpose. All right.
So the point is prime numbers seven is the best. And
in the universe of cryptography,
primes are hugely important and I would be shocked if
anyone can learn anything from the last five minutes.
Yeah.
-- Also three is a close, is a close second to seven
-- maybe. I mean, 123, more than three.
Exactly. Three is a good one.