Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and the guy staring at me, Josh Pressers.
I'm not looking at you. I was actually looking at my keyboard at that moment.
So, so for people listening, who have no idea,
Kurt and I use a service called Squad Casts to record the
podcast and it has the ability to look at each other,
which is nice for visual cues and things like that.
And when we started using squad casts, it would crash the web browsers, obviously,
meaning the web browsers probably had a security
vulnerability and rather than look into it,
we just turn the cameras off because that's way less work.
Right. Exactly.
But now it's working because I've been using it for
like the hacker history podcast and some work podcast stuff.
And I told Kurt one day, I'm like, hey, we can leave the cameras on if we want.
And so they're on and it like,
disturbs Kurt that apparently I'm staring at him
even though you know what's really funny,
I realized I look at myself, not you as I speak.
And that's very strange now that I think of it, but whatever.
So there you go. I'm not even looking at you. I have no idea.
You could pick your nose. No clue.
So, containers,
apparently there,
some guy actually wrote a reasonably interesting article about
sort of tech in the future in general.
But one of the predictions he sort of made was that containers were going to go away.
-- At least as I read it,
-- I did not read it that way. So, so even more background,
Kurt
sent me this article and I'll try to dig it up. We'll hold on the show notes
and it's basically like this post apocalyptic what TECA look like and
it has nothing to do with everyone murdering each other over food,
but rather tries to take some sort of attitude of like, well
post
apocalyptic programming.
So
what will be? Right. Right. Right.
Like what, basically 50 years from now,
like which languages are going to be still popular,
which runtime platforms kind of stuff like that.
And it takes into account.
I, like there was someone did a study that, like go or is it Rust?
I think Rust is the most efficient programming language and like
javascript is the least efficient from an electricity usage perspective.
And no one should be shocked by that in any way.
But,
but anyway, anyway, uh, Python sucks too just for all you Python nerds out there,
which it broke my heart.
Well, I, I suspect that it's
the amount of electricity used by the programming language
is also inversely correlated to sort of the productivity,
right?
So there's that classic study somebody did of like
essentially like how many lines of code does it take to implement X and like in Python
import foo and you're done, right?
Like you can, you can control the web browser in six lines of code.
And you know, obviously in C you're gonna need
probably more than six lines of code, maybe a few 100 or 1000 even, you know,
for a full web browser.
Like obviously I'm joking here, it's gonna be billions of lines of code.
Um And so I suspect obviously, well, like for
Python, it's doing a lot of stuff, it doesn't necessarily need to be doing,
it's maybe not necessarily doing it all that efficiently which like
in the modern world on a modern CPU with electricity being
-- priced up what it is kind of who cares,
-- right.
And look,
I think an interpreted language is always going
to be less efficient than a compiled language.
Like I think that's just the reality of it.
I think part of it is with compiled languages,
you only write what you need and you don't, you know, pull in
-- mass amounts of stuff.
-- Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
And in fact,
the compilers do this when you build like a go application go
only includes the crap you actually need to run the application.
It's not like where with, with no Js
you do an N PM install and you get 9000 packages and
you literally need six lines of code out of the 9000 packages.
But anyway, anyway. All right. All right.
So, so Kurt finds this article and it talks about containers towards the end and
it, it didn't say containers are bad. It said big fat containers are bad.
And then this also reminded me of,
we'll get to that, we'll get to that.
I'm
so
and
I've read a handful of things over the last probably year that
I think it's becoming hip to hate on big fat containers.
And oh, I'm gonna name this episode. Big Fat containers. I like that. But anyway,
it's become the hip thing
and
obviously working for a company that also does, you know,
supply chain management and vulnerability scanning of container images.
It it from uh
attack surface perspective, it just kind of makes sense because obviously
more crap equals more attack surface, right?
So well and not just attack surface but living off the land, right?
So as an attacker, once I get in, I oh I don't need to install like a web client.
There's already one here, there's, you know, all these other things
here that I I don't have to like,
you're not going to notice like a big
blob of binary data moving into your container because
you left me a full set of furniture already.
That's right. That's right.
So anyway, we,
we basically got to talking on signal and decided we should talk about containers.
And Kurt thought we should have a pro and anti container perspective
which,
well, not so much pro and anti container.
That's maybe it's, it's more of a debate, right?
So, like we'll just take opposing viewpoints and be contrarian to each other.
That, that's not unusual at all for us.
But
I, I, and I told Kurt that I'm pro reality, not pro or anti container in any way.
But, ok, so we kind of explained that
and
I think there's some added
interesting tidbits we can include in this that, that maybe not everyone knows.
So back in the early days, if you use containers,
you basically got a Linux distribution,
right?
Where you took a Linux distribution,
you kind of airlifted it into a container image and that's what we called
our base images and that was fine because you needed the C library,
you needed Python, you needed, you know,
Etsy password, all that crap.
-- Well, we also didn't know, what else would we have done?
-- Right. Right. No, I agree.
I agree.
I mean, it was basically, we pretended they were virtual machines in the early,
right?
We didn't pretend,
ok,
no offense, but
we basically just turned V MS into,
we stripped out the kernel
and we're like progress and, and to be fair, it was actual progress,
right?
And, and certain distro had five megabyte containers,
other distro had like 600 megabyte containers.
And
the world was simple.
And now we look at technologies like Go and Go is
one of the easiest where it is very common now to
build a Go application which ends up being a binary because
go statically compiles everything we like it just kitchen sinks,
your build
and then you have this binary
and depending upon what you're doing, you can often
run just the binary and you don't need
anything else in the distribution. And like an easy example is
Anc
Cor has these two open source tools called sift and Gripe.
If you look at the sift and gripe containers,
they're literally one go binary in each container.
So the containers are comically small obviously.
But it's also like this is what go does. So
when you think about containers like
imagining this world a
decade ago
was ridiculous, right? There would have been like no way
you can't run a binary in a container.
That's just, it's not, that's not practical and it turns out you can.
-- But
-- well, again, it's the ecosystem, right? It's
like I wrote, you know,
that cloud slide deck way back 10 plus
years ago about why didn't cloud happen sooner.
It's, you know, we didn't have software, we didn't have enough compute,
we didn't have enough bandwidth and reliable bandwidth
and going back to this like a good example of this is
like a red hat everything use or everything is
kind of supposed to use the system libraries.
So that like if there's a flaw on G zip, well, we updated the G zip dot
So and
-- like restart your server or restart the app G
-- zip is why they do that.
And so like,
and that's fine and dandy. But then obviously people build software and
you don't use the system library and they,
they compile stuff in like a go static binary.
And
well part of it is
people take for granted things like C I CD pipelines.
Like I remember when building software and getting it to run
like typing dot slash configure, make, make install or make test, make install,
you could do that twice
in the same directory on the same system and one
would work and the other time it would not work.
And like, you know, and you're running,
you know,
mem test 86 and like testing your memory to see because I once found I
had a bad stick of RA M because I couldn't compile a Linux kernel anymore.
Everything else worked.
But the compiling the Linux kernel used enough RA M and it, you know,
a bit flip mattered
that it
died.
I'll try to find this story.
But I remember I read a story one time about this person filed a bug
that they only had a problem with the
riser file system with memory corruption or something.
And it turned out like the riser file system was making their CPU overheat, like,
just a little bit more than anything else.
I had that happen when I upgraded from 4 to 8 megs of RA M on OS two,
my computer started overheating because the CPU could actually run
and ended up drilling holes in the case of
a fan of it,
you know.
Um, this was
a,
what was it? A 46
something like that.
Anyway.
Um, but anyway, so
part of it is like we used containers as a VM because
what else would we have done? Like we didn't have the tooling for it.
We didn't have the mindset or the culture for it.
And here's the other thing is,
is one of the reasons fat containers are so popular is because I build a fat container
and people install stuff and it just works and they don't complain about X missing.
Whereas if I build a skinny container now they have to install a whole bunch of stuff.
And
10 years ago that meant doing it by hand and it was a chore.
But now with the dependency chains or go well, it's easy
and, and people forget how far we've gone in the last 5, 10 years.
I mean, you know, you know what this reminds me of is I remember
when I worked at a company called Progeny Linux system,
we had this,
this tool that would build a Linux distribution,
right where it took like a pile of Debian packages
and it would wrap them all up and build the I
OS and all that crap and it only ran on one person's computer and no one knew why.
And, like, we had to ssh into their computer su to root
su to them
and then run the BUILD because there was like some magic
layout in their home directory that made it work. And it was, it was brilliant.
And, and although, oh, man, I remember, like, also I worked at a little ISP
and I worked at the CIS
man
and then he left
and the day they deleted his account,
the ISP went down because like all the scripts were running out of his own
factory,
not to segue.
But that's something we're seeing at the CS A like
we're moving into software as a service stuff and automations.
And so, for example, we have a system automation account
because like when you use Zap here,
it has to tie into a Google account to access Google files and stuff.
And I'm like,
this cannot be a person because they will either leave us or change jobs or whatever.
So like we have a scheduling account to hold calendars because if you've ever tried,
you can actually now transfer ownership of calendars and Google calendar.
But that wasn't possible like two years ago,
you know, so all these things where people are rediscovering that, yeah,
you need to use system accounts for this stuff because if
you tie it to a person and that person goes,
whoops,
that's a world of hurt. So,
-- just never delete their account. It's fine.
-- Yeah.
Well, and, but you also got to like up anyway, but back to this, like,
I think part of it is like, like installing all your dependencies once is,
that's pretty amazing to me.
Like you and I come from an era where we did that by hand, you know,
like where you'd literally try to compile something, it would fail.
You'd go install some library, edit your LD, preload, reload that. Ok.
Now we get one step further in the compile. Like literally, you remember doing this,
I do
six months later or a year later.
Of course, the compile fails because the,
the version you installed is now too old or incompatible or something.
You have to upgrade it manually.
Again, people just take, we have a lot of magic that just works now. And I think
obviously skinny containers can work.
Now,
they couldn't work in the past because if you gave
somebody a skinny container five or 10 years ago,
they would have had to spend three days
feeding it
literally feeding it software to make whatever work.
Absolutely.
And you'd have to create layouts like certain applications want slash dev,
slash whatever slash proc.
Well, I think slash
proc might be mounted, but you know what I mean?
Like there's all those weird things in a UNIX system you
don't always think about like this crap and slash Etsy or V
lib or whatever
you want. Sound
silly. You,
uh, I don't know if,
I
don't think the sound is mounted by default in containers. I know you can do it,
but
I
like, I remember. Yeah, anyways, uh,
part of it too is talking about this
original container technology is literally like talking about
horse buggies
and actually more people use horse buggies. Well,
some people are still using the original
container stuff because they have a system,
they've never upgraded and
-- like a horse bug is they're, they're choosing to live in the past
-- II.
I don't think that's
a, I don't think that's fair.
I think there are many people using containers in what we
call the traditional way where you take like a Debian base image
and then you layer your stuff on top.
I'm talking about people actually using like an implementation,
like they're still running a, a,
you know, a Red Hat Enterprise five or six box
with whatever old version of Docker. That's what I mean,
right. Where they, you know, they're just
choosing to stay old.
Um And then that's the other problem is like
once you get fat containers and stuff working,
yeah, why would you spend time on
making them thinner or like redoing it if it works
well versus
writing new features?
I agree with that. I think
it's easy for us to complain about legacy architecture, but you're right,
once something runs
dealing with that technical debt is a massive cost
center for literally zero gain in most instances.
I mean, there are times that
actually paying off technical debt
has a return on your investment but generally speaking, it doesn't.
And, and you're right, if I have a
and I think this is one of the kind of dangers of containers.
-- Oh, it
-- lets you hide so much technical debt,
right? You, you put it all in the container and everything's fine.
Oh, my operating system.
Yes, we upgraded to the latest version of redhead Enterprise Linux last week.
Oh, except your container is seven years old and no one's ever looked in it.
This leans itself though to, I, I have a funny story I can relate this to. So
historically,
no one was paying attention to any of this. I mean, obviously this is literally what a
cork does is we peer into your containers and tell you what's up.
But
I remember I, I worked for, we'll say my previous company we won't name names.
They were running these containers in some infrastructure
and one day basically we scanned it.
We were like, holy crap. This can't be right.
And like no one had updated the container in like five years now.
It wasn't like connected to the internet.
It wasn't doing, it was a very benign system,
but we're like,
who's responsible for this? Everyone's like, I don't know
-- they
-- did it
right.
And it was just this giant finger pointing in a circle eventually where it's like,
I don't even care like we just need to fix this.
Someone run freaking like
app
update on this thing and it'll be fine.
And that's literally all we did and it was fine.
But
it, it's, it's one of those things if you're not looking, I, I think,
I think developers found it as a way to escape responsibility
at, at certain points And that,
I
-- don't
-- know,
I don't agree with escape responsibility so much as
I'm not sure a lot of them are even aware of the responsibilities.
A
good example would be I have a Windows desktop windows 11
with the LINS subsystem for Linux
or the WSL
Windows
subsystem
and I have A
to LTs installed
and I on the regular run app, get update and upgrade.
Also. It does give you the N
screen when you log in.
But I'm guessing there's a good chunk of people that don't
probably not because again, unless you need to upgrade for something to work, like,
you know, why would you bother? Like, how many people
don't upgrade windows, let alone, you know,
some weird specific sub Linux subsystem thing, you know, and
yeah, they're developers and they should know this, but
they don't.
Most developers have never been operationally responsible
for something that has to run 24 7
and they will get woken up at three in the morning if it goes down
and that's the difference is you and I have and other people have.
And so as operations people are like, yeah, let's automate this.
Let's, you know, C I CD this, let's
all this because I don't want to get woken up at 3 a.m. That's
one of the reasons I'm a big proponent of cloud service is because like,
like I remember literally, I was like sitting on the can reading my feed le
and feed le stopped working. It wouldn't let me say bookmarks.
I'm like, what the heck? Ok. That's weird.
And then, like, I get an alert that the cloud security lines website is down.
I'm like, oh damn it,
you know, and then my website's down, I'm like, what?
And then finally I twig and I'm like, oh, cloud flares down and it was, you know,
they were down for like 45 minutes and it's like, cool.
I'm gonna go do a Sudoku because like, I can't fix this. It's not my problem.
That's true. That's true.
You know, I was actually, I,
I ran into this this weekend in fact where I have a big fat virtual machine
thing in the basement, right? It runs Debian
because Debian's nice and slow and I like that.
And I have, I think like 12 V MS running in it, right?
Everything from my plex server to my elastic search cluster to
my like little machine I ssh into and do weird stuff on
and
I was thinking on Saturday because it's the long week, it was the long weekend,
the Memorial Day weekend in the US.
And I thought on Saturday, oh, I should upgrade Debian
because I'm a version behind.
And then I thought, wait a minute
in order for me to do this,
I have to shut down all 12 V MS upgrade that system reboot that system
and, you know, all 12 V MS are not going to come back up.
One or more of them will fail for some insane reason
or worse. They won't fail. They just won't work quite right.
-- And it might take a while to notice.
-- That's right. And so I did nothing.
And the reality is this system only has an SSH port open to the world.
Even if the software is a little old,
it's very low risk. It's running in my house like
it can wait a while. I'm in no rush here.
Well, and this leads to something I was gonna say earlier, which is one of,
I think the better ways to deal with technical debt is if
either you're mature enough to actually understand your technical debt,
but in most cases you're not,
you just let it pile up until you rip it out and replace it.
-- That's right.
-- Exactly.
You know, like Africa skipping straight to cell phone towers and cells and like,
not doing landlines.
It totally makes sense.
You know, I, I agree and, and I think about that all the time is
in the vast majority of environments. When you have technical debt.
If you wait long enough, you just kill the whole thing and all the debts gone
-- well,
-- or even better yet, you like in some cases,
you can just buy some new product that does it so much better
or that actual kind of business process or function can be
maybe completely outsourced or some,
you can do something a bit more clever, like as a solution, right? Where
you just,
oh, great example.
Um, at the CS A, apparently we have two fax services we're using,
there's one official one and I mean, like, I love the one quote was like, oh, yeah.
-- Yeah, we did, we wait,
-- did you say fax? Like sending paper?
Yeah, we did, we did get a fax like two months ago on it.
Well, we deal with Asia pack and stuff, right? And the fax is still a thing in Japan and
whatever, right?
And for what it costs, it's just
if, if somebody wants to fax you,
they don't have an alternative
otherwise they wouldn't be offering to fax you, they would have sent you an email.
-- You should
-- send me your fax number. I'll send you fax.
I have actually no idea what it is, but that's the point, right?
If somebody has to fax us, they have to fax us like they
literally, if they could email us,
they would have just emailed us and never mentioned faxing.
That's,
that's
right.
And so, but, and that's an example of like,
I love how people still use faxing even though the majority
faxing now is you send a fax to a phone number
and it turns it into a PDF and sends it via email to somebody.
And it's like, why,
why don't we just skip that step in the middle and just send the PDF.
In fact, I had to use a fax to send something to my bank.
This is probably was when I, when I got my mortgage on my current house, which is,
I think 10 years ago now I had to fax them and
I used an email fax service and they got an email.
I'm like, so wait a minute. So I,
I emailed this PDF, it turns into a fax,
it sends your service and then you get a PDF in your email.
And the lady was like, yep,
I said, that's ridiculous. She goes, yep.
Well, and the thing is that, but they have the workflow set up and built.
Yeah. Right.
And there were some legal things, I think,
I don't think email signatures for whatever particular thing I was,
it was some weird historic property thing.
Well, there's a lot of case law
about wet signatures which has been sort of transferred to faxes,
which,
you know, and now we're getting to the point where docusign and stuff is fine. Like,
you know, everybody's using docusign and sign now and
panda sign. And
so I was just looking at some alternatives.
Um,
-- we're talking about containers but
-- back
-- to
-- containers. So I think
part of it is,
it's again, not so much that the devs are trying to escape responsibility. It's that
it's like buying somebody a puppy
and thinking that's a good idea.
Like
I,
so many
times I have talked with people and pointed out
that if you give somebody a living thing,
you're not giving them a gift, you're giving them an obligation.
And I think that's part of what's with
software that you deploy operationally. If you care about it enough,
you, you are somewhat responsible for it and if you don't care about it,
then why are you even running it?
Right. Like, just turn it off.
No. Really? Right.
Like either you need it or you don't and if you don't need it,
turn it off and if you do need it, well,
-- do something with it
-- or secret option c install it and never look at it again.
Well, and, and
you can do that with software. You can, you should not do that with a puppy
or plants. Um,
you
can
said plants, you totally can ignore puppies, not so much, they leave your
house.
But, um, and I think that's part of it is,
a lot of people don't understand that operational side.
And part of the challenge is by doing DEV
ops and now I've heard it called everything ops where, you know,
we have people at the CS, a building stuff, an air table
and like building good stuff,
but like, kind of, yeah, who's operationally responsible for it?
Like, that's literally the answer is,
and so I'm looking like, who's responsible for the security of it.
Well, and I've been looking and it's like, I, I,
we don't have any security visibility or real controls. Like,
you know, as we all learned from that recent github
Hiku thing, like that's just a giant mess. And
Hiroko's emailed us a couple of times to say, uh,
we're pretty sure your account wasn't broken into
the attacker, did look at your organization name but probably didn't break in.
But we're going to make you change all your passwords anyways.
Like, so we did that and, you know, we've rotated all our tokens and our passwords
and actually, ah, their,
their update on that is supposed to drop yesterday or today actually,
now that I think about it.
But long story short, like we're using Hiroko
and it's like, well, maybe we got hacked, maybe we didn't,
we have no freaking clue unless they tell us.
And
this is going to become more and more common as people. Like we use a great example.
We use grammarly, right? Write more English good better.
Right.
Well, in theory, if somebody breaks into our grammarly, couldn't,
they see a lot of documents,
I assume so.
Right. Because there's that web plug in that.
Right. It uploads everything. I can only imagine the purpose of content they have.
Exactly. So, like,
I have no idea if our accounts have been broken into or
not or if somebody's in there or like some Russian IP,
addresses, accessing them.
Yep.
No clue.
And so this is something I'm starting to look at, at the CS A, you know, it was like, ok,
we're probably gonna have to stop ignoring this at some point.
Well, I mean, that's where we are with containers is we ignored it for a long time.
And now we have companies like
Encor.
Yeah. Right. Right. Well, and, and look, I, I
don't want to
sound like I'm berating people for ignoring their containers because
it's not that we kind of did it on purpose.
It's just this is the, the ebb and flow of technology, right?
Where we get a new thing, we start using a new thing
and then we're finally like, ok,
we have to actually start taking care of this new thing
and that's kind of the point we've reached where now,
I mean, this is even true of just using open source in general, right?
Where everyone thought it was a free for all. And now we're like, wait a minute,
we have to actually pay attention to what we have.
Let's create some sort of inventories that we can
then query and understand and we can actually start making
like real business decisions based on, you know,
risk input and how much it costs and what we're doing.
And this is just an important part of the game and, and we've reached that point.
It's a maturity, right?
Like containers are coming of age and they're, they're,
I don't know how old are they, they can probably drink in the US now.
Like they've got to be 20 years old.
I mean, it would depend on exactly how you define containers.
I mean, if you want to talk containers, sort of what about C A root in jail in free BS D?
I'm, I'm comfortable saying like the docker containers.
I think all that other crap was nonsense and to
-- root isn't a security, it's
-- not a security control.
It isn't.
I wrote an article about this explaining all the ways
you can like break out of that at one point.
And
anyway,
I would say actually interestingly my definition
of what containers are in the modern world
is less about the container technology and more about
the compos ability and the tools to build them.
I agree
with that.
I would say that that because that's honestly, that's kind of what matters.
Like, like running virtualization
and machines and stuff is actually hell, we've been doing that for 20 plus years,
but building a VM building a good container, building a thing like that,
that has been a nightmare up until recently.
Uh Yes. Yes. And in fact,
I remember
Red Hat created openshift.
I think
it might have been a writer when Docker became a thing or slightly before
and Red Hat lacked the compos ability, aspect of it.
Whereas Docker had that compos ability and I think is what really
pushed it to the front was the fact that you can very,
very easily in a very descriptive simple file.
Say
I need Debian put this crap over here
like
this.
Stick on my
QL
in on port 33 06 and Apache on 80.
Expose it on 81 or whatever
and you know, stick my rails, run time over here. Yeah.
No, that's, that's basically,
yeah, like it's,
that's the thing I looking at cloud kind of why this stuff didn't happen sooner is OK.
Great. I have like Amazon E two.
How do I use it?
Well,
the only way to use it was spin up a VM and like use it
like you would a physical system and so hence forklift stuff into the cloud.
Because
what choice do we have?
Do you remember in the early days with like,
I'll pick on redhead again where there was,
it was uh anaconda was the installer
and you would create this thing called a kickstart file, which
you would,
you would basically all those questions you answer on install the
kickstart file is just the answer to all the questions.
And then you would use that
like your auto
install on a real computer
and it was like,
-- and
-- that was super progress.
If you had like five or 10 systems that were identical to do.
Yeah.
You, you did a manual install one and then replicated it and that,
that was actually real progress.
Yeah.
Yeah, because I mean, if you were a windows admin,
you had to click like 100 and 70 times to install windows and us, us UNIX people.
Windows actually had automated install tools and
the slipstream stuff for quite a while.
The problem is a, nobody knew about it. And B
it was actually quite
complicated to get right. Like slip stream allows you to
have a gold image that's completely up to date with apps and stuff installed.
I
it's one of those things, if you know how to do it, it's not that hard,
-- but you don't even know it exists. So good
-- luck
right now. This is literally the first time I've ever heard anyone use that name
in reference to Windows,
which
that, that was like, that was the thing though.
When you were a Linux admin is you could install 700 machines in an hour and look at me.
I'm awesome.
It was, yeah, you had like a, well, a CD
you
would put
in.
Yeah. Slipstream has been around for more than a decade,
two decades, maybe now.
Exactly.
Yeah. Well, unless you're a windows,
why the heck would you know,
even the Windows Edmunds I knew, didn't know
they don't,
it's not like this stuff is, yeah,
like these are master
level tools like this implies a level of mastery and understanding the system,
you know,
which
also
need to
admins weren't that
well.
You know, I remember Windows small business server,
which the whole premise was you had
one machine running Windows small business server.
That's it.
And,
and that's like what 90% of small medium businesses
needed back in the day in the early aughts.
So you needed to run your own email server,
your own email. It was actually really sweet.
It had your web server, your uh your web server for serving web,
your web proxy for outgoing stuff, your email server, your file share, your print
everything all in one ball. It was actually a really nice product
in, in, at that time. Now it
-- no,
-- then code red happened
amongst others
because no one had ever installed a single security update on those systems.
-- Well, no, no, no code red was just the default password
-- was which one was the, the,
the IAS worm?
I thought that was code red.
Code
red. I thought code red was the my SQL one.
-- No
-- slammer was the sequel one,
right? Slam.
So I'm thinking slammer.
Look at you and your old man
was the IIS worm. Slammer was the my
QL one
-- man. I remember those. I
-- remember in my defense it's been over 20 years.
Uh It was 2000 and one
code red was 2001.
I, I thought it was funny. I was the UNIX admin in a window shop when that hit.
And I basically just sat in the corner and laughed at them for a week
and I was extremely smug,
we'll say, and not at all nice.
And
in 2003,
and now it's inconceivable that we would
stick stuff online without passwords publicly available.
But,
-- hey, that's how we used to roll.
-- Don't say that that happens all the time. You need to.
There's, there's a guy,
uh, Bob
Deco, I think his name is. I'll, I'll put a link to his Twitter.
Well, no, no, no, but we don't do it as commonly now. Like, it's still,
-- it's like Microsoft isn't like Red Hat's not doing it, you know?
-- That's true.
That's true. But, yeah, Bob does crazy research where he looks for wide open, like,
basis on the internet and like at least once a week.
He's like, oh, I just found 7 million
pi I entries in this open database.
-- Like, oh my goodness,
-- once a long time ago, scanned an IP range.
You know, my local government, they had two DNS servers,
one IP apart on the same subnet,
they had um some real interesting reverse D
oh, the other thing was reverse DNS, right? Like oracle internal database.gov,
basically with an open port. And it was like,
uh
I'm not even going near that system
but uh
no, I think
the, the funny thing to me is that
what fundamentally happens is
you can basically compose software, one of two ways, one,
you can compose the software.
So it's kind of lean and has external dependencies like system libraries
or
you can basically go for,
I'm going to call it a static binary and I don't just mean like a static binary,
like go does but like a container as a static binary where it just
like I get that technically, it's got system libraries in there,
but they're not meant to ever be touched or updated.
It's like I got this working, don't touch it.
And I think that's, that's what's interesting to me because obviously, if you,
if you have a piece of software that relies on dependencies that can
be updated live and then like the software either restarted or it just
reloads the dependencies.
Obviously that introduces risk of you update something and it breaks
versus
you have this idea of like I give you a blob,
you run the blob until I ship you a newer blob and then you
replace blob A with blob B which is newer.
No, I, I agree. And, and I guess we'll just kind of wrap this one up.
-- But the
-- point is we have tools to do that now we didn't use to.
-- Exactly.
-- And that I think is where the fat containers and stuff come in.
And I suspect that will be more the model moving forward because
I can test it. Like I can hand you a container and say this works.
Not like this probably will work, but like
you turn this on and you'll get stuff off. Port 80.
Right.
Well, and I, I think it's,
it's all of that put together. Right. It's all the c I, it's all the testing.
It's the unit testing. It's the functional testing.
-- It's, it's the smoke test you
-- have, it's things like let's encrypt,
I can ship you a
container
that you turn on and it will go magically get a certificate based on reverse DNS.
That's right. That's right. And then,
but even beyond that now, thanks to technologies like cloud and Kubernetes,
we have the ability to say how many containers are we running?
What is in our containers? You can inspect them.
You can say like when was the last time this container was updated?
How many vulnerabilities does this container have?
How many packages does this container have? And you can gain all this insight.
Now, I will say
actually doing something with this data is still like it,
everyone's working on that.
It's not like don't feel bad if you're, you're not necessarily making, you know,
like decisions based off it all because that is hard.
But I think we're approaching the point where we can
now start looking at all of this stuff in aggregate.
And we can say, OK,
like these containers are really old, this system's really old.
No one's working on this. Like we can say, why is this happening?
Is, should we get rid of it? Is it in use? Is it mission critical?
I mean, if you have a mission critical system that hasn't been updated in two years,
like
I don't think, why is that?
You know,
and we can start asking questions and we can start getting intelligent answers,
which I absolutely love.
So, I, I mean, from my perspective,
I think it's not about like fat or thin containers.
I think it's about all this other stuff around them.
Yet we focus on what's in the container when the reality is.
I think that's far less important than just
having all this other process and understanding.
Well, one thing to add to that, it's not just about making informed decisions,
but it's about making informed decisions and then being able to sell them.
Yeah, that's true.
And if you have some data,
you're gonna have a better chance.
And I think that's one of the critical things. Right? Because
I always love all these,
basically every single one of these security discussions boils down to
and so I need some resources to do X.
Right. Right. Because otherwise, like, I wouldn't care.
It's like if you can just fix it in five minutes without extra resourcing, just
like you're not going to talk to your manager, you're just gonna go fix it.
But every single one of these
evolves into that I need
resources to fix this.
And also there's potential risk of like breaking stuff down,
time users being unhappy, whatever, which is a form of resourcing, right?
Like losing access to the resource or whatever
and having this data
obviously,
like,
I love that so many security discussions boil down to
you should do the security thing. Why? Because you'll be more secure,
will you?
Well,
yeah, and, and assuming, OK, first of all, let's,
let's just assume you actually will be more secure somehow.
But then the question is like,
does it matter? And so I actually just had this discussion with somebody who
has now become the target for like some fishing attacks and spear fishing attacks.
And I'm like, whoa, you know, I'm like, I'm like, do you need, do you want some help,
like, with your kind of it?
Like this person's pretty savvy. So I'm not very worried about them.
And he's like, oh, I actually just ordered a up key and everything.
I'm like, oh, good.
Ok, because I was like, you know,
you got to turn on your two fa but like real two fa not that S MS crap.
And it's like I ordered a UBK and I'm like, good,
but you should probably get two in case you lose one.
So you don't have to,
don't have a spare tire, right?
And he's like, oh, yeah. Ok. I hadn't thought of that.
And I'm like, yeah, um, apart from that. It sounds like you're good though.
But for most people, why should I do this? Because you'll be more secure.
That's not an answer.
No, no, it's sort of that. So, actually, you know, I, I'll put a link in the show notes.
The Yahoo
paranoids just came up with the new podcast and I just
started listening to it yesterday at the time of recording,
I listened to the second episode this morning on my bike ride.
And
in the first episode,
they, they are, they call the head chief paranoid or something like that.
It's, it's got like the co equivalent.
And
there's two things they talked about that I really liked. The first is
every decision they make is made with data where they're
collecting information and they have the ability to say like,
if we do this
thing,
I
-- shouldn't it be how we make all decisions in life?
-- I agree.
However, we know it's not and you just keep laughing.
But then the second thing they said is they don't tell you
what, like what risk is acceptable.
They can explain to you what the risk means,
but it is up to the business to make the decision of,
do I accept this risk or do I do something to reduce the risk?
And like,
I think that's something a lot of security teams often miss is
our job isn't to tell people what their risk should be.
Our job is to help them make informed
decisions about risk and then help them implement
whatever
controls or policies or whatever it is
to reduce that risk.
I would say one caveat is when you have
regulations that require certain behaviors or risk management,
that's totally different though.
And I, or I guess what I'm trying to say is my one caveat being is there's,
I would have a concern where the business isn't mature enough to do the
risk and the security people are a bit more mature and they just,
you know, and, but that's more of a cultural slash political level problem.
But again, if you have data and you can show the business, like, look,
you're ignoring all this risk that could result in a giant GDPR fine.
And that's the thing, right?
If I show up and say, oh, if you don't use two factor
off,
you could get hacked. They're like,
well, what does that mean? I'm like, well, you could get hacked,
you know, like that's not,
that's not an outcome.
Whereas you can say if we get breached, this is how much a breach will cost
if we spend
$1000 on yi
keys. Like this is what we can avoid.
Now we're talking about,
you know, numbers and something human can understand.
But all right, anyway, I'm going to call this one.
It was, this was, this was good big fat containers. I love it all. Anyway.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up the show, not, it's Suzy Pound
O
Podcast. Hashtag You hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the.