Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my pertinent thought crime, Josh Bresser.
-- So
-- we have murder bees. Now that's no
murder hornets,
murder bees in the eighties. Remember?
No dude.
I remember watching the CBS evening news and
they had like that graphic on the screen with
like North and South America with like showing where
the bees were in South America and that,
you know,
they'd kind of steadily march up the Rio Grande or whatever to the South
US and then eventually pop out kind of in the midline us because,
you know, thank God for winter.
-- Those weren't murder bees. Those are killer
-- bees.
Yes. Africanized honey bees because we thought that was a good idea.
-- But
-- everything's a good idea, especially with bees or stinging insects.
Yeah.
But I love the fact that, I mean, for, you know, when they said it was murder hornets,
I'm like, oh, that's a little bit, you know,
and then they showed a picture of the size of it and I'm like, no,
that is actually entirely correct.
These things are two inches long. They're bigger than a quarter.
Like they're bigger than a Canadian or us quarter like
that.
That's just not right.
-- So,
-- strangely enough,
I know a lot about these hornets because I became extremely interested
in them a long time ago because of an oatmeal comic.
I'll try to find a link to the comic. It's very good.
But the thing that makes them amazing
in a bad way is
in, they're from Japan
and in Japan,
their honey bees have a defense mechanism to kill these hornets because
the honey bees die at
a temperature like 10 degrees above the temperature of the hornets die at.
So the honey bees create like a ball around a hornet and then they
start vibrating and heating themselves up until the hornet cooks itself to death.
But most of the honey bees survive like it is bananas. What happens here?
You know what my favorite animal adaptation is wombats. They have square poo.
Why do they have square poo? So it doesn't roll or fall?
So they mark their territory by making little square poops to mark their territory.
How on earth evolutionarily speaking, how do you get to that point?
When I learned that
-- I thought the person who told it to me was trolling
-- me. Me too. Me too.
I like, I like check Wikipedia and I'm like, OK, somebody hacked Wikipedia.
Let's, you know,
like I found reputable, you know, zoological papers. Yeah. No, it's true.
Like square poop, square ish poop, not perfectly cubed.
-- Obviously that would hurt
-- either way, whatever,
whatever animals in nature are ridiculous.
Like, I mean, it's one thing to pee on stuff,
like dogs pee on stuff constantly to mark.
-- That's not very kind of like, ok, whatever, but like square poop man like that.
-- Just
everything in Australia has dialed it up to an 11.
Everything
that voice
is bananas actually, you know, it's really interesting.
So there something due to the, my reading about murder bees,
I'm going to keep calling it murder bees.
I don't care if it's wrong.
But reading about murder bees, one of the topics that came up was there is a Peppa pig.
Peppa pig is a children's cartoon, a Peppa pig episode about spiders.
That's like, oh, you shouldn't be afraid of spiders.
And in Australia they banned it because in
Australia you definitely should be afraid of spiders.
I was actually wrong the other day.
I told my son there's no poisonous spiders in Canada and then I was like,
wait a second and I double checked on that.
There are now in Ontario, black widows and whatnot.
That's fair. Fortunately, we only have one kind of venomous snake in
Al in Canada and it's so it's pretty rare. You'd have to go looking for it.
I mean, generally speaking where we live,
-- most animals and insects aren't going to kill us.
-- We have coyotes.
-- How many human deaths are there due to coyotes per year?
-- Oh, very few.
But people have been attacked.
My favorite was when they had like a lynx or something.
You know, we've told this story before, but they had this lynx and the guy was like,
no, no, no, it's ok.
I was like 30 ft away from it and I'm like, dude,
a house cat can mess you up from 30 ft away before you can blink like a lynx.
-- 50 pounds of angry murder meat.
-- They could get angry. I suppose
they're not like bears.
-- Friendly bears a
-- well, I mean,
-- we've got those cinnamon bears now which there's
-- nice bears and mean bears,
friendly bears.
-- Happy bears.
-- You're forgetting about polar bears, which are an apex predator.
Actually, I have another wonderful thing.
So when I was a kid there was this zoo we used to go to
and I'm going to use the word zoo with a lot of poetic license here.
Those us animal.
Yeah, it's pretty clear to me now as an adult, it was really not a zoo,
but they had a bear in a cage and you could buy soda,
which was just like sugar water in a bottle
and you could feed the bear soda through the cage.
You like stuck the bottle through a hole in the cage.
That's the most American thing I've ever heard.
-- Yeah, it kind of is in hindsight, poor
-- bear probably had diabetes.
-- Whatever
-- man, that bear was probably living the best bear life ever. It died happy.
I'm sure it got really good at, like,
you'd stick the bottle through and it would grab onto the bottle so you couldn't
pull it back out and then it would drink all of it and then,
like, go like that bear, it knew it was up.
Anyway.
Anyway,
we're going to talk about software
updates today because that's less horrifying than
murder.
I
-- think we'll get to the horrifying part.
-- I
think we will too.
So, like to be clear, I am not against software updates.
-- I'm,
-- I'm just going to be against them because I can.
Yeah, that's fair.
What gets me about software updates is, you know, on the one hand,
like everybody on the planet,
I want my system to be 100% stable and just perfectly work all the time.
But I also want all the new features
-- also
-- true
-- and all the bugs also true and all the security flaws and everything fixed
also true. All those things are,
you know, without impacting stability or making me do much work. Exactly.
So can I please have, you know what my cake and eat it and sell it to somebody else?
Of course, it'll be fine. Yeah.
And so I think one of the biggest problems here is traditionally,
we haven't really made a strong distinction between different
kinds of computing systems because we didn't really have different
kinds of computing systems up until a decade or
-- two ago
-- before we go down this rat hole.
Why are we talking about software updates
today?
Oh,
Buntu
released a new version 20.04. It's a long term support version. What is it?
-- Every two versions? 1416 1820.
-- If you don't know the
ubuntu support model, go look it up and then come back.
-- It's too complicated and weird to explain.
-- Right. Anyways.
So it's a long term support version.
That means it'll, you can run it for many, many years.
Hopefully it'll be boring and just work and sort
of two things they're doing that are really annoying.
People are number one, they're using this software packaging called Snap.
Well, those aren't new. No, it's not new, but they're more heavily
relying on it.
-- That's fair related to this is they're going to a forced update
-- model,
which is kind of new.
And so what that means is you install your snaps and nearly everything is a snap.
Now, a great example is Google Chrome,
I believe is only available as a snap in the new version of
ubuntu, I install Google Chrome, I get it as their snap.
And then I basically, it's going to be magically upgraded whether I want it to or not.
Obviously, in the case of Google Chrome,
I want it to be updated. So I won't complain very much.
But there are always things on a lytic system where you
don't want to install an update because something stupid breaks.
And
-- that is its own weird problem
-- right there.
You stated the problem without realizing it on a Linux system.
-- Can you define a Linux system? For me?
-- Everything is a Linux system now, right?
But I mean, there's a big difference between, you know, a desktop Linux system,
a server, Linux system,
a routing server and my light bulbs which are I'm guessing running Linux
everything does. I mean, and that's a really good point.
And so this is, it's funny you bring this up. This was a conversation.
I remember I had a long time ago with some developers from the Ganon
project because they were all about, oh, we should force updates on people.
And I was like, I don't think that's a good idea.
And after a lot of beers and a lot of talking,
we realized that a desktop for people is a very different story than
a server and like a server should never ever automatically install updates.
Whereas a desktop you're probably
OK there.
-- So
-- again, this, this goes to sort of history and how things have changed in the past
a computer that was a desktop.
Definitely somebody had physical access to it and could like repower it or
troubleshoot it or otherwise interact with it face to face as it were.
Sure that's still mostly true.
I mean, there are virtual desktops and that is taking off,
especially with the whole everybody working from home thing using
their insecure gaming pcs to access back end offices with virtual
desktop environments,
we get to that sort of server style usage of the computer where for example,
I as the user, I can't turn it off and on.
-- I don't have that level of access,
-- but you probably don't need to.
So what I'm trying to get at is is when my desktop computer does something goofy,
I can physically interact with it and try and kind of fix it or troubleshoot it.
Whereas if a server dies and you can't ssh into it. Great.
I hope somebody has keys to that room in a car, time to go find it.
-- It's all in the cloud now. It's fine.
-- Hopefully.
And so I think that's one of the big things is we need to make a distinction between,
there are systems that you cannot just randomly reboot because
if you do that people will die medical systems.
I remember having this discussion. Do you remember?
Oh, jeez, this is going way back. I just call him by his first name. I think it was Dave.
Remember he worked at the University of Washington and he did a lot of the
early work on distributed denial of service
attacks and at the University of Washington.
And the problem was I was like, well, ok, cool.
Like, so you have these computers that, you know,
are infected with malware and bots and stuff doing D
DOS attacks, tell
people to go fix them or boot them off the network.
And he's like, yeah, I can't, it's an MRI machine, right.
You know, and I was like, oh, well, ok. Yeah. Don't boot that off the network.
Well, why don't you figure out what it is and boot it?
And he's like, because we can't, half the time we don't know what it is like, you know,
to trace it down and figure out what it
is and if it's life critical or safety critical,
you know what if it's the PC controlling your elevators,
you're I think conflating a bunch of different things.
Let's ignore that problem. For now, MRI machines, let's focus on
TU specifically because we're going to see two big you
cases, there's a desktop and there's a server and when you're using a desktop,
do we think automatic updates are acceptable to be just like magically installed?
And the user can't say don't install this update right now.
I think that should be up to the user.
I mean, now here's my comment, I'm going to say by default,
we should have automatic updates on desktops and the user
or the rather I should say not the user,
the administrator of that system should be allowed to control them.
-- But
-- what happens with the administrator is my parents.
That's why you default to them being on and if they
don't know what they're doing and they don't touch anything,
then it just automatically updates.
I agree with that.
Now, the funny thing about that is Windows does that and you can, for example,
Windows will pop up the box and say, oh, I need to install updates.
Should I do it now or? Wait?
-- You can click. Everyone. Always clicks. Wait,
-- I like that. It's gotten smarter.
It's, well, at least on the Macs they've gotten smarter.
It's basically do it in an hour, do it tonight or later.
-- And I think that's a much better solution.
-- Windows can do that now too. Oh, it does.
Ok. Yeah. Well, but that didn't at first.
And so it was always,
I remember I was at a conference one time and the
presenter opens up your computer and Windows is like f you,
I'm updating now.
Well, this is neat. And
then of course,
the presenter had to get a new computer and shuffle it all around and everything.
But it's like the perfect example of why forcing things
on people without giving them the ability to be,
like, hang on there for a minute is hilariously bad.
Yeah.
I mean,
and even a regular desktop computer for all we know somebody's
to be using it to deal with some sort of time,
critical, sensitive problem.
Probably not going to result in loss of human life.
But, you know, could be very uncomfortable and awkward for all concerns.
There's a possibility.
But I think bringing that into the conversation
changes the conversation in a way that's unhelpful.
Let's talk about servers.
If you have a server that's automatically installing updates. Yeah, don't do that.
It really depends on its own because some, here's the thing you've got to remember.
There are different kinds of software.
For example, there's software that, well,
a great example being the old Inet D right, you connect into a machine
in NE D, fires off telnet or SSH or something to service your connection,
your connection is serviced, it goes away.
And so for example, there, if you do an update of the software,
you change the bits on the disk.
The next time that server is
that service rather is run, it gets the newest version.
Now, for example, a web server like Apache,
you can't just change the bits on the disk
and the version running sort of magically updates itself.
You have to restart that server.
And that's a big problem is the vast majority of services
now are not run from like an ID style configuration.
They're run like as a background service, you have to restart the service
and
that at a minimum gives you
a
small interruption.
Now, if you engineer your systems correctly, you know,
you have multiple back ends and you do a rolling reboot, nobody will ever notice,
right.
But the problem is that also assumes that that
restart will work and they don't always work.
Ignoring the problem of restarting the service.
It's super common for Linux distributions these days to add features or
they break something.
There's a new configuration option like, especially, I mean, I would,
I would consider Ubuntu more on the bleeding edge side of things.
There's things like, you know, Cento S and Red Hat Enterprise,
Linux that are definitely more conservative
and those are substantially more trustworthy.
Even Debbie and stable honestly falls into that camp where I can't think of the last
time I did an update on a Debbie and Stable machine and had anything go wrong.
Whereas Fedora
Unamuno, every time I run an update, it's like,
I wonder what's going to break now
pretty much.
And, and then that speaks to the, again, giving the user control of,
I want to update 1% of my machines.
See what happens.
Then I'll try 10% see what happens and then maybe do the other, you know, 39%.
So that gets me to half are updated and then do 50%. I want to have some control over it.
Not.
Oh, well, it's, you know, it's Microsoft patch, Tuesday,
everything gets reboot it and forcibly updated.
Now, whether I like it or not, in the case of ubuntu, it's,
I think there has like a two month time out at which point at the end of two months,
it forcibly does the update.
And so here's what makes the ubuntu problem and
I'll call it a problem more interesting as well.
Is there is a blog post that's going to be in the show notes and I'll even,
I'll specifically link to the forum
where the person who wrote the blog post kind of
submitted a question to the forum and was saying,
you know, hey, I don't like this.
What's up? And the
Ubuntu people were surprisingly unsympathetic.
-- I would say as to this,
-- literally, their tone was well, we discussed this and we
to do X right to put it bluntly within their context, their framework,
their reality.
Yeah, I can see why they would say that and do that.
But
yeah, for them,
here's what frustrates me is that they are taking
away control of the system from the user.
And this is something, for example, people complain about with mobile devices,
right?
I can't make my phone do XY or Z I mean we have a show about
this where you know the apple walled garden consists of like look at the flowers,
smell, the flowers, do not touch the flowers, you know,
you get shot in the stomach and that's your warning shot.
Well,
and like so this has been one of my complaints for a long time is I feel like Ubuntu
has been jealous of Apple in trying to mimic a lot of their,
-- well,
-- they're really chasing this desktop market heavily,
which I get it because that's sort of the visible Linux market.
I mean, you and I, you know, let's face it, right.
I've been using Linux on and off the desktop for, well,
I tried starting 25 years ago and I literally would set aside two weeks every
summer where I would force myself to put the latest version of whatever cool.
Linux was on my desktop and force myself to
get it up and running and totally perfectly running,
you know, for two weeks,
you know, so that way you get all the little glitchy things like, oh, you know,
I also need this file supporter.
Oh, I forgot that I need to do this or whatever.
I did run Linux on the desktop for a number of years. And then honestly,
Windows stopped sucking, basically run Windows seven. I was like, you know what?
This is good enough. It drives eight monitors, sound works, everything just works.
I have virtual machines and then, you know, then I moved to Max
and I gave up, I'm,
I'm still a believer. I run Linux on my desktop every day.
Well, technically I have chromebooks now.
So I, you know, I am using Linux on a desktop but, you know,
it's basically a
-- real deal
-- and
here is what I would say to that is I've been writing Linux on the desktop for probably
20 years exclusively and I had a two year stint with a Mac for work and I hated it
-- because I'm just like a brainwashed zombie. At this point
-- in fairness.
There are some really nasty glitches in Mac
Os and when you encounter those nasty glitches,
that's it that you can't fix them.
You know what it really came down to was just like,
I'm a shell junkie and while the shell experience isn't terrible on the Mac,
it's not amazing either.
You have to install G set. Otherwise
N doesn't work. I don't even know what you just said.
I said the, you know, the, the line serial editor,
you have to install G set. Otherwise when you would like max default set,
you try and tell it like, you know, replace this character,
-- put in the liner turn and it barfs,
-- whatever,
no one runs that
I do it like
-- three times a week because people need me to manipulate CS V files,
-- maybe whatever.
I just write a Python script. Anyway,
so
I gave up on set and a,
a long time ago, I just write Python now. Anyway. Anyway,
the point is so having experienced Mac for a while,
it is apparent to me that the Linux desktop,
people are jealous of the Mac and they want to be Apple and they want to be
able to force things on people and say you do it our way or you shut up.
I mean,
honestly,
the whole point to running Linux is not to have someone tell
you do it our way or shut up and you can argue.
Oh,
but you can install a different window manager and
you can install a different distribution or whatever.
-- But like
-- the problem is not that they're saying do it our way or shut up.
They're taking away your choice and forcing you to do it their way.
-- That's the same thing. You're splitting hairs.
-- Again, we go back to the,
give me a reasonable default that I can change so that the argument being for. Ok.
My parents, yeah, fine.
They get automatic updates and they live with the machine just
randomly saying I need to reboot right now for an update.
So you better have saved your work, right?
Whereas, you know, those of us running it on servers are like, no,
I want a maintenance window at three in the morning
or the maintenance window is when I run it.
Yeah, exactly.
And
yeah, it's, it's interesting to see this.
It's weird to me because like,
my number one takeaway from Linux was always that for good or for bad.
Here's the config files, right? Like you can go touch the config files and slash E DC.
It's, they're reasonably clear, you know,
you compare that to like the Windows registry experience where it's like,
I want to configure something to do this and you google it for a bit and then it's like,
ok, go in with the registry editor and, you know,
-- create ad string with this value and I'm just like, oh, I'm
-- like, De
-- Nome has that now.
-- Yeah, exactly.
And it's, you know, I feel like, I feel like I'm, you know, it's like, ok,
cut the red wire, which red wire they're all red, you know,
is that one Maroon or is it red?
You know, and I feel like, you know, like one of those movie tropes where, you know,
somebody's like, you know, the bombs counting down.
I got like five seconds left to go and I got to make this thing work versus, you know,
a config file where it's like,
I literally go copy config file to config file dot
or Ridge and then I monkey with the config file.
Did it break? No? Cool.
And I leave the original there too with stuff like the
registry editing and the way these systems are being moved,
it's kind of like you touch that configuration, it might,
you might regret it just to take it away from me entirely. Like
I, I was planning to do like an upgrade from Ubuntu 18 to Ubuntu and 20 in production.
And now I'm like, no, we're just going to skip it.
Stay on Ubuntu 18 and transition to platform as a service.
Now, I assume their containers don't have this problem.
Well, the thing is the way you're supposed to use containers is that, you know,
they don't live for very long and you instantiate a new version of the
with all the software up to date, run it through your C ID system.
It works, it doesn't work if it works, you deploy it, if it doesn't work, you know,
-- you go chase down the flaws
-- if the snap updater is running in your container?
Is it going to be like I need to update myself now because
it's been a really long time and I hope they didn't do that.
But if they did that's beyond idiotic.
Well, again, that goes to the whole continent,
you're not supposed to be running containers for months or years on end.
-- Oh,
-- whatever,
everyone does. I know. But
even you don't run it for months. What if, what if the container was built a year ago?
It starts up and snap says, oh man, I haven't updated it in a year.
It's time to update everybody.
Your process should be to build a fresh container before deploy.
That's not practical.
I know. But the thing is if you don't do those things, then this is the risk you run.
This is the modern world, the world has changed, right? The world has changed.
If you're not doing C ID, then yeah, you're,
you're going to be at odds with how the majority
of the world is now viewing and using software and it's
going to suck you and I both work for a vendor
where the principal idea was take a version of software,
freeze it n
for 13 years, right?
The reality is there are a lot of people willing to pay a lot of money for that.
They're out of sync with sort of modern reality, right?
In the sense of that,
the only way to do that is to pay a vendor a huge amount of money to service that for you.
Whereas, you know, all the node and all the everybody else is like, well,
whatever I got today's version, I hope it works, ran smoke tests, you know,
deploy it.
And I think fundamentally this speaks to the difference between, you know,
software changes over time quite rapidly, you know,
compared to say bridge technology or cars and the
more out of sync you are with reality,
the more risk there is.
So you need to build a system to manage that risk or you
have to accept that risk and accepting that risk might look like,
OK, we turn the container on and snap,
ran and sat there for three hours running updates.
That's a bold statement. So talking about
Ubuntu outside of containers.
Where does that fit into that?
Well, the reality is if you don't keep your systems up to date,
you're going to diverge,
you're going to the delta between you and
what the vendor like ubuntu's providing is going to
grow and you're going to have increased risk
of there being a change that breaks stuff.
But according to that attitude, then they're applying automatic updates.
-- It's a good thing,
-- right?
Again, automatic updates, but with user control,
because some users rightfully can make that risk
assessment and make that trade off and say,
look, that's not what you just said.
This machine, for example,
is running an MRI server system and we're keeping it offline because we're,
we're going to eat the risk.
You know, a great example always is us submarines. Right.
They go on patrol for, what, 90 days?
They're not getting software updates while they're under the water.
I would hope not communication channels to those
subs as I understand them are quite slow.
You know, the, the, what is it, extremely long
V
or whatever?
VLF, you know, radio transmitters, those miles and miles,
miles long cables buried all over the US to transmit them.
So the thing is again, I go back to that,
make a reasonably safe and sane default that works for people
that don't care and for the people that do care,
do let them run with scissors.
But you just said that's not how the modern world works.
Some people want to run with scissors and are willing to take that risk and
they should be allowed to.
I mean, I agree. I agree completely. I think forcing
anything onto people is dangerous outside of a consumer universe,
especially when you don't have to force it.
Like a great example is a light bulb, a light bulb can't really have
an interface for me to easily update it or not update it.
You know, I, I obviously through the app on my phone or whatever I could do that.
You know, there's going to be a lot of embedded systems running software
where the choice is either
this thing never updates itself
or it updates itself and, you know, you just,
it updates itself in a way that is quote unquote safe that it won't break itself,
it won't reboot and like your lights are off for a minute,
you know, or whatever, or like I said, you, you take that risk of, well, look,
this machine is not connected to the internet.
It's a light bulb or whatever. I mean, they are connected to the internet now.
But what it boils down to for me is there's no good reason to take away the choice.
There, there are good reasons to force a default choice on these people. I
agree with that, but to actually take away that choice,
we short of me really hacking the system up to prevent this.
You know, people on that forum thread are like, oh,
we'll just block DNS access to like what is
it like updates to ubuntu.com or stuff like that,
right.
And I'm like,
yeah, that's not a solution. Like a solution is there's a flag in a config file.
I mean, you know, not that I'm firewall access to.
Well,
so one of my complaints always is when people talk about these crazy workarounds,
like black holing some website or something is
if for whatever reason
that goes away accidentally
at some point now everything explodes.
And speaking of which there's another problem we've ignored.
We kind of assume everybody has good internet.
Like a lot of people don't have high speed internet, like for example,
I go to my parents' cabin, I'm on my cell phone.
Right.
And I don't want emacs updating, you know, pulling down or chrome or, you know,
like Microsoft Office is a great example. That's anywhere from 1 to 2 gigs a month.
It's a chunky boy.
-- I believe that. Actually,
-- that Excel powerpoint
Word.
I mean, every time I run a yum update on my fedora machine, I bet it downloads
probably almost a gigabyte of crap. And I do that about every two or three days.
-- Like it's a lot
-- of stuff.
Yeah,
like I look at my kids mobile devices and I for a while was keeping track of how
much the software updates for their apps are and it averages about 1 to 2 gigs a week,
stuff like Minecraft.
They've got some big assets in there.
Minecraft is huge and well, if you run Steam every time start steam,
it updates itself.
And so for example, I mean,
one thing I love is that I think we mentioned this previous show,
but Amazon Prime won't work on a version of chrome that isn't up to date.
I think that's somewhat acceptable because by virtue of using
something like Netflix or Amazon Prime video to watch video,
inherently, you have access to a bunch of bandwidth.
That's one of the few situations where a software application or service can say,
look,
I'm pretty sure this person has access to a bunch
of bandwidth all other situations are pretty much good luck.
And so that's,
that's another concern is somebody takes an ubuntu
machine out to their people live on farms,
people live in rural areas and have, you know, by our standards.
Pretty terrible internet. There's,
there's still people in America on dial up, they can't use ubuntu.
We need to reframe this completely because you're not wrong.
But it's also easy to get into a weird rathole talking about this.
Here's what it comes down to
is the vast majority of people in tech are developing and
testing in an environment that is functionally San Francisco United States.
And that's what it is. They have fast internet.
People are relatively dense, they have good cell coverage
and this is no doubt the exact same trap of the people
developing Ubuntu have no idea what happens outside of their bubble.
And so to them, it's fine.
Statistically,
you think the people developing ubuntu don't
have above average computers and internet access.
I would hope they do or they think you don't go
get another freaking job and work someone that treats you well.
Well, exactly. Right.
Like I've actually downgraded now to only having one internet provider.
Like I work from home and traditionally I had two internet providers because, well,
one of them will fail once in a while.
Right.
And you know, and then I finally did the math on how often they fail and blah, blah,
blah.
And I was like, ok, I can ditch this. I don't need it.
You know, I still have by my standards, you know,
relatively slow internet at 100 and 70 megabits symmetrical.
That's not normal that the normal is
like
five or 10.
Like here's the deal.
This is,
this is very true of security as well is we generally
design systems and process for a mythical user that doesn't exist
and we don't live in the real world. We don't see the things normal people see.
And so like the sales guy who opens his Wi
Fi hotspot up to allow anyone to connect to it.
That's because his job is to make sales not to secure his Wi Fi hotspot.
And it's, it's the same thing with this, with the people who designed this system,
no doubt
-- their job is to install updates
-- where their job is to ship updates.
Thus, they think they have inherent value and thus, you know,
foisting them on people forcibly is acceptable.
Yeah, that's fair. And I mean, this is
there,
-- there isn't a great answer to this outside of like
-- there is a great answer though.
There's a really great simple answer which is you have a relatively sane default.
That is well documented saying
-- look, all of them to has to say is Kurt,
-- they think their default is sane.
-- They don't know it isn't.
-- We make a sane default.
And we also make it clear how you change the behavior to do what you want.
Like for example, you live on crappy internet.
Ok. Turn off, uh you know, automatic updates
and then for all we know,
you drive into the city and use a coffee shop or somebody brings you out the updates on
another USB key, whatever. I don't care.
But the point is we make it possible for somebody to do
that and if they don't care or don't know to do that,
they never have to know or care because the default is
it just updates and it's fine and if it bothers them,
they can do something.
I guarantee you, they think their default is sane. I guarantee it.
And I am ok with that default.
What I'm not ok with is them taking away my ability to change it.
But they think that they, I guarantee you,
they think what they've done is normal and expected.
-- I guarantee it. Yeah.
-- And that's a fundamental.
But how, ok. No, no, no. Hang on.
How are they going to find out?
They've just made a silly mistake because let's
face it going on a forum and whinging is
no one ever pays attention to those. Right?
You're just a crazy person yelling into the wind.
That forum is quite a long discussion thread.
And Ashley ubuntu did modify their decision slightly if you read down for.
-- I, I
-- didn't make it that far and I'm sure
they did,
-- but
-- that's, well, they modified it a little bit.
But not materially as I understand it.
They basically still,
they give you up to two months now and then forcibly update you.
Well, that's stupid though. That whatever, it doesn't matter,
that's still dumb. It.
But for real, like this is,
this is the same challenge security people have is how do we figure out
where we find the information we need
you talk to your customers, you talk to your users.
I mean, that's easier said than done, of course. But that is the answer. Yes.
-- You
-- literally like I've, I've made it very clear, for example,
internally at the CS A where
if you people have pain, tell me, come to me, I will help you.
I will try and understand your pain and fix it.
And that's part of the maturity model of, you know,
being a security practitioner and rather than just saying no.
Yeah, I, I agree. I agree completely.
And,
and I think that of all the lessons we can take away from this weird rambly episode
is that
as a professional,
it's our job to understand what people are doing with our products, don't guess,
don't assume, you know, actually go and find people
and work with them and talk to them and understand what they're doing.
But then most importantly is when someone is sticking a fork in the outlet,
you don't say like you idiot, why would you do that?
You say? All right, why is the person doing this?
Because there's clearly some sort of deficient design here going on
and now all the outlets are tamper resistant with little plastic covers.
This is a perfect example of the sticking the fork in the outlet.
The solution is that now, if you've been Home Depot recently,
all the outlets are tamper resistant in the sense of you have to,
you have to jam the large neutral in first to open up the hot.
Otherwise if you try to jam in the hot, it won't open, the plastic won't release.
But the point is
don't just say the users are idiots. They're sticking forks in the outlets.
You need to figure out why are they doing this and how can we maybe make sure they stop,
you know, killing themselves.
And I would say this generalizes more generally to all professional activities.
Of course,
understanding what your users want, what they need,
what they're trying to do because a great
example being is I needed some stumps removed
and my brain just went to OK guy with a back who dig them out.
And then I phoned for a quote and they're like, well, can we just use a stump grinder?
And I'm like, uh yeah, actually, yeah, that's, yeah, he's like,
you don't want them like ripped out,
we can just grind them down and fill the hole in with dirt.
And I'm like, yeah, that's actually what I want. Like what I want is flat dirt
because
oh, I
don't care.
This is another problem we have in tech is you went to someone with a solution,
not with a problem.
Yes. Exactly. And the problem is you need the stump removed.
The solution is a stump grinder. But you said I want it yanked out with a back
and, but they were smart enough to know that I was, you know, they've encountered,
that's probably every third call.
Right. They're,
they're used to dealing with, know it all idiots, right? Like it's fine
but
like for real, this is there isn't a good answer to this and there's no,
there's nothing I can tell you.
Oh go read this book or go watch this video or whatever
-- that even tells you how to accomplish this. There's
-- try to listen.
Yeah, just don't be in
unemphatic.
-- Like just listen and be nice.
-- Try to listen and ask them why.
Yeah, that's fair and focus on problems.
We love to focus on solutions and solutions. Just
usually if you jump to the solution now you have two problems
instead of one.
Anyway, we are out of time. But this has been
uh
yeah, I guess good luck with your servers, man. I'm glad I don't run a
Buntu right now,
although
it would not shock me if this shows up in Fedora at some point in the near future.
So, all right. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening. You can go to open
source security podcast.com. Hit up the show notes, usually Pound
OSS podcast hashtag
-- to hit us up on social media. Kurt. Have a fantastic rest of your day. You
-- too.
-- Thanks
-- everybody. Thanks
everybody. Bye bye.