-- According to December 18th, we're getting
-- there. Don't roll your own crypto or
off.
Oh God. No, people can't even get password storage. Correct most of the time.
-- No,
-- no one does.
Well,
so I think this is funny is obviously we
talked about don't roll your own crypto for decades.
And I feel like that idea has mostly sunk in and now
it's don't roll your own off.
Yeah, because I see people doing this on a completely regular basis.
-- I would say as well if possible, don't host your own
-- author.
-- I think those are similar well,
-- descriptions.
Well, I would say it's unacceptable to write your own a system that is just,
it's like writing your own crypto, you're going to get it wrong
the story.
But if you do grab some, you know, there are some completely
finished off open source off systems that you can just grab and run.
There's loads of them if you use
a web framework probably comes with authentication.
Exactly.
And I would say, ideally don't host the accounts,
allow people to use their Google or Facebook.
But also conversely, please do allow them
to not have to have a Google or Facebook account because I've, I used to be very much,
I don't want to make, create an account.
I want to
use my Google or whatever.
And I'm coming around now because there's all these
reports of people just getting randomly booted from Google
and it breaks everything.
And if you have your own domain name, you can sort of recover from it and, you know,
re-establish your email somewhere else and get things up and running again.
But, well,
that only works with
Google and your own domain.
You obviously can't do that with linkedin or Facebook or Twitter or whatever,
right?
That, that is,
that account is tied to Twitter. That's it. You can't lift it somewhere else.
-- So
-- you know what I'm really enjoying,
there are a handful of services I use like Feedle is a great example where on Feedle,
I have a user name and password. I have a login with Google,
I have and then they have log in with other stuff,
but I only use Google and user name and
password,
which means obviously I can click log in with Google to just get in quick and dirty.
Actually, Nintendo does this too on their account and, but,
but I still obviously can log in with the user name and password
if let's say Google decides I'm a bad person and they need to kick
me out for some reason because I agree that's one of the terrifying
things with some of these authentication providers is if you get the boot,
-- like, well, that's
-- all.
And what's also interesting to me is I've noticed
I enabled the advanced security on my Google account both
working for a personal, you know, so I'm forced to sign in with hardware tokens and,
you know, it's kind of a chore.
Everyone should do this if you're listening,
pause the podcast and go do that right now.
I would disagree.
I would say Google's default security is good enough for your mom and dad. But
if it's a corporate account or look, look,
congratulations to moms and dads listening, but
pretty
sure that's not our target audience.
So
yeah,
you, for example, are a super user account in Gmail.
You probably should be or in Google Suite or whatever it's called.
Now, you should be enabling that. But here's the thing that's the,
it's broken authentication with a couple of sites that basically
when I tried to log in using my Google account,
I just get an error and uh
the error was clear. It said essentially this service
is doing something that's, you know, not secure enough.
So I guess they're doing something wonky with the old author or whatever.
Um But a bunch of them just fail,
just doesn't work at all and it works everywhere else with a non uh
advanced protection Google account
we're talking about, don't roll your own crypto,
-- don't roll your own off.
-- And well, and this speaks to these people that are obviously
doing the off
wrong because advanced protection shouldn't break it
because it works with most things.
That's my point. I have proof that, you know, most of these
o or not, most,
many of these oth systems are not very well made because they
break when you turn on advanced protection and that shouldn't break it.
-- Crypto
-- and oth I
think are unique problems in the fact that there is perfect and there is
nothing and there aren't very many things that I think fall under that umbrella.
But these two are that where you can't have mostly OK,
-- crypto or mostly OK off the
-- failure mode is catastrophic as well.
That's the real problem doing account recovery.
And I appreciate that some places are kind of clever about it, you know,
with nominate five relatives to recover your account,
stuff like that will work for normal people.
But by and large account recovery is impossible once they've gank your account.
Yeah, exactly.
Stay safe and, you know,
use those hardware tokens or at least a software token on your phone.
-- And
-- just don't, if you're a developer, like, don't, don't use
-- S MS.
-- Well,
I'm not going to argue that point right now
because that's a whole another can of worms.
But
the point is
if you're a developer don't roll your own crypto,
don't roll your own off. There are,
there are marvelous solutions
that can solve this problem for you.
-- Please use them
-- and more to the point outsourcing it
is probably cheaper because we looked at doing it ourselves,
like even just hosting it and running it
and we ended up paying, you know, we're paying 500 bucks a month for an off service.
That's 10 hours of time at
least.
And there's no way we can do it cheaper than that.
There's just no way we can run an off system.
High availability
-- with all the bells and features for that cheap. Yeah,
-- totally, man. All right.
December 19th is tomorrow.