Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Josh Pressers and my partner in Thought Crime.
Curtsy Fried.
Oh, my goodness. It's not even funny.
It's not meant to be funny.
The point is I'm
Josh Press
and I
said,
yeah, and why shouldn't we believe you is probably the right question. So
now people are wondering what's happening.
We're gonna talk about B GP today and the insecurity and madness of it all.
And apparently I'm KT now.
So
let me, let me,
let me make all the terrible noises you generally make, I'll just smack my mouth and,
and say like too much.
So, one of the funny things, actually, I mean,
just kind of to change the subject for just a second is that it always amuses me when I
listen to a podcast and then I listen to a
real person and it's like if it's been edited,
right?
You take out all the little ticks.
We all have various words we use too much when I edit the show. I take a lot of that out.
I take out weird pauses.
I take out we have certain men will make little
clicky noises with our mouth occasionally and that's all gone.
But when you talk to someone in real life, it's all there. And I love it.
But anyway, anyway,
-- I digress B GP. Tell us about B GP,
-- Josh. So, back in the day you had one computer
and the computer was happy
and then we had more than one computer and the computers wanted to talk to each other.
So we had routing and we ended up with TCP/IP.
Thank God and not like some BS like Net Boy,
right? So TP IP supports routing.
Now, the question is, how do you handle routing when you have
not just millions of computers but millions of networks under the control of,
you know, thousands or tens of thousands of different people.
I think we just have a static text file
-- that actually worked for a while.
-- It did work. Yeah.
So when
long story short, we end up with this thing called border gateway protocol.
And the principle basically boils down to
you have autonomous system networks.
So an autonomous system network is, is generally speaking a single entity,
like say my ISP tell us or Verizon or Comcast or the big boys that are, you know,
like level three.
and also some providers are big enough now, you know,
like Amazon Microsoft right there, you know,
they have enough IP space that they get to play the routing and transit game.
So basically you have an entity like say Amazon and they announce routes for
their various sites either in aggregate or broken up depending on what they want.
-- Right.
-- Right. Well, you should say sites, you should say I
blocks networks. Networks is better. Yes.
No,
because you can do any cast and you can
announce a network block multiple times for multiple sites.
I mean, that's true.
That's what Cloudflare does. And that's why, you know, cloud flare has 200 sites.
So when you look up
cre.org and you get the cloud flare IP of whatever it is,
you end up going to the closest cloud flare network,
which is great because it's faster.
So the idea basically is you own a network block
and you get to decide how you advertise it.
You know,
you could advertise it in one location for
one network link only or multiple network links or
you can do any cast. And anyways, and this was fine like this works absolutely great.
Still
so malicious comes along and goes, hey, I want to, for example,
see all of the traffic coming from, say Google's network.
So they pretend to be Google,
they announce I am whatever Google's IP network blocks are.
And of course, these networks go OK, like you have
announce this and I trust you. So
here's my Google traffic.
And of course, back in the day that that was pretty rare,
it was more of a fat finger type of situation or you know,
somebody did something stupid.
It wasn't really malicious. Typically
it was very difficult to mount that attack because you
needed a certain amount of hardware that nobody had.
And you know what this actually reminds me of,
I was just thinking about what you were talking is we
talked about hacking Voyager one a couple of episodes ago.
And yeah, it's very similar where if you have an enormous,
-- nobody would own a satellite dish that big.
-- Well, ironically if someone did,
the spy satellites would find it.
Right.
But obviously in this case, we're approaching a universe where it is practical,
impossible for literally anyone to stand up enough infrastructure to accept,
say Google's traffic and,
-- you know, falsely reroute it to Google even
-- worse than that.
You don't even have to stand up infrastructure, you can just rent it
well. Right. That's what I mean. Exactly.
There were a variety of proposals to fix this
and basically what we boiled down to is classic,
you know, PK
I layered on top so that, you know, the routes are signed, you drop out routes,
blah, blah, blah.
Honestly, it's not
easy,
but it's also not impossible.
I would say it's ba it's basically on a pretty much the same level as DNS Sec.
No, no, no,
let's not compare it to that because DNS Sec has its own set of ridiculous problems.
But I'm saying from a,
from a perspective of complexity and for the effort to stand it up, it's, it's on par.
-- I mean,
-- that's probably fair.
And, and so actually, here's why we're talking about this though.
Cloud flare, they started this kind of marketing push to
point out
large networks that aren't signing B GP.
Well, not just not signing B GP, but also accepting improperly signed routes,
which is even worse.
Ok. Right. Right. Yeah, because that's true. There's, there's two sides to it and
functionally what they're doing is they're
trying to exert public pressure against
pretty much anyone not doing this and they have a little tool you can run.
That'll tell you is your ISP doing the right thing.
-- Are they not doing the right thing?
-- Well, it's even simpler than that.
It's a website that has a couple of elements and basically, if you can contact
the one element that means it correct.
And if you can contact the other element that means it's being done wrong.
Like it's, it's hosted off a network that you should not be routing to.
And, and so, I mean, essentially
they're making all this noise about it and ironically, people are pushing back for,
we'll say hilarious reasons.
Oh,
my
God. Yeah. So
where do you even begin with? This
is ok. Well, let's, let's first do
is this whole B GP RO signing and RPK I and all that stuff totally secure.
No, of course not. It's PK I, you can subvert it, you can attack it, you can hijack it,
but it raises the bar significantly.
Just like with websites is http S the be all, end all for, you know,
ensuring that you're actually talking to walmart.com and that
your traffic is 100% safe between you and Walmart.
No, of course not.
But it's good enough. And honestly,
it's the whole B GP security thing.
If you're running a network big enough that it
sends out and consumes B GP routing information and you are
not competent to do this or set this up reasonably,
then you're really not that competent to run that network.
I would agree with that 100%.
Right.
I'm sorry. It's just that simple. Like,
like if you can't get a website up and running without HTTP S
in this day and age with like LS encrypt and free SSL hosting
like 20 years ago when it cost 20 grand for a secure web server. I get it.
It was not easy. But now it's, you know,
IOT devices have a secure web server built into them. So,
right. First argument that, oh, it's not completely secure.
Well, no, it's not completely secure, but it will keep out
99% of Attackers.
I've been harping about this for years and I will probably harp about it until I die.
Is saying something isn't completely secure is the same as saying we're not going to
do anything because nothing is completely secure and you have
to make various steps along the way to improving security
and just saying all or nothing,
you just pick nothing. There is no such thing as picking all.
So anyone who uses that argument
either knows what they're doing and they know
that nothing is the outcome or they're just,
like, functionally, not aware enough to be making any decision at all.
Well, and it's worse than that in that
you have to make these baby steps that are often wrong
in order to figure out what's right.
Well, unless you're DNS se and then they're just all wrong. But that's,
but, um, anyway, so, is it 100% secure? No, but it's like 99% secure.
Which is good enough.
Second argument. Oh, it's too hard and complex. Yeah. Sorry. No, I don't buy that
-- the fact that
-- B GP is hard and complain. Yeah.
Like the Wikimedia Foundation has done this.
-- I bet
-- they're more competent than most networks.
True. But, I mean,
when you see the ones that are not doing it at all, some of them, ok.
Apparently a Hurricane Electric is on there.
But apparently they are doing some of this but they're not,
they basically just haven't turned on certain aspects of it completely yet.
-- And
-- look in the case of someone like Hurricane Electric, they, they're a very
large backbone provider.
Most of people have never heard of them because why would you?
-- Well,
-- and they're traditionally known for being very competent, right.
They were the ones running the Six Bone tunnels and doing a lot of, you know,
experimental I PV six stuff to push it ahead.
Thank goodness.
My, my suspicion is if they haven't turned something like this on,
it's not because they don't want to,
it's because they're very careful and methodical of
what they do and obviously just flipping the
switch one day is the best way to make sure your whole network goes down.
Well, and this is a, it's a case of this is one of those security things of when it does,
when somebody does do BG P routing attacks,
it
usually gets noticed reasonably quickly and then gets shut down, right?
But there have been documented cases of B GP attacks where, you know,
some bad things did happen because,
you know, a few minutes of traffic is, is enough in some cases to launch your attack.
I'll dig up the story,
but somebody essentially rerouted a bunch of traffic from a crypt
exchange
in order to steal Bitcoin. And like the attack, technically speaking,
is very sophisticated and extremely impressive.
And in fact, prior to that story, I was like EB GP,
we maybe we'll fix it someday, whatever. It's not that big of a deal.
But after that, I'm like, holy crap. We need to fix B GP right now.
And the, the thing that really frustrates me is that well,
they fixed B GPA couple of years ago.
-- Just people need to turn this on. Well, ok.
-- No, no you can't,
that's a complicated answer because you can't say it was fixed a couple
of years ago because any time you
propose changes to like fundamental infrastructure,
-- it takes years, sometimes decades to deploy this stuff.
-- True.
But at this point all working from home now, so there's no longer the case of,
you know,
the internet has gone from,
-- nice to have to absolutely critical for the world
-- to
fight whatever it's been critical for a long time.
Now. We just know.
My favorite thing is the argument.
Oh, now is not a good time to start messing with our networks.
You know, there's this pandemic on and I'm sorry,
but there's never a good time for stuff like this.
Right. Right.
Like I need to get my yard fixed and so it's basically a case of, ok,
as soon as it dries out out there, I'm having a guy come by to dethatch
it and, like, do as much as he can
and then I'm going to, like, seed it and you know what I mean? There's
the best time to plant a tree was 20 years ago or, you know, now.
-- Yeah.
-- Yeah. I, yes, I will agree with that 100% in the context of this conversation.
I just, I still can't get over some of these people, like the,
this major ISP came out against it and it's just, you know, let me put it this way.
Would you buy email service from somebody who doesn't
do spam filtering and refuses to provide spam filtering.
-- Does
-- that
-- even exist anymore?
It doesn't because it would make email completely unusable.
-- It would be completely unusable.
-- And,
and see, that's the thing,
it's not like you can take additional corrective action to protect yourself.
Right?
And that's the other thing is this is a situation where
you have to rely on your network provider to do this.
You cannot do this.
This isn't like email spam filtering where you
could do it yourself on your own machine
or you could firewall on your own machine or run a V on your own machine.
-- But
-- Kurt, it's not a valid comparison because I, I don't know anything about B GP. My,
my,
my network providers B GP route could all be hijacked right now and all of this
whole conversation could be routed to some foreign
country while they're laughing at us for being
idiots.
I would have no idea.
And it honestly, for like 99.999% of people, it wouldn't affect me in any way.
Spam affects me.
Well, until they use attack crypto exchange or until they, you know,
um what was that case where I think China did a major
a hijack a few months ago.
Yeah. But how did it actually negatively affect people? Right? Like
-- how many crypto exchange users were there actually
-- all
-- of
-- European like or
a major chunk of European mobile traffic was sent through China last summer.
-- And
-- how did that affect people? Realistically speaking?
I bet very few people were affected.
Well, I mean, ok, so how does it affect people if I get a complete database of,
you know, everybody's P I?
Well, it doesn't affect them right now but it allows me to do bad things later.
I mean, yes,
but that's part of the problem is human beings
are terrible at saying this will matter later.
We're like, no, it affects me right now or it doesn't exist.
There's nothing else in between. I mean, look at literally
every crisis that has ever happened in the history of humanity.
How many, I mean, every one of them is, it's kind of like, you know,
you know what's funny is there have been a lot
of tweets lately that talk about every disaster movie starts,
the scientists being ignored.
And now I understand and like that is every crisis ever in the
history of humanity started with someone being ignored every one of them.
And, and I think that, I mean,
this is one of the challenges with B GP is it's not in your face.
And that's what cloud FFL is doing with this site actually is they're making it in
your face and I think people are getting
angry because now they're getting questions asked.
You know what it reminds me of is, it reminds me of CVS and that
vendor has a security flaw,
cool vendor has a security flaw and somebody assigns a CV to it and, oh, crap.
Now it's public and the clock starts ticking at a lot of companies
and they get,
like,
so many organizations I dealt with, like, literally if it has a CV, then, ok,
we need remediation in 30 days or whatever
and,
-- but no CV, whatever, it doesn't matter, it doesn't exist.
-- Right. Right.
And I understand that completely because once it's visible and let's face it,
getting a security flaw, a CVE makes it visible now that I
Ocean can focus on it.
And without that,
it's just a fuzzy thing off in the distance.
And, and I think this B GP thing is the same cloud flare is, you know,
they're standing up yelling, hey, everyone, look over here, look at me,
look at me and the guys we're not looking at that aren't doing anything.
They're like, wait, this isn't fair. You're, you're playing dirty.
It's like, you know what? They're not playing dirty. They figured it out.
Well, and it especially annoys me because these are not small mom and pop shops that
don't have a few bucks to put on this.
Like
that's not what they want you to believe.
You know, I mean, these are,
these are I SPS that are literally entire countries or while spanning many,
many countries.
And
so one of the other funny things about this is the gear that routes, network,
traffic costs millions of dollars for the box.
Right. We're not talking about the $200 router you bought at Best Buy last weekend.
No, no, these are enormous machines.
Well, and we're, we're talking about rack mounted
equipment that it's not. How many units of rack does it occupy?
It's how many racks does it occupy?
Right.
-- Exactly. Exactly.
-- Yeah.
You know, things where, yeah, the amount of,
like ra M is measured in the hundreds of gigabytes.
Yes,
this is one of the challenges I think is why we're seeing some of this pushback is
I have no doubt that some of this gear is probably too old to sign B GP,
which means some of these organizations are now going to have to pony up
-- new gear.
-- I'd say it's worse than that.
It's a lot of the gear will support it, but they'd have to, you know,
actually pay for their maintenance contracts or upgrade the software.
Which is,
that could be too.
You think people that run databases hate upgrading software,
go talk to your core network engineers.
Oh, man, I, I, no, I remember this so many years ago. I worked at a very small
ISP and this, I mean, this is back in dial up days,
we had a one line that serviced the whole ISP, which now is hilariously small.
-- That's 1.544 megabits per second. Yeah.
-- Right. Right. And
now it's ridiculous to think about,
but back then it sort like I think we had probably thousands
of users all on like 14 to 4 dial up modems.
So it was fine.
And,
yeah.
Yeah, I, I remember our network gear once that was working,
nobody touched it because if you touched it,
it broke guaranteed and there was nothing worse than breaking the internet.
I personally really like this because there's been
a number of network testing sites to see.
For example, you know,
does your ISP support DNS E queries or is
your ISP monkeying with your traffic in some way,
you know, for example, doing ad injection or?
Right. Right.
Oh, my all time favorite is, you know, oh,
you made a DNS query to something that doesn't exist.
Let me show you this helpful page.
You know, I ran into this problem where my, my code just
wouldn't air out on bad DNS. And I'm like, what like did
I mean
that how
like I literally couldn't understand what I was doing wrong until I,
I finally figured out like at some point that ISP had started serving
all the DNS no matter what right. NX domain is no longer an option.
Well, not with them.
I mean, this is,
I think why the popularity of things like 1.1 0.1 0.1 which Claude Flair also does
is such a big deal.
Well, even Google, like as much as I know,
Google is trying to like learn everything about me.
I trust my ISP less than I trust Google, which that says,
I agree.
I agree. 100%.
I might trust Facebook more than my ISP.
I mean, that's how bad it is.
Oh, I'd have
regardless the fact that we can't come up with a quick answer to that question,
I think, says everything like that.
This should not be a contest.
I, I like this because it, it makes it concrete, it makes it understandable and it's,
I, I hate to say this but
cloud flare is technically correct, which is, as we all know, the best kind.
Absolutely. I hope that they get more providers on that is B GP Safe yet.com list.
You know, it reminds me of the, uh, the two factor authentication site.
There's a really great website, two factor
dot org.
And it's got a pretty comprehensive list of
all the things from like banking to finance,
to hosting, to legal, to whatever, if they support, uh, two factor
off or not and even some information on it.
You know, what kind of like is it S MS, is it a phone call? Is it email?
Is it a hardware token? Is it a software token?
And, you know, you can make a much more informed decision and as to, you know,
which provider do you use, which, you know, for some of these, like,
say online betting.
Yeah, there's real money there. You will get attacked.
Oh,
yeah, totally.
So, I, I like this because, so much, well, not so much,
too much security is
just not being done because, well,
they can get away with it not being done because it's really hard to expose,
like for a person like you or me
to figure out if an ISP is doing this B GP security
or not like to stand that stuff up to test it is,
I don't want to say impossible.
Basically, like the amount of effort it would take is ridiculous.
It is. Right. Right. And, and additionally, as an end user,
I'm never going to see the results of them doing or not doing this.
But if cloud flare points me at it and says, hey, look over here, I can say, oh,
that's neat.
And, and actually, I was almost sad because my ISP has the, the,
the fancy good job for Cloud flare.
And I was like, man, I was really hoping to write some letters or something.
You know, I was,
you know what, this reminds me of his I PV six support back in the day.
I literally remember phoning my VPs,
like my hosting provider and it wasn't VPs
rather it was actual physical co location.
And like, they were like, basically their response was what's I PV six? And I'm like,
and in fairness, they did start supporting it about two years later.
But like my then ISP Shaw again, they were like, we, we have no plans to support this.
-- Why would we,
-- there's plenty of IP addresses and I PV four, we'll never go
-- there
-- again.
You know, it, it,
I PV six is a little bit different
and that there was actually something pushing like,
yeah, there is no, I PV four space to buy anymore.
Or rather
the fact that
you have to buy it now you can't just go and get a network block from one of the,
you know, a PN.
Yeah, whatever you've had to buy it for a long time. Yeah.
-- But now the price has actually gone up.
-- Well, yes, it's real money now.
-- It used to be basically
-- free and B GP, you know, the, the B GP security stuff there,
there's no,
there's no push, there's no incentive like that other than people, you know,
banging on pots and pans and yell
at their
isps.
I mean, functionally, yes, until, like people start doing mass B GB hijackings and,
you know, make it so bad that we notice it.
-- Even
-- if they did that
even,
I don't think you'd ever notice it because
obviously the whole point of hijacking the traffic
is to make sure no one does notice it because as soon as they do,
they shut you down.
But then more importantly is it's the typical human problem of
the negative implications from this activity will be in the future.
-- So I don't care.
-- Well, or it's, you know, it's part of such a targeted attack that
those entities assuming they even notice again, they can't really, you know,
I hate to say this but even,
let's assume tomorrow the US government said, look,
all of our I SPS have to do B GP security.
What? You know, how long would
it? No, that, that isn't even enough to push it,
-- you
-- know.
Well, you could,
but it would still be like a two year roll out period because that's what,
probably what they need is my guess.
I don't know.
And, and, but even then, even then, let's say the US said we're going to do this,
the US is just part of a large network. And so,
for example, I guarantee that I do things where
the traffic ends up in another country, let's say, or,
or region that maybe wouldn't fall under that jurisdiction.
And so that's how you, that's how you do it, you know, true.
But it would vastly reduce the incidence of either the, well within the US.
Nobody would be a, would be affected by US
prefixes being hijacked,
right? Because they'd all be secured
-- in,
-- in the US, right?
But obviously, even once you left, you could start, you know,
gobbling things from other countries.
And so, I mean, yeah, it's got to be a worldwide effort for sure.
I think this is very much an all or none is where we have to be.
I disagree because the thing is there are,
let's say you've got every major transit network and every major cloud provider,
right?
That,
that is a major chunk of the traffic and that would prevent a lot of the propagation.
Sure. Right.
The brutal truth is with this BG P security stuff is you where you really, really,
really need it is those core networks,
the ones that connect to the networks that's fair. Not like my dinky little.
And when I say dinky little, I mean, tell us is, you know, there,
I do a trace route and it like pops out in the US
with,
tell us names like they own a network that spans North America and goes to Europe
and I would consider tell us small because they, you know,
they're not like level three or, you know,
one of those people that own transatlantic cables like Google does
that, you know of,
-- I don't know their names offhand.
-- Yeah. Yeah, I'm glad I don't anymore.
I'm just glad that network mostly works.
I, I, I'm happy with networks these days.
I remember running Cisco routers a long time ago and
I won't say I was ever particularly good at it.
I was functional, I'll say, but it was definitely one of those things that
I feel like networking is for a certain kind of person. And I'm not one of them
like Sudoku,
maybe, you know,
you know what actually I started playing some time ago was
there's another game called Ken Ken which is similar to Sudoku,
but it involves like math
and
-- that one where? Yeah. Yeah.
-- Yeah. Yeah,
you got, like, the plus sign.
Like, this line needs to be six and this line needs to be
right.
It's so,
it's so difficult to find though because for whatever reason,
it's just not very popular
and, like, I do enjoy Sudoku. Don't get me wrong. It's a fantastic game.
But, yeah, Ken Ken is my new favorite and
I can never find it anywhere and I, I prefer paper because,
oh, first of all, I don't want to print off copy.
So please don't send me like some, some Ken Ken website. Like I'm too lazy to do that.
I want one of those books I wanted in the newspaper or something.
Oh, yeah. You want the old people book of time waste.
I like those though because I can write all my weird little
notes down about what I think things are going to be.
I know there's soft,
like I was actually watching sadly a guy
do a really tough Sudoku puzzle and they've got
dedicated software that allows you to set like the value in the square or to set,
you know, provisional values in a small font.
I would assume somebody has that for Ken Ken,
the Sudoku on.
I haven't found it yet but the Sudoku game
on Brain Age for the Nintendo DS is phenomenal.
It is by far the best because you get to use a pen, which is hugely important,
in my opinion.
You get to use a pen and you can click around and actually draw like you, like,
if I want it to be a one, I draw the number one and it turns it into a one.
-- It's
-- marvelous. There's something to be said for that physicality.
Like I,
there are papers I print out and go through with
a red or blue pen to more actively read,
interact with because I just can't do it on the screen.
I don't even like printouts of stuff. I like having,
I don't know what it is.
There's something about, like, for example, let's say I want a book,
like I want a paperback of something and I could
say print it out and I've done that before.
You print like a couple 100 pages or whatever. I still prefer the bound nice book.
There's a, there's a certain feel to the pages,
the ink looks a certain way and there's just, I'm a sucker for that and like,
even newspapers, I read my newspaper online now because it's
like
a
-- 10th of the price.
-- Can you even get it delivered?
Yeah, I can.
But it's literally 10 times more expensive than what I'm paying online.
And so just from a financial perspective, I didn't want to justify the cost.
But like, I miss sitting down and opening a real newspaper,
-- I think it is one of the true joys
-- I will admit like,
something like the few times I got a copy of, what was it?
The New York Sunday Times. I mean, that is just,
-- that's, that's a satisfying way to spend a couple hours on Sunday.
-- It absolutely is.
And I love it. I absolutely
love reading the newspaper and I don't anymore.
But again, like playing the weird little puzzles.
I used to love playing Sudoku in the newspaper specifically in the newspaper.
Right. Not,
not online, not print off the sheets or whatever. But I don't know.
I'm a weirdo like that. It is. Everyone's got their thing. Right. That's mine.
So, ok. Anyway, we should get back on track.
B GP.
We are obviously in complete agreement that everyone should sign their B
-- GP routes and
-- also ensure the routes consuming are signed and correct.
-- Well, I think that goes hand in hand, right? If, yeah,
-- you say that.
-- But again, we also tell people to floss, I
-- floss every day.
Yeah. And you're like literally the only human being I know
that does that.
I especially,
I'm especially particular about my teeth right now because I really don't
want to have to try to find a dentist right now.
-- Yeah,
-- that is a good point.
Yes, I was thinking about that.
-- I thought, what would I even do?
-- I had that cracked tooth earlier or last year rather.
And luckily I got in like four days, they had a cancellation. I got in four days.
But like that,
I'll be honest, I've had like my appendix try to kill me as an adult.
I've had my tonsils out as an adult
and I mean, with my cracked tooth,
the amount of Tylenol three they prescribed to me after the surgery.
I was like, I'm not sure this is like safe and I ended up only taking three.
-- Yeah, like it, that was the worst pain I've ever experienced.
-- That's wild man.
I have been very lucky with my teeth and I hope to stay that way.
So I'm very particular now about caring for them
because
it is one of those instances where as a human, it's easy to be like, oh,
I don't need to worry about this right now.
And then my brain says, yes,
I do because in 40 years you're going to have
the same teeth in your head you have today.
So take care of them.
-- But it's hard man,
-- every day,
all knocked out in dentures.
Well,
there's days I think about that, but like seriously, every,
every day I go in the bathroom and I think, oh, I won't floss today then I think.
No, you have to floss. Like it's,
there's like a battle in me every day, every day and it never gets easier.
I won't lie to you.
Well,
my understanding is this is one of the leading
reasons for death in a lot of wild animals is
really,
I mean, that doesn't shock me in any way.
Well, if you're a lion and you got a broken tooth,
it's going to get infected and you're going to die. Yeah.
Well, even if it doesn't get infected, if you can't eat right, you die.
And you figure if, if you're one of these
large,
my
cat,
my previous cat
had at the end,
one good tooth and it was so cute because when she slept the one tooth would stick out,
it was one of her incisors.
It was either the top left or top right and a little bead of drool would form.
That's awesome. And it was so cute.
But the point is if she wasn't a house cat with full medical and dental and soft food,
she'd be dead.
Right. Exactly. Exactly.
Because I imagine if a lion doesn't eat for probably
-- a week
-- most house cats after three or four days,
their kidneys get all messed up.
Oh, really? That could be,
yeah, if your cat doesn't eat for three or four days, like,
I did not know that I know nothing about cats.
I've had one cat and it unfortunately had a genetic disorder that
came to an untimely demise. And,
yeah, I've, I've, I have dogs, I like dogs. They can eat garbage and they're fine.
I'm a dog person. Right.
Because if he accidentally eats trash, I'm like, he'll be ok.
It's no big deal,
you know,
maybe call the vet and be like, hey, the dog just ate garbage again. Should I wear it?
My, my one cousin had a dog that ate a septic puck for a toilet.
That's cool.
And she, like, literally phoned poison control.
And they're like, well, if a human did that,
we would tell them to go to the hospital so they don't die.
And she phoned the vet and the vet's like, e just keep an eye on him.
Yeah.
That's like the most dog thing ever. I love it.
And the thing I remember with this dog is we put a pint or not a pint, sorry,
a gallon tub of ice cream outside to freeze it faster because it was, it was in winter.
But anyways
and, yeah, of course, then somebody's like,
why is that dog running around with a cardboard thing?
-- That, that was a lab,
-- wasn't it?
It was part lab.
That
lab. That's,
I
love labs. They're so awesomely stupid.
But they mean, well, they mean, well,
so I was talking to my kids about this actually because we have
some friends with labs that are always up to shenanigans and it's,
it's hilarious because they're smart enough to get into trouble,
but dumb enough to still get in it, you know, I love it.
Yeah. Well, just like my, my kids were like, feeling they were using the, the Google
comment function on documents to talk with each other
in class and then their teacher caught them.
Oh, that's sneaky.
But what I love is, well, no,
it's not because every time you leave a comment on the school box,
the teacher gets an email.
Ok. Ok. So, no, they figured that out weirdly.
And, but the best part is Felix's one comment was like, hey, guys,
I think the teacher might catch us.
Never admit that. That's admitting guilt.
I guess the moral of the story is if you're clever enough to get into trouble,
don't get into trouble you can't get out of.
And I would say this is the B GP people. Like
if you're going to run the B GP network,
-- run it securely, please. And thank you.
-- I agree.
And secondly, uh, send us your hilarious dog stories about them eating things.
They shouldn't because
we could all use some shearing up today.
All right, the security of dogs. That sounds like a marvelous future topic anyway.
And that's why we domesticated them.
That's a fascinating story too.
But, ok, so thank you, Kurt. Thank you
for listening. Go to open
source Security podcast.com. I'll put in all the show notes you can use ipos
podcast hashtag to send us your hilarious dog stories
and Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye
going.