Hello and welcome to the open source Security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
So, what's new? Well, apparently we're headed into a recession.
-- So we're going to talk about job security. I
-- mean, is, is that ok?
So for anyone who's been listening to the podcast for a while every now and then,
Kurt likes to add a topic that he won't tell me what it means or what it is
and
I oblige,
but then by the end,
I'm usually telling him we're never doing this
-- again and
-- then I wait about three months
against my better judgment.
I've let Kurt do this and
I don't understand what the, the title Job Security Has Security in the title,
which I think is
progress compared to some past topics.
But I,
I know as little as the listener at this point about what's going on,
which is concerning to me in, in bad ways.
Well, and that's kind of the point is,
is none of us know what the economy is going to do.
Even the people that
say that they know what the economy is going to do.
I, I will agree with that statement.
So we're going to talk about job security, both in the sense of job security,
but also in the sense of job security, the security of jobs.
So, well, basically, so if the last week has been pretty brutal,
like Elon Musk announced they're firing or sorry, not firing,
laying off or whatever, downsizing,
-- um, 10% of their salaried staff Coinbase is getting rid of 11% of their staff.
-- So 18%
sorry,
sorry, I was thinking of another one.
Anyways,
there's a whole pile of tech companies that have uh instituted hiring freezes.
According to this Yahoo article,
the uh Bloomberg story count for with the term hiring freezes.
Uh
Normally it's about 2, 300 a month with like a massive spike at the beginning of COVID
and then it
like so starting like that April
and then, you know,
like sharply comes back down and settles out and then with
uh this month it's uh spiked back up to about 1200.
So it's about five times normal.
And so I think we can all agree that things are not as normal
-- with respect to hiring and job security of
-- all the lessons I've learned over my,
we'll say extensive time
on earth.
There is no such thing as normal.
There is, there is a
times of ease for the well off which I think often become defined as normal.
But the reality is like no man, there's no normal.
Yeah, I think it's not even so much times of ease, but there's,
there's change and then, especially if you have a lot of resources,
you can adapt to that change.
So for example, if it's hot, you get air conditioning
done, I'm comfortable with this now it's ok.
You know,
and then things change enough again that you are no longer comfortable.
And of course, if you have less resources, which is a play way of saying if you're poor
or working poor, you know, it's obviously you're gonna struggle with this,
you know, just like
online schooling being a great example.
If you have high speed internet and laptops,
no big deal.
And if you don't have those two things, then online school is,
well, it's impossible.
Like just straight up, you can't do like
they were talking about these rural people, you know,
where the teachers are photocopying like crazy and printing out
packets to give to the kids because they don't have,
they don't have internet at home. That's good enough to go for online school. So,
so number one is job security
and we're not going to talk too much about that other than to say that.
Yeah, like if you get laid off or fired or let go,
it sucks. And it's, it can be brutal and it can be really hard to get back on your feet.
And so, you know, please talk to your friends get help if you need it.
Uh There's a lot of good online resources for that.
Um,
but ultimately, it is just brutal but the second part is sort of
how these people are often let go.
And that's the job security part I want to talk about. Right.
So there's the old trope of, you know,
like all of a sudden
two large men and a person from HR, show up at your desk,
you know, and ask you to step away from your keyboard.
Right.
Yep. Yep. That's right.
And then they, you know,
the person from hr starts reading you stuff and making you sign
stuff if you want your medical insurance to continue in the US.
And you know, the two big burly men watch you as you box up your desk and, and
are walked off the premises
and of course, in tech, we don't do that anymore in tech, what happens is you wake up,
you try to check your work email and it doesn't work.
That that is exactly what in fact. So you say that
if you read the Coinbase blog where they detail what they're doing,
they basically said when this blog is published, if you're part of the, the layoff,
you will get an email to your personal email and your
access has been cut off.
So basically they were fired by a blog and a personal email like,
yeah,
well, and again, at scale, what are you going to do?
Well and not just skill? I mean, So
I think
there are different types
of, we'll say, um,
I,
I don't know how to a polite way to say
it but there's different types of companies that fire people,
we'll say.
And
I think any sort of organization like a bank
or Coinbase or even a lot of security people,
there are real concerns about real damage from retribution from the employees.
I mean,
I remember
when, I mean, when you and I worked at Red Hat,
most of the security people we worked with like when you put your notice in,
you were told you have a great couple of weeks off, like you're done,
I was big to stay and they made me work out my two weeks.
Well, not everyone had to do that.
I actually was hoping to get the two weeks off.
That's what I wanted. I wanted to be like,
you know, 20 minutes from then I can't check my email anymore. It's great.
I got two weeks to clean the house and do some renos. No, I had to work those two weeks.
That's hilarious. But
like if you have access to sensitive information,
that is a legitimate concern,
I will say and obviously in the case of something like Coinbase,
you don't want like one of the developers like
cleaning out all the wallets and being like,
well, that was fun guys.
And my response to that is
if you
are in a position where clicking a link in
an email results in the company being ransom wared.
That's not a you problem. That's a company, it problem.
And I would say the same thing here if letting somebody go all of a sudden
means that they could somehow crash your company
or do some significant damage to it.
Well,
they could have done that yesterday or the day
before or the month before nothing has changed.
Apart from the sense of, like in the classic sense of an attacker,
you have a threat plus a capability, they always had the capability,
but now they have the intention, the threat, right? That's fair.
And so the problem becomes what that means is.
So those 18% of people you let go,
they're the only 18% of people that can crash the company.
What about the remaining 70 or 82%
-- that may or may not be happy about this? Well,
-- the other 82% are getting paid
for now
-- for now.
-- Is, is correct.
Have you seen the crypto markets?
-- Actually, I haven't looked at the Bitcoin price yet today, but I, I
-- bet it's,
-- yeah, you might not want to look it.
-- I bet it's stellar. $21,000.
-- It down a bit,
-- a little bit
by a bit. I mean, a lot.
But here's my point.
It's not like those 18 18% or 10% of Tesla
or whatever people are the only people that could,
you know, be upset and crash the company,
there's still those remaining people that can do this and,
and if one of those remaining people decides to throw a tantrum and like,
you know, do something bad to the company and they can do significant damage,
-- then your, it
-- sucks. Sort of.
So I think about this one a lot and I have a really good example actually from the past.
So when you and I worked at Red Hat,
we had a signing server and it is how
all of the artifacts Red Hat distributed were signed.
And this was a computer with a hardware security module in it.
It was one of those like
three of the five power rangers have to come together to reconstruct
the key if it crashes and all that kind of stuff.
Right? Like we did it up, we, we turned, I mean, we turned it up quite a bit.
It was, it was security done, right? It's
not as good as the P GP story that's going to come out the week after this episode.
But, but we'll get to that.
But
anyway,
so
we had administrators for the computer that ran the signing
server because we obviously had people who had to log in
and conduct maintenance on it, do the upgrades.
They had to
like
check the logs, you had to deploy new versions of software like that kind of stuff.
Right.
And I was one of the people who could do that.
There were, I think three people, two or three, I don't remember the exact number.
I think it was three people who had access to this computer. And
I had the ability to sign
an R PM package on this machine
because I had enough access that I could just like, literally,
like go down into the bowels of the system
-- and access the HS
-- M
hardware security
module.
Yes. Yes. And, and for anyone who doesn't know the, the idea of this device is
keys go in and they never come out
and
we'll put a lot of caveats on that because I'm,
I'm sure the software that runs on these things is a,
a complete tire fire and no one's ever audited it.
But that's another story.
But I don't want to get started.
But
the idea is that even if someone attacks the system, they can't get,
they could sign things, but they can't get the key out
and then we rotate the key and move on.
Now the day I submitted my notice to Red hat that I was leaving when I went to Elastic.
Obviously, my access to the key server was turned off immediately.
Well, and more importantly,
hopefully they had somebody else who they then gave access.
I, I have no idea and, and
it, I don't care,
it doesn't matter.
But
I
think that was prudent security to say Josh is exiting the company.
-- He should not have access to this computer
-- for a small number of high trust people.
Absolutely. Like,
yes, but
18% all at once
again, if that 18% is all so high trust that you
have to lock them out because their access is so privileged.
-- That's way too much privilege across the board.
-- I,
I would be skeptical if they had that level of privilege. I think most people don't.
I think it's just from a risk management perspective, it's easier to just blanket,
turn them all off than it has to be like, oh,
these people need to be turned off now and these people
can probably wait a day and these people can wait.
Like, no, just
get it, get it done with like pull that band aid off.
And I suspect that's, that's how that works. I mean, if I was in charge of,
thank goodness, I've never been in this sort of environment. But if I was like the co
of a company
that was laying off a whole bunch of people,
I would be inclined to say, like, we're just going to like,
-- it has to happen all at once.
-- No,
no, it's like ripping a band off.
But my concern is so many people seem to think that this really has,
it has to happen because of security. And I think that's,
if it has to happen because of security you're already
in, for a world of hurt,
you're probably right because my suspicion is if you
have the sort of access level I had,
for example,
you're probably not on the list of people that a company can afford to get rid of.
And so
I, I don't think you're wrong there necessarily, but,
well,
I actually had this happen when I worked for a previous company as a contractor.
They were basically preparing for sale
and to make the numbers look better, they wanted to, you know,
reduce expenses like headcount is ok.
Right.
But
contractor expense is bad.
So they
kept trying to fire me
or to get rid of me.
And of course my manager in the, in the higher ups number, like you,
you cannot get rid of Kurt.
Like I was something like 20 or 30% production of all the security reports,
the, the, the accounting sheet, people just could not understand that,
that they really wanted to get rid of this line item expense that was, you know,
pretty expensive.
Right.
And,
but they couldn't, you know,
same thing and then when the large company bought us and wanted
background checks on everybody before we were allowed to VPN N.
They're like,
no, Kurt has to have access now. Otherwise he can't do his job and
like we need Kurt to work.
So it's always amusing to me that there are
all these policies and standards that are put in place
and
eventually something happens and it's like, no, we got
not this time. Let that one go.
How important is it really?
Well, you know, I see this all the time. Like with how do I put it?
There are like those white glove high touch people
that it's like we have a password policy.
But, you know, if
Bob over in sales, the money tree shaker violates it,
that's ok
because he brings in, you know, seven figures a year of sales.
That's right.
I remember,
I remember being in some situations like that in the past where it was like,
oh,
let that one go.
Like, it doesn't matter, it doesn't matter what websites they're looking at.
Like they can do that.
It's like,
wait a
minute.
Is that still a thing?
Uh,
no,
not the filtering part.
Well, it depends where you are. I mean, there's organizations that I don't do it
but I think now it's more of
you are, you have your Endpoint software and it monitors for bad things
and you're like, oh, look, someone somehow got all this malware from, you know,
this horrible porn site or whatever.
Like, what are we going to do about it?
And, yeah, it's like if they're, if they're the big sales guy, it's like, no,
it's fine.
Just delete the malware. Everything's fine. Everything's fine. Everyone.
No one pay attention.
Like, ok,
-- I guess,
-- and I guess especially in smaller organizations, like,
you can't do separation of duties if you have like, three people,
you know, like we talked about this, about the podcast.
Like, there's two of us, we can't really
do separation
-- of
-- two of us.
There's, I'm, I'm,
you do all the work. I'm the critical path of this podcast.
You don't even have to log in to our, our hosting site,
which maybe we should talk about fixing that someday. But,
-- but
-- I
know
because we actually did ac we for this with voting mechanisms where,
well, well,
a great example is like these consensus mechanisms that require voting.
There was um a uh a crypto token
that got
hacked because they had nine,
there were nine keys and you needed five to get consensus,
right?
This seems totally fine, right?
Except one organization held four keys.
I mean, that seems fine to me.
-- So
-- you have one person in one organization, they got the five keys and they
drained
the thing and nobody knows for a week,
which is the best part until someone tried to do a transaction was like,
why is there no money in here anymore?
You know, it was on the
news. It was great.
And so we looked at this
and so obviously any voting mech
mechanism you choose, it's kind of like a security mechanism.
There'll be upsides and downsides. So for example, if you require
um what kind of majority? 51% 66% 75% a full majority of 100%.
Well, you know, for example, the,
you know, the UN Security Council because they require 100% vote
any member of the Security Council and Russia can just veto everything. Right.
Right.
Kind of, no matter what you pick, there's going to be upsides and downsides,
um, different risk profiles.
And, you know, we looked at this, this assumes that you have some sort of critical
mass or plurality to actually vote.
You know, and the, so the CS A is a great example.
Like we're, we're finally growing out our,
it and ops team because previously it was like me
and
I, but, but here's the thing, I have a 20 plus year relationship with the CEO,
you know what I mean?
And he's treated me very well for 20 plus years. So
that buys a certain level of trust and loyalty that
well, yeah,
it takes 20 years to buy that trust and loyalty and
most companies are not willing to spend that time and money.
Well, it, it, it almost doesn't exist anymore.
I mean, you know, when, when you and I were young,
there were always these stories of people who worked for
one company for 50 years and then they retired and
my dad had one employer.
He went to university and then he stayed until he left when he was like,
-- it's
-- pretty awesome.
Like, I think the odds of that happening again are very low.
And I mean, I think this is one of the things you have to keep in mind, obviously,
when you're creating any sort of architecture of, of like humans or tech or,
or whatever.
I think
one of the things that comes to mind is
you're kind of describing all of this and there's
the aspects of voting and, and there's, you know, how much
like in your case, you have all this loyalty to Jim.
-- Well,
-- how much collusion do you need for something bad to happen?
Not just that, I think one of the things we do,
especially in security is we obsess over
this like perfect security which doesn't exist.
And you always have to decide like, where am I drawing the line?
And I'm just going to say everything below this line,
I just have to trust because I have no choice and everything above this line.
That's the stuff I'm going to put effort into trying to build security
and compliance and whatever else around it
to make it more robust.
And I think that's I like this conversation we're having right here.
-- That line is very blurry, I think.
-- Well, I'm gonna subtly disagree.
I agree with you. But
the caveat being is that there's new,
subtle disagreement, there's new technologies and there's new
ways of doing computing that were not available 10 or 20 years ago.
So for example, perfect example,
here is we use cloud ally to back up our Google our Microsoft 365 and our sales force.
And one of my goals longer term is to get that cloud
ally backups essentially under the control of somebody who's basically not it,
operations.
So that even if kind of it operations, wigs out and fat finger deletes everything,
there's this wholly separate backup.
You mean, like
an off site? Cold backup, right.
You know, things like that.
But yeah, the, the stuff like this wasn't possible a long time ago because just
the services didn't exist.
And I'm pretty sure Google's not going to let
me run backup tapes out of their facility.
Right.
I was just gonna say that it used to be
possible because we would ship the tapes off site.
I remember the, the crate would come in every Monday morning.
I would take the tapes out, put the new tapes in and then the crate leaves on Tuesday.
That is a line item on every single security questionnaire I've ever gotten.
It was like,
you know, how, what is the physical security or are your back? Oh, yeah.
It's, are your backup tapes encrypted? And I'm like,
not applicable.
Right.
Although I'm, you know, like,
yeah, so
I think that's part of it is not just,
there's a line in the sand we're going to care about,
but there's also
the new thing is the sort of that line in the sand of what can we do
to kind of put this data or control of this data or a back with this data
in an entirely different sandbox
in a way that wasn't possible 10 or 20 years ago.
And I think that's part of where a lot
of security people fall down because they don't,
they don't know that these new things exist.
Like Amazon Glacier is a great example because Amazon Glacier by definition.
Right.
It's my understanding is it's a bunch of hard
drives that get fired up every what is it?
4 to 6 hours
to do data reads and writes.
So that right there gives you like that kind of cold off
Lish storage capability
where you don't, like,
you have minutes and hours to go deal with something
because it's on a hard drive that is like,
physically offline,
-- you know.
-- So
it's funny you say that
I know someone who
was involved in glacier at one point in the past.
And I said,
I've heard it works like this. Is that correct?
And they just seem to me and said that is incorrect. And I said, well, how does it work?
And they said I won't tell you that
I don't know anything about it, but it's like, it's the greatest mystery in all of it,
I think.
Like, how does the Amazon glacier work?
Well, it's clearly not like a, I'm pretty sure it's not tape or like DVD S,
I
don't know if they have a printer that's just
paper actually. You know, it's really funny. Funny side note.
I remember one time
I was, it was,
I was in an intern in college for an ISP and they were
small and the people running it were very old and out of touch.
They were, they were part of a phone company
and
we were requested by the FBI at one point to produce logs for, we,
we needed the logs for computer access and they wanted phone access logged.
And the guy was like, these log, these go back like two months.
We don't have two months of logs. I'm like,
how long do you keep your logs for?
He's like we changed the printer paper every couple of days.
I'm like, wait, wait, what?
And he's like,
well, yeah, what do you, what do you do with your logs?
You don't just print them into a box. I'm like,
wait, what?
And yeah, like, seriously, this phone company had a printer.
That was, it was that long like that?
Remember when the paper came in, like the big long sheet, which is paper went in,
it came out of a box in the front,
went into a box in the back and those were their phone records.
And I'm like,
this is, this can't be right.
I know a lot of places did that, like, um,
police forces did that for their internal door, sensor logs and stuff.
You know, who's accessing what door, the evidence locker, stuff like that because
you can't tamper with it.
Like it's in a lot of room that only three guys have access to
there. But that's like 20 years ago.
This was in the
mid nineties
it would have been 99 98 probably.
And, and look for a police store. I think you can make that argument.
But for a freaking phone company that this guy didn't even
fathom that you could just write the data to a disk.
Like he didn't understand because I said
you should be keeping more than a couple of days of logs. He's like,
well, how much paper would I need for that? I'm like, none. You need no paper.
Well, though,
you'd need the same amount of paper because it's not like you're just printing the
logs out and it's just a matter of keeping them at that point so that
you don't actually need more paper. You're already wasting it.
Anyway.
Anyway, it was,
I'm confused
the most ridiculous conversation I've ever had in my life. But anyway, OK,
back to
my point of drawing the line and saying the
things underneath any glacier is a great example.
I have no control over glacier. I don't care or have to know how it works.
I draw the line above glacier, right?
And I think what you're talking about is no different at all. I think
everyone has a line somewhere. Backups are part of it.
Like when I would ship a crate of tape
every Tuesday off to
the vault, we'll put that in quotes. Like
I literally had no idea what was happening there.
Like they told me it was being stored in the secure warehouse.
But like I didn't go and look,
maybe it was being put in some guy's basement for all I know.
You know, like they, they only show you the vault when you get a tour.
But then,
and again though, I had to draw a line and be like,
I have to trust these people because it's not worth my time
to go above and beyond that.
Yeah. No, I'm always reminded of, remember a few man, when was this?
Oh, this is back in 2006, remember two Iron Mountain facilities burnt down
and everybody was like all conspiracy theorists crazy.
And it turns out one was an accident and one was an intentional fire.
I vaguely remember that. Yeah,
they're really not supposed to burn down.
Well, I mean, that's the idea
like which kind of raises the question of like,
how's the fire suppression of all of these?
Obviously not that great. If two of them burnt down,
nobody knows.
Well, no, we know we have, we have two data points, two of them burnt down
-- out
-- of how many facilities anyway, whatever it doesn't matter, doesn't matter.
But again, this is where insurance and things like that hopefully help out. But
ok, anyway, we are talking about
the security of jobs,
I guess in this context and I want to bring us all
the way back to the thing we're supposed to be talking about.
-- So,
-- no, I think this is interesting. And I think
again, you know, it sucks to literally
you check your work email, it doesn't work,
you phone the support desk and they're like, we don't know who you are.
You're not allowed to talk to us. Click.
So hopefully you've checked your personal email to find out.
Although I guess at this point it's in the, in the media.
So I guess when you turn on the TV, you might find out that you've been fired,
you know, kind of like, um,
what's that scene from the fifth element?
You know, like with the mail comes in the little shoot chunk, you know, and the, the,
the vendors like, oh, it might be good news.
You're fired.
I do remember that when
Zerk has to get,
you know, to cool down the economy.
And, uh, yeah, I just, I guess what I'm saying is, don't lose hope.
I mean, Josh, you and I have been through what?
Well, the.com crash, the 2008 crash,
we seem to have a lot of these once in a lifetime crash
right now.
Yeah, they are every couple of years I think.
Actually, you know what's funny is the dot Bomb
was,
I graduated from college in 2001.
So, like, I was job seeking in the middle of the.com disaster
and
it, it worked out. I, I got, I mean, look, I love my first job.
It was for a little company that wrote life insurance software and they
needed a UNIX admin and it was all a IX and I was,
of course, the Linux nerd they hired to part partially,
they wanted me because I understood Linux because
they were investigating porting the product to Linux
and partially they just needed a UNIX nerd who could take care of things. And it was,
it was a wild job. But
yeah, I mean,
it is what it is, you know,
it wasn't particularly exciting. Like life insurance is not an exciting industry.
-- Thank goodness.
-- Well, it pays the bills.
But, but anyway,
it's, uh, I don't know.
And look, I mean,
I think one other thing to keep in mind is there's
going to be more of this like we're not done,
we're gonna see.
-- Well, it
-- seems to be about every 10 years now.
-- Uh Well,
-- no, I just mean, in this particular recession we're entering,
we're going to see more organizations cutting back on staff.
I mean,
one of the other things that happens to a lot is once you start cutting back on staff,
it's very common for a big company to cut back literally across the board.
And you're going to see
security teams, you're going to see reduced development teams,
-- you're going to see reduced sales teams like, like everywhere
-- I think.
Well, and a lot of this classic too will be
moving from a reliance on people to more on processing
and products because
again, that's something that's a
lot of these things have matured enormously,
you know, like I have, I mean,
well, some of the sales products I'm seeing now are,
you know, they, they save our sales people so much time.
There, there is some cool stuff and even in the world of security, I mean, there is,
there are better products for, like,
sifting through all of the alerts and all of that kind of stuff.
But
there's still, like,
when you take people away from a security
team that's probably already overworked now you're,
you're creating, like, what does that mean for the business?
-- What are they not doing? How does that work?
-- Where there blind spots? Yeah.
Yeah, it's, it's, it's going to be wild man, I think,
I think it'll be interesting to see.
So, something that would be fun. I don't,
it would be interesting to watch the companies that
reduce their workforce
and then look at, are there security, are there, like,
more or less security incidents?
Several months down the road?
And I'd have to guess roughly the same.
I, I don't know.
I mean, I,
-- I
-- honestly don't think it'll be that much of a contributing factor
just because security across the board is such a tire fire.
Probably. You're probably right.
But anyway,
anyway,
-- and there's
-- so many confounding factors too. Right.
This is like, trying to say, like, does eating mangoes make you healthier or not?
Well, there's just so many confounding factors. Now like,
well, I mean, what is it, what is it the causation or is it
correlation
or correlation does not mean causation? Right. That, that's the saying.
Right. Right.
And,
and
you can't control for like COVID or
monkey pox
or
-- you know,
-- I
know,
I know.
Yup.
-- It is what it is.
-- Speaking
of
good luck on your flights coming up.
-- Uh
-- this will come out, yes,
this will come out Sunday night and I will be getting up very,
very early on Monday to go to the Open Source Summit something or other
from the
foundation
in, in Austin, Texas. So if you're there, if you listen to this,
I, I guess right when it comes out,
there's a good chance, I'd say there's a higher than average chance, maybe,
maybe come say hi.
You know, I'd love to see you.
Yeah, I, I man,
I've only been on one airplane since COVID and like it wasn't
super exciting to me and I'm not super excited to travel again,
but I am excited to finally give some talks in front of humans.
I, although I did get my Star Trek talk at cipher
Khan and that was
an amazing treat
to get to speak in front of people and enjoy myself.
And I also escaped cipher Khan with no COVID.
So let's hope I escaped Texas with no COVID also,
but I'll be wearing lots of masks and,
and all that jazz. So, so we'll see we'll see anyway. Anyway,
and, and actually this is also, uh, we're talking about the GSD
and that, which we'll have to, we should,
we should talk more about that at some point.
But anyway,
-- I think,
-- especially as we get the edit button working.
Yeah, that's another story.
Just got to get the back to ba
it's,
you know, ok, so before we go,
I just want to mention kind of one thing and
I'm even experiencing this elsewhere as part of other,
like open SS f work I'm doing and even work at,
at, at, at a
car is,
it always feels so easy when you want to start a project, you're like, oh,
we'll just create a repo and then we'll write some code and then we'll do this thing
and
there's always some,
like writing the code is literally the easiest
and shortest part of the entire process.
There's like all the other stuff that consumes
so much time and building community is hard
and just everything like it's,
it always fascinates me when I
start any new project. And I'm like, oh, it won't be that hard.
And then I'm like, in three months,
I feel like nothing's done because all we've done
is commit some things to a repo and that's,
that's the easy part.
-- But anyway, anyway,
-- well, I think that's true of many things.
There's just, there's a lot of underlying work that people forget,
like having a house.
I like, I had to mow the lawn
that takes time.
You know, I
just, all these little things.
Yeah, it's true. It's true.
There's always the little stuff and I, yeah, anyway, I should,
whatever I'm calling this before we go off on some
ridiculous tangent that has nothing to do with anything.
Thank you everyone for listening. Thank you, Kurt.
Go to Social Security podcast.com. Head up our sh
it's easy.
Podos
says podcast hashtag hit us up on social media. Kurt have marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.