Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 118 with myself,
Kurt Siefried
and my partner in Thought Crime Josh Pressers.
So I'm starting to feel like I might be getting
sick and I don't know if that's just like,
like some sort of Stockholm Syndrome from talking to
you too much or if I'm legitimately becoming ill,
probably there's, there's been,
there's been two really nasty colds going around locally.
-- Yeah,
-- I know some people who are basically bedridden from catching whatever the,
the plague that's traversing the globe.
-- Is that the one with the puking?
-- I, I didn't ask for that level of detail, but
we'll see. Maybe.
Right. That's
when, when people tell me they're sick, that's not on my list of things. I, I ask them
no, social distancing works for preventing the spread of plagues and, you know,
the first week or two of school and
voila
the freshman
off.
That's right. That's right.
And, and thank goodness for airplanes now.
So the whole world can enjoy disease at the same time.
It's fantastic. Yeah.
Every time I travel there's somebody on the
plane sneezing or coughing and it's just like.
-- That's wonderful.
-- Yeah, seriously, man. I, I have a very large event in Europe.
I'm attending in a couple of weeks
and
I am completely confident I will,
I will leave with some sort of disease that somebody else brought with them.
-- It's
-- great. Can I suggest?
Because this is something I'm trying to do is I'm trying to no longer shake hands at
conferences because it's just too many people and
probably most of them have good personal hygiene,
but
some of them probably don't,
I would assume none of them do. It's easier. It's kind of like, assume, compromise.
Right.
I just assume nobody washes their hands and
I, I'm sensitive to what you say. But I, like, I'm a hands shaker
so I'm,
I'm probably never gonna not do that just because it's
something I do without even thinking about it and,
and rather than trying to,
to be something I'm not, I just wash my hands a lot.
Maybe I should get some golfing gloves or something.
Well, you don't know. Something that won't make my hands too sweaty. Right.
You're not a big enough weirdo.
-- Put on some gloves.
-- Yeah.
Well, just, I know because, like,
you shake somebody's hand and it's like moist and it's just like, oh,
-- nice.
-- Right. Where is that hand been?
Yeah.
Then you use
alcohol wipes.
-- Oh dear.
-- Just whatever it, it, and part of it as well is I view this as
the more disease I acquire when I'm younger.
Hopefully,
when I'm much older I will have some level of immunity that might keep me not dead
for longer.
I think we're past the point of that working because
just there's so much stuff going around all the time.
-- Now, let
-- me, let me have this one.
Ok,
I'll give you this one. We'll pretend it's 18 hundreds.
Yes.
That's right. You died of dysentery. You lose
anyway. Anyway. So, let's talk about cloud flare today. They're up to some
stuff.
Yeah. Well, I mean, they're usually up to some pretty cool stuff and
that's true.
To be blunt,
you don't do boring things and get 10%
of the world's internet traffic coming through your,
they
-- only have 10% 10
-- percent.
Well, it's,
it's depending on how you measure it
volumetrically versus number of requests versus whatever.
Right. So, like volumetrically, the majority of web traffic is video,
right? Like youtube
Netflix,
you know,
no offense. But you watch one hour of Netflix at four K
and that's equivalent to like reading every single
-- text web page for the rest of your life.
-- Right.
You know.
Right. Right.
Um, so, yeah, when you look at, you know,
iii I don't think we can measure web traffic simply by raw volume of traffic because,
yeah, all the video goes over it now.
So that kind of skews it a bit.
Um, number of requests is also a bit skewed because, you know,
just, you, you load a front page like cnn.com and it's got how many third party
things?
Like hundreds,
-- probably hundreds now. It's,
-- it's a lot.
Um Like, I'm just looking at, oh, wow.
Adblock plus 3403. Let's see. What's this other one blocking doing? It's uh 3499.
Uh Where's the other one?
Wait, this is how much crap is being blocked from cnn.com? No, no, no.
This is in total, like, since I've opened my browser right
now
and I use a youtube ad blocker. Holy jeez. And it says
total ads blocked 9972 total time, save two hours, 26 minutes, 27 seconds. And to
keep that in context, that's with like you only having to watch, I think,
what is it like three or five seconds of the ad and then you can skip it.
It, it depends.
So I actually don't block youtube ads on purpose because I feel like it's
altruistic of me to make sure the content creators are getting their ad revenue
and it's super annoying and there are more and more
unskippable 15 2nd ads lately it feels like and,
and I don't know if,
if everyone sees that or maybe they just decided I'm a sucker or something, but it's,
it's,
it's on all my mobile devices.
I don't have good ad blocking for youtube and II,
I personally cannot watch youtube videos on my ipad anymore.
It's just too annoying.
Um, my kids still watch youtube videos, obviously,
but they're like banging away at that skip ad button as soon as it pops up.
I also feel like it's a gentle reminder
from the universe to quit watching youtube and go
do something
-- else.
-- This is true.
This is hard to argue.
I tell you that as well because I know when I had no ads on youtube, it often be,
I'd start watching, you know, a video on, on security
and then I'd end up watching something about, you know,
like carving a duck out of a potato.
It's like, what, what have I done with my life for the last two hours?
So this way when like some horrible political ad pops up,
it shakes me out of my trance and I think, oh, crap.
-- Well,
-- it's like the Netflix Shame Screen. Are you still watching? It's like, yes.
Yes,
I am.
Yes.
Stop judging me
actually.
You know what, you know how I get around that is,
I always make sure I click the button instead
of letting it time out to the next episode.
And I'm also too impatient to wait the 13 seconds.
-- Are
-- you
one of those
people that takes, like,
stops the microwave and takes your food out with like one second to go.
I,
if I'm standing near it. Yes, because then it doesn't,
it doesn't beat through
times. It annoys me. I hate three beeps. I don't need three beeps
once
one beep is enough.
I want a setting on my microwave that says don't beep three times three is too many
anyway.
Yeah.
So
basically the thing with cloud floor has, uh,
rather cleverly is they found a business model
where the people using cloud flare for free added value to cloud flare, both
for the users and for cloud flare. Right.
Um, and it reminds me of, I don't know, this is going way back in the day,
but security focus.com way back in the day
acquired this start up, whatever that was basically,
they would take your firewall logs for free process
them and give you like a really pretty dashboard.
And when I say a really pretty dashboard, I'm talking about 1520 years ago
where nowadays if you looked at that dashboard,
you would cry because it's so terrible, right?
But back in the day that was all we had
and, and, and well to digress for a second,
but I never really understood what the point of that dashboard was because action
speaking, what are you going to do with it? Right.
But anyways
and,
and so much like that people would get their firewall logs going through the system,
they'd get their pretty dashboard, they show it to their boss, whatever,
everybody's happy.
But what this it allowed security focus to do
was to aggregate a whole big pile of essentially sensor data from the internet.
And so they could track things like internet worms and viruses going around,
you know, based on like, oh you know,
port 4321 is like getting super active starting in China now it's spreading to,
you know, Asia and oh, we, now we're seeing it in North America
and to build that sensor network obviously would be horrendously expensive,
you know.
So getting
we're, we're,
we've really strongly established. I think economically speaking data is
potentially very valuable and you can extract a lot of value from it as a company.
And you know, and,
and that to some degree is what cloud flare did by hosting
people's sites because part of it too is the marginal cost,
right?
Once they've built this system and have, you know,
a couple dozen points of presence around the globe and have it all working,
you know,
the incremental cost of adding a few million
websites that honestly like my website only see
kind of like 100,000 hits a month or something like which in today's terms is nothing
is like so close to zero as to effectively be zero.
You know,
like one gmail account is the cost of Google hosting. That is,
yeah, it's, it's pennies
and so
they've got all this traffic coming through their
system and that's part of their thing is,
you know, how do they keep kind of getting
more traffic and growing? Right?
Because their existing customers obviously will hopefully
be growing and getting more traffic.
But how do you acquire new customers? Right.
You've already got free, you've already got free. Http S that was a big one, right?
Like a lot of people. Oh, you know, I need to go to HTTP S,
oh, I just, I go to Cloud Flare for, for free.
Oh, that was easy. Click, click. Done. What, what's next?
Right. How do we, how do we make it better from here?
And clearly
IP FS Internet, what is it? Interplanetary file system?
Which is a great name.
Yeah, I wasn't, I was, at first I read that I was like,
are they doing something with the deep space network?
Like what?
That's the first thing I thought,
jeez,
we are
-- old men
-- and then I got sad to learn. They weren't.
Yeah, exactly.
So IP FS is,
as I understand it, the long and the short of it is
they run an IP FS gateway
that talks to an IP FS back end, which is this like file,
coin Blockchain thing anyways,
the long and the short of it is, is IP FS is
effectively, it's a Blockchain slash file system
that stores data.
Um, so you store a document in it,
like a web page and the sort of name of that web page
is a hash value for that web page and they use multiple hashes,
I think they said they use
sha 256 and something else. I forget what.
And so that's the
that big long fancy string is the
uh the the identifier of that web page. So
you go to an IP FS gateway slash the
site slash that identifier and you get that document.
So obviously you need like a, a bit of magic wrapped around it for, you know,
all the URL S and links to work and for people to be able to find things, right?
And people have, you know, they've written some tooling around that.
So you can like, basically you can take a static capture of a website
and dump it into IP FS
and you know,
all the links work and things like that, you know,
things like search and stuff won't work unless you kind of rebuild it.
What this means is
they are now strongly moving into the territory of,
you know, we're a carrier, we provide access to content,
we don't necessarily host that content ourselves
in the sense of
we may have a cache or a copy of that content,
but the actual back end hosting that content is not us, right?
It's, it's on wordpress.com or it's on your personal web server or it's
whatever, right?
And this is something that they've been pushing for a long time, right?
Because they, they keep coming back to the whole,
like we basically don't boot anybody off unless they're like, truly,
you know, really violating our terms of service,
right? And they did that once in the past um or at least once in the past that we know of.
Right. Right. Right.
And so this IP FS what this does is it gives people a way
to
host content in a way that is very hard to take down
because you basically have to get cloud flare to blacklist it,
but to actually get the back end taken down
is basically damn near impossible at this point.
Right. It sounds like the, the, the data can never be removed once you put it in
and
it's
a
Blockchain.
That's the
whole
point.
It's a magic Blockchain though because like
the Bitcoin Blockchain is hosted everywhere.
Whereas it sounds like this one,
you will have a subset of data on a client.
Well, you would set up your own copy of this Blockchain with your own data,
right?
Like
it's shared like you
-- control what you're sharing,
-- right?
Well, you could share,
you can run it privately or you can be part of the bigger one is my understanding,
right?
So
same thing could happen with Blockchain, right?
You can, you can effectively take a bunch of Bitcoins
for example, and do your own Bitcoin network now,
nobody would because the value of that smaller network is
much less than the large network.
Yeah, but that's stupid.
There's, there's no point in that.
Exactly.
Um Whereas with this, with hosting your own files, you can now take your files,
shove them into this IP FS thing, you know your own copy of it or the global copy,
as I understand it
and then get it fronted on cloud flare.
Well, you can even, I mean,
you could host it yourself.
I mean, well, you put yourself in quotes where you,
you plug your own website into this.
And I guess so here's, here's what I'm wondering about this. I see
kind of two plays here
is, first of all, this gives cloud flare access to
more data and I guess maybe easier for people to,
to upload data into the cloud flare ecosystem, right?
Because the idea here is you in theory,
just run this and start shoving stuff into it.
-- And now you have a website hosted somewhere.
-- Well, let's be even more brutal.
It allows people to shove content that may or may not be their
own content into a system where that content can no longer be removed.
Yeah, we'll get to that one.
And, and secondly though is so let's face it today.
A significant amount of data is stored on S3
and,
and
you can't build a new S3 and I I have a suspicion called
smart enough to know this and this is where a lot of people fail is they always think,
oh, we're going to compete with S3, we'll build a better and cheaper one.
But it's like you can't compete with the technology by copying it.
You have to out innovate it,
right? The scale of three, you just, you can't approach their call
and, and so here. But, well, some you could, you just need to be able to
like someone like Claude
might be able to where they build enormous data centers with.
But
so here's my point. Here's my point though is
we,
we kind of got taken the model of we have a giant file store
in Amazon to we have a giant shared file store that is the planet Earth
and this is
this is awesome in a lot of ways.
But the thing that I guess is somewhat terrifying here is
you need a lot of people to join into this to really make it scale,
right?
Because essentially you're going to be limited by the
disk space that's on probably N divided or,
or you know,
the number of users divided by some value because
there's also going to be some level of duplication
and it's not infinite.
And so it, it will be interesting to see how that works. I mean, let's face it.
You could conceivably
just fill this thing up with garbage and make it unusually slow and bad.
Well, my understanding is that currently all the IP FSS that are available,
essentially, you have to kind of, if you really want to use it,
you have to build your own IP FS Blockchain host it, run it and
get, you know, set up the gateway with cloud flare.
And the other thing to remember is I think one of the big problems is solving crap,
disappearing off the web all the time
-- in that part. I like a
-- lot. Right. And that drives me nuts.
It's really
annoying.
I was just at a conference besides Edmonton and, you know,
the, the main conference guy,
I guess a few days afterwards took the kind of took the site down and said, you know,
thanks.
See you guys next year.
And I was like, oh, please put the content back up because I want to like reference.
Exactly. I was like, please like, and he did like, he was like, oh, yeah, good point.
Right.
And I guess it just didn't occur to him that people
would still want to look at the schedule after the fact.
And I'm like, no, trust me,
you
please leave this up forever. You know, and that's,
you know, like I still maintain
cre.org. I haven't
updated or changed it in like over a decade.
Right? It just lives in an S3 bucket.
We're using cloud Florent to
turn it into a website and
that's it.
Right. And that, that will be there.
I need to do this with, with my website breast.net and I should,
I should investigate this and see if I can't just use
IP FS instead because it would be fun to learn.
And
it, it like, it's just some static content at this point.
It's, it's nothing exciting. It hasn't done anything exciting in
you
as I understand it right now. You'd have to run your own IP FS.
Um I don't
know where you would get access to an IP
FS where you can just upload your arbitrary content.
But no doubt those will exist at some point.
And that's the question. Right? Can I,
I don't know.
Well, the thing is also once you upload data into an IP FS,
as long as that IP F is running that content is available.
Well. Right. exactly.
You can't selectively delete a bunch of it.
Like I can accidentally delete my half my S3 bucket or whatever and be like whoops
now.
Right. Right. Well, that's why.
But even then you can set up rules like for example, with S3,
all my buckets have rules that anything I delete
sticks around for 30 days before it's deleted for real,
just so I can accidentally screw things up.
I'm more likely to forget to pay my Amazon bill of like $3 a month at some point.
And then, you know, Amazon will turn it off.
Right.
Yeah, that,
that is actually my biggest fear is my credit card being
declined someday and then they delete all of my data.
That's actually probably the biggest scenario for cloud data loss
is billing related issues.
So I,
I think what I really like about this
IP FS though is that we're strongly establishing
these content networks as effectively as carriers in
that classic American sense of the phone network of
we're not responsible for this content.
And,
but here's the trick cloud flare is getting to a point
where they can sort of have their cake and eat it,
but we're not responsible for this content.
But if it is really heinous content, you can tell us and we will block it.
And so they have that out of,
yeah, we, we kind of agree that there is some content that is so heinous that. Yeah, I
just,
I I'm not even
going to say
that,
I mean,
you can have copyright
issues, right?
Where somebody might own a video and if I upload the video to my website
and then you get a takedown order like that's perfectly legitimate and I'm OK with
so,
yeah, I mean, uh I think, I think this is good because quite frankly,
obviously I'm a bit bullish on the Blockchain now
that my job title is Chief Blockchain Officer.
And I think
this property of many blockchains of, you know, once the data is in there,
it's in there, it cannot be removed
is applicable to a lot of systems.
And here's the thing, I think that really changes things that people are forgetting
data storage used to be expensive and we had to curate the data and get rid of stuff.
You know, it's like like a lot of libraries, right?
They,
they get rid of their old books and they
get rid of garbage because they have finite space.
That's not a problem in the data world really anymore.
It, it is true.
Not
only that,
not only that, I guess here's the thing I keep thinking of,
this might end up being a terrible idea
and cloud flare might end up abandoning it in a couple of years.
But even if they abandon it,
they're going to learn things that will be invaluable in the future
-- and the rest of us will learn too because, you know the experience of it.
-- Exactly.
Exactly. And I think that's the beauty of doing something like this is
even if you fail, if you learn some lessons, you didn't really fail.
And, and that's what excites me more than anything is the things we're going to learn
to go off on a tangent.
Our research and development has really been gutted in a lot
of the western world and R and D has gone from,
you know, something we have as a budget line item
to, we spend money on start ups. So essentially you're, you're,
you're providing a lottery pool for people who do the R and D privately.
And if it works out then they, they win, you know,
they get acquired and they go public or whatever.
And
the other thing with R and D is a lot of R and D now is like, no, this has to be directly,
um, something we can product
like right away.
Like my favorite example being the swifter, like God, I hate the swifter. I get it.
It's useful, it's handy.
But fundamentally the amount of R and D that was spent on the swifter to come up.
Like, it's like razor blades. Have you heard the latest thing in men's razor blades?
He has no idea
why would you want that?
Apparently it makes the shave more comfortable or something.
I'm just like, whatever I use
warm water,
hot water,
hot water, warm water. Yeah.
But, you know, remember we went, we were now,
I think what is the maximum six or eight blades or something stupid?
There's ones that vibrate, there's ones that squirt goo, there's ones with like,
something on the bar.
So you want to know something really funny is I bought
a safety razor because the blades are like three cents each
and it, it does a very nice job.
It's, and it's enjoyable. I have a brush and soap and,
yeah, I, I, I've done it in the past but the problem I find is with a safety razor, I,
I gotta pay attention whereas with like a five bladed razor
I can just hack away at my face half asleep and,
like,
I just can't cover
myself.
It is true.
It's easy to look like you've been in a bar
fight with you to shaving with a safety razor.
But,
-- yeah, it's, it's an acquired skill.
-- Oh,
totally.
Yeah.
But, um, no, back to this, I mean,
it, I also like the idea of this,
you know, it drives me nuts like sun.com. It's gone.
Right.
Um,
there's all these websites that had
good technical documentation that's just gone.
Right.
There's so much stuff that it was out there at some time and
it probably is still out there. But good luck.
Well, here's, so,
here's the other half of that though is if
cloud flare decides not to host old content,
this doesn't save us because today it sounds like their,
their front end is pretty much the only way
in at the moment and hopefully that changes.
But,
you know what I mean?
Yeah. Oh, I agree. And I mean, ii, I don't know, I can't speak for cloud flare.
I mean, on the one hand, they,
they do
generally seem to be a reasonably well behaved network player,
but on the other hand, like,
they're certainly not open sourcing their crown jewels.
And I don't blame the one bit for that because,
like, come on folks, like, really, you know,
and part of it too is, you know, I keep coming back to with a lot of these cloud players,
for example,
let's say Amazon web services was like, oh, you know what?
We got a little drunk last night and we decided we're just,
we're going to open source, all of our source code for all of Amazon web services.
Would it matter?
And the answer is not really because
the operational experience needed to run something,
the scale of Amazon
I can give you the code and I can give you the source code and I can give you all the docs.
But like the only other people that have the expertise
to run something that big are like Google and Microsoft,
nobody else has anything remotely that big that
and understands the scale issue,
right?
You know, it'd be like giving you and me
the blueprints to an Airbus 320 it's like, no, we can't build this in our
garage. We can't do anything with that.
However, however you say that and there,
there are players in other parts of the world that could take that
and, and do something with it could damage Amazon as an organization. So
it
-- is a tricky line to walk for
-- sure what I'm saying essentially is we're,
we're at the point now
and this is especially true with cloud services.
Cloud.
The thing people really got to remember is
cloud services are not just good software,
they're good software combined with good operations.
Yeah.
And I think that's part of,
and I think that's part of what cloud flare has been doing traditionally is
cloud flare has traditionally been
taking on that ops work for their customers.
You know, I I very early went to Cloudflare because
oh, for like 20 bucks a month plus, uh what is it? $5 a month for every domain after that
you guys will do my SSL certificates and all of the, you'll eat all my D DOS
attacks
and you'll basically do like
my DNS serving and, you know, a whole pile of stuff
done.
Right.
They make it easier and, and let's, I mean,
let's bring up this onion service right now because of that.
-- Like, oh
-- God, getting an onion service.
Right. It's terrible.
And, and now cloud flare, you have the ability to, basically, your website can be,
have, have a dot onion address on the Tor network.
Well, it still feeds into the whole kind of concept of and this with
Tor Onion especially we don't host the content
and we can't
necessarily like we can blacklist the content, but we cannot,
absolutely cannot take it down and we can't even tell you who's hosting it.
It's just this dot onion address and God knows where it is,
you know, unless you're the NSA and you start turning off like half the internet to,
you know, ok, we turn off that half it was still up, ok.
Turn off this other half it went down, ok.
You know, start localizing it like crazy stuff like that
if a Tor
service is run properly and not, you know, exposing its public IP address.
Yeah, it's, it's the, it's just, it's,
there's content online that we can't take off, we can block it but we can't
remove it.
Well, although now the one thing I will say
is the, the advantage I can see to what cloud flare is doing is
if you want to run your own onion service.
You, there's a lot of heavy lifting and it's actually painful to get. Right.
Whereas now anybody can have a dot Onion address,
meaning there are people in
certain places that can access your site where they may not have been able to before.
-- And so that could have an advantage.
-- Didn't,
uh, China just block Twitch. Yeah, they just block Twitch game streaming.
Ok.
That's it. It's, it's, it's turned off for now until they decide to turn it back on.
Right.
Yeah, exactly. That's,
you know, that's, uh, yeah, like we run into this all the time.
Well, I run into this, you know, the, I want to CV e.org thing is
ad N
sect to a Google form because
I'm not hosting a form.
Google does it great, you know, it feeds into a spreadsheet and I can access it
and, you know, once in a while, uh, everybody in China just can't do it
interesting, you know, trying to block Google once in a while,
it just happens. Right.
Right.
So, you know, and,
and I part of me really disagrees with that and part of me is really like, well,
you know, China is a sovereign country and they get to pick their rules
and what they
-- want
-- and
it
is, I can disagree with them personally,
but obviously what I think doesn't change their policy,
-- which
-- is
probably
more to the
point. I think we firmly established sovereign countries get to do what
generally speaking they want to do.
Right. And that's just part of the,
that's just part of how it works
and that is a huge threat to clown flare. And they're
raison
d'etre,
you know, that's their core thing is to get this content to people.
Well, things like the great firewall of China make that a big problem.
So, things like this
allow them to, you know, get their, get the content out.
Um And there's a lot of people with content who really,
really want it to be available to everybody,
right?
And, and there's one other advantage, the Tor or not,
the Tor the cloud Fuller website says about this is today.
If you visit a lot of websites through
Tor,
it will give you a capcha or it'll say things like you have to
wait to make sure you're not like conducting ad D OS or whatever.
And so it is like tours already slow and then you add that on top and it becomes really,
really slow.
And so I, I won't lie.
I will appreciate that because I mean, anytime I see a dodgy URL,
I need to check out like fire up tour.
Like I, I'm not going to that with my browser, like I don't need a visit from the feds
to go into some crazy website.
So it, I don't know.
Again,
I feel like this is one of those things that
I applaud cloud flare for trying something new and different.
And let's see if it works and even if it doesn't,
we're going to learn something new and interesting.
Well, but it also lets people experiment with these technologies and use them.
You know, like,
because the bar to entry to a lot of technologies is quite painfully high.
Yes.
And not only that, you know what,
you know what I love with the onion addresses is
your onion address
is based upon an RS A
key ID
and like Facebook has one that has Facebook at the beginning of it.
And I guess they used an insane number of computers to brute force it
generate a
couple billion keys.
When you're Facebook, you just run that
and I can totally do that.
Actually you put in Amazon or just how much GP U time are you willing to buy?
Right, $0. That's my budget.
So
right. We'll get right on that.
Indeed. Indeed.
That that is one of the things I think of those
sometimes that could be fun to like just pre generate a gazillion
torque
onion addresses and look for fun ones like with, you know,
maybe foul language or clever sayings.
But again, I'm I'm too lazy to do that. So,
and I guess this is one of the other advantages log
flare brings is
you can use the dot onion addresses because
they're stored in a organization's DNS record,
which is,
which is actually really cool because now you don't
have to worry about going to ridiculous string.
I possibly can't type in and have to copy and paste from somewhere
to, I'll just type in, you know, conf.com and I end up in the Tor network.
So that's neat.
Yeah. No, like I said, the
usability is something we often forget. That is a huge barrier
to entry.
Uh
Yes. And Tor
is
in Tor
is comically unusable.
It is,
is not too bad anymore.
II, I tried out the Tor Browser the other day just to see if it, what it was like.
It's nice. You run it, it connects and you do tour stuff.
I mean, I wouldn't dare use it for anything.
I would consider a sensitive operation but for like just
checking out random URL S, it's, it's totally awesome.
-- All right, man, I, I think we need to call this one. Do you have any parting
-- thoughts?
Maybe? Try, try something new today?
That's fair, I guess. Good job plot flair. Keep, keep the fire,
right?
Alright, sweet. So thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up the show notes.
I will put a link to the IP FS client in the show notes which actually Kurt and
I tried to find this before the show and it took us much longer than it should have.
So
-- we will save you the trouble if you go to
-- check out the
show
it was very hard to find and then you can hit,
you hit us up on social media with the Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag and yeah, Kurt, have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks. Bye bye.