Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
I am
so excited.
We have, we have a repeat guest, one of the most amazing projects on the planet.
So we have Josh O is the executive
director of internet security Research Group ISRG,
which is better known,
we'll say by as let's encrypt even though that's not really your name.
-- Josh. Welcome back to the show.
-- Thanks for having me
-- looking forward to
-- it.
We're so excited you were,
you were on the show in May of 2018 and I'll put a
link in the show notes to the first episode you did with us.
But
listening to that show was very surreal
because let's encrypt was, I mean, you were four years old,
which is not
young necessarily, but it was really just starting I think to gain traction.
We were, we discussed chrome
adding the insecure icon for http websites which let's face
it without let's encrypt that could have never happened.
And it's just, it's very surreal listening to our discussion from what,
what is that?
That's four years ago now
versus today. When, like,
let's encrypt. You won. I mean, it's, it's no one even asked questions anymore.
It's amazing.
Yeah, we've had a lot of growth.
We're up to, I think almost 300 million websites
today.
290 maybe.
Yeah,
there was, like,
I think it can be summarized as there was a comment on
hacker news pointing out that lets and crypt not only killed,
like, a billion dollar certificate industry,
but it replaced it with something that was better and free.
Like straight up.
We didn't set out to kill anything, but we didn't set out to make some things better.
And I think we've succeeded in that stupid question.
But why haven't the certificate authorities done some
of these automation things that you've done like,
seriously?
Like, like not only are you free but you're easier, like,
because I just set up cert bot
and
it's the wrong cool rotisserie. There's no step two.
-- It just works.
-- Well, I should say first that I actually don't
know that much about what other certificates are. Authorities are doing.
I mean, we're pretty focused on what we're doing and we,
we pay surprisingly little attention to
what other certificate authorities are doing good
-- in a normal sense. You know, we, they're
-- doing the same thing they were always doing.
We love talking to them when we have chances to collaborate
with them and we have some really good relationships with other cas
um talking about the acne protocols that we use and I think they,
they are definitely making progress.
There are a good handful,
if not most of the major cas support acne in some form or another these days.
So I think the whole industry is moving forward.
You know,
we have the advantage of starting from scratch and being able to do whatever we want.
No existing, you know, no existing subscribers, no contracts, no,
you know, legacy tech that we built
1020 years ago. So that's a pretty big advantage no matter who you are.
And I think trying to move
an existing,
you know, billion dollar industry in another direction,
that's a much harder task in some ways.
So
I think they're working on it and I'm glad to see them making some progress.
Awesome. Absolutely. Ok.
I don't,
I don't even know where I want to start with this one because there's just so much, ah,
you've done so much.
It's absolutely amazing. II, I guess
why don't we start with, give us the state
of
let's, and I'm gonna just call you lets and crypt from darling because that's
what I have in my brain. So I'm gonna, I'm gonna give up
just, just like, lay it out for us. Like, what do we look like today?
What, like, how, how big are we talking, how many certificates are you issuing on a,
on a regular basis?
Just
what is, what is the state of the universe?
Sure. So we're serving almost 300 million websites today.
2 9200 and 90 million, almost exactly.
We do that
with about 220 million active certificates.
So, since you can have multiple websites per cert so active means,
uh, we issued it and it has not yet expired and ours are valid for 90 days.
You know, that, that's how we're doing,
but how the web is doing is probably the more important issue.
And back before we started,
you know, in 2015, about 39% of all page loads on the web.
So that's every page you load, not just website,
you know, we're looking at what percentage of page loads are encrypted
and it was about 39% right before we started issuing
certs and today in the United States it's up to 93%
in the, in the globally, it's up to 81%.
So it's, we're living in a very different
world on the web today and it's much safer for everybody.
So this is, you know, this is what we set out to do,
make the web much safer and do it fast. Where in web terms, five years is pretty fast.
I mean, I guess we're up to seven years now, but the goal was to, you know,
get as far as we can in a relatively quick time because we don't want to,
-- people shouldn't have to wait 1020 years for security, you know.
-- Right.
Oh, my goodness. Amazing.
So, ok,
so let's start with, I saw on your website,
I looked at your kind of recent things that happened and you just received,
I think a grant from the Ford Foundation
and I, I that made me realize
the work you do is not free, right?
Someone is paying for this work. So explain to me
what the kind of how are you paying for all this? Because obviously
I can get free certificates, but they're free to me, they're not free to you. Right.
Right.
So we have roughly speaking three
revenue streams,
most of the money that is used to operate lots
of crypt and other projects comes from corporate sponsorships.
So that's
corporations out there that recognize the work that we do is important
and they make contributions to us.
And so most of our revenue is corporate sponsorship,
probably the second biggest category is grants.
So that's like the Ford Foundation and some other stuff.
And the third category is individual giving.
So that's people who come on our website and
you know, donate any amount of money that works for them.
And there's some really great information about all this stuff.
Like more than what I have on top of my head in this moment
in our annual report.
Um We have a team at, at,
at our organization does a great job putting together
that annual report that has a ton of information,
including a breakdown of, of where we bring in money.
And I think that's,
I think that's still,
you can get that. It's not too hard to find.
-- Yeah, it'll
-- be in the show notes.
So anyone, anyone interested should, should go totally check that out.
Ok. So
I guess
I was not aware prior to, we'll say a couple of days ago when I figured it out that I,
as a person can donate to.
Let's encrypt. That is very cool.
Actually, you can, and not only can you donate, but we're excited to team up with yo,
this September
so you can support a more secure web and bolt through your own
security at the same time with an easy to use authentication key.
So when you donate 50 or $50 or more by September 30th,
you'll receive a coupon code for either a security key
NFC or a security key C NFC from me.
-- And that's for shipping in the United States
-- only.
That's pretty awesome. I think those things cost more than $50.
Yeah.
Well, those ones, yeah, they're like 50 or 60.
Yeah, they're worth every penny though. I mean,
I use them, our
staff uses them.
They are a really important part of our security
posture for the whole organization and lots encrypt.
It, it's a great way to improve your own security.
It makes, it's the best thing you can do to avoid getting fished.
Yes.
Yeah, we're, we're pretty big fans.
We, uh, we'll say we've talked about it more than once or twice.
-- So,
-- one thing I'm curious about and,
and I don't really want specifics but kind of what are your major expenses?
Because I know again, like,
I remember back in the day when like
coating a bunch of servers on 100 megabit
line was horrifically expensive and like a server was
lots of money.
And now, like, if you spend 50 grand on a server, you basically get,
what was the 19 eighties internet in a box?
And like bandwidth wise,
it's not free but it's not expensive anymore. So like,
is it just people, is it?
Yeah, by far our biggest expense is people. So salaries,
um, in the organization in total, we have 22 or 23 people right now.
And about 11 of those are engineers that work on lots encrypt.
And so if we're talking about lots encrypt in particular,
staff,
staff salaries are by far the most expensive part of doing this, you know,
good people,
you got to pay them
the rest of it. You know, it is not necessarily cheap but it's,
you know, maybe a third of what the salaries cost, you know,
I'm not sure I have the exact numbers here.
But, you know, if salaries are 3 million, maybe the,
the rest of the stuff like hardware and things
like that are a million and change a year.
So it's not, it's not.
But when you, when you divide this out. You know, you're thinking about
maybe $4 million a year to run.
Let's encrypt itself that is not a lot of money to serve 300 million websites.
That's like,
let's straight up like a penny
-- to
-- serve the
internet.
And I remember you specifically mentioned you could not even charge a penny for
these things because then people would have to haul out a credit card except,
oh, wait,
can't have a credit card or that country has a blah, blah, blah or you know what I mean?
And,
and I was like, oh yeah, like even, even 1/10 of a penny would be too much because
it would be a hassle, but
it kind of blows my mind. But
-- yeah,
-- yeah, we're trying to make it
as easy as possible and price is part of that, you know, and as you said,
it's not just the price, not the sticker price.
It's the fact that going through billing
motions introduces a lot of friction for people
and makes things unavailable for a while
when people give us money, that's a big deal to me.
Like people can choose to spend their money in a million
different ways and when they choose to give money to us,
we really
take that seriously and try to do the most good we possibly can with it.
So one question,
because I was actually kind of under the impression let's encrypt was just,
let's encrypt, but it turns out.
Lets encrypt is actually
part of the internet security research group, which to be honest,
I had to look up like Josh said, you know,
like we're going to call you let and crypt because that's what,
what we know you of. So what is the Internet security research group?
So
Isrg is the nonprofit that runs lots encrypt. So lots
and crypt is not the name of a nonprofit. It's the name of a service that's run by Isrg.
So originally Isrg was created to be the home for Lots encrypt.
But the reason we didn't call it Lots encrypt is that we knew that in the future,
we might do other things besides Lots.
Encrypt,
which turned out to be the case.
So today, Isrg has three projects and the, the largest
and most well known of those projects is Lots Encrypt.
We have a second one called Divvy Up, which is
helping to
bring privacy, respecting metrics to the web.
So that's deployed right now to help with a
lot of COVID exposure notification applications around the world
or we're providing,
you know,
a secure background to process a lot of the metrics
that the systems use because we're asking people to,
you know,
trust us to collect some of the stuff.
And then we got to do a really good job
making sure we're not invading anyone's privacy with that.
So
Divvy Up is intended to take this
work that we did to help out with the COVID situation and
bring it to lots of lots of kinds of applications out there.
So that could be web, could be mobile
desktop, things like that.
So we're trying to, to make metrics collection more privacy, respecting.
Our third project is called Pro
Simo.
And that is where we are trying to bring memory safety to some of the
most important services that uh software that
we use when we're running our services.
So when I say the most important stuff, I mean, like the Linux kernel, DNS, tlsntp,
like the stuff that every,
every computer, certainly every server is running out there.
You know, most of that stuff is written in C it's not memory safe.
You know, if you run a server,
you're doing security updates all the time and
a huge percent of that percentage of that,
you know, maybe 70% is memory safety vulnerabilities.
When you get an update on your phone,
it is typically a long list of memory safety vulnerabilities.
So I think we got to get away from C and go to safer languages. So the promo
project is moving some of this really
the most critical stuff to safer implementations.
And then we want to use that at LS
Encrypt
and
D, but we also want other people to use it as well.
-- Well, it's
-- pretty clear to me that the last, over the last 20 years, well,
now 25 years of the web that yes, he has, we can't fix it.
Yeah,
there's been a lot of effort put into things like static analysis and sandbox
and fuzzing
and that stuff is great because I do think you get a good bang for your buck there,
but it doesn't solve the problem and it's kind of an expensive ongoing thing.
Whereas if you can move to a safer language, yes, it's more work up front for sure.
But you can more or less solve the problem and,
and not have to pay the price going down the road.
Well, and I think it's that traditional cat and mouse game, right? Where
we created things like stack canaries and sandboxes
and various memory checking
libraries
and that held off the Attackers for a while.
But the Attackers have figured out how to go around a lot of it. It's still hard.
But
I think
the, the the cat has caught the mouse again and now it's time to do something else.
And, and I think this is,
this is a brilliant project
because
you're right. C can't be used. And now we have things like Rust, right?
That are memory safe and, and performing and are easy to integrate.
So I'm really excited about proo
I didn't know about your divvy up. I would like to talk
about that for a few moments because I think this one is a
-- really cool idea
-- divvy up is meant to,
you know, if you want to collect information about a population,
you typically have to go collect information about individuals and
then sort of sum it up and get the averages.
And the problem here is even if you don't want to know about individuals,
you just want to know about the population,
you normally have to ask a bunch of individuals
questions in order to learn about the population.
And so the goal here is to kind of let you have your cake and eat it
too to get you the aggregate metrics that you
want without actually collecting the data from individuals.
So the way that this works, let's imagine a cell phone and, and to be clear,
the cryptography and the things going on here are
pretty advanced.
And
you know, I'm not an actual engineer who works on
dup,
they know a lot more than me and probably are smarter than me to boot.
So there are limits to the depth here, but I will give you a pretty good overview.
So let's say you have a cell phone app and you want to collect metrics about,
you know, how many times somebody clicks on a certain button or might,
you know, be, be like
the frequency of something that they do.
OK.
So
you'll start collecting a counter of that information on the
phone so that it is still on your phone here.
And then when you're ready to send it,
your phone will apply some local anonym organization techniques.
So for example, if you're looking for an average,
the phone might change your data so that it's not exactly what you did,
but it averages to the same thing.
That's like a rough overview of that kind of technique.
So we apply a little bit of fuzz on the phone before your data ever leaves the device.
And then we basically split that data into two pieces
and we encrypt the two pieces with two different encryption keys
and one belongs to Isrg as divvy up and the other one belongs to someone else.
So it could be you running your own provider, you
it could be another provider like divvy up and then
the data leaves your phone split up in two pieces.
So it's had some local anonym organization
and then it's split up
and we cannot read the other half, they cannot read our half.
So by the time we get the data,
the data already,
you know,
we don't know what the original data on your phone was by the time it gets to us
and we're playing in the same stuff from a bunch of other people.
So we would call it a batch but a batch, you know, could be
thousands of people or phones could be a million. I don't know,
it's a batch, it's a bunch of people.
And then we take this bit of the half of the data that this batch of people sent
us and we sum it all together or we
do whatever mathematical operation we're trying to figure out here
could be averages, could be something else.
And then we come up with the aggregate
stats for that batch. But remember this is just half.
So then we send what we call our partial aggregate
to
an aggregator that takes our partial aggregate and the other partial
aggregate from the other provider and sort of sums that together.
So you get the full aggregate,
so you get the, you get the final stats about the population that you're looking for.
But the data was
not sensitive the moment I left your phone, right. So like
let's div
app never had enough data to know what you were doing and the
other provider never had enough data to know what you were doing.
And the APP provider at the end here who's
looking at the stats never had your data either.
So
it's tricky.
It's not the easiest thing to understand in the world, but it's a,
it's a really important innovation that I think came out of, of Stanford
and Mozilla
spent a good amount of time championing it and we are hoping to
take it the next step.
And
I don't think it's realistic to ask
application makers and to stop collecting stats about populations.
It's too important, they're not going to stop.
We just need to try to make it safe and this is a really great mechanism for doing that.
That is not what I understood at all that description is way cooler because
you're not even sending sensitive data somewhere else.
And I think if you think about data in the historic sense,
it has always been about send sensitive data somewhere and
we'll say trusted and I'm making ear quotes that,
that no one can see and
you have to rely on that trusted person to anonymize the data properly,
which they never do.
And studies have shown time and time again that it can be de anonymized
easily.
This is
this is very, very cool and I think it makes way more sense.
OK?
So a perfect example,
it's actually my marketing team wanted me to
enable demographics on one of our websites.
And I'm like, OK,
and
we actually don't want your information.
We just want to know like what percentage are from this country,
what percentage are on this type of device, what percentage, you know what I mean?
Like we actually don't want to know stuff about you.
And I'm, I'm also one of the DP OS data protection officers at the CS A. So I'm like
very strongly,
I don't want your data because then I have to take care of it and that's more work.
And I don't like more work.
In this case, it's not too bad because it's just, well,
we get the data from Google and Google's just doing Google stuff.
And
but yeah, at the same time,
these people have to trust Google not to leak it or to sell it or to whatever.
And as we've learned, you know,
from some other providers like maybe Facebook or whatever that,
yeah, they're not so good at that,
not so trustworthy.
And
this is a good example because like we absolutely need that aggregate data.
And in our case, we very explicitly do not want the
individual data.
And I know enough about this to know that even if we like
kind of. Well, perfect example, if only one person visits our website,
that
statistical aggregate is now one person, right? Like so
yeah, I I we're not going to try and de mask anybody, but at the same time, obviously,
that is, that's the thing that happens, right?
Like that German researcher that was like, hey, look at this anonymous data, except
you spend eight hours here at night and eight hours here during the day.
Well, that's where you sleep and that's where you work and now we know who you are.
Yeah, this is a win for everybody.
You know, the the people who are getting their data collected
are
getting great privacy production here, right?
Their data is basically not leaving their phone in a recognizable way.
And the organizations are getting the insights without taking the data, right?
It's much less of a liability for them. So
if you're, you know, the legal department of the company wants to collect some data,
you should love this because you're getting what you
want and you are not paying the price.
You know, you, you do not have this toxic data sitting on your server somewhere.
No, I love the idea because we have like, like I've actually consistently
at
the CS A.
We, we try to collect as little data as possible,
so I don't have to protect that stuff because it's just,
it's a pain,
like it's a super pain and you have to protect it forever.
And so, yeah, if I could have some magic system that would like,
I get my aggregates and I don't have to have your name.
Yeah, I would love that.
Yeah. So the challenge here for us is that the,
the cryptography and the system is actually fairly complex.
You know, there's a document
in the ITF working group
where we're trying to standardize the stuff that lays it all out, but it,
it's not that easy to understand and it's not that easy to implement.
The challenge for us is how to take this thing that does something really amazing,
but it's pretty complex
and make it really simple for people to consume,
you know, complex security
and privacy technology
does not have a good track record if it's not made really easy to use,
you know, so
we want to implement this stuff correctly.
But the real challenge is packaging it so that when you want
to use it for your website to collect some demographic information,
you do not need to know how this thing works, right? Like
it is our job to make sure that you do
not need to know all these cryptographic details and anonym
organization techniques that are happening.
We want to give you a library that you can use on the web or the phone or whatever
and just say, you know,
here's a configuration blob for it.
Here's how you feed data into the API and we will take care of the rest of it.
Well, you've done it once before, so I have a strong suspicion, you'll do it again.
-- I hope you're right.
-- This is exactly what people said about TLS certificates
10 years ago.
Googling, what is it? The keywords are Google open SSL create blah, blah, blah.
And then hopefully you get the right one on stack overflow and then
you realize it's a self signed key and not a CS R and then,
and then you realize the CS R is screwed up because it added
this field you don't need and then eventually you get it right?
Alright. Alright. I want,
before you run out of time, I do want to talk about
it's pros.
Is that pronounced correct?
I
think
Simo,
I
believe, I believe it's an Italian word for next
and I don't speak Italian so I could be butching the pronunciation.
It's fine. It's fine. OK. This one I want to talk about a little bit because I think
it is something near and dear to topics, Kurt and I have discussed,
we'll say at length on this show over the however long we've been doing it and
you, you touched on this a little while ago,
but kind of memory safety and all the pitfalls and cucks
and we all know that stuff.
But I think the, the truly clever bit
of what I understand
is
when we look at attempts to bring memory safety in the past,
it has always been like a a lift and replace
process, right?
Where we're saying, oh, we're going to throw away this application,
we're going to rewrite it in something else.
And after a year of work,
we have something much worse than the original and it's not uncommon
at all to just be like it wasn't that bad after all,
I guess.
And we just kind of ignore the work we spent doing.
Whereas the effort you're doing is not a lift and replace.
It's a slowly replace the most sensitive portions of something as you go.
And I guess we kind of end up with the ship
of Theseus sort of situation where hopefully we eventually replace it.
All right.
-- Yeah,
-- that's roughly the plan there,
there are different approaches that work better in different contexts.
So
what we really prefer is a modular approach where we
look at a big piece of software and we say,
you know, what is one module or one component of this where we can swap out
a library written, see and swap something written rust as easily as possible
and do that. Ideally with the support
of the maintainers of the project, that's,
that's the dream because not only are you delivering value
much more quickly and not depending on something rewrite,
but also you can focus on these libraries, right?
So like a TLS library is a perfect example where
if we put a lot of effort into building a great
TLS library, we can swap that into a bunch of different things.
So for example,
we can swap our Russ TLS library into the curl utility and we
can do the same thing into Apache ht pe the web server.
So libraries are great because we can focus on something,
make it a really high quality replacement and swap it in.
And our strategy is also to put cap
around the Rust libraries so that the people maintaining the software don't even
need to learn Rust to swap out critical components for Rust components.
That's definitely our our preferred strategy.
But there are there are cases where not all software is modular or
some software is
relatively simple and it makes more sense to just
rewrite it.
So it's not the same approach in every context, but we definitely prefer modular.
Sure. Sure.
OK. So how does this actually happen? Because you mentioned the maintainers and
is are the maintainers doing some of this work?
Are you bringing in other developers to do this work? Are you doing the work?
-- Like, I'm curious what this looks like.
-- For the most part, we do not do the work. We
make strategies and do a bunch of coordinating work and we manage the contracts. So
typically we figure out what we want to do and
we do that by talking to maintainers and community members
and
people who know more about a specific piece of software than we do.
And we come up with a plan
and then when we're ready, when we have a really good plan that we're happy with,
typically, we go out and see if we can pay the maintainers to do the work for us.
Um
Our, our goal is to try to provide financial assistance, to maintainers
to do whatever work it is that we want
in some cases that doesn't make sense.
You know, some maintainers have full time jobs and they don't,
you know, they're not going to
take a year long contract to work on something.
So then our next step is usually to say,
are there other developers that are already a part of the project that you trust?
Um
You know,
there are recommendations that you have since this is going to be a
bunch of work on your project or the people you trust that we can
financially support to do this work.
And if that doesn't work out,
then we'll help go and find contractors to do the work and
help start a relationship between the contractors and the maintainers so that,
you know, everybody's on the same page about what's happening.
But generally speaking,
the work that we do is done through contractors,
whether that is the maintainers themselves or
other contractors that we help find. And we have a really great,
you know, pool of contractors to pull from after working on this for a while.
Sorry, stupid question. So, for example, Russ,
how do you pronounce that? Rust? Ls Russ TLS,
Russell?
Oh,
I would not guess that Russell. Ok.
So Russell's, I,
I took a quick look and it says it's a fully drop in replacement for openness cell.
Cool.
How do you then actually go get people to use it because like I'm,
I'm guessing it's not the default on any major Linux distribution yet.
Like nobody's actually swapped out open SSL for Russell
yet or have they
people definitely have in a,
in internal project.
There may be external ones that I'm, I'm not aware of,
but you got to build this stuff up.
So
there is a long list of companies and pieces of software using Russell already.
Uh a lot of that stuff is internal, but there's, there's external stuff too.
There are a lot of Rust based projects that want to
use a Rust TLS library and that's a natural choice for them
for us. You know, we are, our goal is to make it the default somewhere. Like ideally
open SL cell will go away. And be replaced by Russells.
And the reason is not, it's not because we think
open SSL,
the people behind that are bad or anything but open SSL is written in C and it's
going to continue to have security problems like that.
Yeah,
there's a bit of a plato flaw for that and it probably needs to go away for that.
So ultimately, if we want to make a default,
we need to find a way to get it
into Linux distributions and into larger pieces of software.
So we started with an experiment to get it into curl. So we,
you know,
had the maintainer of curl
work to replace the HEP library with a Russ Hep library.
And then in this rare instance, we had one of the people who works with Isrg
replace
uh open SSL with Russell's
in
curl and, and do that work
while the maintainer was doing the other work.
So today you can go build Curl with mostly Rust networking. So Rust Hep, Rust DLS
and our hope is that
in the next
distributions or anyone who is packing a machine up curl will say, hey,
I have the choice now to build curl in a much more secure way. We
wanted to make that choice.
And that's how we would get in there.
We did a similar thing with patchy HVD where we, you know,
they provide SSL services in H DB through MOD SSL. It's an Apache module
we wrote another module called MOD TLS. And that uses
Russells as the TLS
back end.
So if you build H TBD, you can choose to build and run mod TL SS instead of MOD SSL.
And we want to see more and more people make that choice over time,
but it's on us to prove that this works well.
Right? If we need to make a good quality implementation,
it's going to have to live in the world a little while to get some
testing and build up some confidence in it.
Is it, is it a drop in replacement today for Openness Cell? Does it cover all the API
S, do you know,
chose not to duplicate open SSL API?
And the reason for that is that the API of open SSL itself
is responsible for about just as many security problems as C
the reason is just that the open SSL API is too complicated
and so
you get a lot of vulnerability from people misusing the API itself.
So
normally we want to maintain API compatible and make it truly drop in.
But in this case, it's just too,
too bad for security and we chose just not duplicate that.
Well, I mean,
even open as a cell kind of admitted to it because Openness
Cell 3.0 dropped some of the old API stuff is just like
you, you shouldn't be touching this like it's an internal API only
you as a end user should never touch this. So, I mean,
even they acknowledge that their API is
overly complicated and
sometimes abused.
Yeah. But in our experience changing API S has not been that much work.
You know, we got some experience doing that with curl
and
it wasn't bad at all.
-- Gotcha. Gotcha. That's fair. That's fair.
-- Well, the thing was sorry. But like
my experience with open SSL over the last 20 plus years is like,
I want to create certificates.
I want to validate certificates.
I want to establish a SSL or TLS connection
and I really shouldn't be monkeying with the low level guts because
every time I see people monkey with the low level guts,
I end up assigning them a security vulnerability identifier.
Yeah.
So Russells doesn't do the like creating or there open SSL does
so much stuff like it's a Swiss army isa of crypto tools.
Really?
Russell's is just a replacement for the TLS connection party.
You know, it doesn't generate certificates and things like that.
But
-- maybe we'll get there someday. We'll see. Yeah, we,
-- we have CPA
-- to
-- make sure
I was gonna say we just use lots and crypt.
Ok.
Ok. We, we're about out of time here, Josh, this has been,
this has been lovely and I guess I will give you the floor for the last word.
So, is there anything you'd like the audience to know or any call to action or,
or it's up to you?
I think
the thing that's been on my mind the most over the last few days is that on uh
Friday. So
about five days ago,
we lost one of the co
founders of Lots and Crypt. Um Peter
Eckersley passed away,
um sort of unexpectedly last Friday and it's been
a big loss for our community and our organization.
He was a really bright and kind individual and we
love working with him to create lots and crypt.
He did a lot for this and
it's just a tough loss. Um He's a great person.
There are a lot of tributes and stories about him online.
If you want to go learn some more,
I think he has a Wikipedia page that has some basic info too.
So
we're thinking about Peter and his family and
it's tough time.
Yeah. No, absolutely. And, and that's true. We should have led with that.
I, I'm truly sorry for the loss. I know everyone I've spoken with.
I, I did not know Peter but
every person who knew him had has nothing but amazing, positive things to say.
I, I also want to add the 11 bit I think is,
it is a true testament to the work that the Letin Krip founders have done
that. The organization
it will live on for, for probably forever at, I mean, we'll put forever in quotes.
But,
you know, like,
like it's a truly great organization and amazing in the work you're doing is,
is just, it is the, the best II I told this to one of your people actually,
when we were setting this up,
it is the best thing that has ever happened to the internet.
And, and I don't say that in Jest, like, it's absolutely 100% true.
Your organization is one of the true jewels of humanity and,
and thank you and everyone for it.
It, it's amazing.
Yeah.
You know, Peter was a fantastic person and
one of the best ways we can honor his memory is to
do the best work we can for as long as we can.
Absolutely. 100%
awesome.
Awesome.
Well, Josh, I want to thank you so very much for coming and speaking with us,
it has been
an absolute pleasure and I can't wait to see what
happens in the next four years when you come back
and we'll see what, what other
ridiculous challenges let's encrypt to solve that.
No one else thought they could solve. So, thank you, everyone for listening.
Thank you, Josh. Thank you, Kurt.
Go to open source security podcast.com for the show notes.
I'll have ample show notes from everything we've talked about today and you. Pando
says podcast hashtag
-- up on social media. Kurt and Josh have marvelous rest of your days.
-- Thank you.
Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye,
the