Hello and welcome to episode 121 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried
and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Pressers.
So, listener,
you, you don't know this.
But when we talked about number 1, 21 Kurt and I said, 0,
100 and 21 that sounds like a neat number.
And so we looked it up on Wikipedia because Wikipedia has numbers and I found
a Wikipedia page called List of Numbers and I'm pretty sure it's missing some.
The
-- dumb
-- is there
P
I it's just, it's a page.
I'm the bad joke is there's obviously an infinite number
of numbers so you can't have a list of numbers,
right?
Anyway, anyway, which I guess it's actually ironic
you, you could have a list of numbers. It would just be very large
and incomplete
-- because we have finite storage.
-- Well, I suppose if you want to look at it like that,
right? Anyway, this is actually related to the topic of the day.
Speaking of numbers,
because something Kurt and I have been talking about is voting security,
which seems relatively topical given the fact that
this,
this episode is going to come out right before an election in
the United States where voting security has been a hugely popular topic.
So I guess before you reach for the stop button at this point, it's kind of a heads up.
Our goal is not to start a political discussion about voting
country.
That's right.
You live in a nice country where, although you almost certainly still have voted
security issues because everybody,
no, not really
because we have a federally run election system
by and large for our federal elections. And then
state level is generally quite
reasonable and well controlled.
It's see,
what's interesting to me is the US has federal
elections that are operated at the state level.
So between states it varies greatly. Like I know some states, for example,
uh, I think it's, what is it? Oregon? Like, it's all voter mailing.
Yes,
it's all done by
mail.
It's actually really cool.
I remember, I didn't know this but I went to college with a guy from Oregon
and he, one day he gets like this huge package in the mail.
And I, I said, what's that?
And he says, oh, it's my voting book for, for the election. And I said, what now?
And yeah, he showed it to me and it's like this, it was quite large,
just this was one of those years where they had lots and lots of stuff to vote for.
Basically, they mailed him a book.
It looked like one of those fill in the bubble tests
and he voted on all the things and then he mailed it back.
Well, see, and that's,
that's another problem the US has with elections that Canada doesn't have,
is that the US has elections on everything. Like sheriff dog catcher judges.
We do a
lot
and see in Canada, we, we don't, we elect, obviously at the federal level,
we elected at the provincial level that you would call state level,
we elect at the municipal level. So like
uh school boards and city council and the city mayor.
And that's basically it,
right. All of our, our legal record,
the entire legal system is appointed,
right? We don't vote on them
and, and I've always thought that was an odd thing to do, right?
It doesn't seem like the,
-- the sort of position you want to be partisan
-- if you look at the history of the US,
right?
The, the US was effectively a British colony that broke away from Britain.
-- That's a polite way of putting
-- it.
And Canada did not. Right.
So Canada, I mean, we're still a constitutional monarchy.
The queen is the head of state. So, ultimately, what do
they call it? The commonwealth, right? Where it's like Canada? And I think
-- the
-- commonwealth is something different.
Oh, that's not, not you. Ok.
Well, no, we're in the commonwealth but that's
different.
Yeah.
-- Yeah,
-- you can be in the commonwealth but not have the queen as head of state,
for example, Australia no longer has the queen of head of state.
Um But no, like technically, for example, when I, when we, we elect MP S,
the MP S form a government,
they essentially go to the queen's representative in Canada to
well effectively ask permission to form a government
and you know, the
queen's representative
representative
government.
No, let's, we need to move on because it's as fun as it is.
-- So,
-- but basically
really what it boils down to is the beauty is Canada. We don't
have as many elections and our elections are
like, I don't vote on prop 217. You know, whether or not we should ban plastic spoons
like we just don't have stuff like that. Right?
And so, so the part of the challenge is when you look at the voting,
like when we have a federal election, I literally vote
for my local, like whichever local party I want to support. That's it.
I vote on one thing,
right?
And it's not like the US where they have that like giant sheet of like, well,
we're holding a federal election so we might as
well do all these other elections while we're at
-- it.
-- Sure. Well, yeah. Anyway, anyway. All right. So, so let's, let's start here.
We have the concept of a voting,
right?
Which we've kind of talked about a little bit. But II, I think fundamentally
the,
the ignoring the technology because we'll get to that and I do
think the technology is super interesting and has a lot of crazy,
I guess, problems and opportunities.
But
so fundamentally, if we start with the people
and we're talking about security,
the big thing we hear about here in the US right now is voter fraud.
Right? Where
the idea is you have people who shouldn't be voting are voting in elections
or people voting multiple times.
Right. Right.
And, and the reality it turns out is this is actually a, a comically low number
which, which in terms of security kind of the way I view this is
no security system is ever going to be 100%.
And if you try to make it 100% you actually
end up shutting the door on more legitimate people.
You're
disenfranchising a lot of voters.
And just to put this in context,
the vast majority of voter ID laws in
the United States target only a voter impersonation.
So number one, that's they, they mostly target like, you know,
Josh claiming to be Curtin trying to vote twice both as Josh and as curt
of which there are only 31 documented cases in the United
States from,
from 2000 to 2014.
That's so it's like two point something a year.
And, and this is this, I feel like kind of
this is,
is one of the fundamental problems we see in the security industry in general
is there's like one relatively inconsequential corner case
and we end up building these enormous systems around it
that end up like throwing out the baby with the bathwater
when the reality is just,
you can ignore this problem because it really doesn't matter.
I mean, I know locally it's,
for example, students quite often get disenfranchised because, you know,
they want you to bring
some idea or some proof that you live there.
Well, the students are like, well,
but I moved here from out of province so
I don't have like a driver's license or whatever
and I don't really have a utility bill because, you know,
I'm a poor student living with seven other people.
Right.
But like I attend the University of Alberta, you know,
and so,
I mean, the, the really rude part of this is,
is that there's a lot of people who are quite happy to disenfranchise people.
So they're quite happy
to use security, for example, as a excuse to, you know, disenfranchise people.
I mean, a great example of this is the airlines, right?
The airlines love the ID
to ticket laws because it eliminates the secondary market of
reselling your ticket if you can't make your flight.
-- Yep. Yep, that's very true.
-- You know,
they love that. Right?
Because I remember back in the day you would see ads for like, you know, uh
I have tickets to some nice exotic place a week from now.
I can't make it because I like, broke my leg,
I'm selling these tickets at like 80% of what they're worth
or whatever. Right.
And you could just buy them,
right?
Because airline tickets were like these physical pieces of paper that literally
didn't have your name on them or anything.
Sure.
And you, I mean,
you can make the argument about some level of security there because obviously
there are,
I guess evildoers who, who could abuse that. But, but I, I don't disagree with you.
I couldn't abuse it in any way that they couldn't abuse it with the existing
laws of like getting somebody who looks like them or swapping ID or whatever.
Right.
Yeah, that's fair. You know, the same thing.
I know some bus companies are trying to do that where, you know,
matching your ID to your bus ticket or same thing with, um, concert tickets.
Right. Trying to prevent scalping.
They have this thing now where, you know,
you have to bring the credit card that bought the tickets with you to get in.
So, the idea and, and what,
but what happens is then scalpers will get six tickets or whatever.
The maximum they can get usually is around six
and they'll walk five people in and leave.
Clever.
Right. Because if, if you're scalping tickets at 100% markup.
Well, you know, yeah, you eat one ticket for yourself,
but if you can sell five tickets at 100% markup,
that's still a good chunk of profit.
Yeah.
Yeah. Seriously. Seriously.
Yeah. So, anyway, anyway, let's,
I,
I don't want to dwell on this point too much just because I
guess this kind of sets the stage so people need to go vote
and they need to record what they're doing and this is where we
start getting into some of the concepts of like the electronic voting machines
and, and kind of all the man is.
So, so see, what's interesting to me about voting
is the way we've structured voting in most of western democracies
is we have a couple of sort of conflicting goals.
We want you to cast a vote.
We want you to cast that vote in secret, right? You should be able to vote
and not have anyone know what your vote was. And
we also want you to be able to somehow verify
or validate that your vote wasn't monkeyed or tampered with,
but still be secret
that that part is becoming questionable.
So the way we solve it in Canada, as I've said before is, you know,
we make a mark on a piece of paper, shove it in a locked box
and you're going well. Ok, great. How's that? Secure?
Well, we have this idea of what are called scrutineers.
These are people that sit in the room and watch
and they're from different political parties.
See, that's the trick
you put paper in a box, it doesn't go through like a scanner first or anything.
Well, they, sometimes there are like the, not the federal elections but like the,
um, I think it was municipal,
whatever it was scanned and then put in a box so that the recount would be, you know,
it's relatively easy.
Right.
But essentially the,
the way we secure our elections is we have people
from multiple political parties and you can also have independence.
So, like, you could just be,
decide to be a scrutiny and go to a polling station and watch.
And so essentially who watches the watchers?
Well, the other watchers from the other political parties,
right.
And, and I,
I know in the US that exists where there are people
whose job is to just keep an eye on what's happening
in the room.
But I can't watch the insides of an electronic machine
and you can't. And
so I've lived in a number of places and I voted on a variety of machines.
My favorite to this day still is a long time ago.
They had these giant machines,
they were like taller than a person and they'd wheel them in
and they had like these weird little switches on
the inside and like you'd flick your switches and,
and ironically this
probably has a similar problem to electronic
voting where you'd flick little switches,
vote for the people you wanted
and, and it had like a little curtain that you draw.
So obviously no one could see you vote.
And my favorite part though is it had like this handle on
the front and you'd pull the handle over to it was,
you know, like, I think it was right to left.
If I'm remembering correctly,
you'd like, pull this handle over
and it would obviously record the vote in some way. It would reset the machine
-- and it would open the curtain.
-- Are these the ones that punched holes in paper?
I, I assume it was doing something behind the scenes but I know you
didn't.
-- No, I didn't, I don't know what it did actually because
-- I've seen that machine where,
where, like you set
the, the switches or whatever and then you could chunk it,
like you pull the lever and it could chunks and it punches holes in paper
and then you take that piece of paper and, and fold it up or whatever and,
and walk it over to the box and shove it in the box and,
and I'm ok with that because again, holes in paper, relatively easy to validate.
Right? I can look at that and understand it.
But you're saying there was this giant mechanical machine with,
-- I'm going to assume maybe a paper tape or something inside of it.
-- Something. Right?
I don't know what and, and it was, it was crazy.
I mean, in hindsight now that I think about it, that was,
that was probably my first time voting and I think it
might have been the only time I ever used that device,
-- which was a long time ago.
-- How do you?
But you never got to see what your vote was recorded
on and see this is what I hate about electronic systems,
is the electronic system will show me some representation of
what I,
how I voted.
But that may not be what was recorded.
And, and that's really the question, isn't it? Is kind of,
how do you know,
you make a black
mark on a piece of paper?
Well, yes, there's that.
No, you're absolutely right.
And it's funny because every security person
I know who pays attention to voting security
and I've read a lot about this just because it's one of those topics I enjoy
everybody who pays attention to this and
actually knows what they're talking about.
It is
almost unanimous
that you should have a paper ballot and people should fill out a paper ballot
and then you stick it in a machine, the machine can read it, it can read it.
Humans can count. It doesn't really matter. But like
that thing
is super important. Now, here's the one thing I keep thinking of
is kind of one of the issues with, with this model.
So
a paper ballot means you probably have to go somewhere to vote. Right.
That's kind of the fundamental behind that. And, and I feel like
making people go places it annoys me. Right.
I want to click a button on my computer and have things happen for me.
Well, so um I, I agree,
one of my concerns is that we typically hold elections for one day.
Well, and you know, some people like
that's just not super convenient or they might be bedridden or
whatever.
So I, I would prefer to see better availability of mail in voting.
I would love that and personally, I, I would almost prefer to see
II,
I definitely understand the allure of just 100%
mail in voting like we send out the packets
and when we get the packets back, that's great because let's face it, right?
The US postal system and the Canadian postal system
are like basically the gold standard for you put an object into it
and it pops out at the other end
end of story like it almost always works
in like two days, right?
It it blows my mind.
Yeah.
Yeah and affordably.
And like, I mean, I I know for example, you know,
you can mail well within Canada, you can't export them.
But you know, people mail firearms around
and the only deal is you got to put a trigger lock on the gun. When you send it,
it doesn't even have to be in a locked case again
just and and literally the RC MP says you must
use Canada Post's highest level of secure mail signature required.
That's what it says on the web page. I'm not making this up, right? I checked sweet.
So, I, I definitely would
love to have mail
voting because, yeah, I mean, I just get my packet.
Scribble Scribble Scribble, shove it back in the post.
I would even assume that they would have like, postage
return handled. So I don't have to go buy stamps.
You know, I, I would assume because like you can,
you can send mail to your MP for free in Canada.
That's neat.
Well, it's, it's part of, well, but think about it 100 100 and 50 years ago.
How else would you contact that guy?
-- Uh, that is true. There were no telephones.
-- Well,
not for poor people.
Right. Right.
-- Right.
-- And, and sorry to be sexist.
But when I say guy, but if you look at the history of Canada, yeah, like we,
yeah, it's only within about the last 50 years that we've had women in politics,
really, like most of the western world
which we do need more of.
If you are a lady listening, please get involved in politics, please.
I think we just need more people that are passionate,
involved in whatever it is they're passionate about. Be it, politics or cooking.
-- I, I think that would not be a terrible outcome,
-- man.
I, that's a topic for another day.
I question if, if being passionate about politics is the right prerequisite.
But, but anyway, anyway,
so,
so here's where I want this conversation to end up at and I think we kind of keep rat
holing ourselves just because this is one of those interesting
topics that we could go off on tangents forever.
But, but here's the real question,
can we make
an electronic voting machine
that is secure?
Well, no, the problem is it doesn't have to just be secure.
-- It also has to be verifiable both to myself and to others. I
-- would
-- lump that into the definition of
-- security.
Well, but let's be clear what we mean by secure because for example,
I if I'm voting on an electronic machine, I want to be able to validate my vote,
easily,
not requiring some app and double crypto proof and encryption keys.
And this that and the other thing,
right?
It also my vote needs to be verifiable
to someone else who may not be very technologically sophisticated. You know,
with the current system,
we have a scrutineer can be like an 80 year old woman who as long as she's not blind
can, you know, it's pretty easy to understand the process.
People get a piece of paper, they go into the booth, they make a mark on the paper,
they fold it, they shove it in the box
at some point. We then
open the box, either there or we take it to a central place and open the box there,
take all the votes out, sort them, count them.
That's the process, right?
That is super easy to scrutinize you just watch
and make sure like make sure nobody's marking ballots,
you know,
make sure nobody's ripping ballots up and throwing them away or eating them or
whatever has been tried in the past. I'm sure there's millions of things,
you know, hiding them in sandwiches.
Whereas, you know, the electronic one is like, yeah, no,
I even with unlimited budget
and,
and I know there's cryptography around this where
I can have like a secure vote mechanism
that, you know, third parties and myself, you know, zero knowledge proofs.
We can all validate it.
Yeah, I, and just the cost and the complexity of implementing it correctly.
So that's the other thing, right, is
implementing paper votes correctly,
relatively simple and cost effective implementing
these electronic systems that get used for
once every couple years.
You know, that's the other ugly truth. Right?
That, that is true.
It doesn't, well, once a year, we'll say maybe twice, but generally speaking,
I think once a year is probably correct.
And, and where did the machines go
for the rest of the year?
We
store
them
vlad
storage service offered to store them for free.
Let's use him.
Right.
You know, and that's, that's the thing, right?
Like even, I mean, unless you're in some really
strange place. Yeah, you're going to be having elections at most, maybe once a year,
maybe twice on a really weird year.
I remember one year we had,
I think we had two federal elections in one year because it went a whole bonkers.
-- Uh,
-- I know I voted more than once a year,
a couple of times where there's primary elections and
in a bunch of crazy stuff like that.
But regardless it
more, even if it's five times a year,
you're talking about machines sitting in storage for a significant amount of time.
Yeah.
Right. Without question.
And, ok, so, so here's,
you rattled off a whole bunch of words
and they mean something to me and probably some of the listeners. But I think
here's the thing I keep thinking of
is somebody who doesn't really understand computer security
and they hear somebody say, oh, this voting machine is secure,
why would they believe them or not? Believe them.
Well, they wouldn't believe them because most
machines of this class.
So I think generally we lump voting machines in with say like ATM S
and slot machines and that it's a very sort of specific use computer,
right? It sort of does one thing and one thing only hopefully,
and the reality is what's, what's really sad to me is,
is I know for a fact that like ATM S and,
and slot machines have much higher and
more rigorous security standards than voting machines
-- in the US.
-- We should just get those guys to,
well, the funny thing is no de
bold makes ATM S and makes voting machines and they, they've,
do you not remember the whole kerfuffle about DeBolt
being found to make them much less secure voting machines than they made ATM. S
which doesn't surprise me because the banks were paying much closer attention.
I'm sure
the guy running de
bold promised to deliver an election to a candidate.
Remember that?
Yeah, let's not get into that.
Well, but that's part of the problem is so the people making this system,
these systems,
they're humans, they,
are they not allowed to vote or are they not allowed to participate in politics?
Do they have to recuse themselves from the election?
I don't think so. I think that would be terrible.
So I,
I think that would be a terrible system if the
people who built it had to recuse themselves because that,
that would suggest it had some sort of weakness that was so bad
that you can't trust the people who built it. But then more importantly,
that just means it's so fundamentally flawed. You really can't trust
-- it.
-- Well, and see, that's the problem is building a system that is both secure
and verifiable by a third party.
And I don't mean just verifiable in the sense of like, oh,
your vote was recorded correctly, it went through.
But like,
you know, I we would need people to verify the bootloader because for example,
the, the voting machine might have firmware that says, OK, you know,
for 364 days of the year run the, the correct, you know, safe firmware.
But on election day run the, you know,
run the crazy teapot party firmware or whatever,
you know,
how do we validate that? Right. Because that's the thing, right?
Is these things are so complicated that,
you know, just,
just a tiny change to load a slightly different
file and the whole system is completely different.
That is
perfectly reasonable. Yes.
Well, not only that, actually, it's funny you mentioned that, uh,
there was some security researcher at one
point that was attacking electronic voting machines
and there was like a USB port on it,
right? And you're already relatively private when you're voting.
So you could easily muck with the machine itself.
Right?
Well, they, they've done that where they had the,
the USB thing where they just basically plug the USB thing
and reset the machine and booted or whatever off the USB and
like you now own that machine
and there's no way to validate it.
So
see, that's the thing.
So like here's the, the thing that really annoys me is,
is a lot of these problems have generally been solved.
So a
good example might be like a Nintendo switch.
Those things are actually pretty secure because you know, Nintendo
actually,
so funny
enough, the
first
generation,
the first generation switches have like a special USB boot mode,
like built into the actual processor itself.
Yeah, they can't fix it in
software.
Nintendo's releasing a new version of the switch that has a much nicer screen,
I'm told
and probably also fixes this problem.
And that's a perfect example is the company is incentivized
to fix as many of these machines as they can.
Right. With voting systems is, you know, we're not using them on a daily basis.
We use them like once a year.
Oh, this thing has a flaw. Well, we can't fix it today.
Well, in, and not only that
they're not widely available, the switch is widely available.
I just read a statistic. They sold 22.8 million units, I think is the number I saw.
That's,
and,
and those are in the hands of many people and
some people have obviously done the research and cracked it,
whereas something like a voting machine is not the sort of
thing you're going to see in the hands of everybody.
Right.
It's going to be hard to get a hold of these things.
Well, sadly, it's, you can buy used ones quite easily on ebay and, you know,
people were doing that and finding out that the
hard drives and whatnot had not been wiped.
Oh, I have no doubt.
I would be shocked if they were white.
Um
But so I personally, yeah, I mean, we keep coming back to, yes, in theory,
we can build a technological electronic solution that is secure.
But then even if you build something that is secure,
how do you build something that is both secure and again, like I said,
verifiable by third parties that are not, you know, n
or
a university research lab with 20 people.
But like you and me, let alone a normal person.
So
why, why do we want to say, let's say mail in ballots are secure?
What would stop somebody from intercepting a
bunch of these ballots and changing them
or, or
just removing them from, from voting?
Well, that's a great thing is
these things are not 100% secure but they
are difficult to tamper with and modify at scale
now.
And I know there's elections where we've literally, I think we had, I,
I mentioned this before but we had an election and there was a riding in Calgary,
literally one vote difference.
Like they had like,
I think some five or six recounts because like
literally it boiled down to one vote difference.
So, you know, so that's not common, but
it is.
So there even a small amount of tampering could potentially have a big effect,
right?
Like my understanding is with the US election,
there's only a couple dozen or like it was
like 50 or 60 counties where if you'd managed to
swing the vote one way or the other, you,
you could have had a totally different outcome to the US federal election.
Yes,
it was something like 30,000 people basically decided the presidential election,
which is
like an astronomically small number in the big picture.
But so that's the thing is, you know, we, we have to,
we have to concern ourselves with the sort of more realistic attacks,
you know, can somebody subvert a single voter?
Of course, I could glue your doors shut and then you can't go vote.
Well, and that used to be a really big problem.
I know back in like the 19 twenties,
early 19 hundreds where basically you'd show up and vote
and then
you'd get dinner, but only if you voted for the right person
and like,
if I was hungry, I, I'd do that.
Who, who I vote for? I need, I need to eat.
Yeah.
So, and well, one could argue we already have that issue with, you know,
politicians making promises that they then do not follow through on.
Um, you know, like we were, we were, I don't want to say promised electoral reform,
but it was very strongly implied and made up, you know, a fundamental campaign
platform piece
and it's not happening.
So I'm a little miffed about that because I would like to see electoral reform.
But, you know, we did get legalized marijuana.
So they followed through on that, which is nice and, and I'm guessing
to put it bluntly, you know,
that's one of the promises the liberals made
because they knew that would be popular with
a lot of young voters and a lot of old voters who are against the liberals,
well, that they're still going to be against the liberals.
It doesn't matter,
you know,
it's true. Um
So,
yeah, so I think we have to sort of put that aside to some degree.
So tampering with the system itself. Yeah, definitely. That, that is illegal.
Uh, usually very illegal in most jurisdictions. Right. Tampering with votes.
Uh, but again, it's,
it's difficult to do at scale with something like the post office and,
and quite frankly, if the post office is in on it,
you know,
it's not like the post office is some monolithic, you know,
evil corporation controlled by the lizardman.
Like,
I'm pretty sure the post office is roughly like 5050 Democratic and Republican.
Just like the rest of America.
You haven't, I'm sure we could find a website that disagrees with you.
Well, you know,
it's actually the reason the post office is the way it is because of the flat earth,
right?
-- They just shoot the mail out of cannons anyways.
-- That's
right.
Ok. Ok. So let's assume subverting the mail is hard.
What about a box full of paper ballots? How hard is it to subvert that?
Well, when there's multiple scrutineers keeping an eye on it pretty difficult,
especially when those
are going to transport the ballots to somewhere.
So the, the ballot boxes are sealed, you know, by elections. Canada,
right?
With like those security tags like you'd see on
an electric meter or whatever kind of same idea,
right?
Little plastic thing with serial number and whatnot.
And so, you know, you'd have to cut that tag to
open the box and tamper with it.
Right.
What, what if I just steal the box?
Ok. So actually I think once uh hang on a second election missing,
I know that's happened in other countries where like just, oh yeah,
all the boxes from this one riding that typically
votes not the way we like went missing.
I think there was a case of some boxes being missing for a while,
but they were like literally left in the back
of the truck by accident or something stupid.
And then they were found a few hours later
and the seals were still intact.
But again, people,
pe people are people, man,
you know,
-- it
-- is true. People are
um
again, you know, it
generally speaking, these systems generally work, we don't screw them up too much.
And, and here's the important thing that, that you've discussed this whole time.
I've asked you these questions.
If you're going to modify a paper ballot,
you have to go to a place and do it.
And in most instances,
especially in a country the size of Canada or the United
States because while Canada doesn't have a ton of people,
it is an enormous place.
You would have to subvert
probably millions to, maybe
you'd only have to probably subvert a few
tho if you did it strategically, you'd probably actually only have to subvert
a few dozen or 100 ridings to swing certain key ridings to whichever MP you wanted.
But still that would be
so, so.
Exactly. Right.
Like people would notice that, ok, in these 30 places,
the votes have all disappeared.
We can't accept this as a valid election.
You, you basically,
the point is when you're dealing with paper and physical things,
somebody is going to figure out what happened. It would be in it.
It's like movie, plot security to subvert that to the point. Nobody notices. Now,
let's say we have an electronic machine,
you could subvert
that particular election depending upon how it's set up.
But generally speaking, you have the machines that vote
right person goes, they push the buttons on the machine.
The machine is usually networked to some central machine at the voting station
and then that central machine reports the results into some
other central location where it's all tallied and put together.
So you have multiple instances where this could be monkeyed with.
But most importantly
is if somebody could subvert the,
the data and it is probably traveling over the internet, let's face it.
-- You don't
-- have
to be there,
you can be in another country
-- and you could monkey with this
-- election.
And that
truth is with most of those, these electronic systems,
you can then tidy up after yourself.
-- Right. Exactly. Like nobody need know if you do it
-- right.
And I'm guessing most of these voting machines don't have like really
like NSA levels of like security auditing and you know, cryptographic logging
on the device because like these things,
some of them are still running windows 95 or XP or whatever,
almost certainly. And, and I guess that is,
that's kind of the crux of this. Right.
Ignoring all other potential problems with voting,
which are for the most part you can deal.
I
wish we just did the purple thumb.
Like a lot of countries where they don't have good record keeping.
It's like
you vote, you dip your, uh thumb in indelible ink
and you don't get to vote again that day, right?
We, you know, so you could, in theory have, you know,
a bunch of people dog pile a couple of different writings, you know,
come from out of riding to vote and vote in a riding and swing that riding.
But it,
the purple thumb thing solves the voting multiple
times from assuming that you have thumbs,
right?
And, and that would be acceptable for like a federal election obviously, but,
but could create some issues for local things.
But regardless
it, it is a huge, huge
problem solver and it is painfully simple.
Now, now, I guess here's,
here's where we, we bring it all home and wrap this up no matter what we want to do.
There is no way and, and I'm sure you agree with this. There is no way
we can have
an electronic voting system and this is even true of internet voting
that we can honestly trust given our infrastructure today.
-- I won't say
-- it'll never happen.
It's even
worse than
that. It's,
they can't even begin to approach
the safety, security and verifiability of a paper based system.
Anything approaching the cost.
That's that too. I
like
that.
You just can't build this thing for what it costs to print paper ballots.
And, and I guess that's,
yes, I, I think you just summed it up perfectly.
Is we,
we have the infrastructure in the physical world
to operate an election using physical objects,
ie paper ballots in this instance.
And that is because we have a certain structure of society that lends itself to this,
right? Like the idea of having a paper vote, if you say are, are in,
we'll say go back, you know,
thousands of years to a tribal like society that wouldn't
work because they lack certain infrastructure to make it happen.
We have that
we'd lack the technical infrastructure to implement proper electronic voting
and someday we might get it,
but we don't have it today.
We could do it, but it would not be affordable and I'm not sure it would be verifiable.
II, I don't think so.
I think if I told you, you literally have all the money in the world,
go make the secure.
I don't think you could do it.
Well, see, and that's the challenge is I, you know,
I want something that's more secure than a switch for boot loading.
And I want something, you know, that's,
and these are, yeah, these are,
the other problem is I'm not going to sell 28 million voting machines.
Right. I'm gonna sell tens of thousands of voting machines.
Right.
And,
and if someone wants to give me all the money in the world to develop secure voting,
like I'm willing to try just in case, just in case.
But,
but no, I mean, I, I think you're totally right. There's just,
I think that there's not enough economic incentive to do it. Right.
And I think we just don't have the infrastructure today
to have an honest conversation around this topic. And so we end up in a position
where we have people, there's half truth and in some cases just lies
for, for something that let's face it. Like paper solves.
Right. That's, that's the honest answer at the end of the day, paper solves it.
It's not just the paper solves it, it's, it's worked quite well for over 100 years.
We've ironed, like we've had over 100 years to iron out the kinks.
And if you read about some of the
election shenanigans like Chicago in the 19 twenties,
I think was a good example.
You know, where, get out the dead vote and
give people sandwiches to vote and stuff.
Yeah. No, we've, we've largely solved those problems
affordably too. Right. It's not like we need some big task force. It's,
it's, uh,
yeah.
All right. So, let's, let's end this one here. I guess in summary, go paper ballots.
Don't, don't use electronic voting, please.
And that is that and,
and I guess unfortunately there are people in places that are
trying to use electronic voting and I weep for you.
So good luck
-- vote.
-- Anyway, I was just looking at Estonia. They, but they are a special case.
So they have those, you know, national ID cards with the crypto chips on them,
which they have to replace now because that one crypto chip
was found to generate weak keys but ignoring those minor details.
I'm just looking at this. This is quite interesting.
Uh This is
um
doesn't, oh, this is for 2005.
So it's probably changed but number of persons with the right vote,
uh 1,060,000 give or take
votes 500,000. So 50% voter turnout sounds about right for everybody.
Number of E voters, 9000, 317 E votes counted
909,000, 287 E votes canceled 30.
So that's interesting.
So even even a country where they've
deployed a huge amount of specialized infrastructure,
like, you know, these national ID cards with, you know, the,
the the cryptographic chips on them and everything.
Well, 13 years ago was not,
I would say getting a lot of value for their money on this E voting.
Uh maybe it's changed. I don't know.
But yeah, fundamentally as a computer security person,
I am just not comfortable with electronic voting
-- and
-- that, that pretty much sums it up and maybe someday but definitely not today.
All right, cool. Well, thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com, hit up the show notes
or hit us up on social media with the Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag And I guess
more than anything if you're listening to this before the election, please,
please, please vote,
please. It's important.
-- All right, Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day. You too.
-- Thanks everybody.
Thank you. Bye bye.