Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast
episode 169 with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime,
Josh Bresser.
Do you ever get sick of doing that intro? I realize you've done that 169 times now,
actually,
more because there was a couple of times it got deleted or scrubbed or whatever.
It's true actually.
And more than once you've done the intro and
we decided to start again for whatever ridiculous reason.
So, yeah, that's true. You've probably done it more than 100 and 80 times. I bet.
Now that's,
that's the worst thing is I've been trying to think of ways to mix it up a bit and I just,
I'm drawing a blank.
Yeah, I hear you.
I think about that too where I think, oh, we need a new theme song because, I mean,
we've had the same, you know, intro theme song for a long time and
-- I, I
-- just,
I love that piece of musical and what it represents, you know,
man's inevitable decline into, to meaningless.
It's really where kind of like a, I started stealing the human jobs. Right.
They can play the piano better than we can.
Yeah. In the 18 hundreds.
That's right.
All right. So, this is another one of those, you won't tell me what the topic is.
I
did
it out.
Just government security.
Right.
That doesn't mean anything.
So, well, we've, we've got a couple of kerfuffles about government security.
So, like the first one is,
is that whole, the Republicans storming a skiff with their electronic devices.
Yeah, I read about that. So I want to start this conversation by saying
neither Kurt nor myself condone
-- any particular political party and I do not want to turn this podcast into,
-- oh,
I know I'll be, I disapprove of all of them.
I, that's true. I hate them all.
No, I straight up, I disapprove of all political parties pretty much.
I, there's not a single one. I'm happy with that and, and to be clear, I'm Canadian.
So I, I also
group of political parties in other countries too and
I'm sorry if that offends you there. I've fulfilled my Canadianness.
It's easier to dislike everybody than it is to pick and choose. So
we will preface it with that.
So I guess why don't tell this story, especially as you're not an American.
-- And so I'm always very interested
-- in,
I'm blameless in this.
No, you're not current. No one is blameless.
-- Everything is everyone's fault. Yeah.
-- Yeah, I guess. Yeah, distributed blame.
So a skiff is a secure compartmentalized information. Facility.
And the idea is it's basically a box
and to be clear, like some of these are literally
like a small, slightly larger than a phone booth sized box.
And some of these are, you know, multiple uh sized uh football fields, you know,
data warehouses and things like that.
So they vary in size.
And the idea is is that you can securely
uh process data within this
box.
And when I say process data, I don't mean just, you know, with computers and whatnot.
But for example, you know,
somebody can
pull out, you know, top secret information and write notes or, and you know,
think about it and work about it or,
or two or three people can have a conversation about the uh the whatever, right?
So apparently the US President travels with like a portable skiff,
which is basically like this
electromagnetically shielded tent that they can all huddle in so that, you know,
nobody can hear them, nobody can see them,
you can't
electronically monitor them things like that. Right? Sure. And so
the idea is
that
obviously you can't be bringing
electronics in and out of these things, right?
Because for two people to discuss, you know,
top secret information in one of these secure boxes,
that kind of defeats the point. If I pull my phone out and hit record
and then wander off with it later
or ignoring that
the reality is with a lot of these people,
they're the target of nation state attacks where they could conceivably have a cell
phone that is literally listening to them all the time by a foreign adversary.
Exactly.
You know, if, for example, you were to set 111111 as your phone passcode,
hypothetically speaking.
Yeah.
You know,
it could be possible for somebody if they physically get a hold
of your phone for even only five or 10 seconds to,
you know, open it up and
go to a web page or something that compromises your phone.
-- Or
-- look, man,
these are the people who buy these zero days that affect Android and Os X and I OS.
Right. I mean,
when, when you hear about selling things on the black market,
-- they end up in the hands of nation state actors. That's where they
-- go even simpler.
You know, these nation states, a lot of them have information security,
the groups that find zero days, like, sure, that's literally their job.
You know, and, and I would be offended if governments weren't doing this because,
you know, it's,
it's like developing weapons. It sucks. But
you got to do it.
Right. Yeah. Exactly. And everyone's doing it.
Any,
any government or anyone who says they're not like they are totally lying to you.
Some are not doing it
very well.
I will say from what I've read and looked, you know,
there's a lot of countries that are not my choice.
No. Exactly. Yeah. Exactly.
But yeah, fundamentally,
this is something pretty much all governments want the capability of end of story.
You know, it's like when governments are like, we don't want to be a nuclear power.
It's like
anyway, so continue the story, we know what a skiff is now.
-- So,
-- so the idea of a skiff is,
you've got this secure box, you need to control what goes into it,
you need to control what comes out of it
and you need to, you know, make sure it's sanitized inside, right?
So there's no, like you can't just have like,
like a desktop phone sitting in one of these,
you know, again, that could be like remotely hacked, you know, like a, like, um,
jeez, I don't even know what brands,
I, I only know the Canadian brands and they all out of business 1015 years ago,
Nortel and whatnot,
I guess Cisco. Cisco makes phones, right? Ok. Let's pick on Cisco for
sure. So, you know, if you had like a Cisco
and when I say a desk phone again, you know, these aren't phones, these are
shooters that
kind of have the appearance of a phone,
you know, they've built in web browsers and stuff now.
So you have to be really careful and control what is in the skiff and, you know,
you don't want people leaving a listening device behind, you know,
either one that transmits or one that can, you know, store and record
and
so my understanding is most skiffs, you know,
it's not like an airport where you have to go through a metal detector and like a
whole bunch of security measures.
It appears that most skiffs kind of run on the honor principle
of essentially the people that have clearance to use these things,
understand that
it's important to,
you know, be secure.
And so, for example,
they'll have like little lockable cabinets outside
where you like dump all your electronics,
your keys, you know, that kind of stuff, you know,
you pat down your pockets and then you go into the skiff,
have your conversation about
aliens in area 51
and then, you know, exit the skiff and get your phone back or whatever.
And apparently
for normal people, at least the penalties for violating,
you know, skiff procedures are quite harsh,
like at a minimum you're going to get that.
I love the word they use is you're going to get counseled,
you know, which is I,
I assume what that means is they're talking to you but not screaming at you.
You know, in the same way I counsel my Children when they do things.
And for example, people were talking about how they don't even wear their,
uh Bluetooth hearing aids into these facilities, which makes sense.
Right. Because, uh,
uh I did some research on hearing aids and, you know, all,
all the modern ones have Bluetooth built into them
so that your phone can ring to your earphone.
And
yeah, and I mean, and,
but that is the literal definition of an audio bugging device is like, well,
it listens to audio, it probably has enough memory chips to record some of it.
And it's got a Bluetooth transmitter receiver on. It
sounds like an audio bug to me.
Ok. So why are you telling us this story about a skiff?
So a bunch of, mostly, I think all Republicans
stormed into a major skiff where there were some hearings going on
and they took their electronics in, not only did they take their electronics in,
but they were apparently live tweeting and taking
video of themselves in the skiff and,
and broadcasting this
and, and apparently they all knew better. Like it wasn't some mistake.
-- Like they didn't know what a skiff was or how to behave in one.
-- Everyone there
should have known better.
Yeah. Well, no, they knew better. And
so
it got me thinking it's, you know,
how do you do security when your users are willfully disobedient, let's say,
because fundamentally to, to implement security that
where you can't even sort of trust your insiders
or the people that are supposed to have access.
-- You, you're kind of up the creek.
-- I would agree completely. And I feel like this story
really helps bring home some of the concepts you
get in the security universe where it's almost like
you think of different socio-economic classes
where obviously someone at the bottom.
Generally,
let's say you have someone at the bottom and someone
at the top and they commit the same crime,
you're going to see drastically different sentences
for them for a variety of reasons.
Mind you and I don't want to get into
kind of the, the esoteric details of that because it's, it's complicated and,
and it's
fair with security, especially, you see this a
lot where somebody who's maybe at the top and this
could be a CEO could be a congress person,
could be a member of the board of directors,
whatever it is.
And they know
they don't have to follow your rules
and it's a very difficult place to be in when they
just willfully disregard what they know to be the right decision
because they just don't feel like it.
Yeah.
And it's worse because often those are the people that are actually the targets.
Well, of course, because the bad guys know and,
and they especially know if that person is, let's face it,
not smart enough to follow the rules.
Well, I mean, a simple example that I can make public, you know, at the, at the CS A,
we often get external phishing attempts, you know, from our CEO saying, hey,
I need you to go talk to this lawyer or oh, you
-- to send $10,000 to this thing right away. And
-- it's like itunes gift cards.
Yeah, pretty much. And I mean,
so for example, if, if we didn't, you know,
we enforced two factor authentication on our email
accounts for this and many other reasons.
But, you know, hypothetically speaking,
I know places. Well, this is a hypothetical. Come
on. You know, we all know that there are places where the CEO or the high levels,
uh, refuse to do
the good security. Right. It's a hassle
and those places. Yeah. How do you force CEO to do something?
You know, I'm lucky in that.
I work for a security organization and our CEO
is quite security minded as it turns out.
But, yeah, I mean, I've heard horror stories of other CEO where they,
they literally have had to put the CEO on like his own instance of an email server,
you know, and
set up a VPN from his phone to the email server
because he refuses to use a good password or something.
I don't know if there's a good answer for that even.
Well, and I would say it's actually worse what they did in that. It sets
an example of, well, the, the higher ups do this and get away with it.
So, is it really that big of a deal?
Yeah.
It's really hard to say, do as I do or it's really hard when somebody says, do, as I say,
not as I do.
I agree with that 100%.
And I think that is a sign of, of bad leadership for what it's worth.
But I, I have a very strong suspicion
that if you're part of an organization with leadership that acts in that way,
you're probably not, that, that organization probably just isn't going to exist
for, for a terribly long period of time.
I mean, it's, it's conceivable, it made it this far,
potentially because of different leadership or, or whatever.
I think you'll eventually reach a point where that becomes
immensely problematic for the future.
Well being of whatever group it is you're a part of.
Well, and in a similar vein, this came out about a couple of days ago,
an internal White House memo published today by AXIOS
reveals that recent changes to the information operations and
security organizations there have left security team in a
tumult with many members headed for the door.
So basically, it sounds like back in the day
by, back in the day, I mean, like in 2014 or something,
they had a breach of an unclassified White House network by Russian intelligence,
a breach discovered by a friendly foreign government.
So, I mean, nice of them to tell you
right.
You know, uh but in July,
in a July reorganization,
this office was dissolved and its duties placed under
the White House office of the Chief Information Officer.
Now in fairness,
I think the White House should absolutely have a Chief Information Officer.
I mean, they,
you know, like they're not using typewriters down there.
-- And um essentially
-- they were even if they were, Kurt,
there was, there's an instant, I'll dig this up and put it in the show notes.
But, like,
the Russians bugged the typewriters at one point
and I think the Moscow Embassy where the,
whatever it was typed, all of the, basically the characters,
it was like a key logger and a typewriter
where it was transmitting
whatever was typed on the particular typewriters. Like, freaking genius. Right.
Yeah. The first electric, uh, the first electronic typewriters. What they
good on them? Clever.
Right.
So,
yeah, I mean, so the, the White House is even if they're not gutting the security
sort of office, the,
when you're,
when you're mixing things up and making it all kind
of messy that's going to impact your security posture.
Unquestionably. Absolutely.
You know, you want a smooth transition, not a,
not a bumpy transition if you are going to make changes.
Exactly. And
so again, I come back to this whole, you know, it, it's kind of hard to,
I, you know,
the US government is always talking about computer security
and how important it is to have computer security.
But in the last
week, I mean, we've seen that the higher ups just,
it's not that they don't care, it's that they're,
you know, actively misbehaving quite badly in some cases.
Well, so let's break this down in kind of a different way first.
-- And let's start with the first story of people infiltrating a skiff with
-- phone
infiltrating it was, they were quite loud about it,
but here's the reality if you or I did that we would probably go to jail.
I'm pretty sure
I,
yeah.
Yeah, we would go to jail. And there are,
if you were an employee of, let's say, some defense contractor and you did this,
you would lose your job immediately.
If you have clearance, it's gone
and you'll probably never work again
in the United States public sector, potentially in any public sector
in basically any of the Western nations.
Because
this, I mean,
this stuff is taken very seriously by the people who are responsible to enforce it.
And as it should be
because
these are the sort of situations where generally speaking,
when these people make mistakes, someone dies like literally someone dies, right?
This isn't like the metaphorical oh ha ha. They're gonna die like
you and I talk about, no, no, this is,
this is the real deal and I think that's what people
forget sometimes is when you're dealing with security at this level,
like lives are literally at stake.
Well, and it's, it's tricky too because you're dealing with, you know,
parties that have to have a high, high degree of trust
to do their job.
You know, you can't have two intelligence officials
having
a proper discussion and you know, they're,
they're afraid to say things because they're afraid they might be listened to,
right?
They,
you know, it's what's a classic thing with you know, the,
the various diplomats that have been,
you know, their communications have been leaked and it's, I mean, part of the,
being a diplomat is to have, you know,
open and honest and frank communications with your government.
You know, the one you work for,
to, to tell them what's going on. Right.
You know, and sometimes these diplomats say things and, and unfortunately,
you know, they, they can't really be
made,
uh, they can't be said in ways that
they inevitably be, inevitably will end up offending somebody. Right.
You know, there's just no nice way to say some things and they, you know,
if they have to worry about what they're saying, going public, they,
they literally can't do their job,
right.
You know, this is, I've read a lot of World War Two history and history in general and,
you know, this is a classic case of where governments don't,
can't have open and honest internal communication.
You know, people start filtering things or censoring things
and things go off the rails real fast.
Like this is one of the reasons the US sr
economy collapsed is because everybody was hiding bad news,
you know, and their, their economy literally was,
you know, shaving some sawdust.
You know, it was just a mess.
You know, these skis
are incredibly crucial
for
the government to operate.
Like there's, there's no,
you can't put too fine a point on it.
But, you know,
these things are absolutely required for people to just do their daily job
and talk to each other and if you take that away from them.
Yeah. I, I can't imagine how the US government would work.
It won't,
that's the answer.
And let's, let's keep going. So then we have the angle of
the White House has gotten rid of most of their security people
and we may never know why that is or what's happened.
They're,
they're getting rid of one office and apparently taking it under another group.
-- But the transition is very ugly.
-- Ok, that's, that's probably fair.
Although it sounds like from the story you sent me that a number of people
have departed due to this.
Well, it sounds like it's gone political. Which,
right,
how could anything at the White House not go politically
maybe.
But at the same time, I think this is one of those situations where, and I mean,
this is true of any organization.
If,
if your security team is trying to play politics in your organization,
you, you're probably going to have a bad day. I mean, that's the reality of it.
-- I
-- think it's inevitable that security teams end up playing politics. But
it,
I mean, there's playing politics and then there's playing politics where,
you know, things are ugly and people are trying to throw each other under the bus and,
you know,
and, and especially then you have your leadership,
not necessarily listening to you and doing things in a secure manner and I guess,
like, that's the sort of environment that look,
anyone who's any good is going to leave.
I mean, this freaking industry has a negative unemployment right now.
It's,
if, if someone wants a new job, they're going to have it by the end of the day.
And so if you're not treating your people right,
and you have a toxic work environment, like, say goodbye to anyone worth keeping.
I mean,
that's, that's what's going to happen.
Well, I think it's,
it's even worse than that because the majority of
people that I know that work for governments,
at least in Canada,
they actually believe like in the government trying to help make life better
for
people. They don't,
I mean, the pay is ok.
But yeah, you can definitely, especially in it,
you can make a lot more money in the private sector.
Absolutely.
I mean, I go back to, I mean, what we talked to, to Dick Clark about the book, right?
The Fifth Domain and
you listen to him talk and I mean,
that's a person who dedicated his career as
being a public servant and like he truly believes
in the mission of the government and that
it's going to make things better for people.
And I know that's,
uh, it'll say a topic that's up for debate in many, many cases.
But I, I respect that that's someone who, who is definitely,
he probably could have made
10 times as much money in the public, in the public at
least.
And he didn't and like that's very respectable. II, I appreciate that.
I think we need people like that.
And, and then there's just the more mundane day to day.
I don't even know what to call it,
stupidity of literally somebody with a passcode on their phone of 111111
and doing it on camera like it was on public TV.
You know, and, and this is literally, you know, as I mentioned in a much earlier show,
this is one of the reasons I got an iphone se is so my son couldn't
surf my password, right? I use my thumbprint to unlock it.
-- And that's a great reason
-- because, you know, Felix is good at that.
Sure.
Well, it, all kids are in, look, if the guy's password was 19462,
we'd be picking on him for that for some reason too.
-- But
-- it would take about 10 seconds to figure it out
as opposed to you just watch the thing and you're like,
seriously, like you just went.
Yeah, I mean, at least you could say then there was an attempt, an attempt was made,
you know, versus no attempt was made.
Although, you know, maybe, maybe he's playing like 3D chess and he's actually,
that's his burner phone.
I doubt it.
Who knows? And he was just checking the weather or ordering a pizza.
So, yeah, I mean, and again, how do you, how do you talk to people and be like,
it's really important to have a good password, you know,
-- when stuff like this happens constantly. No.
-- Look,
I bet you if you took a group of 100 people and you
will say, acquired all of their telephone passwords,
they would be the normal terrible distribution of passwords.
We see in every single password dump that has ever happened where you've got, like,
30% of them are going to be 1234.
And then it's kind of long tail after that.
And, and look the,
the House of Representatives and the
Senate and really all politicians everywhere,
they're probably a pretty accurate representation of the population as a whole.
And so I bet you a nontrivial number of them have won two,
34 as their password and they just always will because that's what people do.
Yeah. But I mean, these people, if nothing else should have been
educated, you know, we both work for Red Hat. Right.
We both went to the thing where you are given your
laptop and told to set a secure password and all that,
you know, and we're told what a secure password is.
They didn't have that when I started at Red Hat.
It was too
late.
Ok.
Well, anyways, they, you know, and, and the built in Linux
tools will filter for
some of the especially terrible passwords, you know,
-- built in the little dictionary thing you
-- can still get around that.
But, I mean, point taken.
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
But, I mean, it's so, I don't know, like,
-- no here
-- because fundamentally how are we going to secure all this stuff when,
you know, when your leadership doesn't, we
don't, that's the reality of it.
This is so, there, there's two problems here. Right.
Let's say we ignore the fact that the people in leadership positions
can do whatever they want with basically zero repercussions for their activities.
I think that is,
that is a symptom of a broken organization is what that is.
And that starts into political talk, which we don't want to do.
So let's just leave that at that and say that is the sad reality of it if you are
in a group and your leadership doesn't follow the
rules because they think that they're special for whatever reason
that is a dysfunctional organization and there is basically no
way to fix it because the leadership is broken,
which means it's going to be broken from the top to the bottom.
Full stop. Now,
let's talk about
crappy passwords on a cell phone. And you're saying, how do we secure that?
-- And the reality is we
-- don't. Oh,
no. I think that you replace it with fingerprints and face.
That's exactly right.
The fact is that passwords are terrible and people suck at password
and they're always going to, and the only way to fix it is to just not use passwords.
And yeah, fingerprint scanners are a great one. The face rec,
what are they? Face ID? I think Apple calls it
like, that's a good one right there. There's,
and, and we're even getting better with things like web often
in web browsers and you're getting like the click to login type
stuff where your phone just pops up a thing that says,
do you want to log in?
and
that's the stuff that's going to matter?
Because if you're relying on humans typing in passcodes, you're going to fail.
Well,
you know what it reminds me of is the difference between anti lock brakes
and teaching everybody to pump their brakes when they get into a slide,
anti
lock brakes will always work better than a human.
II, I
don't even remember. I remember learning about pump your brakes.
But yeah, it's,
I don't even think about it anymore because
everything I know has anti lock brakes now.
So who cares? Now? Now, here's the thing though.
So
we know people have terrible passwords,
which means you need to account for that
when you're architecting any sort of solutions.
And I'm going to pick on,
let's pick on email in this instance. Right.
So you've got your emails and you know
that some of your users have terrible passwords.
Now,
just to be clear you're talking about terrible passwords on
their emails or terrible passwords on their like phone.
Exactly.
That's, this is exactly where I was going with that. Right.
So you can protect the email system with,
let's pick on Gmail in this case because it's easy to understand
with Gmail. You have a pass, you have two factor authentication, right?
User logs in with a password, then they have to type in the,
the TOTP code or they plug in the UI
key or whatever the Titan key and they push a button or now even your phone can
do a little pop up thing that says is this you and you can say yes.
Right. Like there we go. That's great. Now people will log in with their phone
and they might have a password of all ones.
So now someone who has that phone has
the ability to potentially understand what's going on.
But this is also one of those cases where
all of the email is hosted somewhere else and you have
an auditable view into what's happening there.
And so this is a case of you can look at who's
accessing what and how and when and if suddenly one of your users
is we'll say, you know, downloading gigabytes of email. Why is that happening?
-- Like let's talk about this
-- sort of, but I mean, modern email clients download,
you know, kind of a lot of the email stored locally, blah, blah, blah,
but no, definitely you can get behavior,
you can get behavioral stuff based on the server.
Right. Right.
And if you're dealing with a group that, you know, is being actively explored
by known adversaries. That's the kind of stuff you look out for. You look out for
-- well,
-- actively targeted, I think would be a better phrase
either way.
Hopefully they're probably both true.
But you know what I mean? Like this is one of those cases where you have to assume
that the end user devices are corrupt and
they're, they're essentially,
they are the adversaries in a situation like this because
man, I, like I said, I bet 20 per,
20 or 30% of those Congress people have absolutely crap passwords on their phones.
And so what does that mean? Right. And you can architect around that and plan for it.
It's,
I'm not saying it's easy like
it's hard, but this is, I mean,
this is part of the challenge of being a
good security person is rather than telling people,
oh, you need a good password.
-- Well, that, that doesn't work. Right. Let's just pretend that we
-- tried for 50 years
and
-- it didn't work
-- like
we straight up, tried for 50 years and
we
-- are.
-- Right. Exactly. Exactly. And like
I was in, I was in a meeting the other day where they were,
someone was going on and on about training people to be more secure.
And I'm like, you know,
I would love to stand up and just start going nuts on this person, but it's like,
you know what it's not worth my time, I'm just going to let them talk and whatever,
whatever doesn't matter.
But it's the same deal. Right. Like you can't train people to be more secure.
-- People are people, they're going to do what they do.
-- I suspect you.
-- The thing I think more is that the return on investment for that is so low as to be,
-- it's
negative.
Well, once you count in productivity lost. Yeah,
it is. Right.
Well, not only that, most,
a lot of people will misconstrue what they've learned and they will
probably make more mistakes or take up more of someone else's time
-- than they would have in the first place. Well, or
-- worse.
They, you teach them something and then they refuse to forget it like that whole n
guidance on rotating path.
Now we're never going to kill
even though Nist is publicly recanted.
-- And everybody,
-- I still argue about this with people who say
they, they, they believe Nist
was right the first time.
And it's like if you can give me even bad evidence of this, I will agree with you.
And they of course,
have zero evidence of any sort because there is
no evidence because when they actually did the research,
they found out this is a terrible idea.
Who knew anyway. Anyway, we've been,
we've been rambling on and on about this and,
but, but for real, I feel like there's, there's two sides to this coin and I know we,
we, we've beat around the bush a lot and we, we've gone here and there.
But I mean, fundamentally
you can have bad leadership is bad leadership, right? You can't fix it,
don't try.
And I think this is another important thing actually that
I see with security people on a regular basis is
we see bad leadership
and we feel like we can fix it.
We're just, we're not, our message is wrong or we have to try harder.
We should push more. We should do. No. Look, sometimes your leadership just sucks.
Like, get out. That's the, that's the only way to fix that. You will never fix
bad leadership. It is the reality of it.
Well, I think one addendum to this is, is a lot of security people would benefit from
learning how to get,
how to sell to senior management. Yes. I mean,
right. If you can
a compelling argument and sell to them,
you're going to have a much easier time regardless.
-- I mean,
-- I'll agree with that and that's kind of a topic for another day.
But, I mean,
sometimes leadership is just bad and toxic and there's
nothing you can do about it except in,
in the, in the case of industry, go find a new job in the case of your government, like,
you know, boots on the ground, get out there and,
and find someone you can believe in and support them any way you,
because that's how it works.
But anyway, anyway, we've, we've gone on and on about this.
But then the other side of this story as well is
when you're architecting security solutions,
you should do your best to assume the reality of the situation.
And assuming everyone has an Impenetrable cell phone is ridiculous.
A significant number of your people have terrible passwords.
You know what the good news though is,
is that from what I've seen, at least of Apple and the higher end android makers
-- they're shooting for that target. They are.
-- And I appreciate that.
Right. They are actively, you know, security co-processors, security enclaves,
the biometrics based stuff, you know, I like, for example,
I sort of disagree and agree with Google's whole, the new face unlock thing on the,
what is it?
The Android,
whatever. Google's new. Yeah, their new flagship phone.
It still works with your eyes closed.
Like if you're sleeping I can just hold your phone over your face and
it wakes up
well, and I mean,
we've had documented cases where somebody's been sleeping and
somebody used their finger to unlock their phone,
you know.
So, on the one hand, you know, I can sort of see where Google's coming from that.
It's not a security vulnerability, but on the flip side, I love that. They said
-- they're going to work on fixing it.
-- Well, of course, it's a security vulnerability.
They're just, this is potato, potato nonsense.
Yeah. But, uh, but they're actually working on fixing it.
Which is more what I care about,
you know?
And I, I just think it's, I'm kind of wondering, you know,
another five years of this and we might
have Impenetrable phones or something close to it.
Maybe. I mean, I'm not going to hold my breath, but
-- that's good. I think
-- you would agree.
Got a lot better than
they're way better and they're getting better and they're
going to keep getting better and that's good because
these are people that are looking at actual problems
and they're coming up with actual solutions versus the,
I guess historical security precedent of just making
up solutions for problems that don't really
exist and your solutions don't work anyway.
So, like, you're just making everything worse for everybody
anyway. That, that, that's the point I've been guilty of that.
Everyone is we're all guilty of it. If you say you're not, you're lying.
It is easy to fall into that trap. And so, but, but for real,
that, that's kind of all right.
This has been a weird mishmash of, of, I guess, topics in that regard of,
of both ends of it.
But I mean, yeah, it's
all in all.
I would sum all this up as people are gonna
be people and that's just kind of where we land.
Ok.
No, I mean, I just, yeah, I,
-- we still can't teach everybody to use their turn signals
-- and
the solution to that is not to let people drive.
Right. Self driving cars will always use a turn signal
just like maybe, maybe we should build computers to run the government.
That sounds wonderful. Right. What could possibly go wrong?
I think there are some movies about that
anyway, I'm calling it.
All right. Well, thank you, Kurt. Thank you for listening.
You can go to Overs Source Beauty podcast.com. Hit up the show
not to Z Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag to hit us
on social media.
Kurt. Have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks
-- everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.