Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Curtsy Fried
-- and my partner in Thought Crime. Josh Bresser. Oh, man.
-- Thought Crime.
I feel like this week is a thought crime. It's,
I had Monday off because it was Memorial Day in the
United States and I have no idea what's going on.
I yesterday was Tuesday and I missed a bunch of stuff because people like, hey,
are you coming to this?
And I said it's Monday that's on Tuesday and they're like, it is Tuesday.
I'm like, oh, it is Tuesday, isn't it? Well, I'm still not coming, but
actually it's Wednesday. Now,
now,
now I know it doesn't matter anymore. I'm like, whatever. I don't even care.
And by the time you edit this, it'll be Thursday.
Well, it'll be later than that.
I've got other stuff to edit too, but I don't, I don't know what the hell edit this,
Kurt.
It's
-- anyway, time
-- and his illusion
time. Lunchtime, doubly so. Right.
Yeah, I think that was Tuesday afternoons.
It was a Thursday, right when the world ended Thursday.
Sorry,
Thursday.
This is Hitchhiker's guide to the Galaxy for Eddie View.
If you don't know, go read the book. You won't regret it. Yeah.
-- So
-- you had a topic for today?
I have a doozy of a topic. Ok. So
I'm going to put this in the context of
two services that have recently come to my attention.
The first is a site called
Code
Beg. Code
beg.org. I'll put links to all this in the show. Not Code
Beg is meant to be something similar to github, but run by a foundation, right?
So it's
basically, and they're,
they're specifically only hosting free and open source software.
They're not letting you host
non open source, right?
-- It was defined by like O SI. Yeah,
-- it's
-- got
-- to have an O SI license.
OK.
Cool.
There's also this thing that came to my,
it's called, is it veiled Valid? I don't know how to pronounce this word veil
ID
doesn't matter.
So anyway, this is, there's uh the guy who runs hackers dot town on Mastodon,
the Gibson
is his name, which is a marvelous name. Go
oh, pronounced
Vid
Valid
-- according to their Twitter. All right,
-- I'll try my best. But
Vid
go also go watch a movie hackers if you haven't. Why the Gibson is such a good name.
But anyway,
Vid is they, they, I'll just read what the Gibson wrote.
It says this and this is of course, very grandiose. But take it for what it's worth
this summer, we restore the future together.
Hackers that town has teamed up with CDC cult of the dead cow to take
back our birthright from the billionaires who squander
our best hope for a better future.
No more
veil it is here and it is our chance to restore, recover and rebuild.
And then I will also tie this in with Mastodon,
which you and I have become prolific users
-- of
-- because the alternative is Twitter and that's
just a pile of fire
even ignoring, OK, even if for a moment,
you ignore all the people that left and don't post there anymore.
Like my feed is like, even before I deleted it, it was pretty damn dry.
The outgoing links were broken one day and like the site is
slow or just apparently they decided not to pay their reddest bill,
-- which is why a whole bunch of stuff broke for the live casting
-- doesn't matter,
doesn't matter.
Let's move on.
-- I don't wanna, I don't wanna rant on Twitter
-- for we're unmasked on because it's,
it's the least worst option at this point.
Here's the thing though is I'm, and, and this is for us to discuss and
I feel like we are seeing this.
I don't know if I call it a resurgence necessarily, but a,
in an above average level of interest
in
cutting the shackles to what I would say is the,
the current like Gigantor it companies that are kind of running the world.
Well,
I like it personally, but I, I don't know if it's gonna make it. That's the thing.
But it's also how we ended up here in the
first place was a bunch of weirdos and start ups
that became Gigantor and then market forces and
incentives took over and they turned into jerks.
And I don't understand how you escape that because a great example would be open.
A, I started out as a nonprofit ostensibly to do a I open.
Well,
yeah,
that sort of changed
or? Oh, a great example. Wikipedia, what's wrong with Wikipedia?
Have you looked at how much money they're sitting on and
there's constantly begging for donations and what they're paying their people.
I'm
on the fence about that one because I recognize the value in a foundation
creating a heap of money to sit on because you don't know what's coming.
II I recognize the criticism.
I'm not gonna give them a free pass.
-- They've got 100 and $65 million in the bank.
-- Is that a bad thing though?
I mean, if we, if Wikipedia fails, like it would damage society
irreparably.
But I mean, at some point, well, it's like the, but here's a great example,
all these universities like Harvard that are essentially now an
endowment fund with the university stapled onto the side.
They are. Right. And, and that is my concern is how do you fundamentally
you can't fix social and business problems with technology?
Like no amount of clever.
Well, like all the Blockchain people Oh, we'll have a dow that'll blink,
blank blink and they end up just being evil.
I don't want to get into that this discussion
because I think this discussion is one of society.
I want to talk about the potential for these kind of grassroots,
purposely free and open
things
-- that feel like they're getting a groundswell
-- and here's a dirty secret.
One of the things that's really helping them get a groundswell is
running this stuff from a technical perspective is so cheap now,
like 20 some years ago, secure to portal.com.
Like I would write an article and it would get 100,000 views in a day.
And that was a massive amount of traffic and
we made so much money off the advertising. It was kind of frightening in hindsight.
But the like we needed, I think it was two or three racks of servers
and like,
and we started running into problems like the log processing
server was taking 23.5 hours to process the day's logs.
You got half an hour extra, it's fine.
And the admin was like uh so like, and I think we ended up getting a second one.
I don't know, like it used to be horrifically complicated to survey static website.
I mean, I'm not even talking
like reactive or people talking to each other or sending messages to each other.
I'm simply literally talking about static content and images going out
and serving that more than 100,000 times a day used to be an incredible nightmare.
And now you could have a Raspberry pi do it without breaking a sweat or
a raspberry pi could just run your instance of Mastodon with like 10 users.
No problem. You can do that.
Yes, I think that is one of the big changes is it's,
it's like the whole 3D printing thing.
It's like, oh, I want to prototype this plan
thing, but oh, getting a, a prototype mold and everything set up is like, you know,
$100,000 or more.
Well,
now you can have a 3D printer do it for like all in like
1000 bucks us if you buy a new one and filament and everything,
if you buy a really nice printer
way cheaper than that.
OK.
You, you may be correct. And I think part of this story as well is the
open source tooling to run all this stuff is better than ever.
Well, and that's the thing.
So you can focus on the value that you wanna
add and not running a bunch of stupid servers,
-- which
-- I guess ironically is why open source one because
the the universe adopted it because now instead of like
building
all of the crap, I need to serve a website, I can just serve the freaking website.
I, you know, I had to set up a static website for uh schema dot GSD dot id and I was like,
I want to do this with as little effort and management and maintenance as possible.
So yeah, like Cloudflare pages via github
-- done in like took about 15 minutes to set up in total.
-- Now.
Now I want to clarify though a lot of these
open source
services are not leveraging cloud flare, they're not leveraging Amazon.
Well, they're explicitly avoiding it.
Exactly because those organizations are part of the problem.
They're trying to circumvent. But
I mean, a good example is so like we had Jerry Bell on the show a while ago and he,
I don't know if he still does it,
but he was updating his blog on a regular
basis about like what was running Infosec dot social.
And it was a shockingly small amount of
hardware and he found that running it on actual
hardware was cheaper for him than running it on like cloud and we'll put
-- cloud in quotes
-- assuming you have the expertise to install and manage like that.
That's like you and me saying like getting a really high speed
mesh Wi Fi network at home set up is super easy.
Well, you know what you're doing.
And like,
and I had that problem where I had to rebalance my wifi channels and
I have to do it once a month now because like stuff stopped working,
like half my IOT devices dropped off the network and wouldn't rejoin.
I just had to rebalance the channels like magic
but that's the thing, right? People take a lot of this stuff for granted.
It's like a car mechanic saying, like, why do you,
why do you pay somebody to change your oil?
It's so easy.
Well, yes,
if you know what you're doing and own the right wrench and own
the little slide dolly thing in a pan to put the oil in.
I used to change the oil in my pickup truck all the time because it was like,
it was very expensive because it took like a ton of freaking oil.
And eventually I gave up because I'm just like, oh,
this is not worth my time because it took, you know,
it was an hour of my life vanished versus just dump it
off down the street and come back tomorrow and get it.
And that's, I mean, and, but again,
part of this is
there are more people with these expertise
and these expertise are easier like you and I
know how to tune file systems in ways that nobody in their right mind
ever needs to know again because you just buy an M two drive.
I have a fun fact for you.
So
at the time of recording last night
I installed an update to my, my Macbook that work makes me use
and the disc cooked itself,
it happens to me at least twice a year. I hate Macbooks.
They hate me like it's just, it's a mutual dislike. And so I spent
is significant basically all night long,
reinstalling Mac Os and getting all my files back. So,
-- it's very exciting. No, it's not nice. Their file system sucks
-- to be clear.
I'm not trying to
say it's, you know,
essentially things have gotten so much easier that it's actually,
you don't need a six figure salary
for assisted men. Plus another one to build the website. Plus another one.
I agree with that. But I don't want to talk about this either.
I'm just gonna keep kicking this can down the road till we get to the.
So here's the deal, let's say there's all of these free services like
KBG
is my favorite example right now.
Like I created an account, I poked around a little bit.
It's not as feature rich as github. Big surprise.
That's actually not necessarily a bad thing because in some ways,
things like github have too much like, like every time I log into linkedin,
I'm just like,
I just wanna go manage the groups that I have to manage and get the hell out of here.
Oh, man, I know. But anyway, so here's the thing. It takes a concerted effort
from
all of the people using say github
to want to migrate to something kind of more free.
You would it cost time to move your stuff
-- and all the links break. Right. Right.
-- All kinds of stuff, right.
And the question kind of, I, I keep thinking of,
I'm sure there's going to be people who move their stuff.
There's gonna be probably a nontrivial number of people because, like,
there's a lot of open source nerds who love this kind of stuff.
Do we think this sort of thing
can make it?
And I want to say yes. But I don't know.
-- I really don't, I'm
-- actually gonna steer you back to Mastodon in the sense of,
I don't care if Mastodon is popular with the masses or not, it scratches my itch.
-- You
-- know, that's a good point.
-- That's a very good point.
-- I don't care
because all the people I kind of wanna keep an eye on and chat with are on Mastodon.
-- So like
-- for sure,
you know, that's a good point.
You know, like there's a bunch of local restaurants.
I don't want to be super popular because I want to go there and eat and not wait in line.
I know how that,
you know, like I want them to be successful.
Like here's the thing that I noticed during COVID,
all the places that I truly love did find
some of them actually expanded, like,
like there was one that basically they were like,
yeah,
we took half our dining room and expanded
our kitchen because our take out business is
-- too busy.
-- Yeah, a bunch of restaurants.
I know, like they don't even have seating anymore.
They're like f in your take out now and I'm like, I can respect that.
-- Like, that's cool.
-- So the thing is you have to define success here and,
and it's like these, you know, these maximalist who are like
this solution has to take over the world for it to win.
Well, no,
like if this solution is even used by 0.01
of a percent of the existing Infosys uh Infra
uh ecosystem,
-- then that's a gazillion users and that's fine. And you
-- know what else?
I think that's, oh my goodness. You just flooded my brain with thoughts.
When you aren't trying to make money.
You don't care if your growth is 10% per quarter.
Like Mastodon doesn't care if it grows right?
-- Because Mastodon's just,
-- can we even really measure that because it's Federated.
-- So all the different servers and
-- like there was a,
a site that was basically checking, looking at Mastodon.
Oh, that's right. Yeah, I was checking.
But I mean, also like how much of those are spammers
-- and how much of that is blah, blah, blah. Right.
-- Oh, for sure. Absolutely. Like you.
But, but I mean, Twitter is no different. Twitter's always break.
Oh, we have like a billion more users. Yeah. And like half of them are spam.
Well, but again, it, it boils down to what is success like having more users? Cool.
But here's the problem.
Twitter defines success as, as that horrific user engagement.
The doom scroll keeping
you
hooked in and shoving ads down your throat and blah, blah, blah,
which
like to, well,
we were just discussing actually the attention economy before the podcast
and I was pointing out that like, as a, you know,
sophisticated technical person of means, we,
you and I do a lot of things to protect our attention, right?
-- Ad blockers,
-- I'm not sophisticated just
for the record.
But I mean, we, well, but do you run an ad blocker?
Yeah. So you're sophisticated?
Ok. And so that's the thing, right?
Like Twitter's version of success is literally my version of hell,
like if Twitter gets what they want out of me,
that would be my life would be a living hell.
OK. So no one can see this, but I just want to clarify what's going on.
So Kurt just moved his cameras so I can see his cat on his desk,
my,
my son's cat, whatever.
And this is twice. Now you've done this for me and he likes hanging out with me.
It amuses me that for some reason you feel the need to
move your camera so I can see you petting a cat,
you like chatting.
-- He likes
-- to be part of the, you know,
it's a three mammal podcast now,
a mammal.
Anyway. Anyway, OK. So,
-- oh man,
-- I always wanted to get him to purr to see if you can remove the noise.
I, I of course, I can, I, I have magic powers.
Kurt, like I should say, I don't like there's so many good plugins now.
The soft, well, and that's an,
an example of this is like, I've actually set up a CV S server
and it was a horrible nightmare back in the day,
-- the CV
-- S the version management system thing, you mean?
Yeah, that was
that
system.
If you don't know what that is,
-- like
-- the alternative was a shared folder.
Uh
Yes
and
no,
there were the most of the source code management systems of that time.
What they did is you had to lock a file,
check out a file. And when I say check out a copy,
you lock the file,
you check it out and now Kurt's moving his camera back that the cat left.
But you check,
you lock the file, you check it out, you make your changes,
you check it back in and then you unlock it.
And so it wasn't you, that's what made C DS so popular is CV S could apply a diff.
So you didn't have to lock a file because I remember what always happened.
Invariably at any of these places I worked,
someone would lock a file, go on vacation
and then we'd have to like unlock the freaking file.
It was, well, the, the metaphor was a library book
and it made sense because that's all the technology support at the time.
But, but again, that's the thing like setting this stuff up,
got so much easier and running it got easier and using it also got easier
-- and C DS was terrible.
-- Yeah. Like it was, there were books on it
and I mean,
using G
well and using Get
beyond simple pulls and checkouts. Like you start re basing and branching.
Yes, it gets complicated fast.
-- But like 99% of us never need to do that.
-- Uh C DS supported branches. It was terrible.
Yeah. So
I think the thing is to define success and here's the thing,
like a good example is the Global Security Database.
I I define success as people use it and find it useful.
And we're not there yet admittedly, but I don't define success, for example,
as like we beat CV E like I don't care.
See and part of this actually goes to
um
what is it, the uh what is it the four or five stages of management where
uh like the bottom level,
you essentially have prison games where people are shaking each other,
including people in their own group to get
tribal leadership is the name of that book.
Tribal leadership. Thank you. That's the one
I just recommended that to some people I know. Excellent.
And I'm kind of like where I am with the GST is like, II, I just don't care
about CV E like and I say this as somebody who used to
be very much into CV E for 20 years, well, 15 years
and I just don't care anymore. Like I want to go do my GSD thing.
And make something of value for the community.
And you know, and by that measure,
then KBG
will absolutely succeed.
Probably by the measure of, will Colberg get 1% of github
-- to transfer over to them. God, no, probably never.
-- No, probably not. Probably not.
But like,
who cares?
-- Yeah, I
-- mean, that's fair. And now here's going back to your Wikipedia complaints.
KBG
claims they have 12 years of revenue.
Well, 12 years of runway,
-- right?
-- 12 years of runway. So like I'm glad, right? I want a foundation, I want
12 X then they only have one. Well,
I don't know the math but you
know,
-- I
-- I understand what you're saying.
And obviously Mastodon is a similar situation where, well,
Mastodon's decentralized though.
So like if in
like for example, Masto
dot Social, that's where I started out. And so did you
and then both of us,
I went first
and then you went to Infosec dot Social because it was kind of like this is
infosec dot exchange, not Infosec dot Social. I think we called it that earlier.
We're like nubs.
Yeah,
the the Infosec site run by Jerry. Um
and like,
see that's the thing and and
Mastodon is a great example where it actually explicitly
in the protocol has a transfer mechanism of like,
you know, Kurt left here, went over there and like it told all the people
-- my
-- Mastodon account multiple times because I think
I started out on Mastodon dot online.
And then I think I went somewhere else and then
I went to Mastodon dot social and then I went to
Infosec dot Exchange. But, but here's so here's the thing though, right?
So Infosec dot Exchange
man, I wish, I wish stuff like it did that.
Oh man, seriously.
But, but so here's the thing, right?
There's still like the the core Mastodon people and like,
I still give them money even though I'm not using Mastodon dot social
anymore because I recognize like they need to fund development of Mastodon.
And then I also give Jerry Bunny for running
Infosec dot Exchange because I recognize like
he's a guy who's working way harder than me to give me a marvelous service, you know,
and, and I think that's part of it too. Like if Twitter said
we're gonna charge you $5 a month, I probably would have been like f this amount,
but I, I'm giving infosec
dot Exchange $5 a month and I'm happy to do it.
I don't feel like an abusive partner at infosec dot Exchange.
We're like Facebook and Twitter and all these social networks. Like
it's just about we're going to cram garbage down your
throat and you're gonna eat it and you're gonna like it
and monetize your privacy and monetize your
attention in ways that are detrimental to you
for sure. Oh, you know what? That's another thing.
My mental health when I quit using Twitter,
I
recognize the definite change in myself.
And I'm like, this makes me sad because if I see what happened to my, my, like,
happiness, I'm sure other people
really noticed it.
-- Yeah.
-- I think the other thing too is
we've only now had the time to see
the problems, especially at scale that come from these things.
Oh, perfect example in Canada is like the whole trucker convoy protest
debacle,
social media component of that.
Like if you told me that 10 years ago, I'd have been like,
like we need to get you to a hospital.
You've clearly taken all the drugs,
we need to get your stomach pumped,
right?
But, and now it's like, oh wow, no,
this is like some horrific toxic like stuff that leads to people getting dead.
I mean, like, oh for sure, for sure.
You know,
people are being radicalized online but the point is until like part of it is
people are like, oh, Facebook's not great. It's kind of gross, whatever.
But now we've actually seen how horrifically terrible it
is to the point where people are like,
oh, we need to build something better.
I mean,
that
has ideally
sort of technological and maybe social components to
prevent the failure scenarios of well Facebook and
you know, Twitter.
So I, I wonder and I don't want to come off sounding like a, a little too weird on this.
But I wonder if part of the failure problem, these social media sites have,
is their revenue
is ads
and
when your revenue is ads, you probably need like obscene user growth. Not, not 10%.
Probably way more than that.
No, it's worse than that because you're competing for attention.
There are so many things you can do now. Right? Like, whenever
mono is my, like whenever Felix says he's bored, I'm like, well,
you're a boring person
because you have books, you have a cat, you have homework,
you have like a ka jillion things to do.
You have all of the internet on your phone pocket thing.
The knowledge of humanity is within reach.
And so the problem too is,
is that Twitter is competing with linkedin
is competing with Facebook for your attention,
for your money, for your
hitting
share link or whatever.
Like we perfect example. We run a podcast.
We are competing for people's attention and, uh, to the tune of half an hour a week.
That's true. And we're a great example because we lose money on this podcast.
No,
none of this wee stuff. It's, you,
-- you pay all the bills.
-- I pay the bill. Wait, look, it's $40 a month. I can live with it.
-- I should probably cut you a check or something. I don't care.
-- Here's the thing.
-- This gives me joy.
-- I'll
send you more cheese.
There
you go.
Yeah, I'm almost out of cheesy
from when I smuggled them out of Canada.
-- Oh, ok.
-- I'll go, I'll go I'll go to Costco.
Which if, if anyone listening, there's a snack food in Canada called Chey's.
-- The bag looks like it's from 1965. They're still shipped in.
-- It is
-- because it is, it probably
-- is.
Like they are the best thing ever.
Well, the best though is their website. Have you been?
I've told you to go to their website.
It, no, it's like three pages from 1990.
-- And I
-- love their construction spinning.
And the thing is they're the kind of company that we make.
We're Hawkins, cheesy, we make cheesy.
I mean,
that,
that's the,
this,
I think this fits in nicely.
The conversation like this is a company that does their thing.
They, I assume they're not a public company.
-- Uh,
-- I think they're family owned, but
you know what I mean?
Like, there are times you can be content with what you have and that's ok sometimes.
Right. Like, there's plenty of small businesses like that.
Like our podcast is like that. I don't care what
our listener numbers are. It's not, I have no interest in, in growing the show.
It's just something we do.
And I think that's the power and that's probably what should scare
the crap out of anyone paying attention to all this open source.
Like they don't care if they grow or not.
Wt Hawkins Limited is currently under the directorship of President Ken Hawkins,
grandson of founder WT after WT Hawkins passed away in 1961.
His son WW
Hawkins,
uh assumed control and guided the company for nearly 30 years.
Continuing with the basics, family values fresh year.
But yeah, they basically, they make, they make cheesy and cheesy are delicious.
They are like, they're,
they're the best thing I was in Canada for the Open Source Summit in Vancouver.
And when I, when I got to the airport I had some time to kill.
And I look,
and I see they're selling cheesy at an airport store
and I literally filled my suitcase with as many cheeses.
I bought all of the cheesy.
They were selling at this little shop and the
lady looked at me like I was on something,
but I'm like these are the best.
I love these.
Yeah, that I filled my suitcase as full as I could fit in.
Well, it's like nutter butter up until a few years ago.
You could not get nutter butter in Canada reliably
or tim
tams. They're available in Australia and Western Canada.
But ok, so back to this. But that's the thing people.
The problem is a lot of people look at this from
the business point of view slash start up point of view
where we have to have hypergrowth because I'm gonna put two
or five years of my life and money into this thing.
And if I don't get a payoff at the end of a million dollars,
like I'm basically stupid and broke.
Whereas a lot of these open source people are either, like, this is kind of a hobby,
this is on the side or they're like, kind of, I'm just gonna say hippie,
I don't know what other word to use, but they're kind of like hippie and they're,
they're happy to live a very minimal lifestyle
and, like, turn out some code.
Ok. Ok.
I'm going to do the thing
I promised myself I wouldn't do. And I'm going to tie this into the last episode.
We just did about new spaces. Like
when Toma and Carol say we don't want to do name spaces, right?
What like our incentive is I like name spaces because
it makes certain things I want to do easier.
But
they don't and it doesn't make their lives easier.
They can say no, it's open source, there's nothing I can do.
They,
they have all the power and I think that's
the beauty of this and that's also what makes it
amazing and what makes open source so powerful.
And it's also to some degree the market has spoken like, if enough.
Oh, perfect example. Master Dawn and Search,
right? Masson
does not have search, which I personally believe is a good thing. A very good thing.
I didn't like it at first, but I,
-- I'm ok with it now. You
-- know what?
It prevents so much toxic and malicious behavior, right?
Because people can't get dog
pled. Like if you, if you want to be outraged about something.
You have to really work at it. You can't just search for people tooting about
cats and then go hate on them.
Right.
So,
yeah, so I, I personally love that Mastodon does not have search again.
At first I was like, oh, this is so stupid.
I need search and then I was like a few weeks later, I'm like, no,
apparently we don't need search.
This is just fine.
And
if enough people really, really, really wanted search, well,
they would demand it and somebody would fill that need either
for money or because they also think search is needed
and they would run a server with search now.
Is that gonna happen? Yeah, absolutely.
Because we've already seen that there's those
instances that are just crawling the,
the, the uh Fetty versus spear or whatever it's called
and like indexing everything and like
A I
companies are like, they, they're picking that food.
Well, and they,
they absolutely have to because like Reddit and all those companies are closing,
like, they're gonna be like shutterstock now, like, well, Twitter, right?
Like you want access to the tweets, it's starting at, what,
10 or 20 grand a month or something stupid.
Now, 42 $1000 is the expected cost for Twitter's API and this, this actually ties in,
there's a link I sent you earlier today.
There's
a
Reddit third party client, uh uh Apollo
is what it's called
and apparently
they're gonna start charging these third party apps to use
the API and Apollo will need $20 million a year
to
-- consider
-- that open A I was trained on every reddit comment with plus
like over three vote up
votes
like that is such gold in those hills.
So obviously,
conde Nast probably had a bunch of screaming meetings with their lawyers,
you know, saying how can we change the terms of service and how can we blah, blah,
blah anyways,
you know, for sure.
So
that's,
I think
again, it really boils down to is what does success mean to these entities.
And if the barrier to entry is so like perfect example, I was like, hey,
Mas sounds really cool.
Wouldn't it be cool if you could like find
people more easily by using their email address?
Well, yeah, there's a thing for that called web finger. It's literally a protocol,
right? Designed for that.
And so you can like
in your Mastodon search bar, you can type
K
at KT at
seafood.org and it will magically through the magical web finger,
bounce you to my actual account on infosec dot exchange.
And so I
built and run a web finger service that is free because
while the the cost of setting it up and building it was,
it was tens of hours to learn and to program, it's fun to do.
And I also wanted to learn how to do web finger.
So I'm like, well, what better way to learn than to build one.
And I ran into a bunch of weird problems.
And I also learned a lot about the protocol in actually
building it and deploying it and running into stuff.
And for example, I was pretty sure Twitter was going to go full
silly.
And so I basically have like AAA headless chrome thing that will actually, you know,
look at your Twitter profile to look for, you know,
to make sure you're linked to your, uh Mastodon profile.
And of course, now I'm like, ha ha
because I thought they were gonna maybe pull the plug on that in a year or two.
And then it's like, no, like a month later they pulled the plug
that and I'm like, whoa,
good thing. I'm smart and paranoid.
It's, it's like, literally just, it's not a hobby.
It's part of my job, but at the same time, it's such a small amount of time.
It's doable for one person and it's open source. So now anybody that wants to do it
doesn't even have to build it. They just
like
fork the code and turn it on. I
mean, to a degree that makes sense.
And that's the beauty of this is like, we're getting there with stuff, like get,
get used to be very complicated.
Now,
I'm sure you and I could probably build a passable, get service in a few weeks.
It wouldn't be great. It wouldn't be pretty,
-- I
-- don't think it would work,
they'll just use code
beg
and code
is built on. There's, uh,
what's the name of the thing that, that report that, that undercuts it.
There, there's some open source
software that's basically driving all of this and I, I don't remember the name of it.
Um, it's in their docks, I think somewhere you get the idea. There's,
there's a lot of open source that kind of
does a lot of this stuff that's really exciting.
And here's something I really love about a place like KBG
and how much they essentially don't care about the
quote unquote competition on the about page alternatives.
KG. And then they give a list of alternatives
like self hosting, git lab community edition source Hut Forge
go uh for,
for
Joe, I can't pronounce it.
That's the name of the thing that it runs on top of
the.
Yeah,
but that's the thing like they're like we're doing our thing and we're
so happy about doing our thing and we still fundamentally don't care about
winning or losing.
Here's some alternatives to use if you don't like us.
I mean,
I bet you there's not a similar page of github.
Yeah, I agree with that. And, and I think let's, let's land this plane.
But
I think from the open source angle and obviously not a lot of security in this one, but
I feel like we are at this inflection point in the world of software and services
and you could argue we were there with software
probably 10 or 15 years ago where I think
you had like the dominance of Windows and you had the open source people saying like,
we have to do something about this.
And I think
ironically
that war ended because open source one and Microsoft
-- just join the club
-- even more web browsers one.
-- And,
-- and sure that's part of it. And I think
though,
how many, how many things do you use on a daily basis that you can't live without,
that don't actually run on your computer and are just a web browser
mediated.
-- And so
-- as we record a podcast in a web browser,
basically open source one in the sense of,
oh, we don't really care if Windows owns the desktop, 90 whatever percent.
It just, you need a web browser,
-- right?
-- I guess that's fair. It doesn't matter.
-- They
-- basically went to the ne it's like
it, they skip to the next iteration of technology.
And I think now we have all these as a service things
that
at first they were novel and amusing. And I think now
many people are starting to ask questions and say, you know, like, what is going on?
Why are we doing these things? And so I'm hopeful
that we can see some of these like nonprofit foundation fueled entities
kind of catch on and maybe not take over.
But I think they're going to drive change
within these larger organizations and that's fundamentally what we want
or even, no, I would say even better than that,
they're gonna give people options that didn't exist before. And that's ok
and much more palatable options. Like, like, like
comparing
KBG to
github,
if I had to label one, like, cruelty free to programmers building,
it probably would be Coburg.
Right? Like,
maybe, maybe I, I don't know if I go that far but,
but
it, it's,
I think
I finally have some hope and II,
I would blame Mastodon for the inception of
-- this hope because I remember
-- that showed the Fet
Averse can work because the, the fetter
has been around for a long time. But
-- who cares?
-- No one, no one cared. No one
used it.
And it was until Twitter went full silly.
Like we actually do need somewhere else now.
-- And
-- that's the thing. I don't think
github's ever gonna go full silly.
-- I don't think a lot of these other services, Microsoft
-- is way
-- saner than people give them credit for
-- II, I think they are.
But I also think it's healthy
to have
something there poking them with a stick. And I feel like that was
ironically, it was open source to Microsoft 15 years ago.
It's now open source to Microsoft again, just in a different way.
I
think it only ever can be open source because it's in the
sense of it can only ever be the crazy small start ups.
-- It,
-- it has to be free and it has to be unencumbered by
the, the limits of capitalism as, as, like, like lefty as that sounds.
I think it's true though. I think
it is what has to happen. And I think in many instances,
open source had they, they hold all the cards
in these conversations.
And so, I don't know, I'm, I'm excited to see what's gonna happen. I, I'm, I
love the cult of the dead cow so I can't wait to
see what sort of ridiculous thing they probably do this summer.
Remember the birth of the web and just all the insanity from 95 to 99.
And now it's just a, we don't even think about websites anymore.
It's just, it's like roads or
-- like sidewalks.
-- It's,
it's unregulated infrastructure and that's a different problem.
But,
yeah,
but I mean, and then we saw that with, you know,
taking payments online in commerce and all of a
sudden now we're doing all this purchasing and whatever online
and now with these now we can do that with relatively
complicated and difficult services are now not so complicated and difficult
to
like, well, yeah, exactly.
And so I think we're going to continue
to see this and I think right now we're right for this explosion of community
because people realize
community matters like this is like we're humans like
that's true. Like community matters. I'm sorry, full stop.
But community
driven by
had based companies as we've seen with Facebook. Maybe it's not the way to go.
Yeah, I'll agree with that. All right, I'm, I'm landing this plane. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you ever for listening. Go to open source security, podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes, UZ Pound
do says podcast hashtag hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye.