Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 154 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
-- And
-- I'm so excited today, Kurt,
we have the two authors of a new book called The Fifth Domain.
Here. We have Dick Clark and Rob
Kaki with us.
So, since there's two of us, we're gonna need a little bit of,
I guess traffic direction here.
So,
Dick, why don't you introduce yourself first?
Tell us who you are and, and a little bit about what you're doing.
-- So,
-- I'm Dick Clark mainly. I'm Rob
Ky's co-author.
Nice. 10 years ago, Rob and I wrote a book called Cyber War. And we've been working
since then together. Both Rob and I have worked
in government in the White House on the National
Security Council doing policy in the Cyber area.
And
uh both Rob and I have been consultants independent of each other,
working with major corporations around the country trying to
help them figure out how to do cybersecurity.
-- Fabulous and Rob tell us about yourself.
-- Sure.
I spent about five years in the Obama administration for
those uh in the White House writing cybersecurity policy.
I am now out in the academic world and at
the Council on Foreign Relations where I'm a senior fellow
that is awesome.
And the reason they're here, I kind of mentioned this at the beginning is
there's a book that's coming out.
Actually, the, the same day this podcast is being released called
The Fifth Domain.
And so
I'm I I, Kurt and I read the book, we were, we were given copies and I must say it's a
fantastic book.
But for, for the listeners who might not understand, why don't we first?
Like what, what is the title? What is the Fifth Domain? What does that mean?
Well, the military, the US military thinks of everything as a domain
that they have to dominate in the past, they've talked about
land,
sea air
and outer space
as individual domains. And now
now that they have us Cyber command, they're talking about
cyberspace as being
the fifth Domain
where war will occur
and a domain that they have to dominate. Very cool.
And,
and there's something really special about this domain you talk about in the book,
which is the first four
that they exist, right? But the fifth one
-- we
-- built. Yeah.
And we think that's really important because
there's this view in the cybersecurity community
that
offense has this tremendous advantage
in cyber warfare and that it will never go away and that defense is hopeless. Well,
our point is that within the fifth domain because it's manmade,
we can therefore change it.
And that gives us a tremendous advantage over
the other domains which largely exist as they were
created by Mother nature.
So, and just so the viewers are aware, this book covers quite a lot of uh material.
And so,
uh me and Josh actually had a discussion yesterday about
what we wanted to talk about because quite frankly,
this could probably about 10 half hour episodes in total
if we cover the whole book at least. And so, well, I guess where do you even begin?
Well, I guess the, why, why do we need to secure this? Right.
And one of the things, one of the aspects you talk about is election security,
which I think is topical, right?
We have a federal election coming up here in Canada in the fall and the US,
-- you have elections coming up next year that are kind of important,
-- right?
We do,
we have a presidential election coming up
and the way we run presidential elections and
other federal elections is that we let the States and even the counties run them
and there are over 4000 counties and the notion
that 50 states, some of whom are largely populated by cows and, and, and,
and 4000 counties
that they're going to be able to know when the Russians,
the Russian military have been able to hack
into them and defend against the Russian military.
That's pretty, that's pretty ludicrous, but that's where we are.
Well, and so one of the things I wrote down actually is,
I know there's a lot of focus in this book about the Russians attacking the pri
the previous US presidential election.
And
I think there's irrefutable evidence that happened.
But the question I,
I keep thinking of is they were successful to a degree what's
going to stop other hostile nations from essentially doing the same things.
They're going to be like, well, heck I want to get in on this.
Well,
-- I
-- think
-- you have to understand the American political system to manipulate it.
And the Russians have made a practice of that over generations,
understand our political system as well as we do perhaps even better
because they were able to manipulate it at the precinct level,
at the lowest level of voter activity.
And they were able to use social media in a way
that none of us really recognized that you could do.
But you're right
now that it's become clear this is possible. Uh Others will try it.
I don't think they will be as adept
as the Russians were at manipulating our politics.
And one thing I was curious about so is
obviously there's more than one way to interfere
or to sort of manipulate an election.
And from what I've been reading, it sounds like, ok,
so one obvious possibility would be, you know, the Russians hack,
a bunch of voting machines and like, oh, hey, we elected Elmo.
Fantastic. Tickle me president and, and that doesn't seem
to be
what they're pursuing largely. Right.
It seems to be more, they're pursuing sort of the, the soft side
of,
well, like social media, the news, the, I,
I guess you could call it the propaganda sort of based attacks
which strikes me as something that's, you know,
we can't just use more firewalls and,
and necessarily apply technology to fix the problem.
I think the important thing to understand about the Russians is this
is not something that they're going to do every four years.
This is a continuous campaign really with the goal of sowing disruption and discord
than the United States.
And so it leaves many people wondering why would the Russians do things like
coax
anti vaccine sentiment
in the United States?
But they're doing that and the reason they're doing
that is because they want to show divisiveness,
their goal is to try and divide the country and they're doing that very successfully
in many people's view,
using social media and using targeted ad campaigns. So,
moving away from that a bit. So are there sort of technological solutions?
Because I I,
one thing I find fascinating is I've been reading more
and more about school systems all over the western world
having classes now where they're starting to learn about
how to research online and, and a component of that essentially,
is this a good source?
Is this a bad source. You know, they're, they're basically being taught to,
uh, discern the truth as it were.
And unfortunately though there don't seem to be any classes for adults in this,
uh,
do you think there will be any good technological
solutions here that can sort of be applied?
Well, there's a lot of talk here in Washington that there should be a federal law
and there should be federal regulations that regulate social media.
We certainly regulate commercial broadcasting.
I know it gets into the realm of, of restricting liberties and no one wants to do that.
Uh No one wants to restrict content or freedom of speech. But there may be times when
you need to really prove who you are.
There's certainly places for anonymity on the web.
Human rights people struggling inside China need
to be able to do things anonymously.
Uh But if you're an American voter and you're putting
your name out there saying this is my opinion,
perhaps you need to prove who you are and that's not
difficult if the social media companies want to do it.
Well, and that's something I've definitely noticed.
You know, I've, I've been on the internet for a long time now and back in the day,
you know, the quality of forums was, was relatively good and then we sort of hit,
you know, that inflection point where there was all these new people and
trolls and stuff.
And so I'm,
I'm on some forums where there actually are very strong identity requirements
and they're quite nice.
What I'm finding is, it's not so much that it's about the identity of the person.
It's about you get one account and if you, if you get booted,
you don't get another account. Right. So people
behave or they get kicked out and, and I don't think Facebook is going to do that,
but I, I've definitely noticed that the,
the forums where people have an incentive to behave
otherwise they don't get to come back.
They're much nicer than say, you know, something like Reddit or Facebook.
I mean, well,
let's pick on Facebook for a second because
Facebook hired everybody around me in my office.
Literally
from the Obama NSC Facebook now has the ability to validate
identities using a driver's license in order to buy political advertising.
They're doing a real world through the US mail verification system.
In order to be able to buy an ad online,
there's no reason that they could not extend that
out either on a voluntary basis or on a
mandatory basis so that you would have some trust
when somebody says I'm a member of your community,
I'm thinking of voting this way.
I'm telling
you, it's not a throwaway vote, vote for Jill Sanders.
You might not,
in fact trust them if that was an anonymous person
who didn't have a check mark next to their name.
And so I think for that reason, we really should be pushing Facebook,
Twitter and others towards real names.
Now that said there are plenty of real name trolls on Twitter.
I won't mention any right now,
but
I'm, I'm thinking of a couple.
I think that's a good point because, well,
in a similar situation I've noticed with reviews on restaurants, I,
I tend to look at the, the best and the worst reviews right,
to make sure it's sort of consistent, whatever.
And quite often
the best reviews will be, you know, you click the best review and it's glowing,
but it's written a little strangely.
And so it became pretty obvious that, you know,
this person is probably not a person and it's
reviews for hire.
And I, you know,
the the problem I had was that I could have gone through and reported them all.
But,
you know, is it, is it worthwhile? And that's my,
my other concern is even if we kind of have this real ID, that will definitely,
I think help with, you know, this person telling me to, yeah,
vote for whoever locally
is this person local and informed or is it some, you know,
someone from the other side of Canada who's being paid to do this.
But secondly, is, is the mechanisms to then
if you suspect somebody is a troll, how you know, how do we handle that at scale?
Well, I think artificial intelligence can do some of that at scale.
But what we propose in the book is a system separate.
And apart from the election issue.
And apart from social media,
we propose a system called Really You with the letter
U because we need to be able to replace passwords.
Online,
passwords are a mess. They're 1/20 century solution. We need to move on.
There are ways of doing it.
But in, in the United States,
at least we don't have a national ID and people don't like the idea of national ID.
They think that's big,
big government and Big Brother and the first slippery slope
to ending democracy is to have a national ID.
It's crazy, but that's the way people feel.
So what we propose is
let's have
two or three companies,
they could be banks, they can be things like mastercard or Visa
issue,
a
multi
factor authentication token card that you can use
anywhere online to verify who you are
and to get this going,
we call upon the government
to be the first adopter to say,
yeah, we'll accept that online as a way of getting into
your social security or your Medicare or your taxes.
I'm glad you brought this up. It's so
I think telling Facebook
you should verify identities is never gonna happen. Let's face it.
They, we, we can barely get them to do anything decent.
This is, I think that's so far out of the question.
But I feel like, and,
and this is something I've said in the past more times than I can count is I,
if we don't regulate a lot of the security,
it's just never gonna happen because people don't care.
And I, I feel like
the government
having something like this. Well, you're right.
It's going to be difficult to convince people to, to use it perhaps, but it would,
it would have enormous
consequences, I think for like, like literally everything we do. Right.
I mean, one of the it it's I I guess
tell us about
how,
how, how do we get this to happen? Right? It's easy to say. So the government should,
you know, have a national ID? But, but what does that really mean? Right.
How do we see something like that become a reality?
I think where, where we really began with this is to say, ok, Congress has got to act.
Congress has got to put a mandate on the federal agencies
to sponsor the creation of the system
and then to pay for it on a transactional basis, right? Every time you go to validate
your ID,
in order to make a tax transaction or
social security transaction or apply for a passport,
they need to be willing to pay an identity provider of your choosing.
And if you do that,
you're going to be doing one of the most powerful things that Congress can do,
which is to create a market.
Once you have that market started,
I guarantee you that the big banks and even maybe Facebook will latch on to that
uh and use it but it is not something that seems to be happening on its own without that
shove from the US Congress.
I like this because
I feel like when the, when the government shows up and mandate something, people,
it doesn't matter what it is, right?
They could, they could mandate like, free money and someone would complain.
But
I, if you
leverage the spending power of federal agencies now
the market is driving the change, right? Which is, that's really cool.
Well, a stupid question here but like I actually have us government ID, right?
I have a nexus card because quite frankly, no lineups.
I mean, well, couldn't you simply have the IRS mandate that if you want to talk to us,
you have to have this strong identity,
right?
I mean, we, we have this in Canada where, you know,
if I want to have my Alberta government ID account
so I can access my health care records online.
I have to sign up for an Alberta, you know,
government online identity which involves validating it through the
mail with my driver's license and all that.
I mean, it, it seems to me that you,
you can just simply have somebody like the IRS do this.
And so I guess my question would be why,
why hasn't this happened or is it just the political will, isn't there
a couple of reasons?
One is a group of Americans that will never
do whatever the government tells them to do,
get a measles vaccine. No, no, that's big government.
Uh, ok. Die, I mean, you know,
the, the other reason is that there's a,
a group of largely Republicans in the Congress and
now in the White House who think that regulation,
federal government regulation is some sort of sin.
And they've even had a rule in this Trump administration
that you can't have a new regulation
unless you get rid of two existing ones.
Uh And how lo how logical is that it's difficult to get regulation
in some cases. However, we need it. We don't want micro
regulation where the government tells you how big the screw is and
how many times you have to turn it to the right.
We want regulation
that identifies goals and says this is what we want you to do
and we want a third party independent of the government independent of you
to come in and audit that you've gotten to the goal. And that's kind of the, the notion
that we have with the National Institute of Standards, the so called N
cyber framework, it's voluntary, but increasingly a lot of companies are doing it.
Yeah, because it, it works right.
I mean, it's,
I, I know, I, I have a lot of personal experience with it.
People deploy it because it, it does what it says, which is, which is fantastic.
So I guess speaking of the cybersecurity framework.
Let's use that as kind of a pivot point because I know we could,
we could all whinge about I DS all day long, no doubt.
But I'm, I'm really curious. One of the things that's covered in this book in depth is
many of the cyber attacks we've seen to date
and there are more than I can count or go over in the short period of time we have.
But I guess
the one thing that keeps sticking out to me is
there are
numerous cyber attacks from a nation state against another nation state.
And we've seen really no sort of response ever. Right.
I mean, I'd compare this to in the, in the kinetic world, right.
Kinetic being, you know, traditional warfare essentially.
If somebody shoots a missile at you, like you're gonna come get them,
you're not just gonna sit there and say, oh, well, that was neat.
So this is one of the challenges, I mean,
one of the things that's happened in the United States is at the end of the Cold War.
Everybody who understood
Cold war tactics. Cold war strategy. Cold War ideology was kind of out of a job.
And then 10 years later, we got terrorism and kind of 10 years after that,
we got cybersecurity.
And so we've been kind of reinventing
all of the strategies from the Cold War,
principally deterrence and trying to apply them to cyberspace and trying to
find equivalency between a cyber attack
and an intercontinental ballistic missile.
And even though we have probably written 10,000 pages on the subject, I mean,
the Rand Corporation alone has probably written 10,000 pages.
We really,
I think have concluded that deterrence does
not work in cyberspace for cyber attacks.
-- What,
-- what does deterrence mean in cyber even?
-- Well, I
-- think deterrence means if there's a cyber attack on me,
I will be able to identify who did it called attribution.
I'll be able to identify who did it with a
99.9% certainty.
And I will be able to strike back at that person
and do more damage to them than they did to me.
Now, for that to work,
you have to believe that the guy you're going to attack
has that offensive capability and that you're afraid of it.
Well, how do you know, how do you know what cyber weapons somebody has,
how do you know how well they will work?
And frankly how do you know that you'll get caught because, you know,
not everybody is the North Koreans who leave a Kimchi trail to, to, you know,
Pyongyang,
there are lots of people like the Israelis and frankly the United
States and occasionally the Russians that do things in a way.
It's really not clear who did the attack and sometimes some of the people use
the other people's weapons so that it will look like it was somebody else.
This is the interesting thing that the Russians have stolen American weapons,
cyber weapons.
-- It was the NSA one, the eternal blue. Right.
-- Right. Right. That's one of them.
And some CIA weapons have shown up online
and now Chinese weapons are being exposed online.
Gee, I wonder who did that.
So,
you know, if you're attacked by a Chinese weapon,
does that mean
that was a Chinese attack or what was it? The American attack?
I want to build on Dick's point here.
The, the final piece of it is even if you can sort out all those puzzles.
There's a major question particularly with the Russians
about whether or not Vladimir Putin actually cares if
he turns out the lights in the United States and we turn out the lights in Moscow.
Does he, he care about that?
Russia is a country where 25% of the population doesn't have indoor plumbing.
So taking off the lights may not really matter.
And if you look over the last five years,
the consequences that he has accepted on behalf of his
countrymen for the things he has done in Ukraine,
for the things he has done in Syria.
I suggest that he doesn't actually care about the care and
feeding of his people on a day to day basis.
We have a line in the book where we talk about,
let's say the Russians turned out the power grid in the
US on a cold dark night and kept it off,
you know, they didn't just turn it off, they destroyed the equipment.
And so
two or three weeks into a blackout where the ATM S aren't working and you
can't get cash and you can't buy food and just in time deliveries aren't happening.
And the United States says, oh, well, fear not.
We turned off the lights in Moscow,
we have a line in the book that says, uh
how will that make you feel? You know,
is,
is it really equivalent because you're going to be
freezing in somewhere in the United States and?
All right. So are the people in Moscow, but at least they have vodka.
Well, so it sounds like the whole, you know, this goes back to the Cold War,
the counter value target won't work, right?
So, attacking sort of the civilian side of say your adversary.
So what about the counter force targeting? Why don't we just go
if we know who did it? And we know
like it was, it's actually attributable to a government, you know, it's not about
rogue people or whatever, why not go counter force and attack their, you know,
their attack infrastructure and take it out.
So I think it's a really interesting idea and
the United States has toyed around with that,
right.
We saw Cyber command very loudly announced that they'd carried
out disruptive attacks against the internet research agency in Russia.
Uh You know, my, my view on that was great.
You knocked out the power to their building. Ok.
Where's the nearest Starbucks turns out it's, you know, almost two miles away.
So they might have had to drive instead of
just walking across the street with their laptops.
Right. Counter cyber force is, is really not something that is likely
to be that effective.
I think there is some gains that can
be made from targeting the external infrastructure.
But right now the the mechanisms that you
have to legally take down third party infrastructure
are really not there.
They really can't move at the speed that Attackers can reconstitute them.
Yeah, because the attacks frequently come from within your own country.
You know,
we saw that when the Iranians attacked us banks a few
years back and when we traced back the attack routes,
they were coming from servers
that they had compromised
inside the United States.
They, they were all in Texas.
And I, I really think I was,
I was in the White House at the time and I really think
the office of legal Counsel is still actually wrestling with the question of,
could the president have ordered cyber command to attack a server in Texas?
I, I would hope the answer is no,
but I know it's more complicated than that
Canada weapons free. But you know us.
Right.
Well, I mean, it occurs to me, you know, for example,
we do have established legal doctrines that if you know,
something is of significant hazard
you know, uh, for example, like the fire marshal shows up and tells you to unplug it,
right? Or, you know, the police show up and tell you to stop.
For example, you know, when it's dry out,
you're not allowed to shoot off fireworks because you might start a forest fire.
Right? And they'll go confiscate your fireworks and arrest you.
-- If you're being a real jerk,
-- the FBI can do that.
The FBI can get a warrant and go and disconnect a server.
But you can, you know how easy it is to get a server these days.
You want a server on Amazon's Cloud and you've got a credit card
that still works.
Even if you, even if you stole it from somebody, if,
if you got a credit card that works and you've got a laptop,
you can have a server spin up in Amazon's Cloud in a matter of two minutes.
You do your attack and then you spin it down
and then when the FBI shows up with a warrant, who are they serving?
There's no, it's a virtual server and it lasted for two minutes.
Well, I'm always reminded of when I get the, uh,
the spam text with a link to a website that's obviously been hacked.
You know, it's usually some ill maintained little small business website. And,
yeah, I've kind of wondered about that.
Like, should I report it to somebody who should, like, turn it off?
So they may notice and fix it or it's just sort of like litter on the streets.
It's just something we kind of have to live with.
Yeah.
I mean, I, I think one of the interesting things and,
and I think we're gonna get some push back for this.
A lot of
the book. We're, we're essentially saying, look,
we need to make the victims or the intermediate victims
of cybercrime
responsible for some of the consequences. right?
The first reaction that most people have
is when something bad habits in cyberspace,
go find the people who did it, go find the Russians, go find the Chinese. Well,
good luck with that.
We've had indictments out now for five years against the Chinese
actors that were responsible for a series of very serious intellectual property
uh incidents, uh intellectual property theft,
they're never going to see the inside of a courtroom.
So just focusing on the actors
isn't enough.
One of the things that we've been pushing for in, in the book is to say, look, you know,
if Godaddy or Amazon or Microsoft is the staging grounds for an attack,
they have to have some responsibility,
they have to have some liability for that bad outcome. And if they do,
they will do a much better job of policing their own infrastructure
and that's how we can get to it. Not by FBI door knocking,
but by creating liability in which Amazon will say, oh,
-- we can't have that kind of activity on our systems, on our
-- network.
That seems fair to me. I'm curious, is,
does that exist elsewhere
in, I guess the Real World? I'm, I'm,
-- yeah,
-- Josh, we have, uh,
there's definitely liability for something that's a known hazard.
Well, I mean, the, the simplest example is, you know, here in Canada, like if you
don't shovel your walk, uh, you can get a fine
but more to the point if you know, your walk is icy and somebody slips and falls,
you know, they, yeah, they can definitely pursue you legally because
uh it's Canada, we know that our sidewalks get icy.
-- You should go salt and sand that right.
-- And you,
and you know that your servers are going to get hacked.
You shouldn't be surprised when they do. Right? And so
from that perspective, I, I think there is a strong
uh view, at least in some legal communities in the United States,
then you just want to place liability where it's going to do the most good.
We're holding somebody liable is going to make uh the situation improve.
And that's what we've been advocating.
And, and one of the examples of that is the, is the idea that
actually it was Rob's idea first,
which is
when your data is stolen, the company from which it is stolen should have to pay.
And if you pay a penalty based on the number of identities stolen,
let's say how about $10 in identity every time your identity is stolen,
that company has to pay $10. You'd bankrupt some companies.
-- I,
-- I'd be a millionaire right now. I think so.
No, I, I like that though. I feel like there's, you need incentives. Right.
And we let's face it on the internet today.
-- Right. Yes.
-- Well, that's true. I guess in that case it's, it's a disincentive
but, I mean, today there's, there's no consequences for, you know, you,
you hack someone, no consequences, you steal the data, no consequences, you, it's,
it's, it's crazy, right?
Yeah.
And the I mean, the place that we can introduce the consequences,
right is on the holders of that data, right?
We can't introduce consequences very easily. I'm not saying we shouldn't try.
I'm not saying we can't do more to pursue cyber criminals. We can
and we absolutely should. But where we have levers are over the holders of the data.
And so that's where we need to apply pressure.
We're, we're kind of approaching the end and I would love to give you each
and a chance to kind of say closing thoughts as kind of what can we do?
What does it mean?
And of course, why everyone should,
should purchase a book because I will say if
you're listening to this uh buy this book,
you will not regret it.
So
as as was decided previously in the order of the authors on the book, Dick, I,
this book is
optimistic. 10 years ago, we said
no company can defend itself against cyber attacks. In this book. We say
there are companies who are successfully doing it.
There is a way to do it.
The technology has evolved.
You just have to figure out how to do it involves spending money.
Yeah, it involves changing procedures. Yeah,
but
it is now possible, maybe this will be a moment in time that only lasts a few years.
But it is now possible to defend yourself in cyberspace.
And we should not accept it when people don't.
And just to add to that, you know, what,
what I would say is that what we kept coming back to as we were writing
this book was the idea that we get so much value out of the internet.
And what we're not doing is pushing any of that value back in to protect it.
If we realized how truly valuable the system is,
how truly valuable our information was, we would absolutely
be spending a lot more and taking cybersecurity a lot more seriously.
And that's the big argument we're making in this book.
Cybersecurity is possible. It's getting easier all the time.
The Attackers advantage is eroding.
We know that because the Attackers are getting caught left and right now in a way,
they weren't 10 years ago and that actually is good news.
Yes,
I, I love that. It is. I, I think you, you two summed it up beautifully. And so
I I also
want to call out that
Dick has a podcast called Future State, which
is a fabulous show.
I'll put a link to it in the show notes and anyone who's listening
to this show and has any interest in us policy would adore it.
I, I love it. It's been fantastic since I've discovered it.
Yeah, I guess Kurt. Do you have any closing thoughts?
Well, just
the one thing I really took away from reading the book
is that as they said, you know,
it is becoming increasingly possible to defend yourself,
but that it's going to take some effort.
But I,
I just keep coming back to the simple fact that
I don't know a single person who has a job
that they can really effectively do without the internet,
like full stop.
Right.
And, and I mean, even trades people, you know, they,
they need to access their manuals and stuff.
So, yeah, it just, it kind of blows me away that, you know,
like electricity and running water that's safe to drink.
We,
we take this for way too much granted.
Well, you gotta remember though.
I mean, it took, took a long time to get clean drinking water.
So we're, we're on the way.
But in, in books like this, I think are a much needed step in the right direction.
And so
thank you gentlemen for everyone listening. The book is out today.
If you're listening to the show, when it comes out. Uh But it's July 16th
and you will not regret purchasing this book.
I, I highly I cannot recommend it enough.
I'm already telling all the people I know to preorder it because it's that good.
Marvelous. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com.
I'll have links to the book and, and Rob and Dick and,
and all the other things we talked about.
You can use the Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag You hit us up on social media and yes gentlemen. Thank you all for your time.
-- I truly appreciate it. Thank
-- you.
-- Thank
-- you. Thanks everybody.
Awesome. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.