Hello and welcome to the open source Security podcast
episode 166 with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime,
Josh Pressers.
So I'm feeling extra aware this month. Are you by chance?
No.
So I guess happy cybersecurity Awareness Month to everybody.
I hope you've prepared gifts.
I feel like a month is too long
or maybe every month should be cybersecurity awareness month.
Well,
yeah, because, I mean, should we only
be extra,
like, is the threat level orange or blue or green or something now this month?
And we need to be
cautious.
Tomato. Ok. Heirloom tomato or just regular tomato, whatever. It doesn't matter.
It's all the same.
It's,
I always love when it, it's not.
So it's different now, but back after September 11th, I remember the,
the airports that always say, you know,
the Transportation and Security administration has raised the
threat level to orange and it's like,
what does that mean?
And nobody knew and it didn't matter.
Well, there's nothing actionable. Right. Right. Right. Exactly.
Like, there's nothing actionable, like, like does threat level orange mean,
I need to start duct taping up all my windows with plastic.
I don't know.
I mean, they might as well have said, like,
the threat level is toothbrush and that would have made as much sense to me
except I would have cared more if it was toothbrush, they'd be like,
why is it toothbrush?
What does that mean?
Yeah, because like, some of these awareness months kind of make sense.
Like, um, there's, uh, what's the one for smoke alarms or you should, like,
go change all the batteries in your smoke alarms?
And like, if you do that once a year, that's a good thing. Like that's,
that's simple.
And it's, you know,
we can all get behind having smoke alarms with actual batteries that work in them.
So what we probably need
is just Password Appreciation Day where we all
go online and type our passwords into Google
and appreciate them.
But
no, I mean, I agree with you and I think
this is something that's becoming more and more apparent to me over
time is the fact that the security people love handing out advice,
but there's never any actionable items in it.
Well, oh, actually worse, sometimes there is actionable advice,
but it's ridiculous and it's like,
somehow magically qualify each link before you check on
it to make sure it's trusted and then,
and only then click on it like
that's ridiculous. I can't do that.
And even if you could,
there's, what was it?
Wasn't there just an adobe redirection that was found where the link was literally
going to Adobe and then it could send you anywhere they wanted after that.
It, you
know, I, I agree completely. There's,
there's so much rotten advice and I feel like
cybersecurity Awareness Month
just feels like a poke with a hot poker of ha ha
ha ha.
There's still nothing you can do.
Yeah.
Yeah. I, I don't even know what to say anymore. Like I just,
I think it's, I like the idea of,
like, I get from a media marketing perspective. It's
probably more effective to do this once a year than to try and do it every day.
But
again, I'm not real clear on what I'm supposed to be doing or
anything. Like,
should we all make sure everybody has automated updates enabled everywhere and is,
you know,
ideally goes and gets a password manager because
honestly those two bits of advice would actually
help.
Yeah. Yeah, they would. But I'm sure nobody will talk about it
because why would they,
it's
anyway, whatever, whatever it's annoying. I don't have a lot to say. I feel like
everyone has their special days and special months
and cybersecurity gets one.
And unfortunately
once again we squander what we have because we don't know what to do and
it's frustrating and I guess we'll just remain
bitter and complain on our podcast and that's
pretty much it.
Yeah. I don't know. I
like honestly the thing I actually did and maybe this is a piece of actionable advice
for our viewers that might help is I've set up a bunch of calendar reminders.
Generally quarterly things.
For example,
I have like a little an Amazon instance running a web server to do my my omni
focus to do software synchronization between all my devices and so quarterly,
I get an email saying like go log into the host and
reboot it and make sure all the packages have been updating,
you know, or for example, I have, oh,
I have a monthly reminder to check my son's
cell phone plan because it's like a prepaid thing.
And if you don't pay every once in a while after it expires after 365 days.
So it's,
it's kind of annoying because it's one of
those situations where it's rare enough that,
yeah, I'll totally forget at some point and then his cell phone will stop working.
Yeah, that, that happened to my kids too.
Actually, I had,
my son had a prepaid for a while and that exact thing
happened where I didn't pay it and it just quit working one day
and he got a text message and when they finally, he's like, dad,
you need to turn my phone back on.
I said, oh, did it expire? He was like, yeah, a
couple of weeks ago they sent me this message.
I'm like, but you got to tell me these things. Come on.
It's, it's typical, I guess user behavior is how I would describe that well,
until it breaks, it's why would you complain?
It was broken for a month.
And, well, apparently, well, can I just point out my response would have been, like,
clearly I don't need that prepaid plan.
Yeah. Well, that was kind of the thinking. Yes.
Yeah.
I set up a bunch of just reminders, like,
even things like to check the programming on the thermostat to make sure, you know,
because I, again, I forget to change the temperature, you know,
from like summer to fall
to, well, it's winter now.
It's like minus three degrees outside and it was snowing this morning. Right.
So, you know,
I need to go twiddle with the thermostat and get it kind of into wintery mode.
Right.
I, I think maybe the moral of the story is
because to me, I mean, there are definite things you can do
that are beneficial once a year, like changing the batteries in your smoke alarms.
But when it comes to infosec,
I feel like it's more of a continuous process type deal for most things.
Like you should probably check that your backups are working more than once a year.
I mean, yes.
And if we tell people, ok, so, I mean, let's, let's put this on its head a little bit.
Let's say I'm already using a password manager.
I already have two factor off enabled.
What's my yearly check? Now,
what,
what do I do make sure software updates are
enabled and that it actually has been updating.
Ok.
That's, uh, that's about all I got. Right.
There's, this is, I mean, it's terrible, I think,
and now I think there's two sides to this coin, I think on one side,
this is an acknowledgment of the fact that what we do
is,
but on the other side,
I think the reason it's difficult is because we don't truly understand a lot
of these problems and we don't have effective measures to go against them.
It's kind of like if there is no such thing as a smoke alarm,
what would you?
Oh, let's, let's, let's explore this actually thinking about,
let's say there's no such thing as smoke alarms.
You have fire prevention month and you're telling people, all right,
you have to prevent fire.
So I want you to move your oily rags and make sure you got
a pail of sand next to the furnace or a pail of water.
Right. Right.
Exactly.
And the reality is that advice is terrible and
most people aren't going to do that crap.
But if you have a smoke alarm,
that is an enormous difference and is a complete game changer because let's face it.
If your house lights on fire, smoke alarm goes off,
you just get the heck out and call in the professionals.
And today in the security world we don't have that.
You don't know if your house is on fire part of it is the
changes so much.
Like, I remember when password managers, I mean,
they've been around forever but they were basically unusable
in the sense of it was like an encrypted text file.
So, like you might as well just have an encrypted spreadsheet or whatever. Right?
I remember those days. Yes, it was, it was terrible. I
agree.
And now, you know, with the integration with web browsers and,
and even the integration with applications.
Well, that, that's better. I
mean, I noticed, you know,
uh I forget when it showed up on Apple devices but at
some point I os had that automatically update button show up,
you know, in settings.
And it was like, yes, please like and, and it's reasonably intelligent, you know,
it tries to do to overnight when you're sleeping and only if
you have like 50% battery or more and stuff like that.
So it doesn't like brick itself, you know, which is nice.
I appreciate my device, not auto bricking itself.
You laugh, but you and I have both had that happen.
I'm sure I've, I've broken so many things. It's not even funny.
Like I had to do this crazy bio
upgrade path that I think I talked about on the podcast.
Remember about with the gaming PC where,
you know, it was literally, I ended up
doing something like about 15 updates of software and bios, firmware, bios,
firmware, utilities, drivers, you know,
rebooting windows multiple times so that I could get,
I basically wanted to get the bios on the motherboard up to date enough so that I can
upgrade the CPU at some point in the future and then not have to do it then.
And, you know, the, the binaries of utility
I need are missing.
Uh, no, you did not tell that story on the podcast because it was really,
really long and you cut it.
Oh,
yeah. Exactly. Right. Exactly. It was, it was such a,
like, it literally took two hours with, you know,
about half an hour of actual work and a lot of waiting.
No, I'm gonna cut this one.
But, um, yeah, so, I mean, I
guess
what I would do is if
you want to do Cybersecurity Awareness Month, my advice would be,
is probably the two biggest things you could do is get people to make
sure their software is up to date and where possible auto updates are enabled,
which,
you know, shout out to things like Firefox and chrome and, I mean,
even windows and I like has gotten a lot better that way.
You know, you can set a window for when you want it to work and, you know, you can, uh,
it's actually configurable and reasonably
unlikely to break your device or, you know,
get your windows into some spot where it just, it reboots halfway and dies,
but there's still nothing better than when you're at a conference and someone's
giving a talk and their windows computer designs right now is the time
I'm going to install that update and there's nothing
you can do about it because you've clicked.
Ignore too
many times. It's
marvelous.
I think you've talked about this and I do the same thing is before I travel,
I may make sure I run update on all my devices.
That's right.
And it's not even for security. It's so that you can turn them on and they work. Right.
Yes. In fact, where was I, I was? Oh, I think, I don't even remember now.
I was, I was traveling not long ago
and a major update for my phone came in and
it was just staring at me and I kept thinking,
I want to click update so bad,
but I also want to get home and my plane ticket is on this phone.
Exactly.
That's, uh, that is a very, very good point.
Yeah.
Like if I,
my computer, whatever I can fix that, but if my phone is bricked,
I am in huge trouble because, I mean, Uber
tickets,
everything. It's just going to be so unnecessarily painful.
It's like if you have a spare tire, ok,
it's not fun to get a flat tire.
But if you don't have a spare tire and you get a flat tire,
that's
right. Anyway, anyway, I'm, I tire of this topic.
I guess the thing we should all think about
isn't,
what can we do for cybersecurity Awareness Month
because I think the answer is fundamentally nothing.
I think what we need to do is think about how do we create a smoke alarm
to make cybersecurity Awareness Month effective?
Because I think right now it is ineffective well, to make it unnecessary.
No, not unnecessary because like you said,
you have to make sure people change the batteries in their smoke detectors.
So that makes sense.
But modern smoke alarms beep incessantly when the battery starts to run down.
And so you'd have to
ignore that for quite a while. Like you'd have to try, basically.
But in fairness,
people do go on vacation and you have to test
them because it could have just up and died.
You don't know.
And, and a really important thing, this is just a kind of a, the more, you know,
for everyone,
the smoke detectors only last for about 10 years
because there's an element in there that decays.
And so that's why it's important to,
yes,
you have to test them and make sure they're not
too old because if they're too old they don't work.
Actually,
I need to clean my smoke detectors now that you say that I've had a
lot of dust in the house lately and the dust can get stuck in them
and make them do weird things.
Right. So, anyway, that's a good reminder.
Anyway, anyway, I have a funny personal anecdote to tell.
So I got an ear infection, which I thought only Children got. Right.
Seriously, I went into the doctor and I'm like, what,
what
are you going to? Weird swimming pools or something?
I haven't been in a swimming pool in months.
I have no idea where I picked this up.
I've known, like, whatever, whatever I got an ear infection and by the way,
they're really, really painful.
So, when those little kids cry a lot, like,
they're totally justified and they're crying because it sucked.
But anyway, so I go to the doctor
and they, they were like, wow, this is a really bad ear infection.
It must really hurt. I was like, yes, yes, it does. Thank you for asking.
That was super helpful.
So, anyway, they prescribed me a ridiculous amount of antibiotics
and I go to my pharmacist to get them and there are like 100 people at the pharmacy,
which I've never seen so many people at one time.
It, whatever. It's just the way it works when I need medicine, I guess.
And it was, it was comical because the pharmacist is like,
do you know what to do with these?
And I said no, and I have no idea what you're even giving me.
And so she's like,
trying to whisper to me how to use my antibiotics because it's basically,
it's an eardrop in this, like gigantic horse pill.
I have to swallow
and she's like whispering and I'm like, it's just an ear infection.
You could talk like it's, it's ok, but it occurred to me at the same time,
I'm sensitive to the plight of this poor
pharmacist because when you have like 100 people,
like, what if I was getting some, well, but doesn't hi
a require them probably. Right.
And what if I was getting like some super crazy embarrassing, like, you know,
here's your STD medicine, sir.
And like, oh, crap, shut up, you know,
and I
get it, it's kind of a weird problem to have.
Right, because on one side, how are they going to do this?
Don't they have like the little kind of not booth but the little
thing where you sit down and they give you your meds and explain,
you know,
like you eat these pills and these pills you don't eat and they go up your whatever.
I mean, they, they have a booth and I'm sure if I would have asked nicely,
we could have gone and sat down in it.
But when there's 20 people behind me also,
I understand that this poor person and isn't looking to, you know,
tell me a 20 minute story in a little room off to the side.
So it's kind of a weird problem.
And at the same time, I can see where when you're under pressure,
obviously, a lot of the rules kind of go out the window sometimes, which is,
I guess just good advice for all of us.
To keep in mind
anyway. Anyway. So
I think the real news this week of course, is the, uh, is the polar bear sized pigs.
This is the greatest story you have to tell it. I love it so well.
I mean,
how long have humans been breeding animals to be bigger
and meatier and easier to raise and slaughter and eat?
10,000 years? Probably 10,000 years.
It's been a long time.
Yeah.
And so, I mean, this is obviously the logical progression is, you know,
big pigs are good.
So bigger pigs are better.
And so in China now they've got these pigs that weigh 500 kg,
which is 1100 pounds for Americans. That's insane.
I, I wonder if it's more efficient.
I would imagine.
It is like,
if you get more meat for the input of feed stock and antibiotics and
all the other stuff that you need to use to raise a pig,
I would imagine raising one giant animal is easier than raising three little ones.
Is my suspicion.
It's like the other question, would you rather fight a horse sized duck or
100 duck sized horses?
That is the question.
What gets me though is I was thinking about this and I
was thinking logistically like they need fences and stuff because they,
they will try and break out and get into shenanigans because they're,
they're very smart animals.
And I'm thinking like a 500 pound pig like,
if that thing wants to go somewhere and you're in its way,
like that's gonna, that's, that's as heavy as a horse. It's,
it. Now, I, I have so,
I don't know how big it was.
There was one time I was at the Indiana State Fair in the United States
and they had the world's largest pig on display and it was,
I think probably
350 to 400 kg. Give or take. It was like, that's impressive.
It was huge. It was like probably six or 700 pounds.
It was enormous and it just laid there and it looked kind of
miserable and I felt bad for it because I have a strong suspicion.
It's not the most active animal because I don't think it can move around very well.
And
so that's likely part of the problem here is kind of like how we,
we raise turkeys now on these farms that are basically like too large to move.
So they just kind of lay there and eat and then we, we kill them.
And that like that, that feels mean even though they have an obvious, you know,
sad ending to their life.
But I don't know, man,
I, I feel like a giant pig is the thing of nightmares and I want to eat those
barbecue ribs.
Oh, that would be amazing. Maybe, I don't know. Maybe it's like eating leather.
I have no idea. It's, this is,
this is what people have come to is we're creating monstrosities now
we've run out of other things to do. I guess.
I, I do sometimes worry about the industrialization of farming,
but the reality is if you want to feed 7 billion plus people,
you're probably gonna have to industrialize it a bit
unless you want 98% of us being farmers.
We tried that. It didn't work.
I mean, that's the reality of it.
No,
I
don't know. I don't know. It's, it's just a crazy story. Giant pigs.
Completely not related to security in any way. Just crazy. Awesome.
So, anyway, anyway,
well, when's the last time Infosec
did something crazy. Awesome.
Like honestly,
apart from chrome shoving http S through and actually getting people to, you know,
between Chrome warnings and Google se search rankings.
Like in the last five years, what's been done that's really made the world better.
I don't know if there's anything amazing we can point at
and
I don't know if that's good or bad necessarily because I believe we
were promised some A I that would fix a lot of stuff.
A I fixes everything. Kurt.
You should know that by now and Blockchain those two things
solve them. All
right.
Totally legit. Ignoring the marketing hype.
I,
I'm struggling to think of any significant game changers
and there's two ways to look at that is
on one side,
a mature industry shouldn't see amazing breakthroughs.
Like you could point at I don't know, let's say the, the dishwasher industry
where dishwashers have been basically the same for probably the last 20 plus years.
And it's just like constant march of
progress where they're a little more efficient.
They use a little less water. They clean a little bit better.
They're less noisy.
Yes.
Well, the, the expensive ones, the cheap ones are still super noisy
because I have a cheap one in my, in my kitchen.
Well, I had it, it's gone now, but that's anyway, that's another story.
But,
and I, I
feel like our industry isn't mature enough to be lacking breakthroughs and
I can't think of a significant breakthrough in quite some time.
And like the things that pop into my head are auto updates, obviously
Google forcing hetps and everybody I think is a good thing.
I mean,
there's things like content security policies in web
browsers which were a big step forward but
it,
I mean,
everything I can think of is pretty old and it was all pretty low hanging fruit,
I think where,
like where to the point
if I was going to compare it to, you know, many other industries of
the, the really easy stuff is gone
and now you need like impressive R and D to
take the next steps and I don't know who's even doing that necessarily.
I mean, you see people like SNCC
is doing some cool work.
You've got obviously Google project X is doing some cool work.
Well, R and D in general has been outsourced to the start ups, right?
Because that way there's zero risk downside and
you just, you have to spend a lot more money to acquire that R and D in the form of,
I think you're right.
But I think the problem with that is this is like saying, all right, start ups, uh,
we need you to build a rocket that can go to space.
And the reality is you need something with substantial
resources to kind of bootstrap that into a place
where the,
you know, the smaller companies can then take it from there perhaps, or somebody,
you know what I mean?
It's, I, I feel like we have a chasm
where you can say, oh, the start ups are doing the R and D
but I don't see anything coming out of a lot of start ups that I would say is
amazingly changing the game.
Like I see cool stuff and I think they're making it the world better,
but I don't see anything that's going to
drastically alter the current trajectory of security.
Well, yeah, I mean,
we've been promised a I that would just magically
make a whole bunch of stuff go away and it's
obviously not there yet because it made all my money go away.
Yeah. Uh No, I mean, a I and ML are hard and I think
I, I feel like Alexa
is my favorite example where Alexa came out and everyone was like, this is amazing.
I can talk to this thing and it does stuff and now we're, what, like,
three years in and it's like, it basically does the same thing.
It did three years ago. What's going on here guys.
Yeah, I got to say there's really not a lot of compelling.
I mean, I, I do enjoy that.
I can say, you know, I, I set up some key words like, you know, Alexa
Goodnight, which turns off the lights and does a bunch of stuff like that. Alexa
Good morning, which turns on the lights and reads me the news and the weather.
But I mean, that, you know, has it significantly
changed my life? No, not at all. Right. I mean, exactly. It's a novelty.
I think the only thing I enjoy is I can just yell
Alexa.
What time is it?
And
it tells me and I apologize to any of you with an Alexa
that are listening to this podcast
with,
but now you know what time it is? So you got that going for you?
No, I mean, for real, actually,
I was in a conference call the other day and someone yelled that out and it was,
it was hilarious. How many people had functional
Alexas in the background, which made my day. No, it's, I mean, I've got an Alexa,
the one with the screen on it
and the integration with the ring doorbell is so poor that it, like,
won't show me on the screen what my ring doorbell is seeing.
They, they own ring. Right.
Yeah,
that's ridiculous. Come on.
Yeah. It would be nice to have that capability because I bought this thing.
Actually a friend won it and it was like, I don't want this and I'm like, well,
I'll buy it for, like, you know,
about three quarters of what it costs new and he's happy and I'm happy.
But I'll be honest, this thing is useless
as far as the thing with the screen on it goes like it,
right. Like the screen doesn't, nothing really can use it.
I, I believe that.
I mean,
I find it's actually really funny because my wife tries
so hard to use the Alexa because I actually,
I got one kind of by accident.
I needed a fire TV. And because my Roku died, it's a long bizarre story.
But anyway, I ended up with the fire TV, with Alexa built into it
and
she tries so hard to talk to it and ask it, like, play this show and it never,
ever works ever under any circumstances.
And I, I feel bad but whatever,
I, I it's always gives me a good chuckle.
And anyway, anyway, but my, my point is
this is what I feel like security is where
we're just,
I feel like we're just sitting here with this stuff and where do we go next?
And like, I don't even know.
But I guess that's kind of part of,
part of how progress works is because obviously prior to smartphones,
if you would have told me, or rather, I guess prior to smartphones,
if someone would have said, what's the next big thing in computing?
I would have never said, uh, a phone with the screen on it that you interact with,
with your finger in a million years.
Right. It just, it, it, I, I didn't see it
so I don't know.
Yeah,
I,
yeah, it's a strange world. Indeed. Indeed.
And maybe it is a I, we just haven't found it yet, but I don't think it is.
Anyway.
All right, man, I guess uh this was a bizarre grab bag of nonsense,
which is always fun.
So
I guess happy Cybersecurity Awareness Month. Do you have any parting thoughts?
I know like literally nothing comes to mind
and in summary, we're all still doomed.
That's all. Yeah.
Anyway.
Oh, well, but again,
it's not that bad.
No, we still have giant pigs to eat.
That's true. Giant pigs. We got, we got something to look forward to.
All right, I'm gonna, I'm gonna call it. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you ever for listening. You can go to open source security podcast.com.
Hit up the show
notes, UZ Pound Os S podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day. You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks everyone.
Bye bye,
the