Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Linux use Josh Bresser.
That's right. I'm extremely excited.
We have Greg Kh here to actually be an authority on Linux
security even though Kurt and I pretend to be all the time.
So Greg, welcome to the show, man.
-- Thanks.
-- Thanks for having me. This is gonna be fun.
Oh,
probably.
Ok. I want to set the stage because
I suspect a lot of people know who you are but not
a lot of people understand kind of the the Linux security ecosystem.
So why don't you maybe give us an intro of, of how'd you get here as well as like, what,
what is everything going on in the Linux kernel security universe?
Uh
Security is a big like vague word like hot plug, like what does that mean?
Whatever
you want? So everything is security. Um
So there's two types of security, right? There's proactive and reactive.
So a long, long time ago in the kernel of the world,
we came up with
a idea of having a proactive security model
and I was part of the people that worked on that.
Um, Sc Linux came from that, I didn't do Se Linux,
I worked on the framework to work on that.
So that was proactive security.
But due to the work I was doing in there and then all the work I did when I
started doing with the stable kernel releases,
when we came up with the idea of a kernel security team back in
what, 2005,
I was one of the people that joined that because I've been fixing security bugs
earlier than that for things like that.
And that's reactive security. So colonel at se
sorry, security at colonel.org is reactive.
All we do is people send us, hey, this looks like a bug
and the people on that list were just triage it.
We're like, yes, that does look right or no, it doesn't.
And then we grab the maintainer for the subsystem that's responsible,
bring them in and fix the bug.
Push out the fiction as fast as possible. Go.
Um If you're drug in too many times, we just add you to the alias. So
it's not a badge of honor if people are like, oh, I want to be at it.
I'm like, oh well, you can have a really bad subsystem.
No, you wanna be off this alias.
Um So that's what we do.
And we used to get like lots of bad things like people like I want ac be for this, this
over here. It's like No, that's not what this is about.
Um So that's the security at kernel.org and we do reactive,
we fix it as soon as possible.
We push out the fix to our trees and we move on to the next thing, a bug is a bug is a bug.
Um, at our level. So, um, we don't call it anything specific.
We can't tell the world because
if we told somebody, we'd have to tell everybody.
And that's the thing, people don't really seem to realize. Um,
the fun I want to be on the embargo list.
I mean, I jokingly say that, um,
either if you have an embargo list, it's either a leak
to the world or
if not nobody uses your product
or if otherwise, why would the government allow it to happen?
It sounds simple. So it's either nobody uses it, it's a leak or,
um, nobody cares, or the government wouldn't let you do this in the first place.
That's a
better way to say that.
-- I
-- actually, that's something I've noticed over the last 25 years is because I,
I think embargo is sort of used to work 25 years ago
because there just weren't as many products with,
say the Lenox kernel embedded in them
and now it's everything,
it's everything and also the other issues.
I don't know if this bug affects you or not because, I mean,
remember we have 30 thou 30 million lines of code.
You only run on your server, 1.5 million lines on your phone, you run 4 million lines,
your laptop, you run two
different.
Um So,
and I mean, I joke, Linux is in a cow milking machine, your server and a satellite.
So it's in my, it's in my washing machine.
It's in my phone, it's in my watch. I mean, it's in all these different things.
Um So I don't
know how and somebody made a really good qu
like it's almost impossible to tell if a bug is actually
a vulnerable is can be exploited or not in your situation
because it's
my situation is different than your situation.
And I don't know what code you're running and
you don't know what your code you're running.
Survey is a different model, right?
So
we fix the bug, get it out as soon as possible, especially at our love level.
Anything that can cause
a crash at our level or v
um
access where it shouldn't be
is a big deal.
Some programs they know what they run, they know what code they build,
they're a lot simpler. Those, those would be nice to deal with.
We don't, we don't have that luxury. Um But to be fair, I mean, everybody relies on us.
So that's good. We want to be, we want to be thorough and
good about this.
So, preannouncements just don't work because also, I mean, remember
Android is the number one use.
So that's a couple billion, maybe four or 5 billion devices.
Everything else is a rounding error,
everything except for android.
So I've been working really hard and we got android working much more securely.
So we got them to use the stable kernels. They've documented the heck out of how,
if you follow the stable kernels,
you get fixed all the CV S before they're even known.
Um The Google security team has a lot of work that Google security team is do
Android team has documented the drug,
the six with 300 out of tree drivers through every single RC release
the link. This is ever done in 2.5 years, three years and it worked
so you can just update the kernel and it works.
Um It is possible to do and Androids putting their money where their mouth is,
they're making all their vendors update good job.
So Android is being more secure
after that,
it's Debian.
Debian runs unofficially 75% of the world
officially or, or, I mean, I think it's,
I think the number is really bigger than that.
That's what the cloud vendors will tell us.
So I have Debian and then Debian and then after that,
then we start going down the paid routes and the paid routes. I mean,
they act, I, I don't want to say they don't act like they're bigger than they are.
They are big,
they're valuable, they're worth money. What not?
But in the overall eco size system size.
They are small potatoes
on the scale that we're working on, which is kind of interesting in the past 10 years.
It's really, really changed.
So Debian does great. Debian follows a stable colonel release.
You want a secure system on Debian?
I just tell people that right there, those guys are really good.
I want you to explain what you just said because I think
to a lot of
we'll say non security nerds who listen to you.
That doesn't necessarily make sense because you have
will say a long history of telling people to run the latest stable kernel.
What does that actually mean?
And why do you say that?
So latest stable. So I, so Linus does the development releases.
I have a big funny graph. I can point out
every 3.5 months, 2.5, 3 months. He does a release.
I take that and I fork from that and then
we start doing bug fixes only to the stable kernels,
the stable kernel about once a week,
um sometimes more.
And then we keep some of these stable branches alive for one year I pick and we keep
them alive for longer because people like making products
and things like that and that's a stable kernel.
So those are the stable kernels that you can rely on
to have a product and they have bug fixes in them.
They have all the the rule is it has to be
in Linus's tree first and then it goes into our,
the stable tree
and that's where all the bug fixes happen. And we're averaging
30 to 40 bug fixes a day.
And um, famously, I had one company a couple of years ago, say, hey,
we're gonna evaluate every single past that goes in and see if
it's
security related or not. I'm like,
please do that.
I, I would love for that to do and, and then they went off and I saw them a year later
and they said we gave up, we just couldn't do it.
-- I'm like, so
-- could you even hire enough people? Like, do those people even exist?
And
they, no, they can't. And they tried, they wanted to do that
and I said, just take them all.
And I've been in, I've been in meetings with very big companies when somebody said,
just call out the specific ones that affect me. I'm like, I don't know, take them all.
I know the ones that just affect me. I'm like, I'm giving these all these for free.
And then finally the, my VP of the whole group said he's giving them to you for free.
Take them all.
-- So,
-- so I'm sorry, just one thing to clarify. There are companies that expect you
to sort of understand their product and essentially do their
triage job for them and they honestly ask for this.
Yes. Yeah. People are bold. People are bold.
I'm,
I'm not surprised. I mean, look at,
look at the response to log for shell with open source groups that had
companies sending them questionnaires to fill out.
Yeah, it's, people are funny.
I mean, nobody's forcing, I always say nobody's forcing you to use Linux.
You're using Linux because it solves your need and you want to,
or pay somebody pay Red hat pay Sousa. Those guys do a great job.
They take most bug fixes. Sousa takes more than Red Hat. I will call that out.
Um
So, um, do that and,
and get a pay, you have the contract and work or if you want to do that,
use Debian because Debian takes the stable kernels
and they use them and they release them
and those are documented.
Google has documented this very,
very well that all the security bugs they found for a whole year
were already fixed in the stable kernel before they knew about them.
Wow.
And oh,
except for two and those two were for a driver
that they had out a tree or something like that.
So it wasn't even our fault.
They've documented this. So take the stable kernels and run with them.
-- Well,
-- that leads to the next question is like,
so what can we do to actually get companies
to update and ship software updates that don't break things like because that,
that always, what come for me, it always comes down to
who cares about security fixes if I can't apply them without my system being,
you know, blue screen of death or doesn't reboot broken,
right?
So there's, there's, I mean, so Google documented, like I originally said,
three years, every single Linus RC release pixel six foam works perfect.
I
mean, 300 out of tree drivers. Too insane.
Um I keep saying, why don't we move them up to the tree?
Um
So it can be done. So the colonel's goal is we will never break us.
We will never break your, your,
that's our goal.
Now, sometimes we can unintentionally do it and talk to us and we'll fix it.
Sometimes we have
feeding conflicts and
I mean, there's always, we're human,
we always will break our goal is if you tell us about it,
we'll fix this soon as possible.
That's our number one thing is we want to solve regression. So
12 years ago, we made the statement, we will not break you.
So you should never be afraid to upgrade that being said,
test test to the system.
Infamously, I got yelled at once because a patch and a stable colonel took down
a bunch of mcdonald's kiosks in a different country.
A
bug in there that when they rebooted, it did it.
The funniest thing is it turned out it was a patch that,
that one of their own engineers had sent me to include in the stable tree.
So they didn't even test it. So it was on there but just test it.
I mean, your infrastructure should be able to test this.
I'll call out android again. They built an infrastructure.
I helped merge the stable kernels into their
system.
I merge a stable kernel in it. It goes off and runs a whole bunch of tests. I get into,
it takes like 2.5, 3 hours before it comes back and it says it's good.
So it's bad and here's why it's bad,
do this. This is not,
this is not rocket science. So
what is used in rockets too?
Um
Just,
just, just test this stuff. I mean, you should be able to do this stuff and, and
go from there.
If you don't have a way of testing an update today, you have much,
much bigger problems.
I
mean, that's fair. I I won't argue that.
So, OK, so I want to ask you, then you're talking about
a little while ago. You mentioned that
when Android was looking at security vulnerabilities,
they found every vulnerability was fixed in the stable kernel
before they knew about it.
So this,
that is also because historically, Linux
has handled security vulnerabilities a
little different than other organizations,
right?
Where a lot of groups will specifically
identify security vulnerabilities and treat them special.
But in your world,
you've never really done that before, right?
We mostly will hold on to a security fix as one week,
maybe two. I think we've done two. This is after we have a fix,
I think we did two weeks
because
of a good reason somebody couldn't update their systems.
Um, yeah,
we don't want to.
Now that's different from the hardware and bar goods of stuff like specter
meltdown. I actually
rant about, that's totally different.
But we want to, we do not want to sit on in patches for longer.
Um, it causes problems, people leak.
Um, things happen. So we do not. So one week push it out and go
and we don't call things out specifically because also,
I don't know whether all the other bug fixes I
just did was a vulnerability for you or not either.
So we just don't call anything else special.
OK? Well,
you used to not call things on special
because the Linux kernel is now a CV ECN AC N A cur
for CV E numbering authority,
CV, numbering authority.
-- OK.
-- So
he's saying CV ECN A is redundant but
OK. So I'm, I'm really curious because I don't totally understand this.
So what does the kernel being AC N A mean?
And what are you going to change in the future because of this?
So AC N A means that um being AC N A means
you're responsible for all the CV E assignments for your product,
whatever you assigned
we have in the kernel traditionally never done this.
Um The CBE group made it hard for open source groups to do
this because of corporate issues what not over the past year they've changed.
-- Um We're just
-- having a PTSD flashback to my work
had been trying to fix all this.
Um They've changed. Right. So they've changed.
Um Python, I think plays the way I think Python did it first.
They wrote up a great document for all the other open source projects to follow
the OS SF group. Um open SSF group,
um took that and made it a little bit more generic and
I followed that to A T you and it works great.
So
CBE now allows individual projects to be AC N A. So what this means is
me and two other colonel engineers who are good security engineers
um are responsible for assigning CV ES for the colonel.
The only reason I did this is because people
were signing bogus CBES for us and never telling us
one company in particular would assign CBES just
to work around their broken engineering processes.
They would assign AC be,
get it stuck in there and then we never hear about it
or they'd signed AC be for a six year old colonel that we never heard about
or they assign, anybody could assign AC be for,
for the colonel because there was no authority so anybody could and anybody did.
And it was a nightmare.
And I gave a whole big long talk about a number of years
ago and we never wanted to do this because we couldn't do this So
now we have taken ownership of this.
I will say the EU has kind of forced us to because the new um cr a rules from the,
from the EU
are going to mean that open source projects are responsible for identifying
known security issues.
So the EU is kind of forcing our hands.
If we didn't do this, we'd have to do it eventually
governments want to know. Right.
Um So now we are responsible for being
a
assigning cbes.
So we have, so we started this week. Um
It's been a lot of back and forth with me in the
CBE group working on some automatic tools to handle this stuff.
But also now
when we do this, um
the data is actually good.
So before we would have these a kernel,
there's a kernel CBE for this bug and there's a random mailing list post over there.
Nobody knew anything about that. You'd have to dig it out and whatnot.
Um I'm now telling you where the commit was when it was associated, when it was fixed,
what branches it was fixed and we'll keep it up
to date because as we do other stable branches,
we'll do this and it's in a machine parcel format,
Json
as
fun as
JSON is.
Um So you can handle this stuff.
So we've assigned, I think 20 already 15 already in three days.
Um
And so other CNAs have come to me and I will call out Google for being really good.
They're like, OK, we can't assign our own.
So please give me one for this commit and this commit, this commit.
I'm like here, here, here,
there you go.
And then me and the other CBE team members are going and starting to review,
we'll look at what we've been doing so far and um in the past week,
couple of weeks and then we'll start
saying, OK,
this is a vulnerability and the CV E is
a very specific definition of what a vulnerability is.
And isn't
we're trying to follow that.
So not every single bug fix that goes into the kernel of CB.
Um That said somebody funnily had an argument like,
oh and what about the sound driver fix over there?
And I was like, no, not.
And the sound developer was like, well, wait,
that fixes that could actually break the sound system.
So
yes, that could break hardware. That would be a vulnerability.
Um We now have the ability to bring the maintainers and
developers and uh that do the work and do this.
And if any maintainer of the code as a CV assigned against your code, they can easily
say no, that's not right. And I can easily reject it. I can easily append it.
Um We now own this process before getting a CD E rejected or
was almost impossible. Now, I can do it easily push a button and it goes.
So we're taking ownership of this,
um this is causing some gnashing of teeth by the companies that
were used to just being able to sign whatever they wanted to.
And we got some
nasty emails about that already. But it's like, hey, um
you guys abused the system for so long
time to play games. So if you had done it right.
Yeah,
so I, and OK,
I'm going to argue from authority here because I used to be
on the CV editorial board and I assigned about 8000 CV S
and I'm gonna say this bluntly,
if a company behaves well in the CV ecosystem,
they will not have a problem with you being the CN A for the Linux kernel
because
because I've known of you for a long time and I've
known of the Linux kernel security team for a long time
and you guys are about the best behaved open source security team.
That's it like,
especially by volume,
like the amount of volume you guys handle is absolutely bonkers.
So,
yeah, I don't, I don't buy for a minute,
any, any company that complains about this too bad.
Yeah.
And, and it's like, I mean, I will call a Google saying they're like, great,
wonderful.
We don't have to do this work anymore.
And they're like, I mean, they're just literally sending these commits.
I'm like, boom, boom, boom, boom. And they're, they're all so happy.
They don't have to fill out the paperwork and
I actually have more better data than they have.
And it's like
it over time, it's like they're all happy.
And I think something people don't see is the actual
effort to the process of getting a CV is,
is reasonably nontrivial and it is quite a bit of work even with automation.
And that's, I think,
especially at scale.
I, I mean, I spent two weeks working with the CV team scripting this and so I can,
I can do this at
a machine. It needs to be done at a sense of scale.
And I can just literally say, boom, boom, boom,
we're, we're almost there. Um And that's good and that's the only way we can do this
end up going forward. That being said,
um you guys did the GSD database, right?
So
CBE explicitly said, hey, go back in time and take all that GSD data,
enter into the CBE data
like OK.
Wow. So
they're willing to, for me to come and create a couple of 1000
entries for the past couple of years.
Yeah, I, I was, I didn't even ask for it.
So um I'll call out Sasha Levin has been doing that work with you guys for so long.
And um
yeah, he's part of the CV team and he's like, oh, I'm gonna take all that data and just,
-- we just type that in there and away. We
-- go,
well, it, it literally was
vulnerabilities like the whole point of CV.
I want to ask about this because Sasha has, he has a talk,
I'll take it up and put a link in the show notes.
But Sasha has a talk about
using essentially machine learning algorithms to
commit. This is not that.
-- So you are not including all of his maybe vulnerabilities.
-- All right.
So let's talk, let's roll back. How does the perhaps get into a stable kernel?
Right.
So there's different ways, there's one, the easiest way is a maintainer says, hey,
this is should be go to the stable kernel fixes the bug.
They add a little tag to the
commit
and the way it goes, our tools pick it up, we're good.
Another way is somebody accidentally says this fixes this thing over here.
Our tools will go back and catch that.
They didn't really do it the right way and away we go
things that will also scan, change the law and whatnot.
So there's the problem is many subsystems and many developers,
we have 4000 developers a year, many maintainers don't do anything.
I'll be like, I'll call out some file systems,
some major subsystems don't tag anything.
So what Sasha has done is
the he fed all of our manual data into the system, uh machine learning. It's just,
I mean A I is just pattern matching, right?
Just statistics and say, OK, him and Julia Le
has written some really good papers, did some good work.
And then he said this is a corpus of actual security or bug fixes.
Let's match this against all the other
fixes we have coming in to see what matches.
So
all the
fixes. And so then he then takes that
and that's his machine learning.
He manually reads those and then he man and then we send them out for
review to all the developers that wrote those patches and they can say no,
that was stupid or why did your tool pick this or what not?
Because sometimes we miss them.
And then we take that and then we apply those to the kernel.
So
the ones that end up in the stable tree,
a
tiny portion are those ones that are found through machine learning.
But those have gone through much, much manual review and I review them all as well.
So these are about
OK, I I follow, I follow
and some of those, I mean, I will call out his tools
c things that are
actually really, really good fixes that nobody thought to attack such.
Now
some subsystems say no, we're going to do it all ourselves.
I'll call it XFS the file system
and they want to test and what not. And that's great.
And then they will send me a curated list of patches every couple of weeks and say
please take these.
This raises
an interesting point is that I think
so what I'm hearing is at the scale of the Linux kernel,
even within your relatively mature community.
There are very different levels of capabilities and maturity and,
and even workflow and process, I imagine.
Yeah, in the subsystems. Oh, totally.
I mean, remember, I think maybe I can count on one hand,
the number of maintainers that are only paid to do this or rails has a day job,
right?
Um And also one of the goals of the stable kernels is I never want to
impose any additional work on a maintainer or developer that they don't want to do.
So if they don't want to do it,
I can't force anybody to do it.
Um There's some, some maintainers and some developers just refuse to do it,
which is fine and I don't blame them and then we go back and review their stuff and
we'll do it on our own time as well.
Um
So
yeah, and Sasha's tools are great and he has some good talks up there and
there's some good academic papers that have been published because of them.
I mean, it's, it's just
pattern matching
-- that belongs on a t-shirt. But anyway, OK, it's just pattern
-- matching.
It's just, it's just
what applied statistics.
-- Right.
So here's my question about all of that put together now. So it sounds like
the numbers of kernel CV S
assigned per year is going to increase by several
magnitude over what it has been in the past.
Is that an accurate statement? Do you think
-- that's a
-- very accurate?
But I don't even know what has been done in
the past because I don't ever have never seen it.
That's fair. I've tried to manipulate that data and figure it out.
And I even, I couldn't,
-- because
-- nobody knows because there's been a project to assign it to.
Now, we have a real project to assign it to and we can have the proper medicine.
I
-- don't actually see
-- this. OK.
So here's my question then, I guess,
and I'm curious if you've heard from anybody about this is,
as you mentioned a while back there are, we'll say commercial vendors who have made,
well, they've done well, we'll say
supporting the Linux kernel in strange and unique ways, right?
Like Kurt and I used to work for one of them. You used to work for one of them.
There's, there's many, now,
I'm curious if, if they have been,
like, spoken with you or, you know, of anything through the grapevine,
if the number of CV ES increases by several magnitude
that's going to crush their security and development teams.
-- There's no way they can continue business as
-- usual with current workflows.
Ok.
Let me call out Android
-- Android today. Takes stable kernel
-- updates.
-- Right. But they didn't used to.
-- Right.
They didn't used to. Right.
All right. It's not like I haven't been telling everybody for a decade to do this.
I know we've all ignored you. It's fine.
Shut up, Greg. What do you know?
Exactly.
And that's I mean, and then you've abused, you've ignored me and abused the system.
So I'm not gonna die.
So, I mean, there's two models here, what you can do.
So I will say
when I do ac be here is the fix
that we think fixes this. I will not say what depended on that. Fix
preparatory ones that's on you.
I didn't know what it was there because we test releases as a whole.
So I did a bunch of releases today. RC releases.
There's
say 200 patches at once. We test them as a whole chunk,
tested integrated work. OK. Great.
Where you go, that's why cherry picking just doesn't work.
If you try and cherry pick things, it doesn't work.
I'll cut out some android vendors that insisted that oh, we aren't gonna update.
We'll just cherry pick the ones we know
and I audit them and I have a fun presentation every year and saying,
here's how I get rude on your phone.
Um So famously, they even missed the patch that Thomas Fleer
wrote saying this is a security fix and here's how to exploit
it in the change log and they miss that one. So
um
our, our
fuzzy matching. Got that one.
So
yeah,
so either they can cherry pick away wonderful or
they can update to all the stable kernels,
they can do whatever they want.
I mean, I'm not in the business of dictating somebody's business model.
They have a business model. I don't have a business model, right.
I'm an open source project. They don't have to use Linux. So,
um but here's what I'm saying is these are known
issues that I think and others think are vulnerabilities,
they fix issues.
They have been there. We know the bad actors are reading our change log.
We have known it for well over a decade, we have the,
we have the documentation proof that they've been reading this.
The fact that people haven't been picking up
and taking these security fixes is almost malfeasance,
malfeasance.
It's,
it's, it's, it's horrible. Right. Sure. OK.
So
now that being said
when I published the CV E today, I say what files they affect.
So Android famously, I know they're vendors,
I've seen these different vendors again,
you're only building 2 million lines of code.
You can look at all patches and say, oh look
out of all these 100 patches.
I only have to care about three of them because that's how I actually built those.
Let's go read those. Oh look, that looks good.
Great. Take them all and away we go
or I put cherry pick what I want away. We go,
they have the data now.
They never,
nobody was ever providing this data for ac be
record what file was affected how it was all,
what when it was introduced, when it was fixed, what the commit ID was fixed
and kept it up to date. Over time that never was there.
So now, at least it's there and you can see that.
And I, I think one ugly truth is a lot of people had to do that work.
Like at Red Hat, we had an entire, within the product security team,
an entire kernel team,
but there was no way to share and publish it.
So
it was in the CV, they could have published in the CV record
CBEJ. So
records are there.
We tried a few times and the problem is that the maybe now it works,
-- but back then it didn't,
-- the CBE team was very,
they were very forceful to get me to implement all this
and I will push back and say they were the right.
They did the right thing in making me do all this work.
But come on a couple of engine, an engineer, a week's worth of time,
set up the tools you could have done that.
I
mean, there, there was also Bugzilla like there was,
it wasn't easy to find. But yeah, I mean, more could have been done. I agree.
-- Oh
-- I'm I'm saying,
and I'm not saying the records we're going to be producing a perfect,
we've already had complaints.
Great.
Give me some text and I'll update the record. I have, we have access to do that.
I can again, push out an update really
bad.
That's
no, I'm speaking more in the past. It wasn't a technical issue.
So much as if we wanted to update a kernel entry.
We had to go to whoever issued it and deal with them.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, you had to go and you didn't know who that was and it was,
even if it was Mitra as a default, you could never get them to update anything.
Um, just because I don't think their tools could do it. Right.
Yeah. I mean, that's why I pushed Jason.
They wanted, they were talking about moving or staying with XML.
And I'm like, no, like we need to,
we need to go to
Jason.
Ok.
So
here's,
here's the thing I have in my brain at the moment.
After everything you've just explained,
talking about
only 2 million lines of code, run a typical system, let's say a laptop or whatever,
which also tells me that
those commercials vendor who have historically done a lot of CV E assignments and,
and that sort of thing.
They're also, obviously this is like the old, why are you looking for your keys here?
It's because that's where the light is.
Like, they're only going to focus on the, the things they build, right.
So there's an enormous number of other subsystems and files and everything in
the Linux kernel that have like never really been paid attention to,
from a security perspective.
You're assuming that any vendors actually been
knowing security audits of the kernel.
I have, I have yet to see that I, I have No, I have no,
let me say I have no proof of that happening.
Yeah, I've never seen it and I've, I've actually looked for that.
Yeah, I've never seen it but do that.
No, I
-- heard
-- his expertise,
like the expertise to do a security auditor of the Linux kernel.
If the expertise to do that,
you're hired to be a kernel engineer in your writing code,
you're already working on the kernel. Exactly.
Um We have, we have had security experts,
audit our release process and our development,
development and release process and how we do that.
But that's good. That's there's domain experts for that.
So we're audited on that but not the code itself.
So now we're all
so, yeah, I'm not saying I'm going to go back in time and all of those stuff.
We just see the fix
for
sure.
But, but I'm, I'm, my observation is more just
we focused.
We had the eye of mordor on a very specific part of the kernel historically.
And there's a lot more, I didn't realize
that of 30 million lines of code,
only 2 million lines are generally in a running kernel.
That's like a bananas number.
Yeah. But now everybody uses a different 2 million
-- and
-- well. Right. Right. Well, but all of the Red Hat customers, right.
So Red Hat will build, say Red Hat will build 10 million,
but your hardware only needs two.
I understand.
OK.
Like think of all the skater vendors that have code in there that
like three people only ever looked
-- at or
-- only ever use. I mean, ATM,
we just, we just have bugs in ATM the other day. Right.
So, I mean, ATM is an old networking protocol that nobody uses.
Um, ISDN is still there but the German,
um
Barrero industry still uses isdn. So it's still maintained. Actually,
-- it's good.
-- Wasn't there talk of removing floppy support at one point
we keep trying. Um, it turns out virtual machines, use it.
Right.
Yeah,
it will
die
before it does
floppy drives. One of those, the last person touches the maintainer.
So it's like PAG you're in.
But no,
I think there is somebody I think your has
taken it over and he's actually done good work.
Yeah,
it's horrible. So, actually the
sy driver has been a really big source of vulnerability introductions into,
into virtual machines.
-- Oh, I'm sure I have no doubt.
-- Yeah. Yeah.
Oh, wow, that's hilarious.
-- I love that kind of stuff.
-- Well, I mean, if you want to update the software on a 747,
you,
you better have some floppy desk
-- like the US military still.
-- Like, hey, Linux is running battleships right now.
-- I know
-- too. It runs everything like Linux
won,
you know,
I
mean,
Microsoft runs Linux
like that's the end right there.
Yeah. I mean, Microsoft runs, I mean, they publicly said they're not sure what
Azure is. I mean, Microsoft makes a whole bunch of money on Linux
and, and to be fair, Microsoft's a really good Linux developer,
they contribute back a lot of code.
So
which is hilarious because like, remember like 2030 years ago when it was like,
good versus evil and now they're,
-- I
-- mean, it wasn't, no, no, no. All right. So let me put this fight.
People thought there was a fight. We didn't care,
-- you didn't care.
-- They
-- cared
-- a lot. They cared a lot, but that's fine.
I was like, oh, I didn't even think about you. I mean,
but I do have the paper somewhere that says
the Seattle Times that said is cancer cured because,
because
you know, the famous old quote from Balmer that the
is a cancer and then
the Microsoft was one of the top 10 colonel
contributors one year.
That
is
so, yeah, I mean, I may not lived in Seattle. I mean, I'll call out Microsoft.
There's a bunch of really good micro,
soft kernel developers that are working on Linux now.
Um Those are good engineers.
I wanted those people and they, they're having fun and they're like, this is great.
We, we love to do it.
Valve is basically full of all ex Microsoft people and
they're so in on Linux, it's not even funny.
Oh, I know. Right. Because I mean, the steam deck runs Linux.
I mean, the steam deck is amazing. I got that thing here.
It's, it's, it's windows running on top of Linux.
It's, that's amazing.
And those guys, but I mean, before that they were doing the, the steam box and other
stuff and
their VR stuff runs Linux
and it's all good.
Um Those engineers there are great and they contribute back
and they pay for other people to do work and
I'm happy
the way it should be.
And the steam deck also runs the stable kernel.
I did not know that. That is very cool. Holy cow. That's amazing.
So they're updating it all the time.
And
actually we've had a regression and they found it and we fixed it and pushed it out.
It was like this broke the, the sound on the steam. I was like, ah
quick, let me fix that.
Um So even they have aggression
and I imagine their testing found this, right?
They did
seriously.
That's what you gotta do. Oh,
look regression.
Email it to us. Yes.
And A MD works very closely with them when the regressions and how that works with
A MD has been.
They've been well, I mean, Intel and a MD,
all the chip makers have been heavily invested in Linux for
-- they're gonna
-- sell chips. I mean,
the old joke of my old boss,
his boss', boss at IBM always came to me every year and said, when is Linux finished?
And I never had an answer until like 10 years later.
I was like, finally like, oh when you stop making new hardware like that.
I'm not adding stuff to Linux
for the fun of it. I'm adding it because we have to,
because somebody, because somebody, it solves their problem.
Linux solved my problem like 15 years ago. I'm good.
Awesome. OK.
I, we, we, we're nearing the end, Greg and I have one thing I want to, we'll say semi nit
pick just semi question, like honest, real question.
I'm not trying to troll you at all with this.
So you are,
you've said many times about, you know, don't run old stuff,
you should be upgrading and kind of on bleeding edge and all of this.
However,
most open source projects I would say lack
the quality and aptitude the Linux kernel possesses.
So
do we like, how do,
how do you view that sort of attitude in the wider context of open source or sometimes
running the latest and greatest is just going
to like ruin your day with other projects,
not specifically the kernel because I get the kernel does special things.
-- I mean,
-- I've been running a rolling bistro for over a decade.
I started the rolling distro Tumbleweed
at souza as well.
So I'll call out, I mean software
from an engineering point of view. You should never break your users.
If you're writing software, you should never break your users.
If you break your users, then that's your fault.
So
that, I mean, it just, that's just good engineering point of view.
Now, if you're writing open source software to fit your niche and your need
and that it's not breaking your new, I mean, that's a tough thing.
You can't tell people what to do. Right.
But if you want people to use your code, then you have to make it.
So they aren't afraid to upgrade, you're not gonna break them or if it does break it,
you're instantly responsible and you fix it.
That doesn't mean you have to be like at their beck and call,
you don't have to add new features.
You don't have to do all this type of stuff, but just don't break your working stuff.
Now things move around and things
change and what not.
Um
I mean,
I'll call the Python two to Python three is the perfect example of what never to do.
And the only reason they succeeded is because Pearl messed it up even worse.
Um
And dropped the ball on it. I mean, I loved Pearl, I love the developers there.
I still use Pearl. But um
so I mean, don't do that, don't break your users, don't do that.
And if you want to rewrite the world and re invent the world and do what
Pearl did and go invent a whole separate
project and help people do that differently.
Um But that's just good solid engineering, basic practices. So
if you're a software developer, you should do this and we're not anything magic.
Our code is just c, and we just test it and we just listen to our users and
we're not special, you're special.
We're special and unique like everybody else. I mean,
um,
so we just, I mean, just pay attention and
fix your bugs and be responsible. I mean,
a lot of the work we do is trust, it's not trust that. I know that you got it right.
It's trust that I know you'll fix it when you get it wrong because we all get it wrong
and that's it.
I mean, I've written more security bugs than anybody else accidentally.
It just, I mean, I went and went through and did a long time ago to check who got,
who wrote the most bugs.
Like, oh, no, who do we worry about?
And the people that write the most bugs are your most prolific developers,
of course.
But I
think that that isn't exactly obvious to a lot of managerial types.
Um, but that's the basic
fact. So have good testing infrastructure.
We have really, really good testing infrastructure for the kernel.
I'd like to call out Shua
Con doing a really good job with that and there's lots of other people kernel C I,
um, we have good testing and that we
Google's invested a lot in testing. Google's paid Leonardo
to do testing.
I mean, there's lots of testing infrastructure do that for your project.
If you can't test your code, then you don't know your code works.
To just do that. I mean, we have github
provides free testing for anything. Right.
As a developer,
you shouldn't have to worry about things like that.
Anyway. That's my rant for the day. But just, it's nothing.
It's not rocket science, it's just
listen and don't break things or if it breaks it, fix it,
that's fair. I mean, I,
I don't think you're wrong but I do think there's about 700 asterisks
at the end of that rant.
I mean, some of it is survivor bias, right?
The Linux kernel is here because they were
successful and they're successful because they are here.
And it also, the Linux got to a point quite a long time ago. I think, where,
what was your option?
Like,
I guess technically you could grab a BS D but fundamentally if
you're making a product and you wanted up to date hardware support,
that's how android uses the kernel. I mean, you call it those original developers.
They did not want to use Linux,
they want to use BS D but they couldn't because their, their hardware didn't
it.
And it just, it's a little feedback loop. So, I mean,
everybody, I mean, drivers don't matter.
There's 10,000 drivers don't matter except if you,
the one that for your hardware is missing.
Right. That's the goal.
I mean, it's really easy to ride an operating system.
It's really easy to ride a kernel. It's really, really hard to ride a Zillion drivers
and that's what I focused on for the last 25 years.
Um, it's fun watching other operating systems come and go.
I love some more competition.
I mean, I know the BS C developers have known them for a long time.
Um, we work closely with a number of them but, I mean,
unfortunately we've passed them a long time ago.
Um, I was hoping I was holding out hope for fuchsia But,
um,
I mean, I'm not
some competition. It's no fun being the person shooting, getting shot in the back.
We'll
see
there's probably a Rust kernel in the works right now.
What do you mean why
Rust?
-- You want competition?
-- No, I know. But I mean, that's the problem with open source.
We can just assimilate everybody
I'll call out. So the, um the there's a really good
presentation last couple of months ago at the plumber conference by,
I think her name is Alice Fry
who wrote rewrote the binder code for Android and Rust.
Um Had it working showed the phone devices out,
they're rolling it out to devices. So a
couple billion devices
will be running Rust
I PC on Linux.
That's a,
that's if you don't think of a good proof of concept for the language in the kernel,
that's a pretty big proof of concept in a big, big, um,
big ass they're doing and a big, bold move. And I,
I mean, I call it, they're doing a really good engineering process there.
Um, that's some good development work.
Guys
do.
Those people are doing amazing work. Um,
and so, yeah, she can write Colonel Cut and Russ, but I love the rest one.
You wind it back a minute. Look at our bugs.
The majority of our bug.
Yeah, sometimes there's sea issues
but the majority rust does not save you from logic.
I mean, I've talked to the restaurant
and I'm like, how, what about this? Like, no,
that's just
a bug.
That's a bug.
So
logic issues and the majority of our stuff is still just stupid
things and rust isn't going to save you from that.
No,
not at all.
It does cut out one old big class,
but we've been cutting out that one big class of exploitable sea bugs
through the work of the hardening project.
So there's proactive kernel we have made c really,
really hard to abuse these days and fix the string handling
and fix it over a flow buffer checking and all that stuff
it's built in. Thanks to compiler work.
Thanks to good um work with the compiler valves and the sea and bounce checking.
We have a lot of much we're getting
and the fuzz,
the fuzz
are doing amazing work
um
to finding this stuff. So
I'll call them
for
doing good work.
Yeah, I watch what keys cook is up to every now and again.
And it's just like this is rocket science. It's amazing. It's so cool.
And
so his, his cases work with the um with the Macros for C is just amazing.
And um Gustavo who also works with them is
they're just going down.
And I was like, ok, let's look at it.
There's a major class of vulnerability, how do we prevent this?
And like they knock it down,
they fix it all and they just knock the next one down and fix them all.
And the
best thing about the kernel is all the source code is there.
Those 30 million lines of code are all drivers.
So they fix it everywhere and then they prevent it from ever coming back.
And that's, that's what's made us so much more stable. And
over the years
that we passed other operating systems a long time ago, just by virtue of
they could fix everything.
I mean, the B sds do a great job of those too. They fix all of user space.
Open BS D does a wonderful job of that.
Um So that model is pretty powerful.
Epic.
All right. All right. I think, I think we've come to the end.
I'll give you any, any parting thoughts for us, Greg before we head out,
update your colonel,
-- update your colonel. I love it. Don't
-- be afraid of it
should
work if it doesn't let us know.
Don't let us know two years from now. That's the thing.
They're like this broke over there. I'm like, I don't remember what we did.
-- I don't remember what I did two weeks ago. OK.
-- So let me ask a real question about that.
Let's say I do find a kernel bug. How do I report that?
So,
depending on where you're using, if you're using a rolling distro report to distro,
Theora
is really good at that. March is really good about it.
That means really good about it.
And um sometimes they'll provide stock generic kernel.org kernels
and they'll say run this one or not and then they'll point and if not then come to us.
So,
um we have a whole document on how to submit a bug report.
Um We have a lot of documentation and
um we have some good documentation writers and there's also we have regressions at
the
colonel.org or something.
Just say I found a regression here and then we have
some bots to pick it up and we can go from there
straight people.
All right, I'm calling this one. Holy cow. This was amazing. Thank you so much.
All right. Thank you, Greg. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to open
source security podcast.com. I'll put the show notes there.
Usually pound
to us as podcast. Hashtag on Mastodon.
-- Kurt and Greg have marvelous rest of your days.
-- Thank you.
Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.