Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 82 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Pressers.
So I'm excited you have something to tell me about,
but you haven't told me before now because
you apparently want my unadulterated reaction to it.
So
-- what's going on, man,
-- a
quick back story as people may or may not know there's a large Chinese. Uh
I don't even know what to call it anymore. Like what do you call Google and Yahoo?
They're not internet providers, they're internet properties, they're internet
-- conglomerates. There we go. That's the word,
-- conglomerates, a nice word.
So there's a big one in China called qq.com and uh they do a lot of stuff, for example,
free email.
Uh One of the interesting things being is that you,
you have to actually have a Chinese mobile number
for them to send the confirmation code to.
So like you and I can't sign up,
right? It's basically Chinese nationals only
and like a lot of conglomerates, they produce a web browser because I guess you want,
well, you want to capture ad revenue and shopping and you know, it's kind of like,
was it Weibo
is the other one where they have like
the online payments now and everything built into their client? Right.
Right.
So they have a browser
and what do web browsers have to make us all safe?
Nothing
they have crypto.
Yeah.
Um So they have crypto,
right.
So uh these
rather clever guys uh from the Department of Computer Science,
University of New Mexico, Cornell Tech.
And uh yeah, again, University of New Mexico
did a paper entitled when Textbook Rs A is used
to protect the privacy of hundreds of millions of users.
And so this is literally
here's the thing, right?
If you're a developer and you need to do some crypto code, what do you do?
You should totally write your own, right?
Oh Wait, no, I mean, don't, don't roll your own crypto.
No,
never roll your own crypto or even if you don't roll your own
crypto and you try to use like open SSL libraries and stuff.
The problem is they,
they go to like a textbook or like stack overflow and like look for the answer to,
you know, how do I make web crypto
and then they, you know, follow what is in there because
well, it'll probably work.
I think it's safe to say if you're going
to stack overflow to enable TLS in your application,
you probably have two problems now instead
of one, right?
So anyways, um they do crypto on the web browser
they have a browser for Android.
And uh so the uh the wup um
the WUP requests contain basically information about, you know,
the user's phone number, QQ user name, the Wi Fi Mac address,
they're on the SS ID blah, blah blah, right?
So anyways to encrypt this wup request, we use crypto, of course.
So first and, and this is verbatim from the paper.
This is not me making terrible stuff up first.
The client generates 100 and 28 bit A S session key
-- for the session, right? That's, that's good 128 bit session key.
-- It's all right.
-- It could be better
-- using a pseudorandom number generator. OK? We're good, right?
Seated with the current time in milliseconds since the UNIX
epoch.
That's bad.
Now, tell us why is that bad?
Because if you know about when somebody did something, you can easily regenerate.
Well, that's not a pseudo random number. Well, I can't,
it's, well, it doesn't matter what pseudorandomness if you,
even if you don't like,
even if you only know within an hour or a day of when the person sent this request,
you can brute force it.
They pretty easily without question. Yes.
I mean, that's the whole point of,
of pseudo random number generators is that there's no
way for an attacker to ascertain the internal state.
And if you're setting it based on milliseconds,
I can easily figure out your state.
All right.
So, well, OK, then
then the client encrypts the session key using a 1024 bit RS A public key.
This public key has the exponent 65,537.
And the RS A implementation is quote textbook RS
a unquote, meaning that no form of padding such as OAP is applied at all. Now,
what is padding? Can you explain that to us in a crypto sense?
Yeah, I'll try to make it make sense. So when you have crypto,
you obviously have a message, let's say you have 36 bytes of text,
we'll just say for this example.
And when you encrypt 36 bytes of text, you get 36 bytes of
encrypted data essentially, right?
And there are various crypto algorithms that require say 1024 bytes or
there there's a number of other reasons including if, if someone knows it's 36 bys,
they can conduct certain attacks on it. And so you generally pad it out to something.
So it's consistent no matter who's doing what you always have, say 1024 bits.
And that, that helps with the algorithms.
It helps with consistency and it makes certain attacks much, much harder.
And so not padding is generally frowned upon in most situations today.
Yeah,
the client then uses the session key to encrypt, the WUP request in ECB mode,
hang on a second ECB mode for web
crypto. Let's see what the top result is.
Probably don't necessarily want to be doing that,
I believe. Yes, insecure cipher mode is what they call it typically.
Uh So the long and the short of that is, is there's different modes of encryption,
some of which are suitable for the web and many of which are not.
So anyways, step four,
the client says the R A encrypted,
sorry, let's talk about ECB for a second as well. So, so ECB
is, there's CBC and there's ECB are kind of the two big ones. And with CBC,
imagine it's,
we could think of it in the context of
even the Blockchain just because I can say Blockchain now
is you kind of take the results of the last operation
you did and you feed it back into the algorithm.
And so obviously, if you pick up the stream halfway through,
even if you have the key,
it's not useful to you because what it's been doing is part of the key essentially
where ECB doesn't work like that. It's, it's more of what we would think of as
you know, you, you kind of X or let's say, and I know that's grossly inaccurate.
So please please don't hold me to that.
But it, it's, it's more static in that regard, right?
Where kind of each block is encrypted in the same way.
Yeah, if you go to the Wikipedia page on ECB and CB or on ECB,
they have that beautiful image of to
the Linux
Penguin
and
using ECB mode. You can clearly see it's to
-- the Linux Penguin and you know,
-- right.
Any non ECB mode, it, it looks like, you know, the TV, on the fritz,
it's just white noise.
Right.
That, yes, that's, that's a great example.
And we'll put a link to that in the show notes.
Yeah. What it boils down to is don't use ECB
for web crypto.
Is
there any time it's appropriate to use ECB anymore?
It's
for file system encryption because any time you
need kind of random access to the data,
you can't use CBC or you have to basically replay everything
in order which would be bad in a file system.
Yeah, that's true.
Uh So then number four,
the client sends the RS a encrypted a session
key and the encrypted wup request to the server,
the server then decrypt the RS A encrypted AES
key it received from the client using its private
key then chooses the least significant 120 bits of
the plain text to be the AES session key
white.
No, no,
see this is. Oh, anyway, so, well, obviously we have your reaction out.
Now, can you please explain that reaction?
Uh
There's so much wrong with this,
read this again slowly and then I'll pick it apart. OK?
The server decrypt,
the RS A encrypted AES key it received from the client using its private key, right?
That's fine.
That's
fine.
Then it chooses the least significant 128 bits of the plain text
to be the A E session key.
And so this is where
I'm, I'm
a couple of things pop into my head here. So, first of all, it's already an AES key.
Right?
And, and I don't know exactly what's in the session text,
but it's quite likely it's going to be something relatively predictable.
And
the first thing that popped into my head is they're not padding anything.
So are they essentially dealing with like null bites in
some way if there's no padding as part of this?
It's,
this is, this is wonky. I mean, you don't ever use
when, when you need to generate a cryptographically strong key,
you don't use things like known plain text from the, from the,
essentially the client you're communicating with because everything I've,
I've heard so far
strikes me as
it probably wouldn't be terribly difficult to man in the middle of this process.
Well, like Ime I numbers, there's,
there's a lot of them. There's
not
a
lot so
much known.
Yeah,
there's so much known about these sessions and
I would, I
could put my tinfoil hat on and say
this was done on purpose so it can be broken. But I have a greater suspicion.
This is just someone who didn't actually know what they were doing.
So the server then decrypt the w uh sorry, we said that uh oh sorry,
the server then decrypt the WEP request using the session key that it,
that it obtained via the RS A decryption.
Great.
And then finally, number seven,
if the A as cipher text received from the
client decrypt to a valid wup request correctly,
the server sends an A s encrypted response using
the AES session key also using ECB mode.
Yeah.
At this point like this is where the expert basically
takes a deep breath and then goes for a drink.
And so man, there's so much messed up with this.
So I'm not even a crypto expert, right?
I'm,
I'm there's people way smarter than me that I know are probably crying right now.
But
so,
so here's the biggest problem I see with ECB encryption using something like this,
there are going to be parts of this message that are known and understood.
And this is kind of like that, that Linux Penguin example where you know,
there's going to be so much, so many bites of header,
there's going to be so many bites of message.
There's gonna be, you know, probably some sort of ending bites in, in the message.
There's, well, there's not padding apparently, but there should be.
And like this is one of the challenges you get with ECB is is
if you look at the patterns and if you collect a lot of them,
you can start figuring things out and, and it's very easy to do cryptanalysis
when,
when you are able to collect huge volumes of basically similar
looking messages sent over and over and over again here.
Well, that's neat.
Now, here's the other thing that, that comes to my brain though,
when I think of this is,
are, are the, the Chinese developers, have they seen this report?
Will they see this report
and will they fix it?
Apparently it was fixed. They went from 128
to 1024 and some other stuff. But
in my experience when you have
especially your own crypto code,
when you have inexperienced developers,
they may have plugged these specific holes and problems.
The problem is they're going to probably write some new functionality tomorrow.
Yes.
Yes. Without, without a doubt. And
well, other things are less dangerous in crypto. I mean, crypto is hard, man.
Even, even the guys who know what they're doing, get it wrong.
Yeah.
So well, and speaking of crypto and getting it wrong and making it hard.
So we now have
two big events coming up this summer.
-- Oh, man, it's going to be the summer of TLS. I'm so excited.
-- Oh, yeah.
So the, well, the first event chronologically
is the PC I the payment card industry standard.
Uh They will be deprecating TLS version one point. Oh and well, SSL
uh
it, it won't be allowed and, and of course,
there are exemptions for like payment card terminals and
a pile of other stuff that can't be replaced reasonably
cheaply.
So, of course, they're letting people just not,
um, you know, and they sort of are going with the whole wily wobbly.
Well, these things aren't really web browsers so it's kind of mostly. Ok.
Ish,
I
mean,
for some tax is true.
I, I've talked to a lot of PC I auditors about this actually because it was,
I think the 3.2 standard basically said you had to use my,
and they just said modern TLS
for new deployments and now old deploy, well,
only certain aspects of the PC I standard depending upon what you were doing.
It was, it was modern TLS.
And that was interpreted to mean in TLS 1.2 by every auditor I talked to
and,
and this one sounds like they're,
they're going to bring the hammer down maybe a little harder than they did before.
And
the, the thing is though to that PC I does, it's really clever is
you, you can fail technically, but as long as you have a plan to not fail next time,
they will often let you continue operating,
which is obviously the right way to do it because if you fail and you're like, yeah,
screw this, I hate this stuff.
They're gonna be like, nope, you're done.
But if you say, ok,
I failed and this is why I failed and here's how
I'm going to fix it in the next three months,
they'll be like, ok, great.
-- You know, let's let's
-- work out.
And realistically these guys can't turn their stuff off and just not
process credit card money because then they would go bankrupt.
Right. Right. Exactly. That's, so, that's not an, like, like, literally failure
is not an option,
like true failure.
Um,
but yeah, so it's, it's,
yeah, I,
here's the other thing that I think is really important to
clarify and you and I were talking about this yesterday.
TLS 1.2 which is the latest standard is like, it's nearly 10 years old now.
-- Right?
-- August 2008 is when it was,
we're not talking about like
people have only had three months to get ready or something. It's been 10 years.
There is, if you're still using SSL, I just shame on you. Right.
That's all I can say to that. I mean,
no piece of hardware should be in use for 10 years if it's not maybe a car and even then,
right, nobody keeps cars for 10 years.
I'm sure these guys have mainframes and older systems creaking along.
I mean, I, ok, let me put it this way.
Would you bet money against there being at least one windows 95 machine in
use by somebody in the payment card industry somewhere doing some automated task?
Oh, I have no doubt there shouldn't be, but I'm sure there is.
And this is a great example of finally saying, you know what it's time to be done,
get rid of it.
And, and not only that, I
have a sneaking suspicion that if you actually did like an
ro I assessment on a lot of this old gear,
the cost of, of upgrading it
well, carries a certain amount of upfront. It,
it is probably cheaper over the life of the product
versus whatever you're paying now to keep the stuff alive.
Yeah, the problem being is that, you know,
a lot of financial thinking is quite often short term.
Right. You gotta, gotta hit the number for Wall Street, right.
Yeah.
So that's the first thing that's gonna happen.
And that's June 30th and that date was already pushed back and I, it
doesn't look, I, I
don't think they're going to push the state back again because as you said, this,
you know, everybody's had just about 10 years at that point.
There's been a long time in, in PC I 3.2 landed more than a year ago.
It's been like two years I think for that one.
So there's,
there's not a very good reason
at this point to not be using TLS.
A new version of TLS we'll say. Right.
Yeah.
Oh,
and the other nice thing too is that they're going to be disallowing the use of weak
ciphers and unapproved algorithms such as RC four
and MB five which have at this point,
they, you know, your laptop can crack them
in real time.
So, yeah. No, this is, I mean, this is good.
This is gonna actually, this is something that will
hope. Well,
the thing I always wonder though is realistically,
has there ever been
a crypto based attack against a major
PC I player
or do they just break into the database and
hoover it all up like they did with equifax?
-- I, I
-- don't think you.
Well, ok, so first of all, my guess is if there was a proper attack,
we'd never hear about it.
But kind of the way I view this is,
it's maybe less about the crypto itself and more about if you can't do this,
it's because you have bad hygiene,
right?
This is kind of like one of those just outward signs that if,
if you're using SSL three,
what else are you doing?
Right.
Yeah.
Well, I was talking with this about somebody um,
with respect to
essentially doing CV S for services and part
of the challenge with CV S for services is
with the majority of services provided by companies.
We don't really have any insight to them, right. It's just here, you know,
often times here's a public api that's it. That's all you can see. Right?
You don't know what,
what it's doing on the back end or what software it's running
on the back end or even what it's written in some cases.
And one of the things I mentioned was that, well, you know,
we might go with like SSL and TLS kind of stuff
initially because that is public facing and can easily be quantified,
right? You,
you can run like a tool like N map and say,
like give me a list of all the ciphers and protocols and combinations and blah,
blah blah that this endpoint will do,
you know, and show me the bad ones, right?
Or like the SSL lab stuff from qual, you know, query my server and
give me a, you know, an A through an F score.
Um So yeah, that's no, that's a good point though.
If, if you literally can't upgrade to like TLS,
then chances are like, are you even patching?
Right. Exactly. And, and that's,
that's my view on a lot of this compliance stuff is,
is compliance is like just saying I wash my hands after I use the bathroom,
right? It, it's not showing really anything deep.
It just shows that you have the basics under control and,
and a lot of organizations don't.
It's,
and I'm not gonna lie.
If you have legacy infrastructure and you're not already compliant,
it is very difficult to change the way you do
things and in all seriousness in a lot of instances,
it's probably easier to just start over.
Yes.
Yeah. And so in line with this, we also have Google Chrome
in July of 2018
with the release of version 68
chrome will mark all http sites as quote not secure unquote.
So I am so excited about this
in the address bar, it will say you know, like right now
it says example.com and in future, it will say not secure little bar thing and then
the uh the actual URL.
And yeah, this is interesting because users have been trained, you know,
oh you know, look for the lock, the lock makes it secure, blah, blah, blah,
but this is way more in your face, right? It says not secure right at the top,
you know, instead of saying like right now, I,
I see I'm looking at this blog posting on Google and
there's a little green lock and it says secure and then,
you know, HTPSF
slash
security dot google blog.com stuff.
What I'm really curious about is like,
how many people are going to upgrade to Chrome 68 not
notice it for a few days and then just flip out
when they go to like their favorite ecommerce website or bank or something.
I'm, I'm sure there will be some without question.
But at the same time, actually, I put a thing on Twitter about this. I said
this will do more to further security than every fishing training session ever
combined.
And,
and here's my thinking on this and I know
this will be kind of controversial to some but whatever
is
we have obsessed for a long time on
teaching users to do the right thing.
And I feel like this is the first big stake in the ground where we're admitting
it's not about the users. We need to use our technology to make things better.
And now mind you
what, what the TLS everywhere is going to do
isn't make site secure because let's face it.
Anyone can get a certificate from, let's encrypt now.
Yeah,
-- or use cloud flare or whatever,
-- whatever. Exactly.
Like HTTP S is not a high bar any longer.
But what this does is it sets us up
for a universe where we can start imposing certain limits
on, on the way the internet is working to make it better for people.
And let's face it also, I think my, my guess is
the real reason Google really likes this is
there are various
I SPS now, at least in the United States
that are
they, they're modifying HTTP traffic to show their own ads
and, and let's face it at the end of the day,
Google is making all of its money on ads
and I'm sure this makes them incredibly grumpy.
I'm glad this also has the effect
of making the whole internet
-- use http S everywhere. It will be glorious if port 80 is gone someday.
-- Right?
Well, I mean, you know, we've had hsts so the,
the HTTP S strict transport security header for a while.
And basically what that says is,
you know, you go to the,
the insecure version of the website and you get handed this header saying,
you know what from now on only talk to me via http S,
you know, for this amount of time. Usually you said the thing to be six months
at
the
same time.
I
mean,
-- look how hard is it to man in the middle of something like that? Right.
-- Exactly.
So the idea behind hsts is ideally,
people would access their bank or whatever from home at first and then, you know,
later when they're at a coffee shop and somebody's
trying to man in the middle of them,
they can't,
you can also whitelist your domain
uh with Google and Firefox and the other browsers pull this. So for example,
creed.org has been whitelisted as
uh an HSTS domain
for several years now. And so when you actually type in
cried.org into your web browser,
it automatically flips it to http S whether or not you want
end of story, it won't give you a choice.
And the other nice thing about hsts is it
doesn't allow you to click through uh
warnings,
right?
Like normally if you get like uh oh you know,
the certificates wonky or it's out of date or it's expired or whatever, you know.
No. Yeah, I really want to go look at this. It's cool.
Uh And with HSTS, the browsers are like, nope, I'm not going to let you do that.
Not cool.
Um
And so, yeah, no, I agree. This is, this is kind of
what really gets me is that the number of websites that are not properly maintained
will become somewhat apparent.
I know that's going to be great. And again,
I view this kind of similar to
the whole PC I,
if you're not doing this, what else aren't you doing?
Because at this point,
there's basically the bar for HTTP S is, it's about as low as it can get.
I mean,
there's even scripts you can get
from nuts encrypt that basically automate everything
like you, you don't need to be overly skilled
to use HTTP S anymore. And I will say though,
I do remember the days of generating certificates and
having to send them off to the C A
-- and man, it was horrible to do that and you always screwed it up or
-- oh,
my favorite part was always trying to get the
chaining certificates
served by the
server working
correctly that I mean,
just for people who are listening and don't know what the hell we're talking about.
-- Just trust us when we say it was a nightmare.
-- Well, ok, so, no, we should explain this.
So what happen is when you go to a website
and let's say we go to
cried.org and it's signed by, I don't know,
let's say let's encrypt and I don't care if it is or isn't,
let's say it's signed by, let's encrypt.
Uh Your browser will trust the, let's encrypt route.
But let's say there's a couple of cas in between because
it is in the real world. You might have like real root C A, right?
And then you have like say two or three levels of resellers.
So like whatever signed your certificate might be kind of like
three layers removed from the actual C A your browser trusts.
And this is the point of certificates so you can do this sort of delegation.
And so what happens is
you have to make sure you include all of the certificates along your chain
that the web server hands to the browser. So the browser can say, OK,
I trust this certificate, the certificates,
trusted or signed by this certificate and signed by this certificate
and that signed this the connection I'm using right now.
And so. Right. Exactly.
And if you missed one, the browser would, well,
the browser would sometimes flip out depending upon what you missed.
And if it knew about the certificate already, it was like it was such a freaking mess,
man.
Oh my goodness.
Just thinking of that gives me pain
and all the clients were different too.
Of course. Yeah, because they all did different things,
right? Some clients did ssl somewhat reasonably correctly and a lot of them didn't,
you know it was. Yeah, I remember those days.
So yeah, I mean,
fundamentally if you can't get HTTP S working properly in front of your website,
then you know it better be a uh
like a personal blog or something that you're running.
There's no excuse anymore. Look, there's zero excuse. I'm sorry, I'm just gonna,
if you're not using hhps already,
you need to start and if you don't know how spend like, 10 minutes getting,
lets encrypt working and you will never regret it ever.
I mean,
yeah, it's, it's time there, there's no excuse. Get it.
So, the other thing that's interesting about this is it will have
a side effect of effectively
punting Windows X is it Windows XP that does still doesn't do SN I
maybe, maybe like IE six or something. But I mean, even at this point.
-- So
-- basically, well, here's so here's the thing, right?
When you do SL RT LS to a server,
you talk to the IP address. And if you want to talk to like a specific host name on it,
there's a thing called server name indicator.
Um because as part of the initial request,
like you have to set up sort of an encrypted channel with the server
and then you can talk to it and do stuff, right?
And for a server that hosts multiple hosts,
you know, host names, which is like all the web servers. Now
we have this thing called server name indicator that
you create an encrypted connection to the server.
And then you say I want to talk to super.org or I want to talk to
let's encrypt.org or whatever
and you know, yeah, older browsers and stuff don't support this.
And the reality is to,
to do http S at scale,
we can't do one IP per
web address.
You know, I remember, I remember being ac a
man
on servers that had one IP per address for it was SSL back then.
It was a management nightmare.
Oh, I remember, yeah.
Like you'd run if config and there'd be like 400 pages of screens.
-- Oh, man,
-- it was brutal. It was brutal.
But again, so here's, here's what I'm going to say is
if you're using a web browser, they can't do this.
you have way bigger problems than just your web browser.
I mean, this is, you're not washing your hands when you go to the bathroom,
that's what that means.
You know, start doing it.
There is no excuse any longer and, and this is,
this is why I'm so excited about this because
someone who,
who can actually make a difference is finally like standing up and saying no,
we're done, right?
And you're, you're not, it almost feels like
you've got like your, your typical
bully versus victim sort of person
here where, where the, you know, like, oh no, we can't disable ssl one point.
Oh, because someone might be using it. It's like, no,
no more like I'm done with you.
If you're doing that too bad, you lose where the world is moving on.
Yeah.
And that's, and that's one of the things I worry about is, I mean,
I get that people want to buy stuff and use it for 10
or 20 years and a lot of people don't have money to say,
upgrade every three years to the latest phone or whatever.
But at the same time, you know, it really reminds me of cars. Right. Older cars
fantastically dangerous.
Right.
Not just for the people in them because they didn't have air bags or anti lock brakes,
but for the rest of us.
Right.
You know, like modern cars have crumple zones for pedestrians.
I would go farther than that and say this is like taking your horse on the interstate.
Right.
There's a reason that's illegal.
Ok.
There's a good reason that's legal
because there's going to be dead horse and,
and broken cars everywhere is what's going to happen.
Right.
Yeah, it's just, it's, you know, all these things are parts of botnets that,
you know, you can't realistically secure them unless you're some, like,
crazy corporation that needs to run this thing behind seven firewalls.
But, but I would hope. And so again, you're not washing your hands,
but more importantly is like, if you absolutely have to do this.
And now I know, like,
I've heard stories about someone like Boeing needing windows 95 from whatever,
like their C AD program was for designing something
that's fine.
Set up a VM and, like,
lock that sucker up and make sure you have the expertise to actually take care of it.
Right. But like, yeah, the person sitting at home running a, a 12 year old computer,
like, there's so much wrong with that you can't even start. Right.
Yeah.
No, I think it really does boil down to, you know,
when you're out in public you need to cough into your rebel,
not your hand for the love of God.
People. Stop coughing into your hand.
-- Right.
-- And, and think about that, like, if I was walking around coughing on people,
I have a suspicion, something bad would happen to me. Right.
I'm either gonna get beat up or arrested is my suspicion.
Well, we're just going to shun you
that already happened. So,
so,
but yeah, no, I'm, I'm excited because these two changes essentially
will have the side effect of breaking a ton of old obsolete clients which
sucks for the people using them. But at the same time, I think will
probably measurably help and make things a bit better for the rest of us.
I, I have no doubt.
I'm, I'm very excited now. I, I recognize there's going to be some pain,
but I think
when it's done,
we will look back and say, thank goodness we did that.
Yeah. So I guess with that we're going to wrap this up.
Yes, there's, there's no better way to end it than that. I guess we, we're ending.
Thank goodness we did that. Um
So
thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can hit up open source security podcast.com for the show notes.
You can use the Pound Os S podcast hashtag to
get the attention of Kurt and myself and social media
and if nothing else, Kurt, you have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks.