Hello and welcome to episode 44 of the open source security podcast
with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime. Josh Bresser.
How are you today? Kurt?
-- I'm doing pretty good. We had a LEGO party last night. What
-- a LEGO party.
Yeah, we invited friends over to play LEGO
-- and drink.
-- That sounds awesome. I've never done that. That
I, I've, I'm, I've clearly,
I've been missing something important in my life and that might be it.
So, here's a question though is if you have adults playing LEGO,
not LEGOS, LEGO
and uh they're drinking as well. Uh How much fighting was there over the uh
one by four piece that everybody needs.
Well, funnily enough,
we didn't actually end up really playing with the LEGO mostly just a
big pile of mini figs and making up a big battle scene because
like I, so for those of you who don't know that don't know,
I have just over 100 pounds of regular Lego.
So needless to say
I
bought it online used before my kids were born.
-- It was about eight years ago when you could get this stuff cheap.
-- Ok.
-- And now you can't get it cheap because
-- people know what it's worth. It's
-- really expensive.
-- Yeah.
But I was buying the stuff used online for typically around 8 to $10 a pound,
including shipping.
Um, new sets are around 40 bucks a pound. It works out too.
Uh, but anyways, yeah, so we have like, several 100 mini figs,
some really cool ones too.
Like going back, you know, 1020 years.
And so, yeah, we basically just had like this sort of giant Mad Max Spaceman
-- Castle battle scene thing going on.
-- And, and how many pieces did you step on?
Uh Basically zero. I have developed lego radar.
Lego radar.
Yeah. Also it's uh when, when the lego is out, I, I walk differently.
I sort of like sweep my feet rather than sta
I, I know, I know exactly what you mean.
It only works on hardwood though. If you have rugs.
-- Well, you're up the,
-- if you're, if you're on a rug,
it doesn't hurt as much either if you step on it because a certain amount of
the Lego goes into the rug and the rest of it goes into your foot.
The,
the problem I find with rug though is it tends to go down at a diagonal angle.
So then you get the sharp end sticking up, right? Whereas on hardwood,
the Lego tends to lie flat.
I won't lie.
I don't know.
So, anyway,
uh you know, though, I, I oftentimes think that there are some lessons for us all in,
in LEGO.
My son
has many LEGO sets
and a LEGO set is incredibly expensive and some of
them are more than $100 for the things he has.
And do you know what he does? He builds them.
Well, usually I help and I, he suckers me to doing most of the work.
But, but anyway, so the, the set gets built.
It is sometimes played with for a short period of time and then
it is torn apart and put in the box at which point it's
why somebody bought this for you child. And,
and, and I'm torn though because on one side,
somebody paid a whole lot of money for a Lego set that is now pieces
and on the other side, like what do you expect?
They're LEGO, it's just how it is, right?
Yeah. See my rules. I don't
uh I do glue some of my LEGO sets together,
uh usually vehicles because they have a tendency to kind of get exploded and
especially in the large amount of LEGO, I have, they're gone forever.
Um So I do glue some of the smaller vehicles together.
And the trick there is you use Acetone paint, both sides of the legal piece.
Wait about a second and then smoke it together and then you go
like you, you take
Acetone and you just paint the plastic and then obviously assume it melts a little
-- bit and then
-- exactly what you really want to use is methyl lethal ketone Mek.
But, um, thanks to methamphetamine production,
that stuff is incredibly difficult to get a hold of. Now. There's all sorts
of paperwork.
Yeah,
that's like when I need cold medicine and I feel like some sort of criminal when they,
-- like,
-- looking at a
veteran
in
it.
-- Oh, man,
-- I hate that. Right.
It's one of the precursors for meth.
Um, yeah.
so you just, yeah, you just, I, I get a bottle of Acetone at Home Depot, you know,
like once every couple of years,
uh pour a little bit of it into like a ceramic dish.
Obviously, if you put in a plastic, they should start to melt minor.
And um and then you just use like a small cheap
paint brush just to paint both sides and like I said,
just press it together.
The trick is you got to paint both sides
and also
you definitely want to wear uh like nitro gloves because that stuff
because the plastic melts a little bit and then it gets
on your skin and it's just incredibly annoying to clean off.
I can, I can see that
nice, very cool.
Um So
although I must say he uh my son got
the Millennium Falcon and the uh Star Destroyer Lego sets
and apart from the incredible cost of these,
I said these are too cool to take apart and I put shelves really high in
his bedroom so he can't reach them and then I put them on the shelves.
So II I feel like a bad parent for doing that.
But I think it, it's for the good of humanity that I did it.
Well, it's like my one son wants the Lego Simpsons house and the Lego Simpsons,
Quickie Mart.
And those are both like $300 sets.
What,
-- how big are they?
-- They're really quite big. They're, they're really quite nice.
Um
Why do you let your kids watch the Simpsons? Your kids are like six.
What's
wrong with
you?
On
the? No, they, they've actually never seen the Simpsons.
What they have seen is Lego ST Motion Simpsons on youtube? Ok. Ok.
Right. So he wants that and it's like no
abs,
I'm sorry, buddy. Like I'm, I'm not spending 600 bucks on Legos
for
him,
you know, especially when he has like a pretty good collection of lego to play with.
-- I,
-- I totally get it. Well and it's like typical kids.
There'll be some new shiny thing in a couple of weeks and that'll be fine then. Right.
So now that we've talked about something nice and
made everybody happy and nostalgic for their childhood.
Should we talk about something that will make everybody angry?
Yeah, we should probably fill them with rage because that's fun.
Ok.
Well, I guess, yeah, you lead off because you brought,
I'll bring it up.
So by the time this,
this podcast is out a blog post I've written is going to be published and
I'm making the argument
that
pen testing
in the near future is going to be replaced with bug bounties.
And I made the suggestion of this on Twitter.
And you know, a number of people, like, like they were clearly annoyed
by this statement
which tells me I'm clearly onto something, right.
It's the old saying that if nobody's upset with something you're doing,
you're not doing anything interesting.
And
I will explain the story behind what really got me to thinking this way is,
uh, at
work, there have been a handful of individuals I I've been dealing with, we're,
we're kind of
someone shows up with a pest
report and will say something like fix it,
right?
And these things have like literally thousands of crap
issues that you aren't going to actually fix,
which then really got me thinking about.
But a typical P test and
every time I've dealt with them in the past,
I'd say a normal pen test report actually results in what,
maybe three or four real fixes
maybe,
right? It's very small. And that got me thinking then
what are you paying per bug? Right? Because
the thing is when you do a pen test,
people generally think about kind of cost per
issue found is what most people think about.
But I got to thinking
what about cost per issue fixed?
Because just because the pest
has 15,000 findings in it,
you're not gonna fix 15,000 findings. I mean, that's just the reality of it.
Ok.
And, and I, I don't think anyone's going to disagree with that. Right.
Well, unless it's some sort of automated thing, like, um,
you know, I, I, for example, Google with their fuzzing, you know, project,
uh, has also, then, you know, with chrome,
at least kind of automated part of the fixing of that.
But I mean, that's,
that is a very much, you know,
way out in left field corner case that is basically proves that
you're right because there's only one person on the planet doing it.
Well, in,
in Google is special and I'm also not talking about kind of
internal pen testing because I think an internal P test group can provide
significant value
due to the fact that they have access and knowledge that other people want.
Because let's face it when you show up to do a pen test,
you don't want them to spend a month getting familiar
with their product because you're gonna pay for that,
right? You want to hand them something,
have them do their pen test
and they get the results back, right? That's kind of the reality of that.
And then that can be kind of thinking about the context of a bug bounty is
if you're only going to fix three issues,
why are you paying for this huge pen test when
something like a a good bug bounty
could potentially get you those three issues for a fraction of the cost.
Right.
Yeah.
Well, I think a lot of this boils down to so historically,
security knowledge was difficult.
I mean,
we
led,
well, it, but for,
well, sort of, but for example, pen testing
used to be like, only, you know, a
very small handful of people knew anything about pen testing, let alone how to do it.
Well, And now if you look at, say the OAS
project, they actually have a really good pen testing document
that describes how to do it. And like, what the top 10 or 20 things to look for are,
you know, they have a list of tools how to use them, you know, like, basically
what was like the top of the line pen test, you know,
five or six years ago or maybe 10 years ago is now like a nice document
and you can walk pretty much anybody through it, you know,
just like setting up an email server used to be
like, do you remember the days where if you knew how to do routing,
you can make over 100 grand a year, just like configuring c
-- routers.
-- You know, I do remember those days and, and
funny enough is, is we'll take a side note. Here is
a long time ago.
If you were willing to be a Cisco tech support person,
you would get all of your Cisco certifications for free.
And I knew a number of people who went to Cisco
and they became like telephone support
to get all in, like, they're the smartest people I knew.
And so Cisco had an amazing tech support program
because they had all these crazy, smart people who didn't want to shell out.
I mean, it was tens of thousands of dollars to get all these certifications.
Right.
So they go to Cisco work tech support for a couple of years,
get all these certifications and then go make like literally
five or six times as much money in the,
in the, in the industry as they were making answering phones at Cisco, which was,
I mean, but at the same time I get it right, because Cisco got a huge benefit for a, in,
in a variety of ways out of this.
But anyway, anyway, sorry, back to security.
Well, yeah, so back to this.
I mean, the reality is, you know, stuff that used to be crazy, difficult,
hard is like now entry level knowledge,
you know,
um and pen testing isn't there quite yet. But for example,
you know, while talking about these, you know, huge numbers of pen test results,
like the one thing I always consistently see is people run NUS
or N
I or how we pronounce it against the product,
you know, and there's a couple of things
nus
consistently finds and
they complain about it and you know, these are trivial things like
that just don't matter.
Or they can just, you know,
they can be configured away very trivially in almost every software product.
And
so, you know, the, the, I think part of it is the, the majority of
companies, um, on the operation side,
you know, they're not really all that strong security wise,
like they don't have good security people typically.
Um, and, you know, most software vendors, um, that I've ever dealt with,
you know, just trying to report a security problem to them, let alone
them having a good security person or team,
you know, it is very rare, right? So I think,
-- but, but this is actually you touch
-- on this is how we ended up in this.
But what I'm trying to get at is this is kind of how we ended up in this mess where,
you know, there's a, let's face it in pen testing.
There's a lot of snake oil salesmen,
you know, I've, I've seen pest reports complaining about, you know,
insecure storage of credit card numbers
when it's like,
but the product doesn't do any form of that at all or take any
-- payments or anything if
-- I was gonna guess they put that on every report,
right?
-- It's an easy thing to add. Yeah,
-- or we've literally had like,
you know, cross site scripting results in this page and we're like,
there's no page there
like,
you know, so just basic stuff like I, I
the quality of a lot of these reports is, is
quite honestly from what I've seen on the being on the receiving
-- some of these, it's not
-- very good.
I, I won't disagree with that, but I also don't want to dwell on that point because
the, the people who are,
are now furiously shaking their fists at their computer screen
are gonna
be
good people. And that's the thing right. There are people who are good at this.
And so I, I'm happy to acknowledge
that the people who are good at this are
very good at it and they provide immense value.
Right.
And, and no one can deny that.
Oh, yeah. No, I, I had one p test report done by a very competent person,
you know, and, and what they came up with resulted in, like,
I think it was between half a dozen and a dozen CV ES,
you know,
and, and this, but, you know, this is, again, this person is very much a
corner case in the industry, you know, they, they're very, very good at what they do.
Um,
you know, and, but part of the problem there is is, you know,
there's a very finite number of those people.
There's filler. Right. Yeah, basically.
No, no, there's, there's more.
But, but anyway, I,
I want to go back to a point you had that I think is really important and this is
going to be one of the problems with the bug bounty industry
is let's face it.
The,
the real purpose of a bug bounty for many people
is to help raise their public profile right there,
there is money
without a doubt.
But it, I, I see a couple of advantages here.
If you're the company participating,
you obviously get a certain amount of press saying, look at us, we do a bug bounty.
We care about security, which is very true and deserved.
And then the researchers obviously can say, look at me,
I found a bunch of neat bugs in this bug bounty program, aren't I neat?
And, and yes, yes, you are
so good job. But
here's the problem is what happens if you're a company
that's relatively small and has a very boring product.
Is anyone gonna want to do a bug bounty on your product?
Well, I, uh, ok. I'm just blanking.
What is that name of that email server that was written by?
I think it was Daniel J Bernstein.
Q,
right. Q
yeah. Do you remember for the longest time people would say basically Q
was more secure than send mail the postfix because,
and I quote Daniel J Bernstein had a $500 bounty for bugs found in it.
Ok. Do you remember that?
-- I do like he, he still has a bug bounty and all this stuff, doesn't he?
-- No.
And yeah, and, and now, ok,
and again in fairness D GB is like one
of the best software security guys on the planet.
But my point is more that people basically said
this, their logic train was, he's offered a $500 bug bounty.
Therefore, his product is more secure because he, like stands behind it.
And I think that's one of the big aspects of, of, uh,
bug bounties that, you know,
these large companies will use it to sort of signal security virtue
because let's face it right.
If, if a company says, you know, we're actually gonna stand by in our product and say,
like, if you find a bad flaw it, we'll give you like
10 grand or whatever,
you know, that,
that does kind of give me a little bit more confidence
in them in their process than somebody who does nothing.
I don't follow that line of reasoning though.
When I see a company has a bug bounty, I think it means
we understand
our software has bugs and
we would like you to tell us about them
and we promise not to sue you and if it's really good, we'll also give you some money.
Well, yeah, exactly. They're signaling virtue in security like that.
You know, they're not gonna, like,
be mean to you and that they hopefully also have a
way to deal with these bug bounties like the result.
But I, I don't interpret this is, um, suggesting there's a higher quality in any way.
I, well, from what I've seen of some of these, you know,
service providers and stuff there has definitely been, you know,
some of that going on for some of them, not all of them.
Um, it's possible,
I will also say that I suspect if you're involved in something like this,
you're probably going to improve
eventually
because you're going to have people finding things. And
if you keep making the same mistake over and over again,
I'd hope somebody starts asking questions internally of, you know,
why do we keep doing this?
Why have you fixed the same bug in 12 different places and pay 12 different people?
Well,
what I've also noticed is people who have bug boundaries kind of have to deal
with it because otherwise the reporters get
really angry because they want their money.
Right. So, I mean,
you know,
makes
sense
and there's been cases of that in the past where these reporters have gone public,
you know,
with these companies that haven't paid out the bug bounty or have, you know,
essentially waffled on it or, you know, done other shenanigans,
shall we say to avoid?
It's really funny. I totally agree with that.
And I was talking, I, I, I'm talking to hacker one about this right now actually.
And somebody said to me at one point,
well, well, what happens if, if the security researchers get angry with us?
And I said,
then I hope they publish something in public because it either
means we're wrong and we deserve to be made fun of or
we're actually, right.
And someone publishing something wrong in this instance,
actually helps it reinforce our correct position on a certain issue.
Right.
And I mean, it, it's totally, this is one of the things about,
about security is we love doing things in secret.
And I think that is a huge problem with this whole industry in a lot of time.
A lot of cases,
no embargoes are definitely overused,
not even just embargoes. I mean, like a
great example is
if, if you get a pen test report done, do you share it with anyone?
Nobody does,
right.
How many security bugs did you fix in your last update?
A lot of people don't say that they'll just say we fix some security issues.
I mean, even Microsoft does this where
if, if they have a certain module with say 20 security issues, they'll say uh yeah,
it's uh one important in,
in this module and here's the one C pe ID and like they admit they do that even.
Yeah. No, we've
um, well, I don't want to talk about it too much,
but there's been an instance of this happening with a vendor uh regarding CV ES where
they basically say they want to sign CV S if the component gets automatic updates.
Interesting. I've never heard it.
And of course, that's,
yeah, so one of the things we need to discuss now in the CV world is
uh one of the requirements is, you know, for CV, when the, when the flaw goes public,
the CV has to be announced.
So what constitutes going, you know, public with a flaw? Right? Is that
an advisory or is that like just a binary update?
But you can make the argument about a cloud service?
For example, if, if there's a problem in Gmail and Google fixes it,
do they need to tell anyone
and, and even if they told us why do we care?
-- And that's kind of the same deal on automatic updates,
-- right.
The good news, there is a lot of cloud providers again,
want to be more transparent there because they want
to essentially show that they're doing security better than their competitors.
Ah, that's fair. That could be a competitive advantage.
-- And certainly the cloud world, I can see
-- and we've already found that with, you know,
with the cloud security lines and the stars uh program,
you know, there's uh 250 or so public registry, uh like entries for stars,
entries for these companies.
I know that there's several 1000 of these entries floating around.
They're just, you know, they haven't submitted them publicly
to the public registry.
Um,
but like there's a number of governments that basically require this document now,
if you want to sell stuff to them.
That's interesting.
So, yeah, a couple of major universities, a couple of major companies,
they just because part of it is,
it's the same format.
So it makes it easy to consume. Right? You can just,
you can line up the spreadsheet next to each other and be like they said, yes,
they said no, they said yes, they said yes.
Right.
It's like, see,
like one of the biggest problems I have
with security is it's like cell phone shopping,
right?
They intentionally, everybody phrases it differently and does it differently.
So it's like, basically impossible to compare
meaningfully.
It sadly is,
you know,
um,
but back to the pen testing thing, I mean, the other, well, the ugly little truth is,
for example, the open source world,
you know, I very few open source projects can
pay for a P
-- test of their software.
-- Most of them can't because a pest is, is expensive.
I don't think, I, actually, I can't think of one that's ever happened.
-- So,
-- actually
that's
not
true. I've heard of a handful of them. I think
I got a proper, I don't know if I call it
A P.
Yeah. Yeah. Ok. Ok. So, yeah, that's true. Yeah, there's been a, yeah, I'm sure if we
Google, there's a handful, but that's my point. Right.
That these are, like, very much the exception to the rule
totally. And the reality is the open source world, you know.
Well,
based on the fact that I've assigned 5000 CV S more
than 5000 CV S now for the open source world,
like, clearly people are reporting bugs with, without even a financial incentive.
Right.
-- And, you know, so
-- this does work.
I read a thing once and I forget who, who wrote this.
But they basically said that
it appears financial incentives
aren't what actually drives people to do the security research.
They, they want to work on interesting things.
Yeah, this is true of a lot of problems.
Um,
there's actually a really good article in
the Economist about this about volunteer versus,
like, paid volunteering.
Uh, and they found that a lot of situations
isn't paid volunteering. Called a job.
Well, yes and no, because they're, they're, well, when they say paid volunteering,
there's different kind of forms of this,
like volunteering with some sort of reward, like either monetary or lunch or
whatever. Right.
But, so they just call it paid volunteering.
But, and I think if I remember right, the example they used was with a ARP, you know,
the, um,
-- what is it, the association of retired people, something
-- like that.
It's, it's an organization when you get old, they,
they automatically stick you in and then you get
cheap dinner.
Yeah.
So, anyways, part of what they had was a program where, you know,
people who used to be like accountants and stuff
would provide like financial advice and tax prep
help and that kind of stuff to other people
that were retired. You know,
because honestly, you know, if you, if you're an accountant doing somebody's like,
what is it in the US?
The 1040. Easy.
Right. It's, it's like a one page tax form
and it
is, you know, so for somebody who's like in the industry, you know,
you can sneeze and you're done,
it's easy. But, you know, to like you and me were like, uh, can I deduct my couch?
You can't do deductions on the 1040 easy.
See,
I have a really funny story is, but a long time ago
I got this,
this terrible letter from the IRS where I used to do my own taxes and I made a mistake
and basically I had a stock sale that occurred and I, I accounted for it incorrectly.
And so when you do that, the IRS assumes
all of the money you make is just income.
Whereas, you know, versus you got what you paid for it minus what you made and blah,
blah, blah, the capital gains.
It's kind of b
and anyway, uh,
they, so they sent me this letter for this ridiculously large tax bill
and I first had a heart attack
and then I started calling accountants being like I need help.
Can you please help me do this? And this was during tax season
and I didn't have a lot of time to send it back in.
Obviously, they all laughed hysterically at me on the phone and then hung up
because, uh, it was, they were already busy and I did my own taxes.
They're like, screw you. We're not touching that. Right. And,
and I kind of get that
and,
you know, there's probably a security lesson than this of, you know,
when you screw something up, like,
competent professionals are not going to help you.
But anyway, uh, so,
you know what I did is I went to the IRS website and I started reading tax code
and
I learned so much. It's for what it's worth. It's bizarrely fascinating.
But, yeah. Yeah, I know way more about us taxes than I ever wanted to because,
and funny enough though I fill everything out.
I sent it back to the IRS and, and I got a letter back basically saying good job,
everything fine.
So I was extremely pleased when that happened
because when I saw the letter come back, I'm like, oh,
I, I hope this isn't like a letter saying they're going to come to my house and,
and audit me to death.
-- But no, they didn't, they didn't. I got out of it,
-- but
back to the volunteering side, what they found was,
was pretty much the minute you started doing sort of paid volunteering.
The number of people willing to do it dropped off dramatically.
I totally believe that.
-- Right,
-- because it's no longer like, oh, I'm gonna volunteer and be nice.
It's like, oh, I'm getting paid, like, three bucks an hour to help people, you know,
screw that.
Yeah. Well, not only that if, if I'm volunteering,
I kind of am willing to deal with more garbage from people, I think,
than if I'm being paid a paltry amount, it's like, not worth it.
Right. Like, just, nope, I'm done
so. And I mean, that's, you know,
so I think part of it is for me, at least, you know, to me, bug bounties are,
it's not a question of will it work?
It's just a question of like, how
well will it work because
it's already been working without money in the, in the open source world,
right? Even not in the open
source world, man. I mean, Microsoft's been getting security reports forever.
Right. Same deal.
I mean,
um,
and more to the point too, I mean,
we've seen this sort of economic model across all industries where,
uh, you know, a good example is a lot of companies don't
invest in research and development nearly as much as they used to
and instead, you know, they acquire start ups.
-- Yeah,
-- it's way cheaper, right. You know, you already know they're successful.
Yeah.
You know, they've, they've gone to some degree of products
that whatever that their magic sauce is.
I totally get that. It makes a lot of sense,
you know,
and that's the reality, right?
As a business, I mean, if I'm only paying for the winners,
you know, like one of the comments on Twitter was like, well with bug bounties,
you're gonna have like a lot of garbage and stuff
to sort through or like a lot of false positives.
-- And it's like, well, not really
-- because you do. You do and, and I want to,
you can outsource
that.
Well, yes.
Now you can, you couldn't before it's hacker one has a thing now where they can do
the triage for you if you want them to, of course, you, you pay for it, but
here's, here's my point to this is
you will get more noise
and,
and the bug body programs are working on eliminating a lot of the noise and silliness
that you naturally get.
And I mean, look, man,
we both dealt with incoming type stuff for various open source projects and it's
the same deal where you've got a guy who's found like a ridiculously pointless issue
and he thinks it's the worst
of sea view requests. I've been uh
plowing through all the requests sent to the uh DWO for the last four months. And like
some of it, I, I've just had to email back very politely.
Like, you know, what on earth are you talking about? Right.
Exactly. And of
course,
they're gonna argue with you
that,
that it's super important and you're an idiot for not understanding that.
Right. And, and this, but here's the deal. Here's what I see is
in the bug bony universe
that is a fixable problem and they're working on it.
Whereas the pest industry is basically it,
it is what it is.
There's not a lot of innovation happening,
there's not a lot of new and exciting things and there's
not a lot of way forward that I can see.
Whereas I think the Bug Bony Universe has a lot of room
to kind of innovate and, and make new and interesting things happen.
-- You know,
-- I've been kind of wondering about pest
because I've always assumed, like, you know,
because traditionally was handcrafted, right?
Like every, every vulnerability is lovingly, you know,
crafts those anymore.
Well, exactly. So it's, it's partially automated.
But then I look at these, you know, like
cross site scripting scan results and like
there's so many false positives,
I
bet it's more than 80% on most automated scanners.
Yeah.
And, and I think part of the problem is, you know,
a lot of these pen testers want to generate a huge report
with a lot of results because that looks like they did something.
Right. Right. Exactly.
You know,
and so I think part of the problem with pen testing is that
we're back to the consultants dilemma of,
do I want to solve your problem or do I want to maximize my billable hours?
No, it's not about, look. Right. That's exactly it is.
When you turn a pen test in that had three issues and granted 33 critical issues,
you'd be taken, you'd be hung out to dry.
Right. You better return a pen test with hundreds of thousands of findings.
Not three.
Exactly.
And so I think the problem is the pest world to some degree is
incentivized against becoming much, much better. I would
a
company like a company like hacker,
one is severely incentivized to become like super efficient web scale Amazon,
you know, whatever
of like, we're gonna handle like 10 billion submissions a minute
and pull out that one piece of, you know, gold.
Yes. Yes, I, I agree with. And actually, you know, it's funny as you bring this up and
I think it's bug crowd is letting open
source projects participate in the bounty program.
And if I had to guess that's a minefield of data
for them to start figuring out how to start automating things.
Well, you know, that's what I found with the DWF with accepting the CV request.
Right. Like
some of them are just flattered insane. Some of them are,
you know, obvious trolls and some of them are like,
actually it's clear that like they're, they're kind of on the right track,
but they need some, you know, hand holding
-- and then some of them are just, like, really good, high quality requests.
-- Right.
Right.
Well, I mean, but this is part of your intent with the DDWF is you'll have
something resembling a rating system where there are people, you know,
you can trust
that if they show up, like you can just hand them out like it's candy and you're fine.
Well, more importantly, also having a way for the, the, well,
the newbies to essentially get the help and
the knowledge that they need so that they,
you know, if they genuinely want to be involved in this and get better at this,
they can,
that's one thing we need is we need a lot more
accessibility and on ramps to becoming a security person
100%.
You know, I, if anybody asked me, how do you become a security person, Kurt,
my answer would be like, uh,
you know, and I get asked that that's
a
fair bit and
it's, it's difficult.
There isn't necessarily a good answer and, and actually I've got something here,
I'm gonna pull up on Twitter
that I really thought was hilarious.
So there was kind of AAA bit of a thread that went on talking about,
you know, what are, what are we gonna do? How, what do we do with new people?
And it started out with, uh, this new guy.
But anyway, it ended up with, uh Steve Christie was involved with.
This is, I think I replied to him. But anyway,
uh, basically
one of the guys in this is he's a freaking see.
So, and he's talking about like, oh, some companies, what do we do?
Where do we find talent?
And I'm like, you, what I mean, you are in the perfect position
to be leading the way on this,
-- but all these security
-- wants to feel mindless.
Well, part of it too is we've, we've gotten to this, you know, um,
especially in North America where companies don't want to pay people
to train them to learn. Right. They,
you know, we,
we literally have ads for jobs where it's like we want six
years of experience in this technology that's like six years old.
You know,
like, they don't, you know,
we want somebody with 10 years experience doing something, you know, entry level.
Right. Yeah. No, I, I know, I know exactly what you mean. Which is, which is madness.
I mean, first of all,
if you do get someone to take that job, they're clearly an idiot.
I mean, I, I, or lying. Well,
you, ok. Yeah, we'll take that.
But
exactly,
you know, you know what it reminds me of as well is I remember when.net came out and,
and it was brand new people, you'd look at job postings and they'd say, you know,
needing five years of.net experience and it's been out for six months.
But then it makes me wonder as well. How many people did it say?
They have five years of.net experience on their, on their
CV. That,
although,
although for what it's worth it get pass hr but any
competent technical person to look at that would be like,
no, absolutely not.
Well, I mean, conversely, the competent technical person is going to know that,
that, you know, the whole thing is just,
I mean, we, those articles were coming out of Google where, you know, they've,
they've taken all the data they've assembled about job interviews
and resumes and everything and found out that doesn't matter.
Right. I mean,
from all the studies I've been reading about because I, you know,
it's something I've become interested in is
sort of on the, I, I'm interested in, how do people get hired?
Because part of what I want is I want the DWF to not only help people be, you know,
become better at security but also then make
them a bit more employable because the reality is
I, this has to be sustainable. So these people need to feed themselves,
you know, and,
you know, and probably so in my mind, at least it's
generally a good idea.
Like, if they're doing sort of volunteer security work,
then it probably makes sense for them to work in the security industry.
So how do I, you know, what can I do to help, make them more hirable, more employable?
Um,
but, yeah, like I said,
from everything I've seen looking at this whole resume interview process thing,
it's basically like a complete crapshoot
where, uh, what was it?
This one study was like,
basically you should just go with whatever your gut says in the first,
like 14 seconds of talking to somebody.
And statistically that that was basically ok.
I believe that
I have hired a lot of people in my day
and I've interviewed tons of people and there've been a lot of folks who
I thought were going to be weak employees that ended up being super strong.
And there were a lot of people who are super strong that quite frankly like,
like they got fired
because they were, they were no good.
And it's, it's hard, man, it's really hard
to
put together a good feel for what a
person's like before you necessarily work with them.
Now, that said though,
the one thing I will say is
it is wonderful when you can look at the open source world
and see what someone is up to
and you can,
their writing, you can look at their responses on email.
You can look at what they're doing on Twitter. You can,
and in fact, for what it's worth. Now, when I look at
people CV S, if,
if you're not on Twitter and you're not involved on github
and you're like, if you're doing nothing, I throw it away because you're,
there's clearly something wrong with you, in my opinion.
Yeah, I've had the same thing where, you know,
people come to me and they want to help with the DWF.
And I'm like,
who are you, like, literally, who are you? Because I can't find you anywhere but
like a profile on
-- linkedin.
-- That's a huge problem in my opinion. I mean, I don't think it's ok.
Well,
and I get that some of these people wanna like their
entry level and they want to start and that's cool and,
and I want to build stuff for them.
But I've also had people who are like, I want to help you formulate policy and stuff.
And I'm like, what?
Yeah, you know, like we're, you know, let's put the cart before the horse kind.
But also like, you know,
who are you? Like, literally like,
and I, I, you know, I've even had the occasion where I've asked you, like,
what do you do in the security industry?
And,
you know, like no answer or some answer. That makes absolutely no sense.
Maybe I just don't business bingo words speak enough. I don't know.
But there is, there is thought leadership pushing synergies. It's fine.
Well, you know,
and it's funny because I have actually met legitimate thought leaders.
No, there's no such thing as a legitimate thought leader.
-- If you call yourself a thought leader, you're dragging out what
-- I was going to say,
every legitimate thought leader I've, I've met or read or heard of
would never call themselves that
-- horribly offended.
-- They're doing other work as well.
-- Like,
-- yeah, you know, like, like schneer,
for example, he is clearly a thought leader in the industry, right? Like a
blog and it's like he says things that I'm like, OK, yeah, I need to think about that.
You know, he's also doing many other things at the same time.
Yeah.
No, these, these people are like, like Dan Walsh and Se Lennox and stuff, you know,
like they're clearly doing work of good value.
-- You know.
-- Right. Right.
Right.
And, you know, you don't have to look them up because it's like, oh,
I already follow this.
Right. And remember kids, friends don't let friends turn off se lens
anyways. I'm not gonna talk about that
for
me.
I think it's still out on my computer. Um,
-- yeah. Anyway,
-- anyway. But, uh, yeah, I mean, that is the thing. Right?
Is like part of the, this industry is, like, how do we, you know,
the biggest problem in security
economically? What I've seen is the lemon problem. How do we,
you know, tell the, the good stuff apart from the lemons and again,
especially with the people, how do we tell, you know,
the visionaries who are a little bit crazy but
very visionary and are going to do something useful
-- against like the crazy snake oil salesman.
-- I think it's hilarious.
You bring this up because actually I'm talking to
some, some sales guys tomorrow
about this exact topic and I put together some slides because the point is
it, it, there are a lot of companies
talking about security
and
there's a lot of people in general
and a
we'll say a nontrivial number of them are full of crap
and it is very difficult
to tell which is which,
and I mean, this is a huge problem in our industry I think is,
I think it's in every industry that,
you know, highly technical and specialized because
unless you have a ton of domain, domain specific knowledge, you know,
he's saying all the right words, it's like car mechanics, right?
Like, I don't know what the heck is up with my transmission control unit.
-- Like he says, it needs to be replaced,
-- right?
Uh You know, you might have a point there is
it, it is probably every industry.
And in fact, you know, funny enough you say this and this is one of, I,
I bought a Toyota as we talked about more than once.
And one of the things that happened was I got something
called Toyota Care with my Toyota and basically for the first Apple
Care, I,
I don't know, I don't know what Apple Care does.
Uh But anyway, I fix
your stuff.
That's basically what it is, right? And, and I get the feeling that
that has certain advantages because when I bring my car into the mechanic,
I don't care because I'm not paying for it and he has no incentive to rip me up.
Right?
-- So
-- Toyota Care literally is Apple Care.
It's like for this period of time we'll just make your car.
It's a couple of years and it's great too because
they include the oil changes and everything. It's fantastic.
Ok. Yeah, see,
and, and that gives a much better customer experience, right? Because like,
you know, the one time I had my uh my iphone,
the speaker on it died and I took it in and the guy swapped it out and brought it down.
He's like he here now it works. And I'm like, no, it doesn't.
He's like, oh, yeah, it doesn't work. Took it back, came back out. 20 minutes later.
He's like, ok, I swapped it again. See it works. And I'm like, no, it doesn't.
He's like, you're right. It doesn't work. That's very weird. He's like,
he's like, well, I'm not going to swap it a third time,
but we can just do a refurb for 100 bucks.
And I'm like, let's do that
and,
you know, five minutes
later
-- didn't test
-- it in the back.
Well, he, I don't know, man, but whatever point is,
you know, like,
because my phone was actually off, like I had Apple Care,
but it was past the Apple Care warranty period.
I see. Otherwise it would have been a free swap
instead. It was $100 swap.
-- And I'm like, you know what, I'm totally fine with that,
-- that box
is worth it,
you know,
-- I totally
-- get it. And that's the thing, right? So
I know as long as my Apple Gear is on Apple Care,
it, it's just, they literally are like, just bring in enough pieces that we can
tell what it was and we'll give you a new one
and if it's off Apple Care, it's like, it's this much for a reaper.
No, I literally asked him. I'm like, what if my kid takes a hammer to it?
And he's like, well, I'll just bring back a bag full of parts.
He's like, it's not the first time it's happened.
I'm like, oh, ok. Then,
so you could, like, cut it in half and I take half, you take half and then we,
uh,
I think it's like a dollar bill. Maybe they look for a part with a serial number.
I would, I would hope so.
Yeah.
But I mean, fundamentally, I mean, that,
that gives the customer a much better experience, right?
Because you and I don't want to actually buy a car. We just want something that works.
I would agree with you 100%. I don't even like cars. So
it is what it is.
But back to the state
and the level of knowledge needed to tell
the bad guys apart from the incompetent guys,
apart from the, well,
meaning incompetent guys apart from the actual useful people.
Yeah, actually that's a really good way to categorize it because you're right.
There are some people who I would say following the end of like evil
and then there are people who are, they have good intentions, but they're,
they're actually gonna make things worse.
And the problem is how do you tell them apart? Because for
example,
there's like, there's that, you know, we're not going to say any names,
but there's a company doing a,
like a cryptographically secure quantum
hardware-based random number generator. Cool. I think that's awesome.
But they're doing a free,
like a free random number generator as a service in the
cloud type deal where you get your random numbers from them.
-- And I'm like,
-- oh, no, no, it's, no, no, it doesn't do that. Actually. Uh, it's Richard
from Whitewood.
Whitewood encryption, right? Or Whitewood cryptography.
Whitewood is the name of their organization.
I talked to Richard at length about this because at first he told me that I'm like,
whoa, dude, that's not cool.
But anyway, what, what it ends up being is they aren't, it's not random numbers,
it's entropy.
And here's the thing with entropy is, is now, this is
what I understand.
I will apologize to anyone who's actually knowledgeable
in this topic for whatever I get wrong.
But the point is uh
in,
in the way entropy works on Linux is you kind of take
entropy from lots of places and you stir it in the pot
and it, it, it turns into, you know, gray paint or whatever, you don't know.
And then that's used to generate random numbers
as part of the random number generator algorithm.
-- And so
-- it
-- was part of the pr NG. Right.
-- Right. Yes. Pseudo
random number. Exactly. Right.
And so apparently
you can like, I can tell you
from
any source safely.
You also have other sources as well.
So you might be, let's say I'm giving you entropy and I know what the entropy is
that doesn't give me any advantages necessarily in terms of understanding what's
going on because you have other entropy sources on the system.
They're just not very good. Well,
yes, they, they exist, they just suck. OK.
They are there. They are bad though.
But here's the thing is just giving you entropy doesn't necessarily let
me know what the internal state of your random number generator is.
And if I don't know what the internal state is
that isn't useful to me.
Now, I, I won't say that it is very conceivable.
There are some crazy attacks that no one's figured out yet around this.
And so personally, I would not necessarily be super
excited
to do this.
If I owned a data center,
I might be excited to have one machine generating entropy and
handing it out to all of the machines I control.
But I would not be excited to be pulling entropy down from the internet.
See, and, and part of me wonders is this just me being old and being like, oh, you know,
it's a security thing and you can't trust some external person and blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah
rum for rum,
you know, or is it legitimately, is there a problem there? And the answer is,
well, yeah, like you said, it's, it's, it's maybe,
maybe not.
If someone with a phd tells me it's OK and then explains it
to me in a way I mostly understood and it sounded legitimate.
I'm willing to say maybe I I would feel better if a handful of other very smart people
with interesting titles,
put some work into explaining what's going on and saying whether it's good or bad.
But
so this
actually
you've just hit on exactly the problem.
We are technically not qualified to
answer those questions,
-- but we're doing it.
-- We don't know. Like, so we don't know. For example, are they evil?
-- Are they? And are they mind eating space lizards?
-- I don't believe
there is a
completely competent and well meaning and totally legit.
Somewhere in the middle.
I think he's that one.
I suspect that. But I don't, you know,
again, I, I can't prove it.
-- I,
-- I spoke with him.
Right. Well, you can't prove anything. Right. You can't prove that I'm not evil.
-- And this is just part of a great plot. I have to,
-- like,
I
know you're evil.
I hope I'm not evil. I'm a nice guy. Come on. You know, I am.
No, you don't.
So
you think squirrels,
squirrels? I hate squirrels so much. Anyway,
anyway,
how
-- can somebody good hate squirrels,
-- squirrels do nothing positive for society.
-- They,
-- they plant acorns that grow into beautiful trees,
whatever they get into my roof and I hate them all.
Uh, so anyway.
Right. Right. I think we just proved our point though is
in terms of sneak
like we are, well, meaning idiots here. Right. We're talking about random numbers.
We're not evil, but like we don't really know what we're talking about.
I mean, that's reality but at best I'm parroting something.
A smart person told me once.
Yeah.
-- Right.
-- Well, and that's part of what gets me is like,
kind of, you know, if somebody,
uh, if somebody essentially, if there's an outcome that is sort of quasi evil,
like somebody, you know, inserts a really nasty bug into the code.
Does it fundamentally matter what their intention was?
Yes and no, I mean, hopefully it, well, I think it matters a bit because, you know,
did they do it repeatedly or just by once, you know, do it
-- accidentally,
-- once we're talking about bug bounties.
-- And
-- that's what I mean, like, so with these bugs and with these things, you know,
again, it's, um,
you know, like, for example,
a bug bounty isn't going to work for a software offender that has like
a bunch of evil people working for them putting bugs in the software.
And,
-- you know,
-- I,
I don't think you can assume that is a reasonable
scenario because if that's true you have some huge problems.
Yeah. Well, exactly. And so again, it goes back to this, I mean,
these people submitting the bugs, I think some of them are totally, well,
meaning just new to the process and they, they,
and they might really have thought that they found a truly world ending bug
and, you know, but they just,
they don't have that experience to get that sense of perspective to be like, oh,
it's not that bad.
I think
anyone participating in a bug bounty program is going to be fundamentally.
Well, meaning
because if you are, if you have an ulterior motive,
you're not going to use the bug monty program.
Well, there are people that do try to gain the system.
-- There
-- will
-- always be that and, and I think those people are, are borderline.
I would be willing to put them in the neutral
camp probably because I don't think they're legitimately evil,
but they don't necessarily have positive intent.
It is up to the bug bounty program to find and stop people gaming their system. Right.
Well, see,
because I have this problem with CV assignments is
there are people who want to gain CV assignments
to get as many CV S as possible to their name.
Yes.
And so there are some ways to game the system.
I'm not going to say what they are because
they
are doing it and they will make my life a living misery.
Folks. You can game the system.
Well, you can game,
that's the nature
-- of system
-- and that's just it. Right. If there are rules, you can get around them.
And actually this is one of the things that I really like is,
were you, uh, we, we, we had that meeting or, uh, uh, yeah,
it was a team meeting one time on that Red Hat.
You were there. You
were,
you
-- were it was one of those, it was one of those games. I'm
-- actually,
because I didn't think of that.
It was one of those games where, where essentially you, the idea was, uh,
we got a bunch of parts and we had to build a tower
and whoever had the,
the ball, like you had a ball, a little ball, golf ball or something
and whoever's,
I don't know, whatever, it doesn't matter,
whoever's ball was like, farthest from the, the floor or something won.
And so, uh, we literally did nothing but screw around for, for like 15 minutes.
So everyone else built towers and then, uh, one of us ran upstairs with our ball
when they said time's up
and, and we clearly won by breaking the rules. Right?
-- And, and of course, well, the rules
-- haven't been clarified
properly, right.
And that was, well,
so funny enough that's kind of the intent to make people think cleverly.
But as, as I was speaking with the organizer of this,
he was going to refine the rules for certain groups like us
because,
and, and, and this also makes me think of the, like, underhanded c competition
where basically how whoever won it or, or however it's been won in the past.
Like now there's a rule that says you can't do that,
right? Because,
and that's kind of how this has to happen is
as people are found to be gaming the bug bounty,
you just say, all right, now this is a rule and you can't do that
and, and that works. I mean, it works
well,
but sometimes there's systems where you can't change certain fundamental rules
and so they just can be abused. And that's, you know,
I'm going to disagree with that.
I'm going to say that if you have a fundamental rule and you can't get it fixed,
you have, you're just fundamentally broken at that point.
You need to rethink your entire model.
Yes and no. See, part of the problem is the rules aren't entirely up to me.
Well, in your case for, for CV E, right?
Because I mean, you have to work with Miter as well, but in the case of
the
hacker one, hacker one is in charge of their own destiny,
right?
I mean,
yeah, just change rules if someone's abusing a change of rules
and that's kind of why I see that as,
-- that's not an excuse of why bug bunnies are bad because not
-- at all.
I mean,
if anything bug bounties are currently immature,
but I would say that almost all tech,
uh,
you know, we clearly,
I mean, you know, well,
I certainly wouldn't drive, you know,
like when you look at the state of self driving cars, for example, it's like, no,
we still have a ways to go.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, we do.
I mean, you know, I would say the tech industry in general is still, you know,
we're maturing because for example, we still can't, you know,
write a web browser that doesn't reliably, like,
you know, do something horrific when it encounters a weird web page.
We've been at that for 20 years. So
I know you gotta love it.
We're getting there though.
We are getting there and, I mean, let's, let's bring it home. It's, it's time.
I,
yeah, I, I guess the beauty of it is
for those of you listening, who've made it this far,
who haven't smashed the computer in a fit of rage is
I'm not opposed to a pen test. And if I had to pick between the two,
I would pick a pen test if I can only pick one
because I think it is the current industry standard for the way things work and, and
you understand what you're going to get.
I do think eventually the pest will evolve into the bug bounty,
but
we have a long way to go until that happens.
I think it's inevitable because,
you know, some of these bug bounties were paying like decent money, like 5, 10 grand
and in a lot of parts of the world, you know,
-- that you can make a living doing a couple of those a year.
-- I'm unsure if that's the
true for everybody.
-- But, but anyway,
-- it, it would have to be true for everybody.
Just a sub, like a small enough subset that they actually do it.
Uh,
yeah. Yeah. Ok. That's fair.
Anyway. Anyway, let's take it home, man. It's time.
Thank you everyone for listening. Thank you, Kurt for the
crazy conversation as always, which I love
if you want the,
there's not a lot of show notes,
but if you're interested in them or more importantly,
if you wish to yell at Kurt or myself
via social media, you can find links.
That's right.
The Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag
You are welcome to Hit us up on Twitter and tell us why we're wrong.
We love hearing about that.
Anyway, you can go to the, uh, open source security podcast.com website.
We've got the links there. We'll have the show notes there
and
if nothing else, Kurt,
you have a fabulous day and I cannot wait for the hate mail we're going to get.
Yeah, I'm gonna go shovel snow.
I
thought it was spring.
We got like 23 more days of snow coming.
Happy spring, Kurt.
Happy spring.
All right. Bye bye.