Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself.
Kurt Siefried and my partner and old timey radio shenanigans. Josh Pressers.
Yeah.
Well, it's not very old timey. I mean, all the topic, all the things you pasted.
We are old. Well, we're old
but all of the radio based stories you put into the show notes are not old at all.
-- Uh, Tetra is old,
-- sadly it's still in use.
-- But
-- what else are you going to replace it with? Like,
-- nothing,
-- you know,
and it's a good, it's a good,
so it's
ok. What is Tetra? Tetra is terrestrial trunked radio? So
fun fact, if you want to send a radio signal 100 kilometers,
right. It's expensive and difficult
nowadays, 20 years ago, like, you better have a car to haul that thing
is impossible.
So, the idea was
what if we basically have something that's kind
of like a cell phone but longer range,
lower quality and can also like locally mesh up well, like a radio.
So basically the way it works is you have a pretty standard radio.
But locally, you know,
if you're in the next room you can hear me or a block over whatever.
And if I kind of want to make like, a longer call to control or whatever, well, I just,
it trunks
to a terrestrial station
and then I can, you know, go talk to my boss who's sitting in some other city.
It's not just for that though.
It's also lets, like, the fire department talk to the police department,
even though they have completely distinct radio systems,
it allows them to interoperate by essentially like
whatever system I'm using
talks to the same ground station that whatever system you're using,
talks to the ground station,
that's
essentially it's a reinvention of a network of networks
also known as. Right. Well, no, but seriously,
so Tetras a good system and of course,
it had encryption because you don't want people listening to the policemen and
all that.
And of course, that encryption was
private and hidden and it turns out to have probably not been very good. Like,
who knew?
-- I know. Right. I'm so shocked
-- that secret encryption
is bad.
Yeah. So, and in line with that though, we also have the GPS thing.
So apparently GPS around Iran is being jammed and,
or spoofed and they've almost want like
-- boof
-- mostly it sounds like.
Well. Ok. So,
all right, I'm going to admit to a felony. I own a GPS jammer.
I bought one off of a rather dodgy
Hong Kong website a long time ago.
And what was fascinating? Ok.
So what's fascinating to me about GPS is that it works because
it is
barely above the noise floor.
The like galactic radio
-- signal echo from the Big Bang. Basically the
-- cosmic microwave background,
the
cosmic microwave background that like those guys that
bell ran into when they were trying to,
you know,
make stuff work.
It's the pigeon poop. Oh, wait, no, it's a Nobel Prize.
-- It's a fine
-- line,
but an important one.
So what gets me is like, yeah, I mean, because these satellites are
not big and it's not like they have some giant like nuclear reactor on them to,
you know, crank up the radio
power on the transmitter.
So like the radio transmitter on those things is like, it's not strong.
And so the fact that,
you know, thanks to the magic of digital signals processing,
we can actually pick out those signals and like, tell you where you are
to within a high degree of accuracy. So
I tried out my GPS jammer on a couple of different GPS things I owned back in the day.
Ok. And
some failed the way I expected them to,
which is they lost the GPS lock and just kind of went
and like
I
would,
but that's not how all of them failed.
One of them started drifting sideways at over 1000 kilometers an hour.
Oh, that seems normal.
-- Right.
-- And I was like, what now? Huh?
And it like, literally, I it was totally 100% reproducible.
I would turn it on and it would sort of get confused and then it would just start,
it would just go
like a, like a plane and I'm like, ok, that was, that's weird.
So, the thing is when, when you say
I, I
don't know that it needs to be GPS, spoofing,
GPS jamming could result because here's the reality.
Have we ever really, truly extensively tested this and published the results?
No,
I mean, probably not.
Well, for one thing, it's, you know, you gotta get like a special,
all sorts of licensing from the SEC to do this in
the US which like the US Navy does all the time,
right?
Like
they send out those no dams
airman saying like GPS in the San Francisco region will be like kind of
screwed up for a few days because the US Navy is doing something.
It's a
thing.
So,
and then related to that is Apple is apparently there's rumors
like the kind that get reported on slash dot
About them putting an in house cellular modem
on their like system on a chip.
I mean,
yeah,
that doesn't, they already have
like cellular modems in the iphone
and ipads, for example. So I don't feel like this is a, is a huge stretch.
The one thing though, they buy them from Qualcomm today
where they're talking about building it themselves.
They've been talking about for like a decade now
-- and still haven't done what's
-- fascinating to me is
I love to find my iphone
and stuff. Ecosystem. Right. Like we have
a collar that holds a little air tag.
So when he disappears under the deck you can find.
Right.
You know, I love that. I can,
where's my ipad?
And I can make it ping. I can know exactly where it is.
Same with my son's, you know, phone, we left it once at a mcdonald's,
it fell out of his pocket and I know exactly where to go to get it.
And it would be nice to have that level
of accuracy with my laptops because they're not cheap.
I mean,
would, would, having a cellular modem in it necessarily accomplish that though.
Well, yeah.
Right. Because it would have better.
The thing you're forgetting is it's not about the location,
-- it's about working when the device is turned off.
-- I mean, that's all apple magic.
I don't, I mean, that doesn't necessarily mean they'd support that though.
You're taking a huge leap.
I suspect they would because that's kind of one of
the big use cases because how often have people?
Have we heard those stories of, like, my iphone was stolen?
And I'm like, hey, policeman, it's right over here.
Like, can we go up, can you go get my phone back and arrest these people,
like those people who put air tags in their luggage?
Right. And, like,
lead the person, you know, or the,
I love the people who put air tags and things and then, like,
they mail it or it's in their luggage or whatever and then they track it as it travels.
Like the world. It's so amusing.
It's so good. Ok.
Anyway, how are we going to tie all of this together from a security context?
What's fascinating to me is it's, we now live in a world
where I can affordably stick
a small computer system on a chip with a baseband modem
that runs at a low enough power.
But when the device is off, making air quotes here off,
it is still communicating with the cell network and
telling it where it is and what's going on
and it's drawing a low enough amount of battery that it, that's fine.
It doesn't really matter.
And
I think this has some really interesting
implications because like, one thing I've always wondered about, like,
for example,
my sister
and her husband bought a car from Germany and had it shipped over here
and it got lost
elastic. I'm like,
well, they didn't lose it,
lose it. It's, it's like my luggage. Like we didn't lose your luggage.
We just don't know where it is.
Right? And it'll pop up in a few days or weeks and it did, right.
The car eventually popped out of the system.
But I'm like,
man, I'm like,
that's an expensive item that might be like I can track my pizza in real time.
Why can't we track this asset. That's like
almost six figures.
I,
because like my cell phone does it, my ipad does it,
my laptop sort of does it. But like my car,
I have an airtag in my car. And actually,
it was funny because the San Francisco Police
Department just stated that you should put an
air tank in your car to track your car when it gets stolen because like,
we don't really care.
But in fairness it's easier and faster
because
we even work in a parking garage underground because
as long as somebody walks by it with an iphone
it'll later ping off the system and
there's my car.
I mean. Right. Ok.
I want to reframe this in a different way.
I think that it, I'm gonna hope is more interesting
and it's all radio related, right?
Radio even, I think a decade ago or more
was this
magic thing
that was out of the realm of
access and usability by nearly every person.
Yeah, we had cell phones but it still wasn't near what it is today.
Like, freaking everything has a wireless chip.
Now,
there's a guy with a Christmas house decoration by my
kids school and he broadcast music on 105 point whatever.
And I was like, did you have to get a license for that? Like, are you a ham guy?
And he's like, no, it's low enough power that I can just do it. Yeah.
-- Yeah,
-- that's, that's always been like that you could,
you could buy actually. Do you remember back in the day
-- when F
-- M Bluetooth to FM transmitter for your car?
-- No, no,
-- no, no, no, no, not even that.
So back in the nineties
there were,
let's say you had a CD, a walkman or a disc, man,
I guess they were for people who don't know, this is a portable CD player.
-- You could bring places because that was a big deal.
-- 10 seconds of anti
skip technology.
If you were lucky, you had 10 seconds of anti skip,
which I'm not even going to explain, go look it up.
But anyway,
there was the tape.
If, if you were lucky enough to have a car with a cassette tape player,
you could get those weird tapes on the wire thing, you'd stick in the tape player,
plug it into your CD player and then you could listen to C DS in your car,
which is magic.
Now, if you didn't have a tape player in your car, as I did not,
you could buy a transmitter from Radioshack that would transmit,
you plugged the transmitter into the CD player and
then you had to put the transmitter very,
very, very close to the car antenna
which was like in the corner of you.
Obviously, back in these days, we had a literal antenna on the, on the car,
you'd occasionally drive past somebody and you'd hear like,
because it,
they also had one
but anyway, so,
like those transmitters have been around for a long time and granted,
they were terrible in the nineties and didn't work very well.
But
the, the point is
if we look at where we are today, right,
we have the ability to take something like flipper, zero, the flipper zero, the,
the tetra look, cracking tetra a decade ago,
out of the question. Even if you knew the algorithm was crap. Yeah.
-- there's like no way you could have done it,
-- right.
The thing is you need a software to find radio just a hard,
it's like having a network sniffer probe thing
like 20 years ago. That was,
-- that was just completely magical,
-- not just that
you can buy a freaking
TV tuner
that is a USB adapter for the,
these things are like you can get them
for literally $20 and they're very functional,
not as good as the expensive ones.
And you have a software defined radio and
you can sniff an enormous amount of radio spectrum
just with that stuff, right? It is absolutely amazing. The concept of jamming gps.
And here's the thing,
they're jamming gps near Iran.
It could literally be a Rando doing this now, right.
Potentially a decade ago, it would have unquestionably been
a nation state doing it because no one else had that resource. Now anyone could do it.
It
is mind
boggling and amazing.
Well, but what's also interesting to me is Iran should know of all the people,
you know, that GPS guided drones are a potential hazard,
probably what they've been selling them to Russia.
You know, and, and apparently, like, around the Crimean area and everything, like,
there's pretty near constant on off GPS jamming
from the Russians and the Ukrainians because,
yeah,
because I was thinking about it.
How do you know where you are?
Right. There's a couple of ways to figure it out. Why you look around.
Well, yeah, you look around for and that's how the,
that's how the original Tomahawk cruise missiles worked right
there.
Well, they didn't have GPS, my friend,
they had terrain guidance mapping
and
that's why they didn't work in the,
in the first Gulf War is because they were built for like Europe
where you had hills and churches and other landlords to look at,
which works fine in western Europe.
Right. There's lots of churches everywhere. They're pretty distinctive
-- and in the desert, not so much in the
-- desert, the sand dunes move around.
You can't like
a dune here today isn't going to be there in a week. It's gonna move,
which is
so
you can look for where you are and that can work. If you have landmarks.
Like if you're standing next to the Eiffel Tower,
-- you're probably next to the
-- Eiffel Tower.
You can see it wherever you
-- in the city. It's marvelous
-- number two,
inertial reference. So you can know where you started.
I took four paces forwards, two to the left,
three north. And you should know where you are.
-- I
-- mean, yeah, the good old fashioned gyroscope navigation. Right.
And there's like,
nist has a thing where they want to get those down to a cubic centimeter with a,
you know, circular of probability of X and Y.
Well, things like submarines and stuff that you just can't,
you're just going to the freaking moon, like.
Yeah.
Right. So, what's the third way?
Well, the third way is something like GPS where,
which is a form of looking around where you are.
Really?
Yeah, that's fair.
That's fair.
But you're just,
you're able to see something that you can't see because it's transmitting,
it's broadcasting.
But as we've covered, you know, the radio signal, not very strong.
And so
what gets me is how critical GPS is for everything?
Like you want your pizza, that guy better have GPS or he's gonna get lost.
Well, I think all,
actually, it's funny
you say that because I was talking to one of my kids the other day and they were like,
how did people deliver pizzas before you had GPS?
They,
they had a map,
they had a map on the wall
and they would figure out where they had to go. It was nuts. But anyway,
I, I don't think it's just GPS.
So, Kurt, you look at all of this radio technology that exists and it, it,
it fuels the model
world now.
I mean, you think the,
what the internet did
to all of us a decade ago is what wireless is starting to
do to us now where we have access to enormous amounts of location,
information and data
and literally anything we could want
-- all the time and it's become normal
-- and even simpler things. I mean, I,
I don't think I've seen a security system now
that's wired anymore because
like, wires are expensive and hard to run,
you know,
and I actually just got a notification. My front doorbell needs new batteries
but, or, uh,
yeah, the front door lock, not the doorbell,
the doorbell is actually wired up to the 12 volt circuit.
So I just, I really wish I could do that for my front door lock because it, every,
every month or two, especially in winter when it's cold,
the batteries just instant death
batteries don't like the cold.
-- That's kind of how it works.
-- But what gets me is that it actually works,
right. Like, we had some issues.
We, I hadn't and nobody had ever thought to rebalance the,
the Wi Fi channels at the CS A office
-- and they were having some minor,
-- nobody. It's your job.
-- Like I'm
-- remote, I just assumed one of them was doing it.
So anyways, but what's funny is as bad as it was,
it was only noticeable because it would, like,
glitch during a video conference for like 1/10 of a second.
And that was the worst fail of it. And of course,
that as actually is unacceptable because like,
it's really not great to try and be presenting and be glitching,
rebalance the channels and it basically went away
and, you know, in the long term, we'll probably move to, um, well,
we'll move to the Wi Fi 66 gigahertz
once we have people with devices that can actually use it
because right now it's all 2023 and later Mac devices.
-- So
-- it's
-- like
it's really good. Actually, it's scary good when you use Wi
-- Fi six,
-- I have Wi
Fi 62.4 and five gigahertz here.
And the slow spots are now 100 megabits per second.
Uh Yeah,
-- and the fast spots are 600. Uh
-- you go way above that with
the,
I don't have any client devices that are new enough to do six gigahertz.
-- I
-- am, you know, funny enough, the laptop I use right here that runs Linux
has Wi Fi six
-- but I only, it only works when I run windows.
-- So Wi
-- Fi six or Wi Fi six with 66
-- with six gigahertz.
-- Like it's got the real deal on it and it's amazing
-- because that's a confusing thing,
right?
Is every time I'm like, I'm dealing with Wi Fi six, I'm like,
I have to check the spec sheet because Unify, for example,
makes a PS that are Wi Fi six but not six gigahertz.
Yeah. Yeah. No, No, it's,
-- anyway,
I'm looking forward to it because I have stucco on the outside of my house.
What does stucco get mounted on a metal mesh
if you're lucky?
So, I have a metal mesh surrounding my house.
It's
a,
prior
to wi
fi
65 gigahertz. My backyard was like three megabits. Now. It's like 100.
But, um,
yeah, it's, I,
I am looking forward to six gigahertz because
it should apparently just go through that,
like
a hot knife through butter. It's a good question. I don't know.
So,
anyway, the smaller the, the, the, the,
the higher the frequency of the transmission,
the more stuff it kind of punches through, like, look at x rays
-- because it's higher energy.
-- It's
anyway. All right,
a
broad rule of thumb.
That's fair. That's fair.
It's,
yeah, I know. It's complicated. But as a generalist
-- for the purposes of getting a good signal in my backyard, it's true.
-- Ok. That's fair.
That's fair. It's very close.
-- It, it should work well
-- and, and funnily enough,
that's actually one of the big benefits also of using six gigahertz and stuff.
And the beam steering is that
you then instead of broadcasting in a 360 degree
space, y
your beam steering,
your beam steering and
you actually
do
transmit less and broadcast less. And so there's less pollution of the spectrum
can
-- use
-- it.
Let's hope so.
Yeah.
Yeah, probably we'll see. I don't know.
We'll see, the devices are still spewing garbage in all directions. But
anyway,
-- well, that's true. The clients are, but
-- the
access points are, are, are more powerful. I don't know. Anyway. All right.
-- Well, the access
-- points have a better antenna because they're bigger.
Well, obviously,
ok,
so I want us to get back to all the security and all of this race
and everything.
I love that.
Here's the thing. How do you prevent data exfiltration
if every system has a built in broadband modem that you can't turn off?
I mean, and so that's actually one of the many concerns, right?
And this is very, very true of like any computer today
because every computer has Wi Fi built into it. Right?
-- And so you just have to assume if an attacker
-- but you can sort of turn it off.
It's all software though, right? You can't turn a lot of this stuff off.
-- But,
-- I mean, with the base band chips as we've discovered in cell phones,
you, it's on even if the device is turned off
-- in,
-- in, in many instances. Yes.
And I think this is where from an intelligence agency perspective, this is a huge
conversation and concern, I think.
Right? For like you and I,
whatever, like my computers are always connected to the internet.
So it's not like a huge concern I have and let's face it.
If someone with those capabilities is after me,
I have no hope. Right. This is the classic. Massad versus not Massad argument.
I would hope they would just cut you a check for free
50 grand rather than spending the 50 grand covertly entering your house.
Why would they cut me a check for 50 grand?
Well, because, you know, then they also can blackmail you.
It's going to take more than 50 grand to blackmail me. Kurt.
-- How many bags of cheesy would it take?
-- I don't know. We'll see, we'll see.
Actually, you know what's funny is I ordered some off Amazon.
Yeah, I can buy cheesy off Amazon.
They sell, I mean, you can buy everything off Amazon but
they're expensive. But I don't,
I mean, it was the same price I paid at the Vancouver airport at that time
but,
and then I bought them and then my family ate almost all of them.
I need to start selling cheeses with Amazon. Wow,
that
is,
I mean, I don't know, I don't know what they're supposed to cost
a 420 g package for $18.
That is not what I'm paying at Costco.
I mean, they sell them at Costco. I'm
so jealous. Where do you think I buy them?
I
don't
know that
I get that
-- giant bag with all the little tiny bags because I
-- want, yeah, that's the one I got.
-- I got the giant bag with all the little tiny bag.
-- What did you pay
for it?
I paid $45 for that.
Uh, I'm gonna say like, I think 17,
what? Holy crap. That's cheap
corn
meal and cheddar.
But
no, it's not just that cheesy are the best thing ever.
And if they weren't, I wouldn't pay $45 for junk food.
So, uh, sorry, um, uh, 36 by 36 g is $26.
$26. That's Canadian dollars and
it's like
18,
that's like $2.54. So
anyway, I wish.
But yeah, no Costco sells the giant bag with the 36 little
bag,
which is
so they stay fresher
because once you open that bag of cheesy,
they actually do go stay.
That's not my problem. My problem is I will eat all of the cheesy,
regardless of the size of the bag I open.
That's how ches
work. So if I eat a small bag, I don't eat a lot of cheesy. I open the big bag.
I eat a lot of cheesy and I'm like, oh,
I wish I hadn't eaten them all and then I go look for more cheesy.
But
anyway, anyway, ok,
I want to talk about
security of radio and just all this stuff and, and tie it all up. Right.
-- I'm
-- not
-- even sure.
Like I'm, we're at a point where, for example, from the CS A office
there are over four or 500
other Wi Fi clients and
-- a PS visible.
-- That's fine though. Who cares? We, we've solved Wi
Fi
But my point is
if I'm looking for a covert transmitter,
how do I look for a covert transmitter
when there's 500 things shouting
within
two blocks of the office?
I mean, look, you could do it if you needed to and you had the right gear like ham radio.
People have had this ability for literally decades.
Well, there's actually apps for android and stuff now,
that kind of replicate it to a degree, maybe
not bad.
Well,
you don't get as much directionality but you do get the signal strength and stuff.
Sure, sure, sure.
The problem is you can't do this on Apple because
you don't get to touch the hardware that way.
That's probably fair.
And I, who cares? You don't look if this is,
it is a legitimate concern you have, which I don't think it should be.
If this is a legitimate concern you have,
you're dealing with an attacker with capabilities
probably beyond anything.
-- You can truly defend
-- against one of those $20 USB
cables that has a built in Wi Fi transmitter,
but you're still dealing with an attacker that almost certainly has abilities.
You cannot counteract,
I think. And that's the thing with all of this radio stuff, right?
Like Tetra burst is part of this story is tetra burst was created
at a time when the only people who could basically break this
were people that didn't need to break it,
right?
Because they already had probably access to all this data anyway, that was going on.
And I think when we think about radio,
it's very similar,
I think to like someone sniffing internet traffic where
you can apply TLS to your internet traffic,
you can, there's a certain amount of stuff you can do.
But fundamentally, there are Attackers
that have capabilities beyond our imaginations and we can't stop them.
It's kind of like,
remember all the research talking about how if you looked at SSH packet,
you could figure out passwords people were typing in
that is an attacker with a capability. I cannot stop.
Well, except now that,
that used to be hard. And now
as long as I can get traffic, I can just feed it through an A I,
you
can get the traffic, you're already in a point where I can't functionally take,
I would say good defense against you.
But part of the challenge here, for example,
the OMG Elite Cable is 100 and 80 bucks retail,
right?
And that's not a ton of money.
No, it's not.
But here's the thing, I'm not just talking about nation State Attackers.
I'm saying
if someone has an OMG cable and they know how to properly use
it and they can get into your organization and plug it in,
you can't stop them
like, and, and that's ok. I'm not saying
it's good or bad necessarily or I'm dumb or they're smart or, or what, what not,
right?
It's just, it's one of those things that
I think in many attacker, defender relationships,
there's always going to be a skew in one direction or the other. I would say
asymmetry.
Yeah, an asymmetry. That's better. Right.
You're looking for asymmetry, like,
like it'll always be cheaper for me to throw a brick through
your window at your house than for you to defend it.
Right. For sure. Right. Right.
Yeah, I could put, you know,
a bunch of metal bars on my window and now
I can't see out my window and life is terrible.
Right. Like for sure,
there's always that and I think all of this wireless,
everything that everyone keeps talking about is a very similar situation.
Like
let's pick on the flight jamming
for Airlines.
Airlines should not be relying on civilian GPS. Right.
Well, and that's the thing, right? There's so there's GPS, there's GLO,
there's the Chinese one whose name I can never remember.
There's the terrestrial radio stations like the one in Hamburg
that broadcast a signal like the old uh us Loran
system, you know, at,
at
various points on the coast.
And then in theory, like I get that a,
a small private plane might not have an inertial guidance system, but, you know,
something like a 737 and up should
maybe have one
maybe.
Well,
because GPS does go down or glitches or weather or
part of the challenge too is the skills atrophy,
right?
Like most people cannot navigate, given a map and a compass
and, and I was guilty of this too. I was at a playground.
I was at a playground and they had the thing pointing
north and it was off by 25 or 30 degrees.
And I'm like, oh, that looks pretty bad.
And then I actually checked the magnetic deflection here in Edmonton.
And it's like, oh, no, that's actually correct. That is because I live so far north.
Like our, our
north and our magnetic north are off by like 30 degrees.
Everyone's is off by quite a bit now because the, the north pole is moving.
Well, it wanders about 100 m a year since forever.
And there's like a beautiful map where it's just kind of like, do, do, do, do,
do,
do.
But the skills atrophy people aren't even aware
of that because they just rely on GPS.
And if GPS stops working
below a compass,
-- they're gonna walk into a lake or something.
-- No, they're not.
Like if you're using a compass, you just
look, the compass tells you like north is that ish direction, right?
Like that's, that's what it's for.
It's so when you're walking in a straight line, you walk in a straight line,
that's really all the compass is good for.
Well, and also for figuring out where you are, like, look at a landmark, take a shot,
compare your map,
right? Like, but nobody,
so, but what gets me is like, nobody knows how to do that,
including probably a lot of airline pilots and who cares.
-- They don't need to know how to do that. Well,
-- unless they're flying near Iran
they almost, apparently some planes almost wandered into Iranian airspace.
-- Which
-- that would be bad. I bet.
Well, I mean, they did sort of air quote again,
accidentally shoot down that airliner.
That was,
you know.
Yeah,
it was a thing in Canada because we were grumpy about it
again.
Putting all of this together. Right.
I think
there are security threats we can legitimately deal with and there's some,
we can't, and I think as humans,
we do a terrible job of obsessing over the dumb things.
I think
an example being if flying near Iran is causing GPS problems,
the solution in almost every instance is just, don't fly near Iran.
-- Yeah,
-- but you can't because you got to fly from A to B and Iran's in the way or
you have to just
go
around it.
Ok.
So you say that and yet there are almost every
flight in Canada to and from Toronto goes through us airspace
and so we have to submit passenger list to you guys and
when everybody was in an uproar about that and they're like,
why don't you just fly in Canada and the airlines are like,
that'll add like 10 minutes to the flight and cost this millions of dollars
a year.
But then that means if you have and this is a perfect example, right?
Saying
I'm taking this action and it's costing me this right.
This is a very this is the the security equation every time
where by doing this, it's costing me this right?
Or by not doing this, it could cost me this Canada
having to fly to the US and submit passenger list to us.
Authorities is the price you pay to do that,
but there's other savings elsewhere, right?
If you need to fly near somewhere that is known to be blocking gps or,
or spoofing it or whatever
that means, you need a way to deal with that.
Now,
it sounds like from what I read in the article
and I'm not an aviation expert by any means,
but it sounds like they just call flight control and say
-- where
-- are we?
And flight control says
here you
transponder
and that's great the solution, right? Maybe, maybe that's good enough.
Maybe it's not,
maybe you need something else.
But the
one challenge there is, for example,
there was talk of movement towards transponders that
you don't know where they are.
The transponder in theory knows where it is and reports where it is,
which is currently how most radar works.
It's not the old timey World War Two radar where it like paints the target and
gets a return and says like,
oh there's a plane over there moving at the speed and height and whatever
modern radar is like, I ping your transponder and your transponder replies with,
hey, yeah, I'm me at this flight level.
-- Maybe. I don't know.
-- How else do you get the four numbers off? Right.
I mean, well, yeah, the numbers for sure.
But, you know, I would assume the radar station decides where it is
sometimes, but not really because
-- it's expensive and hard to manage and maintain. Well, it
-- is.
And again, you have that trade off. Right? Like is the trade off worth it?
I don't know.
This is again where we talk about, you know, securing
terrestrial radio between
police and fire and stuff. So Tetra burst has been hacked.
Anyone can decode the messages.
Well, not, I wouldn't say hacked. It's just we actually published how it works.
And if that can,
it's very hackable.
The, the,
the algorithm they use is crap because it's like very old and it was
created in secret and almost every encryption
algorithm created in secret is terrible.
I was going for it.
It's was created in secret. So right there, that's a huge black market.
And number two, it's 20 years old. Like I'm sorry, but even
it's like Des Three, Des Three was pretty decent.
And ok for the time, except everybody got laptops now with, you know, five gigahertz
what was 20 years ago? Like
-- 1000 bit Rs A maybe
-- 20 years ago was, remember eff building deep crack.
And
I
remember that
was like
-- $100,000
-- the 60 five bit key was cracked by us in a month
and it's like, I think my laptop will do it
basically,
-- which is fine. That's how progress works.
-- Yeah.
But the problem is,
do you know what it's gonna cost to replace all those tetra radios?
Well, no, no, no, here's ok. That's just it. Right.
And this is what we're gonna close on.
The cost is substantial.
But does it really matter?
And the answer in almost every situation is it doesn't,
if someone can listen to the police department talking in all seriousness,
I think that's probably a good thing.
I don't think it's a bad thing.
I
see the problem I always have.
And this goes, for example,
a great argument when people start talking about police body cams.
I am generally in favor of transparency and for example, police body cams,
but they do get into situations where you don't want that stuff ever being public.
I think there are instances of that, but I I
this is a much larger discussion we're not going to have today.
There, there is certainly victims rights. There's, there's pieces of that,
but I think generally speaking, what's happening over radios
doesn't need to be a secret.
I would, I suspect in most instances the,
the data traveling over a voice radio as used by Tetra
burst
is not going to make the world the worst place.
In fact, encrypting it might make it worse.
Well, I feel like more to the point,
the majority of criminals are probably not going to be listening to it.
Like that used to be a thing sometimes. But,
you know, like the movies with the, you know, the bank robber sitting in the car,
I'm skeptical
that was ever a legitimate concern.
It's, well, it's one of those things where it,
it's happened enough that we have some anecdotal evidence for it.
-- But like, is it a problem? I suspect,
-- I doubt it. I seriously doubt it. So, anyway,
and I think this is a perfect example. Right?
The, the, the cost of fixing tetra burst versus the cost of keeping it
is completely lopsided
and someday it'll something better will happen and come out.
But for the foreseeable future, whatever,
they're just going to keep using it because it works and
they've had probably billions of dollars invested in radio equipment,
tens of billions
in
the base stations, the radio equipment, everything.
And
when you look at what
organizations spend on radio equipment that need to spend on radio equipment,
it's actually quite shocking.
Well, no, it's not at all. I think this is a good example.
-- I would
-- have
thought it would be cheaper, but like,
I guess it's also stuff that you can drop and flush down the toilet.
This isn't consumer grade equipment. This is like essentially industrial grade.
-- These guys are IP 68. You can't
-- say
no
one knows what you're
doing
-- is holding up a radio.
-- I'm holding up a walkie talkie.
I bought these for, uh, actually for skiing
because they have a, uh, 16
Ketter range.
They work reasonably well in the mountains. They're IP 68
uh,
which is important if you're skiing because
it's going to be outside and getting snow
on it.
And they were not that expensive. They were less than 100 bucks each.
Yeah. And that's those radios. I would not trust my life with in any way.
-- But I mean, I just,
-- here's my favorite example of this, right?
It's where people mock like the military for spending so much money on stuff,
let's say, right?
But at the same time, this is a situation where this piece of hardware fails,
someone dies.
-- Are you going cheap out on that? Like, I hope not
-- or worse? The, the attack fails.
Well, then they probably die like
it changes the equation substantially when it goes from this minorly
inconveniences me to this will literally kill me if it fails.
Well,
my favorite is I was just watching a history of the Battle of Midway and there was
the Japanese apparently should have scouted the American forces,
but there was cloud cover and the guy flying the,
the one scale plane there was like 10 or so of them going, you know, in a radio pattern.
He was above the clouds and didn't see the US task force. Oh, interesting.
Oops.
Like it literally that could we could have different history books if
that one pilot had seen share a ship's wake or something.
And like that's what gets me is if you read military history,
there are some insane levels of, like,
just for want of a nail, right? The battle was lost.
Yeah, I mean, that happens all the time for sure. Yep.
So I'm just looking at this with this radio stuff
is,
I do wonder, you know, will anything major happen from this? Right.
Because we've had all these like log for J, I mean, as big a deal as log for Jay was like,
I would argue there's a bunch of ransomware,
exploiting six month old vulnerabilities.
That's way more impactful.
Yeah, I mean, that's always how it works and I think anything we talk about,
especially like in the radio space.
Yeah, it's exactly the same story
that it's, it's the crap that's six years old. No one's patched
and, and that's far more impactful than someone worrying about apple, putting
a, a
radio in a chip in a Macbook. So
anyway, it's, it's funny and we'll end it on that note.
But it's just, I think the fact that like,
it's always the dumb stuff, no one worries about. That's actually impactful.
All this freaking secret squirrel crap. Everyone obsesses over
almost never matters.
All right.
All right. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you, everyone for listening. Go to Social
security podcast.com. Hit up the show. Not Suzy Podos
says podcast. Hashtag I Mastodon Kurt. You have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You
-- too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.