Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast.
Episode 142 with myself Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Pressers.
Kurt. My long nightmare is finally over.
Oh,
yeah.
Yeah, I got rid of the Mac. I had for work and II,
I have a,
you were holding it wrong.
Uh Yeah, I must have been, I must have been. No, I, I have a Linux
laptop now that, that I'm also using as my desktop and it is, it is heavenly
-- when something goes wrong. I know what to do. I, I'm loving it. I'm
-- curious.
Did you go with like one of those Linux laptops or did
you just get like a generic Lenovo think pad or whatever?
And
-- a Lenovo X one carbon. And the reason I got that is,
-- oh,
those are nice
but they're, they're very nice machines.
But also given my history, I used to work at Red Hat.
I know most of the Red Hat devs also have
these laptops so they basically just work and in fact,
I can close the lid and it goes to sleep.
I open the lid, it wakes up, you know, things don't just crash for no reason.
But now here's the really crazy thing about it
as part of my like Mac package I received,
I got the LG five K monitor
and it freaking works, man. Like I plugged it into the, the thinkpad and it works.
It only runs at four K which whatever I can forgive that.
But the fact that the thing works at all like blew my mind.
That's a lot of pixels for a laptop to drive.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
And in fact when I turn on, like, screen sharing and stuff, it, uh you know,
you've done it when, when that happens, but that's OK.
It all just works and it's using Wayland.
So, like the high DP I works the way it's supposed to work and
it's like, I don't even know what to say. It took me.
So I, I got the machine and I figured, all right,
I'll spend the next week setting this up and like,
four hours later I was working off of it and I thought what,
what has happened to the world?
So, what distribution are you running though?
Fedora? 29?
Oh,
ok.
Yeah, it's, well, I, I know it really well,
I know the Fedora devs are using the thinkpad and in fact, there's uh here at Elastic,
we have a whole bunch of Fedora users so I can, you know,
use them as a crutch when necessary if I have a problem or,
or I guess I can help them whichever.
So, no, I'm, I'm loving it though.
It's, I would have to say my,
my main complaint with Fedora was always the OS updates because you only get,
you know, what is it?
12 months of support. But the fed up the Fedora update thing is
mostly the few times I've used it. It, well, I didn't notice any breakage.
It's been pretty good lately. And in fact, so I had a Myth TV.
Well, I have a myth TV machine
that was running like Fedora 19 and I upgraded it to probably Fedora 26 or 27.
Kind of in, in one go
and it freaking work
-- in
-- one step. Or did you have to, like, go 19 to 21 to 23 to 25?
I went all the way and it just like, it just,
it was crazy. I loved it
because I love that guy that did that. What was it like? Do
1.0 to Windows 10 upgrade?
That was,
I think it, I think it's in one of the shows anyways.
So here's speaking of things that should just work.
Here's what I want you to do.
I want you to tell me
how to safely
plug an unknown USB device
into my computer so that I can see what's on it.
Well, right. Don't
that's number one.
So here's what I would do if, if I had,
if someone showed up and said I have this unknown USB
device and I really need to know what's on it.
Can you help me?
Yeah. And, but to be clear, let's go all the way paranoid.
Let's assume for a moment, maybe we're with an organization like, oh,
I don't know the secret service and maybe we just found somebody
who has a pile of USB drives that are interesting looking.
This is a hypothetical, right? This would never happen in real life.
-- Hypothetically speaking, any names or places are a coincidence,
-- you know.
So, so let's come up with a safe protocol
assuming with the secret service.
So that basically means we are state level and we have access to,
I'm not going to say unlimited resources, but we have access to a lot of things.
So,
so what should we or what do we need to do to safely
plug a USB drive to a laptop to see what is on it?
So in the case of an organization like the secret service, they,
they should have a forensics lab somewhere that you would bring it to and they have
various, we'll say tools at their disposal,
things like you could image the USB device in a manner that would be non destructive,
wrong answer.
What if it explodes
it could, I mean, I don't know what their labs look like,
but I'm sure they have the ability to like x ray it and figure out what's going on.
So I think we agree, the first step is probably to X ray that sucker
potentially.
And I would point out
number one, it might explode or number two, it might be a USB kill device.
It's certainly possible.
I mean, you never know, but again,
like when they plug it in it's going to be plugged into
what is essentially burner gear that if it does ruin it.
-- Oh,
-- well,
I agree. So, so I think we'll agree.
Number one,
you need to X ray this thing and make sure it doesn't contain explosives or, you know,
back up.
So those of you that may maybe don't know or don't remember USB K
is a USB stick that essentially has capacitors
and discharges. Well, it doesn't actually discharge electricity.
It discharges like negative 200 volts through the USB
repeatedly and
like
just kills the computer like super fast and
you can buy these at USB kill.com
and they even make it anonymized version without the logo on it
and they're not that expensive. Oh, and they also have swift and discreet shipping.
Yeah, I love it.
So,
yeah,
you need to X ray this thing first and just make
sure it isn't physically gonna like explode on you or,
or blow up your gear.
They can do this. We can't,
I don't have access to an X ray.
-- We
-- could pry it apart, I suppose and hopefully not damage it.
I mean, maybe, but if you're dealing with an explosive device.
So if an explosive device is one of your legitimate concerns,
which honestly it wouldn't be for me most likely.
But if it was even opening it could potentially set
off explosives depending upon what they used inside of it.
Yeah.
Yeah. If they used a switch or something light sensitive or whatever.
No, not even that. Just the fact is most explosives are highly unstable.
Put it in a Ziploc
bag
and rig a hammer up to like, fall on it
and like have a string, pull the string, the hammer falls and whack it.
No, look, no, if this is a legitimate concern, you have like,
just throw it in the freaking river.
Just don't, don't, don't touch it
-- or take it to the cops.
-- Sure. Sure. Right.
Don't.
And, and
why are you asking me this? Like, it's not gonna explode?
Yeah. So, well, ok, let's get past that. So now we've got a device that is physically
safe to plug it in the sense of it's not
going to physically harm us or the physical hardware.
Ok. Ok.
What, what, let me put it this way. What kind of burner device would you plug it into?
I would use a chromebook myself because they're fairly
inexpensive and I won't say they're hacker proof,
but I think they're not a target of most of this sort of problem.
Yeah, I would, I would go even,
I get something like a Raspberry nano
running
very running a very minimal Linux that you plug in
because part of it too is you can have an SD card
in there that you can then pull and easily forensically examine.
Right.
Sure. Sure.
And they're, they're the little ras,
so Raspberry pi and I don't think they're called Nanos.
Uh I forget the name of them.
-- They make a Raspberry Zero. I think that's the one I meant to say. Yeah.
-- Zero.
That's it. Zero. Nano is Arduino's but it's like fire box.
It's super cheap.
Yeah,
so you could plug one device in and then literally throw it away when you're done.
Right. Right.
And or just throw the SD card away because,
well, no, because for example, they could infect the USB chip set
or they could infect the CPU or they could. No, these are
there's exploit code for these floating around.
This is not in my threat model. Nor will I allow it to be. Let's just say that
I, I would generally agree because that way man
flies,
what happens when this stuff shows up on github, which it has
and people actually start using it.
-- I
-- mean, if, if it becomes a well known problem and let's face it,
it's going to show up in the, the typical places we watch for news and events,
then I would potentially change my mind.
But as of today right now,
I would not be concerned with a device infecting chip sets on a raspberry pie
and that's, I, I'm going to presume it's possible. I don't know, for sure.
-- I don't understand the hardware that terribly
-- well,
part of the problem is computers used to be a computer.
So, like
RC
and nowadays computers are
like, literally every chip is.
-- Yeah,
-- everything's a computer. Exactly. Exactly.
Yeah. Like your network card.
It, it has a, it's capable of doing computation, your video card.
Absolutely. That's kind of the whole point nowadays.
That's what you got to mine, your Cryptocurrency on, right.
You know, your USB slots.
Yeah, I mean, I,
I remember I had an Asus motherboard that had a built in hardware level firewall.
So that, and you could configure it to
block and allow network traffic. So,
you know, before it even got to the US.
That's pretty cool. All right. Anyway, we're whatever. All right.
So we have a device,
we need to plug it in.
You would use a Raspberry Pie Nano. I would use my chromebook.
And what now,
well, how do you,
how do you image it and actually know that you're getting
everything off of it because it could lie about its size.
It totally could. And a chromebook actually isn't good at that.
That's where the Raspberry Pi, you could totally do like ad D type operation,
assuming
it's a disk and assuming, like you said, it's not lying about what it really is.
You see, my, my one thought would be is if it,
if it was designed to say, only be plugged into a Windows machine.
Like, oh, I don't know, like, apparently that's what that secret service guy did.
Hypothetically speaking.
Yeah.
Hypothetically speaking, if you just like, plugged it into your Windows laptop,
it could run software that could then, you know,
essentially uh
unlock further information on the device because there's,
there's ways to format and partition a USB drive
and even in and to put hardware into it, you know, there's,
there's those encrypted USB drives, for example,
that actually have like a physical keypad
on the USB drive, like a little 10 digit numeric keypad on the key drive
that you have to punch in the number for it to like unlock itself,
right?
And most of them suck. I think Schneier
wrote about a lot of these where the
vast majority of them were absolutely horrendous.
-- Well, of course, there are, what else would they be?
-- Yeah. OK. So here's,
I've been thinking about this actually and I,
I did not know you're going to start the show with this particular hypothetical,
which amuses me, I will say.
But here's my breakdown of this problem is
if a normal person finds a USB device somewhere,
it is highly likely they will just plug it into whatever they have.
Now, let's say you have an organization like the secret service
or let's say the FBI or the Department of Defense,
you would expect many of those people to know better. But they don't
because if you've ever been to, uh, basically a highly secure data center,
what do they do to the USB ports in those places?
I know in some places they,
they glue them shut everywhere. Why did glue them shut?
Because people plug cramp in that they aren't supposed to,
even when they know better.
And you got to think like these dod people that are operating in a skiff, they know
they know not to do this and they still do.
Yeah. Well, ok, two things. Number one, what's a skiff?
-- Because not everybody knows this. Oh, sorry.
-- It's, I, I don't remember the acronym.
It's basically just a highly secured data center.
Well, it's a secure compartmentalized information something.
And it's essentially typically it's a tempest shielded room or area
anywhere from the size of like a closet where you can have, you know,
a private conversation with somebody to things, the size of football fields,
holding data centers.
And the idea is like, I, I've dealt with people where they literally are, like,
I'm outside in the parking lot in my car making this phone
call because I'm not allowed to bring my phone into the facility.
Right. Right. And I've, I've been to, I've been to meetings like that.
It's always, it always amuses me.
It's like, put your phone in this, this locker, we'll give it back to you later.
It's like you're going to mess with it and then they just look at you funny.
And they, they never answer.
-- So,
-- yeah, I had that, that situation with, uh,
with some meetings that were supposed to happen on the campus.
And they were
number one when they found out I was not American and I was Canadian.
They're like, oh,
awkward,
followed by like, and, and I was,
I was quite clear that I was not giving up my phone because I can't,
I just won't and I won't.
But
anyways moving along.
So, ok,
we've got this thing physically plugged in it may or may not have attacked
our USB chip set and we may or may not be aware of that.
So I would say the number one thing now is if you really want to do it safely,
you need some USB level hardware like kind of the reverse of a USB Power condom.
So a USB power condom is a thing that
essentially it's a little pass through
USB device that only allows electricity through
data
so that you can now plug your phone into charge.
-- They rename them because the USB condom was the worst name in the world
-- did.
-- It kept getting blocked by parental controls.
-- It might have, I don't know.
I always,
I always felt bad telling like what is this when you're at a conference giving?
It's like, oh it's a USB condom and then they just look at you. It's like, oh
black
Day.
Anyway,
they're called sink stops now and they come with a nice case and stuff and it's,
it's not like the good old days when it was just like a, a
board of Bear electronics.
No, they're, they're nice. They're nice.
But here's, here's the other part of that though.
I used to travel with one all the time and I don't anymore. You know why?
Because I just have a big freaking battery in my backpack.
It's,
that's the solution anyway. Anyway.
Ok. So
I guess here's the thing.
If you plug it in and it starts doing stuff,
you've lost all your gears compromised
you.
If you're, if you're an organization with resources,
you're going to just turn it all into the lab and say, I don't know what's happening
if you're, you or me,
uh, you're going to throw it away and if you're a normal person,
you probably won't even know anything happened.
That's
if it's chromebook, they power wash it or if it's, you know, really bad,
they maybe get it formatted and reinstalled.
Uh, right. Actually, I would sell my hacked chromebook on
ebay. Probably.
Well, I'm not going to use it anymore.
I'll just power wash it to pretend it's fine. Right.
Yeah,
I wonder that sometimes how much of the gear,
unlike ebay was because it was horribly infected.
Nobody wants to use it anymore.
Oh, I've heard some stories of people buying things and just getting.
Yeah, that's, it's,
-- yeah, some of this gear has definitely been compromised and I have
-- no
doubt,
you know,
stock or software or whatever.
Right. Right. So, anyway,
-- so
-- I'll be blunt, I think what this boils down to is unless you have access to
or you're willing to have the discipline to have like Bernard Gear
that's running Linux and, and, you know,
really image it and then look at what it is and see here's the problem.
So now you've imaged what's on this USB drive, you've got a nice little DD, you know,
output into a file.
What do you do with it?
Right. Who has the software to forensically examine it
-- and then understand what that output is?
-- Well, I don't, I don't have the skills even.
So this topic actually came up.
It,
it's popped up about four or five times for
me in the last probably two months about digital forensics
and, and here's the thing. So I, I know there's certain things I could do,
but it would be an amusement at best.
I don't have the skill set or the tools to do proper digital forensics.
But here's the more important thing is when you're an organization
that's part of, say law enforcement or,
or any time you think there could potentially be something
like criminal charges involved in what's happening around you.
There's,
there's very strict procedures that have to happen around
things like the preservation and handling of evidence.
And obviously,
when you have say a bad USB drive that's evidence.
And so like, if you plug it into your computer and it does stuff you,
that evidence is now worthless.
You're going to struggle to get that admissible in
court because the defense is going to say,
well, you plugged it in and your computer had a virus and infected the flash drive.
Like, well,
it didn't, but I can't prove it didn't because, like,
I just smoked my computer plugging in this bad drive.
So,
I mean,
that's what makes it so hard when you look at a lot
of this stuff is this is such a specific and unique skill set
that, that most of us,
it's kind of the old thing.
There, there's, you know, unknown, you know, there's the things, you know,
there's the things, you know, you don't know.
And then there's the things you don't know, you don't know.
And digital forensics for the vast majority of us are things we don't know,
we don't know, we think we do but we totally don't.
Well,
and I would say it's even more complicated
than that because it varies by jurisdiction.
Yes. Yes, it does. You know what I mean?
So, there's like,
there's like the physical rules of the world and then there's the legal frameworks
that
you are operating under which
it's, and it's not going to be completely different.
But, I mean, I, I'm,
I'm pretty sure there's going to be differences
between where I live in Canada and where you
-- live in the U si
-- guarantee there are and I won't even pretend to know my jurisdiction.
I live in what, how those rules work. I mean,
I'm not an expert at this.
Well, you actually,
I think
you
live in multiple jurisdictions technically depending on if
-- it's state or federal or
-- whatever and,
and local and it's, the US is wild about a lot of that.
I don't, I don't know how other places work.
But, yeah, I mean, you could be charged with federal crimes.
You could be charged at the local level, their state level.
It's just, it's,
uh,
I
don't want to think about it, but, but again,
I'm not qualified to do any of this work and I know that and if you think you are,
you probably aren't, is my suspicion.
Well, unless you have official certifications and you've taken
at
least a year or five of training.
Absolutely.
Yeah, because when I, when I, when I look at digital forensics, all I know is
I could do a very limited, like
if you accidentally deleted photos on your phone. Yeah, I could definitely help you
and, and my help would consist of Googling for a piece of software to recovery.
Right. That's it. Let's be real.
Uh, and, and I know enough beyond that, that no, sorry guys.
And, and definitely don't take it to the geek squad.
-- You don't wanna do that.
-- I don't trust any of those places with my gear
and
it is I, I don't think there's anything wrong with them necessarily.
It's just the fact that if, if, if it's a problem I can't fix,
it's a pretty big problem.
Right. That's kind of the way I, I tend to see these things.
So, anyway, I guess here's,
here's the question I have for you over all this
in our hypothetical scenario where a secret service agent doesn't
know enough not to plug in a USB flash drive.
And you
almost certainly think they should.
-- What hope do the rest of us have and what can we do about it?
-- So, here's the problem.
Fundamentally, human curiosity, you find a USB drive,
you're gonna want to be helpful,
plug it in and see who it belongs to and send it back to them.
-- No,
-- you don't, you want to plug it in and see how big it is and then keep it if it's good.
Right.
But fundamentally, and I don't want to, you know, come across as mean and harsh, but
don't, I mean, maybe turn it into the police and then it's their problem.
Yeah, they're not going to care either.
Let's face it if you show up with a flash drive.
-- Well, and
-- they're just gonna plug it into their, their computer and be like,
probably, and see if it's any good and then keep it,
like, what else would they do with it? Right. Send it to the forensics lab.
-- No,
-- because why would they,
you know, to quote the big Lebowski.
Hey, we got, we got four more detectives working on it in shifts.
Well, and, and here's the other half of that is in our hypothetical situation,
the secret service people were in proximity to the President of the United States
who is a legitimate target for what we would call movie plot threats.
But in the, in the case of, of the president, of probably most countries,
they're not called movie plot threats.
They're just called threats.
Well, I would say that's just a Tuesday for them,
right? You don't want to see what Thursday looks like.
But I, I mean, it, it,
it should be different but it's not because people forget things,
people make silly mistakes and I,
I get it. I'm not gonna, I'm not gonna fault.
I, I know the, the secret service people who,
who theoretically did this may or may not be catching a lot of heat on Twitter.
But it's like people, people do dumb stuff. It's just how people work.
It's not that they, the problem is, it's not so much that they did something dumb,
they did something normal.
Yeah, that's true. And the problem is they're not supposed to do normal things.
That is also very true. And that's a very difficult problem to fix.
-- It is potentially an impossible problem to fix. Yeah,
-- because humans be human. Yo,
-- humans got a human.
-- Now, now here's the question though. Is there anything
that can be done to mitigate against a problem like this for,
we'll say a relatively normal person.
So at an organization level, there are things to control access to USB.
But obviously that's not going to work for a normal human being, even myself.
Like I'm not going to spend the money. Those things are not cheap.
I do know that I could lock down my windows, Apple and Linux devices to not talk to
any USB device
other than like what I explicitly allow.
Right.
Yeah, I'm not going to bother because honestly
I'm just generally not going to plug random USB stuff into my
machines
and funnily enough.
So the way I generally buy my USB devices is I buy them, you know, new,
I don't buy you stuff.
I buy new off of like,
hopefully, uh, from like, staples or whatever, you know, Amazon
and hopefully I'm not getting something that, you know,
previously had a virus installed at the factory or,
but that
too.
Oh, exactly. Yeah. All those picture frames that, you know,
-- constantly for some reason get viruses.
-- Right.
Right.
Yeah, I basically just, you know,
don't plug in random things and I don't let people plug random things into my stuff.
I don't plug my phone into random charge ports like
this little walker cabinets at the airport or whatever.
Yeah, like you said, the solution there is I just, I, I buy
or? Right, but once every year or two I buy a new battery from Costco.
You know,
-- and, and yeah,
-- that's
-- it.
-- Tap the problem, which is, let's say, charging devices.
But what about if people, I mean, look,
if a normal person finds a USB device on the ground,
they're going to plug it in full stop.
-- Is there anything they can do about it? And should they even really care
-- generally?
-- No, because most people are not the president of the United States.
-- Right?
I would argue it, it, you know, I mean, if this is something you worry about,
don't do it because obviously,
like, if I find one, no, I do not, I don't even pick it up most of the time.
But if, if
Norman people are going to pick them up and they're
going to plug them in and in all seriousness,
I think in the
99.9999% situations, it isn't going to matter.
It's just going to be like some college kids, term paper he lost
-- or
-- photos or whatever.
Right. And
I mean, if you're someone who worries about this and let's face it,
like there are plenty of organizations where you hear
about parking lot attacks and things like that.
This is where you need to rely on technical controls to prevent this.
We're locking USB ports and making sure people can't bring USB drives and plug
into the corporate network if that's something you're actually worried about.
Whereas telling people don't pick up USB drives and plug them in,
I mean, whatever that's like saying,
-- quick clicking on fishing links just it doesn't work
-- well.
And that's part of the problem is you're telling people not to do something,
but you're not giving them an alternative behavior to kind of assuage
what they want.
So, what I would say is, is I wouldn't say, don't pick them up and plug them in.
I would say if you find a USB device, please turn it into
infosec or it,
-- and it will deal with it.
-- Right. So,
so you know what the first thing that popped in my head
was what you said about alternative alternatives to the behavior is,
oh,
you should give up like Starbucks gift cards or
something if someone turns in a flash drive,
but then
you could conceivably go to the office store
and buy the 100 pack of flash drives and just turn one in every couple of weeks.
You're like, oh, I found another one, everybody.
Although,
although I guess this is one of those situations also
where after someone turns in the fourth flash drive,
like, you know, they're game in the system.
So
I would, I would probably not do that. But no, I think you're absolutely right.
And this is something we fail at insecurity often is we just say, well, don't do that.
We don't say instead of doing that, you should do this instead.
And if you tell people don't do something like that's the best way to do it. Like,
I just think of my kids where you say, oh, don't do that.
And as soon as you turn around, what are they doing? Exactly.
-- The thing you said not to do
-- well or something
right up to the line of that thing.
Yeah. Right.
And then circumventing it somehow. Like, like at the pool, at one pool we go to,
there's, uh, you know, there's the little, the wire with the plastic things on it.
What do you call those things? The, the lane markers,
the lane dividers,
lane dividers. I
know that's what
I, so everyone's strung across the pool to, to, to, uh, say
off the deeper end
and until you can swim a lap by yourself and they
write a happy face on your shoulder with a sharpie.
You're not allowed to go
into the deep end alone
or even with your adult.
-- Right. Because a lot, a lot of adults can't swim. That.
-- That's true.
Actually, that's fair.
So, my one son knows that he's not allowed to go past this barrier.
And so he will do everything, like holding on to it, getting his body past it,
like flopping over it.
He's still holding on to it.
You know,
he knows exactly how far he can push it and what the lifeguards will allow and what,
you know,
will.
Right.
So, he's, he's tested those limitless boundaries and,
-- and I respect that because that's how we learn
-- So actually this is,
this is a really good comparison you bring up.
So I will, I will relate this back to a, a real life story I have. So
I, I grew up swimming a lot. My son is on a swim team.
My daughter, I keep trying to get to swim on the swim team, but she won't be,
she's an excellent swimmer and she do really well.
And my, my wife swims well enough.
I'm not, you know, she didn't grow up quite in the water like I did,
but she's more than competent.
And I remember the Children have been in swim
lessons basically as soon as they could walk,
they were taught how to swim and they're,
they're phenomenal swimmers and we were down by the river one
day and the kids were out playing on the docks,
you know, out in the water and stuff.
And my wife looks at me goes, what if they fall in? I said
they swim like that. This is why we taught them how to swim like this is why.
Yeah, I, I agree. Exactly.
Yeah, folks, if you have kids, please teach them to swim.
E even if it's just like recovery paddle
actually.
Did you know that if you, if you go to MIT, as an undergrad, I guess they have,
you have to take a swim class when you're there.
And the reason they do that is studies have shown that parents
who know how to swim have like a 80% decrease in,
in child drownings of their Children,
which I totally believe that, you know, unquestionable.
Well, you know, if you don't know how to swim,
what are the chances you're going to teach your kids to swim?
And like I said, you don't have to swim.
Well, just recovery crawl, keep your head above water. Get to the edge.
If you can't swim and your kid falls in the water.
It's quite likely if you go in after them.
Now there's two people, you have to get out of the water instead of one.
And, and that's kind of a problem also.
And I think I would, I would relate a lot of this to security in, in the fact that
you can tell people don't go, don't go on the dock, right? Don't go by the water.
They still do.
And sometimes people fall in and if they,
if they don't have the skills necessary to deal with the situation,
which let's face it.
Sometimes they don't,
you need someone who knows what they're doing because like,
I've taken all of the lifeguard training courses and when someone is drowning,
they act in a very certain way.
And in fact, even recognizing drowning,
like in the movies where they're splashing around, going, help, help, help,
that does not happen.
It is drowning.
People act in a very specific way that normal people don't understand.
And like, oh man, this is such a good comparison.
I'm gonna, I'm gonna put more thought into this. But anyway,
the point is if you don't know how to swim and you jump in to help someone,
now there's two problems.
But if you do know what to do, you can totally jump in and help out and,
and you'll have success and this is very, very similar to security in general is,
I think we see a lot of situations where someone falls in the
water and then someone else jumps in the water and now there's,
you know, and before you know, it,
there's 30 people drowning and the security person shows up and it's like,
what the heck just happened here. I can't say 30 people.
I know.
Well, and like you said, as the security person and I also,
I don't have lifeguard training well, a little bit.
But for example, at the cabin, I have a throw rope.
-- Yeah.
-- Right. Or a pole or whatever like that.
-- That, that is a perfect compensating control for not being a
-- lifeguard.
But the problem is you have to, but you have to know to buy that.
-- Right. And they're not cheap either. It's like 30 bucks.
-- No, they are expensive.
But they're, they last like, freaking forever. That stuff is fantastic.
-- It's so, it's such high quality.
-- But again, like, who, who knows?
I've never,
but I've never seen anybody else with a throw rope out of the dock at the cabin.
I I believe that, I don't think, but again, normal people, how would they know?
Right. How would they know not to pick up the USB Drive?
How would they know to get a throw rope?
How would they know how to find someone that could help them if they fall in the water?
And, and I don't, I don't know if there's even a good answer to some of that.
I mean,
some of it's awareness you always hear about
water safety training and things like that.
I keep coming back to, especially with the USB type stuff is, is kind of like call 911,
-- go to your it person, go to, go find an
-- adult that's perfectly fair.
And if someone falls in the water and you call 911,
they're, they're probably going to tell you, is there a rope or a stick nearby,
you know,
like do not get in the water if you cannot swim is what they're going to tell you to do
and they're going to tell you, you know, go, go yell for help,
find someone who can help, find someone who knows how to swim.
And I mean,
if your cell phone can call 911, it is highly likely
there will be someone within
earshot of you, I would guess in many instances. So, yeah, I mean, I, I love this.
This is, this is a great analogy.
Actually, I need to put more thought into this So, anyway.
All right, we're, we're basically out of time here. So I guess
any closing thoughts about our hypothetical situation,
if you're not sure what to do, call for help
straight up.
That's, and that's something like I'm drilling my kids on is like, if,
if things go a bit sideways,
call for help, ask for help, even things like,
you know, like
even simple stuff like opening the peanut butter jar is like, I can't open it.
I'm like, ok, well, what can we do? And he's like, oh, I could ask for help. I'm like a
smash it on the counter.
Yeah.
Well, it's plastic that we tried that once.
Now, there's a very important second part to this we need to add
is historically speaking, security.
People have not been helpful where someone would ask for help and
we'd often yell at them or demean them or make fun of them
and you cannot do that to people because then they don't like you
now,
although they won't come to you for help
if you go to somebody for help and they're mean to you. You're, they're
no, you'll never go back.
Exactly. Now, I'm not saying it's not ok to go to the pub with your friends later.
Maybe chuckle about some stories because I, my wife actually just went out for, for,
uh, dinner with, with, uh, someone in charge of an hr department and
she's got some stories to tell.
It's pretty sweet. It's, it's great anyway. But the point is
when someone comes to you be helpful and kind. Right. I mean, don't take abuse.
I'm not saying that.
But like if someone says, oh,
I found this drive and plugged it into my computer and now it's broken, like,
don't yell at them,
help them understand what's going on and make sure
they're going to come back to you again later.
Because if, if you yell at them and make them feel bad,
well, they're just never going to come back to you and that's,
that totally defeats the purpose.
So,
all right, sweet. I love it. This was, this was a fun one. So, thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. You can go to open source security podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes, use the Pound Os S Podcast hashtag to find us on social media.
Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks
-- everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.