Hello and welcome to episode 76 of the open source security podcast
with myself, Kurt
Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime. Josh Pressers.
Well, the internet's on fire again
also. It's 2018.
It is, those are two things that are true.
I forget it's not a leap year, right?
Because divisible by four but not 100 but yes to 1000 but not.
Or is it 2000?
What
if it's divisible by four? It's a leap year unless it's divisible by 100.
In which case, it's not a leap year.
In which case, if it's divisible by 1000 it is a leap year. Hence, 2000 was a leap year.
I think that's the rule.
I can just look at my calendar
and it will tell me.
Well, I know 2018 isn't, I think. Yeah, because 18.
Right.
Cool.
We're safe then.
I, I guess, I mean, right. We have enough trouble. We don't need it.
-- So,
-- yeah. Yeah. Can you believe it? That am DC pu bug with the certificate processing
that allows remote code execution.
I'm impressed by that one actually.
Yeah. Oh, wait, no, you're talking about that other one.
There's, there's been more than one. Right.
So, wait. Ok. So I, I thought, I thought I could buy an A MD processor and I would be safe
and
maybe not.
Yeah.
Right.
Anyway, so,
well, do you? Ok. So for those of you who don't have,
oh, I guess for people who just run on raspberry pies and are immune to this,
uh,
apparently speculative branch prediction and CP
US and security are really tricky.
Yes.
Who knew?
I, I'll be honest,
I'm more shocked that this kind of flaw hasn't become public
before because quite frankly, I mean,
how many gates does the CPU have? Now?
It's in an astronomical number.
And actually, you know,
what's really funny about this one is I remember looking at it
and reading about it and thinking like this is really obvious.
I'm amazed nobody put the numbers together to figure this out before. Now.
That's actually what really fascinated.
That's one of the top five things that fascinates me about this issue is number one
in one case.
So there's a couple of issues that were found and one
of them was found independently by three different sets of people.
And the other issue was found independently by two sets of people.
So,
uh and then then there was a speculative thread on Reddit talking about
uh question and whatnot and how essentially
uh their theory was that Intel
has allowed this bug to persist,
you know, as long as it's not publicly known
because like it is one heck of a backdoor for
like three letter agencies that want to do targeted attacks.
Uh
Me and I don't know about that,
but I feel like
no
offense lately,
Google projects are all smart people, these other researchers, very smart people,
like the NSA seriously never looked into this.
I feel like it would be criminally stupid of them not to,
to be like, oh, hey, you know, these high fancy amazing CPU features,
maybe they have flaws in them.
We should look into that.
I mean, the NSA used to make their own chips apparently. So
you think they would have some people that know about this stuff?
Well, I, I mean, I'm sure they do,
but I feel like there's lower hanging fruit it could easily go after
and,
and the other thing is this is kind of a second order
flaw in most cases where by itself it's not necessarily a problem.
It's that
the attacker has to get in and then they can
use this to their advantage to do bad things.
And, but
there's a problem now with your comment about the attacker has to get in
because
so these flaws generally require you to run untrusted code
or for the attacker to have exploited something like network wise
to get to run code, right?
-- Like like your web browser maybe. And
-- that's the problem.
Now your web browsers are downloading third
party code from literally God knows where because
see the front page of cnn.com or youtube is like
two megabytes and like a third of that is javascript.
Um
you know, ad networks and stuff.
That's,
that's why I block ads is because all that Wonky javascript code being run from.
God knows where
um and just the speed issues. But anyways, that's the problem.
Like, so a flaw like this
for a three letter agency would have been amazing because all
you would have had to do is like insert some javascript,
you know, obviously in a javascript
and you could read the complete contents of an, of a, of a system
memory like
sort of, it's complicated.
Well, true, but fundamentally the the attacks are not theoretical, right?
These attacks work, there's working exploit code,
the exploit code works from unprivileged.
Like you don't need to be root to run this code.
You, you can just run this code as a user and read all the memory space basically,
which is neat.
And it was about in the one case,
what they were saying it was about 2000 bits per second which ain't super fast.
But I mean,
it's good.
It's pretty good man.
I mean, especially when you probably don't have to really babysit it,
-- it'll
-- just do its business
is sequential and you can control it to some degree, right? Like
there's been a lot of Linux kernel memory leaks where
it's like they can read like four kilobytes of memory,
but they can't control what it is.
It's just totally random
in which case that's not great.
And it's, you know,
it's difficult to exploit but when you can control what's being read.
Well, yeah, I mean,
yeah,
that's all about what encryption keys, passwords, you name it.
Yeah. Right. Right.
And actually you remind me speaking of what, 22 K a second or whatever, uh,
there was somebody dumped the PS four kernel and it took six days
because they could read like 600 bytes or something at a time.
It was crazy.
But anyway, and, and that's the thing. Right?
Is time, is irrelevant in my honest opinion because I think if you have
-- on like reddit or CNN or something
-- constantly. Absolutely. Like. Right.
Yep. Yep.
-- I, I know
-- the whole point with those crypto miners
that insert crypto
currency mining javascript.
Yeah. Right.
Right. That only works because people leave tabs open for like, ever, like,
uh 24. I don't even know how many tabs I've opened. It's a bunch.
I probably can't count that high
and I rebooted the other day.
Here's what really fascinates me is, this is a really,
like,
this is a really solid set of technical flaws like that
are actually useful for bad guys to do bad things.
And you know what? I honestly don't really care that much
-- because you know what I
-- find an assisted
man.
Well, I am but it's not my problem. But you know what I'm really fascinated by is in
this case,
the cure is potentially far worse than the disease.
Uh Yes. And, and I think, why don't we, why don't we start with,
we're not interested in talking about kind
of the deep down scary technical details.
-- If you want those, go somewhere else,
-- go to Google's blog.
Right. Yeah, that's true. It's, it's actually very well written
but there's so many other crazy things about this issue to talk about and,
and I think starting with the cure is a great place because I, I agree with you.
There are going to be organizations where
applying the, I guess the, the slowness they will get the performance hit
will outweigh the potential security impact.
Right? Because, because let's face it if you think about it as, as a cost
where a performance impact has a very dollar centric cost, right? Or, or
to say,
right. Whereas getting hacked,
what are they going to get? Right. What are you going to,
what is, what is, how is it going to damage your business? Right. That too. Exactly.
I mean, let's face it. Right. The
great is a great example because
you think like Transunion and all those other companies aren't just as bad.
Oh. Right. Yeah,
that's like even all the, all the people saying, oh,
we should all buy a MD processors now and it's like, I, I bet you buy black hat
someone has figured out how to do this on A MD chips.
I mean,
I mean, they already did that on Wednesday. I mean, there was the, what is it?
Um
the uh remote code execution via crafted uh EK certificate in AM DS.
Uh They have this thing called trust zone
that provides
basically it's like part of the trusted platform management T PM stuff, blah, blah,
blah, long story short
parsing certificates is tricky like it legit.
I mean, I dare anybody to go read the A SN one or X 509 standards.
Oh man, it's brutal. It's so complicated.
And so anyways uh point being you feed this thing a certificate,
you get code execution
straight up. But here's the difference, right?
99.9% of security flaws, the resolution boils down to here's a code patch boom done,
right?
And there's no,
there's almost never any like severe weirdness or performance hit. And
in the few cases where there are typically what will happen is either like, oh,
we have to like kill that feature because it's really terrible.
So we just can't do that anymore.
So we're gonna like break backwards compatibility to some degree, you know,
like a great example being SSL, we just, we can't fix SSL,
right? It's just so broken at this point.
The the solution is go deploy TL SS 1.1 or later
like straight up,
right?
Um
The other case like a great example is shell shock, right? Remember shell shock,
it was a, it was a bug and Bash introduced in 1995.
So again, kind of like the CPU bug and that it affected like everything since ever.
That's kind of the first big problem.
The second problem is it was super trivial to exploit, right?
Like somebody tweeted out
a working exploit code in a tweet
and then we went through that whole like, oh, we're going to fix it.
We're going to fix it this way, didn't quite fix it it that way.
And we ended up having to break some backwards compatibility
and fundamentally it didn't matter that much.
No
funny enough.
The the story behind shell shock is upstream released a
couple of patches trying to avoid breaking backwards compatibility.
And in fact, it didn't work. And at the end
after wasting days of people's time,
they ended up releasing a patch that broke backwards
compatibility because it was the only way to fix it
and the confusion
because there was multiple CV
S and there were new CV S being issued and oh, it was a gigantic cluster kerfuffle.
And um this is a family show, right?
Although please don't let your Children listen to this. That's, that's cruel.
-- Yeah. Don't, don't make anyone
-- do that.
But anyways and so like even in a case like shell shock,
which is a great example because I mean, it it was a mess,
it was backwards compatibility or
um,
like some of the SSL TLS stuff like where it's
just literally there is no answer other than to like,
OK, we got to deprecate SSL straight up.
That's all, that's the answer.
Um, life goes on, right.
Like it's, you apply, like you get a source code or a binary patch from your vendor,
you apply it, you reboot or you don't reboot whatever
and you're done.
Right. That's, that's basically it.
-- Yeah.
-- In most cases,
-- and in this case, the problem is, I mean, the there,
there's basically two solutions.
Either you apply the workaround patch, fix whatever in software
or
you like buy new hardware.
But,
but here's the beauty of it is Intel even shipping chips today that are immune to this
uh aren't they still shipping atoms that don't have this capability?
I believe the Intel
atom
or maybe those are the older ones I'm thinking of,
but they didn't have speculative branch prediction. So they're just
no harm, no foul, just like Raspberry Pi.
The Raspberry Pi is such a simple CPU. It's just not affected.
I love it.
But here, although did you read the, the cert
advice was to replace your CPU
patching, that's for chumps, just buy a new computer.
Well, and, and here's the thing that gets me replace your CPU with what even if Intel
somehow magically like for the sake
of argument tripled their manufacturing capacity.
That still wouldn't be enough.
Right.
There's literally just not enough, you know.
And this is what kind of worries me about the IOT.
It's like everybody go replace your toaster. But with what?
With a new toaster, a stick and fire
like,
yeah, I've got a kitchen torch now, so I've got a plan B
-- right.
-- There you go. There you go.
Awesome. So,
yeah, so,
yeah, realistically replacing hardware is not
-- an option other than like,
-- completely ridiculous
to,
unless you maybe
decide to switch from Intel to a MD going forwards and like after three years of
amortization and replacing everything you're, you're done.
But yeah, so you got to apply this uh the software patches that,
you know,
depending on what kind of CIS calls and
whatever you're doing have uh an impact performance
of between like zero and like 30 or 50% with sort of an average around 5%
which doesn't sound terrible. And honestly, like for desktop ain't that bad. But
when you think about servers and a data center and like, just
like losing 5% of your CPU capacity or conversely in increasing your
CPU capacity by 5% and thus cooling and all that by 5%.
-- Like Amazon, I mean, that is a major, major amount of money.
-- Right. Right.
Well, you've got to imagine the likes of Amazon or Google or Facebook or whoever.
Well,
they probably have so many CP us that if they wanted
to replace them all say in the next two years,
they couldn't
under any,
they probably do replace a lot of it on a 2 to 3 year cycle because
the newer CP US are so much more energy efficient, they'll pay for themselves.
It's like S sds in the data center
literally will pay for themselves in six months or less
because of the cooling requirements are so much lower.
-- Ok. I mean,
-- that's
the other thing to remember too is so a company like Facebook
will have to eat that cost because the CP US are slow.
But a company like Amazon web services, like my web server is 5% slower.
So that means I got to go spend
and buy 5% more web servers.
-- Yeah. Right.
-- So Amazon is not going to eat that cost.
No, no, absolutely not. And in fact, I read a thing on I
was hacker news or reddit. I think, I think you sent it to me
where someone was talking about.
They had their Amazon reserved instances and now essentially they,
they paid ahead for less than they're getting.
I
mean, that, that's
interesting
to think about.
Yeah.
Well, and that's the second big issue around this flaw.
That is most fascinating to me is that
for probably the first time in the history of computing
history, we actually have a security event
with a confirmable amount of loss in the billions.
It's Intel's market share stock.
Yeah, market cap, sorry, not market share. Intel's market cap dropped.
Something like, what was it? $6 billion
and A MD went up about a half a billion. I think it was.
Um, I was also quite shocked about the, the,
the difference in market caps Intel is like 210 billion.
A MD is like 11
A MD is significantly smaller than Intel.
But I, you know, I read it, I read a statistic once about kind of companies
and generally speaking, whoever is in first place commands 80% of the market,
whoever's in second place usually has 10 to 15%.
And then it's just scraps after that.
And I mean, that's totally the processor market today, right?
And,
and that's kind of what led to this is that Intel does
amazing stuff like speculative branch prediction which like gives you a,
a
pretty significant boost in performance,
like for real, you know, like this is not a half a percent more CPU gum.
Like it's a, you know, it's a pretty good amount of improvement
because Intel is basically doing voodoo
in the CPU.
-- Like
-- it's their voodoo,
it's magic.
OK.
Sorry magic.
You know,
um like they're, they're basically saying like, oh,
we probably know what your program is gonna do.
So we're gonna go do that and if it turns out it's wrong,
we'll like somehow magically unwind it and then do the right thing.
Uh No, it's, that, that part's actually easy.
I mean, branch prediction isn't, isn't new.
You, you just basically when you hit the branch,
if, if what, what happens isn't what you thought it was,
you just dump the pipeline and, and let it run from there.
It's that part's actually really well
because I did, I was in, in college
in
man, it would have been
99 maybe 2000 somewhere in there.
And, and I took a processor design course and like we talked about
doing the, the brand prediction stuff and how it works.
And obviously we designed a trivial one that
was basically it guessed for the most part,
you know, we didn't actually do anything interesting.
But you figure in
if you guess your 50% chance, right?
I mean, practically speaking, obviously Intel does better than that.
So my guess is they're probably somewhere in
the high seventies in terms of R prediction.
But
you get the idea.
Yeah.
No. And um so yeah, I mean,
to me that just the fact that we can actually quantify
to some degree the actual loss from this in, in
the form of the stock market,
I don't think that's really happened before.
Maybe not. I, I don't know, I feel like the answer is no,
but I, I also have a suspicion
that in, in like three months, Intel stock will be fine.
Well, you know, this whole thing reminds me of the Equifax thing with the whole,
like we're shocked, this is terrible blah, blah, blah.
But what are you going to do not use Equifax
is
you and I can not use them. We
just
data points to them. Right.
And all their existing large contracts are locked in for
God knows how long and they're buying that stuff.
Like
you can't just switch CPU providers like overnight because more to the point,
even if a MD wanted to service
this market, they, they, they can't, they, I mean,
they can't magically turn out 10 times as many CP us tomorrow.
Yeah.
Right. Well, and not only that, like,
I, I don't want to drop a grand on a new CPU tomorrow. Right.
So I'm gonna live with it.
Well, you'd also need a new motherboard.
Probably different ra M and then that means, like,
physically swapping everything, which
is a pain for you and me. But when you think about somebody like Amazon, oh, sweet.
Like
I was actually talking with somebody. It was funny because they were,
they had a problem with auditors at the data center because their auditors, like,
we want to see how you build a server and they're like, but we don't like
racks come in, they're shrink wrapped. We like unshrink, wrap them and like,
there's like a fiber plug thing and like a power, well, two power plug things
and like, and then the guy, like,
you know, he slots it in jams in a couple of plugs and like,
that's it. Like he walks away from it.
Like he's not installing stuff or touching stuff or like turning screws,
like at that scale, you know, you have a semi truck back up to your loading bay
and a guy with a forklift,
man,
I remember building out racks and it took more than
a day usually to fill a rack with one use
because
I mean,
well, well, not just that, well, the screws
you
have
to screw because I remember,
I remember the time I built a rack full of one use
we got in a rack which is empty and then there
were rails and there were screws and you had to first
put in the screw the rails and then you had to
attach the server to the rails and then put it in.
And then when you were done installing, what is it like? 46?
I don't even remember how many it is. It's a freaking lot.
Right. When you're done with
-- 75 inches
-- each.
Ok. Right. Right.
-- And
-- then you have
to
memories
or anything.
I thankfully have forgotten. So I consider that an accomplishment.
But then you have to wire the stupid things up too.
Right.
-- Do you remember
-- wires,
Facebook and all these guys came out with their open rack specification
and part of it was straight up,
there's like two or three copper bars in the
back that you don't touch because they're running like,
what was it like 48 volts at like
100 amps or something stupid?
And like, there's just clips to, like, on the back for the power, you know,
and, and when I read that I'm like, that sounds ridiculously dangerous and
to
open them up.
I mean, well,
more to the point you shouldn't be sticking your arm into the back of a rack.
Right. Right.
Well, I'm, I'm trying to think.
II, I don't remember dealing with, with broken machines in a rack very often.
Like, if it broke,
you probably just stopped using it
because it wasn't worth the pain and suffering of
taking the stupid thing out in most cases.
My favorite was because I bought some really cheap cases that didn't, like,
fit properly.
Uh, I had a one u acting as a shelf and that one you died and of course,
I couldn't replace it because it was a shelf.
Right.
Leave it in, it's fine.
It's structural
actually. You know, you know what else? I remember?
I remember one time I put together a rack, it was Dell Servers.
A Dell rack, like Dell everything
and the fricking machines didn't fit. It's like, come on guys.
-- This is the only reason. Well, it's
-- like IKEA,
IKEA has cutlery trays and cutlery and they don't fit together
like the freaking, the short part is too short for their spoons and forks. Oh,
my goodness. It's off by like, half an inch. It's, it's awesome.
It
makes me so angry
and that is the world we live in.
Yeah. Going back to this. So, I mean,
what's really like what I find so fascinating is that
you've got this directly quantifiable cost of a having to install a patch,
having to reboot.
Um The best part too is this patch.
It's not just like,
oh install it on the bare metal and you're good to go like a
lot of like CPU microcode updates where you update the CPU microcode and you're done
or you update the underlying operating system and you're done.
No, like in this case, you have to update
the underlying operating system,
you may or may not have to update the micro code in the CPU as well.
And then you may or may not have to also update your V MS
like with kernels
because of the way virtualization and CCU shenanigans work,
just update everything.
-- Exactly.
-- I mean, don't, don't try to guess.
Yeah.
Um
and then like you said, I mean, part of it too is like how bad this is this going to be?
You know,
you might have a database workload which hits that magic 30% performance impact
in which case like, wow, I, I don't have advice for you.
Like I literally don't know what to tell people with that problem, you know,
and, and well, you know, I mean, I I'm at elastic and obviously we,
we have workloads that are crazy, crazy write and read dependent,
which can have a hit.
And so like this is something we're,
we're doing some significant investigation into now is,
is we want to understand exactly what this performance impact means
because it, it is going to matter to some people. Right.
Well, I, I'm just thinking how much did you guys spend,
say optimizing elastic to be 10 or 20% faster?
There's people that, that's their job.
I bet they're curled up in a ball crying right now because
all that work they did is just potentially out the window.
It's not out the window, it will. Ok. So here's, I see this as two
sided,
there's like people like us,
we now have room for extra optimizations because we, if we can find ways to, to hit
the disc less
we will gain speed, right? We will gain significant speed.
Well, I shouldn't say gain, we get it back right?
Because you're not really gaining it recover, uh
sure recover.
But in, in all, additionally, kind of from the operating system level,
we're at a point again where people can do some clever things to gain that speed back.
And I, I honestly fully expect
that in a couple of years,
the kernel will have found ways to get the vast majority of the speed back.
-- I really do think
-- that and that raises a third topic.
I'm really, I've been thinking about is how long are we going to be stuck with
this performance? Hit security fix?
Like are we at some point in five or 10 years going to say,
ok, everybody should have upgraded their CPU by now.
You know,
the Linux kernel is now taking away
this performance penalty penalty security patch.
Oh, man, I wonder if they'd ever do that?
Well, I, I feel like we've never had
a security update with this broad of a performance impact.
Um,
no, no. You know what else though?
I mean, so the way that the patch works is if you're running an A MD system,
it just doesn't do the, the page table isolation, right?
And, and I,
I don't know about Windows or Mac or whatever.
Yeah, I can't speak for them,
but we'll just focus on Linux because that's what we know.
Now,
I would imagine eventually Intel might have a chip they produce,
that doesn't suffer from this, which means, you know,
conceivably you could look for that chip during boot and,
and re enable or I guess not re enable, but don't,
don't turn on the page table isolation patch, right?
Well, my understanding was that
Intel was looking to ship
CP US that don't have this flaw or work around this flaw,
-- you
-- know,
they,
they fix the flaw without the performance impact because
the thing is Mac Os.
Yeah, it's, it's with the PC ID,
Intel, hang on a second
PC ID
because my understanding is with Mac Os
running on more recent
uh Intel CP US that have the PC ID stuff.
There's like no performance hit
and there's some, I have it on my, my desktop and
if I do certain things, I see it,
like, like my audio editor for actually how I edit this podcast.
I, after I upgraded,
I spent some time fiddling with things and like when I start Chrome,
I, I know it's, it's significantly slower, but when I start Chrome,
it generally opens like 100 and 50 tabs.
And so it's doing a bunch of crazy stuff and, and the audio when I edit audio,
when I run certain operations and now mind you
the way audacity kind of deals with things is,
is every episode of this podcast will have
like probably tens of thousands of files in, in directories.
That's how they kind of do it. They split it up into teeny tiny chunks
and, and that is not a happy place right now
when I'm, when I'm doing stuff.
But yeah, my understanding is, is dis
IO especially SSD dis
IO is,
is one of the major problem cases here with this solution.
Yeah.
Right.
But yeah. No.
So well, and speaking of which you mentioned, we're going to talk about Linux only.
I also wanted to talk about Microsoft because
um apparently so
Microsoft in order to fix this had to like
significantly rewrite and monkey with a whole pile of
in like internal memory management stuff
so much so that like most A V software will basically poop itself.
No,
no, it doesn't poop itself. It gives you a blue screen of death.
It sounds like your machine becomes unusable, right?
You get that lovely air that I haven't seen in forever. Thank goodness.
You know where it's like,
call your system administrator and tell him this
magic number and he's going to be like,
what are you talking about?
That's how bo work, right?
I
know.
And um
so there essentially is this registry key that your antivirus software
is supposed to set if it's compatible with the update?
Cool. But
what I'm not clear on is,
well, number one,
if you have really crappy a V that never sets it at
some point is Microsoft going to force this update down your throat.
And number two,
-- what if you don't have a V
-- software? Everyone has a V software now.
And that was my second thought is that if you don't have a V software,
then either you better know what you're doing and set this
key manually or be like you're so far up the creek,
it don't matter
basically. Right.
Well, no, if you, if you don't have a V software, you have Windows defender now,
I don't think you can get away from it. Like you're running a V,
-- you don't have a choice.
-- I was going to test that.
I have one last little laptop running Windows 10 that I was gonna,
I was trying to, I guess if I take it off the network,
I can remove windows defender and then reboot it and see if the update hits.
But
I wanted to try that out or if one of our listeners knows, uh, or anyways,
we'll google it.
But I'm, I'm just curious because
this is definitely going to be something that
people are going to be looking to exploit,
especially by.
I mean, if you, if
the moment somebody writes a working javascript exploit for this,
right? People are going to be like, oh, this is awesome. I love this.
I can like go spy on people that are like looking on my website or,
you know, uh via ads or whatever and, you know, they're gonna do it because I,
I'm kind of tempted to, to be honest.
Um, you know, it's cool like you get to look in people's computers.
So I'm kind of wondering like,
again, you know, what's the patch up take going to be like, I love that Mac Os just
kind of silently fixed it. Apparently. What? Back in December,
-- that's what it sounds like,
-- you know,
kind of like Amazon with their rolling reboots where it's like, uh yeah,
performance sucks now, sorry about that,
you know,
um
Amazon
like I love that I got, this is what also gets me is no,
like I am shocked this issue didn't leak sooner because
it was found in June,
they told Intel
and like people have been working on this for several months.
So this is a perfect example of one of the very few issues
every year that actually needs what I would call like a proper embargo.
I'm not talking like a, like a four day or a one or a two week embargo,
but I'm talking like an embargo
where like you, you kind of
like, what's the longest we can push this embargo?
So we have as much engineering and testing and QE time as possible
so that we can make sure we get this done right? Because
like shell shock, I mean, shell shock, not getting that right.
Whatever it was ugly, people reapplied patches.
But like this is every single,
it's basically every single server on the planet, right?
Except for like my raspberry pie in the basement
and more to the point, I mean,
the the amount of stress and confusion and annoyance it would have.
Yeah, it just
so much.
And so
there was an embargo that lasted and it was supposed
to go for about another week but it leaked early.
I don't know why.
Um I have my thoughts,
people
figure
out,
no,
no, I I can explain that one actually because I mean, you were on the inside,
but I was totally on the outside.
And what ended up happening was there were patches
that went into the Linux kernel.
-- Was
-- it actually just the A MD commit from the 20 ninth?
No, that was what sealed the deal.
But basically what happened was uh probably a week before it leaked.
People were pointing out the these patches that went in
the kernel that were about the page table isolation,
right?
And they said, what's the deal with this?
And of course, there were a bunch of people that were like, oh, it's no big deal,
whatever.
It's just page table
-- isolation.
-- I was like
so sick for seven days over Christmas.
So I, I basically have, I literally have like a seven day gap in my memory.
That's good. That's good.
But
so, so anyway, right there, there were people were wondering, thinking,
what's going on
and then, then the A MD patch landed, people were like, oh yeah, like Intel Chips,
this is a problem.
And then in fact, I, I saw someone on Twitter
posted a, a demo exploit essentially
because they guessed what the issue was and they figured out how to reproduce it.
And at that point and then, and then people started going on and on and on about how,
oh Intel Chips, Intel chips and then Intel
issued their press release and that seems to be when like it was, it was done, right?
Like,
well,
I remember the press release came out and that
was after like the register article and stuff.
Yes. Right. Right.
Like, so, I mean, there were like long articles talking, it was interesting,
you know, they were talking about the performance hit and everything, right.
So this, that, that was part of the problem. Right. It was blowing up.
A, we have a huge problem.
B like the solution sucks and there's a huge performance impact,
you know, everybody's freaking out and, yeah, I do remember that part.
Um Luckily I've been on PTO this week officially, but whatever.
Um
So, yeah, it's, yeah, it,
I,
I mean, can you imagine if this had leaked back in August or July, you know, with,
with not having patches and proper engineering effort
to fix it.
Um, or
I
can
have a solution,
I can tell you it would have happened
is people would have made very poor choices
and then they would, we would have ended up with something terrible.
And in fact, like, like this is something that
when this happened and I was talking to some people
I know who are trying to deal with it.
Like, oh my goodness, we have to hurry up and fix it. I'm like, no,
do not hurry because if you rush, you will make poor decisions.
And I said this isn't so bad.
You need to like, go blow up the garage, take your time and do this. Right?
Well, and that's the funny thing, like on the client side,
this is so exploitable because javascript, right? Like is there a single client
system now that doesn't do web browsing? Like for a lot of its life?
Like when I look at my phone and I look at my laptop and my tablet, like
you know, it's 80% web browsing, 10% fallout shelter, like 10% you know, omni
focus and email.
-- Actually.
-- You want to know what's really cool.
Is I bought a little chromebook for, for my travels
because it, it's way less hackable than, and, and let's face it.
I know you love the Mac. But man, the Mac has like no boot up security.
It's really bad.
But
-- with the T two chip,
-- do they
just read
about it? I haven't paid attention anyway. I have a chromebook.
Do you know what a chromebook is? It's a freaking web browser.
Like that's, that's all it is. It's amazing. It's, it's awesome though.
I really like it.
I've seriously thought about buying one.
the main thing is just,
I haven't gotten around to it because I have an ipad Pro now that basically does that.
-- Yeah.
-- Right. I would assume an ipad
Pro is basically a chromebook. Probably just fancier.
It's got a really nice touchscreen, like, oh my God, it's gorgeous.
I have a touchscreen. I don't know if it's good. I've never touched it.
I don't like touching the screen because then it gets all smudged up.
Like,
I don't know how
figured that one out, but they did.
But yeah, going back to this. So it's uh yeah. No,
the whole thing, just
what's fascinating to me is that the flaw
itself is definitely real and definitely bad.
And like I said, it's, it's
very exploitable.
On the client side because javascript, but on the server side,
let's be blunt on the server side.
-- OK.
-- No, I, I would argue it's worse.
No, let's be blunt on the server side, especially with Linux,
there's enough Linux kernel flaws that if somebody
gets code execution on a Linux box,
sooner or later, they will get root code execution. I mean, there was just,
uh let's go to OS S security and look at like,
was it today's traffic or late yesterday's traffic
where there was yet another Linux kernel flaw where they're like, we don't think,
I mean, it's definitely a denial service
but it may or may not be. Uh Here we go.
Uh I use after free vulnerability was found in network games faces code blah, blah,
blah, blah blah.
This vulnerability could allow an unprivileged
user to induce kernel memory corruption on the system leading to a crash
due to the nature of the flaw privilege escalation cannot be fully ruled out,
although we believe it is unlikely.
All right. And it probably is unlikely. But
literally this email with this Linux kernel flaw is like
-- we get several of these a week.
-- Yeah, but OK, but here's the thing is
on, on a server,
you are probably correct. But on something like an Amazon host,
it's a huge deal man where you've got that shared resources.
This is the magic breakout of the VM thing.
And, but if you remember, like if you look back 10 years ago
VM.
Escapes were all the rage because we had just
built this VM technology and let's be blunt,
security wise, it stunk
and we're going through the same thing with containers, right? Containers
are,
you know, they're good from an operational point of view.
They're amazing, but from a security point of view. Oh, good Lord.
They're, they're not secure yet.
Like we're, you know, now that we have the name spacing stuff going that,
that will add heavily to the security.
Um But I mean, a, a great example of the,
the container issue is like you're still talking to the host colonel
and like I said, you know, the Linux kernel has no end of flaws.
I mean, it's what, 65 million lines of code or something, goofy
give or take,
you know.
So the reality is,
I mean, yeah, VM escapes are really,
really bad because we've come to rely on
V MS for that security barrier like firewalls,
you know?
Right. Right.
Um Like, remember back when firewalls,
you could bypass them with source based routing,
you know,
and like every single firewall currently available at that time,
you could literally just bypass by turning on source routing
and literally putting in the packet,
like go from here to here to here and the firewall is like her, the
ok, doke, you know,
and then firewalls got less stupid.
Yeah.
Well, it's like any technology and this is something that I love to harp about is
nothing starts perfect.
You know, you, you,
you've got to make it better over time and problems
will be found and they will be dealt with.
And I mean,
this issue is part of
what are going to be many similar issues on what will be a very long journey
for Intel because they haven't really had to deal with this kind of problem before.
Well, but I mean, in the last few, well,
in the last week we've had this,
the certificate flaw,
we've had the Intel management engine flaws and the
Intel management engine flaws are arguably much worse because
not only are they like,
exploitable over the network but exploitable over the network when the machine is,
I want to say off right in the sense of you.
And I think like, hey, there's no lights on so it's off, but apparently
it's on because of magic, lights out management slash network, wake up stuff.
You know,
the
magic,
everything is magic. That's the lesson.
Yeah. Well, bad magic or good magic. I don't know.
Yeah.
And I mean, I guess also good news is too, we're also getting layered defenses,
right?
Like, uh Firefox
solution released an update. Chrome is releasing an update that is making
this flaw harder to exploit even if you don't patch the underlying system.
That's really funny. Do you know how the Firefox patch works?
No, they, they made their, their timers suck more.
So you basically.
-- Yeah.
-- Yeah,
they,
they reduce the uh the accuracy of the
-- timers
-- because you need a very high precision timer
to, to,
to exploit this.
And so Firefox no longer has a very high precision timer in javascript,
which means you can still exploit it. Technically, you just can't measure it.
So it's like schrodinger
-- flaw now or something exploit
-- well,
and for an information leak or uh an information disclosure flaw,
that that's good enough.
Well, not only that, actually, I think Firefox doing
is wise because like you said,
everyone's using web browsers for like everything my guess is
most web browsers don't need high precision timing like this.
And
there are going to be more problems similar to this, I think, found in the next six
months to a year.
So Firefox is going to be ok.
Yeah,
almost every single situation I've seen where the server or
whatever client component will report back exactly how long stuff took
ends up being a problem, right? Because it allows an attacker to very
uh
discreetly and, you know, with a high degree of confidence,
figure out what's going on internally to some degree.
-- Actually,
-- you know, it's interesting you bring this up that this has me thinking now
how many applications really need a high precision timer?
My guess is not many.
No, the trick is most of them need a high performance timer
but
-- internally or for logging not to explode.
-- Not
exactly like
my guess is there are very few applications in
user space that actually need high precision timers.
And I wonder if you had like ac group or something
to control
how much I, I guess how, how precise your timing can be
in user space.
You could probably neuter most side channel attacks because let's face it,
side channel attacks
-- almost always rely on timing. I
-- wonder if you can monkey with the system clock.
What do you mean monkey with the system clock
uh reduce the accuracy.
Uh For example, do 10 millisecond chunks or 100 millisecond chunks?
Oh, I see what you're saying.
-- Yeah, that could be
-- like literally the system clocks like it's now
0.1 of a second later.
You want better than that. Too bad. Go away.
Yeah. Well, no, you can re enable it or something, right? I mean,
because there are applications that need it, but most don't funnily.
Yeah, like QT pass, for example,
QT pass, this is great.
QT pass uses lipsy random
which is based on milliseconds or something. But here's the best part is it
instead of using the number of milliseconds since epoch,
which would not have been good, but it would have been
somewhat better than what they did.
They did the number of seconds since or sorry,
they did the number of milliseconds since the last second,
which meant there were 1000 random possibilities.
So QT pass when it was securely generating you a
password would have securely generated you one of 1000 passwords.
Yeah,
that's great.
the uh the original author of the pass code that he was like,
you probably shouldn't use these other
applications to generate passwords because they're,
uh, and in fairness like this reminds me of,
I remember I was reading some C code
and rather than use, make
temp to make a temporary file securely,
they shelled out to bash with a set of six commands trying to make a secure directory.
And the funny thing is if they just shelled out to bash and called
Make a stamp in bash, it would have been fine.
But they actually, like, tried to manually make a directory using shell commands
securely and of course, they failed miserably.
And it was this horrendously complex thing with like
probably 100 times the overhead of just using Make us
T
right.
I see problems like this on a regular basis and I have a suspicion the,
the author didn't know what make it t
is.
I mean, that's what it really comes down to. And so they did what they knew
and it was, it was wrong and it was bad, but it's all they knew.
So,
you know.
But I mean, well, I feel like especially in today's world when you Google,
like make directory securely or something,
you're going to get a good stack overflow answer
you will now.
Yes.
And I guess,
and I guess in fairness the intel guys don't
have that luxury of like how to securely make,
you know, speculative branch predictor.
Oh, hey, look at that answer.
You know.
So I, what I'm curious though is there's got to be more of this.
Oh, you know, there is,
there's tons of it, man.
Well, not only that, I mean, that's something to think about is the fact that the,
there, there's really, there were two flaws,
there's meltdown and specter and meltdown is
what's fixed with the page table isolation
specter is basically unfixable today
and it affects basically every CPU on the planet.
So
that one is where I suspect there's going to be tons of
new and interesting research happening because it's ripe for the picking.
Well, and the beauty is
hardware, it
just can't get updated like software can
I mean, software is bad enough but hardware like,
you know.
Yeah, I, I can't throw it on my laptops, let alone my data center.
Yes, that's micro code man. Right. That's the answer.
-- Except not in this case,
-- right? Minor details.
And
so, but the good news is raspberry pies are immune. So just buy like several
billion trillion. I don't know. Lots, rack them up, you'll be fine.
You know,
that's something I think about a lot is I I've done some investigation into
seeing like how could you build like
a nice Raspberry Pi racked infrastructure thing?
And
it's, it's painful, man. There isn't a good way to power them.
That's really the trick because you need all those stupid micro USB cables.
Uh,
yeah, I guess you could just build an adapter that clicks on to a five volt.
I don't want to do that. I'm so lazy.
They actually for,
for the Raspberry Pi Zeros you can get like this big
board and plug in like 20 of them or something.
And that's really neat and all.
But I'm, yeah, it's, it's more expensive than I'm willing to pay.
I want like four raspberry pies
with a nice rack and like 11 power outlet thing just.
But anyway,
anyway,
right,
I guess the moral of the story is
expect the unexpected
because it's probably gonna happen anyways.
No, that's not the moral moral of this at all.
I think what this is, this issue has been a monkey show, man. I mean,
you look at
it, it, first of all, it got discovered early
and now I'm going to give all the people involved a ton of credit because I
think the Intel and the developers who worked on the patches did a very nice job,
right.
At least a little early, big deal, whatever it happens.
But then everybody jumps in with their own little commentary and everyone's, I,
I've read like 40 blogs describing the issue and some of them got it right.
And like, it's just been
a total circus and I mean,
we're doing a podcast about it obviously, but our focus is on the, the,
I guess fringe things, we'll say maybe the meta
around it. But like,
you know what this feels like to me kind of
the way Intel has done some of their marketing driven announcements
about this and stuff. This feels like security flaws in 2002
when it was very much a marketing problem and not a, a security problem.
Like that's what this feels like.
I think part of it is
the security marketing side of software has become a solved problem.
The security,
the security marketing side of hardware flaws is like something that's sort of
-- new again. It is
-- just beginning is what it is.
Yeah.
Um because there's definitely gonna be more of this.
I mean, people, you know, there's golden in our hills,
you know, why do you rob banks? That's where the money is
now on that note though, exploiting these kind of flaws like
-- this is tough stuff, man. This is like voodoo magic.
-- I mean, until somebody makes a
metis
-- even
-- with a metas
module, man,
this isn't one of those things that you're going
to see people like fuzzing their way into.
I wonder if you could
probably not
anyway,
you
crashes,
whether or not they're exploitable is another matter.
That's what I see with fuzzing mostly is they're like,
here's 200 things that crash law and I'm like, super good for you.
Are they exploitable? And they're like, oh, I don't know. I want you to look at them.
I'm like,
-- don't,
-- I
know, I know. And it ends up being like one patch,
right? Like one little line,
one just check.
That's all it was.
Yeah. So,
um, yeah, this stuff is a lot. Information disclosures are especially
generally more tricky. I mean, funnily enough.
I did find information disclosures back in the day in file wiping programs.
But that was pretty simple because I basically would like, write the hard drive,
uh, you know,
wipe it and then write files to it and then supposedly wipe
it and then try to find any trace of those files,
you know, and
I found traces of them.
Uh, but that, you know, that was easy in the sense of,
I had a lot of control over what was being written and read and all that,
you know, with stuff in the CPU, for example, like
it's, yeah, it's, uh, it's a little more tricky.
Yeah. No, I, I agree completely. I think this one is special. Well, it's special now.
It,
except
it was
one of the three sets of people found it.
So,
you know.
Yeah,
-- special.
-- Like your momma used to say you were special. I am
special. K
we all know that
just not for the reasons I think I am.
But no,
I agree about the monkey circus of like everybody trying to chime in and get their,
they're saying and well,
even a MD is kind of like we're not vulnerable and Intel is like, yes you are.
And
I mean, I love Linus's response of, well, a MD seems confident so, like, cool,
we'll accept this patch and if it bites them, well, too bad for them
and you know what?
-- I think that's totally fair.
-- That's exactly the right way to handle it.
If A MD says we're fine, believe them
and if someone proves them wrong we will make fun of them for a very long time.
Yeah,
I do hope they're right.
Well, just for the sake of it's going to be stressful for a lot of people.
-- If they're not,
-- I,
I'm confident there will be a similar problem found
in a MD chips in the very near future.
Hopefully though A MD has the ability to update the micro code
-- and
-- fix
-- it. Right. Right.
That would be ideal.
-- But we'll see,
-- I also wonder if there's not other defenses people will be looking at,
you know, when they build CP us now to not just have micro code updates,
but what else they can do?
You know?
Uh, probably I'm sure there will be work done
to make sure this kind of stuff isn't a problem in the future.
I guarantee it
-- so.
-- Well,
I guess that's it.
I
guess that's it.
Oh, man, it's been, it's been a week.
Well,
and timing wise that was part of the benefit is
because everybody wanted to get everything ready before Christmas.
And good to go.
-- So it largely was,
-- you know, and honestly,
we are very lucky this didn't leak before Christmas because man,
there would have been some seriously ruined Christmases.
Yep. Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
You figure we took what, two weeks off from podcasting. I'm not gonna lie.
It was kind of nice,
but we're back, we're back. People have to put up with us again. So.
All right, cool, man.
I'm, I'm calling it, I'm calling it. I don't think we can add much more to this one.
So, thank you everyone for listening. Thank you, Kurt.
You can go to open
source security podcast.com. For the show notes.
There's a link to Facebook group.
You can hit us up on Twitter with the Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag
And yeah, if nothing else, Kurt, you have a fantastic rest of your day.
Yeah.
And I hope everybody actually has a better rest
-- of their year
-- and patch your system folks.
That's all.
Yes.
Yeah.
For the love of God. Apply system updates from your vendor,
right? And, and patch heart
-- while
-- you're, that's what you're paying them for.
Biker
the