Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself.
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime. Josh Pressers.
Oh, man. So, you know what something
I,
-- we laugh
-- because
300 in the bunker
is it?
I don't, it's been
years
I
think,
I don't
know.
I have no idea anymore. Time is an illusion.
That's,
that is my life now.
I think of it every day.
I can't even imagine how bad it is for our kids. Right.
Because they've been out of school for five months.
Yeah.
Yeah. Actually it's funny because
we were talking to our Children about going back to
school and they're going to do all virtual and stuff.
And my daughter's like, I just want to go to a real school and we're like,
yeah, we want you to go too. But
you can't. So there you go.
It's
anyway. Anyway, whatever it is,
it
is what it is. The dumpster fire of 2020.
Well,
the good news is there's other people that do silly things and take years to fix
what seemed to me to be pretty, I don't want to say a simple security flight.
It's simple on the surface and I know it's more complicated under the surface,
but fundamentally,
it seems like this is something Microsoft should have fixed a long time ago.
Yeah, why don't you
issue and then we can go into some details.
So as we all know if you're going to distribute files,
signing them is the most perfect way to secure the whole thing, right?
You sign the file, customer downloads the file checks the signature,
the signature is safe.
What could go wrong? Nothing, right?
It's not like people could go by code
signing certificates or steal them or anything,
right?
That's just not possible. So it's fine.
And so the deal is you download like an MSI installer, your system,
your windows machine checks the file signature, the
signature matches and you're you're totally safe to double click on it.
Nothing can go wrong. Sure.
And then, well,
there's this little annoying problem of apparently with an M SI file,
you can actually append data to the back of it.
Like you can take the M SI file and like literally cat space file name, you know,
greater than greater than M SI and just jam a bunch
of data onto the back of the M SI sort of.
Yeah, I mean it's conceptually it's that simple like it's not,
-- you don't need a hex
-- editor.
Well, ok, so here is what's actually happening
and
this is hilarious for all of the right reasons.
So it's not just M si it, it, well, ok, you can take any M si, ok.
It just has to be a signed M SI
which is like the Microsoft installer format or whatever.
And you then append a jar file to the end
and then you rename
the new file
with a dot Jar extension. What happens is hilariously stupid.
So a jar file is just a zip file, the,
the lovable compression format we've all had for a million years.
And
this is important because floppy disks are part of this story, right?
I'll, I'll, I'll, I'll,
I'll let you wait in suspense as to how floppy disks come into play here.
But so anyway, you append these two files, you rename it dot Jar.
And so basically what happens is if there's a signature check
on the file, it's going to pass because the way a signature works is
these M si files, basically, there's like the, the file content, right?
The actual meat of the file
and then it's wrapped around a little shell
and the little shell basically says like,
oh, there,
here's the signature and here's what's in the file and here's what's going on
and that's the thing that windows or antivirus or whatever is going to look at
and then check.
But the beauty of it is, it'll say, OK, I'm the wrapper around the content.
Here's the signature and the next 10,000 bytes is the file, right?
So obviously the thing is going to check the 10,000 bytes,
it's going to calculate the check sum.
It's going to check the signature and it says everything checks out. That's great.
Except there's uh megabytes of garbage on the end.
But we'll just ignore that because we don't care.
Technically speaking, if you treat it as an M si it doesn't matter.
It's right. It's metadata, whatever. Now,
zip files,
they have the unique property of storing the metadata for zip at the very end.
Well, it makes sense.
Well, it makes sense in the context of why they do it in history.
This is where the floppies come in.
So back in the day, you had the ability to tell the PK zip command,
which is,
that's a blast from the past on M sds that I want you to zip this data
onto floppy disks.
And I don't know how many it will take because obviously you can't,
you can't say, OK, I've got 12 megabytes of data.
You're going to need,
you know, 10 floppy disks or whatever.
There's no way to prec calculate that in a reasonable manner.
Well,
this also assumes that your floppy disks actually hold
1.44 megabytes because I don't know about you.
But I,
I had a tendency to recycle those free AOL floppy
disk that would hold anywhere from a couple 100 K to
-- whatever they were supposed to hold.
-- Exactly.
And I mean, there were different sizes of floppy disk, whatever.
There's a million things that could happen.
So basically,
what zip did is it just started zipping crap and writing to disk it fill up a floppy,
say give me a new floppy
and it didn't care how big it was, whatever, it didn't matter.
You just start feeding it floppies and then it gets to the end and it says I'm all done.
Now, I'm going to write the metadata onto the floppies.
And so if you ever then unzipped,
it would basically say unzip this file on this floppy and then say, oh,
insert the last disk.
OK. Now I know what's going on now, insert these disks anyway.
The long story is that basically the signatures
checked at the beginning of the file,
the zip content is at the end jar files are just zip files.
So you rename it dot Jar.
It passes signature checks,
you double click it and it's going to run your malicious jar content.
Well, and also I think there's a subtle thing where
the signed file is a signed portion of the file.
And that is a big distinction because when I heard this, I'm like, wait,
how can you have a signed file that has crap in it.
That's not signed, that is no longer a signed file.
You've signed part of the file, this other crap. What is that? Like?
-- It's not signed, it's not part of the signed file. It shouldn't be
-- there.
It's metadata.
And I think that I, I think it's, well, so it's that perfect combination of
one thing reads from the front, one thing reads from the back
and
it treats a signed, it's,
I hate using the word signed file in this context because in my mind,
a signed file means the entire file is signed like an R PM
-- or like a AP GP.
-- Well, R PM does this too though.
Yeah. Well, exactly.
-- And that's broken
-- R PM literally does exactly this.
So, and here's so here's a challenge.
Here's something like a thought experiment for all of us. I want you
to have a file
that has the check sum of the file
as content in the file.
-- I've done that with shell scripts. No,
-- you didn't.
Yeah. Yeah,
I don't believe you.
What you do though is so you have a shell script like it's,
and it's like basically bang bin bash
and then you have like check some equals whatever number and then you basically
have a function that reads the entire file except for the top two lines,
check sums it.
I don't mean that that's cheating.
-- That's literally what you
-- want.
The signature embedded in the file with the whole file.
-- OK.
-- Well, then you basically you use MD five and a bunch of playstations.
Yeah,
that is,
don't use MD five, please.
Actually with MD five, you could probably do some magic to do it.
-- But here's the point,
-- right?
No, no, no, there's, there's, there's source code out there to build
these files. OK. Maybe.
But here's,
here's the point of this thought experiment is
signing the whole file is basically computationally impossible,
especially if you're using say like sha 512, which is very large and is slow.
And so that's why they kind of sheet in this way.
Now, this is also why there's things called detached signatures
where you can, for example, say here is a whole file.
I want you to sign it and then put the signature in this file over here.
And that gives you obviously an instance where now you can
sign the entire file. You don't just have to sign parts of it.
And I mean, this is, this is perpetually a challenge because
what do you sign? How do you sign it? Do you sign all of the content?
Do you sign the headers?
Like this is a challenge at R PM, for example, where you have an R PM header,
then you have R PM content.
-- What do we sign? How do we do this?
-- I would say honestly at this point in it's 2020. Yes.
Sign everything.
Well, I mean, yeah, I agree.
You sign the content and the headers like come on guys, it's
girls like it's, it's 2020 we sign everything because
if you don't sign it,
somebody's going to tamper with it and we're all going to
-- end up in tears
-- even if you do sign it.
Yeah.
OK.
Yeah. So, no, I get it.
But, I mean, the thing is too,
we've had a lot of systems that have signed things reasonably correctly.
So it's not like this is impossible. Oh, right.
It's, it's definitely, and look, here's the thing.
So I'm going to this Microsoft bug, I would break down in two pieces.
-- There's the angle of this was a stupid mistake and they obviously fixed it
-- after two,
after being notified, two years after they were notified,
it took longer than it should have.
And I don't think there's necessarily a great excuse for that.
But my suspicion is the reason it took so long
is they were like,
how, you know,
you've got to get a file on the system and then
a user has to double click the file and like,
how often is that really going to happen?
So this Windows 10 computer I just bought and
the drivers I was downloading from the motherboard website.
Uh, there's some pretty sketchy,
like I was downloading some stuff that wasn't signed and it's just like, you know,
click the ignore button and continue with.
Yes and like enter your password to force Windows to install it.
And I'm kind of like, well, I guess I want my network to work so I better do this.
And, um,
there was, you know, I was downloading science stuff and in one instance,
my favorite is I bought a new computer mouse
-- and the driver for it. Was actually hosted off of mega.
-- Yeah, you told me about that.
That's hilarious.
I guess that's a cheap way to host a file.
But, like, it's an unsigned file coming off of mega.
I'm like,
I'm throwing this thing through virus total and it's one of the
few instances where the file had been put through virus total.
Well, a lot, like a long time ago.
So somebody else had that thought too where they're like, you want me to do what? Now?
With where?
Um, so no, this is, there's tons
of, and the thing is also, I was getting signed M SI files
and signed DXC files to, you know,
install various drivers and stuff off of insecure
websites or off of insecure content delivery networks.
So there's a ton of signed files floating around out there.
And then my favorite thing is, of course, is what happens if you Google like
your, your, your most part, your most part number. Slap space drivers.
Do you?
Does it,
does Google Point you at the like Corsair or
Steel Series website first or some like dodgy,
like most drivers.com?
I mean, you never know. That's one of the challenges always.
It, it could go anywhere.
Some of these drivers were like most drivers.com or whatever and I'm like, nope,
not going there.
-- Yeah. No, I, I
-- agree. You and your printer drivers for your relatives.
Yeah, this is, this is why I just buy crappy mice off Amazon that don't need drivers.
I'm not a cool kid. Anyway.
Anyway, anyway,
so I think sort of the root cause of this whole thing
is that there's no established way to handle and treat a file,
right?
Like is a file, a zip file because it says dot zip or is it a file, a zip file?
Because the file is actually physically like a zip file as far as I know there's,
there's no iso or
standard on this, right. You just kind of do your best.
And,
yeah, I, it's, it's complicated. Right.
I agree. The good news is they fixed it.
The bad news is that, you know, how many systems got infected by this?
We will never know.
I know.
Let's just say, hey,
users don't download crap off the internet because it's your fault.
There we go. Problem solve.
Well, and this is what drives me nuts.
I, I should be able to reasonably download files and
run them now, whether or not, you know,
if I give a file permission to install to my system then, yeah,
kind of all bets are off.
But even that shouldn't be so unsafe that it like bricks my system or, you know,
totally destroys my system.
Which, uh, you know,
I think that's a pretty simple reason why tablets have taken off.
Right. Because you, you can't screw up your tablet like this.
Yeah.
Like there's literally nothing my kids can do their tablet that would mess it up.
Versus if I gave Felix admin privileges on the Windows 10 machine, what, maybe a day,
two days
before
a
-- couple of hours,
-- man.
I mean, I, I, so I actually gave my kids admin access to the Windows machines.
I have an admin account and I gave them the PIN code and I was like,
just try not to screw it up too bad.
But yeah, that machine as far as I'm concerned
is an adversary.
I never use it in a,
we'll say, man, like I, I've never logged into Google on it. I've never logged in.
The only thing I log into is Steam so I can play games.
And I'm like, you know what, it would suck if my Steam account got stolen,
but I would not cry too hard if it did.
So I can live with that. I would lose my 500 games. I've never played that would
anyway. Anyway.
All right, let's move on to the git lab news story that we found.
So I will, I will explain this one basically Git lab which is like an open source.
Github
competitor.
Fundamentally said we're not going to allow
support to reset multi
authentication on free accounts.
And I'm curious, just give me your hot take on this. What do you think?
Funny,
you mentioned that I was just logging into youtube on
my ipad and I was having trouble and it said,
basically log in with your key or a PIN code
and if none of this works and you need to recover your code,
it's going to be 3 to 5 business days to contact Google
and
I have a paid Google account with which allows
me to have the advanced protection turned on,
which I do have turned on.
So the reality is doing account recovery beyond.
Oh, you control that email address. That's you. Cool.
Is
expensive.
I had a friend who had their, I think it was Pinterest or Instagram account hacked
and they had to go through account recovery and what they did.
And I thought this was very clever.
They had to,
they basically got a one time code via email that they then had to like
write on a piece of paper and hold up and take a selfie with.
And that actually works with like Pinterest and Instagram because they have
past pictures of you on your account, right? So they can,
they can do like a proof of life picture with you,
but that requires a human being by and large.
The thing is if you want to do account recovery securely,
then you basically have to have either
a hugely complicated technical system that is
basically a human being or you actually have to have a human being.
And that costs money like a five or 10 minute phone call,
even with a poorly paid support person
-- that's costing the company 1020 bucks.
-- Well, not only that,
there's So from what I read
about Git lab,
I don't think that was even necessarily the inception of this.
I feel like this is more of a,
lots of people are using this now
and we're seeing Attackers
abusing our basically friendly support staff to gain access to account.
So our solution is just to not do it. Which
-- I mean,
-- well, that's the Google way.
-- Yeah, and I'm not opposed to
-- it.
Well, I mean, the perfect example is like, you know,
somebody's homeless and they're saying, look, I have no ID,
like I got rolled, like I got mugged my ID, all my, you know, all my identification,
all my papers, all my worldly possessions are missing, but I'm Bob and I want to,
you know, get registered for this program or for some support thing.
Well, what do you do? Right.
If we, we generally don't have biometrics of people in North America, you know,
there's countries out there like, um I think India is one where they're collecting,
you know, fingerprints as part of the ID scheme.
But fundamentally if somebody claims, hey, I'm Bob but, you know,
I got mugged and all my ID and everything's missing.
Well,
yeah, what do you do then? Right? You can't prove a negative.
Like you can't make Bob prove that he lost his
ID because he could just throw it in the garbage.
It shouldn't be git
lab's job to do that.
Well, but it is, if they own the account, right? If they're hosting the account
and somebody shows up and says that's my account, but I don't know my password.
I've, what the extreme is like, install Google Chrome.
And it's like you want to, I want like, do you want to log in?
Did you forget your email address?
And I'm like, how the heck do people forget their email address?
But apparently it happens enough
that that's in the first screen of logging into Chrome.
It's like if you forgot your email address, you can enter your phone number.
And I actually did this once to see what happens,
plugged in my phone number and it like,
spat out all my email addresses that are register
with that phone number. And I'm like, oh, ok.
And I've talked to some people about this who work in, you know,
in public service and they're like, yeah,
we deal with people all the time where we
ask them their email address and they're like,
-- I don't know,
-- that's a meet space government problem
though. And I view that as different.
The point being is that,
you know,
we live in a somewhat privileged world where we expect
people to have their user names and accounts and passwords.
And the reality is what percentage of people use a password manager personally.
I'm going to guess about maybe 1%.
I'd be shocked if it's that high.
And it might be 1% though because there's people
like me who force my Children to use it.
That's true. My whole family is using it and it's, it's actually really funny is so,
uh my son who is
dreaming of becoming a youtuber,
he,
he's setting up all of his youtube stuff
and one of his options was he decided to
create like a special account just for youtube stuff,
which I'm like, that's not the worst idea in the world.
It's like
they're asking me about two factor O.
I said you better install two factor
off. Like
there's no excuse not to.
Well, and the good news is like, I know natively in the apple world, you know,
with Safari, it's doing password management, your web browser and stuff.
Same in chrome. Firefox does the same, I assume internet
or what is it edge now? Whatever it is edge.
So that's, and, and let's face it.
Web based passwords and credentials are like,
pretty much that's all that matters to people.
Like I'm trying to think if I have any credentials for
anything else that matters and the answer is nothing important.
No account recovery is one of the easiest ways to hack someone because
you don't have to guess their password.
Hell, you don't even have to guess their user name in half the cases.
You just phone up the support and you're like, I'm Bob and I want my account, please.
Right. And this is
so my, what I always like to tell people about this is,
this is something that sounds really easy in theory.
And if you're say
hosting data for six people, it is,
well, it is easy because they know those six people,
right?
And it's different when you try to scale this problem and it becomes very difficult.
And especially when you're dealing with adversaries,
there's almost nothing you can do.
And adversaries if they are motivated,
they will acquire the information, they need
to accomplish their task.
There actually is one thing you can do that's rather clever as you just don't do it.
And that, and I,
I don't mean like git lab where you just don't provide support for that.
But for example, the CS A has some systems where
we really, really don't want you to make an account,
we want you to log in through a different account
provider like Google or Twitter or Facebook or linkedin.
I agree with that 100%.
There's no way unless you give me like about $100 million that I can provide
anything approaching the security and reliability of like
-- a Google
-- login a long time ago.
I was, I think it was at
OCON, maybe I had lunch
with someone who was working on the Microsoft Identity platform and I don't even,
this might have been before office 365 even existed.
I mean, this was, this was a long time ago.
And anyway,
I was talking to this guy and something I'd never considered
before because he told me that on a daily basis,
Microsoft was seeing billions
of failed
login attempts that were malicious.
And I know I was like, that's
-- nuts. I couldn't fathom that.
-- Well, credential stuffing.
I mean,
there's public databases of all the passwords that people have used.
Yes, exactly. That. And so this is, I mean, this guy
over the course of lunch basically completely revolutionized
my thinking on authentication on the internet.
And so they obviously they see this, but he said the most important part of it
is they collect this data
and then they use it to protect other users. So for example,
they might see 2 million login requests coming from some IP address in the Ukraine.
And they're like, well, this IP address is just never going to log in, right?
Like we're going to block it for a month.
You think about that on a on a scale of me running a computer on the internet,
I can't
fathom
doing something like that, right?
But to them, no big deal now,
now they know when that when that person running that attack,
when they do hit a valid login,
they're still going to fail. That's huge.
Well,
a great example of this is log into your Gmail through a Tor
enabled browser and you're going to have to re log in constantly.
I would hope so. And I'm OK with that,
-- right?
-- Because those Tor
exit nodes are, let's just say dodgy
like that. I don't mean the Tor
exit node itself is dodgy but like the,
the kind of people that use them to log into Gmail.
I mean, well, you know,
I've worked for a company where we provided a service and we
found that 100% of the signups through Tor IP S were malicious.
I don't doubt that.
And so we ended up blocking signups through Tor
IP S.
Now you could access your account through Tor.
We didn't care that that was fine
but the actual sign up part,
not, there was not a single legitimate sign up through
Tor.
-- It was always malicious people hiding their tracks and stuff.
-- I believe that.
And in fact, it was just a report that came out the other day.
I'll see if I can dig it up and throw it in the show notes.
But they basically point out the fact that like a nontrivial number of Tor exit
nodes are believed to literally be malicious where
they're spying on what users are doing.
Somebody ran a research paper looking at what ports
were blocked and there were Tor exit nodes blocking.
Like
um this is years ago when Tor was actually still reasonably fresh,
but it was blocking like all the encrypted email options.
Like it would allow port 110 and 19 for IMAP and pop, but it was blocking um like,
uh what is it like 553 or whatever the encrypted IMAP and encrypted pop options.
One.
Yeah.
So, same thing for Web. It was blocking 443 and allowing port 80.
Now, obviously, nowadays that wouldn't work,
but back in the day it did and I guess maybe somebody's stupid enough to use Tor
and be like, oh,
you know, I can't get my mail encrypted. So I'm going to
go to unencrypted.
I bet a lot of male clients a long time ago would just fail over and not say anything.
-- I mean, that was the way things used to work.
-- Well, that's it. The
even US supported encryption. I remember
when they started supporting encryption and setting it up was often quite a chore.
The other aspect of this is that whole law of large numbers, right? Like,
there's a fundamental difference between making dinner for one person,
making dinner for 10 people, making dinner for 100 people
and making dinner for 10,000 people. Were to be blunt,
-- you're now managing a logistics chain. You're not making dinner. Yeah,
-- exactly.
This is what git lab is doing is where Git lab basically went
from being the cool alternative kid on the block to now they're,
they're having to deal with logistics and infrastructure
and it's different.
-- The,
-- the reality is even if they were somehow able to provide the service,
they just don't have enough bathrooms and parking for all the people.
No, like, really, I mean, you know,
it always astounds me.
I remember the official alternate seat of government here in Alberta was, uh,
it's a building called Government House.
It's by the old Provincial Museum. It's a lovely stone building.
It's the Lieutenant Governor's mansion and I believe it had
something like 20 phone lines and about a dozen toilets.
And I'm like,
that is not going to work so well as the alternative to
government when you try and cram like 300 people in there.
Yeah. Right. Right. I, oh man, no.
You know, so you know what's funny is this is one of those things that
I think as humans were really bad at understanding.
We, we look at our,
our one computer with three users and we think it
wouldn't be that hard to scale it up and,
and it's kind of, I forget,
I forget where there's some culture
that basically their counting system is 123 more than three.
And I,
I get that
like
it is, it is so hard for us to envision
things at scale
and
it, it feels like we should be able to just say, oh,
that's easy or II I understand or I can do that and
it's not, I mean, so one of my, a great example I have actually is. So
I know we've talked about this in the past,
but I basically took all of the Bitcoin data and I shoved it into elastic search,
right.
And I did do all this fun stuff with it.
Of a fun talk I give and whatever.
But the point is like when I started,
I was basically doing things in a nice linear manner, right?
And you don't think about it.
But I could say, oh, I'm doing like a couple of 100 entries per second.
I, I'm like, I'm on fire here. But then you realize a couple 100
entries per second when you have literally now, like, you know,
500 million transactions.
Like
that's,
I'll be dead before this is done.
And so,
and it's funny,
it's totally changed my perspective on a lot of things because I realized like,
I need to be able to process
millions of things per second to even hope to make this practical
and to get a meaningful answer in a short time frame.
Right. Right. And so it's, it's,
it changes your perspective when you have to scale things up.
Well, not just scale them up but make them still happen fast.
Like again, if you're going to make dinner for 10,000 people,
you can't take three months.
That is a good point. You would have a revolt.
You actually have, you have like a two hour window to feed everybody
otherwise it's not dinner anymore.
Right.
Just blends into drinks in the evening. No, I mean, I, I agree. I totally get this,
here's how I will end this, this conversation.
It is a curse and a blessing when you reach this point because it means git
lab has been successful enough that they have to worry about this level of scale.
And the curse is obviously you have reduced some of the
user experience value that you could obviously bring in the past.
My comment on this would be I think
places and this will a lot of people are going to hate me for saying this.
But I think places should as much as possible avoid human support,
not because they can save money and create crappy user experience.
But because they should actually invest in creating a really good
automated support system, but even better prevent the support from being needed.
Do things, you know, like Google is doing things on the front end so that you can, oh,
I forgot my email address, plug in my phone number.
Oh, there's my email address right now.
I remember, you know, things like that because that's
the only thing that is sustainable in the long term.
I think that's a really powerful statement.
Otherwise, otherwise you're doing artisanal it services which,
and there's a market for that.
Right. There's a market for that. Absolutely.
You know,
there's old people that will happily pay 50 bucks
an hour for somebody to hold their hand.
It's a small market though. Good luck with that.
-- Yeah,
-- it doesn't scale.
I mean, I think that's a powerful statement you just made and I think it's, it
is the right way to do things. I think, I think designing to not
support is the,
it's the only way you should be designing
a great example of this is road construction,
right?
You look at interstate freeways in the US and
they are amazingly well designed from a safety perspective,
right?
You have this like 10 to 20 yard run out on either side, that's basically flat.
So even if you come off the road,
you're basically going to lose speed before you hit anything.
In theory, you have guard rails.
I mean, when you look at them,
you look at those youtube videos of people crashing and walking
away from it now in like just normal cheap cars.
And a lot of that is the car, but a lot of that is also the road design, you know,
Jersey barriers that redirect the energy upwards the guard rails the here locally,
I've noticed we have a big ring road,
the Anthony Hendy Drive and pretty much the entire thing now in the middle, you know,
the, the metal stakes with the three or four wires
and like there's a couple of spots where it got clobbered.
Well, yeah, those are designed to sell you down
on, well, and to prevent you from going into oncoming traffic when you wipe out.
-- Right. Right.
-- That's going to end poorly.
The challenge there as well.
And the thing to always remember and the thing we don't have in it is
those kind of safety measures and those kind of regulations are written in blood.
We don't kill a lot of people. Thank goodness.
-- The
-- thing is, at least people are thinking about it and the systems are starting to do
to get better.
You know, Google has put in your recovery, uh email address,
put in your recovery phone number, nominate a recovery person.
So again, I don't know if you notice this in your Google account, right?
Because you pay,
but you're a super admin for your organization and you
can nominate someone else to be your recovery person.
I have not looked at that. II, I don't, I don't know if I can do that or not.
-- If it's
-- paid, you can,
you're paying, right?
Oh,
-- that's
-- right. Your grandfather in, under the free one
way back in the day,
it's always Google's accounts are all separate that way. It's really messy.
-- Like
-- I don't have enough people that really matter. But it's like,
I,
it'll cost me a couple of 100 bucks a year
isn't the end of the world, but it's like I'm pretty happy not to pay anything.
-- I
-- honestly pay so that I didn't have to worry about them.
Like going away or I had some recourse basically.
-- Yeah,
-- I
-- should,
-- I should probably look into that because it's,
if I lost my personal email address,
it would,
-- it would make me sad.
-- It would be a problem
actually. So I'll end on this one silly story is I was talking to a friend.
So I I've set up, I've got some honey pots running in digital ocean
for
and,
and obviously just to kind of pay attention to
some attacks going on right now in the world.
And this guy was saying, oh, I'm going to set this all up in, in GCP.
And I said I never run anything even remotely questionable in Amazon
or Google just because I don't want them one day being like,
we think you're a bad guy.
Like all your, all your accounts are gone. Now,
that is my nightmare.
Well, my favorite is those people who are like,
Google suspended my account and they're like, but you're not a Google customer.
So you can't talk to us,
even if you are a Google customer, you can't talk to them.
I mean,
like that's one of the things I think is,
is if something bad happened to my Google account,
I would be like, who do I know who works for Google?
I wouldn't even dream of trying to go through support.
I would totally backdoor myself in because I know that's
the only way I might maybe have some traction.
Yeah, pretty much
anyway, I'm calling it. It is.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening. You can go to open
source security, podcast.com. Head up the show notes, Suzy Podos
says podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks
-- everybody.
All right, thanks, everyone. Bye bye.