Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself.
Kurt Siefried and my partner and being slightly sick but not entirely sick,
Josh Bresser,
I'm not sick anymore. I mean, maybe, I don't know. I feel pretty good.
I can't complain. It is amusing though because Kurt knows this, but no one else does.
After we hit stop last week,
I became violently ill for 24 hours to the point.
Like I, I just mumbled incoherently in, in bed. So I'm, I'm standing up again.
It's quite nice.
But anyway, anyway,
my kids brought home something from school.
That's how it works, man.
That's part of the fun,
I guess, ironically, in this particular instance, it seems I, I was patient. Zero.
So I got to get my kids sick finally for once.
Anyway, I don't think I've ever done that.
-- I bet you have.
-- You just don't know it.
One of my,
one of my core memories of my Children when they were
small was Felix looking up at my face with love.
He's about 34 years old.
I'm reading him a story and he just looks at my face with love coughs into my throat,
like, and I can feel it hit the back of my throat and I'm just, like,
oh,
and then, like, yeah, 24 hours later it's like, I don't feel so good.
Yeah. Yeah, we've all been there. It's the joy
of parenthood. Anyway. Anyway, we're going to talk about something better.
Well, this is basically the topic at hand is the so
called supply chains
where
I, you know, these companies are, like,
you make a software component that we use and we need you to fix it and update it
and keep it secure and enable two fa on your account and do a bunch of other stuff.
And like Google wrote a blog posting where they
were even proposing that for the critical software components
that,
that you could not be anonymous. Like
you have to
hold
on
-- just all sorts of insanity.
-- I know, I know, OK, let's back this up all the way.
There is a, a person who is, I'm, I apologize for butchering your name,
but I believe it's
Iana
at a on, I can't pronounce the last name,
but they wrote a blog post and there will be links in the show notes,
obviously that says there is no software supply chain
and they put software supply chain in quotes.
And then this person goes on to just kind of lay out
some of their grievances with what we're currently calling.
And like, obviously, Kurt and I talk about the software supply chain constantly.
But, but basically talking about that
the, the software supply chain
as defined today is really these kind
of large corporations strip mining open source,
we'll say,
versus the developers who are doing this for fun and it's something they want to do.
And obviously these two groups have we say
-- opposing viewpoints and goals,
-- well, incentives.
And so to be clear, there is a commercial
software supply chain, like for example, Wolf Ssl.
Right.
Yeah.
Oh Right.
Oh What was it? It was like an HTML to PDF converter that was commercial.
And you know, anyways, the point is though
when you compare that
to the open source market,
it's like comparing an apple to one of those Maersk container ships.
You know what I mean? Like in that they both exist, but one is
just multiple, multiple, multiple scales larger and more widely used.
And I think that's part of the challenges people are
conflating the commercial supply chain with the open source supply chain
and the open source supply chain is vastly huger and
totally different set of rules
like literally
in the licenses.
And I think
a lot of the corporations using open source are
will say expecting the same things from open source you might expect from
working with
-- a company.
-- Well, and I think it's worse because they look at the open source world
and they see that the majority of people
have been treated quite well by their supply chain
but I think they forget that it was people being treated well by the supply chain,
not large companies that were strip mining it, right?
Like there's a vast difference,
you know, if me or Josh goes to some open source developer, like, hey, you know,
we like, oh man, like this would be a killer feature.
Could you maybe implement it
or, you know, hey, I found this bug and I think this patch might work,
but it's not great.
I don't really understand the code too well, you know,
when you're dealing with a human like that, it's, you know, it's like,
oh, I'm at a stoplight the other day and I like, look over and I'm like,
I start shouting at the guy. I'm like, hey buddy, buddy and he's like, what?
And I'm like your car is leaking like straight up.
There's like something leaking from the bottom of your car.
I can't see what color it is
but like, I know that that part of your car shouldn't be dripping like that.
And he's like, 00, thank you.
You know, like humans want to help each other,
right? That's how it works. Like, oh, Josh, you dropped your wallet. Here you go.
You know, I even left the money in it for you,
right?
But you know, when it comes to a large company, it's like
no man, like I'm not gonna go out of my way to, you know,
do what they want me to do for them for free.
Well, ok, I, and I can't be sure their expectations are insane
in
many,
a lot of times they are. But, ok,
let's reframe this a little bit before we just go on this big ranting binge
against giant corporations.
So if we look at this blog post,
there's a couple of things in it that I think really stand out that, that I like a lot.
And
one of them, I think the most interesting one is
there was a security advisory
github released
that was, it's titled ant C underscore term is unmaintained.
And this is a a rust package that apparently hasn't been updated in three years.
And the author basically said like this isn't maintained and then
it looks like someone submitted a security advisory to github,
github
published the security advisor. He did not get a CV ID, just a GHS A ID
and then
it was retracted
some period of time later
because people kind of freaked out a little bit because kind of, I mean,
one of the questions becomes like, is that a security issue if a,
an open source package is no longer maintained?
I mean, that's a harder question.
This speaks to what the GSD is doing, which is, is it a vulnerability?
No.
Is it a security concern?
Yes.
And there's a difference there, you know, like I would love like,
because I do this all the time I go and I look for a package I need to do something.
Um For example, I need like
uh 01 thing I need right now is a Yaml to
Json converter.
And so I go looking for them and you know,
I look in pi pie and I look in a bunch of
other places and it turns out that there aren't really aren't many.
So a better example would be oh
json
um merge, I need a thing to merge Json files. And so I look at pi pie
and there's like a bunch of them.
And so I start looking at kind of like, well, how much are they, you know,
how many releases have they had?
Oh, this one's like a 0.002.
This one's like 1.3 0.0
and then I also look at like, when's the last release date,
you know.
And so a perfect example of this is um oh, I was looking for ac pe library to, you know,
process C pe strings.
-- You
-- just talked about that last week,
you can
tell
the last ones from 2016. But that's OK because C pe is from 2011
and that's the thing. So,
you know, I'm, I'm trying to find healthy maintained software
mostly because I'll find a bug in it.
I would like to have somebody that I can maybe ask nicely to
fix it
versus, you know, an unmaintained library where OK. Now it's my problem
OK.
So I think you accidentally hit on an important point with that statement is
you
Kurt, the developer
kind of have an idea of what to look for in
the open source world where you're looking at a library,
you're understanding what's in it, you're making informed decisions.
But you also, you have a great deal of knowledge about open source.
If you are someone, let's say who doesn't necessarily know a ton about open source,
you're just gonna start pulling in stuff that does what
you need and you're not gonna necessarily pay attention.
And I think
this is part of where the supply chain story starts to collapse a little bit.
I think in the open source world is these companies, I think
were just pulling stuff in for a long time with no regard for what it was.
And all of a sudden they figure out, oh, holy cow, what am I doing?
And instead of looking inward
and saying, let's figure out what happened, let's figure out how to solve this.
They say open source, why did you make me hit myself?
Well,
and it's worse than that and that they pull the
first library that kind of does what they want and then
quite often they'll encounter like, oh,
it doesn't do everything we want like it does 90% of what we want.
I need this fixed,
right? Like or there's a security flaw.
And the other thing is I the supply chain
-- metaphor implies contracts.
-- I mean, well, business relationships do. Sure.
And the thing is you can't
really have that in the open source world with random open source does because
this is what drives me nuts is for a contract to exist.
There has to be an intention to contract, right?
There has to be an offer to contract, an acceptance of that offer
and a consideration
and there is no consideration ever in this
license. No, no
said this so
-- provided as is
-- but, but if you look at contract law,
there's no consideration. There is no,
there's nothing coming back from that company back to the open source developer.
So in in my mind, the open source developer is completely
blameless
because like, I mean, if I publish it,
like I literally have written crap Python scripts that I, I just chuck onto my github
publicly under, you know, the Apache 2.0 license
and like
in theory, some company could download this and start using it and relying on it
and then get angry at me when it doesn't do what they want. And I'm like, well, no,
too bad.
Well, OK, but, but no one cares. OK?
I I think that comes to the second part of this is your,
you're personifying some of these companies and some of
the companies are good about getting involved in being,
you know, stewards of open source and some of them are just like,
I'm gonna file a bunch of issues and complain constantly about the free stuff,
networking.
But
there is as part of this
blog post there, Google wrote a thing in February of 2021.
It's called known comma Prevent Comma Fix a framework
for shifting the discussion around vulnerabilities and open source.
And it lays out kind of a lot about the, we'll say the problems with open source which,
-- well, it takes a very corporate approach to
-- this. It takes a very Google approach.
Like
it,
it talks a lot about all of these expectations around open source and
things like you said at the beginning about you can't be anonymous and
you need to be using single sign on and you need to have
multiple sign offs on commits and you need to have vulnerability databases and
how does that work with those single developer projects?
Well, and, and that's just it, right? This, this casts all of open source
into
the
the play doh mold
that Google wants it to have. And I mean, this is Google has always done this right?
Where Google is a giant company.
They, they live in Google land where they can do things like zero trust correctly
because they have more security people than you have employees.
They have vending machines with like spare parts for your computer that
you can just walk down the hall and grab a new mouse
because it's cheaper to do it that way, right?
And that's just it though, like,
I think Google doesn't always see the world the way a lot of other people do.
And if you're, if you're a single open source person,
the world you live in is not the world Google lives in for the most part.
And, and I think
this is true of many large corporations is when you are part of a big company,
you exist in a very different space than when you're say
part of a start up or if you're one person.
And
I think
this is something that's often forgotten when we talk about like supply chain.
I mean,
I even see this like at the open SSF where we have all these people talking about, oh,
we need to have metrics on what healthy open sources
and it needs all these things and it's like,
hold on
who's gonna pay for any of this stuff. And it's like,
that's,
it's just not practical in many instances to expect
the open source universe to take this work on.
And kind of not now, I will say as well.
Like before I, I finish bashing Google,
Google has been a very good steward of open source
and they've dedicated enormous resources to the open source world.
So I think they're an instance of
they have these high expectations
and they will actually like send people
to help critical projects reach those expectations.
-- And that is the right way to do
-- this.
Part of the problem is Google has their view of the world
and they forget basics like you and I forget that most people don't
have taps that you just turn on and clean water comes out.
Well, that's,
that's maybe a bad example. This just came up this morning
when I was talking to someone where I made the comment off offhandedly.
Oh, s bombs are everywhere and he's like, no,
no, they're not.
S bombs are ever where for people like us
because that's literally what we do for work.
Everyone else.
They don't even know what an S
bomb is.
And it's funny because sometimes we get trapped in these bubbles
and this is even true of like supply chain security,
which
I, I,
I'm around all the time and you'd swear it's the most important
thing in the world and the company is working on it.
How could everyone not know who they are?
And the reality is the vast majority of developers don't know, don't care whatever,
you know,
and I'm done, you know, that's, and I don't blame them.
So, and the other thing is like, well, for example,
your metrics thing is hard because like I remember auditing some software from
a company that Red Hat acquired it was a Rails uh platform.
And for example,
they were using some libraries that were like horrifically out of date.
Like I remember there was this one library
that was like seven or eight years out of date
and it was called American Date and it literally converted
date strings
to month date, year
and it was like, 1020 lines long.
And I'm like, I looked at it and I'm like, nope, that's fine.
Like, it's, it's seven years out of date. But it's like,
it literally converts this to the stupid American Date format.
That's it. It's,
it's done,
like, there will never be an update for this library.
Yeah, exactly.
You know,
with the worst feature ever.
And so that's the thing, right.
In that case, well, that's an old library, unmaintained. Nobody cares about it,
-- but it's fine. I
-- mean, it probably is, but that's, that's a corner case.
That's my point.
That process is not sustainable. That process takes one or two hours
and if you're pulling in 1000 dependencies and you do the math.
Well, you better hire some more people. See.
And that's just, it's not sustainable and nobody cares,
nobody cares.
I think this is one of the important things we forget about insecurity sometimes is
we make these big deals about certain things that will say, oh,
you need to be logging this or you need to have single sign on there,
you need to be doing this secure thing and you need to
be watching vulnerabilities in your products and all of this stuff.
And the reality is if you look at
an enormous amount of the way the business world works.
That's a simple question.
If I do this how much does it cost if I don't do this? How much does it cost?
Well, how much does it make me?
Well, sure. I mean, that, that's fair.
-- That's, that could be a better way to look at it.
-- Like I want to make money.
If I do this, will it make me money or significantly save me money or something?
And this, this whole supply chain thing,
you know what it really reminds me of is like,
you have a company that takes pictures of houses and sells them
and they're going to people being like, can you please clean up your front yard?
-- I want to take a picture of your house. I mean,
-- that's probably a fair explanation
and, and some people might say, oh,
you're taking a picture of my house. I better clean up my yard
and other people are going to be like f you, I'm not cleaning up my yard.
Yeah, it's actually sad.
I just thought my lawn service sent me a picture of my front yard and it's like, oh,
it looks really bad right now.
They're like, you need to water it. And I'm like, nope,
I'm planning clover next year. I'm getting rid of the grass
I have.
So it's funny,
my, my yard
I've given up on and I mow it and it's, it's full of weeds and grass and whatever. I mow.
It, it looks fine and it's funny because, yeah, when, when it gets really dry,
everyone else's grass starts to die and mine looks fine and, and it's because I was,
I was watching a TV show
and they were talking about like new grass they're growing in Illinois, which is,
you know, south of me and it does get very dry in the summers.
And they were basically saying, like, by planting clover in the yard,
it needs like, 60% less water. And I thought, well, that's neat.
My yard is full of clover and I keep
ordering it every year.
So I just quit putting chemicals on my lawn and yeah, it's like, it's perfect.
I love it.
Yeah. No, I'm done.
Well.
It's just, I, I live in a, in an area of the country which is basically the,
all of the country that like the grass we plant here is not at all native
or even remotely suitable for this climate,
you know, anyways. But
going back to this, like, it just,
the problem is
the ship sailed in that there is open source
in everything and it's like so much open source,
we can't walk it back
like we just can't, and we can't walk the process of this back.
Like there is no alternative for these companies anymore.
Like
I need to put
some device on the internet. So, like go grab Linux
because anything else costs money or is too heavyweights. That's it.
Ok. I have a,
a different way to look at this. I think
you are correct that there's no walking this back.
And I think I'll even go further and say
we're not, we're not going to fix open source because it doesn't need to be fixed.
And I'm putting, I'll put fix in air quotes in that statement.
And I think if you look at a lot of this, all of this supply chain talk,
it often focuses on this concept of fixing
open source where we have to have project with
more developers and we have to have sign off. So we have to be signing everything and,
and we need M fa and right, there's all this stuff that's expected.
And in some cases, I'm not saying it's a bad thing,
but I think we have to be very mindful
that when you're essentially going to a natural resource
and asking it to do things for you,
you're going to be disappointed on a regular basis because I think what we
currently call open source is better viewed
as a natural resource we are extracting from
than
a thing we are cooperating with in many cases.
And so this is where I think the view I I've, I've developed on,
on all of this over the last probably year or two
is really one of it's not about controlling open source.
You have to just be able to understand and observe what's going on around you.
And sometimes you will need to step in
and take an action. But the vast majority of the time
you just need to watch and understand.
Well, and the other thing that drives me nuts is if any of these plans rely on
all
of your open source dependencies, doing these things,
you, you're going to be disappointed, like you said,
that's just not possible. Yeah.
No, no, I mean, I think expecting 10 or 20% of your open source to be doing,
this would be optimistic.
Like, and there's,
there's gonna be projects that work in a way that will say is
palatable to the likes of Google and many of them like Kubernetes,
obviously huge project Google is,
is a heavy investor and they made it what they needed it to be and that, that's great.
But there's also gonna be like N PM projects that everyone uses,
that's one or two people and
it probably won't change because even, even if you wanted to change it,
you could show up and say, oh,
we're gonna give all these resources to help
and the authors are probably gonna be like,
why? Like I don't, I don't want to do any of this stuff. I do this for fun. Go away.
It's
the other thing is there is no, again, like I just keep coming back,
there is no open source.
Like there's, this is like saying food,
like globally food is everything from a guy growing
potatoes in his backyard to like Archer Daniels Midland,
which if you don't know what ad M is, it's, it's a big company.
I
would think of it as saying,
we're going to go and we need to get stuff from the forest for work.
-- You're like, what, what do you need? Trees, rocks, dirt,
-- the oil underneath of it.
What are we doing in the forest? You're like, no, no, we just need the forest.
The forest has what we need. If people are going to be like, this isn't how it works.
The thing that I just keep coming back to is also it's
they're like shouting at the ocean.
I mean, you and I did this thought experiment of could we even do like
a survey of all, say the pi pie or N PM developers and get them to respond.
-- No, no,
-- I think we can't even contact them, we can't even talk to them or,
or get their opinion.
Here's a better example actually. So, so there is a
uh a dashboard from
pipe.
I give hi P A ton of credit for this because they're,
they're obviously are rolling out the multi factor off
and they made all their data public and I will
put a link to the dashboard in the show notes.
But basically
they're seeing they've asked the developers of
critical packages to enable two factor authentication,
right?
-- Not as
-- they forced,
they haven't forced them yet,
they're going to force them, but they're still, it's still voluntary.
They asked them nicely 20% compliant and I think this is basically
how it works is if you ask someone nicely to do something,
you're going to get 20%.
No problem.
And then you might trickle your way up to maybe 30 or 40 if you're lucky over a long,
long period of time.
But I think
that's kind of the trick to open source. Same thing here.
Like if Google says, oh, open source, I need everyone to do this.
I bet 20% would comply
and the rest would be like, nah, whatever.
Well, no, it's not even that 20% would complain.
And the rest are like, you know, whatever.
It's like a good chunk of them aren't even going to hear
about it because they're on vacation or they don't read that website.
Like that could be too, you know,
like I have this all the time at the cloud screen lines where I email the, the,
the internal everybody alias and we tell them about something
and then like three weeks later somebody's like, hey,
what about this? And we're like, yeah. Did you read the email? Oh, no, I'm busy. Like,
like, am I supposed to call them?
And I mean,
that's not even sustainable in an organization of 100 people, let alone
how many, tens of thousands of global debts for which I don't have phone numbers,
thousands, millions, millions and millions.
That's the thing, right?
Like, it's not that people don't want to comply or are unwilling to comply.
It's like you're assuming that they even know that this exists.
I mean, that's true actually.
And, and I keep,
-- I keep falling into this trap of like everybody
-- reads their email on a timely basis.
Have you met my son?
No, no,
-- not that
-- I've started sending him cat memes to try and teach him to read his email.
Cat memes never fail.
He still doesn't read his email reliably.
Oh, man, you gotta,
you're gonna have to up your meme game.
No, no, I'm I'm saying when you're in the middle of something,
it often feels very important and like right now like things like
bomb and supply chain and open source vulnerabilities
feel like the whole world
and, and most days to me because it's, it's literally what I do,
but the vast majority of people, yeah,
they don't care why should they care what it does?
It does it matter.
The thing that blows my mind is like this system works so well,
like look at all the software based on open
source that's out there chugging along getting stuff done.
It works like the amount
of millions of people
years of effort that have been saved by being able to like pull in open source, right?
I mean, I, I've always wanted to do an actual calculation of
like how much software is produced using open source,
how many hours does using open source, save them, right?
And, and the only number I can come up with is at least millions of years.
It's, it's a ridiculous amount for sure
without question.
Now, now, here's what I wonder sometimes and I don't know
if this is a, a reasonable question or I, maybe I'm off my rocker.
Open source has existed in the state.
It's in for a while and I'd say the last,
probably 5 to 10 years are when it really came into its place.
And you say everything is working and I agree.
Well, no, no, no, not everything is working,
-- everything is working well
-- enough every ok
and you say everything's working well enough,
which I agree.
But then
as this agent
in five or 10 more years,
will we be able to say the same thing or will there be
enough like crusty dangerous open source that it will be more of a liability
than an advantage?
So here's my follow up question to that or my response is,
do we actually have an alternative?
I mean, no, absolutely not.
This is like all those people that are like, oh, we should like redesign cities,
not around cars and it's like, ok,
so we're going to do what exactly with all these roads?
Like just ignore them.
Yeah, it's fine.
We'll put parks on them. It'll be, it'll be great.
You know,
I
know,
I look at this and I just do, we actually have an alternative.
You know, this is like saying we should end world hunger Yes.
Yes, we all agree that that's probably not the worst idea in the world. Right.
Ok. Well, but there's so many problems, like, there's
like, there's the lack of food issues in certain parts of the world.
There's access to the food, there's
safe distribution, you know. So it doesn't get stolen.
Like, there's a lot of, you know, there's security problems,
there's safety problems.
There's
like,
oh.
It's complicated, you know.
-- Yeah. I mean,
-- that's the answer to everything is, it's complicated.
I don't know that there is realistically, even if you,
like, had, even if you somehow got tens of billions of dollars to, like,
fix open source,
like, what would you actually do to make it?
I wouldn't look at it that way. I think, I think you've gone too far. Maybe
in, in a experiment
point of view
of it.
Think of it like this.
So, I've got all this open source. I can mostly use anything I want with
little to no repercussions.
So, if I just do, like, an N PM install of any random package,
I'm probably going to be fine. Right. Like,
it's, it's, there's really no issues
now in five or 10 years.
Are we going to be at a point where I can't just blindly N PM
install because there are going to be things that are dangerously out of date.
Will I have a system in place that maybe does look at, like, when was the last update.
How old is this thing? How many security vulnerabilities?
Well, then I just don't use the super old thing.
All the core functionality.
Well, no, no,
in some cases it might. But if I'm starting fresh,
I would just not use the really old stuff. You know what I mean?
But sometimes that really old stuff is your only choice for that thing.
Like I've looked for certain libraries and there's like one or two and,
and that's true.
There's not a plethora of like, like if you want a web server.
Sure man, there's like literally more web servers than I can name.
Same thing with email servers, same thing with a lot of things.
But you look for specific libraries to do specific things
and sometimes there's like
that American date and that's it.
I mean, and, and you're, you're not wrong and that, that could be true.
It, I don't know.
-- I guess it'll be interesting to see,
-- you know, it's,
it's a risk most people have decided is acceptable
because the problem is they don't have an alternative behavior
for that risk.
Well,
the alternative today is to write it yourself or
-- fork the project and take it over
-- that.
No, they can't.
That's, but that's like saying be less
can do that.
But I most places can barely glue code together,
let alone write a complicated piece of
software that actually does something tricky.
You know, like when I look at stuff like, uh in the Python world.
Like, I look at stuff like fuzzy wuzzy or numpy
or panda and I'm just like, wow,
like the phd S and whatnot people working on this thing are so smart
and like, performance wise,
like there's that, that hacker news post where they, they did something to uh numpy
and it just magically makes it like 10 to 50 times faster. And I'm like,
-- ok, then like
-- magic, I mean, this is why I'm glad smart people do things like this.
And that's the thing, right? Is
I, I don't think most of these companies
realistically, you know, this is like saying to a company, oh,
you can't find the screws.
You want, just make your own screws. You,
you can't
Google can,
Apple can't Apple.
Remember Apple was like talking about on shoring their, their distribute or their,
um their, their laptops and they're like, well, we can't even get screws in America.
Like there's nobody that makes these the screws we need.
Well, remember when Apple started with the tiny,
tiny holes in their laptops for the speaker grills, right?
And how they were drilled with a laser?
Oh, yeah, they, they bought, they bought the company
that,
-- that made the laser
-- and apparently there's two or three spots in
the world now with these giant manufacturing plants where Apple just has,
I forget the name of this.
I think it's a Swiss CNC milling machine and they buy
like a major percentage of this company's milling machines to,
like, churn out the bodies of the laptops.
-- Yeah.
-- But Apple can do that.
You and I can't.
Exactly. And that's the thing. Right.
Even just to make a custom screw is we're
talking tens to hundreds of millions of dollars.
Sure.
You're just going to go buy some screws that
are close enough from wherever and use them.
And that's, and the same with software.
Like, how much is a good software dev with overhead about a quarter million a year,
minimum, 100 grand, more like a quarter million.
Ok. Now you need about five or 10 of them to build something complicated.
Oh, now we're talking like a million bucks a year.
Or you pull in an open source dependency.
Like, come on.
Well, no, I, I don't even look at it like that.
This is like if my core business is building laptops
and I'm spending a significant amount of my resources making screws.
I'm, I'm doing something wrong because I'm not gonna make any money on the screws.
I'm gonna make the money on the laptop,
I think. And this is why open source one.
Because if I'm a company and I'm creating a product that's made
of software and I'm paying developers to write like commodity functionality.
Well, I would say everything is software. Now that's a given.
Well, no, of course, obviously you don't even have to say that.
But if I'm paying a developer to build commodity features.
I'm not making any money on that because no one's paying me for those
-- features
-- to the second part of the question I was going to ask you.
So I would posit that it's not actually realistically
possible for the companies to even build these components.
But let's assume they do build these components.
Are they actually better off than pulling in an open source component?
And the answer is no like they still have all the problems
that the source component would have in the sense of security vulnerabilities,
maintaining it, updates, adding functionality, blah, blah, blah.
-- It's not like building it yourself is somehow magically cheaper and better
-- than
it's almost always works.
And that's what I mean is realistically,
I don't think they have an alternative to pulling an open source because
they, they can't build it themselves.
But even if they could build it themselves,
it would cost more money and be more hassle, right.
So there is no actual alternative
-- to pulling an open source realistically,
-- there isn't.
And, and again,
I'm curious what happens in 5 to 10 years
as there are things that are now several years old
and out of date when they become even more out of date in that time span.
-- I don't know.
-- Well, we've already seen that with web apps, right?
And we just Chuck Web app firewalls in front of them, right?
And
I mean, that's something important to remember is as long as it's like,
if you can't talk to the stuff over the network, how do you attack it?
Well, I mean, that's,
if only it was that simple, that's not, that's not how it works at all.
Well, but I'm saying, like, that reduces your attack service significantly.
I
know
I have out of date devices on my home
network here and if you're inside my home network,
I have bigger problems than
that software being out of date.
That's probably fair.
And, and I think this is, this is kind of where it all ends, right?
Is where we get back to that idea of
oftentimes, things like containment and observation
are vastly easier and, and more effective
-- than
-- prevention. I think again, it goes back to.
But do you actually have an alternative?
Well, the alternative, if, if your one choice is
eliminate all the security flaws in the software, that's
not an actual alternative,
right? Like that's,
that's just not,
that's like saying just let's get everybody to stop being poor or unhealthy,
like you just know.
And so like Apple's a great example, Apple could, can literally just
literally fill dump trucks full of money and burn it.
And instead they went with like blast door for iMessage,
you know,
and
because even they, you know, you look at their security advisor,
they're pulling in all sorts of open source to do various file parsing and mantling
and it's just, it'll never be secure because like any file parser.
Actually, I was going to say more complicated than,
but I'm just going to go with any file parser will have security flaws.
Full
stop.
Yes,
that's true. That's true. I mean, ok, so I guess I will end this with
there. There may not be a software supply chain,
but there sure is a lot of open source.
I will agree with that.
All right.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to open source Security, podcast.com. Hit up the show now. It's Suzie Pound.
Oh, it says podcast. Hashtag hit us up on
social.
I just was going to say hit us up on social security, hit us up on social media.
It's been,
I'm just gonna say one last parting thought
too is imagine if these companies all built their
own stuff now we have how many things to fix versus one open source to fix.
That's true. That is true. And, and you're right. You're right. Alright.
-- Anyway,
-- thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.