Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
Hey, Kurt, I, I'm super excited today. We, we have another guest.
We have Mark Lovelace security researcher at Git lab.
Uh Mark goes by Simple Nomad on Twitter, which is what I've known him as forever.
-- So, Mark, welcome to the show. I'm very excited for you to be here.
-- Good to be here.
Good to see you or to hear you and
uh and Kurt.
Awesome. Thanks. So, I guess tell, tell us what you're up to, man.
-- What am I up to?
-- You're at, you're at Git lab, you're doing some cool stuff.
-- Tell us a story.
-- I'm work, I'm working at Git lab.
You know, the uh the fun uh open source kind of company that does uh DEV
ops and I'm desperately trying to put SEC
into the
DEV
ops part of everything I do. So, and just my whole background of being a
uh paranoid uh security researcher is just perfect with this type of job.
Everything they give me, they feel like they're giving me something to work on,
that's horrid and and, uh, sad and, and
soul crushingly
hard to do.
And it, for me it's just like, oh, my gosh, this is the most wonderful job ever.
So, I'm having the time of my life doing what I'm doing.
That's awesome. Well, and you've been, I mean, you've been around as long as we have,
-- like, definitely no newcomer to this industry. No,
-- I'm not.
-- I've been, yeah, I've been doing this for quite a while. All right. All
-- right.
So,
I guess let's kind of start at the beginning because
I'm actually a pretty big fan of git Lab.
I, I think they're doing some really interesting stuff and I think the most, I,
I guess unique thing I would describe is
Git Lab has a very unique way of releasing
software.
Do you, do you want to tell us about it?
-- Like, it's, it's a special day, isn't
-- it a special day?
The 22nd of every month? Right.
Like,
who does that?
Well? 000, just the fact that we release so freaking often.
-- Is that what you're talking about
-- that? And just, it's like, it's a day, right.
And,
and I think that the discipline to
accomplish that boggles my mind sometimes because
that is
a skill set. I don't think you find often
in just the, the software industry in general.
-- Yeah,
-- the thing is, is like, ok, working here,
I don't even think about that if that makes sense.
Ok, because
I,
it's just, there's because I, I run my own
git lab instance here in my home lab or whatever
and,
and it's like, it's a full, like, stand alone on its own server.
It's got its own static IP address and up on the internet for people
to come in and attack and we look at it and see what happens
and
it is constantly updated. Right?
Because we're not, not just, not just talking about the uh
uh the point releases, but just the
in between those, there'll be just, you know,
up, you know, updates that occur.
I would say I'm seeing updates probably almost weekly.
Wow, that's awesome.
I just set my system up at home here to download the new package that they've got,
you know, the Debian style package and just pull the thing down and,
and do it and it just, uh it's, it is amazing.
It is, uh it is amazing when you think about
it.
The, the, the other amazing thing is trying to,
uh make sure that what you're releasing is secure,
unquestionably.
Yeah, that's, that's the other, other uh uh fun and exciting challenge with that.
I mean, ok, so, so tell us about that, you know, you, I,
I know just from paying attention to your, your workings over the many years that
you have a strong background in security research.
And so I'm curious,
what does that mean in the context of a company that releases software and,
and git lab is
incredibly open.
There's
an alarming amount of openness.
-- You could almost say the inner workings of git lab
-- before I started working here, I,
I became unemployed, as they say, from my last job, I didn't want to,
I worked at Duo that got bought by Cisco. I didn't want to work at Cisco.
And so that was, and that was fine.
So I'm unemployed and I'm, I get contacted by some, some people that get labs and say,
hey, we saw on your blog that you're
funemployed, maybe you should come work here
and I start taking a look at, at that and I see the
handbook online
and it's just like holy moly.
This is like really wide open,
this is frightfully wide open and I'm supposed to do security at this place.
Yeah.
But you know, it's funny because
like we come from Red Hat and we're sort of used to, well,
Red Hat's not as open as g lap to be fair, but like the source code is out there.
-- No, nobody's just
-- open it.
But yeah, and that's, but that's the thing.
It's just like every single process I'm reading
about almost literally everything that I can,
I can read about that I can think of is, is there.
And
the, but the thing is, is like, as a researcher particularly,
it becomes extraordinarily freeing.
OK? I mean, we have there is data that's going to be uh
uh you know, secret ok, that's, that's, that's obvious customer data, you know,
just,
you know, stuff that would be handled by, you know, hr kind of thing. But
there's a lot of openness in there and
as a result at other places where I've worked, they've had problems where they said,
ok,
we found a security flaw.
We need to be really careful how we word this when we release it.
So
we don't look bad,
you know, or, or whatever their motivation is at git lab,
it's just we're going to be completely open and say, ok, here's the flaw, here's
how someone could potentially exploit it. Here's how
we recommend you mitigate it. Here's our fix for it, et cetera, et cetera.
We just lay it all out there and
from a security perspective that makes it a lot easier because
I don't have to focus on someone from upper management telling me
you can't say this, you can't word it that way.
It's just like we're going to have, we're going to just basically lay out the facts
here. It is because the idea is this is what we would want if we work someplace else,
you know,
get the most amount of information that we possibly
can so that we can make a decision.
And so that's really, uh that's really exciting and, and to be able to do that,
that makes it a lot easier doing security here.
Totally. Totally. So you have uh a blog post that I will.
Well, I'm, I'm gonna put a bunch of stuff in the show.
Not, it's like all the crazy stuff git lab's doing for anyone listening.
So just go find those.
But anyway, you wrote this blog post that,
that really resonated with me where you talk about, what's the title?
It's called How We Approach Open source security. And you focus on that
openness aspect of security. And I feel like
this is something coming
that I don't think everyone gets yet.
But II,
I think Kurt and I just talked about this in the last
episode even is there's like this cult of secrecy in security.
And I think it's actually more damaging
than helpful.
And I feel like, but we, we secretly think it works but it, it totally doesn't. Right.
Yeah, the, the, this is the fun, this is the fun thing.
I've been working some of the stuff I've been working on.
I'm hoping there's,
it's gonna be another fun and exciting blog
post coming out pretty soon on the project.
I'm working on that.
I, I want to say I just completed because it's, it's not completed by any means.
Now does hoping mean the editors need a poke with a stick
or does hoping mean Mark needs to write the blog post.
Uh
I'm going to say the former, but it's truly the latter.
No, I,
I just, I put a lot on my own plate because I just like doing a lot of stuff. And so,
yeah, things get, things get tossed by the wayside sometimes,
which is unfortunate. But, uh,
I know the project I worked on for the past couple of quarters
was a threat modeling. And
introducing this is kind of like you go to talk to DEV and OPS and say, hey,
there's this thing called SEC and we got to get
that in there because we're going to do this devs
ops thing. So we came up with this idea where we're using threat modeling.
We're using um kind of a variation on
the uh pasta
threat modeling and pasta stands for, oh
threat modeling.
I, I can't,
I
can't remember what it stands for.
The biggest,
I think the biggest thing because I've just been
through this with a bunch of different threat modeling.
I actually wrote like a 30 page paper on all the different threat modeling systems
and the biggest takeaway I had from Pasta versus Stride.
And these other more technical methods was pasta takes
a very holistic view and includes components like actually getting
buy in from the upper echelon,
you know, defining the business requirements and sort of all that, that non
technical squishy stuff that to put it bluntly, a lot of threat models ignore.
Oh yeah,
exactly. And the other thing that I really liked about uh pasta was the fact that
it would take elements of, uh let's see,
how would you word this previous threats
that are previous risks that have occurred,
like you've had previous incidents, security incidences or just like, you know,
hey, we had a problem with this code.
They had a
security issue with it or whatever. So you can take that
kind of stuff and so you can list out all your risks and everything. Ok.
Here's all the potential threats that we might see regardless of whether they
are going to occur or not, But here they all are.
Now, let's use our past to help us say here,
this will help define what's more likely to occur
than others.
I mean, you can still say, well, because we're introducing this new component,
it's gonna cause we're going to open up this new world.
But it does allow you to go back and look at your past and be able to say
uh based upon the way things have gone before
it looks like our major areas of risk are going to be here.
And so being able to take that and then include that in
so, and that's fine.
The, the, the the thing with uh using threat modelling, that's, that's great,
that's,
that's fine. And because past is in seven stages and, and we're
mainly focusing on three of them.
So we're kind of doing kind of our own kind of version of that.
Uh mainly focusing on identifying the threats and
trying and figuring out which which ones are most
likely and that's where we dedicate our resources.
So that's, that's the fun part. Now,
the real trick is trying to get
everyone in DEV or everyone in ops or everyone
in whatever department there is because you can apply this.
And this was the, this was the goal was that we didn't want to have a, a
threat model that just applied to code.
All right, we wanted it to be able to apply it to operations.
We want to be able to apply it to, I
mean, you could even apply this to marketing,
ok? Or sales,
you know,
someone's coming up with a new sales strategy and they're
going into a new vertical market to go do whatever,
where are their big risks with doing it this way, et cetera.
So there's all kinds of ways that you can apply
this and that's what we are trying to do.
That's pretty cool. The big one, the really big one is trying to get
the people that are
coming up with the new thing,
writing the new chunk of code or whatever
to go through the process themselves to where
they don't need the security department in there yelling at them,
ok?
You know, just
get them to be involved in the process.
And so that's the main thing that we've been working on is trying to get,
start getting these things involved because there is
a review process that where security has to
get involved when you're introducing new features and
stuff like that into the git lab product.
So instead of like at the,
you know, they're saying, ok, here's our code. What do you think?
And we go through the threat model and say, look,
this is what you should be looking at when you started the project and
get them to start to say you go through the threat model thing,
we don't have to be there for you to do this,
but you go through that threat model thing.
And if you have questions during the process, certainly bring us in,
then when we come time to that review thing,
you've already got this whole threat model thing worked out
and
in the process, they ended, they end up writing more secure code to begin with
by the time they reach that point.
And so that's kind of a neat thing that we didn't think was
going to work and so far everyone that's done it has been like,
oh, well, this makes it easier because
I fly through that security review or
whatever really. They're not, they're not flying through the security review.
They kind of did it themselves before they got to us.
And so
I'm not saying we're tricking them, but I mean, they get,
they get it and it ends up where their code is more secure and,
and uh
overall everything works better now, that's I'm giving you the ideal thing.
I mean, obviously this isn't gonna work perfect in every aspect everywhere,
but the, in some of the initial projects we've been working on, it's been hopeful
and the thing is we put out, I think this got committed to the project.
Just I think within the past two or three days,
we put out some uh examples of what we've been doing. So if you search the
handbook for threat modeling, there'll be links to show all this stuff.
Some examples like on my stand alone that I have here,
I did a whole full threat model on that
as a result of some of that, there have been
some uh code changes that have occurred in
the product simply because it's just like we,
we found some things here, we need to make this change.
And someone said,
hey, I've been working on that and just like, OK, now, now they've got some, you know,
kind of ammo or whatever to kind of help back up their point of view.
And so things are, it, it does work, it does work. So it's just, it's good.
So one thing I'm curious about because I've been doing
a ton of work on threat modeling and trying to,
one of the biggest things I've been struggling with is trying to
clearly define
the value and benefit of threat modeling. And
in general, I've only come up with essentially it,
it allows you to kind of add security to existing things,
it doesn't sort of create anything new, right?
Like for example, network programming brought something completely new to dev,
you know, now systems can talk to each other
but threat modeling, you know, it doesn't sort of enable anything
new or it doesn't create something new.
It just kind of slips into existing processes.
Is that what you found or have you found
it sort of enables and allows completely new things?
I wish it was uh enabling completely new things.
Uh But no, it just, it just basically has been helping to secure what we have.
I mean, it's,
there's always this thing that I, I've talked about this before,
I've given talks about it and stuff where, you know,
you got to make sure you cover the basics in things.
And the analogy I like to use is uh
OK, if we will die, all of us will die at the end of our lives. All right.
So when you die,
there's a reason why you died. OK.
So
the odds are,
and so, you know, people think of, oh, I, I don't want to die.
Uh But you know, of course they are.
And there's a chunk of people who say, well, hey, you know what?
I, I've discovered that
murder is a bad thing and I don't want to be murdered
and they'll focus on that because that's what's in the press all the time.
And then you look at the odds of them
having died for murder
and
I think the odds were, I think the,
the figures that I quoted from were from a couple of years ago or so, but it was like,
your odds were like one in 400 or something like that.
And it was like one in 400. 0, my gosh.
And they get all freaked out about that
value. But then you say, well, suicide,
it's one in 100 and 19.
Ok. So, and then that puts it into a completely different perspective and
then
saying, well, ok, the most common way is from heart disease. One in six.
Ok. So,
you know,
it's just like
a lot of people that are not deep down in security
are in there saying either and the vendors do this too.
So they'll, they'll sell the try to sell murder blankets or,
or, or whatever
it is to prevent,
you know, so you got to have this murder blanket to prevent your murder.
But really, it's just like they need to be eating salads and stuff like that,
you know.
But hamburgers are so much better.
-- Well, yeah.
-- Yeah,
you could sit under your, you know, your murder blanket with your hamburger.
But
that's someone who eats bacon every single day for breakfast. I
like, I actually
consciously did this cost benefit analysis.
Well, you see, you're probably doing what you're doing what a keto diet.
Uh,
sorry, let's call it that.
No, I just, I like bacon
or that.
Yeah. But that's the, that's the thing. It's just like, that's what secure.
That's the hard part about security,
getting people to do this stuff is saying, hey, man,
there's some basics you need to get back to the salad thing.
-- Ok,
-- I mean, you, that was a lot, a
lot. You just, you just dropped on us from, from many different angles.
I will, I will add, but I, um, we're gonna focus on security security podcast.
But,
ok, so
you're, you're talking about
this kind of realistic view of security? And this is not,
can I
for a second?
I think this is one of the things is having
data to actually inform you of what the like,
there's a huge difference between one and six and one in 400.
Right. Right. Well,
that's just it. Right is.
But even with security people,
I feel like I'm constantly pushing away
movie plots of
no, like I don't care about like Russians breaking into our network.
We have to like password protect this thing over here because this is,
you know what I mean? And
I, I feel like this infects
all of a nonsecurity and security people alike and, and
we have no data
to back this up. And it sounds like you're, you're
so curt and I
not, not on the podcast necessarily, but I'm always harping about that
threat modeling today is a process that is incredibly manual
and
almost always ineffective and it sounds like
that is not what you and git lab are trying to push because, like, I'll, I'll put a,
like, git lab has this list of, like, all the security stuff in the product and it's,
it's a large list and this obviously is, is another thing to add to it. And this is,
I'm thinking about this now and I, I like this. This, this makes sense to me.
Oh, cool. I'm, I'm, I'm glad.
Yeah. And that's, that's the thing.
And that was kind of the, the influence in with the threat modeling
part of it was, you know, so at the beginning,
we can have all the fun and we can talk about and say, yeah, you could be
eaten by sharks, you could be murdered, you could be whatever and
you know, and still bring up heart disease and stuff. But then you look at the
patterns of what's happened in the past and you look at what's most likely to occur
and
yeah, even though it would be really, really exciting to say, yes, we were
killed by
invading extraterrestrials.
The odds of that happening are rather low,
you know. And so, but you know, so it's
it it does,
it does add an interesting dimension.
So I mean, the the thing I think of here and obviously
git lab is completely focused on developers given what git lab is
and
making your developers.
Well, I guess making is maybe the wrong word,
but we'll say letting the developers create the industry threat model.
This feels like the comparison I would use is like a,
a wiki where everyone gets all excited with a wiki,
you fill in a bunch of content and then it rots for like six years, right?
Because like it's no one's job to take care of that.
Whereas if, if, if, if part of your development process is
putting together this threat model, which is really,
let's face it just a fancy architecture model.
Like
that's, ah man, this, this solves so many problems because every,
every time I've ever done this,
it's always the security people making the threat model.
And the developer is like, oh, these guys again, you know, and it's just,
it never goes well.
Exactly. And that's the thing, it just hand the, the, the whole thing. OK?
Here's, here's my,
my goal and I, everyone in security goal should be to work ourselves out of a job.
Ok?
Totally.
And
I, this is a, this is a step in that direction.
I mean, the,
the other thing too to keep in mind is like if we were doing
the old school traditional threat model thing where we had to run the thing,
we would need a security department of thousands, ok?
Because basically we need one security person for every single line of code,
I would think it would just,
you need this ridiculous amount of security people to go in there and, and do that.
It doesn't scale. And so
this also helps that whole problem of just like how am I gonna
reach all these people
and
get to that. So this, this is kind of the, this is why I want to do a blog post on this
is I think this is kind of the direction that we need to be, need to be heading it.
And so far just initial, like I said, early days on this with us right now, but
it's working, I mean,
the other thing too that kind of helped us with this is we're also
we've got a fairly healthy hacker one program going on.
And so with that, we can actually incorporate
hacker one data into our threat models
and say, look, here's where we're
paying out all this money for these people, finding bugs
is
in, in these types of flaws.
So let's look for those in our code, that kind of thing
-- that
-- makes a lot of sense.
Yeah.
So one thing I'm curious because again,
when I was looking at all these threat modeling tools,
there's essentially a huge pile of like sort of,
well, basically visio diagram style making things
which you know, is not the most friendly thing for developers to be using.
You know, it's yet another step. And I was looking for tools that
for example, allow you to actually put,
you know,
structured comments in your source code that then get collected
by the threat modeling tool and turned into a something useful
like what
technology are you guys using to actually do the threat modeling and, you know,
make this less painful for the developers.
Well, we're not doing anything with like that.
That's, that's for sure. It's
mark down.
I mean, we're basically creating documents and, and working off of that at best,
we'll get a, a,
you know, a mermaid diagram in there
-- and that's,
-- that's actually what I ended up using.
-- No,
-- I'm not kidding. Like I, yeah,
that's
otherwise I spent 90% of my time doing artwork trying to make the boxes fit.
Yeah, that seems to be kind of the going thing.
It literally is
and, and we do it within, uh within the, you know, the git lab product.
It was, it was kind of cool when someone, we had a,
a coder that we'd worked on this before and then she was working on another
project and as a part of that project in there in the project files,
she had her Threat Model and, you know, just, I, I
don't know, threat model dot
MD or whatever it was called. But,
you know, it was just a simple markdown file that had,
that had she where she'd gone through and, and worked this
and it was, it was great.
-- That's pretty
-- awesome.
I have to say, it worries me when I see convergent evolution, you know,
from two completely different people and organizations.
That's either I'm right or I'm completely wrong
now, now you're both wrong. Right.
Yeah, but we're both spectacularly wrong.
That's
no, you know. No. You know what I mean? So, here's the thing is,
I mean, I, I gave up on threat modeling a long time ago just because the tooling was,
was beyond atrocious and I feel like
I know, not
all agree on that,
but I, I think starting, I think this is one of the reasons it, it hasn't
ceded the way it has because virtually everything I've read or seen about this area.
And I mean,
this is true of just security in general in many
cases is it's here is the the perfect solution,
right?
This is what you need to do it. It's like
you're starting at step 70 instead of telling people like here's step one,
start here.
This is easy and you basically like this is fall, you can't fall off the floor, right?
Like step one.
And this sounds like that's what it is where if you start with Markdown,
everyone knows how Mark Dunn works. Nobody's going to screw that up.
Whereas if you have,
oh here's this giant diagram you have to create like that's just you,
you failed at the beginning, like just give up, you failed.
You know, this is cool. I like this.
Yeah. Yeah.
Well,
and the other thing I found is is this has to be done by the people close to
the code because the just the time and effort
needed for me to understand what the code,
you know, I had this happen at Red Hat all the time where I'd have products
and to understand a security flaw in the product.
Well, first I had to understand what the product does,
you know,
like, what's the intent of the product? How does it operate?
You know, because it was Red Hat had over 100 different products
and just the amount of time I spent
understanding products so that I could then apply,
like, how does security flaw actually affect it?
You know, it's significant, right?
Whereas the developers just, well in theory know that like off the top of their head
and I think that's the other problem with security people is, you know,
we don't know their, well, in theory,
we don't know the products as well as the developers should.
We don't, not, in theory we don't
anyway. Anyway. All right, we are, we, we've,
we've run ourselves out of time already. I, I feel like I could talk to you for days.
I won't. But so I want to end this mark with you.
Have a very interesting story on your blog that is about
the time the TS A picked you up for having TNT.
Why don't you tell us your story? Because this is really funny.
Yeah. Yeah. Well,
it's funny because it wasn't me
and it's funny because it's in the past. OK.
But I,
the thing was, is like, I don't know why,
but it just I have a habit of weird things seem to happen to me a lot
and
I'm in Las Vegas
for a, um,
conference. It wasn't a black at defcon. It's another,
another conference
that I'm there for,
you know, at the time,
you know, I hadn't,
you know, started losing my hair or anything like that,
you know, I'm,
I, you know, I shaved my head bald now in, in protest,
uh, to that happening.
But at the time I had really long hair, you know, scraggly beard.
I probably didn't look great.
So I'm going through,
uh, security
and they do this occasionally. They would,
uh, they would do this and they pulled me aside and they said,
uh,
we want to do, uh, they were doing like, uh,
swabs on your,
on your hands. I don't know if you, you've encountered this before.
I've had that many times actually.
-- Too
-- many wires in the backpack.
Yeah. Yeah, you have, he have had these odd tools and stuff like that.
And so, you know, I had, you know, a lot of basic gadgets and gizmos that a
lot of us hacker types might, might have.
You know, we're on a trip, we're bored, we're going to play around with stuff.
We bring, we bring fun things to play with.
And
so I get the hand swab
and
no big deal and then they get the results and the guy
is kind of like looking at the thing and it's like,
hm.
And so then he comes over and he does, let's do the hand swab again. And
then next thing I know he's calling someone over to talk
to him about it and they're talking and I'm starting to get
a little nervous and then they come back and they start
asking me all these weird questions that didn't make any sense.
They said, have you been on a military base? No.
Have you been to a gun range?
No. And just all these weird things and it didn't make any sense to me.
I, I finally, you know, asked one of the guys says, what's going on and they said,
well, you tested positive for TNT.
It's just like
I'm thinking,
oh, this isn't good.
This isn't good at all.
And so they, they're swabbing my bag
and everything and it's all over the outside of my bag. They pull apart my bag.
There's like swabbing the inside and it's apparently ok. But
so they're just like tearing apart all my luggage and everything.
They call over there.
I mean, all of a sudden there's like some guy shows up that's like, you know,
he's got a,
he's got a gun
and he's standing there
and I'm thinking, oh, this is really, really bad.
And,
and so I get more questions, you know, about where I'd been and
who I've been in contact with.
I mean, everything except, you know,
them just like holding me down and saying where's the bomb?
You know, I mean,
that's what I'm thinking
but they're, they're mystified because
I, oh, this is the funny thing too. They even swabbed my fly
on my pants
of the zipper fly,
I guess because, you know, you make,
if you're making a bomb,
you might have to go to the bathroom
and you, you're probably lucky you still had clothes on at this point, honestly.
Ok. So then,
so they're, they're calling like a, you know,
supervisor over and all this other kind of stuff
and another guy shows up and he has a bigger gun
and II I am thinking, ok, this is
we're gonna, it's gonna be body cavity search time
or
you know, any moment
they finally get one of these other supervisor guys and he's a little bit,
a little bit of an older guy
and comes over and they kind of are filling him in and everything.
Oh and by this, by this time they got me pulled aside and
yeah, I'm away from other people and everything
and so everyone else over there is staring and
people are taking pictures of me and stuff because
you know,
they figured they're gonna be
selling it to CNN later or something. I don't know.
So
that the guy that the older guy, he comes over to me and he said,
um he started to ask me some different questions.
He was saying, where, what hotel were you staying at? And,
and II I tell him whatever hotel it was that I was staying at, it was a Treasure Island.
And
he said, did you go to the pirate show? Because at, at
Treasure Island, they used to have this pirate show and they'd have like, you know,
all these pyro
techniques and they, because they have the
and everything.
And I said,
I said, no, I didn't.
I says, but I walked by that thing every day because the
conference I was attending was at the hotel next door.
And so I would walk by there and he said, did you walk by there today
with your bag before you came here?
And it's like, yeah, in fact, I set the bag down and,
you know, adjusted some stuff and, and whatnot.
And so I, yeah, I set it down on the right there where they do the thing and that was it.
That was,
he, he told, told the guys, he says that's where you're getting that you're,
you're picking up the,
the, the TNT, it's from the uh,
explosives that there were the, the pyrotechnics that they were using
the flash pots, I guess. And that was, and so that was it. So that was, uh,
that was horrifying,
I can imagine. Scary. II I just thought I'm going, I'm going to jail right now.
You know,
I, I'm,
you know, this is, I mean, as, as an old school hacker type, I figured
the one time that I was gonna call
Jennifer Granick,
you know,
the uh the to come to come help me,
I didn't want it to be, hey Jennifer,
you know,
you want it to be something glorious like the h
something spectacular.
But no, it would be like, hey Jennifer, I,
they, they think I have a bomb,
you know. Oh,
my
goodness.
You know. So
I barely made my flight because I mean, they just,
everything is just torn apart and they're just like you're free to go,
you're free to go. And they point me at this table where all my stuff is spread.
Of course, they don't, they never repack the bag.
-- No,
-- I can't even imagine. Wow, that you'll need your murder blanket for that story.
Oh, yeah, I got to wrap myself in my, my
murder blanket.
That's the thing. They threw my murder blanket out on the floor.
It's dirty.
Oh my goodness. That is, that is a marvelous story. I'm so glad it wasn't me.
So
I guess thank you so much, Mark.
This has been an absolute pleasure and I will have lots of links in the show
notes for anyone interested in what git lab's
up to because they're doing some really,
really cool stuff and I'd highly highly suggest you take a look.
So, all right, I guess. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you, Mark.
Thank you everyone for listening. You go to open source security podcast.com.
Hit up all those show notes. I'm talking about use a Pound
Os podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media.
Kurt Mark have marvelous rest of your days.
Thanks everybody. Awesome. Thanks everyone. Bye bye
that.