Hi, this is the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
-- and my partner in crime. Josh Bresser.
-- Holy cow. Welcome back, Kurt.
It's been, feels like forever since I've talked to you.
-- It has been what about 2, 2.5 weeks.
-- I did two shows without you,
which uh Dave was kind enough to help us out and, and we won't
comment on the, the quality of those shows compared to the quality of our shows.
No, they were fantastic. Dave. Dave is great.
I'm, I'm joking that uh you are uh a, a worse cohos
than Dave,
but, but I won't say that a lot.
So,
anyway, anyway, welcome back, man. It's, it's great to have you back. I'm ecstatic.
And,
and so why don't
we've got kind of AAA crazy show we've got planned today because this is the reason
you weren't able to help us out and, and we mentioned it was
CV E.
Yeah.
So as we all know CV E is the common vulnerabilities and enumeration database,
which is a fancy way of saying
it's
a number,
a description of the problem and then
a bunch of reference links which are really handy because you know,
when you wanna go looking at something
-- you want to find out about it, how do we do that? We do it
-- with the web?
And uh what kind of problems are we talking about here?
-- Like like uh security
-- vulnerabilities, so
security vulnerabilities.
So, so for example, you know, CV E hyphen the year number, hyphen some random number.
The description is something like, you know,
a buffer overflow in project version 1.3 0.4 and earlier
allows remote Attackers to cause remote code execution on the web server,
whatever stuff like that.
And it's really handy because as you know,
the industry currently deals with, you know,
thousands of security vulnerabilities a year.
Uh and the reality is globally, you know,
we're dealing with millions of these things and,
you know, it's, it's really, I mean,
how do customers know that stuff got fixed or that they fixed it properly, you know.
And so with CV E and this tracking system,
uh it becomes quite a bit easier, especially with vendors like Red Hat
where, you know, we have over 100 products.
So, so let's let's back this up. Just a tad is
you and I both have a,
we'll say special
history with, with CV E putting this word
special in quote. So, so first of all,
for those of you who maybe aren't familiar with this is the CV ID is something that,
that the identifier is literally the letter CV E dash year
of 2016 being the current year or 2015 was last year,
2017 will be next year as these things tend to go.
And then a, a number of integers
that follow that is kind of the unique identifier
and those integers are
starting at 0001 for the year and they can go to infinity.
There is no end. And so I'm confident
that we will not run out of CV E I DS
in any given year.
I won't say I'm 100% certain.
But,
well, I, I think we're ok.
So this is important because a lot of people see
this stuff and they don't necessarily know what it means.
And, and so the, the fun fact, some, a bit of trivia here is
a long time ago.
They weren't all CV E I DS,
there were can candidates
and what would happen.
And this is, this is so crazy to think about in, in today's universe,
an issue was assigned a candidate.
So it's like can dot dash, you know, year dash
ID.
And then
the CV E board would vote on every
CV E to promote it from candidate to CV E.
And you can imagine even back then they couldn't deal with them all. And so it's
someday I, I forget when this happened.
Uh I have to hassle Steve Christie, maybe I know he would know,
but they decided no more candidates it's just all CV E I DS
from this point forward and then hence it was all CV E dash,
which is also funny because
any vendor that had been working with this for a long time now had a bunch of cans
and a bunch of CV ES and all of a sudden everything was switched to CV E.
So you kind of had to go back and,
and posthumously change all your, your candidates to CBES in your,
your databases and whatnot.
So it was,
man, those are crazy days.
Yeah.
Well, I remember those days, well, when you know,
like one or 2000 CV S per year was like, I mean,
that was an amazing year for a lot of vulnerabilities.
Um And, you know, now that's like a normal month
and, and that goes to what a lot of the, the CV E meeting I was at last week was about is
we're essentially uh the meeting itself was a bit of the CV board meeting,
but more importantly,
it was a bunch of companies and entities that are what are
called CNAs AC N A is a CV E numbering authority.
And the idea is simply put, um you have this large company called Mir
that runs
the CV project and the ultimate, you know, database of truth.
Uh but they obviously don't do all the work that would be kind of silly.
Um So the CV numbering authorities are large companies like say, Red Hat Microsoft,
you know, IB MH P
uh that ship software
and when they
find a security vulnerability
or have a security vulnerability reported to them, they,
they themselves can assign it a CV number.
Right.
And then they
use that CV number for tracking purposes.
It goes into the advisory, it goes into the email announcements.
Um,
and then ultimately, in the past, the way it worked
is
that's it, that's all that happened, right? Nothing was passed back to Mir
and the, the one true database.
Um And so of course,
the problem there was or one of the problems was that
Miter's Database was not always complete or up to date.
Um So the good news is that's going to be changing now, Mir
uh is going to be having
CNAs pass back the information about CVS.
So the CV number, the description and the reference links
and that will be entered into the CV database.
And hopefully, you know,
we're looking at this being updated daily or more often than daily.
Whereas in the past, you know, uh
Dirty Cow is a good example.
Um you know, dirty cow was a pretty complicated issue. Mier
had to do some research to make sure they fully understood it.
They had to write up the description, they had to do all this work and it took them,
I think two or three weeks
after Dirty Cow officially became public for it to show up in the database.
Yuch, that's like two years
in
years today.
Yeah. So, so the good news is essentially
the people issuing these CV S will be able to
pass the description back to Miter in.
I'm not gonna say real time but very close to real time.
Uh And the way they're gonna be doing that is basically the same process that the,
an open source project called the DWF. The Distributed Weakness Filing project
does CV assignments and CNAs.
In that essentially, there's gonna be a
JSON file
and essentially you'll create like a little
JSON file with information about the CV, like the CV number,
you know the description,
uh the products that are affected
and so on and so forth, you know, reference links, um
things like that,
this will be passed uh over to Mir
who will then update their database.
The benefit here, for example is when AC N A issues a CV E number,
if it's already a public issue,
they can just pass that description and the information back to Mir.
And so that,
that Miter CV database gets updated very quickly.
Uh And another big benefit,
for example is that every because the reality is everybody that uses CV
uh gets their CV S from two places, number one, the vendors that they use.
So for example, Red Hat customers see CV S being issued by Red Hat, you know,
in our security advisories and our email advisories and all that.
And
then the second source primarily
is the miter database
unless you also want some extra information, like say the vulnerability rating.
In which case you,
you go to this place called the National Vulnerability Database run by
NIST, the National Institute of Standards and Technology.
-- These
-- guys
-- love acronyms,
-- don't they? Oh they do, they do.
And so
nvd.n.org uh
pulls their data from mir.
So uh the, the problem has been in past, you know, is,
is if something doesn't show up in the Miter database,
even if like a company fixed it and made it fully public,
you know, if it doesn't show up in the
MOR database for a week or two, then it doesn't show up in the NVD database,
you know, and for example,
then the federal government officially doesn't really know about it.
Sure.
Well, in,
in the NVD database is also really cool because I know a number
of kind of vulnerability analysis and scanning
products rely on it because they provide
things like CV SS.
Are they doing version three now or still version two? They are doing three?
So CV SSV three scores for these issues and granted
there's a lot of issues and they don't always get them 100% right?
But they're close enough.
I
mean, you
know
why?
Because they're not giving the information,
right. You'll notice a lot, there's a lot of CV E vulnerabilities from,
well, typically not so much open source vendors because with open source vendors,
it's really easy to know what the problem is, right?
You just look at the code
uh but with closed source vendors,
sometimes they'll have CV S that literally say something like
an unknown flaw
is exploited through an unknown.
Yeah, with like an unknown impact through an unknown exploitation avenue.
But you know, this version of the product is vulnerable and they,
they say they fixed it in this other version of the product.
So
honestly, that's better than nothing.
They should just give those a, a CV SS score of 10
and then say we'll rescore it if you give us the info,
we we talked about that a bit and the problem is if they score something high,
they they
typically go to the worst case scenario because let's face it,
that's how security people operate, right?
If I don't know something, I'm going to assume the worst
and the problem there is is so that they do end up scoring stuff
higher than it probably should be scored and it causes people to freak out,
you know,
so there is actually a real cost for that.
Now, that's another part of the good news is mir
is going to be requiring their CV numbering authorities
to pass back
data. Now that involves obviously the CV number and the description,
the impact of the vulnerability.
So like what is the impact, you know, is it code execution?
Is it a cross site scripting, you know,
is it a
-- denial of service. These are all very different.
-- What happens though.
I mean, there are security flaws that depending upon how you use them,
-- determine what the impact is,
-- where you would list multiple impacts. I see.
OK. OK. Right.
So yeah, I mean, that's a great example like there's, well, I mean,
every single time we see a um
uh you know, like a buffer overflow,
it it almost always can cause the program to crash
but can it actually be exploited for code execution? Well, that,
that's a different story, right? And that
the case is almost always, yes, they can be because you know Murphy's Law, right?
It's
complicated.
Yeah, but I mean, well, I'm I'm a pessimist.
Ideally long term, one of the goals is to have better quality data in the CV database,
right?
Because the reality is this is what
virtually all the security processes in the world run on nowadays.
If you're consuming
these vendor software and you wanna track the
security of it and you wanna patch it and
update it and make sure you're patched and updated
and you want your scanner to stop complaining,
you need to be tracking this data and using it.
Um And then the other goal is to scale this right.
Uh The dirty secret is um you know, Miter
does the CV project, you know, under the auspices of the US government.
And so obviously, it has a US centric focus, right?
That's what the US government uses
typically US software, right?
They're not running uh like a lot of Chinese word processors or whatever.
Um
Yeah.
And so that's a challenge, right? Because the,
you know, the, the software industry used to be real simple.
It was America basically
the majority of it like 2530 years ago, commercially.
Um But now, I mean, holy jeez, like the, the software development houses in,
you know, Asia, I mean,
-- South America,
-- not even just that man.
I mean, this is, we could,
we could probably spend a whole show talking about supply chain issues.
But I mean, you have to think about
any system probably is running source code from more than
20 different countries just because you've got third parties,
have third parties, have third parties,
but then also you've got hardware involved.
You've, I mean, it's madness when you really think about
the fact that say, you know,
you and I discussing anything right now probably has literally thousands of people
have touched the, the hardware and the software and,
and the countries involved in it.
-- It's, it's mind boggling how complicated
-- everything
really, you know, in the last
five years or 10 years uh has occurred is, you know,
traditionally everything had software to some degree,
like your toaster had a little chip in it to control the dial and the,
the toasting stuff, right?
But your toaster wasn't connected to the internet.
It is now, right?
And that's the thing, right?
Like if you have software running on a device that has no network connectivity,
you know, it's probably safe because to, to hack into it or to muck with it,
you have to physically go there and, and muck around with it.
But as we've learned from like the Marai Botnet
and all that,
you know, when you connect stuff to the internet and it's not secure,
somebody is going to be helpful and take over it for
you so that they can use it in a botnet.
Right?
You know,
and I mean, we're seeing everything, you know, I was like, oh,
what was that stupid thing?
I saw that was internet
connected the other day. Um,
oh, which kitchen appliance? Was it
all of them? Oh.
yeah, basically.
Uh, well, no,
the microwave I get because you could put some food
in it and microwave it when you get home.
But I think it was a mixer.
I'm just
exactly right.
Like a fridge. I, I
guess I get because you can see the weather on your fridge but
looking out the window is too much more.
Um, but, you know, a lot of the stuff we're attaching to the internet now
is becoming stuff that could, you know,
if it's taken over by an attacker would be very
d so a great example being self driving car,
right?
A self driving car being taken over by somebody who wants to, you know,
cause a bit of a ruckus that, that would be very bad.
And so,
you know, the challenges with CV is we've got this huge global software industry
and outside of the English speaking North American and a bit of Europe,
they, they really don't use CV. And I, I don't know how they track vulnerabilities
or if they do.
Interesting. So that would be saying, you know, folks out there, if you have any idea
what happens in, in say non English speaking countries, we, we'd love to know if,
if there's something going on.
Uh
I think though obviously
given the fact that CV E is so ingrained
in the current industry, at least in the
say North American region and, and a good portion of Europe.
I think the goal for you guys is really to kind of bring it everywhere. Right.
Exactly.
So essentially what we're looking at
is a Federation model, right? So
currently we have one Star Trek or their favorite,
pretty much the United Federation is security.
Yeah, it's like DNS. So we've, we've got the old sort of
special CNAs that, you know, happened a long time ago, like Red Hat Microsoft IBM,
those guys.
And now we have a new hierarchy called uh for the open source world, right?
The the and that runs under the distributed weakness filing project.
Let's stop there for a second and let's talk about DWF because
I cannot stress the importance of this project. Nor the fact that you created it,
it is your project and you should be insanely proud of yourself for that.
And so let's start with the name
DWF. How did you get those three letters?
-- It's CV plus one.
-- Oh, my goodness. That's amazing.
I also realized the other day and this blew me away is, it's,
uh dad and then my kids names and that was unintentional.
That's it is. It is. Wow. That's amazing.
That's fun.
Oh, my goodness.
And the funny thing is I've been using this for a year and not realize that
it
is. So this is, uh, there, there is,
there's a word for this. I forget the name of it. But
serendipity, you can. No, no, no.
You see things that aren't really there right where you can look at words or,
-- or this
-- is
a big,
uh,
you see a fox and you think it's Bigfoot
might
be.
So,
and to be honest, the, the, the, the idea for the DWF, I,
I'll be honest, I just, I took, you know,
the open source models that I know work in this case.
Um,
one of the most successful ones being the Linux kernel
-- and, and just let's do that. Well,
-- what does that mean? OK. So, so you create DWF? And
why
did you go down this path? Why did you decide DWF needed to be a thing?
So two big reasons is number one, we needed better
standards and tooling and
you know, some data formats uh around the CV E data.
And number two, structurally,
we needed to distribute it and scale out. So,
one of the challenges I find in the security world is, you know,
we tend to operate on not trusting things, right?
That that's literally our job is to not trust
things and to make sure that they're correct.
Conversely, you look at something like the Linux kernel and they operate in a,
in a high degree of trust,
right? Linux, uh sorry, Linus has, you know, trusted subsystem maintainers,
but, you know,
in turn, have maintainers that in turn have guys actually writing code
and essentially, you know, it's, it's distributed trust.
So Linus trusts his lieutenants, his lieutenants, trust their sergeants,
their sergeants, trust their,
you know, the guys working for them.
And this allows, I mean,
because how many patches is Linus accepting into the average colonel release?
Now?
It's, you know, it's in the thousands, it's,
it's clearly more than he's actually reviewing.
Right.
-- Exactly.
-- There isn't enough time
in
the months
to deal with them all.
Exactly.
So, you know, if, if the DWF ends up doing hopefully tens of thousands of CV S per year,
you know, that's, that's hundreds per day,
right. No one person can or should review that.
And so the idea, you know, is to scale it out to trusted people, um,
and not only to trusted people but to trusted people who have, you know,
specific expertise.
So, so
trust these people, is it like uh I mail you $20 and,
and now I'm a trusted organization or
it's even simpler than that.
Uh Number one, you can already have proven trust.
Uh So for example, yourself is a great example, right?
You have already assigned how many hundreds of CV S on
thousands.
And, and,
you know, we should probably talk about that too.
Is, is a lot of people don't know, is so for a long time, Miter
was,
uh I, I don't want to use the word closed,
but they were,
I, I guess very structured might be the right way, right?
And so dealing with the, the speed and madness of open source was very difficult.
And so what happened eventually was
I became
the CN A for the OS S security mailing list essentially. And then I assigned,
uh I,
I remember Steve Christie told me this one time was Miter was obviously the
number one CN A and I was number two for a long time.
And, and proudly enough,
I had a lower rate of error than Miter did, which pleased me immensely,
but not that, that, that really matters. But anyway, I did that for a couple of years
and then I moved on to do some other things and you took
over for me as the new open source security CN A and then eventually
Miter kind of
rearranged the way things work internally and
they became the open source security.
CN A.
Yeah.
And that's, they're, they're basically miters back to being the open source, uh,
security CN A.
Uh, you know,
with the goal being to transition all of
that over to the distributed weakness filing project,
uh, you know,
uh, and primarily there what we need, what I need there is to, you know,
get a bunch of technology in place to essentially make these, uh,
assignments go faster.
Uh And the other thing is to have, you know, CV, mentors to scale out and have,
you know, dozens of people who can
look at an issue and say,
is this a security vulnerability? Yes or no,
you know, because there's a lot of issues that look like a security vulnerability,
but they might technically not be, they might actually be like
security related in the sense of it's a hardening issue.
And yeah, we should probably tweak that a bit,
but it's not strictly speaking of vulnerability.
And then once we've established that it is a vulnerability,
then the second thing they need to do is apply what we call the CV E counting rules.
So in past CV E has taken
a somewhat pragmatic approach to counting vulnerabilities,
right?
We don't want to count every single individual vulnerability separately.
Um because there's cases where, you know, somebody goes through a PHP application
and finds 50 instances of cross site scripting.
And is there value in having 50 separate CV S for those 50 vulnerabilities,
especially when the,
-- the project fixes all of them in the next release
-- or
even in a single commit in a lot of cases.
Right.
Yeah.
So in that case,
what we tend to do is there's some rules around
merging and splitting issues into sort of buckets of CV.
-- Si
-- really just,
I have this like flood of memories back into my mind from when I did this talking to,
to, to miter about all that stuff I'd forgotten much about.
And it's honestly, it's really simple. It basically boils down to
you want to separate out the vulnerabilities by
like what is the vulnerability, you know,
buffer overflow versus cross site scripting?
Because, you know, those are two very different vulnerabilities and impacts.
Um And then the second main thing is by which version it affects, you know,
because if you have two buffer overflow
vulnerabilities and one affects version 1.0 through 1.2
and the other one affects version 1.1 through 1.2. You know,
that's good to know for the people running one point. Oh, they're not as vulnerable.
Yeah, definitely.
And that's basically what that, that counting rule stuff boils down to. And it's,
it's just, it's a pragmatic approach to sort of collect things up. And
uh because the other thing is to,
that's important to remember is CV,
technically speaking is about counting vulnerabilities,
but where it really becomes important for most people is in tracking fixes,
you know,
because, I mean, it's nice to have this catalog of vulnerabilities.
Uh But, you know,
so we're vulnerable now,
right?
And so the idea is by making the vulnerabilities trackable, then you can,
you know,
you as an administrator can say, well,
I implemented this firewall rule which blocks CV
E whatever or I removed the software package.
Right?
That's,
that's one of my favorite ways to fix a
vulnerability is just to get rid of the software.
You know, because, well, quite often, you know,
you'll find software that you're like, well,
I don't really need that software and it's got this vulnerability.
So do we really need it?
Um, you know, or you or you fix it or patch it
and then, you know,
you have your little check box and you can show your boss and everybody's happy.
The auditors are happy. Your scanning tool is happy.
So the idea really being is that I wanna divorce the technical side
of security vulnerability analysis
from the process side of simply assigning it an identifier.
Yeah, I think that that makes a lot of sense.
So, so the idea basically is to have, you know, a bunch of people who can,
they know which questions to ask and they
basically know what the answers should sound like.
Um because one thing too that started to happen is people have
started to try and shop around things that are not really vulnerabilities
and they've tried to get them CV numbers so that
they can essentially use that to pad their resume.
Uh,
so I don't know if you remember, but the infamous,
um, the infamous Apache, I think it's their 404 error page by default.
Prints out the URL that you tried to access, right?
It says you tried to access this and it doesn't exist. I'm terribly sorry.
Uh, and there's been numerous people that have tried to shop that around as a
CV E worth vulnerability
because the other thing to remember now too is there's money in this, right?
There's bug bounties where if you have,
you know, if you come to a bug bounty with a vulnerability, they might say
no, it's not
and send you away.
But if you come to them with a vulnerability that has a CV number assigned,
it's much harder for them to send you away,
you know, without you get, getting some money potentially.
So,
you know, it's important,
uh, like any system where money is involved, you know,
people are going to try and game it and abuse it.
Yeah, definitely.
Well, and I think one of the other interesting things is,
and this is something we've had to deal with in the past is
there are non
issues that get CV E I DS for whatever reason
and then
you can dispute that which puts it into kind of disputed status,
but it still means that the organization that has had the CV E assigned against, it
has to do some level of effort
to deal with it
even if it isn't really an issue.
And obviously that carries a certain amount of
pain and suffering that comes with it.
Now, now your automated system, do you have anything planned to deal with that?
Well, so basically, well, when I say automated, it's not fully automated,
it's just more of the data collection and some basic validation is automated,
you know.
So the goal is essentially
to get people creating high quality CV request because a high quality CV request
takes seconds to deal with, you know, a high quality CV request looks like
there's a cross site scripting in this project in this version.
And here's the actual,
you know, get
repo link with the vulnerable code and even better.
Here's a link to the patch, you know, and the patch is just wrapping it in
html, special cares, right? So it fixes it
a CV request like that, you know, especially where upstream has fixed it
is super easy to, you know, deal with takes seconds.
And then I've had other ones where I've gone back and forth for
a period of weeks with the report of trying to figure out,
you know, what is the actual impact of this?
How does this actually a problem?
And so that basically coming back to your question of how
do you trust these people to do CV S correctly?
Like I said, number one, they've already shown that they can, and number two,
they will have to take some minimal level of training essentially around, you know,
the CV, is this a vulnerability or not?
And what are the counting rules?
And then essentially we will,
what they do has their email address attached to it as the CV assigner, right?
And so essentially, then, you know, if, for example,
we get somebody who issues 100 CV s and like 10 of them end
up being disputed or 20 of them end up being rejected because they're wrong.
Then we know that that person either needs to be retrained or,
or removed from the system.
Um And the reality is the majority of people myself included,
we typically have an error rate of under 1%
you know, which I feel is a reasonably,
that's an ok error, right?
And you know,
that that's actually something really important as well is we
are notoriously bad at this insecurity is people make mistakes.
People are going to make mistakes when they make mistakes,
like do not beat them to death with a shoe because they made a mistake,
like you accept it and you move on.
But yes, if their error rate is 75% like that person is clearly misguided
or, or just a bad person, you know, one or the other. And so they need to be dealt with.
And so that's a big part of what CV is moving towards is a bit more,
having a bit more data. So the DWF, we actually collect a bit more metadata.
Uh For example, we, we have who requested the CV.
Because
to put it on,
there are people that request CV S and they always request them perfectly.
You know,
a great example being Jeremy Ellison from the Samba project, right?
When he comes to me and says, I need a CV, I'm like, sure, because he,
he and typically when he needs one, he, you know, it's real
um or like Tristan from the open stock project, right?
These guys have done this enough, they have enough experience.
They, they just, you know, they know how to do it.
Sure. Sure. Sure.
Well, and let's face it too. I mean, when you're requesting a CV E,
if, if you are doing it right,
you're going to have less work for yourself as well because you aren't going to say,
give me all of this extra information.
I need to prove this is or isn't what you say it is
exactly.
Like I remember a great example is um I don't know if
you know of or heard of the uh the China 360 guys,
three sixty.cn.
It's a company that makes hardware, wireless equipment and routers and stuff.
Uh And when they initially started, their CV requests were terrible
and then after about six months, they got really good at them
and the other thing that happened is that
it's interesting is the quality of their request,
like the stuff they were finding, you know, these are the,
if you read open source security, the mailing list,
um you'll recognize these guys because they're the
guys that keep finding flaws with Zen and,
you know,
uh Queen,
right? And these are like really high quality bugs.
These are not like a cross site scripting error.
These are like breaking into the hypervisor or, you know,
causing the entire system to flip out and, you know, crash.
Um
So it's, it's really obvious that from a maturity point of view, they,
they've really matured and gotten good at this.
Well, I mean, let's face it too. I think the vast majority of people,
they want to do a good job and they want to do it right.
It's just in many instances they didn't know what to do.
And so
II I think this is, this is one of the disservices I see,
especially in the security industry and in open source
to a degree as well is the fact that a
new person shows up and they do dumb things as new people tend to do
and they get driven away instead of properly helped. And
it's,
that's kind of a shame always is when that happened.
And so this is one of the things actually,
I'm kind of secretly hopeful with DWF is that
you can build kind of a AAA community of reasonable people. We'll say
that
is willing to have patience
with these folks when they show up.
Well, and that's one of the dirty secrets, right?
The uh up until recently, basically, there were two ways to get a CV number.
Either you came from the outside and asked for one
and you had to know how to do that
or number two, you were a fully fledged, credentialed CV,
numbering authority and there was nothing in between,
-- you know, there was no intermediate step.
-- I remember
a lot of people went back when I was AC N A. People would come and be like, I, I need this.
And there were,
you know,
because Miter had very strict rules about what we could or couldn't assign to.
And it was like, I'm sorry, I can't, I'm not supposed to help you
and then they'd say things like, but I've emailed me
six times and they still haven't gotten back to me. And I'm like, I,
you know, I really want to, but,
you know, this is what it is
now. Well,
that's
actually,
so,
so DWF,
are you only focusing on open
source software or are you willing to work with closed source vendors as well?
-- Uh The
-- DWF mandate
uh currently uh essentially as chartered by Miter is we are strictly open source.
Um Now that's, that's brought some interesting questions because for example,
there's
a lot of organizations that, you know,
I would call a hybrid where they do close source and open source.
You know,
I mean, the, the reality is virtually every
software vendor now has, you know, something on github.
At least one thing, some library they use or something they produce.
Not just that. Right. It's, it's crazy.
I,
I wonder if there are any software projects on the
planet anymore that don't contain some sort of open source.
I bet the answer is
probably not. At least nothing that matters.
That guy that wrote his own operating system in Assembler a few years back.
Was it open
source?
Oh, I think you might open source.
Yeah. Good point.
But that's like, cause yeah, that's the thing to do.
Like a clean room implementation of closed source nowadays would be.
-- Wow, where would you even begin? Let's face
-- it. What's the value
in not just reusing something that already exists.
There's, there is no value and well, let's face it too. So
uh some years back which you and I remember being old men now is
licensing was the scary thing because it was like, oh,
I'm gonna include open source in my product now.
I have to open source, my whole product and you know,
everything's running down whatever and, and people didn't quite understand it.
But I think we've reached a point now where
generally speaking,
what open source means and how these licenses work is fairly well understood.
And so I don't think it's near as scary for anybody. I mean,
it's, I mean, heck, what Microsoft and the Linux Foundation, right?
It's like these people are starting to understand
what this stuff means and it's not the demon
that it once was thought to be.
Yeah. No, I, I think basically, you know, based on the empirical evidence,
you know, nobody died,
nobody had to like open source, their crazy huge close source thing and,
you know, things worked out. Ok.
Um
And yeah, so like I said, one of my goals with this
is to, first of all, provide sort of a, a
ramp up from going from requesting CV S to becoming a full CN A
and, you know, have some intermediate steps for people
and then the most important thing. Secondly, is to
provide a way to bring people in
and,
you know, educate them and train them and,
and
have a mentor, right?
Because one challenge I find too is a lot of people I've, I've spoken to,
they don't want to do CV.
S because they're afraid they'll make a mistake. And I'm like,
huh,
you know, like, have you seen what I've done?
Um
Right.
And you know, but like you said,
the problem is you make a mistake in the security community
and the security community tends to throw shoes at you,
right? Because if you're unlucky,
they throw
shoes
and, you know, and, and the reality is, it's a challenge, right?
Because in the security community,
like an off by one buffer overflow or a
single missing character or a single wrongly typed character,
you know, can have a really significant security impact and cause a lot of problems.
And, you know, and that's,
that is how a lot of us view reality,
you know.
Um,
but the good news is the other thing that, uh we're working on.
Uh, and that the DWF does
is
in our CV database,
we explicitly have fields to deal with mistakes and messes.
You know, we have a state for the CV.
And typical states would be something like reserved where, you know,
the CV E has been issued,
but it's not yet public,
right?
Uh Another state would be public like the CV is now public.
Uh,
we have additional states like it's been rejected because it's not a
vulnerability or it's disputed or it's been replaced by a different number,
right?
Because uh this actually has happened. Uh Miter had already assigned a CV E
uh to an, uh, an issue some time ago and I missed that they had to sign this
and I was assigning a big block of CV S to a big pile of issues.
And I, you know, I, I checked,
uh a bunch at the beginning and a bunch at the end didn't check in the middle,
right? And worked on the assumption that, well, they didn't do any at the beginning.
They didn't do any in so the middle must be safe. Well, no, they they had done one.
So, you know, in the C in the DWF CV database, there's a CV that says, you know, CV, blah
replaced by and then the
miter CV number.
Um
And so the goal here is to
two big things.
Number one, when we do make mistakes, I want clearly label them as such.
And you know, why was it a mistake? How is it a mistake?
And number two,
what, what's the correct information?
Right? Make it
very easy to programmatically consume this, right?
It's very easy for a program to, to digest this file and go oh That's rejected.
So that means it's not real or? Oh, it's replaced by, oh, this one.
Go look up that 10 OK. Boom.
-- Now you have the correct data.
-- If I'm an end user,
-- do I need to snarf down the Miter CV E database and the DWF
-- database long term. No. Um
All
the hope is all CNA issued CVS will go to Miter
in as close to real time as possible.
And mir will then be able to put that information in their database very quickly.
The good news there is that the DWF had uh I created a JSON file format
and the miter guys created one and they're, you know, they're mostly compatible,
but you would still need like two parsers, you know,
one for each F format because they're a little different.
Uh The good news is we'll be using the
same format hopefully by beginning of uh next week.
Wow, that's soon.
Yeah.
Well, so basically, well, because the, the,
the formats were already pretty compatible but, you know, it was some minor things.
Um And so basically there will be the official,
what miter needs for a CV,
in that
JSON file, right?
And it'll be things like the CV number, obviously, things like the description,
things like what's affected, you know, what products are affected.
Um And of course, you know,
the DWF needs that as well. The DWF also has a super set of additional information
and so the beauty is you can just write a parcel that understands Mir
and you can also parse DWF stuff and get kind of what you need.
So let me
just
ignore
the
you have a library
that makes parsing the DWF
JSON
yet,
but we
-- will,
-- we should write one and then we can find security issues in it.
And
ID.
Yeah.
No, we'll be doing and that's the other big thing, right?
Is there's no tooling around CV S and CNAs every single CV E assigning
group does it differently? You know, some people use spreadsheets,
some people use a database, some people just added,
I think an extra field to their ticketing system or their
bug system.
Um And you know, and the challenge is especially with the open source world,
we're dealing with people that quite often don't have
a lot of extra time and effort to like,
put into process that,
you know, strictly speaking they don't need.
Right. Well, and let's also
too, if you're a small project, you might not even have a security team.
And so you don't, honestly, this isn't a high priority for you,
you want to get it dealt with and you go on to the next thing.
-- Yeah,
-- exactly.
And so two of the ways we're dealing with that is number one, we'll be,
we'll be creating tooling, essentially CN A in a box,
you know, that'll ultimately just have a web interface.
So you can generate good CV requests.
And the second thing is a process where uh change where
to become a CV numbering authority under the DWF,
you don't actually necessarily have to be able to issue the CV S yourself.
So the idea being is that we'll have, you know,
the traditional old style CNAs where they have a block of CV numbers,
they have people internally that are trained to do it,
they just handle it all themselves.
The new way will be is once you get to a certain maturity,
you can
um essentially
get a CV E mentor.
So essentially somebody who will sign off on your
CV request and say this CV request is correct.
It's well formed,
it should get a CV E,
right.
And so essentially that way the CN A can have their block of numbers.
So it's easier to track kind of what they're doing, what they're signing,
but they don't necessarily have to have a
CV E process person inside of their organization,
they can rely on an external person.
So the goal is they can have one or more of the CV, mentors
who, like I said, essentially sign off on these requests.
And you know, if a CV mentor said this is a good well formed request, it is correct,
then, you know, boom, it gets its CV, it gets in the database and it
lives its merry life.
That brings a tear to my eye when I think about how this all used to work because you
know,
it, it felt like
I don't,
I don't know if you were ever a Simpsons fan but there were always like the uh the,
the people who were kind of in power where they showed in like
Dracula was one of them but you know, they were in their, their dark back room and,
and kind of doing the deals and that, that's what CBE felt like.
I think at one point in time because, and it kind of was,
but man, this is, this is awesome.
-- So,
-- well, see, one of my big goals is
I've assigned about 5000 CV S now and I don't want to do another 5000,
but I want to enable other people to assign, you know, tens of thousands of CV S.
Well, and let's face it too, man. If you're talking about 10,000 I DS a year.
That's
an insane number.
And let's face it, we think it's way more than that that should be assigned.
But aren't,
which means
we have to get people out of this process. It has to be
machines.
Well, it's, yeah, and especially, I mean, if you look at the, so
the modern software ecosystem, I mean,
the last time I looked at Ruby Gems was about 34 years ago and they had 53,000 Ruby Gems
and I'm sure
-- none of them have security issues,
-- right?
-- You know, the Pie Pie project has I think also on the order of 50,000 Pie modules
-- and,
and you have to think about that.
I bet
a good researcher could find at least two issues in less than one hour
with
more than half of those,
which means we're talking about
potentially hundreds of thousands of CV E I DS in that case.
Well, especially when people start automating. So a guy named Larry Cash
Dollar who's also associated with the distributed weakness filing project.
Uh
He works for
Akamai
and
he
made some automated tooling to find flaws in wordpress plugins, right?
Um Because you know, this is something
-- Akamai cares about and wants to
-- block. Look
at
this
at,
at defcon this year, which I believe is on the internet.
I will try to find it and put it in the show notes.
Yeah,
but so the problem is he's in the
situation of like I found 1000 security vulnerabilities.
What do I do now? Right. Like, how do you know,
how do you, how do you even physically contact 1000 word press plug in maintainers?
You know how you actually a problem that DWF isn't going to fix necessarily,
but it will potentially make it better.
We will make it less painful.
I don't know that we'll be able to make it better.
That, that would be an awesome thing to do.
Um I think part of it, what I wanna do is, is just make this more accessible and more
normal, right?
Because right now CV still has that like, oh, this issue got a CV E, right. That,
you know, and, and ok, back when we had 1000 a year, maybe that was kind of amazing.
But now, you know, we're
like, right now I just saw CV, what was it? 9180 something go across my email,
you know, like we're, I think we might actually break CV
10-K this year, like for real,
you know, last year we came pretty close. It's
cracking,
right.
I need your help.
Yeah.
So, you know, the part of it is the normalization of this, you know, it,
it reminds me a lot of traffic accidents,
right?
Traffic accidents used to be kind of a big deal,
especially since cars didn't have crumple zones or like airbags.
Right.
And people got hurt and, you know, every time you drove by car accident,
there's like tons of,
you know, police and ambulances and fire and everything.
And, you know, now, like, for example,
locally the police service is flat outside unless it's an injury
collision or, you know, some other special case
just
come to the police station and file the paperwork.
Right. We're not coming out to help you because that's insane. Right.
So, you know, I've been in, I've had one or two minor fender benders where, you know,
I rear ended somebody or somebody rear ended me at slow speed and it's just like,
you know, you drive to the police station, they go, why are you here?
Oh, you had a traffic accident. They hand you, they hand each of you a form
they say please sit down and fill this out and they go ok, thanks. Right.
And, and that's, you know, traffic accidents by and large are not,
most of them nowadays are not that bad, you know,
and they, you know, they don't need a lot of special treatment and extra treatment,
but they do need to be tracked.
They do need to, you know, we do need a little paperwork around these things,
you know, for insurance purposes or, you know, in this case for making sure
that the vulnerability got fixed. Which version did it get fixed in?
You know, did it stay fixed?
So as as far as I'm concerned, you know,
CV E should just be a normal part of any software project, just like bug tracking,
you know,
that
everybody has bug tracking now that I remember back in the day when
a lot of software projects and even commercial vendors did not have bug tracking
officially
or source
management.
Well, yeah, I mean, like those are things that used to be black magic and now, well,
everybody, well, not everybody has it sadly, but most people have it.
Oh, yeah. Well,
and it's free. I mean,
look at that. It's crazy.
So,
I guess the one other thing we should mention is
you're going to be giving a talk at the RS,
a conference on all this.
Yeah. No.
Um, actually myself and Kent Landfield from Intel, who's another CV E board member
will be talking about basically how we are
saving CV E in the CV ecosystem with the open source way, the process, the methods,
the technology.
That's awesome.
I imagine you, you have your, what,
all your talk all written by now, right? It's already the middle of November.
Uh, I believe the slides are due in
three weeks.
So
that's
a lot
of time.
I think it's in December sometime.
Wow. Wow. Wow, that's, that's really soon.
Crazy, man. Good luck with that.
Yeah.
No, I mean, the good news is, it's, it's an actual,
it's a topic that's easy to talk about
because we're actually making some progress for once.
I like much of the rest of the industry. Right.
No, I mean, that's true. That's true. It's,
it's very
exciting.
It's CV, you know, the problem with CV is, is it was stalled out for a long time.
It, and, and the problem is it worked well enough that that was ok.
You know,
and, but like a lot of problems, it then kind of,
you know, it became a problem and well, then we fixed it,
you know, and now we're fixing it And the other good news is, is, you know,
DWF is not going to be the only CV hierarchy.
You know, we're already looking at
um having country
related hierarchies because
the reality is, you know, uh with time zones and language barriers, you know,
it can be very difficult
uh to deal with, you know, people
um also cultural issues, you know,
uh some countries security vulnerabilities are very sort of shameful, you know,
they're very something you don't want to really discuss in public that much.
But
the good news is these people do recognize the value of CV.
Or, you know,
you've got entire industries like healthcare and
aerospace and say the financial industries where,
you know,
they would probably love to actually have their
security flaws dealt with a bit more openly,
but like from a regulatory point of view, they can't,
you know,
um but there would be huge value in giving these people CV ES so that especially when,
you have to talk about a security vulnerability outside of your organization.
And especially when you're talking about more than one vulnerability,
which is almost always the case nowadays.
You know,
how are we,
you know, which one are we actually talking about? Which one are we dealing with?
And CV just makes that easy.
-- It's like
-- the metric system of security.
Oh,
well, we're down to two countries that don't use metric.
-- So, you know, hey, we're
-- getting
-- there.
-- Oh,
you know, I,
I love the fact that I've been systematically brainwashing my Children into
hating the English measurement system that we use in the United States because
everything can't stand
chains and hogsheads,
you know.
You know, that's something I,
I thought about before is III I didn't do enough research to figure this out,
but it would be awesome to make a tape measure
with all the insane units of length
that have been used in the past. Right? Like a rod or whatever, a cubit.
It
just have something you can pull out and, like, measure something like
two cubits wide.
Uh, it would, well,
I would just pick the most hilarious unit of measure for the given distance we're at
because
I'm sure
there are, there are, you know,
some of these are very long and some of them are very short
with its face and most are fairly long because back in the day,
they just didn't have the ability to measure anything, you know,
smaller than like a human hand,
which is also a unit of measure.
I just love the fact that we have things like the ton
and there's Tontonne, there's the long ton, the short ton,
the metric ton,
the imperial ton.
And if you look at the Wikipedia page for this,
you'll cry because it's not like they're off by a little bit, they're
-- in some cases off by like a lot.
-- Right. Right. Right.
Well, have you ever heard of the metric inch?
The metric inch is uh 2.5 centimeters per inch instead of 2.54
-- that makes, that's like defining pie as four.
-- I
know, I
know
it just
-- makes
-- PP could be defined as three and is a reasonable margin of error at that point.
But yes, it's madness, man. Anyway. All right.
-- I'm sorry, I'm flabbergasted. I metric
-- inch.
I've, I've just created a denial of service with Kurt.
He's going to waste the rest of his day reading up on the metric.
But, you know, I don't even know why I know that it's just one of those weird. Anyway.
So for those of you out there,
if you want the show notes about any of this stuff, because this, this episode is,
is actually quite informative and useful, unlike many of the others
is uh open source security podcast.com.
We will put all the show notes in there, whatnot, uh links to Twitter.
You can hassle us, ask questions, all that kind of stuff. And obviously,
if is the DW
is the DWF project accepting volunteers yet? Are you there?
Well, we're not quite there yet but, um,
I will be setting,
at least there's a mailing list and stuff so people can stay in contact.
Um,
the good news is this will be rolling shortly because now we,
we've essentially done a lot of homework and gotten the homework done.
-- Now we can start doing the fun stuff. Awesome.
-- Good deal. So I guess stay, stay tuned,
stay tuned. You'll figure it out and thank you everyone for listening.
Welcome back, Kurt. It was fun as always and until next time.
-- Yep. Have a good weekend. Everybody take
-- care. Bye bye.