Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime and totally not evading sanctions.
-- Josh Pressers,
-- have I ever evaded sanctions? You know, so I have, I was it a sanction?
I don't know.
So I have a story, I will tell that I don't think I've told on the podcast before.
Is this going to be one of those stories?
Is it going to be replayed in a court of law at some point when you're on the stand?
I'm certain the statute of limitations has passed on this.
But
the first time I went to Germany ever,
I had a friend who is like, I would like you to bring some
-- Alberto beef jerky with you.
-- Oh, that's not sanctions. That's like, that's,
you're not allowed to import meat into Europe because of
ma
we'll get to that, right? And I'm like, ok, sure. So I'm like, how much do you want?
He said, I literally want as much as you can bring. And I thought, ok,
I never,
I've never been to Europe. I didn't think twice about this.
So I put a ton of it in a suitcase, right? Like a lot. And as we're landing in Berlin,
they play a video and they're quite explicit in the
video that no meat products are allowed in Germany.
And I'm like,
I'm going to go to jail, like, I have a suitcase full of meat products
and I'm sitting there thinking like, what am I going to do?
Should I like, throw this away? Should I tell them what's going on?
I'm, I'm, I'm like freaking out, right?
And
now mind you an important aspect of this that
I did not realize prior to going to Germany is
my heritage is very German.
And so like when I would walk around in Berlin,
everyone would just speak German to me assuming I was
a German citizen because I look like a German citizen.
And so I'm standing in line waiting for the customs guy and I'm like,
I'm just gonna open the suitcase and be like, take it like you, I'm sorry,
I didn't know.
And I'm standing there and standing there and standing there
and all of a sudden the guy looks up at me and he goes, you can go and I'm like, thank you.
And I'm like, like, be cool, be cool, like be cool.
And I was like, as soon as I got out of eyesight, I'm like,
I've never run through an airport so fast in my life and
then I get there and I give it to the guy,
I'm like, did, you know, I'm not supposed to bring this.
He's like, oh,
it's fine. I logged a complaint with the government. This should be legal.
I'm like, no, should be, is not the answer here. Like, no,
you, you knew I shouldn't have brought this.
-- I'm pretty sure
-- this should be legal is not,
we're not a valid defense in a court of law.
I know.
But anyway,
that is my, I guess sanctions story and, and
not sanctions. But yeah,
you get the point anyway
anyway.
Oh my goodness.
-- Well,
-- and that actually reads us.
I've been thinking about this because open source travels across
borders in a way that almost nothing else does.
And I don't mean it just like people pull it down and
use it but people embed it and people like it goes everywhere.
And so there's this story where I PM I tools.
So I PM, I stands for intelligent platform management interface.
And it's a fancy way of saying instead of going to the
server and plugging a keyboard and monitor and a mouse into it,
wouldn't it be nice if you could do that over the network?
Is even when the things turned off.
So you could like turn the server on and like have bias level access,
install an os tweak it, fix it. Yeah.
Well, that's what I PM I does because when you have more than about 50 servers
you need I PM I
and if you have like 50,000 of them
you really need I PM I
anyway
uh so I PM I tools is, well, it's I PM I tools and it apparently got,
-- what's the word I want to use? I'm totally spacing out. Suspended,
-- the suspended.
-- Yeah, like archived
-- the get up account of the author,
the author
and everybody of course is like blah, blah, blah. Why?
Well, and the simple answer is sanctions compliance.
Like he works for a company, it's a Russian company
that um apparently is involved with the import
of tech that's being used for weapon systems.
So that company got sanctioned.
So his account is sanctioned.
And I, and I feel like on the one hand, this is a giant nothing burger of, you know,
company gets sanctioned.
Employee, get sanctioned sanctions, take place, you're not allowed to do that.
But it does raise some interesting questions sort of from a risk perspective
because on a related note,
we have Docker
basically saying
the free teams thing is cool and all.
But uh you got 30 days to either start paying or get your data out of here.
And then my understanding is once that 30 days passes,
if you don't get your stuff out,
then you have 30 more days to actually download
it and then they're going to delete it.
-- So you have like 60 days from a few days ago to get your stuff out of there or
-- pay.
There's another piece to the Docker story is there also, like if you're there,
there's no
what, what I
I may get this wrong.
But my understanding at this moment is if you are like a truly open
source project,
you may apply for like an open source license.
But if you are like one of those pseudo open
source projects where you're maybe backed by a company
or you're, you're using your open sources consulting or things like that,
then you have to pay them $300.
Yeah. And it's the consulting thing. So like technically curl
wouldn't make the cut off because he does consulting for Curl.
A lot of projects do this.
Yeah. Right. It's very common. So a lot of projects won't technically.
Yeah, because I mean, you could just make millions of dollars doing this. It's crazy
and by millions of dollars we mean tens of dollars.
Ok.
So I want to start with the the sanctions thing because I think
there's another piece to this that we don't talk about very often.
Another thing we're starting to see in the open source universe
is
the question is coming up of, for example,
do any developers who work on this software
live in China?
And obviously there are like governments of the world that
aren't particularly friendly to China for a variety of reasons.
And so they asked this question and now when they work with a vendor,
they will ask the vendor is any of the software
in your product of Chinese origin or Russian origin or,
you know, pick a country that the, the, the United States government doesn't like.
-- Well
-- and stupid question.
But what exactly do they mean like would a Chinese national working
legally in America with a green card count as Chinese origin?
My understanding is no,
they specifically want software that originates from China because I think
NVIDIA got in trouble for this where they had software from.
I don't even remember what country it was now.
This was like years and years and years ago.
I I if I'm recalling correctly, we get the point
is we have historically ignored borders and open
source because let's face it on the internet.
A border is a meaningless construct.
But we are now reaching a point
where these huge governments and these huge companies
are basically, they've lifted the window shade and they're like holy crap.
Where did all this open source come from?
And they're starting to ask these questions like, where did it come from?
Who wrote it?
Does it use certain encryption algorithms? Maybe that are on our don't use list?
Does it? You know what I mean? And so
I feel like this is almost a new era of open source we're entering
where the companies are starting to ask the questions.
And now we have to figure out like what does this mean
in the broader sense of open source and risk appetite
and securing our software and securing our infrastructure and like it is
an enormous elephant to eat.
Yeah.
Well, and I'm not sure
that
we can, because I, I've been thinking about this, like,
in the S
bomb context, wouldn't it be cool to have an S bomb? That's like your bill chain?
So that, for example, if you're dependent on a Docker container that is
maybe going to go missing in a month or two because, you know,
it's part of an open source project that can't pay for it.
And so they're going to get removed from the github
Docker registry that's going to impact your BUILD C
I CD pipelines and your whole availability thing,
you know, wouldn't it be great to have a list of all the authors that ever contributed
it and what their legal status is for the purpose of sanctions.
And the reality is we're just,
we're not going to have that data to that level anytime soon.
Right. It's just not going to happen
soon, eventually, maybe if there's enough demand
and
for the majority of us, we don't care like I use True Naz.
And there could be a news article tomorrow saying true Nas
is, you know, actually controlled by the Mars aliens that want to subvert
the world government.
And I'd be like, cool,
I still want my pluck server to run,
you know. Right. That's the thing, right.
This whole open source thing is we can do sort of incremental change,
but we can't throw it out, we can't replace it, we can't,
like, we can't do anything significant. It's, it's like road infrastructure.
You know, whenever I, um, you know,
there's all these famous intersections that have
been intersections for thousands of years,
like in Greece and in Europe and they will continue to be
intersections there because people need to drive their vehicles through there and
we can't build a building there. Like traffic needs to go through.
So
sure,
I think what's going to happen though is we're going
to see this sort of classic thing where it's gonna be
sort of complaints, driven, enforcement of like, oh, you know,
this person works for this company.
They're saying, you know, somebody kicks up a fuss and then
somebody like Microsoft can't ignore that. They can't be like, oh, it's ok.
We'll just let their account sit,
like
has to suspend the account.
-- Yes, I mean, I get that. I
-- don't think Microsoft right now is trying to verify
-- the nationality and employer of every account on github.
-- It's certainly not.
And the thing to remember too is when you're talking
about some of these services used by open source Micro
Soft has very little to gain by
suspending accounts like this or, or rather not suspending the accounts,
I should say, right?
Where if they try to put up a fuss,
what do they get?
I mean, sure, the open source community might be like, oh, good job Microsoft,
but the people writing them big checks are gonna be like, no, that's not,
that's not how it works.
Well, it's like the whole D MC A thing. Take down content on youtube and stuff.
Right
here we are two decades later,
still a problem.
People still
haven't left youtube
and, and I think this also then kind of ties into the Docker situation of,
we like to think about some of these services as the company is
ha has the the the true intentions of open source in mind.
And the reality is like companies are companies and they have to do things
that helps keep them alive,
which may not line up with the things the open source universe wants.
And I'm not in any way bashing Docker for this.
I'm certain this was a business decision and they probably
put a lot of thought and discussion into it.
But this is one of the realities of the universe we exist in, right? Like
open source owes you nothing as we've said many times before. But additionally,
companies don't owe you free services either.
No.
But part of, well,
one of the arguments against is that Docker only became
popular because of people using their free service and adding
Docker
hub and registry are only valuable
because of the network effect of having everything in there. And what do they have
in there because it was free
and, and part of this not really a second argument,
but one thing I would say is 30 days is not a long time.
No, no,
I agree.
And a good example of this is to, for example,
to get on the joint Mastodon registry web page.
One of the requirements is you have to commit to giving at least,
I think it's three months warning if you're going to shut down your incident
to give people time to move
for,
for the kind of infrastructure behind Docker like the number of things using
the Docker Registry,
three months probably isn't enough time. I
think six months to a year would be the bare minimum
you could reasonably justify here. So that part I definitely don't agree with.
But anyway,
so all of this put together,
here's the thing I keep thinking of in my mind
is
when you and I were young
nearly. I,
I know that's fine.
It was 20
years
ago.
It was 2020 nice track.
But
so back in the day,
there wasn't all this open source infrastructure that you could use, there was no
github
there. What was it? Source forge existed
for
C
-- A? There were things but there
-- were some things but they definitely,
but we didn't rely on them as much because part
of it is they just weren't as reliable and,
and that's part of it.
And I think that is
an aspect of open source that
it's changed substantially. And I think we have to think about
what that means. I mean, so kind of, one of my, one of my new favorite examples will be
in, in,
what was it, the last podcast I think, you know, I,
I kind of made the off the cuff remark of if Amazon, if Aws collapsed, you know,
society would cease to function.
And someone on, on master, I was like, oh, that's, you know, that's not true.
And I'm like, you know what I think it might be.
Yeah.
But the point is, I mean, think about things like if
github disappeared
open source as we know it would be probably crippled beyond
a level, we can comprehend
the
reason.
That's bad. Remember when Ruby gem sort of got hacked but not really.
I
recall this. It was,
you know
how they recovered.
There was one developer highly trusted
who had checked out the entire thing a few days earlier.
That's like the toy story.
Yeah,
exactly. Yeah. Yeah.
It's the exact same story basically.
Yeah, like toy story developer was pregnant, working from home,
had a copy of the film that was a few days out of date
and yeah, somebody oops and deleted everything
and
thank goodness that lady had a copy at home that was offline because
yeah,
and that's the thing. Like there's, yeah, we can't recreate github
that way. That's not sustainable.
I'm reminded of like, like here's a great example youtube downloader has a,
they made a change in youtube the way it does the file. I DS or something.
And so youtube Downloader broke and it's literally a one line patch to fix it,
which I did on my system because I wanted it to work
and they haven't cut a release yet.
So it's broken for basically all users of youtube downloader.
And apparently the reason is their automated build pipeline is not working
and they want to fix that and then do a release.
They don't want to manually do whatever, don't care.
But the point is something as simple as a one line patch.
The, the issue
on github
for this is several 100 messages now. And like
and rightfully so because
most people they can't
do this,
you know, and then there's the alternate suggestion of you can pip install,
pointing directly at a G
repo. You can actually do, did you know you can do a pip install of like pointing at a G
URL. I, I
-- don't know
-- that
-- I believe N PM does it
-- also? Ok. Cool.
And again, even just getting that to work like telling people, oh, it's easy,
just install GIT and then run this command.
Yeah,
like a lot of software
users can't do that,
but it's not that easy. You have to install Python, you have,
there's like there's a lot of moving parts to that.
Well, you'd have Python already if you're running youtube downloader. But
you know, but the point is like, and this is a simple one liner patch.
And now you're talking about like, oh, maybe the repo disappears,
right? And now, now imagine telling a project
you can't host in github
anymore. You have to host it yourself.
That is not a reasonable suggestion.
And you and I have set that up and we know how much work that is.
That's the thing.
Yeah.
Well, and not just that,
not just the setup setup is easier than keeping it running for decades.
Setup is easy.
The one thing I'm
well and speaking of github,
for example, it it out that thing about, you know,
does anybody else like aggressively hit fork on
repo so they have a copy in their account
and people are like that waste space. And I'm like,
no, this is not how
github or enterprise data storage works.
And one thing I'm realizing is the vast majority of
people have no idea how this works because like,
why would they like, I have no idea how a modern car factory works.
You know,
I've seen the pictures of like the horse like where the horse is dragging
the model T Ford around the factory and a strong man or no,
sorry, it was a strong man, not a horse.
Remember the first assembly line that Ford built, right?
And like
you again,
there's by definition,
the infrastructure that we really rely upon tends to be
hidden and silent, especially when it works and works well.
It's just quietly working in the background.
That's right.
And
like open source is a great example of this. When open source works,
everybody ignores it.
And then when, for example, the Russian developer who wrote CO J is like,
I need to make a living, I need to, you know, get paid
and I'm not getting paid by doing this open source.
So I'm going to basically give it up and go get a real job
and everybody's like uh oh
-- and then there's no step to it like we don't have it. Like,
-- I mean, it's very,
as you describe this, I feel like this is the story of security
where everyone ignores their infosec team until they get popped
and then they're the most important team they have.
And it's like, yeah,
remember all that stuff we've been telling you for years you've ignored
like
guess what?
And
open source is just like that when open source works,
no one cares and no one thinks twice about it.
But when it doesn't work, holy cow, everything collapses
well,
and we've come to be so reliant on this
because there is no option to open source there.
You can't write this stuff yourself. I cannot write a you
-- downloader script.
-- Oh my goodness, stop using this excuse. Come up with a new one.
We know,
-- you know.
-- But I mean, that's the thing is people seem to think, oh,
how many people say, oh, I could rewrite curl in a weekend.
No one can do that.
And the people who think they can are very mistaken.
But I think going, I mean, if we,
you keep saying
no one can rewrite all this stuff. Not economically.
I like the way Toma described it in that I'm not a supplier podcast
a couple of episodes ago where he talks about things become open source because
they are a commodity resource.
They don't become a commodity resource because they're open
source and that kind of turns it around.
And I think that's part of the challenge is we have open source stuff that be
it came into existence because
it was turning into a functionally a commodity.
But now we're running,
we have critical infrastructure that is things like Docker and github
and
Git lab and probably a million other things.
Perfect example, like if Docker registry hub went away tomorrow,
basically every container service on the planet would
absolutely if github,
right. These are services that are like
they're, they're the same critical level
to society as electricity is now.
I can go buy a generator at Home Depot.
I can't go buy a github
or a Docker at home. No, I'm serious.
Like
you can like for about 15 to $20,000 you can very easily get a whole home
generic generator that runs on propane or gas
with automatic cutting and all that stuff.
No problem.
But
there's no alternative. Like I cannot run a github for myself, let alone for the
the
1000 projects. I need for my web dependency.
There are organizations that maintain internal repositories
of the stuff they use and you should
mind you like that is not a bad decision because then you keep things forever.
But even if
you have an internal repository, if github
died,
you're probably still screwed because my
suspicion is you're probably using github
for
the actual software you use, ignoring all of those dependencies.
You have a backup of off to the side.
Yeah. Yeah. Unless you have those Hermetic builds and a
system to support the Hermetic builds, that itself is Hermetic
to make sure you have everything
and, and honestly,
it's just not worth doing because like my internet goes down for like a
couple of minutes every couple of months
when tell us does maintenance or something.
You know, github
has github
been down recently ever, like reddit was down this week for a few hours
down.
I don't remember the last time github
-- went down but I know it occasionally blips for a little while and then
-- you
just
basically, I, yeah, I've played video
and that's the thing is the infrastructure nowadays is reliable enough that
it doesn't make sense to build your own complete backup to it.
Whereas like 20 years ago you had to because it was so unreliable,
you didn't have a choice.
Right. Right.
And I think this is where now
I,
I hate to say regulation because I feel like I
just default to that is the answer to everything.
But I think like we've reached a point where a lot of these services are
like
in the public's interest to have some level of like regulation and,
and stipulations on how they should and shouldn't work.
Like
-- this is,
-- this is kind of why I'm glad Microsoft bought github
is Microsoft is big and they get stability like
you still can't like on your windows machine type make their
Pr N
and watch it fail because Pr N is a reserve D OS device name.
Is
it?
-- Yeah,
-- printer
pr N
12,
there's a
whole bunch of stuff that's reserved but like to this day
you want to get ad OS based program working that expects Pr N to be a printer,
it'll work.
That's it
like.
And so no, no, but from like from that regulatory boring, it just works point of view.
Yeah,
Microsoft is probably about the best entity that could have bought
github and not try to monetize it in some horrific way.
I mean
given time
they're not done yet,
we still to merge it with linkedin.
Oh
my goodness. The things that just entered my mind I will never speak of,
but
I think this is one of the things open source needs to be aware of.
And II I have no answers. Mind you, I have no, I don't even have ideas in this space.
I just think these are the sort of problems we have
been able to ignore for the last what 30 plus years
that open sources existed. And I think
we are reaching a point
where we can't ignore them anymore because I think we're going
to see some of these things happen more and more often.
Well, I think we're beginning to realize we might have systemic risk.
Right.
No, no, no.
Because like for example,
Silicon Valley Bank does have some unique properties and that they have like
a big herd of depositors that all talk to each other on Twitter.
And like when they decide to do a bank run, they
like it was a marathon.
-- Well,
-- there wasn't much running, right. Just click the mouse.
And so I think the thing is,
are, do we have a few unique open source projects that are risky
or is this a systemic risk of,
you know,
are we going to see like
let's put it this way if, if 100
if you and I got to pick 100 core open
source developers that quit and never do open source again,
we could basically cripple the world
probably it would definitely be tough to, to bring some of that,
I guess resource usage back.
But now
I, I would let's, I want to turn this on its head
if elect and this is an idiotic thing to say. But if electricity went away,
the computers don't work either.
But why are we certain we will have electricity tomorrow?
Well, outside of Texas
grids are
and
ok. No, I'm sorry, I'm going to throw
under the bus for this one because
they do not have a well regulated grid. Like it is provable.
Like they keep having massive outages.
They claimed it was a feature and it might have been until
-- a couple of years ago when it turns out that's
-- the thing.
Like electricity is well regulated. We understand it. Well, like I,
you can do backups or replacements at multiple levels.
Like I could do a home generator.
We could, you know, there's different things I can do.
But with software, like I can't replace curl curl, I need curl.
Stop it. That's stop talking about rewriting curl.
Like I, I feel like you're going to go senile someday and just rewrite curl.
That's going to be what you do and everyone's gonna be like, oh,
there's old man curt rewriting curl again.
That's all you talk about
it.
Oh, my goodness. No. Anyway,
I think this is one of the things I
keep thinking about now is like electricity and water
and roads
and all of these things
I don't think are any different now than open
source software or even github to a degree.
Like,
I think they are the same sort of critical
infrastructure except we don't talk about open source or github
as critical infrastructure. We talk about them powering
other critical infrastructures like nuclear plants or dams or whatever.
But
I think this is a conversation
that whether we want it or not,
it's going to happen because I think we're going to
see more and more events until we can't ignore it.
Now. Don't get me wrong
as humans. There is nothing we are better at than ignoring
until it's too late.
Like
we like just look up rivers on fire
if you want to know what I'm talking about.
A very simple example is electrical transformers, right?
They have 12 to 18 month lead times on building
these things because they are horrifically complex and complicated.
And essentially
the way we've dealt with it in Ukraine is everybody's just sending them stuff
and all the other orders are getting backlogged,
right?
Kachi just made them priority.
Canada is sending transformers
like
because we we just and we're pulling them from spares like we're not
making new ones magically in a week because if we could build the transform in a week,
well, we'd have been doing that in the first place, right?
And so
like transformers are very much a critical path component of the electrical grid.
And
but the
for the majority of the time, you know, transformers
die once in a while, but there's no major event that wipes out a pile of transformers.
And I think that's maybe the difference is like
we have github,
we don't have
like
six different competing gith hubs
or six different competing Docker registries.
We have
-- a and that's especially in software
-- Well,
there are competing Docker registries now and I
suspect they're going to get a lot more popular
name. Three.
So the three Docker registries I would name and I can name more than three. Mind you.
There's the, the Kubernetes one.
That was what GCR dot IO that just got renamed like Ks dot IO, I think.
Anyway, they're renaming it.
There's the Amazon container registry, there's the github
container registry. Microsoft has a container registry.
Do you want me to keep going?
And fun fact, how do you get the darker tools to use them?
They won't even make it a configuration variable.
It's hard coded into use the darker registry for a lot of these. You
-- can
-- change that in the configuration file.
It's not super pleasant though, I will admit because I've
see and that's I've done some work and also Red Hat has a registry,
there's lots of registries.
But anyway,
it, it, it can be done, but it's not pleasant is how I would describe it.
But we,
so the tooling already doesn't support having multiple
registries and kind of pulling from multiple sources.
-- We would need to do a lot of work for that to work.
-- Well,
I mean, I, I think what we'll see the answer will be
the container name is just going to also contain the registry name, right?
-- They're, they're functionally name space in that regard and whatever
-- that's fine.
And what's interesting then
why is this not a problem for things like N PM, js.org or for Rust crates
or is it a problem for them?
-- It isn't
-- a problem yet. Well, wait, you mean them hosting all of this data or?
Well, what I'm saying is,
is this a Docker registry problem or is it
a systemic problem with having one registry for X
or one resource for X
I? I think you're asking the wrong question.
Docker is a company N PM and Rust are foundations.
-- And so that's what I'm saying is, is that a meaningful difference or not?
-- It?
I maybe, yes, I think it is
because if N PM ran out of money,
it would become a huge problem.
It's just, it's a well funded foundation because, well,
it's critical infrastructure for lots of,
lots of other companies. And that makes sense.
Docker is a company
and if they don't make money, they can't exist like that's just how companies work.
And so this is a perfect example is maybe the systemic
risk mostly limited to companies and not the nonprofits if so.
Ok, cool.
Like open source is probably going to be OK,
it'll be ugly for a bit once we lose some companies
maybe or you know,
like basically do we need to decompose these into
having multiple entities or is it just we,
they need to be under nonprofits?
Maybe
I can't answer that because all of these foundations are still using github,
generally speaking to drive
everything. Actually, the N PM.
Did N PM Microsoft, I think technically has control over N PM now,
don't they?
But I believe and don't II I may be getting this wrong.
So I apologize in advance and, and please tell me on, on
Mastodon or something, but I think
N PM
is controlled by Microsoft. But is there a foundation behind it?
I'm less, I'm less certain now that I talk about this.
That's
what I'm saying.
When I talk about systemic risk, if,
if the systemic risk can largely be addressed by having it run under a nonprofit?
Cool.
Like that's a relatively in the scheme of solutions. That's a simple one.
-- I
-- mean,
sometimes, but look at
open SSL is a nonprofit and they've had, uh, well, it's,
it's a little better now but they had huge cash flow problems in the past.
Well, I mean,
cash flow problem is going to be an issue regardless of how
it's structured or who you are because you just need resources,
right? So, I mean,
I,
I
don't think Open SSL would have worked as a company.
I suspect it would have been worse than as a nonprofit.
Yeah, I mean, look at Mozilla,
let's pick on Mozilla, you couldn't have a web browser company today.
There's just, there's no way
unless you have some like bizarre niche and you see
that in like opera and brave and some of these,
these, you know, I guess third party browsers, but fundamentally speaking,
-- you've got Google.
-- Well, you've got Chrome and Safari.
Yeah,
those are used by a larger company to drive other things they want to do
and everyone, if you're not using it,
you should totally use Firefox because it's awesome.
We can,
Kurt and I can get into argument now about how he doesn't like
the Firefox profile manager and I keep telling him to suck it up.
It does too. You just type about profiles and you get a terrible looking screen
but,
but it's good enough, suck it up anyway. All right,
we've been talking for 30 minutes and I feel like
I have more questions than answers at this point.
And maybe that's good. I don't know.
Well, here's my hope is that some academics start looking at the open source market
as they have at financial markets and, and maybe start looking for,
like, are these systemic risks? Are they, how do we look at them?
What are the risks like we need a lot more research and understanding here?
You know what I think?
I think we are at an inflection point
in open source
and I don't know what it's going to look like on the other side of this, but I feel like
something big is going to change in the next couple of years.
I suspect it's just gonna keep limping along as it has.
I don't, I don't know, this one feels different to me.
One thing I'm really curious about though is the interaction of A I chat
GP T and code creation and code improvement and code editing with open source.
Because no, like I've been using chat GP T to write code and it's
pretty good. Actually,
it can do certain things very well. It can't do it.
That is a complicated topic.
Probably discuss another day.
But the one takeaway I have from using chat GP T is chat GP T is a heck of a power tool.
And the more powerful the user, the more powerful that tool is
I have had
a very different experience than you I think.
Well, so what I'm saying though is is if you want somebody
to basically if you want chat GP T to write web browser
related code,
you or I doing it versus a actual web browser developer driving it,
they're going to get better results.
And so what I'm saying is I,
I suspect chat GP T might be a heck of a power tool for these projects to start using.
I think that is a different conversation to the one we're having.
And I'm not going to address that in any meaningful way right now.
I think fundamentally
at the end of this conversation,
we are going, I mean, sadly,
we have to wait to see what the future of open source looks like.
But I think the future of open source will not look like the past.
And that is exciting and terrifying at the same time,
I'm not, I just, I can't see the economic incentives changing significantly.
I don't think it's going to be economic incentives.
I, I honestly, and you're going to hate this I regulation.
I think it's going to happen.
I think that's part of the story.
And I think what's really fascinating is all the regulators
I've seen so far talking about this seem to understand that
you can throw companies that use open source under the bus,
but the developers, they're in violet and that is fascinating that they get that.
So let's put this conversation on hold.
I'm going to end this show because we're
going to be talking to someone from the sovereign
fund in the very near future.
And so we will have a literal expert on this topic. We can ask questions to,
well, not just an expert, but this is like
representative of actual government policy and understand
and I'm hopeful we're going to get a glimpse into the future.
So I'm ending it now before we drag on much longer. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you, everyone. Go to open our security podcast.com. Find the show
Pounds
as podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.