Hello, and welcome to the open source security podcast.
I'm Kurt Siefried and with me is Joshua Bresser.
Hello. He said, please, Kurt call me Josh. Don't ever, Joshua is what I hear.
I'm in trouble
as far as I know, I'm not in trouble at this moment. So let's just,
let's keep it informal.
Well, it really doesn't count until I use your middle name.
Yes.
Anyway, how are you doing?
I'm good. I'm good.
So, I'm pleased to say the podcast went public last week.
This will be our second week of actual
real time news. And, and that's exciting for us. And so
what are we gonna talk about this week? Kurt, what you got on the list?
Well, I was thinking maybe we could do, uh, some things around container security,
uh, container security. Everybody's favorite topic.
But, but in all seriousness, that is something interesting.
But how about before we get to containers? Let's, uh, let's look at the news.
You've got a handful of things here that,
that you wrote down that are actually super interesting
and, and maybe not the most open source topics, but still very,
very interesting from the security point of view.
Well, yeah, one of my favorites this week was, um,
somebody basically hacked into a shipping database, uh, for a shipping company
and figured out who's sending gold bars around
and intercepted the shipments.
And it was actually caught because the post or, uh,
I don't know what the correct term is nowadays.
The
postal carrier.
Uh, actually,
well, in this case, yeah,
he actually knew the customer and so the guy at the door trying to convince him to,
you know, hand over a package,
you know, he knew that wasn't the right guy. Yeah.
And it got me thinking there's, you know,
there's all sorts of fungible goods that don't have serial numbers and that you can
sell it a pawnshop or online easily like
stolen beanie babies or magically gathering trading cards
or
probably,
um, but, you know, that's the thing, right.
There's, there's when you think about how
reliable the majority,
like when you think about how many packages go missing from Amazon,
I bet the number is horrifying if we actually know what it is.
Well, true, much like, you know, luggage at airports.
But when you consider overall the rate
of loss, you know, it's pretty low.
I, I suspect this now, but here's what I took out this, that, that is interesting is
I understand the security angle of protecting your
data and sometimes when you're sending something sensitive,
you have to be careful that in fact,
I, we'll have to look this up. I believe that when they shipped
one of those super huge, one of a kind diamonds that were found,
they actually put it in a brown box and,
and mailed it via like regular post because they didn't want anyone to know
it was, there was no other way to do it securely.
So that kind of security through obscurity.
However, in this case, I find it fascinating that it was really kind of the,
the human angle that fixed this because the postman knew who it was supposed to go to
and just due to having that interaction that actually foiled the bad guy in this,
you know,
I would have gotten away with it if it wasn't for you kids and your dogs sort of thing
versus relying on any sort of technology to help us out here, which quite frankly,
I don't know if technology could necessarily solve this problem.
Well, I mean, at a very simple level asking to see some ID, right?
That, that introduces another step of having to create fake ID, at least, you know,
for the bad guys,
you know, and I mean, it's, it's not hard but it, it does,
it does make it a little bit harder.
Um,
has a delivery person
ever asked for ID from you?
Yes. But mostly because of duties that were charged
things that ship from the States quite often I have to pay duty on them.
And so they want to see ID, not for the package so much, but because of the credit card.
Sure. Ok. Ok.
The first thing I can think of here is,
can you imagine how much more expensive shipping would
become if every time a package was delivered,
the delivery man had to say, can I please see your ID? And I'll say, oh, crap.
It's in the house.
Wait here while I go dig through my belongings
trying to remember where I put my wallet.
And I bet in many instances you'd probably be talking about adding near an
hour a day to a delivery person schedule just to find I DS.
Yeah.
Well, I mean, quite the opposite I've done is with, for example,
with uh one of the sh M Comeys, I deal with I, I went through a rather lengthy process
to qualify for their signature not required even when a signature is required.
Right?
So, and,
and the end result of this is I have a little sticker on my mailbox with a barcode
and their logo on it
so that the guy can blip it
instead of waiting for me to take a signature.
And then you can just leave the package uh uh
behind the snow shovel or whatever, you know, under the mat by the door.
That's, that's crazy, man. You, you opted for the less
-- secure option. Well
-- done.
I don't, I rarely buy anything worth more than 20 or $30 online.
That's true too. I, I, you know, it's just not worth it. Right.
Like I bought some D cell batteries for a flashlight
and the weirdest thing
because Amazon use some, like,
off brand shipping company that I've never heard of locally.
Uh, probably because,
uh, probably because, well, yeah,
I just see this random dude standing on my porch with, well,
an Amazon box and I'm like,
thinking one of my neighbors received it accidentally or something,
you know, and then he gets in his station wagon and leaves.
Uh, and I looked it up and it's, it's,
I think what happened is because we were gonna have,
we were potentially going to have a postal strike here a few weeks ago that
Amazon
started outsourcing a lot of their deliveries to be on the safe side.
-- Sure.
-- Sure. Sure.
Um
You know,
reminds me
of is I remember one time.
Uh In fact, no, th th this was
the first laptop I was ever sent by Red Hat.
They sent it in. I think it was three packages. There was the,
the laptop and a docking station and I believe there was
power connections or something like that that came with it.
And I'll never forget this because
the first box comes and it requires a signature.
And I'm like, oh, my laptop finally came. That's fantastic.
And
it shows up and I look at it
and it's the docking station and I'm like, man, come on this, this sucks.
You know, I've got a docking station, no laptop.
And then the next day the laptop came, the guy said it on the port,
rang the bell and left there was no signature required on the box of the laptop in it.
And I'm thinking this is hilarious that this happened in this order.
But that, that, that happens. I'm sure more often than not. But, all right.
Anyway, what, what else, what else we got on our list?
So then another interesting thing is
talking about the French Dark Web
and how, apparently there's,
there's actually some really big differences in sort of
the various countries in their dark webs and their,
you know,
illegal online marketplaces and what they sell and how they sell it, which, uh,
I wouldn't have guessed, you know,
-- I would have thought the Global Underground is sort of more consistent
-- and
it makes France special in this case.
So apparently they have some really strong reputation sort of
controls that basically if you go on these dark webs
and either don't ship the stuff you're supposed to
or don't pay for the stuff you're supposed to,
you will be named and shamed,
uh, and driven out.
Uh II, I believe that actually. Have you read Krebs's book Spam Nation by chance?
So you should
read it again
and he talks about this, in fact, on this kind of, you know,
underbelly of the internet, we could call it perhaps
the way some of these organizations run
is that there's a very specific reputation system
and
essentially, you know, if you can, the thief
you're done,
they will everything from just ruining your ability to conduct business to,
in some cases even, you know, physically coming after you.
It, it's a fascinating read. I would, I would suggest it for anybody out there
about what's going on
it. Yeah. It's, it's wild how
I do. We want to call it advanced.
I don't know what to even call it when we're dealing with kind of this, this
other side of, of the net and, and ransomware is the same thing. Right.
There are ransomware companies
that have reputations and even support for that matter.
I mean, they're running like legitimate businesses. It's crazy.
Well, it's, it's, if you look at some of the, you know,
less developed nations with the kidnapping issues,
right.
Kidnapping doesn't work unless, you know, you're gonna get your person back.
You know, you, you can't, and you can't damage them too much.
Yes. That, that, I mean, that's a good point wild man.
Although I think
so. Does this make France special? I haven't read this article.
I admit, I apologize.
I suspect it's not special and I mean, let's face it,
there's so much of this going on that by definition we don't really know about,
you know, and there's, there are companies that track it
and write reports. Um,
and I suspect in many ways it's not as bad as we fear.
But at the same time, I mean, I know I've read articles talking about,
um, what was that guy? He set up a computer program to buy things off of the dark web.
Uh, just like things that cost, like, what was it, like, €10 or less? Right.
And he was in Switzerland, I believe.
And I've heard this of Amazon $1 a day things but
-- man, buying things off the dark web every day, that sounds like a recipe for going
-- to
end
up buying some drugs and
you know, just it was,
but it was,
well,
and here's the part of the answer was he wanted to
figure out is this illegal having a computer program do something
-- and, and how did that? Is he still in jail or did they let him out?
-- No, no.
Iii I don't think so. I, I, but
it, it does raise some interesting questions. You know, if you have an agent
running on your behalf that does something that's illegal somewhere,
-- you know,
-- you know what this reminds me of is the time
the monkey took a selfie
and then
it spent years in court to decide who owns the copyright on that image,
which it ended up the monkey.
I guess
it is.
Monkeys can't own copyright. So it's a public domain image. But
so
man, I, I don't, I don't see it. I'm sorry
because
so if my computer accidentally buys something illegal and then it's delivered to me
and they come get me and be like, oh, it wasn't me. It was my computer.
I, I just, I don't see that defense holding up in court
and if it does
everything anyone ever does again that's illegal is going to
be their automated computer doing the work for them.
Right.
Well, yeah. Uh, yeah, here we go. The random Dark Net chopper
and it was an, it was an actual art exhibition and he gave it $100 in Bitcoins per week
to go buy things on the dark web.
Uh,
I'm sorry,
I don't see how you can't imagine going to
jail is the only reasonable outcome to this experiment.
Well, what think about, for example, uh,
companies that have written software that they
run that end up doing things that are,
you know, of questionable legality.
Uh, last I checked, I don't, I haven't heard of anybody,
these companies going to jail for this, you know,
um,
all sorts of failures in software that have resulted in major losses or,
uh, you know, some of those trading companies on Wall Street that lost, uh,
what was that one company that accidentally pushed from test to production
and lost several $100 million in, like the space of a few minutes
and, and, ok, last year. But, but here's the thing
that was
an honest mistake as far as I can tell. Ok.
And there's, I,
it's one thing when you have honest mistakes
or even people maybe doing something that,
that is unexpected
with your product or process or whatever it is. You do.
But let's face it.
The dark web
is known for selling illicit thing.
And so when you set something up to purchase items from a place, you know, is just
literally filled with illegal items.
II, I struggle to think you could, you could stand behind the argument of,
I had no idea what my computer was doing.
Like, you know, I mean, it's one thing if you're ordering Amazon
parts for a bomb,
that's different. Right?
A perfect example of this would be,
is there's a lot of things in Canada that are either
flat out illegal or heavily prohibited items such as tasers,
body armor, brass knuckles, uh, certain types of knives
that are
completely, completely
-- legal in the US.
-- But you,
and you can buy
kinder
eggs
and I don't.
Yes, exactly,
because
we, we don't choke on them.
And so as an example, there's,
there's a ton of things I can buy on that on Ebay or Amazon that are, like,
really illegal up here.
Like, not just kind of like a little bit illegal, like, but like, you know,
almost as illegal as kinder eggs in the US, you know, $2500 fine.
What is it, like, five years in jail or something?
It's less dangerous than, than
toys inside of chocolate.
And, I mean, there have been cases of people have bought, for example,
knives that they didn't realize were like flip knives or whatever, those,
those knives with the springs in them, you know,
that are like, really illegal up here in Canada.
-- But
-- here's the thing, I would still expect that to be.
It's kind of like you can't be ignorant of the law. Right.
If you break a law, even if you didn't know it was a law
that's not a defense. And I see this as being very similar to that
-- in principle.
-- Yes.
But the problem is the law has gotten so big now that we don't know how big it is.
Like, for example, uh,
like here I just pulled it up but
they don't actually know how big the US federal code is. At this point.
There's been so
many additions to it,
you
know.
So, so here's the thing too. All right. So,
have you ever been pulled over for speeding?
And the officer just gives you a warning and let you go on your way. Right.
I think that's part of it.
I would expect if you accidentally purchase something from the US
and have it delivered to Canada that depending upon the situation,
you could easily just get a, don't do it again. Ok.
And this is, this is similar to, I mean, I mean, if you're ordering,
say 200 knives that are illegal, that's very different from ordering one
because obviously if you're getting a box of them.
You, you have plans and you probably,
in that case should have known what you're doing.
Right.
And this is similar to,
I know, I, I've heard instances I, I've not, I've not experienced this but where
us customs will catch people with kinder eggs and they generally just say,
just throw it away, you know, get rid of it.
We're not.
And I'm sure technically speaking, they could probably arrest you and,
and who knows what else.
But
more often than not, this is people who just don't understand that.
Why can't I bring candy to my kids?
It's,
it's kind of one of those things. Right.
-- Well,
-- it's like, you know, when I was looking up and I, I discovered it.
Apparently it's completely legal to mail you squirrels
as long as they're an,
a
-- freaking gray squirrel, which is
-- awesome.
And I still part of me wants to try that just to see what would happen.
And the other part of me doesn't because I think there's a
greater than 50% chance of getting a dead squirrel in a box.
Yeah, that's, that's a very real possibility.
-- I want
-- to see what the customs form looks like after.
It's no doubt gone through 12 layers of bureaucracy.
Will people try to figure out if it's actually
legal to let these squirrels enter the country?
Well, it's like this one guy,
he did an experiment where he mailed various strange objects because
apparently
you can attack, you can just attach postage to stuff.
Right. And, and drop it in the mail. And so he mailed like, what was it?
Like a banana and a hammer and a
ski? I think one time
it was all this crazy stuff. I do remember that guy. Now,
I do remember though too, that
the post office stopped accepting items from him at
some point
because they were tired of it.
And so again, though, that kind of falls back to that human angle of human beings. Can
I guess,
bring some sanity to things where if all you're fo focused on is the letter of the law,
things can certainly get out of control.
But once you have a human involved, they can make reasonable judgment calls.
And, and I guess that's probably the next trick with, with A I, right?
Is today A I is very black and white
and it will need that
reasonableness that
some people have we say.
Right.
Yeah.
Well, and I think part of it too is, is, you know,
having people do strange things once in a while is fine.
But,
and here's a great example of a company that mailed all the bricks
needed for a bank to Alaska because it was cheaper than shipping them.
Yes. And although I also remember, I remember I read a lengthy article about that
the postal service tried to stop them
because it would, it would cost the postal service more
basically.
Whatever they were charging to mail one brick was more expensive than
what it cost the postal service to actually deliver the brick.
And so they said, no, this is ridiculous.
We aren't mailing, you know, tons of bricks one at a time for you.
And I guess it went to court and basically the, the court said, look, you,
you can't not mail things that are given to you
like that is your job as the post office.
And so
under
-- federal mandate. Right.
-- Right.
And I mean that now that is an instance where I think common sense probably failed
because while technically speaking,
you're under federal mandate, it that's
bananas,
right.
Trying to make
and this is
sort of a segue,
this is what really worries me about the whole self driving car market,
ride sharing market because
traditionally we have taxis which have legal mandate
that they have to pick up disabled people,
they have to take their service animals, you know, not in the trunk,
they have to pick up people in wheelchairs.
Whereas, you know, these companies like Ride and Lyft and Uber, you know,
there's been incidents where they put the service animal
in the trunk or they just flat out,
don't allow the person in the car as these things change.
You know, I'm, I'm kind of wondering as a society,
do we need regulation around this or like you said,
common
-- sense.
-- In many cases, there is regulation, I seem to recall.
I don't, I don't remember what state it was in the US,
but they ended up passing a bunch of regulation around Uber because they,
they told Uber thing, you know, you have to pick up disabled people.
You have to, you know, you can't discriminate based upon,
you know, race religion or, or whatever else.
And,
and, yeah, I, I think that's important because you're right.
If you don't regulate some of that stuff,
it can get out of hand and people can start to say, you know,
I don't like what this person looks like.
I'm not going to pick them up and, and then, although at the same time,
once we have our robot overlords driving our cars,
they will, I hope
not be quite as uh obtuse as humans are in that regard.
Well, you know,
it's funny because like there's always ways to sort of legally discriminate.
Right. So for example, with a lot of these companies, they flat out
already discriminate because you need a credit card and a smartphone.
So that right there, I suspect takes care of a lot of problems.
Could you make the argument in order to take a taxi? You need money?
I mean, it's
-- kind of
-- the
same. Well, no, but for example, you can pay for a cab with cash,
right? And you can hail them on the street.
So I have just as much access to a cab as you do.
But if, for example, if I don't have a smartphone or I don't have a credit card,
I have absolutely no access to Lyft Uber or ride or anything like that.
-- You're not wrong but you still have access to taxis. So why for
-- now?
For now?
And that, that's fair. I mean,
I'm torn over this cause cause you're right in one sense
but I mean
there are, when you're on an airplane and you want to buy a snack,
they only accept credit cards.
So are you suggesting that they're
discriminating against people without credit cards?
Well, there's a bit of a difference between something like for example,
the ability to travel and move
and the ability to get a package of peanuts on an airplane,
right? One is one has way more impact, right?
Like there's a, there's a current,
a bit of a stink going on in our city because uh the jail and the
remand center have this bad habit of uh
releasing people from the prison or from the jail
like at two in the morning in the middle of the city
with like no money
in some cases with no shoelaces in their shoes.
And you know, and these people have very little resources and help to call on,
you know,
and they're just dropped off in the middle of the city
at like two in the morning or six in the morning,
you know, and the one guy was saying he had no shoelaces, which right now is kind of ok.
But like when it's, you know, there's six inches of snow on the ground.
That's, that's really gonna suck.
Yeah.
So,
and these people certainly don't know.
You know, there's, there's no transit running at that time of day.
So, yeah, I mean, it's just, it's, you know,
it, it becomes a real problem, you know.
Uh, like I know I've looked at using public transit locally and just, wow,
the amount of time I'd spend versus, you know, a self driving car or a ride,
share service, you know, it's fantastic.
But,
well, except
like,
right.
Well,
I
know
for you, uh, they're doing them in Philadelphia though. I know.
I'm, I'm, in fact,
I just read an article the other day that said Uber expects
in five years the majority of their fleet to be self driving,
which I'm not, I'm not gonna lie.
I cannot wait to have a car pull up, the door will open
and there will be no one else in the car except me.
And then I don't have to worry about small talk
or I don't have to worry about tipping them.
When I get there.
I can just get in the vehicle and it goes exactly where I want to,
I don't have to worry about crazy shortcuts
where they're like, oh, I know a shortcut.
I'm like, yeah, you're driving, you do whatever you think is best then, you know,
you end up going through like the scariest neighborhood you've ever seen.
I, I will be
ECAN when, when that day comes.
Yeah,
I'm also really curious as to what this is gonna do for crime because for example,
how do you, you can't get away in a self driving car? Can you,
I,
I don't know, man, you could have like the, the getaway.com uh driving service,
right?
Niche markets here, right? Kurt.
Yeah. So
no, I'm really curious, you know,
with all these self driving cars and taking video and you know,
potentially audio recordings of the surroundings all the time,
you know, can we use them to track people and bad guys
fleeing the scene of a crime, you know, you know,
it's going to happen and then the privacy people are going to lose it as they should
and we will start some very bizarre conversations about privacy
in what will be the new automated world.
Yeah, I mean, I'm,
I have to assume that they're going to use biometrics to identify people
getting in the car so that they can do billing and you know,
you can do, you can just split a ride share without even having to pull out your phone,
right.
Who doesn't want that? Right.
Well, all the privacy advocates.
Right. Right. Right.
Well, you know, actually this, this brings up a good point and,
and we'll kind of segue ourselves out of, out of this story, but
I remember when,
when it was easy pass came out in, in
New York
and
I love 2600 magazine.
And those guys, they actually, they have a radio show called off the hook.
It's fantastic.
But when, when easy pass came out
they complained nonstop about how it was gonna track people and you
lose a bunch of privacy and this and that and another.
And in fact, I just listened to a show a couple of months ago where they,
they admitted like, look, yeah,
it's a privacy violation but it's just so convenient.
It, you're crazy not to use it. And I, I kind of get that,
that there's always a trade off to everything and,
and in fact, for, for tolls,
I have an automated tolling dealio in my car
and I understand that it has certain privacy implications,
but it's so nice not having to stop and pay people
real money that I'm totally willing to put up with it.
-- So
-- to me, to me,
this whole thing is kind of funny because like
all the tires nowadays have RF ID tags and,
or the uh the little wireless pressure sensors that have a unique serial number.
If you have modern tires on your car, you have four built in tracking devices.
-- Yeah,
-- that's probably fair.
Uh
So
listen, I don't want to think about it. We're not, we're not getting into privacy.
Privacy is too complicated and, and there's too many people on both sides of it.
What's interesting to me is that we've lost a lot of privacy in many ways.
And my kids are growing up in a very different world, privacy wise.
And what I haven't seen is nobody having a serious discussion of what
does privacy in 2030 look like for our kids when they hit 18.
You know,
how is
anybody taken over by then?
I mean,
yeah, I mean, a perfect example of this is, you know,
there will not be a single politician who hasn't posted to Reddit or Foran,
right?
And I mean, a great example being this, this, uh, reported story of the, um,
the Mr what is it,
Ketti, the, uh, the email guy
who,
you know,
apparently is accused of wiping the Clinton's email servers and was apparently
posting to Reddit asking how to do this a few years ago.
I actually haven't seen this story, but that's hilarious in all the wrong way.
Yeah. So, I mean, it's, it's really curious to me because, like,
everybody makes stupid mistakes online and now they're, you know,
they're recorded and immortalized forever.
Oh, my goodness. I didn't want to think about it.
Yeah.
So,
oh, I,
I love the future. It's, it's fantastic.
It's definitely a lot different than I expected, you know, II,
I don't know if you read a lot of cipher or cyberpunk when you were younger, but,
you know, the, the vision of the future and the VR and the,
the, the dystopian view of the world. You mean?
I, I don't think I can't think of any cyberpunk novel that isn't dystopian.
They're all basically terrible universes. And I remember it was,
I was, I was in high school when I realized I'm like,
there's no future for the human race anymore.
We're, we're going to ruin everything at this point.
And, and I told the teacher that and they,
they didn't seem very pleased with my lack of optimism, but
it's,
I, I still, I, I will say
that I don't think it's going to be near as dystopian as was once predicted
because you look at the world today and you can complain about it a lot.
But fundamentally,
life is better on a whole for humanity than it was
even 20 years ago.
Oh, yeah.
What really blows me away is, you know, we went from smartphones,
are only 10 years old at this point.
Go anywhere where people are waiting and what are they doing?
Sitting on their phones, you know, staring down at them.
Yes. And, and the old people are judging them for not conversing about
whatever it is people used to talk about.
Yeah. No, it's
so.
And then finally in the news we have again, back to governments and the public good.
Uh, we apparently have a proposal in the UK
uh for the government to run a block list
of sort of naughty domains and naughty emails that you could then
use to firewall and you know, block attacks coming in from these naughty people.
All right, man,
I
there is no way
that
this can be done
in a fair and reasonable manner.
There's just, it's not possible. It is any time you try to do any sort of censorship,
it gets out of hand, it can start with good intentions.
And I'm sure every instance of censorship in the history of humans
has started with noble intentions
and it always goes wrong every time it's
on paper. This sounds like a nice idea.
But after even probably six months of doing this,
people are going to be outraged by all of the
things that have been deemed naughty by whoever it is,
is getting to decide the difference between naughty and nice
and, and maybe they'll check their list twice.
Yeah.
No, I remember, um, what is it, uh, the infamous porn filters that, you know,
prevent people from researching breast cancer
or looking up, you know, birth control or anything like that, you know,
that are pretty legitimate things to be looking up, you know, even if you're a child.
Um, yeah. No, I, I would have to agree.
Even something as simple as, like, uh, uh, a geographical IP database, you know, is,
how do you see part of what comes back is how
do you verify that these people aren't indeed naughty or nice,
you know,
especially when you're not paying for it and you're not really having any recourse.
I see, that's exactly it. Right. There isn't a good answer to any of this.
And I think eventually
it gets out of hand
and, and you, you know, this actually reminds me of just now is,
did you see the XK CD comic from,
was it yesterday I believe,
comparing the fashion police to the grammar police?
And, and that's what you end up at. Right. Is
you have a group
that is just
out of control essentially. And, and while I,
I'll, I'll pick on the grammar police a little bit, but II, I
easily fall into that category.
Occasionally we'll say it depends what I'm trying to do. But, I mean, fundamentally
when two people disagree,
one of them is always going to, well, they both do for them,
they have a reason why they're right.
And so once we give that sort of responsibility to the government,
your reason doesn't matter anymore because they have
the fundamental authority and that is scary and dangerous
when this isn't something that can be easily explained in a,
we'll say factual manner, you know, like most laws are relatively black and white.
Right?
And for when they're not,
that's where we get lawyers and judges to help clarify that.
And if you have a naughty list of websites,
are you going to sue the government every time they block a domain you want to look at?
Of course not.
So,
let's,
oh, my goodness. What a terrible idea. That's all I'm gonna say,
well, it's, it's one of those things that, you know,
in principle sounds simple and effective.
But
in practice, we all know is a,
-- a bit more of a disaster.
-- It's
a,
it's a train wreck. That's what it is.
So like, uh, you know, the fact that now when you get an IP address for a server,
you have to, uh, ideally before you get the IP address,
-- check if it's on a blacklist and when
-- you have that problem with, with email now,
right is if you're going to run a mail server,
you need to make sure your IP address isn't on one of the blacklists.
And in fact, that's happened to a handful of people.
I know where, you know,
they're trying to figure out why isn't my mail going anywhere.
It's like, oh, you're on a blacklist, you know, they're not,
they're not even kind enough to send you a rejection because you're on this list.
They just like,
you know, they, they dump your connection as soon as it, it connects.
So,
oh, man, it's, it's, it's rough. So, all right, let's do this.
Since we're on the topic of, of disasters,
let's start talking about container security for a few minutes and we can,
we'll continue this conversation over the course of the
next couple of weeks and I think it's,
it's a nice way
to end the podcast and to just start getting some of
that information out because I think container security is super important
and there's a lot of people who don't always understand what's going on.
So let's start here. Why don't you tell me, Kurt?
Pretend I am a person who will say, knows what a computer is,
but I don't know what containers are.
What would you tell me?
So, fundamentally, containers are not really anything new.
We've been doing this or attempting to do this with things like ch root in jail.
And essentially what we're trying to do is we're trying to
box off a small part of the computer logically speaking,
so that you can run some software in there without
having to interact with the rest of the system.
So you have a nice little clean environment
that you can
clearly define. You know, I want this clean environment to have
Red Hat Enterprise Linux version seven or maybe I wanted to have Red Hat Enterprise
Linux
version six
or maybe you want it to run Debian or ubuntu or whatever
with some very specific libraries and versions of libraries, for example.
So containers are just an attempt to logically
break your computer up so that you can
run software in these controlled little boxes basically
which then gives you
the power to do things like, oh,
I really need this weird old specific version of a library.
Now, I don't want to install it on the system as a whole because it's, you know,
it's full of horrendous problems
but for whatever reason I need it for this, you know, Payroll software I'm running,
right.
Uh It also allows you to do things like breaking software up and making it easier
to interact with in some ways because you can, you know,
you can clearly define how the software talks to each other rather than
just jamming it all into one giant box in one big pile.
And,
you know, hoping that none of them, you know,
that hoping that they all play nice with each other.
Um
And so containers also make things a bit easier for developers because
the you can actually
replicate the environment exactly that you would
have between production testing and development,
you know, whereas traditionally
people would write stuff and the infamous, well, it works on my laptop.
Yes,
the the call of the developer.
So, all right.
So let me ask this, then you sound like you've just described a virtual machine to me.
Yeah, basically that's exactly what I have described.
And the main difference being is in a virtual machine,
you replicate the entire computer from
essentially you give a pretend hardware,
running a kernel and running a user space and basically running the entire shebang
with containers,
you kind of move up a level.
So you're sharing the hardware with the base system,
you're sharing the kernel with the base system and
you're sharing some other aspects of the base system.
And the advantage here is that you're
because you're sharing resources.
For example, if you want to run 100 copies of something,
you don't have 100 copies of the kernel also running, right?
It's just you're sharing one copy.
So
from a resource usage point of view, you can save on a lot of the resources.
Um
The other thing is
it in, well, I would say once we're done getting containers, right?
It will be reduced complexity. Currently, it's actually
more complex in some ways than virtual machines.
Um But also because we're able to do things with
containers that we can't easily do with virtual machines.
Like if you want to chain
10 or 20 containers together using Docker and Kubernetes,
it's actually you can do it with a, you know, a single definition file.
Whereas if you try to, you know,
fire up 10 V MS and have them all come
up with the right IP addresses and chain them together.
Uh That's still not super easy in most cases.
Yeah, I mean, that's a fair point.
It's
so let's
think about security now. OK.
When we,
so would we say
that containers are more or less secure than a virtual machine?
Currently, I would say that they are less secure than a virtual machine
due to the fact uh Well, due to two main facts, one, they share more things
which sometimes is what you want, you know,
you want to be able to share data quickly and efficiently say over
uh shared file system or, you know, through memory rather than, you know,
with a virtual machine having to shove it over a fake network.
The second thing is that we containers are still young, right?
Virtual machines have been around for what, 20 years now?
-- 25
-- it depends how you want to define how long they've been around.
I would say if we're going to talk in the context of Linux, it's been 12, maybe 15 years
that you've had
virtualization.
Yeah.
So they, you know,
we've had 12 or 15 years to beat a lot of security problems out of these things.
And we're still finding, you know, security flaws
-- with
-- V MS
is there's been certain things added to
the hardware to help make virtualization faster,
but also more secure in the way you can segment off some of these, these devices.
Well, I shouldn't say devices but segment off some of the V MS from one another.
Right.
True.
And so with containers, we just haven't had as much time to beat on them,
find all the security flaws.
And the other thing too is that containers are still evolving, right? It's not,
you know, virtualization is a generally an understood problem.
You know, it's relatively clear what we're trying to achieve.
Whereas with containers, you know,
I I've seen some new things come out in the last year that are like, wow, I,
I did not think of that.
That's a really cool thing to add,
you know, and so
part of the problem is, you know, you have a very much a moving target in containers,
right?
Things, we're adding things constantly.
Now, the good news is if you want
the security of virtualization, but you want to use containers, you you can do that,
you can run your containers inside of their own virtual machine.
It adds a bit of overhead obviously, but you then get essentially
uh the usability of containers combined with
the existing security of virtual machines,
-- which is uh for example, I believe how Google Compute engine does it
-- interesting.
So from the security angle as well,
I think the
the most misunderstood aspect of containers because I hear
on a regular basis it's in a container,
it's secure, which is not the case.
-- No, not yet.
-- It's
right that that's fair. And I, I think that's the
the logical conclusion to container technology is going to be containers that
are as secure or more secure than virtual machines are today.
And then we'll be talking about container escape flaws and things and whatnot.
But I think the current problem today
is that
when you have a system say running 10 containers, they all share the same kernel.
And the Linux kernel is a behemoth.
When it comes to code, it has millions of lines of code.
And so logically, millions of lines of code equals lots of security issues, right?
And so when you have lots of things sharing the same kernel
utilizing the same millions of lines of code.
You have a situation where you've got
if one container
can break into the kernel and e essentially exploit the kernel to become, you know,
root on the host.
Now, they can control all of the kernels.
I'm sorry, all of the containers running on the system, right.
Yeah.
And that's one thing where I'm currently looking at is
see one thing that containers give us is they
give us an architecture that we can actually secure.
Like the reality is it's hard to secure a
system running, you know, a large application with tens of components, right?
But if you break it up and decompose it in containers, you know,
have some very well defined boundaries, you know,
you have your network boundaries, your file system boundaries
and you have boundaries between the container and the kernel, right?
So we already have the fact that you can drop capabilities
in a container, right? So you can have a container
that
cannot manipulate its own network configuration or a container that cannot,
you know,
manipulate its own firewall configuration or a container that is not
allowed to run anything set U ID or you know,
with route access.
So containers give us the ability to start creating these barriers and
and you know, and to start, for example,
dropping the privileges we don't need whereas you know,
trying to drop this privilege
for an application running on a on a base os
uh a base operating system would be, you know, it would be very difficult, right?
Trying to drop this privilege.
Whereas, you know, in the container,
you just say start this container and
drop these capabilities and never give them back
and then whatever is happening in that container short of some
sort of container escape problem can never get those capabilities back.
Yeah, that's fair. And I think
that's one of the other really interesting
things about containers is you can really
split the security view on this stuff
into two pieces where there's the host security
where even before the container runs,
certain things are happening to make sure that it's got a
certain amount of, of security involved
and we're going to say the word security a lot I suspect here.
Well,
and even better is currently running containers generally requires
you to have administrative level access to the system,
right?
You have to be or have pseudo access to run
and talk to Docker.
And I know one of the things Redhead is working on is, you know,
a project called bubble wrap where we're looking at
user space containers, right? Because
the other issue with containers is for example,
is I might want to run a container on a
machine for which I do not have administrative access to,
you know, like for example, my developer machine or
a web hosting server, right?
Maybe I want to run a a very odd version of my SQL on port 33 06.
But, well, that's already taken on the host, you know,
by the actual real my SQL server.
So I think one thing we're gonna see in the next
1 to 2 years is user space containers because quite frankly,
that means that anybody can install it anywhere
they want without having to ask for permission.
And those kind of solutions tend to win because people just do it.
Sure,
sure.
That's,
I mean,
maybe so.
So the thing I keep thinking of there actually is
user space containers make sense in certain multi-tenant environments.
But you look at where things are headed and it's just really headed into having
kind of container runtime infrastructure that you don't worry about user space.
You don't worry about privileges, you just
you have a container, you give it to something
and then something runs your container with no questions asked.
That is the logical end point.
But the problem is there's a lot of existing workloads that don't work with that.
Like a great example being wordpress, right? Wordpress assumes
you have a fully coherent file system
and a fully coherent database that is and both the file system,
the database end up storing data
and having to be state full, right? So you can't just
run wordpress in a container server request and turn it off, right? You have to keep
that request, for example, might have been you uploading a new picture to the,
to the website.
And so there's a lot of applications that,
well, they were designed to run on a real physical server
and making them run in a container is going to be quite painful.
Um And once, you know, even if you do getting running in a container,
you're going to have to have essentially like a, a fat VM style container that
not only serves the data but then holds the data and keeps
uh
that keeps the state of the data, right.
So when you upload pictures to the blog or when you
when you upload the podcast, you know, there's a copy of it there.
I think what will happen though is that this this will become a transition, right?
It be it'll become easier and easier to make that transition.
And people will, you know,
transition to say user space containers,
get everything running in say user space containers and then realize,
hey all my stuff is running in user space containers.
Now I can for example, move the data out of the container and into some
sort of storage service, you know something, for example, like Red hat Gluster or
S
or you know, a public cloud service like Amazon S3.
Once you move your data out of the container,
now you can move your containers to one of these container runtime services and
get rid of all your servers.
Yeah, I mean that's fair, I suppose. And that's always
that is one of the most important aspects I think of any technology.
And this is where security people fail miserably
is we forget the fact that there has to be a transition from the
old to the new things don't just magically appear in the new place.
And this is we are notorious for this insecurity.
We're like, no, here's the new rules do it now
and we are often not the most receptive people to the idea of something,
taking some amount of time and effort versus magically
happening when we tell them it should happen.
Yeah.
And,
and something to remember too is we still have 3040
now 50 year old it systems that are still running,
you know, FORTRAN Cobalt,
uh recently, you know, the,
the Phoenix pay system that the Canadian government deployed
several years ago and has been a disaster.
You know, people not getting paid for months on end,
they're not going to scrap that.
You know, they're going to try and fix it as best they can.
And then we're gonna, you know,
we're gonna be stuck with that solution for at least a few decades
and, you know, something like that is not gonna ever be containerized.
That's,
I don't know,
I would OK.
Never say never. All right. That's rule number one
because as soon as you say, something will never happen, I guarantee it will happen.
There is no better way to ensure an event takes place.
Than to say it will never take place.
This is true.
Humanity's history is riddled with people telling other people
what will never happen and it always does.
But it,
I mean, that's fair. That, that's an interesting point.
And this is part of the challenge I think we
have to start dealing with here around this stuff.
And so
I, I think what we should do for now is let, let's hang this one up
and, and let people just kind of chew on some of this.
And what I,
I think we should do is come back maybe
next week and we can talk about host container security
and then
we can delve our way into what's
happening actually inside of the containers themselves,
which is kind of a fascinating topic for a variety of reasons.
But
I, I will admit that that container security is one of those things that I really,
I'm impressed with where we've gotten so quickly
and it's easy to pick on this stuff which don't get me wrong.
I'm,
I'm as guilty as the next guy of picking out what
the little nitpicky things are that that's wrong with this.
But I think fundamentally
we are on the right track,
which I don't think there's a lot of technologies that
the security folks have been able to say that about
this early on in its inception because let's face it
in the history of security.
It has been bolted onto the side
long after that train left the station.
And I think in this case,
I won't say the train hasn't left the station but you can still see it at least.
So I think we have a chance maybe to get this one. Right.
Yeah, we definitely,
people definitely have much higher expectations of security in new technologies,
right?
Things that would have been past, been totally normal are now, you know,
basically unthinkable,
you know, and we're, you know,
for example,
the thought of having containers not have the ability to drop capabilities.
Right.
In the past, nobody would have even known what I was talking about.
A
lot of people who don't know what you're talking about and, and
rather than go down this rabbit hole right now,
we will come back to capabilities because that in itself is a fascinating
topic and what's happening there is really cool and it's also really powerful.
So for now,
how about we just say thanks for listening folks and
tune in next week for the riveting conclusion of our discussion
-- on container security.
-- Thanks, you have an excellent week,
Josh,
talk to you later. Bye bye.