Hello and welcome to episode 61 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser. What's New Kurt?
Uh, just enjoying my mini staycation at home.
All right. Your vacation ruined by the hurricane.
Yes. Luckily before we left.
That, that's true. And, and
yeah, I could see bad things happening if you were stranded somewhere right now.
-- That's fun, man.
-- Cannibalism
-- being a definite possible outcome.
-- That's
-- right.
-- That's right.
Oh,
go big or go home.
Right.
Anyway.
Oh, man. So,
so what's, what's the topic this week?
Well, I think this week we're going to look at New Meets Old,
like when I go and meet my kids' friends or
something better.
Uh, yeah, that would be applicable here too.
One
started dabbing and I
hate
it.
I
don't know why I hate
it.
-- I just do
-- because it's new and different and it's our job
and its
point
and there's nothing I can actually find technically wrong with it. It's not like,
you know, needle drugs or playing Russian roulette.
It's just
-- fundamentally
-- annoying. So, I have a great story for you is
some time ago. My son got into this
cartoon called Slug Terror,
which if you've never seen it would be worth your time watching an episode.
And
I remember I watched this with him and thought
this is the single dumbest cartoon anyone has ever made, like, ever in history.
And I'm comfortable saying that today still because it probably is.
But then I got to watching a couple of episodes with him
and I'm sitting there thinking this is completely ridiculous and dumb.
And then I thought,
I bet this is what my parents thought about all of the cartoons I watched when
I was a kid. Like
the circle is complete.
Sorry, I'm just
reading the
Wikipedia.
It's completely ridiculous for real.
And if you watch it, I guarantee you, it's much worse
when you watch
it.
It's, of course it is.
Ok. Yeah.
Yeah. No. And,
and,
and honestly I suspect the dabbing thing is like a lot of
what we're doing in the cloud to some of the older,
you know, folks in the management of
man.
It totally is.
Well, actually that's like I, I just heard a blog post that I published,
I think today.
I don't know when I wrote it a while back and I, I scheduled it. But anyway, uh,
I, I compare a lot of security to a BF skinner in his work with pigeons
which, which for those of you who don't know, I'll give you kind of,
the crash course is,
uh, BF Skinner was a,
what was it? Uh
uh So
psychological researcher, I don't know, I don't know what you call it exactly.
But basically he did, he did studies on the behavior of people and animals.
And what he did was he, he,
there's a famous experiment that we often hear
of the word skinner box kicked around.
And basically he put pi pigeons in a box and food was delivered at random
and the pigeons would do things like, for example,
I think one would spin around and then food would appear.
And so the pigeon naturally assumed spinning around made the food appear
and it would spin around and around and around.
And then eventually the food would randomly appear,
even though the spinning around had nothing to do with it.
It, the pigeon kind of built its own. I, I guess, you know, fake religion around this.
Well, it, it built a mental model of the world to explain how it works.
-- Yeah, actually that, that. Right. Exactly.
-- Exactly. So it just turned out to be
completely, well, it wasn't technically wrong because,
you know, if you spend long enough and food is randomly delivered that works.
-- But it's just the causality thing.
-- Right. Right. Right.
And, and anyway,
and then I compare that to a lot of
the security we do today because in all seriousness,
we don't know why we do a lot of what we do.
And my favorite example of this is nist
and their password guidance where there's things like,
you know,
passwords must be 12 million characters and they have to have like three letter
A's and you must use special characters in lowercase and uppercase and this,
that and this,
and when you think about it, it's like, oh, sure, that makes sense.
But it doesn't at all.
It's actually that advice is probably worse than not having
any sort of standards for your internal password policies.
The guy that came up with that actually came out and like,
publicly apologized a few weeks ago.
Remember? And I will never
said I'm sorry, it turns out I was wrong. This is a terrible idea
and literally to the best of my knowledge,
I don't think this has made a single iota of difference in the industry.
No, it, it, well, I, I think it has,
it's made it significantly worse without question.
I mean,
so, I mean, I haven't seen a single password prompt.
That's like, oh, we've simplified things because,
or, you know, anything that's changed.
And, well, and you were saying you were talking to some people who are like,
-- pretty adamant about it being
-- right.
I was, I was at a meet up talking to some friends and
it was one of those situations where I mentioned, oh, hey,
did you guys hear about the new password guide?
And they're like, what about it? And I explained the story and they said,
well, that's not true. You know, the password guidance is important
and I'm thinking
I will never convince these people that they are wrong.
And rather than try, I'm just going to nod my head and smile because it, it's,
it's a losing battle. But I, I think here's, here's a question I have though.
And this is, this is kind of the topic for the day is
there are always soldiers from the last war
that don't know what to do
once the war ends. And I think with the disruption we see in things like cloud,
the last war is over
-- and the new one has,
-- I don't think they even know it's over,
let alone that there's a new one coming
and a lot of them might not
seriously. I, I know ones that haven't. I, I know people in the tech industry
who've never used a cloud service. And by that, I don't mean like set up a fancy
service like Netflix, I mean, like used Gmail
or use like a document, like a sharing thing like G Drive,
let alone like infrastructure or platform or software as a service.
You know,
that does not surprise me. And in fact, I had a friend over a while back
that was saying, oh, my coworkers all want to use uh Google Drive and I don't like it.
And I said Google Drive has changed my life for the better.
I, I do not know how I functioned without this thing.
And it. I think about that every day.
I mean, do you remember emailing documents around back and forth to each other?
Change tracking enabled in more than two people.
Um, it changed tracking if you're lucky.
I mean, it was horrible. Oh, my goodness.
No, I actually love that the local school system went to,
uh, Google Apps, uh,
some years ago. And so I think, I think in grade three they start really using it
and that's how they submit homework.
I,
yes, I, I see that too.
My, my kids started using Google Drive in grade three for homework and
it's, it's marvelous. And actually that's one of the funny things too is
like every kid has the same password
and, and
none of them have.
You, you can guess all the logins and stuff and they're basically just, they said,
you know, don't, don't do anything you should do. And that, that works.
And part of me, like, as a security person
is, is I'm like, I want to jump out of my skin and yell at them.
And the other part of me is like,
who cares?
Third
grade. I mean,
here's the thing, how do you get an eight year old to remember?
Like a really good password?
-- Uh,
-- you know what I do actually. So my kids hate me, but they have various web services
and
I use, uh, uh,
my password manager to set everything up and then I set a very difficult password and
I read it on a sticky note and hand it to them and they're like,
oh, not another password like
this.
I'm like, look, this is what you're gonna get for me if you want my help.
This is what happens if you don't want my help, do it on your own.
No, I, I do plan to give my kids last Pass. If nothing else, it just makes it.
So actually I was, I was looking at Last Pass the other day and they,
they're looking into creating something called Last Pass
Family or for like 50 bucks a year,
you're gonna be able to kind of do some sinking.
And I was thinking
even though I know last Pass has some security issues from the, you know,
tinfoil hat perspective,
I, I think the ease of having that with my Children would far outweigh
you can
do this with their corporate edition.
I
don't have that.
Right.
Um, well, so you can do with corporate, well, it's like most things in life, right?
Like families, if you think about it are kind of like a mini, mini
corporation. But you have like your CEO or typically a CEO pair who like rule by fiat
and then you have underlings who are basically at the whim of the CEO
and that's a family, right?
Um,
so, yeah, I mean, it, I, that's one like, like I, I look at, um,
like Apple with their family set up for things and you know what it, it makes sense.
My one fear being though is like when my Children sort of
leave and have to get their own accounts when they're 18,
like, are they gonna have to rebuy all their software? Like, how does that work?
Right.
Because a lot of these things let you share software and share logins and share,
you know, resources, right.
However, what I've done with my kids actually is
they have email aliases for what will eventually be
their Google accounts because obviously I, I have apps for my domain
and so I just keep signing them up using an email alias. It really just points to me
and then someday I will create legitimate
accounts for those aliases and then they will
-- basically inherit all of their stuff.
-- Well, see, I already did that with my kids.
They already have their Google accounts primarily so
that they each have their own calendar.
Ah, that's actually really clever.
Yeah, because part of it is, I mean,
let's face it right in the modern world you're going to have to learn how to use
Gmail outlook or whatever version of calendaring software you use
-- because that's how the modern world works.
-- I mean,
I don't know how I could survive with my kids in stuff
without a shared calendar.
Yeah.
No, like their grandmother, you know, like, I mean, it's,
yeah.
No, it's the only way it works, you know, how else do you know,
what everybody's doing or where they need to be or when they're going.
Yeah, totally.
So, yeah, I know. But, um,
yeah, no, it's this Old meets New or New meets old, I mean,
yeah, the password thing is a great example because in my mind, uh, well,
for one thing, yes, the,
to me the whole premise of passwords is flawed, right. Passwords are just a bad idea.
You know, ideally you have some sort of two factor authentication.
Didn't Richard Stallman? Tell us that a long time ago.
Yeah.
Um,
more to the point too, you know, and,
and then also just this sort of blindly asking for a password, every single login
I think is also wrong to a degree.
And part of it too to remember is something you and I forget
people use public computers, like at the library or
hotels.
Well, but here's the thing,
uh, they, why,
why shouldn't a website like Facebook
be set up in some way that you can
use it from a public machine
-- and really minimize the risk because for example,
-- it has to be done and
it, so actually I have
two very funny stories about this is, well, not, not very funny necessarily, but
so firstly is
I was just in a hotel this weekend
and
I walked past the business center which had two windows computers in it
and people were using them and I just wanted to, like,
open the door and scream what's wrong with you people?
I didn't, I didn't, I almost did but I didn't.
But then I was also, well on my, you know,
whirlwind tour of the south to watch an eclipse.
I
was at a hotel
and it was, it was a pretty dodgy hotel.
There,
there's only dodgy hotels in certain parts of the
country and I was in one of those places
and there were these people sitting there and they were part of some group
and I don't, it was a, a sports team of some sort, I forget what it was.
And they were using the computer in the hotel.
And I realized that like,
these were two fairly old people
working with some sort of sports group and clearly not from,
you know, the hoity
toity area.
And I, I got to thinking, I'm like, I bet these people don't own a computer,
they can carry around with them.
Right. And in that case, like, absolutely, I think it is totally expected.
You're going to see someone like that
using a public computer,
which of course, then means you are correct that the,
instead of me opening the door and yelling inside, what's wrong with you people?
The right answer is how do we make this stuff work? So let, let's say the computer is p
two ways from Sunday.
How do you make it safe?
-- You don't give them a windows machine, you just buy a bunch of chromebooks.
-- Well, Ok.
So,
ignoring that answer, I, you're right.
I'm gonna totally agree with you and I think that would be the easy answer.
However, let's just assume
there's a computer that's like, completely pumped
-- right in the lobby, whatever.
-- Who cares?
Hopefully they don't do any online banking with it.
Well, well, we have to care today, I think.
No.
Well, ok, when I say we care, I mean, in the sense of you and I don't have to care,
but hopefully somebody like Facebook sets it up so that
Google is a great example, right? I have um,
you know, my uh Google two factor authentication set up with the, you know,
application specific password for like my email client or whatever.
And basically Google doesn't care until I like go to a different country.
And then it's like, hey, are, are you sure you're,
you can you please enter your real password again?
Yeah.
You know, or on my workstation every like, I don't know, 30 or 60 days.
It's like, uh you're trying to like delete or create a user or do something, you know,
administrative.
Uh I'm gonna need that two factor authentication plugged in, please.
You know.
And so for example, I mean,
well, yeah, I wouldn't want somebody like reading my email, but, you know,
it's nice to know that when I try to
take an administrative action with my Google account,
typically it's like I got to plug in my UB key and you know, push the little
I was gonna say button, but it's not really a button. Is it
a surface?
I
know what
it
is. But I, I,
my kids like, do you want, do you want me to rewind this or fast forward this?
And I'm like, that literally makes no,
like the fast forward part makes sense,
but the rewind part makes absolutely no sense.
-- On youtube videos.
-- It doesn't matter because that's just the word that's used.
It's kind of like the, the save icon as a floppy disk.
My Children have never seen and probably never will see a floppy disk,
-- right? It's just like how it
-- is. Oh, my kids saw USB keys for the first time.
How would they not?
I realize they never seen a USB key. Why would they, they have Wi Fi
uh
my, my kids need them.
So they, they, they carry them around, which is funny because they,
the school say you need them.
But everything they do is in Google Drive.
So,
so my suspicion is that's kind of a rule held over from
the days of your and no one's fixed it because they're like,
oh, they might need a USB drive someday.
It's like they
probably
-- hand to have, that's for sure.
-- But yeah, they are.
But
um,
yeah, no, this whole thing is just, um, I would say, you know,
ideally you give them chromebooks and, and, and on the service provider side,
like say Facebook or Google,
you know, you do things like, oh, they're trying to take an administrative action,
like,
um,
well, like, pretty much every site I interact with.
You know, if I want to go update my billing information, it's like, no, you're,
you're gonna have to put your password in
again.
And, and in fact, I was just, I was just doing some stuff on github the other day
and
I was amazed that, like, I did some things
and they made me enter my password
and then I, like, took a break for just a few minutes and,
and they made me enter it again and I thought that's really cool.
Actually,
I like that
and I think that works well because quite frankly
we don't,
you know, typically we don't do those things,
especially as end users. Right.
Like an administrator might be doing that all day long
and, you know, might have to re enter the password a bunch and, ok.
Well, too bad use last pass, I guess.
Um,
but it's, it's not so painful and annoying that it
becomes a real problem.
Yeah. Well. Right.
And I, I think about that too sometimes is the number of times I mess with, like,
my settings or account preferences in something like Facebook or Google or github
is
once a year.
You what?
I'm moving in a few weeks.
So I have to update my mailing and physical address with like,
well, actually I really only have to update it with Amazon.
That's the only one that really matters.
-- The important one
-- because I want my stuff.
Yeah.
But you still need your bank and your credit card and all that. It's
-- a
-- electronic now.
-- Uh, Amazon is electronic.
-- Not the stuff I buy from them.
Right. I understand what you're saying. I suppose.
Like I want my packages.
That's true. That's true.
And I realize now because they don't go through the post system,
they go through the Amazon delivery guy in his minivan with his little smartphone,
you know, they
my change of address card won't matter. But um,
yeah, I mean, it's, and, and that's always been a problem, right?
Is how do we make security good but also not like super duper annoying.
Well,
it's been super duper annoying and the thing I
always say is if it is usability versus security,
security will lose every time.
And
I think honestly that's kind of where we are today
is usability. Kept winning.
-- And I think if you look at some things, I think it should have it
-- should
because
what's the point of having a door with so many locks that you can't get in and out of?
There's no point at all.
And I think if you look at kind of some of the
things like Facebook and Google and friends are doing or have done,
they,
I think have embraced that concept of it
has to be usable like usability Trump security.
So, how do we add security to our usability? Not, how do we make security usable?
Right.
Yeah.
Well, and part of it too is though, is that they actually,
from what I've read of Facebook and Google and Yahoo, for example,
they're actually data driven and they kind of know,
kind of how bad it can get.
Um, you know, the back when he was at Google, what's the guy's name?
There was the, uh, chief security guy for Google and then he left after he
stamos
was at Yahoo for a couple of months
and they gave a,
yeah, he gave a good, you know, a good talk at a, I remember an event basically saying,
you know,
like, you know,
when you or I have our Facebook account hacked or our bank account hacked even
it's really inconvenient.
But, you know, we'll be ok in a day or two or a week or whatever. Right.
But that happens to somebody in a third world country
and that might be like everything they own
their storefront
and, and like, they literally are going to die of starvation now,
you know, we'd like to prevent that,
you know.
So,
yeah, I mean, long term, I'm assuming we'll see a lot more biometrics.
I mean, we've already seen those things like smile to pay in China.
I do
not know about this.
Do you
think? I
assume I can figure it out? Smile to pay. Right.
Yeah.
That's what it says. Um,
-- yeah. Oh, it's Alibaba launching it. So they're kind of big.
-- They are big.
Yeah. And they're launching it at KFC in China.
You
know what
part of it is though?
And this is actually a place where I think, kind of, kind of having that,
that market driven security is impressive is
if Alibaba does this, it's going to be fraud,
it will not be 100%.
But they,
they probably have a pretty good idea of what their rate of fraud is going to be.
And I, we
-- have
-- pictures of all the people committing the fraud.
Uh, well, ignoring that. Right. Ignoring that.
And you're, you're right. But ignoring that
if the amount of money they're making in profit exceeds
the amount of money they're spending to combat fraud.
Like this is a no brainer, right. Credit cards are exactly the same.
-- Like
-- they're perfect example because like the merchant, you know, the,
the visa certainly doesn't take the hit.
They just pass it on in fees to the merchant
and the merchant certainly isn't going to take the hit.
So they just
pass it on in their prices
and consumers.
I mean, I, I
can't imagine living without, without credit cards,
especially with respect to online purchases.
I don't think you could live without a credit card.
Uh, you could do, you could set up wire transfers and stuff, but like just, oh, man,
it would be
the thing. I love about buying stuff with a credit card.
Um Well, great example, being like, I booked a trip,
you know, it got canceled because while Hurricane Harvey just, you know,
clobbered uh Houston Airport
and I phoned the company. It was one of the online big companies.
I won't name it because it's a bit shameful. But
the guy is like, oh yeah, why do you want, why do you want to cancel? I'm like
the FAA closed the airport for like four days
and it's not opening till Thursday at the soonest.
He's like,
oh, yeah, I've heard about this. I'm like,
ok.
Ok, sure. Maybe he doesn't watch a lot of news.
I, I'm not gonna judge, maybe he's not in America. I don't know. Right.
Um, and he's like, oh, I don't see that your flight's canceled yet. I'm like, yeah.
No, it's been canceled, like United said it was canceled because there's,
there's no more airport,
they'll cancel it 15 minutes before it's supposed to take up.
The
-- airport has been closed.
-- The
best part is he's like, well,
I have to go ask my help desk for permission to speak to the airline.
I'm like, what
I'm like, he's like we have to call the airline to cancel.
I'm like, yeah, and he's like, and I have to get permission to speak to the airline
-- and
-- this is like a travel agent site.
Yeah, it's, it's one of the parts Expedia,
you know,
and so he, he,
I'm on hold for 1015 minutes and he gets permission to talk to the airline.
So then we're on hold for 30 minutes and he's like, oh, good luck.
You know, the airline just canceled it because I was on the phone with them.
I'm like, no kidding.
That's what their website shows.
And so, you know, I finally got it canceled and I got a full refund.
But I was thinking like, thank goodness,
I paid for this on a credit card because
if Expedia wasn't willing to fully refund my flight,
my next step would have been to call Visa
and be like Visa.
You know,
uh,
I paid for airline tickets that are not
going to be forthcoming because no more airports.
-- Can I have my money back, please? Right. Right.
-- Actually,
I remember I had something similar happened to me once was
I bought a gift for my wife.
It was a gift card that at some local spot
and I get my, my Visa bill is Visa as well.
In fact, I get the visa bill and they charge me twice
and I, I called them up.
I said, hey, you guys charge me twice and they're like, our computer says we didn't.
I said
ok,
and then
I hung up, I called Visa, I'm like, they charged me twice. Like, yeah, we see it.
You're good.
And like that was it, that was the end of it.
They got,
they got they fixed it all and I suspect the
merchant probably got in some trouble in some way.
Well, that would be one of those, uh, a charge back.
And, yeah, that, that affects their rate long term if they get enough of those.
But if they go above a certain threshold, they,
they definitely do because visa doesn't want to deal with merchants like that.
Yep. Yep.
You know, and the thing is to remember, right? Is these guys have data, right?
Like Amazon knows that Kurt Siefried has only returned a grand total of,
I believe two packages.
Have I ever something? I don't think I've ever returned something to Amazon.
I got too much work.
Well, no, it's not with Amazon. You know what you do,
you go to the website and you basically go to your order history and you say,
like I got the wrong thing and there's a couple of generic options.
Like I got
the wrong thing
unless Amazon sends them into my house and they actually, like,
just take the thing away from me, from my hands without me doing anything.
-- No,
-- they don't. You have to put it in a box and put tape on the box. Right.
Well, but you should still have that box and tape because you just opened it.
But anyways they, they,
they just give you a website thing and it prints out a
mailing label and then you just drop it in the mail.
That's too much work. I don't want to put tape in a box.
Ok.
But, uh,
yeah, I mean, that's the beauty. Right. It's like Amazon knows that. Like,
I'm only gonna return something if there's a legitimate reason for it,
you know, I
kick you out. If you return to,
there's articles about that about people who have
had to legitimately return a lot of stuff.
And Amazon's like, well, we're just
not going to do business with you anymore.
And II I get that
it's,
you know, and I mean,
some jurisdictions have laws that protect customers more and some
don't have laws to protect customers with respect to this.
But
fundamentally, I mean,
if the merchant knows who you are and they know that you're a pain then yeah,
they're probably going to stop doing business with you.
So, you know, and that's another example of this whole clow thing, right? Like,
yeah, it terrifies me.
I really don't want to one day have Google decide to
shut me down or Amazon decide to shut me down or,
or whoever.
Right. Because,
uh, well, like cloud flare is a great example, right? Cloud flare
generally doesn't want to censor or shut people down because quite frankly,
you kind of have to host with cloud flare now,
especially if you get denial of service,
right. They're the only affordable people.
Um
So if they decide to kick you off their platform,
you're kind of up the creek without a paddle
you know, if, if, if I somehow offend the Apple Gods,
uh,
-- I don't have a plan B, is there
-- more than one? I don't know
anyway.
But,
but, you know, it's in the same vein of, like,
pissing off the electric company locally which people have and can do, you know,
by not paying their bills long enough
or pissing someone off.
Like, if you don't pay your bill, they're going to turn your service off.
That's just like the expectation of humidity.
But they, well, and, and they generally don't make mistakes, but there is the case.
Remember I sent you that link where this lady moved into a condo locally
plugged in her address and didn't want to take.
So she ended up plugging in just the building address.
Remember? And then
they had her mailing address, correct?
Like with her suite number, but they took the,
the building address and so her first month's bill was
like $11,000 because it was electricity for the whole building.
See, that's,
well, and then they didn't want to fix it.
And then the best part is they refused to correct it.
They're like, you know, go talk to your building guys about a rebate and, uh, well,
we'll, we'll sort it out moving forward, but we're not giving you a refund.
They are notorious for that
in
various industries. In fact, I, I have a friend one time who
I, I don't know why he did this he should have known better,
but he set up bill pay where the water
company took the funds out of his checking account.
And they, instead of taking out like $40 for water, they took out $400 for water.
And he's like, uh, refund me. They said, oh, we'll just credit your account.
He's like no refund me.
And yeah, he ended up arguing with them for a really long time because they, my,
my suspicion is
in order to issue a proper refund,
they probably have to do a whole bunch of hoop jumping.
And so these people try to avoid that at all costs
and, and, and not that it's right necessarily.
-- But yeah, it, it, it is a pain however now, oh,
-- there's been horror stories with,
you know,
various companies like Verizon and Comcast, you know, uh,
overbilling old people who, like, live on fixed incomes.
That's a whole another topic I think because those people are,
they, they are truly horrible in many ways,
but
to be clear, we're calling the companies horrible.
Not the old people living on fixed incomes.
I'm sure
we don't know that they could be terrible people. We have no idea.
-- I'm not willing to, to say they are,
-- we
-- have proof
-- that Verizon and
complex are pretty terrible people.
So, anyway, anyway, let's bring this back to the top again here,
which really was all about security and the fact that
a lot of the security things we do, we have no data. We don't know what works.
We don't know what doesn't work. We, we, we, we, we're living in a giant skinner box.
-- Right.
-- It used to work but the world has changed. So
I don't think it ever worked, man. I think we thought it worked because,
because it made us feel good or it looked like
we were doing something important because let's face it,
passwords. Right.
Having the password dictionary with all the
common words that people try to brute force
and not allowing like a password of password or God or what is it?
God. Sex, love money.
-- Whatever the, you know, from the movie hackers,
-- right. Whatever, those are wrong.
Anyway, it's a movie.
But, um,
so I, I, you know,
I think it sort of made a little bit of sense but then we took it way too far,
you know, it's like zero tolerance policies, right? Like it kind of makes sense.
So, hey, let's just,
let's go with a zero tolerance policy on this.
You know,
you have to have a password of like 72
characters or longer change it every three weeks,
you know, and it has all these absurd requirements. But
here's the thing.
-- Now,
-- none of this was ever grounded in research.
It was just crap we made up because we thought it sounded neat.
Right.
-- Well, it definitely dealt with people choosing the word password as their,
-- there
was
no
research that's not research even. That's an anecdote, man.
I mean, for real, all of this password advice was plucked out of the air for, like,
seriously.
Think about that.
What are you looking at something else to prove me wrong?
Well, it's just, I know I've seen a little bit of research on this
just
now, but back then
there was nothing I'm willing to.
I think it was more, it was,
yeah, it was anecdotal in the sense of like, oh,
these people choose password as password and then, you know,
somebody breaks in by guessing password as their password.
So let's ban that word.
And, you know, and then taken to its logical extreme,
we end up with modern password policies that are terrible
and more to the point though. A lot of this doesn't matter because,
you know, for example, the majority of people, well,
not the majority but a lot of people, you know,
their primary computer now is kind of a smartphone, you know, it,
it's pretty physically secure and lives in their pocket,
you know,
and a lot of them now have biometric sensor to get into them
debatably worse.
Although when their password is 1234, the,
the fingerprint scanner magnitudes better.
Yeah.
Well, I love that actually, if you try and enter 1234 as a password for your iphone,
it will specifically warn you about that.
Does it actually? So my, my kids got, uh, ATM cards, sometime back
and there were a bunch of passwords.
I, I didn't test this but the bank guy said, like you can't use 1234 or 4567. Like
it, there's,
there's a whole bunch of combinations that won't let you use.
Which is,
I,
it makes sense. I mean,
I get
-- it
-- right. Well, it makes sense in the sense of, wow, we know how broken this is.
So instead of fixing it, we'll just try and
I'm not really fix it.
Just
kind of,
I mean,
uh simple use voice recognition, use a keyboard so you can have a real password.
Uh do
it like
where they have,
uh,
so in Japan they have ATM S with a thermal camera to read the blood veins in your hand.
Ok.
The advantage being that you don't have to touch anything as well.
-- I don't
-- want to touch an ATM like that.
-- Can you imagine the disease you're going to pick up?
-- That's the
-- point you don't have to because it's a camera,
-- right?
So you
just
hold your
hand up.
Well, in
Japan is a clean place. Like I would touch an ATM in Japan.
But like in the US man, I know I've, I've seen these things.
They, they look disgusting.
-- So,
-- no, I mean, but, but the thing is that, you know, to remember we're asking people,
it's like, oh, I want magical security but only with a four digit pin number.
You know what though. Here's the thing.
If, if it wasn't secured, the banks wouldn't be doing it because the banks, like,
it's actually real money
when something goes wrong in a bank, they lose real money.
Not necessarily.
Now it's for example, in Britain there, that,
that was the reason Chip and Pin took off in Britain so heavily back in the day
is because it passed the liability on to the customer.
Because when their accounts and stuff got cleaned out, the bank would say, look,
you have Chip and Pin not our fault.
You must have told somebody the PIN number
and given them your chip card.
And I, I, I've heard stories that there have been some fraud
committed with this stuff, but I, I don't know
for sure how,
-- how rampant that was or if it
-- really is the one in Indonesia
with several million dollars withdrawn in like what a 24 hour period.
Ok.
But if you have something like that, that's obviously like organized fraud, right?
Versus
the way it was working in the US
where you had people constantly stealing credit cards.
-- I
-- mean,
that was out of control. In fact, the gas stations still have freaking skimmers
-- because
-- oh, you know what's intriguing.
Speaking of which, so you know how you guys just got Chip and Signature.
-- Don't
-- remind me, I hate Chip.
I was uh my local liquor store
has a sign up saying that they will not accept Chip and signature only chip and pin.
I could,
I
-- quite frankly, right. You can just steal the card and use it.
-- Right.
Well, you know, it still ticks me off is like I want a pin.
I have asked my bank for a pin and they will not give me a pin. Just come on guys.
Like I don't want to sign my signature.
Yeah, but they'd have to like, you know, upgrade every single merchant.
-- No,
-- they don't. They all work, man.
Here's the thing is so, no, no, I've done this. I had a card, I, I got a card with a pin.
I, I had one at one point because I,
I managed to trick my bank into giving it to me when I was going to Europe.
And anyway,
uh I that card is now it expired and I got rid of it. But,
but I had a chip and pin in the US
and basically what happens is when I go in some of
them you swipe and then it was swipe a signature.
Some of them I put the chip in and it would ask me for a signature.
But the vast majority of places I was
-- swiping is still an option
-- in some places. Yes, it's terrible.
-- And then in some places
-- because
I can't swipe my card.
II, I intentionally disabled one of my cars to see what would happen.
And so the chip didn't work.
So I tried swiping and it's like no, your card is basically set up to only
if, if there's a choice between,
if there, if chip is supported on the terminal,
then it must be chip, it can't be swiped.
So the guy at Home Depot actually brought out the big,
the
old mechanical,
they,
well, it's Home Depot man, they once squirreled away in the,
in the self checkout ladies kiosk thing.
And because, you know, at some point they will take your money no matter what,
like it could be the end of the world.
There's no electricity,
you know, the, the zombies are out and we can still chunk your credit card.
That's crazy, man.
Wow.
I'm, I'm anyway, anyway, but in the US,
the vast majority of places would accept my chip and pin
like it, it just works.
Most of those terminals are set up for chip and pin.
-- We just
-- don't
-- have
-- it. Well, the pin only verifies locally against the chip, right?
It's not, you know, it's not super rocket science, but I mean, you do need a, well,
a reasonably not retarded terminal.
I mean,
I, I've actually,
I don't think I've seen a terminal in Canada
that doesn't have chip in probably 10 years.
Uh Does it, does it do anything locally on card?
Because my, my pi I had to change it at one point and I don't think the, did the bank,
I actually,
I actually did swipe my debit card last
week because I was returning something to Home Depot
and to credit my debit card. They're just like, oh, just swipe it.
And that's the first time in like, 10 years I've swiped my debit card
otherwise I've never swiped it and I don't know where or why. I would.
Crazy man.
Crazy.
Anyway,
anyway,
we're talking about economics and security and the fact that we don't have any.
So we just keep making crap up.
Well, I guess one of the questions is how do we bring these people back into the,
you know,
it kind of reminds me of all these people that dealt with buggies and wagons.
Now, it's like, no, we got these cool model T Fords.
Ok. So, you know what I've thought about this a lot and the only answer I can come to is
it's not our problem.
Right.
It is up to them to fit into society
and if they don't want to, that's great.
I think the one downfall is there's still a fair number of leaders
who are soldiers from the last
I was at Costco buying a removable hard drive
and this poor guy was trying to answer. This lady wanted to buy a copy of office
and he's like,
uh huh, I, like I get what you're saying, but we, we don't sell that.
We, you know, you can buy a one year subscription to office 365.
But like, you can't actually buy the thing
on like,
it's not like the old times where you bought a CD or DVD and then you, like,
had that copy of software forever.
Plus whatever updates. It's like, no, it's like
you're gonna pay.
What is, I think it's, uh,
in Canada it's like 99 bucks Canadian per year for five user license,
like
whatever storage.
Uh,
and that's it. You pay that yearly,
right? You don't buy it, you just pay a yearly rental fee basically. Right.
And this lady just could not handle this concept and she wasn't old or anything.
She was like in her probably early forties, mid forties
just could not handle this concept. Like she wanted to buy it on CD or DVD.
And the guy's like, I just know, like, I
can't do that like Microsoft
to the best of my knowledge, Microsoft doesn't sell that anymore.
It's a subscription.
Oh, man.
Just, just for the record,
we could buy a vintage credit card machine for like 25 bucks on ebay.
That could be our new theme song. It's just raking them back and forth very quickly.
Right.
Hey, I wonder if they have different tones and
-- noise,
-- you know, they do, I'm sure.
And you could probably also put different mediums in it to change the, the sound
right here is a future card. We could make music with old credit card
machine.
I
know what their
name
March.
-- Uh,
-- anyway, anyway, so we were talking about
kind of what do we do with these people who maybe
don't have the right mindset for today.
-- And
-- more importantly, a lot of them don't want to have the right mind.
You see that, that's just the point is
there's, I, I wrote, I wrote an article on my blog,
like a million years ago and I think I called it the third group.
And
what it really was about is this came up in
a discussion I had with uh actually an old guy
who was in my fraternity in college like a million
years ago because he was taking out some leadership roles.
He was asking me questions.
But you know,
how do we deal with this and that and this and what about these people and that people?
And it brought back a bunch of memories and we,
we really had a good discussion about this,
but we kind of put everyone in and there's always gonna be three groups.
You've got the group of people who like are gung ho and they want to do it right?
Like they're there and they're the people who are willing to do everything.
If you let them right,
then you have the group of people who are essentially like, uh if you ask for my help,
I will help you.
But whatever, I'm happy to sit in the corner too, if need be right.
And then there's the people who aren't going to do anything,
even if you ask them for help.
OK.
But here's the thing, the first group, the people who are like,
all about getting things done and wanting to do stuff,
they obsess over that third group,
they will spend more time
arguing and trying to deal with those, that third group than they do.
Like doing good things.
Right.
And I kind of feel like we're in that position here where you've got,
you've got the people who understand where the world is going and how it's changing
and let's face it.
This is like the whole start up culture is very much in this, this place.
And then you've got people who like,
if you tell them what to do and how it works,
they're going to figure it out and they understand and they know what's going on.
And then you have the people who are kind of like those, the stodgy old people,
you know, the soldiers from the last wars we keep saying
and
I think it,
if you,
if you worry about them and you try to argue with
them or convince them or deal with them in any way,
you are wasting your time, right?
They aren't gonna change the best you can hope
for is they accidentally wander into the second group.
But the reality is most of them will never change.
And so really, I think ignoring them is the only reasonable, well,
it's the only economic option.
Right.
Well, I, I guess you're right because, I mean, there's still people that, you know,
insist on buying flip phones.
Can you
still?
Well, it's like checks. Right.
My bank wants, like, it's about a dollar,
it's somewhere between one and $2 to just print me checks.
Like 50 checks. It's over $50.
Except if you're over the age of,
I think it's like 65 you can get the checks at a reasonable price.
The bank, like banks clearly want to get rid of these stupid little pieces of paper.
-- I hate
-- checks. You know? What's funny is I remember I was at a store one time.
This was, this is like a couple of weeks ago
and this person started writing a check in front of me and I wanted to just like,
take my credit card.
I'd be like, I will pay for this. Just leave
like, oh my goodness, it was, it was like, and the thing is,
it took them literally less than one minute,
but it felt like it was the most horrible experience of
my life waiting for that person to write a check.
And I'm like, oh my goodness. What is like, who does that?
Yeah. Well, and I mean, it's, you know, until things happen.
Like,
I remember about a decade ago we had a postal strike and
a whole bunch of old people signed up for online banking.
You know, I was
talking to my bank.
It,
you know, and I was like, I'm curious, you know, like,
what are the, you know, did this postal strike have any effect, you know,
on bills or whatever?
Um, but, yeah, I mean, that's, that, that's the thing. Right.
Some of these people, like, I know, I'm kind of the same way.
I still insist on, like, laptops.
Right. To me, a laptop is a computer. I,
I, you know,
at some point I might have to admit that I might get a pair
of VR head glasses or like a tablet or something that will replace my.
I, I do a lot on my tablet.
Actually, you know, what kills me is I really want to go chromebook 100%.
But you know what, you know, the reason I can't
is because of this podcast right here because I,
I need a real computer to record and edit this thing.
I know I've done a bunch of research. There are no good options today.
And actually the other thing I keep thinking, I'm like,
I bet I could write a web interface to edit audio and then I wouldn't need to
keep a computer anyway anyway.
Well, you know. No, no, no.
You see you're thinking about it if you were smart, you know,
write some MLRA I
to mix the podcast and get rid of all the extraneous noise.
So basically you'd have one or more people just connect to the website.
Yap at it and then magic and comes a podcast,
my podcast editing, you know, honestly, I've got it down pretty good at this point.
But anyway, anyway,
so, ok,
so here's the thing you just made me realize when you're talking
about old people signing up for online banking during a postal strike is
they only did that
because they now had an economic incentive.
They
wanted their money.
Right.
And, and I'm using the word economic, not necessarily meaning just money,
but like time is part of that economic incentive, right?
And,
and these old people were probably super nervous about paying their
bills or knowing how much money they have or whatever,
like, did the check clear
that,
that going through the pain of learning how online banking works
outweighed the pain of waiting for the postal strike to end.
And this is the same thing of a lot of these, like,
like old security people we're talking about is
they have no incentive to change.
Right.
And if they get fired one day
they might
learn the new skills they need.
It might be a bit like
-- that
-- might
-- be.
-- But, but
-- quite frankly if you're 40 or 50 years old in tech looking for a new job,
that's not a lot of fun anymore.
Yeah, I, I think about that a lot is,
it's
III I, it's a young person's world,
I think in a lot of ways and part of me understands why just because, you know, I,
I remember being young and working like crazy hours and stuff.
Like that. It's,
yeah,
it's, it's tough.
But I guess again, it, it's all about the economics of it. Right. Is,
if you are older
and you're unwilling to keep your skill set updated,
why would anyone look at you? Seriously?
-- Right.
-- Well, that's a big thing I've run into is a lot of people
who have been in the industry forever and ever and ever,
but have no certifications to kind of show what they know,
right? And, or they have certifications from 1020 years ago, like an M,
like, I, I have an M CS E from the NT four days
and that literally
no, of course, not useless,
right? It's,
it's beyond you.
OK?
So here's,
here's the
thing,
I'm gonna stop you here and,
and I don't want to have this discussion and here's why is because
it's, it's the name of this podcast is the open source security podcast, right? And
here's the thing with the way open source works today and you have github and you,
like, anyone can have a blog.
I mean, I remember when running a blog was like real work and now,
like I went to blogger.com and click, give me a blog and I, I have one, right?
It's not hard.
And, and here's the thing is certifications I think can have value to show
that
you're young and you're serious about a certain industry or, or something, right?
Even if you're old, it can have value as well,
but I think in, in
a nice alternative
to some of these certifications can be just
right,
write, code, write a blog,
you know, get involved.
Stack overflow has already done that right.
With stack overflow,
they can already turn your answers and stuff into a resume anyway.
But here's the thing, right is like, I, I've hired tons of security people.
Do you know how many I've looked at their certifications?
Zero of them.
Do you know how many I've searched Google to
see what they've done in the open source world,
all of them.
And that's what you do with everybody, you mean?
-- I
-- agree. Right. Exactly.
And,
and so I think the advantage of certifications
is they'll probably get you past the recruiter.
But if you're working for someone who thinks certifications
are more important than contributing to open source,
like,
you've got a problem, you know?
Well,
something to remember though is there's a lot of entry level jobs where
they use that as a filter because otherwise you get people who can't write
and, and I'm ok with that.
But I think also, so here's the other part of my answer now is like you and I
are old,
ok for this industry, unquestionably, like I'd like to think I'm not, but I know I am,
I am a grandpa
in tech
but here's the thing.
We know a lot of people because we're old. Right.
So, if we want new jobs, we're gonna tell the people we know we're looking for jobs.
And so now you've got, you can skip past a recruiter.
So I think the certifications are significantly less important
in that regard for someone in our position.
Right.
So, I think if you're,
if you have that network, yes, if you don't have that network though, you're
-- up.
-- But here's again,
if you're old and you have no network and you
have nothing in public to show for what you've done.
Like, you've done something wrong with you.
It's funny that you mentioned that, but I mean, we just had the whole oracle sls
thing come up in the last 48 hours. That's right. No more solar.
And I mean, I, I, that's brutal because I kind of wonder, like,
obviously, ok, first of all, disclaimer Solaris
engineering wise. Beautiful, amazing. Right. So,
yeah. Yeah. Sure.
-- It's pain in the butt and it doesn't have like half the software
-- you want
-- is a pain in the butt. It
-- works really well.
You know, it's engineered beautifully and I,
I really feel bad for some of these people because, you know,
there's probably a ton of people that are really smart code and really useful,
clever code.
And yeah, can they prove it? Can they, you know, how do they,
yeah.
You know,
how do they find a new, you know, job based on their previous work?
You know, that they may or may not be able to show off?
And,
and that is one of the challenges to close source man is you
can be trapped behind a wall and nobody knows what you've done.
However, I must say, I think we've reached a point where, I mean,
even Microsoft is super open source friendly.
I think if you're working for a company that's all closed source, like,
get out because you're in a bad place. Right.
Well, here's the reality.
If they claim to be closed source, they're lying because it's like, uh,
what was it that drone maker, the HJ I or whatever it's called,
the one that got the department of Defense warning. Anyway,
uh There's, you know,
there's all those accusations of them having GP L code in their software, of course,
people found it and now they've been trying to obfuscate the code and they've,
you know, released updates that, like are hard to decipher and blah, blah, blah,
you know, so the reality is, I mean, ii I, there,
there are probably a handful of people on this planet who
don't use or touch open source code but they're like,
you know, so restricted and limited.
Um, it doesn't really matter, right?
Like, you know, like the guys who wrote the uh, software for the,
uh for the space shuttle, for example,
uh is that, is that publicly released? I feel like that's been open sourced.
Oh, the software itself happens
worst,
I think.
Well, I mean, but in the sense of that a piece
of software that probably doesn't, like, have like open J
PEG or
JJ,
the
first part of it too. Right.
Is so yes,
if you wrote the space shuttle software and let's say it's not released and,
and I think it's the Apollo software that was released.
Anyway, let's say it's not released
if you have on your resume that you worked on the space shuttle software.
Like, I think that you're ok. Right. Like that's, that's all right.
If you have on your resume, like
I worked on these Solaris,
you know, file systems, blah, blah, blah,
something that was completely closed and nobody knows about it.
But even then
there's a certain amount of gravitas and
in many circles that if you were like a Solaris developer,
you obviously have a certain amount of skill.
Right?
Yeah.
And so I,
I guess that's kind of the challenge now is bringing it all back to where we started is
we, we kind of what are our economic incentives that drive what we do?
And this is true of, of all the developers, young and old in,
in the industry is why are we making the decisions we're making?
And we, we don't have good answers for a lot of it.
And I think that's a huge problem and in fact,
that's something I've started now on this.
What will probably be a never ending series of blog posts talking about
like economic incentives behind security and how we can start to
measure what we do and to do things that actually make sense
because I, I think, I look, I'm, I'm gonna say it is.
I think the business has gotten sick of us and I think
we've run out of a lot of goodwill in terms of security.
Right. And if we can't start showing our value, we're going to be
the door.
Well, I mean, if you look at how a lot of start ups are doing security, the answer is,
yeah.
And more to the point I,
I took a security economics course and they point out quite simply,
especially for start ups.
There are so many real threats that can and will kill you in the next six weeks,
let alone six months, let alone six years.
This possible, maybe of a security breach,
causing damage and possibly enough damage to bring you down.
Yeah. It's a possibility. But
there's like real risks of, like, you know,
there's like rabid raccoons under your desk.
Let's worry about those first and then worry about, you know, someday,
maybe possibilities.
-- No, I,
-- I agree completely. And, and I think it goes even beyond that is
you, let's say you're a start up,
you probably have hundreds or thousands of legitimate risks
and some of the risks
are going to be,
you know,
wounding to the point of it will destroy your organization and some of them will be.
Yes, that's annoying. But it's minor and we can still survive if that happens.
And I see security very similarly where there are certain security things, we can do
that
by definition for the security thing to matter.
You'd have to be somewhat successful.
Uh, what do you mean someone successful?
Well, if you have no customers, you have no money
if you get a breach,
right? Like,
you know, it's like if somebody breaches a start up and it's like, oh,
we got like 100 accounts
that literally is like, who cares?
You know,
and somebody breaches you and they get like 200 million accounts. Ok?
Now, now we're talking
and the number of start ups that have the 200 million user problem is
-- quite, quite small,
-- right? And, and you, you, you can grow into a lot of that.
But I think even as you grow into it, you need to constantly be asking the question
if I do this.
Like, what does it matter? Right.
And, and I think you can look at a lot of things and say a great example is passwords.
How many,
how many of these start ups have either insane password
policies for their employees or for the users using them
and they, if they turn them off tomorrow,
it would literally make zero difference for their bottom line.
And in fact,
it might make it go up a little bit because now people don't
have to deal with the pain and suffering of their crappy password system.
Well, I mean, even more simply,
I prefer to deal with online services that allow me to log in by Google or Twitter.
Oh, man, I agree. I get, so
-- I don't want to make more
-- account. I get so annoyed when I can't use Google.
It's,
oh, what has happened to us? We, we used to be security people. Kurt.
Now we're, now we're like heretics. Right.
Martin Luther Nailing our treatises to the church door.
Well, unfortunately, we don't have anything
to say. That's helpful.
I
know we complain a lot though. So we get that.
Oh,
I know. I know. All right. I, I
-- think we should call it. You got anything else to close with?
-- I hope everybody
enjoys their kids going back to school because I know I, I
can't wait.
Those teachers, every teacher is grossly underpaid.
-- That's all I have to say. Like,
-- can you imagine dealing with 30 kids?
I would, I would have been fired on the third day if I was a teacher.
I guarantee it, I, I couldn't do it.
I couldn't do it
anyway. Anyway.
All right. Thanks everybody.
If you want links to the show notes, any of the crazy things we talked about,
you can hit up open source security podcast.com.
We've got linked to a Facebook group.
We've got the
Poland Os S podcast, hashtag
links to Kurt and my Twitter accounts.
Uh hit us up at hassle us as you see. Fit
Yeah, I guess if nothing else, Kurt, you have a fantastic rest of your day.
Everyone else. Thanks for listening and until next time.
Thanks folks.