Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself. Kri
Siefried
-- and my partner, not believing squirrels exist. Josh Pressers, they
-- exist.
Why would I? I hate them. I hate them so much if they don't exist.
-- I have all this misplaced
-- rage.
The government had them all killed a few years
back and replaced them with robots because they,
have you ever seen squirrel poop?
-- And the answer is no, you haven't.
-- No, I have
because they lived in my garage and trust me,
they use the toilet inside of the structure they're living in and it is
beyond disgusting.
So, yes, I have seen vast quantities of squirrel poop and other squirrel
things we'll say.
And it's gross and terrible and the smell is
unbelievably bad.
Interesting. I would have thought it was a little herbivores.
Their poop wouldn't be that offensive.
It is disgusting.
Well, the poop isn't, I don't think, are they herbivores? Are they omnivores?
-- I don't know. Actually, I thought they were
-- herbivores.
I mean, they're awful small for omnivores.
I've seen pictures of squirrels eating like pizza in New York.
I mean, I don't, I don't know.
-- I don't know. That's
-- a good question.
But even like deer and horses will, you know,
there's that famous video of the horse just eats a baby chick on the ground.
It's just kind of like,
uh,
I don't think I've seen that, but
I don't, I don't need to either.
Oh,
they are? Omnivores.
I mean, that, that was kind of my assumption.
Yeah. Eggs, eggs, insects. Oh, insects. I always forget about insects.
There's lots of bugs.
Yeah. Well, they'll even eat snakes. I mean,
I kind of like snakes so I'm ok with that.
I live in a place without poisonous snakes, so I'm not afraid of them, which I love.
They're interesting.
Anyway. Anyway, what,
so we're talking about the contents of stuff today?
Well, kind of. So
we're gonna talk about S
bombs and
this is a topic. I've been kind of kicking around for a long time.
It's something near and dear to my heart. Obviously I work at
Acor, we deal with S
bombs all the time. It's kind of one of our things we do
and
it, it finally,
I think has reached the point where it's time for
us to have a discussion about it because I feel like
everyone is talking about S bombs and
at first it was a very, oh, you need this, you need this, everyone needs to do this.
And now I think we finally hit the point where people are saying, wait a minute,
like what's actually going on here
and I'm seeing a lot of old man yells at cloud responses and it's like,
that's not very good either.
So I feel like this is a great opportunity for us to just kind of
explain what's happening.
-- No,
-- I think we're firmly going towards the trough of disillusionment where,
yeah, we, we passed the,
the S balm hype peak and it's kind of like not only well and what I love about
these hype cycles now is they're going so fast
that we're not even getting people to deploy them.
They're like,
basically like maybe one person in the industry is doing s
-- somewhat,
-- I,
I'm surprised if it's that high
and you know,
the rest are not even at the point of doing
it and they've already gone to the trough of disillusionment,
the trough of,
I can't even talk anyway.
Let's start out by explaining what an
bomb actually is.
I think
this isn't completely obvious all the time and
I hear a lot of different explanations.
Some people say, oh, it's an ingredients list.
And then there's some people saying, oh, it's not an ingredients list and whatever.
And it doesn't matter.
Fundamentally, all this thing is, it's a software bill of materials.
It's meant to be a list of all of the
stuff that makes up a particular piece of software.
Right?
And then you hear people talk about, oh, well,
maybe you only do one level of dependencies.
-- No, it's everything in the software full stop
-- the problem there becomes what if the
also depends on a service
-- that
-- is not something I'm aware of having a good solution for. And that's off topic.
-- So you're not, I'm not going to let you derail us.
-- OK?
So we're going to abstract away services because like literally
the great example would be Microsoft Office.
Microsoft Office depends on a license service run by Microsoft, which of course has
only God knows what Rube Goldberg contraption on the back.
Ignore that.
That's
so basically we're gonna abstract to actual bits that are sitting on my computer.
That's right. When you download the the zip file of whatever it is, you're doing
everything in that zip file.
-- That's what we're talking about
-- and, and I would point out so to skip away ahead.
But one of the aspects of
ssal is there's,
there's, well, two aspects either you get the SS bomb from the vendor
and or you generate the S bomb yourself and obviously you can
only generate an S bomb yourself on stuff that you have.
We're
a
service reliably.
Yeah, you can't, you can't s bomb services.
But that's an important I think point that I
hear a lot of people confusing about the the
acquiring an S bomb versus generating S bomb because
both those steps are important for different reasons.
So OK, so we have this document that's meant to be a list of all of the things
in your stuff. And there's
talking about 01 level deep in your dependencies, whatever.
No, that's all nonsense. You go everything in there. Literally everything.
I don't care if it's
100 dependencies deep. It makes the list.
-- Like,
-- dude, I remember at Red Hat,
like some of those jar files had stuff embedded in them with a zip.
Like I remember actually when uh what was it cloud forms triggered that clim.
A clim A V for some reason, had a stupid,
uh double zip file signature for a while where like if a zip was in a zip,
it would trigger cli maybe.
And I'm like
a,
that's actually a reasonably normal thing to have because
if you heard about Java and number two,
-- how like does any malware actually do that?
-- Like that?
Lots of malware does actually they like to hide themselves,
-- who cares
-- then just detect the malware?
-- Well, so it's complicated
-- though.
I know, but it's, it was a super false positive and, you know,
I had to write a knowledge piece article about
it because customers were freaking out and I'm like,
no, we're not infected with anyways. It's not a tumor.
Yes,
-- in my head is not a tumor.
-- Exactly. That.
And that's
a, well,
we can talk about that another time because there's a lot of weirdness to that.
What you're saying is you need to account for
literally every single bit in that piece of software.
Otherwise it's not an S balm it's a partial ss balm
and the partial s balm is like having
-- anything that's partial. It's worse may
-- contain nuts
if you're allergic to
something says may contain nuts. You're going to assume it does
and
may contain squirrels.
No, just, no,
they're all robots.
Now, remember anyway, that's why you don't want those sharp pieces.
So, anyway, right.
Like if, if you had a bag of chips that said may contain metal shards,
would you be like, I'll roll those dice.
No, you're not gonna roll those dice.
So anyway,
kind of, I, I guess
aspect number one of, of my talking point is the bomb has to be everything, right?
And now we're gonna get to kind of this,
there's also becoming a lot of talk around.
Should we have completely trusted environments generating
bombs? We need to
all of our s bombs we need to,
you know what I mean?
It's reminiscent of that very, if you're not doing it 100% perfect,
it's not worth doing at all,
which I think was a very common view in security a decade ago.
What this reminds me of is and I had to look this up back in November 22nd of 2016.
Uh episode 14,
we interviewed David A Wheeler about the ci I
badges and he pointed out a really good thing,
which was
you get a badge for having a testing framework,
even if there's no test because the testing framework with no test
is, gives you the possibility of plugging a test in
not having a testing framework means
you still have a blank page.
And I think in the context of this S bomb discussion,
it is
AAA an S bomb of questionable level of trust is better than no S bomb at all.
And now granted,
I would love to see like hermetic build environments with signatures
everywhere and whatever it's fully reproducible and all that jazz.
But we're not there yet.
And I think claiming S bombs are invalid somehow is that is red
point.
Well, more to the point, this is how we get there because
the other thing is for people to say
like,
well, I know uh uh remind me again,
which one is it gripe or sift that actually does the S bomb
-- uh
-- sift creates S bombs. That's one of
-- Acors
-- tools.
There was that chart showing, you know, if you uh for the log for J thing,
like if you run a find command, it'll basically find
that was actually gripe
in that chart
anyways.
Well, the point was, you know,
there's like all these different sort of approaches to the technology.
-- Right. Right.
-- And part of it is, and I hate to say this, but doing S
bombs properly means
you need to understand a whole bunch of different file formats.
And some of these file formats are like docker containers.
They are not a simple zip file. Like it's Exactly.
Yeah. It's, it's like
a, it's complicated
and the way we get to a complete S bomb is by having incomplete S bombs along the way.
-- Right.
-- Right. Exactly.
And, and the tools get better with every iteration, which is hugely important. OK.
So there's kind of this aspect of trust
and
figuring out like, can I trust yes
bomb?
But then I think that now the next kind of thing that I think is really important is
there's also this concept of when should we scan our, our software? Like do we,
let's say the vendor gives me an S bomb? Am I done?
What about when I'm going to deploy a container? Should I scan it then?
And I'm done or what about during the build? Should I scan the build that I'm done?
And the actual answer is you should be scanned
for S bomb content
anytime anything happens if you're doing a code check and scan it,
if you're doing a build, scan it, if you're turning it into container, scan it,
if you're deploying the container, scan it, if it's Tuesday scan it,
you know what I mean?
You actually forgot one important case which is your S bomb tool improves
scan it.
Like you if your S bomb tool gets better rerun it all to get better results.
That's another important point is in theory, the SBA
is static, but it actually isn't because
one of the one of the other kind of myths.
I,
I hear is there seems to be this concept of expecting like a human being to build this.
No way.
There's, there is no software on the planet that a human can actually
manually deal with and understand what's in it. It's all too complicated.
Now, we need robots
-- and they can't do it reliably or
-- no, no, not at all.
They can't do it reliably or
inducive
or quickly.
And so what happens is so I might scan my container and I generate an S bomb, right?
And then a new, let's say, in six months,
there's like 10 revisions of the S bomb scanner that have been released.
I rescan it and now the S bomb scanner
can find some new things it couldn't find before,
right?
In theory that should be a static document. But the reality is it's not.
Well, I remember one software product, not at Red Hat. Thank goodness. But
the the software product actually shipped
with like a virtual file system that you then mounted locally on the file system,
like an iso file could be mounted, you know,
and then that's where it ran the software from.
-- I mean, that's basically how containers work,
-- right? But I mean, I like just
the there's a people really forget
that there are so
many complexities that people use
and they're not corner cases like they're not rare like a
Java inside a Java inside a container inside of a jet.
Like that's not actually as rare as you would like it to be. No, no, it's, it's not.
And I think that's what's going to be fascinating to me is
as we actually unpack all this,
because we've already kind of had this argument around
licensing where you have to know every everything,
every single thing you ship for licensing compliance,
especially in the open source world.
Right?
And in theory,
so like we should
already kind of have S bombs solved in the sense of if,
if you claim to have licensing compliance,
then you are also claiming to know every single bit in your software.
That's right. And now it should also be noted that
there are kind of two primary S
bomb formats. Right. Now, there's something called SPDX and cycle. And DXSPDX is a
branch of the Linux Foundation, Cyclin DX is part of OAP.
Now, SPDX started its life as
licensing where the intent was, this was a document format that was,
it's meant to capture open source components and their licenses.
And in fact, even today,
SPDX has a very like strict list of licenses you're allowed to put in.
Like if you don't use one of the licenses on their list,
you're technically not producing an SPDX document
that's
gonna have to
change,
it
creates some headaches.
But well, I mean,
part of me understands why they do it because you also don't
want like you want one way to denote Apache two licenses,
you don't want some people putting spaces, some people not putting spaces,
some people capitalizing Apache.
You know what I mean? It creates a mess. But anyway, anyway,
like that is where that started. Its life was licenses. And
I mean, this is another thing that
like when you're doing S
bomb,
you can kind of get license management for free as part of this because
these S
bomb formats also capture licenses as part of their data set.
Well, yeah, that's kind of important.
Like it always blows my mind that people just for the longest time,
we just sort of all ignored licensing like it was basically
either commercial or open source and it was open source.
We just, everybody used it and did whatever with it and ignored the actual words.
No, I, I agree or, or people specifically avoided open source because they,
they heard about the new GP L and oh,
it's the license is viral and I'm going to have to
like give all my money to hippies if I use the software
or something.
Microsoft Open sources of cancer back in 2001.
-- Was it
-- open? Snow? Linux.
Linux is a cancer, right?
Linux is a cancer.
Sorry. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. I remember when,
when I worked at Progeny Linux systems way back in the early two thousands,
we had a poster we hung up.
That was, it was like, remember kids or remember kids when you're, when you're,
when you're using open
-- source, you're supporting communism and it
-- showed like in
the background,
it was such a good poster
and of course, we laughed at all this stuff and we thought it was great. But I mean,
man,
but, you know, and,
and now we've reached a point where I think there's a lot of lawyers who
understand this stuff and they're starting to recognize
that certain licenses come with certain requirements.
And so you just have to be mindful and it's not even about like,
oh you can or can't use this or whatever.
It's just let's make sure we're not, you know, violating any terms of our,
you
have to use it now because if you,
the time it takes to rewrite one of these components, your competitors,
your launch
right, right now. Now that also kind of brings up
another part of all this. I think that's really funny is
I see people that so they, they get their ass bomb.
They look at the list, they're horrified by what they see.
They're like, let's just write a bunch of this ourselves. It's like
that is,
that is a terrible idea.
This reminds me of in theory,
if you had a proper housing inspection where the guy like
drilled holes in your house and like stuck a Boer cam in
and you know, they would just find so many horrifying things.
Squirrels, squirrels every day.
Like this is one of the reasons whenever like
the last two houses I've lived in and bought
unfinished basements because I no longer trust finished basements.
Right.
Whatever, who cares?
Well, this one, the last, this one and the last one I had, you know,
cracks in the foundation and because they're exposed is
easy to deal with,
you know, and so this one here,
there was a minor crack where the forms anyways, the point is
like, I no longer,
I don't trust housing inspections because they miss stuff all the time.
Kind of like bad ass bomb tools.
But more to the point, the reality is all of this stuff. Like is
a horror show.
Like this is the food safety industry 50 years ago where it's like may contain
100 years ago. I think
we're still
lead in the tea
to make the leaves look fresh,
throw some chalk in that milk, it'll be fine.
OK? So I, we, we've just spent a lot of time and we, we oddly talked about it.
I think some of the setup here, but now I, I want to spend a little time as well about.
So there's all these weird myths around
eal
what it can do, what it can't do.
And
yeah, you hear a lot of people saying, oh, you need an S bomb, you need an S,
you need an S bomb. But then they're not like, well, why?
Like, why, what, what is the point?
Yeah. My favorite thing is, so you've got an ESB bomb Now what?
Yeah,
like how is this actionable? What are you going to do about it?
It feels like the South Park underpants know him
sometimes where it was like step one steel underpants,
step two question mark, step three profit.
And sometimes I think that's like the whole, that's, that's the s bomb story today
because
there's all these people saying you need an S bomb.
But there's remarkably few people saying why?
Right.
Well, there is, there, now,
there is the federal government in the United States is requiring them.
That's a pretty good why.
But even even at some point, they're gonna say, why are we doing this?
I have a Google Drive with 10,000 est bombs in it. What now?
And this is where there's kind of this new branch of products
coming out that we'll call S bomb management or supply chain management.
Because fundamentally if you have a large number of S bombs, which you should,
if you're scanning your stuff many,
many times and you're getting s bombs from vendors.
Now you have a lot of these S bombs,
you need to do something with them.
-- It becomes a data management problem.
-- Well, that's the thing. All problems
essentially at scale become
-- data management. Logistics. I
-- mean, so II I have a funny story actually about that.
So
I was talking to a large software vendor the other day and the person says,
uh do we have an ND A in place because without one,
I can't tell you what I want to tell you.
Sorry,
-- I shouldn't laugh.
-- But it's true though. This happens all the time.
Right to all of us anyway. I'm like, hang on, let me go look, you know, call the lawyer
and I was like, oh, yeah, we got, we got ND A, it's right here and he hands it to me
and it has like an ND A number on the top
and it's in the millions.
And I'm thinking
this company probably has millions or tens of millions of NDAS in place.
How do you possibly manage that volume of documents? Right.
Like this isn't, you're not putting these in a Google Drive, you know what I mean?
Like that's, that's a crazy data problem.
I'm sure the lawyers have some database product.
Well. Right. Right.
Without question, there's some sort of database you're putting this stuff in.
But like you think about that, it's
like if you or I had to deal with NDAS, we just create a folder called NDAS. Right?
And we put like the four of them we have in it.
Whereas,
whereas when you're a giant software company or a giant company in general,
I'm sure you're gonna have, you know,
thousands to millions of these things and you have to do something with it.
And I think s bombs are kind of a similar story where if I have
one
-- enterprise loaner shipped with 8000 packages.
-- Yeah,
-- Right.
Like you're looking at those containers. Right.
There's like alpine Linux on the small end, like, literally on the small end with,
you know, it's tight, little small world
and then there's,
well, but everybody else, we just use ubuntu, like, pretty much a full stack because
-- we just wanted to jam the ruby on rails in there and make it work.
-- Right.
It's, it's easy. I mean. Exactly. Exactly.
And now, I mean, that,
that's a whole another problem and we'll talk about the actual content.
I'm just talking about the literal documents itself, right?
Because
if, if you're, let's say, generating an S bomb,
every step of your development process,
I think you could expect somewhere between 10 and 100 S bombs like per, per version.
In theory,
they'd be really amenable to storing them in something like git because there,
there should be relatively small changes between, you know,
runs or versions like you add something or they
tool gets better. So it shouldn't take up a huge amount of room.
Here's where I want to help educate because you just,
you just fell into the trap of,
I guess not managing your documents of
this isn't about tracking the latest version.
-- You, you obviously want the latest copy, but you also want
-- the, oh no,
I'm saying you have to track all of them forever.
-- But
-- no, no, you want to be able to look at the differences like here's a great example.
Is
when I was at a previous company,
they there was a version of a product that was released that used Ruby Bundler. OK.
And Ruby Bundler had a bug that accidentally
included all the developer dependencies in the release,
right?
So the number of dependencies doubled in one release, we didn't know it.
And then someone's like, why did your dependencies double?
And we're like, what now, how the heck do they double? Well, because
Boer normally doesn't include developer dependencies in the the tar ball,
but it had a bug and it did.
So now we had all the regular dependencies plus all the development dependencies
in the room.
So the number of dependencies doubled.
And this is where having like espo management
is a real thing because you're going to be able to look and be like, OK,
let me go back over time.
-- Holy cow. Why did the dependencies double right here this one time?
-- Sorry.
See in my mind,
the storage of the S bomb data is abstracted from
the actual manipulation and learning something from it because again,
that's going to be another set of tools that
will improve as time goes on because for example,
like I'm not gonna like,
what am I gonna look at ad file and somehow gain knowledge from that?
-- No,
-- you need tools to do this work for you. Absolutely.
And, and this is where that whole like s
a management piece comes from or
like another good example is, let's say
you've got a,
a relatively flat number of dependencies and all of a sudden you add it
to your container and now your dependency rate went up by 10 times like,
well, what did we just do?
And that actually happens.
I got a little demo I give of that where if you use the, the uh node
container,
it, first of all is full of vulnerabilities.
It has like 1000 vulnerabilities that, that's a different problem.
But it also includes like 1300 N PM packages in it,
right?
I mean,
it's one of those things. It does work. It totally works.
But you can see obviously if you use the alpine container,
you have no vulnerabilities.
And if you do no container, you have like 1100. And so it's a pretty easy demo.
I mean, it'll be a shame if they ever fix it because it,
it won't be as fun to watch.
But, you know, I mean, I mean, and,
and this is where I think you can start thinking kind of bigger picture about
what are these s bombs good for is you can start asking questions about like,
what am I doing?
What's in my software? How does it work?
You can feed them into vulnerability scanners to start getting a feel.
Now, now,
one of the other things that always comes up
is people scan their stuff for vulnerabilities and like,
oh, we have to fix them all
if you have a like no vulnerabilities in your scan
and 1000 vulnerabilities in your scan are equally bad.
Like
that's, that's how that works well, unless it's a scratch container.
But that's another story.
So anyway,
this is all just a very long and convoluted way of saying that why you need an S bomb is,
isn't there isn't one answer?
It's really about being able to take this data
and turn it into a data management problem.
And then you can start asking questions. You don't even know you have,
you know what I'm actually reminded of.
This sounds a lot like the whole intrusion detection systems back in the day.
So this is before we actually had intrusion prevention systems
and one person pointed out because I kind of asked, I'm like, well,
like this detection piece is kind of great, but like they've already broken in like,
how is this super helpful?
And he pointed out what you actually want to do
is you have your internet connection,
you have an I DS, then you have your firewall proxy scrubber or whatever machine.
Then you have another I DS
and you compare the delta between the two
and then you go to management and say we spent half a million dollars
on firewall and proxies and look it scrubbed out 95% of these attacks.
And part of it is
like, I think that's the kind of stage where we are with Ssal,
right? Now is where it's not going to be.
Well, by definition like, OK, great. You've got all these vulnerabilities. Yeah.
Now what?
Well, you have to go fix them in some way and, and at scale again,
you can't do this with humans.
It has to be
some automation
but now you at least know the scope and like the, the,
like the literal magnitude of your problem.
Is it 10, 100 1000 or 10,000?
Because those are very different problems.
Even trying to fix a lot of this with automation is a funny story because I mean,
there's things like depend
aot
in github
and if you turn on the automatic dependency fixes, all you do is
you pull up your tests like no, no, everyone turns it off, you turn it on,
everything explodes, you turn it off, you know what I mean?
And I'm not saying it'll never happen but like a a better solution.
Actually, what I see happening in a lot of we'll say well funded organizations
is
instead of letting developers just yank down like whatever container they want.
They're rolling these like golden images where
they're saying if you need like generic Linux
use this
container
and then
like any vulnerabilities found in the container image, not your problem.
Don't worry about it. We'll take care of it. And like that's
brilliant, right? Like that's really cool.
Well, and that's what it should be is abstracting. Like why is my developer
worrying about
the, the, the, the runtime environment
and
they
match it.
I don't know.
But what I'm saying is like, but they should, do, they build their own desk?
Do they run power for their computer at their desktop?
Do they build a coffee machine from scratch? No, you just
-- provide that. You outsource it.
-- That, that's a good point.
And I think run times are becoming commodities where you're not worried about,
you know, handcrafting it.
You're just like whatever, go buy a desk. I don't care.
We use Hiroko
at the CS A,
I believe it's some variant of ubuntu by default.
You don't care. Right. Exactly. Exactly.
Now, now I'll say even though you're using Heroku,
you're still running things on top of it.
And so this is where I think you also run
into this concept in Esma management where for example,
if you're rolling containers
there, there's an idea of like,
OK, so I want to look at all of the dependencies I picked up that aren't in the base
container image, right?
Like that's a valuable question to ask because now
you can throw all that stuff away and say,
what am I actually doing?
And again,
if we have a management system, we can say, OK, what is in my container,
what is in my development environment?
Why are they different? What just happened?
And like, I, I mean, another funny story I have there,
there was one time I think it was a bank showed up and was like, hey,
what's the deal with this, this Google Chrome included in your product?
And we're like,
what we don't include Google Chrome.
And they're like,
yeah, you do. It's right here. And we're like, where did this come from?
And it was a, it was a headless chromium.
And we're like, how did this even get in here?
And it turned out one of the developers built it on their workstation,
uploaded it to Amazon S3 and was like, w getting it during container build.
And I'm like,
what, like, how did this even happen?
But you know, it's one of those situations where it's like, what do we do now?
And again,
this was before s bombs existed. So we had no insight into any of this stuff.
And it was, it's just,
it makes me chuckle. Sometimes.
I remember looking at RP MS from Red Hat and I found
one that had a build host of workstation and a number.
And I'm like,
that's not a build host man.
-- Like that's not what that's supposed to be. Look,
-- man.
When I worked at Progeny and I was rolling R PM updates for stuff.
There were many a times those got filled on my computer on my desk
that was in the early knots.
That would have been 2003 probably.
But yes, it was,
I look back at all that stuff and it was, and the best part
is you'd build this stuff and, like,
there was no clean environments.
It was just like,
whatever you'd have tons of garbage installed and sometimes weird
things appeared in the RP MS and like it was,
that was just the way it worked.
Ah,
man. Oh, man.
It's a miracle. Anything worked back then.
As I remember, we spent a lot of time trying to make things work.
And it's really obvious to me in hindsight why Docker took off because, oh,
it's just you turn it on and it works like
no matter how much Janky stuff you jammed in there.
-- Sweet. Well,
-- exactly.
And I think this is not unlike just kind of the,
the story of development where it used to be like kitchen sink at all, right?
Like we don't care, make it work.
And then we started saying things like, no, no,
let's just include the dependencies we need,
let's make sure we're making things small.
Like, I mean,
if you think about like R PM packages, right, I'll pick on them.
The intent is that like every library gets its own R PM, right?
And then multiple RP MS can depend on one library.
Whereas there were, I mean, there were days back in the early days of like, so
os and stuff,
you just crammed everything and opt,
-- you know what I mean? Everything was statically linked, whatever
-- it works.
-- There's literally no other way to do it.
-- There wasn't, it was just different times.
And now I think with containers, it's kind of the same thing.
Your container is just, oh, just put it all in opt.
And now we're starting to ask questions
about, well, what's in it? What do we need in it?
Can we get rid of some of this stuff, like what's going on?
And I think this is how we start this journey.
Well, I think that's this classic thing of, you know, if I make it work, it works.
If it doesn't work, that's a clear and present problem.
-- Whereas a security problem is a kind of maybe sort of,
-- yes, I agree.
And that's another big part of the story I think is one of the
other challenges you see is so let's say I have an S bomb scanner,
let's say I'm telling developers.
All right, you need to get rid of this library. I didn't tell them
to necessarily fix the problem or, or whatever I told them, make this,
not show up on the SP
scan.
And those are two very different things, right?
And so I think that's one of the other challenges we need to
be mindful of is if you push too hard in your developers,
like they're really smart,
they know ways to trick your tools and the
intent is you don't want them tricking tools,
you want everyone kind of working together for a mutual good.
And that's always one of my fears is like
you say, oh, you can't use this dependency.
Well, I'll just copy and paste this into my tool.
It works good job for me.
Yeah.
Yep. Yep.
So, I,
I think the biggest thing though is we are
getting to the point of tooling becoming more standard.
Like it still blows my mind that there are people not using version control.
I don't think there's very many people not doing that anymore. Are there? No.
-- But the fact that there are any not using it is,
-- I mean, whatever,
there's always gonna be people like that.
I mean, you look at anything, Kurt, there's people who, who don't
-- adapt technology.
-- There is nobody in Edmonton using a horse to deliver stuff.
Are you sure
-- it's all trucks and cars?
-- Are you sure
in Edmonton?
I think this sounds like an opportunity for someone
to create a horse delivery service in Edmonton.
The only horses in use in Edmonton for moving
stuff around are at Christmas time for the slave
uh over on Candy Cane Lane and down by Fort Edmonton Park.
-- I mean,
-- I, I don't think, I don't think version control is quite as far into the,
the current.
Uh how do I say that, you know, like horses were a thing 100 years ago.
We're only like 20 years diversion control in a lot of cases. So I, I think
most people are doing it. If you're not, you should start.
But that one's a little different than using horses to deliver things, I think.
Well, what I'm trying to say is we're,
we're finally at the point where it's possible the tools exist.
The C I CD boiled pipelines exist, you know, as a server.
So like there's s bomb as a service and there should be right?
Like why should I have to build and buy all this tooling and care and feed for it
when? Well,
you know, I'm reminded of virus total. I'm not going to download and install.
What is it like a 60 or 80 virus scanners?
No,
I'm just going to throw this file literally
into Virus total.com and see what happened.
Well, there, there isn't s
bomb as a service yet. I think
there are where
literally s
bomb as a service.
-- There's a whole bunch.
-- What does that even mean?
You give them a file and they give you an S
-- bomb? Well,
-- that's not s
bomb as a service.
That's boring.
-- Well, my point is like,
-- where, where are you finding this? I typed this into Google.
There's like nothing here,
whatever. You're full of crap
so well, but the point is basically, it's like the software signing, right?
I don't wanna make every single open source dev learn how to and do s bomb properly.
No, I absolutely, absolutely not. And this is actually um
so there's II I can put some links in the show notes but like there are, I mean,
Acor makes one, we we have a, a github
action that every time you do it build, it spits out in sp
and it puts it in the repo, right?
Like there's a lot of tooling that does a lot
of this stuff and I think you're absolutely right.
We shouldn't expect any developers to be SBO
experts. This has to be comically easy to use.
You know, what we stopped doing is we stop making developers set up git servers.
-- Well, yeah, because that sucks.
-- And so does ES bomb.
-- So does everything.
-- No, I agree. I agree completely.
And that's, this is where I think like there's,
I, I think SBO
has value
SBA
is gonna be wanted, especially by security teams. It does other stuff.
But you know what I mean?
And I think this is one of those instances
where there's a ton of opportunity in this space
to kind of get a lot of this, right?
And not only that, I think,
I think having the ability to know what's in your software is
it, it is becoming more and more important. And I think log for J
was like the poster child to push all of this down the hill
-- and I think the ball is starting to roll down for
-- sure.
I'm just thinking of all those people that had to spend
all this time trying to prove a negative of like,
no, we don't have log for J or, or if we do have log for J we actually updated it or,
you know,
and just the amount of time spent on that.
Whereas
if you have
one pooling it's like click
here you go.
-- Yeah,
-- I mean, I mean, so Acor
has a customer
that
all of their infrastructure, like one of their,
they have a hard rule of it has to go through Anchor's
product.
And so when log for J happened, they literally went to the search box,
They basically typed in log for J.
They're like, all right here it is, go fix your stuff and like that was it,
right? Versus
oh, we have to find all our computers and then we have to scan them all.
And then we have to figure out which ones have vulnerable versions,
then we'd figure out how to fix a ver, you know what I mean?
I know people that are still working on it like
it's, it's a big job. And I, and I think as we use more and more open source,
as we continue to turn infrastructure into a commodity, like this is the tooling.
We need
to make sure we understand what's going on.
-- Is this not the whole point of it is to automate stuff.
-- I mean, it's supposed to be
right. My
thing of it was the whole point is we were supposed to automate stuff with computers
and then on a, that's on a technical level and on like sort of a business,
financial level
and
sort of specialized and outsource stuff because, like,
I don't want to run a global content delivery network.
-- I would much rather pay cloud floor 20 bucks a month.
-- Yeah. Absolutely. Absolutely.
All right. We should call this one. I love that.
I have all these notes and all these things that we wanted to talk about and, like,
I've checked two of them off.
I think it's,
it is part of the pleasure of doing this show.
I think it's knowing we get completely off track and it's lovely.
But anyway, it's, yeah, I, I guess kind of in summary, I think
this is one of those situations where I think S bombs are here.
I think people on both sides, there's people who are super pro S bomb,
people who are super anti
S bomb, like it's somewhere in the middle, right?
Like be mindful of who you're listening to understand what's going on.
It. It's, it's like any product, right?
Anytime there's any new product, you have to kind of ask some questions. It's
like, what's the angle here? What are they getting out of it because
there's people on each side, right.
-- So anyway,
-- well,
I think part of it too is there's just there's a lack of maturity because for example,
while we were talking earlier,
I was actually trying to find.
So for example,
cloud computing has like the classical mist
definition of cloud computing is like rapidly
scalable multi-tenant blah blah blah blah blah
and I was looking for such a definition of sm and I couldn't find one.
I'd be shocked if there is one. I think it's way too new still.
So. Anyway.
All right, cool. I'm calling it. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up the show. Not easy.
Pound Os Ss Podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody and actually Squirrels are real.
Don't worry, I'm not insane.
Of course.
Anyway. Bye bye.