We were watching some cookie shows and the way
they say some of the words that are French.
If you would like someday, I will take a map of the state of Wisconsin
and I will walk you through
how we pronounce the French names
and you will probably be weeping less than five minutes into that conversation.
The Midwest took it to the next level.
Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself. Kurt
Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime. Josh Bresser.
Yeah. Back to Thought Crime.
Yeah.
Well, it's, it's interesting because I've, I've actually, um, well, the,
the show topic today is video games and cheating
to some degree and I've also been working on
cheating in general because we're preparing for the release
of the new CCS KV five stuff in summer.
And of course, that means a new exam.
Oh, right.
Well, I mean, at this point, every technical exam on the planet has like,
exam question dumps and like
cheating because
people want to get these certifications and not
study.
No, that's it like that, that, that's it. That's human nature.
Like humans have been cheating literally their whole lives. For the most part.
I mean, there's cases of small Children cheating on tests. Yeah.
Well, and I get it like, II, I am blessed in that. I am really good at multiple choice.
Like I'm,
I have really good
and I'm just like, no, I can
like II,
I did my M CS E plus internet back in the day by
reading those little red exam prep books and I would read it twice
and then I'd go write the exam
and I had a sort of enough practical knowledge around networking and windows,
especially that I could just grind.
I ground through like eight or nine exams in a period of like +23 months.
And I met people that were also taking those exams and
had paid like $20,000 for the boot camps to take them.
And I'm just like, whoa, ouch. Like, can't you just read this book and write
it? Apparently not. Anyway,
I've been thinking about cheating a lot and like, what can we do to well,
incentivize good behavior, disincentivize bad behavior,
make it harder for the cheaters, kind of punish them.
And this came across hacker news. It's the guy's name. Le oh, Liam Neeson.
No, Liam Neeson's arm. Sorry, Liam Neeson's arm.
Right.
I don't know if it's the left or right one. It doesn't matter. Some user on hacker news
could be an A I
anyways. He, he made a searchable public database of cheaters and video games.
Which I find kind of interesting sort of, it has two pages of cheaters. So
it's called the Toxic Gaming Database.
It calls itself a community driven public database
of toxic gamers based on reported evidence.
And I went to it and I browsed many of the
reports. I don't call these things
and
they're fascinating, I think.
And this is something I've actually been talking about
in the world of video games for a long time.
So actually let me before I explain
how to find cheat, the, the right way to find cheaters in video games,
what is being done today? Because not everyone understands what's happened.
Like if you don't play video games,
this is probably a foreign and bizarre world to you.
We exist now in a place where a lot of video games install these, like basic, they,
their, their root kits.
Yeah,
they install these like kernel level root kits on your system
to supposedly detect cheating even though all of the cheating apps
can get around them because that's like the job of the
cheating app or you just buy a cheating monitor now.
Right? No,
because on the last show, but where the monitor will flake you alerts. And
also what's fascinating to me is too,
is like there's so much different kinds of cheating in ways of
like one of my favorite things is there are some games,
Starcraft is a great example in Starcraft.
If you actually have proper balanced matchmaking, then your win rate should be 50%.
Right. Right. Right. It's just that simple.
Well, but ok, but let's focus on,
on the toxic gaming database because this is very what Team Fortress Two,
I think the game is right?
That it's focused, it's done.
It's first person shooter oriented, right? First person shooter.
And so basically in the first person shooter world,
what you often run into is people get these things called aim bots.
And the idea behind an aim bot
is you don't have to aim, right?
A computer program, a robot will just say aims for you and you never miss
and you usually have the headshot, which is like the Insta kill and all that stuff.
Right?
Well,
and then also the sees through walls thing is
the other classic side of this where you can see
well,
where the players are when you shouldn't know where they are through the fog of war.
So fun fact about that.
Actually, I,
I think it was Quake two was the
first multiplayer kind of very competitive online thing.
And
back in the day,
the server would send like the location of every player to every client.
And then people figured out, well, if we just turn all the walls invisible, we can see
where everyone else is in the whole game.
And now what happens is when you play a lot of these games,
the server will only send you what you need to know, for this specific reason,
the challenge is they also have to send you with the data a little bit.
Like if you're coming around the corner,
it has to show you to some degree
or
you're in the bushes or, and there's, if you can see someone,
your computer knows where they are. And like, that's what an aim bot
will use, right.
The aim bot will be like, oh, there's a, another player at this location,
I'm going to point the gun at exactly their head
and then we're going to fire a bunch of bullets.
And what's funny to me is, uh, a friend back and this is way back in the day. So
over 20 years ago,
they were trying to build a robot with a computer vision system to like
drive around the room and they could not get any of the stuff working.
So they actually built the bot
in Doom and had it doing like vision recognition in Doom. That's a good idea
and
around and so like to put it bluntly, people have been doing this kind of thing
legitimately. And otherwise for over 20 years, like it's a mature industry now.
It should also be pointed out
that there are other anti
cheating focused things we'll say like, uh, one of my favorites is Genshin Impact,
which is that horrible game my kids play that I would,
I love to play because it looks fantastic, but it's like a security nightmare.
From the perspective of what everything it does to your system.
And, and anyway, in that game there,
it's one of those like use real money to buy fake money
to then buy gems and then gems buy like trolls or whatever,
you know.
And it's like the, the, the crazy pyramid scheme to turn real money into
fake things in the video game,
which of course is funny because my kids have no problem with this.
And I'm like, you're spending real money to buy fake money. This is,
did you ever buy magic? The gathering cards?
Don't,
I'm not answering that question.
I
have boxes and boxes of them.
They're probably worth a fortune because I have the really old ones like from
way back in the day.
So obviously these games that let you turn real money into fake money,
they have a vested interest also because
they don't want people cheating the system,
right?
They don't you to change your luck and get better items
or know how to kill all the enemies faster or whatever.
Because then
in many of the games, if you grind for hundreds of hours,
it equals like four cents worth of money or whatever.
And they don't, they don't want anyone to do that, right?
So there's that angle as well.
Now, now we'll assume that that explanation was, was good enough. So
the thing this toxic game database does that I I
truly appreciate is you click a view toxicity report.
And at the bottom of the report, there's a button that says view evidence.
And when you look at this evidence,
there's a website called Leady,
which apparently is
some sort of statistic tracking app for people who play.
I, I assume Team Fortress Two, maybe more games. I have no idea.
I didn't dig around that much. But
the thing is,
it shows you like the aim percentage of these people have like,
I just clicked a random one.
It says 93% aim percentage. Like no human can do that, right. This one is 97%
like
humans are not doing that.
And then you look at like these other stats and some of the
other stats are terrible and it's like this is clearly a robot.
Well, that's one of my favorite things is like,
I watch a lot of rust because I find Rust very intriguing
and the game Rust
rust, the one where you get dumped on the beach like naked and you have to like,
beat people to death with rocks and whatever,
build an AK-47 of shovels.
But what's fascinating to me is like many games.
There's like the pro streamers who have, you know, over 10,000 hours in game.
And that's why I don't actually play the game because you play the
game and I have my like five or 10 hours and I,
I get murdered by somebody who probably has like thousands or hundreds of hours.
So it's no fun. But these 10,000 hour players
can consistently
not just beach cheaters but, like,
just
school them, like, totally trash them
because here's the reality you and I could be dumped into rust.
We could have all the cheats, all the aim bots,
all the seeing people in the dark and the behind the rocks and stuff.
And we'd still suck because we don't have, like, the technique.
We don't have the, you know,
I think rust is a different sort of game though. Right.
It's, it's very strategic.
Yes. And that's part of it.
What I find so fast about this is, it's, it's kind of past a first person shooter.
Like, there's obviously first person shooter elements to it. Like
you're a person who shoots other people,
but
you have
build a gun out of like coconuts.
And also, like,
there's a lot of strategic stuff you can do with base
design or with how you attack bases and all that.
And so what's really fascinating to me though is, like,
fundamentally a lot of cheaters are still
terrible
or whatever it is. They're cheating on.
Like, we've like,
I've seen that where people writing these technical exams
and they cheat at them and they still fail.
And I'm like,
you, you cheat.
How did you fail? I mean, come on. It's like the 11 job you had here,
like, cheat.
Yes.
And I get that there's a lot of different reasons for cheating.
You know, some people want to just, well, if there's money involved I get it.
You know, if there's a certification vault, I get it, if it's a game, you know, it's
part of me wants to cheat at some of these games just because I'm so bad at them.
Like, it was just to be honest,
like, I feel like, you know, Steam should be like, oh, you're AAA, late forties male,
You're allowed to cheat a bit because you suck. Yeah, I, I agree with that. I,
there's a penny arcade comic that has something like that.
That's like, you know, where's the game for, like, responsible
adults or Children or something? I got, like, 2.5 hours a week
getting into, like, weird chunks of time.
Like this is why I play Factorio with the bugs off. Right.
Because I can't even be bothered to cheat and get the weapons to kill the bugs.
I just wait, you can turn the bugs off. I've never done that. That would be lovely.
Yeah, it's just, it's a relaxing Builder game.
Yeah, that's what I want. I don't want those stupid bugs. They kill me every time.
I need to look at that.
Now it's, it's a setting like, it's, you can turn cliffs on and off.
I turn cliffs off because clips are just
look at. Ok.
So
I keep everything default. Kurt, I'm too lazy to go look in the settings.
But now I will and I'll turn the bugs up anyway. Ok.
I want to bring us back to the topic because I think this is important.
So, the point is like this, this website, the, the toxic, the gaming herd thing.
Right.
This is, well, these people are probably bizarre and they, you're gonna end up with,
like, people reporting just people who beat them legitimately and things.
Well,
and actually that's a fun thing because a lot
of times these 10,000 hour players get reported as cheaters
who they're just thumping on because they're just like 200 hours, 10,000 hours.
I'm sorry.
No, there's, it's like Mike Tyson versus a kindergartner that's
solvable because the
whoever is writing the cheat bot
or whatever can look and be like this person has played 10,000 hours,
of course, everyone's going to think they're cheating,
they know the server admins in most cases, right. So, like, sure report me anyway.
The point is this sort of, of statistical analysis
is really the key to detecting cheaters. And this is true of like
all of these games because even the ones that have these insane root kits,
you can't,
you can't cheat statistics, right?
It's just like, it's the unfortunate reality of math
is
if you are cheating,
you're going to have statistics that fall outside of the expected ranges.
Right?
Also mean that for somebody to appear normal, they'd have to, I don't know, like,
waste a lot of time in game, like, if you wanted to grind and cheat at grinding,
you'd also have to spend a lot of time not cheating and not grinding.
And so,
right. I mean, I guess you'd have to have a computer attached for 24 7 kind of playing.
And I, like it goes back to World War Two where, you know,
the allies had cracked the enigma code and the purple code for the Japanese
And they had to find ways to use this information without showing that,
that they had cracked all the codes. So they, that's
right.
Oh, we sent out some spotter planes. They just happened to see the, you know,
that we need to see. Oh, look at that. Lucky us.
Yeah. So, actually there's a movie called The Imitation Game
where, uh,
what Benedict Cumberbatch plays Alan Turing and it's actually pretty good.
I've read
many historical, we'll say
retellings of like this
Alan Turing whole whole universe and I'm sure most of it it's all hearsay, right.
So you can't, like, count on any sort of real historical record.
But anyway, the Imitation Game does a pretty good job there.
It takes some liberties here and there.
But that is one of the things they bring up is the fact that
they can't tell people they know what's going to happen
because the Germans will figure out they've cracked enigma,
which would obviously be much worse
than,
you know, letting the course of war happen, which is like a, a mind
boggling problem to, to think about.
Well, I've,
I've worked with and for military people and they have that mentality of like,
we have to keep our sources secret and like,
the one guy wouldn't even let me say echelon on the phone and I'm like, echelon,
he's like, don't say that word and I'm like, good God, it's in books
now. Like, come on.
So for those of you that don't know echelon was the NSA program to monitor
all
the faxes and phone calls in America. But no, that was, that, that wasn't happening.
Remember everyone told us we were crazy.
It was
anyway. Well, considering their budget, like,
what did people think they were doing with it?
Oh, really? Right. Like,
I
know
this
isn't like Canada where you look at our
budget for our security services and it's like,
yeah, they're probably not that harmful
compared to, you know, what the US spends.
Right.
Yeah. Anyway, so you're right though. You can't.
Like my favorite thing is financial analysis where
the minute people start committing financial fraud,
they generally start making up numbers
and there's patterns in there
how often numbers appear, how often numbers start, you know,
with the number one versus not the number one, what you've just described.
Kurt is called Benford's Law.
That's the way this, this person, it was a mathematician.
And funny enough that the way they found
out that numbers follow certain patterns is they were
back in the day when you needed to calculate logarithms.
University libraries had books of logarithms
and,
and Benford apparently recognized that the, basically the, the,
the number one pages section book,
I don't know exactly how it was split up was more tattered than the rest.
So he's like, people are obviously looking here more often than
other places.
And then they started doing like statistical
analysis on just how often integers appear.
And yeah,
there's like a pattern to it and one appears
way more often than any other number does.
And yes, the IRS and other tax agencies are using that
to figure out because yes,
if I'm a human and I just like make up numbers and I type them in,
they're not going to follow Benford's law.
They're gonna follow like squishy meat brain law
which has no pattern to it.
It's really,
yeah, I, I can't help but think maybe this like,
because one thing I've consistently seen is where
people talk about games need a replay system.
So you can like, look at what happened,
do the instant replay and see if cheating happened or
not because a lot of cheating is often in hindsight,
very obvious,
you know, like the guy
literally pops around the corner and just happens to be
aiming at the guy's head when he pulls the trigger,
you know,
and it's like less than human reaction time.
Right. Right. But again,
the, the owner of the game can do this if they want to.
Instead they have opted to install these invasive root kits that do,
who knows what on your system?
Because apparently that's easier than hiring a statistician. I, I don't know.
I, well, and I, I do get the idea of prevention rather than
after the fact because,
oh, you just, you just reminded me. Ok. So I watched
the, I think it was the latest John Oliver show last week tonight,
which was on Medicare or Medicaid, Medicaid in the United States.
And one of the things they talked about was Medicaid fraud
in one of the States. I forget which one it was now,
but they were talking about how there was this fraud
task force
that had found like $900,000 worth of Medicaid fraud
and it only cost $6.5 million to run the task force.
Well, that's like the, uh, hang on a second. Let me find the number of New York City.
Oh, the subway story.
Yeah. Where they,
they spent millions of dollars to prevent
more than
a million worth of subway free riders or whatever
anyways.
Yeah, I, well, we, like, we constantly see that with a lot of these things, like,
but, I mean, but video games are a little bit
different
in that. I don't think they are. I don't think they are at all.
I think this is the very typical case of as human beings, we want
to like, we want to live in a just society. It's like it's built into us.
We want it so bad.
And so we are willing to do ridiculous things.
If we think the result is justice when the reality is reacting
to various events, like banning cheaters after they cheat
is easier, cheaper and more effective than trying to stop them before the case.
Which is what we do now in many instances. But
if the game has already been ruined, like,
but it's not ruined as long as you're catching them in a timely manner.
You don't wait until half the game is cheaters and then start banning people.
You start banning people on like day five
because now you have enough statistical evidence.
I don't know, I just, I don't play enough video games.
Like I kind of gave up on video games because
between cheating and between just not being good at them.
They're not, they're not fun anymore. I just don't play online because I'm so bad.
But I can play me some Mario. Oh,
speaking of which, I'm going to put a link in the show notes.
So Kurt sent me a video, a four hour long video but invisible
wall walls of Mario 64 don't say I don't give you nice things.
I totally watched it all four hours. It was amazing.
It was the most amazing video I've seen in a long
time and I don't expect anyone else to watch it.
But holy cow, like the amount of research
that was put into this video is mind boggling.
And I told Kurt before we hit record as well, like,
I've started writing a conference talk basically titled like
The Speed Runners Are the, the Best hackers alive today.
Because if you look at like what people like this guy did with video games, the,
the things they're figuring out are,
they blows your mind. It's amazing. You know what?
This guy has 217,000 subscribers on youtube.
The video has 46,000 up votes and three quarters of a million
or how many views does this video have? It doesn't say
anyways, it's got a lot of views.
It's got 5000 plus comments.
Most videos don't get 5000 views, let alone comments.
I don't look at the comments ever on youtube, ever ever.
But
yeah, like the video is fantastic. Four hours, four hours.
Like he shows every invisible wall in Mario 64 every one of them.
It's amazing.
What's always fascinating to me is sort of like this
reverse engineering of these old video games because like,
you see this with physical things too where, you know, people buy an old
tool or an old car
and like, take it apart and like here's how this works. It's very clever.
It does this, like one of my favorite things is, you know, the VW beetle
to essentially prevent they did something
clever with the engineering to prevent the
engine from getting too hot in one spot by shortening something or whatever.
And
like just these clever engineering hacks that after the
fact when you take it apart and you're like,
oh, ok, cool.
Car people who have been doing that literally forever.
It's what car people do, they, they take their cars apart and they do stuff to them.
Now, you just reminded me as well.
It's in the show notes so well in, in the,
we'll say the Show Notes curtain I have before we publish,
I don't know those called Show Notes, whatever.
Anyway, it's in a github
issue.
There's another story about video game related, I dumped into this called Pre Tendo
and this has an ethical aspect to it that I think will be very interesting and I,
I don't want it.
It's not exciting enough I think to cover like a whole show. But
so
Nintendo, actually,
there's been a lot more I've noticed on L TT and a couple of other places.
There's been a lot of discussion the last month or two about the shutting
down of these video game services and like people paid money for that game and
that would be available.
Yes, let me explain that.
So Nintendo shut down the servers behind the Wii U and the Nintendo three Ds.
They're like 12 years old,
which is longer than most other companies run this stuff in Fairness.
My original Nintendo wii
still works great.
Well. Yeah, it still works great because it, it doesn't need a server.
They shut this down. Now.
There are these people that created this, this application?
Well, they're running a network called Pretend.
Oh, right. Like pretend. Oh,
Nintendo wordplay. I
think we
got it.
Look, I don't assume anything. All right. I'm not the fastest person in the world.
So funny enough. My, my keyboard, uh the Z key broke
and
I, I run vi a lot. I'm blaming V I,
how long did it take you to notice the Z key broke?
And I, I made a little joke on Mastodon and uh uh a fellow I know named Marius is like,
oh, what about the X key?
And I'm like,
I don't get
it.
He's like XZ, I'm like, oh, that's clever.
Well done, sir. Like, I'm not smart enough to get your joke.
I don't assume anything anyway. So pretend
they found a security vulnerability
in the, the way Nintendo was parsing.
I, I think it was um signatures on certificates. Ok. I'm just gonna pause it.
There is a security vulnerability in every piece of
software ever that did something involving parsing of data,
a
certificate specifically, especially certificates because
I dare
to go
download and
here's the
thing,
they found it and they sat on it for like a year waiting for Nintendo to end
of life, their servers and shut them down
and then
announced the security vulnerability and they used
it to create basically fake Nintendo servers
that you can then have your Wii U and three Ds connect to.
I don't know if the three Ds for sure, but I know the Wii U can
anyway connect to
and then basically pretend it's Nintendo and you can do things.
And so your wii U is kind of still functional online because of this.
Now, here's a question.
Is it unethical to sit on a security vulnerability for a year?
No, I, no, because like I would say whoever finds security vulnerability,
there are obviously very unethical things to do with it,
like using it to hurt people.
Like if you find a security vulnerability
in a medical device and use it to kill people through their pacemaker,
I think we could agree that's probably unethical
and conversely, there's ethical things to do with it,
like depending on the kind of software and what it is, you know,
you go to the vendor and say, hey, I found this flaw, can we please fix it, blah, blah,
blah.
But I would actually flip that on his head and say,
is it ethical for Nintendo to turn those servers off?
And I would point out, ok, first of all, 12 years is not a long time.
What's interesting to me is in Europe and in general,
a lifetime warranty is actually 25 years.
That's
really,
yeah,
that's generally what that actually means
a fun fact in Canada outside of cemeteries.
It is illegal to sell a lifetime membership
like it. That's just, that, that, that, that's illegal because we all know
that, that's just not a real thing like the company
fold or be like, oh ha ha. We changed our mind it.
How you're gonna cost money every month. Now,
there's tons of stories about that. Right.
Where someone bought a lifetime membership to a thing
and then it's taken away from them eventually.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
So anyway, so first of all, I would say, I'm
kind of angry that these companies don't state how long this will work for.
Because for example,
if Nintendo said here's this Nintendo wii it really benefits from these
online services and works better and we'll run them for 12 years
and they were upfront about it
then, OK,
assuming they kept their word and run it for 12 years if they had to pronounce this.
And,
but there's no like there's no transparency, there's no
like I paid for this thing and now I'm at Nintendo's whim.
I mean, you're already at their whim, right?
If, if you do something that like let me give you an example.
I have a 3d si hacked my three Ds. So I could play funny enough.
So I could play Mario 64 on my three Ds
because
I think we talked about this years ago now where they decom
pled Mario 64 source code
and then someone recompiled it.
So it ran in full screen and like very well on the three Ds
hack. My 3d has literally delayed this one thing. Now,
once it was hacked,
I never connected it to the internet again
because I knew like, if I and here's the thing, let's say I connected to Nintendo,
Nintendo was like, you hacked your three Ds.
We're banning your account.
I would lose all my switch games,
all my,
you know what I mean? You're already at their mercy here.
And I think maybe we need some consumer protection laws
here is that we as consumers are getting kind of
the short
of the stick here. And so when I see something like pretender,
I 100% support that.
And I actually think if anything they are doing the
ethical thing and I'll point something out e waste.
They are preventing all that stuff from becoming e waste
for you. Wonder how much old video game stuff is worth Kurt. It's,
it's not e waste on many levels. They're doing a service. I think you're right.
I don't want to get to.
We've already went way too deep into the whole ethical, how long
tech lasts and all that stuff. But
I, I, so for what it's worth, I agree with you.
I think what pre tendo did by sitting on a security vulnerability and it's
even like it's icing on the cake just seeing what they've done with it.
I uh for honestly I really don't have a problem with it. I really say simple question.
Did what they do make the world a better or worse place
for the same.
It depends who you ask.
Nintendo's lawyers will assure you that the world is a much worse place.
And, and my honest question, there would be, how, like,
are they losing it on sales of Nintendo we use,
have you read any of the stories about Nintendo's lawyers?
Oh, yeah, they're maniacs.
But my point is like, this is really a case where you, you can't make piracy,
sales claims you can't.
Like this is somebody using something they already paid for
properly. I
know, but I'm sure there's some C FAA violation or something buried in there.
So anyway.
All right. All right. We've covered quite the gamut of topics today, haven't we?
We started at,
and we're ending on Nintendo,
which is exciting. We got some Mario 64 thrown in for fun.
Well, I would say sometimes cheating is good and makes the world a better place.
Like one of my favorite things.
And this is one of the reasons I really despise those root kits.
Some people need to cheat at video games because they
need a system of devices or software because they have disabilities
and they can't play the game way.
And so there are people that have, you know, said like, hey,
my um like my foot mouse pad thing doesn't work anymore or my
Oh,
perfect example,
like screen readers are getting like messed up all the time by all this BS.
Like we don't want to let you cut and paste the screen or we don't want to, you know,
blah, blah, blah, right?
Where we want to show you the content but like not let you somehow
copy it. And I'm like,
but it has to go to my computer to show it to me,
you know.
So
I think
anyway, anyway,
II, I also think from the angle of cheating
when you are like speed run,
especially when they're, they're exploiting bugs and games basically, like,
it's basically cheating and it's epic. Are there any speed runs for like
multiplayer online games?
Like, is there a speed run thing for like, say, well for say of
rust to get up for rocket? Like, is there a thing for that?
There probably are there speed run for every game
and the online ones where they play together
are usually not heavy on exploiting bugs.
They usually just play really well
because obviously these online services tend not to let bugs exist.
I mean, so like one of the things that happens, it's like, I'll pick on uh the,
the new legend is Zelda game, Tears of the Kingdom.
When it came out, everyone's like, oh, the speed run will never be under an hour.
It's like 25 minutes an hour or something. Of course,
I remember obviously, like humans can't run faster than 44 minute mile.
It's physically impossible.
That right. Anyway,
so the thing is though,
in, in like tears of the Kingdom,
they, they specifically will buy cartridge j
least day because they want like the 1.0 Cart
because that usually has the most bugs.
Whereas when you play online games,
you have to keep upgrading to the
latest version and they're fixing bugs constantly.
So you just, you can't rely on them like you can in, in console titles looking at this.
Uh, so Blazed Ashley is a big rust streamer.
He's got a 57 minute rust speed run.
So, yeah,
it's amazing. I mean, some of these people, it's ridiculous.
This is why I don't play that game because like
that guy can basically finish Rust and 57 minutes.
We need a rush server for like old people without any free time.
Oh, I found some. They do exist.
Yeah,
they're actually
kind of soothing.
I went to one and it was like raining and it was the sound,
the sound of the rain and rust is actually one of
the most pleasant things I've ever experienced in a video.
I don't know if I've ever had it rain on me.
I, I played it for like an hour and I kept dying and I'm like, I'm done.
I give up, I'm never playing again
anyway. All right, man. I think we should call this one.
Here's the thought, maybe what we need
is
you can buy skins
but you also have to like prove that you're
like like an older person or you have Children
to get this skin and, and it would also have like armor like properties
and no, but think about it, people would pay for that.
Uh Kurt, the young people would seek out and they would hunt us like animals.
We
would be their trophy.
I shot 30 Boomers today. They would wear our skins
and
I
get
it.
I get it. I totally get it.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you all for listening.
Go to open social security podcast.com. Hit up the show, not Su
Podos
podcast. Hashtag I
Mastodon, Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.