Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast
-- with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime. Josh Pressers.
-- Just crime.
Not thought crime anymore.
Yeah, I'm tired of thinking about crime. We're doing it.
That's fair.
So my smashed thumb saga continues. It took
an unexpected twist. So I'm building
that.
No, I didn't. I actually haven't smashed it. I actually, ok, so
we recorded the podcast and I talked about smashing my
thumb and then I smashed it that night again,
which was
in the same way.
Like I think I smashed it on the, like the frame of the workbench at a place.
I couldn't really see it while I was like, wrenching the clamp but whatever,
whatever.
So then
-- like
-- one of those, your hands in an awkward dark spot.
Yeah, I think, I don't know for sure though,
-- but it still hurts. But anyway,
-- ok.
Have you heard the word proprioception?
I have no idea what that means.
It's the,
it's one of the senses your body has and it essentially
is the sense of knowing where your body parts are.
Ok?
So, like you don't walk into door frames and stuff,
do you I'm just beginning to wonder maybe if this is your issue,
you just don't know where your hand or thumb is.
-- I generally have never had this problem.
-- Can you close your eyes and touch your nose?
Ok.
I, I don't think, I don't know. I don't know.
Anyway, anyway, I smashed it again, which really hurt and it bled like everywhere.
It was terrible. But then, but then, so I get my blanket rack built.
And for those of you who don't know,
this is in reference to something from the last episode,
uh, I, I get my blanket rack built and I'm, I start staining it
and, uh,
I forgot to open the window in the, in the garage.
I was like high as a kite when I figured it out,
man.
Holy
cow.
I
like two houses ago. We refinished the wood floors
and so I cranked up the vent, the furnace and everything, like opened up the windows.
I could, but, you know, it was anyways and I slept there overnight and wow,
don't do that. Oh, man. Yeah,
I
-- don't, yeah, folks, solvents are real. Don't,
-- don't do that.
So, anyway, and, and I guess, thank goodness I've actually been in this,
I did a similar thing, refinishing floors where I figured out what was going on,
like years and years ago.
So as soon as like everything started buzzing and, and the world was getting hazy,
I'm like, oh, crap.
I didn't open the window. Like I knew exactly what was happening immediately.
-- But it was like,
-- well,
it reminds me of that really scary story on Reddit where this guy is like, is my,
is my landlord pranking me or something?
There's this guy leaving weird notes and it turns
out he had like a carbon monoxide leak.
Oh,
interesting.
I
remember that's
don't,
don't only change the batteries in your fire alarms
every whatever day of the year it is.
Make sure you have a working carbon monoxide detector.
Seriously. Actually, it was really funny when I got,
when I got my,
I thought
I own an old house.
I had to get it rewired when I bought it and I
had them install like the magic smoke alarms that are all networked together
and I have way more carbon monoxide detectors that are, are, are legally required.
And the electrician said, you know, you don't need these. I'm like, yeah, I do.
You're putting them in
because
I'm why not? Right. Like, yes, it's, I've maybe spent 100 extra bucks.
-- They are expensive but they're not that expensive.
-- It's better than dead. I mean,
-- yeah. 00, yeah, absolutely.
-- So, actually I'll put a link in the show notes.
A guy I really like,
called C GP Gray and he makes youtube videos and his videos are phenomenal and he,
he kind of did a video about like the pandemic and everything and,
and shutting down and what that means.
And he had a really interesting way.
Think about it where basically
if you kind of rank the, the
pros and cons of things like dead is minus infinity. Right. So,
and I never really thought of it that way. But, like, that's totally true.
Like, yes, carbon monoxide detectors are more expensive than smoke alarms.
But being dead is the worst of all. So,
I mean,
it,
yeah. Right. Exactly. So, anyway, anyway, all right, we should.
I, I don't know if I'd say we're going to get happier but
want us to talk about, well, we're going to start our conversation.
Well, it's a similar thing.
Right, because we've, we're now seeing,
we have to tell people what we're talking about first.
All these parts of the it industry,
it's like they spend time and effort ignoring the lessons of the past.
Yeah, I think that's part of it and
there's no way to put it nicely.
I mean,
so the term I did a lot of thinking about this and I
wrote a blog post which I'll put a link in the show.
That's all.
So, which we're going to recycle a bunch of the content. So I won't bore you with it.
But I, I'm, I'm calling it security signaling
where there's all this stuff people do or don't do that. It's kind of like
if you read between the lines,
you can actually tell a great deal about what's happening.
This is exactly why, like 10 years ago,
when I became the uh it admin for the cloud screen lines,
why I forced all of our web properties onto
HTTP S
and
also started doing the HSTS headers and most importantly, the HSTS whitelist.
So like it is actually hard coded in your browser though,
when you go to cre.org or the clouds security lines.org,
you have to go to HTTP S your browser will not
allow you to go to HTTP like it will change it.
And that was not normal when you did that. I mean, it's perfectly normal now.
-- Well, I
-- mean,
remember those articles from like the BBC or
from these other major sites where they like,
you know, we've,
we've done this transition to HTTP S and it took us a year and here's what we learned,
you know,
because they had like tons of content and assets
from third parties and ad networks and mixed content and
just, you know, it was a nontrivial thing for major sites to do.
And, and of course, yeah. Now it's generally, I would say 95%
because for one simple reason,
-- Google search engine optimization,
-- I bet it's higher than 95%. Even now.
-- There's still a ton of old sites.
-- The web browsers will mark a site as insecure.
-- Now, if it's only using HTTP
-- oh, and they scream when you fill out a form as
they should,
right. I Yeah, absolutely.
So, it's interesting to me to see Well, you know,
Slack being sort of the current you tell the Slack story.
OK. So
I would,
I would say the story is indirect where basically what
happened was Slack has a public bug bounty which is
a marvelous signal, right? Very good.
Excellent.
They want to play nice with the community and they probably won't sue them.
But then
there was an R ce remote code execution flaw reported in the Slack desktop client.
And now this flaw needed some human interaction.
Not well, but it needed normal human interaction
in the sense of like no offense,
but somebody posts a document into the channel and I click on it to look at it, right.
Which I which I always do. Right.
That's like, that's like blaming people for clicking on links and email.
-- Yes,
-- I agree.
-- What else do you do with the links in email?
-- Yeah, absolutely.
This is a really good point and this is a topic maybe for another day.
But anyway, OK, so basically remote code execution,
somebody reports it via their bug bounty.
And then we say it wasn't handled particularly well.
-- I would say if
-- you read it,
they were talking about holding off on all of their disclosures until August.
I
suspect maybe it had to do something with their
-- uh their IP O or something.
-- I don't know. And it doesn't matter.
But then
the worst part of this though I think is the bounty they gave out was $1750.
-- That's a joke for
-- an R ce,
well, an R ce in an application used by
tens of millions of people for, to put a bluntly real work.
-- No,
-- let's not even call it that, let's call it. It is critical infrastructure today.
That's what we need to call it.
That is an embarrassingly low number.
And that sends a, we'll say
opposite signal
about a bug bounty.
Yes.
And so what I,
what I did actually is I started to write this blog post where I was basically just
looking to kind of poke them in the eye a little bit over their terrible bug bounty.
And
what I ended up finding out was if you
actually look at slack and how they're approaching security,
it becomes very clear that their legal and marketing
departments are actually running their external security presence,
which I think is a,
I won't say it's good.
That's how I would classify it.
Well, it, it's actually in some ways, I think marketing and legal should
be the ones to sort of run it,
but they should be running it in a
mature way and they should understand what they're doing
and to put it bluntly, they clearly don't understand
because like under 2000 bucks for remote code execution
in a piece of software used by tens of millions of people is a joke.
I mean, the black market would happily pay more for that.
And even the legal market, you know,
third party like companies that buy vulnerabilities to using their, you know,
pen testing products or part of their, their bug, you know,
hunting products would cheerfully pay a lot more than $2000.
I agree with that.
Now, I'm, I'm going to take issue with what you said though. I don't think
legal and marketing
should be running your external security presence. And the reason for that is
exactly what I would say.
The Slack website conveys if you go to their security landing page,
it's just like full of white papers.
I don't. What is that for?
And then eventually I found a page that there,
in fact even claimed to be part of the legal team where
it was kind of explaining how they take my privacy very seriously.
And then there was eventually a link to the bug body,
but it was very legalese like it wasn't approachable and it didn't give me the,
it made me feel like
if I tried to contact you,
I think the problem is you're thinking of Slack as a piece of software.
Slack thinks of itself as a service.
No, no, I think it's a, it's a service. Everything is a service.
Now, I view the world as a service.
Well, but in the sense of this is a very, I'm just looking at the security page.
This is a very service oriented security page talking about their, you know, their
iso their sock three, their
all that stuff, you know, HIPAA compliance and all that.
Right. Most,
you know, they're
fine.
That's fine.
But then they have a bunch of white paper links and they have no links to contact us,
no links to
like what's up with our security. It's, it is clearly a marketing page.
Yeah, there's no way to report or link to report or even a hint.
And now if you search for the site,
Colin
slack.com, search for security advisory and you should get a link to a legal page.
-- It even has legal in the title. Yeah, slack
-- dot com slash report vulnerability says
if you believe you found a security vulnerability, some hacker one,
it reads like a lawyer wrote it.
Well, but it's just short and to the point,
if you believe you have found a security vulnerability on Slack,
please let us know right away.
Well, yeah, we
will investigate all reports and do our best to quickly fix valid issues.
You can submit your report on hacker one and our security team
will respond as soon as possible to find out more on Slack.
-- Security visit our security information page, which we did and was
-- right.
-- And it's terrible
-- for other security questions or issues, please. Email feedback.
Oh,
-- not security at Slack.
-- Right.
Exactly.
It feels like a lawyer wrote it.
-- So that just goes into the general ticket system and disappears.
-- Probably.
I don't want,
I don't want to dwell on slack too much and kind of throw them under the bus because
unfortunately I suspect they're still better than most.
Well, here's an interesting note, it says on their hacker,
one page reports resolved 1079 average bounty, 500 bucks, 500 bucks is a very
low bounty. Like to put it bluntly.
That's not, that's basically maybe 4 to 5 hours of a professional's rate
if that, I mean, but so here's, here's what the signal I, I see in that is,
is so when you have a low bounty,
there's, I think two sides to this, there's either our stuff is so bad,
we're not going to raise the bounty because we're gonna go broke paying it.
I mean,
or in fact, so like I, I help run a bug bounty
and we had an in
where we actually needed to decrease the reports for a variety of staffing reasons.
And I'm like, let's just lower the bounty, right.
We lowered the bounty, the reports went away. Who knew?
I'm assuming it was more, the low quality reports went away.
All reports, all reports were way down when we lowered the bounty amounts.
And then of course, like we, we dealt with what we needed to deal with,
brought everything back up and hey, it all went back to normal.
Like, so like these bounty amounts totally reflect
-- the way you
-- get.
They're paying out bounties that are still
cheaper than hiring a single person because
it says here they paid out 42 grand in the last 90 days.
So you multiply by four, that's 100 and 60 grand a year.
That's
less than one
info.
Now, now here's ok. So there's the worst. So our, our, our stuff is so bad.
We just don't want to pay because we're going to go broke or
there's the, we couldn't get funding for this.
So
our bounties are low, which has two purposes.
One is you just don't want to pay a lot of money.
And the second is it artificially depresses
the number of reports you get.
So what ends up happening is there are security
researchers who will look at things even for free.
Microsoft used to not pay bounties and they got a ton of reports. Good stuff too.
Same with Red Hat. Red Hat.
As far as I know is never, and probably never will pay a bounty.
I don't know if that has changed, but I know when we were there.
-- That was definitely,
-- well, my understanding is the majority of the open source.
Like the older open source world doesn't pay bug bounties because it, well,
that's ok.
It works.
Right.
Yeah, because, like, the Apache Foundation actually, as part of my research,
I was like, I wonder if the Apache Foundation has a bug bounty?
And they're quite clear, I would assume they pay zero. They don't have a bug bounty.
They were quite clear about it. Like, we don't have a bug bounty.
Here's where you report bugs. Yeah.
-- But they have security at apache.org, which is responsive. Right.
-- Right.
And, and, but, and, right, they still get bugs.
They're going to get information and so kind of the way, the way I see this.
And this is also,
I know some researchers,
I understand kind of their mindset here and if
they find a bug they're going to report it.
If there's a bug bunny, great. That's gravy.
But then there's also people that
if you have a real bug bounty and you pay real money,
they will invest real time into looking at your stuff.
-- Because
-- economically, at that point, the incentives are such that it can be a job.
The payout is reliable enough and high enough then I can
reasonably expect
because here's the blunt truth,
you know, all the good security researchers,
we know if you point them on a piece of software or the website,
they'll find a flaw pretty much.
It's not if it's just like, how long, you know,
how many days or weeks do they spend grinding on it?
If you have a payoff,
a payout that's high enough and reasonably guaranteed of happening.
Because, you know, there are bug bounty companies that are like, oh ha ha.
No, we, we don't believe that's a flaw, but, you know, we're going to fix it anyways
and we're not going to pay you. Right. Well, yeah.
Those researchers don't want to deal with those
people because they want to get paid.
Yeah, I'm just looking at this and, I mean, yeah, 1500 bucks for, you know,
critical flaws
privilege escalation affecting all teams. Yeah, 1500 bucks.
-- Like, that's, that's not a lot of money
-- and, and to give you an idea,
I think Twitter is 40 grand and I think Mozilla is 20 grand for criticals and,
like Microsoft has hundreds of thousands if
you can defeat like their virtualization technology.
So there are some sub
substantial payouts that people have in this space.
So, but anyway, I don't want to just go on and on about bug bunnies.
I think we could do a whole another show just about bug bunnies if we want to.
We probably find someone smarter than us to talk to.
But, but the signaling,
I think the signaling is the important part of this conversation
of Slack has like one step forward and two steps back.
The other thing is like you pointed out in your article, they have one CV,
-- which
-- blew my mind
like they've definitely,
I hope fixed more than one security flaw or
maybe they haven't.
I mean, what's amusing to me is there's a bunch of CV S for Slack plugins,
-- but those aren't owned by Slack.
-- The ecosystem is doing
like,
or Jenkins Slack notification plug in has three or
four CV S so they're doing a decent job
-- and I'll be blunt, if Slack wants to get CV S that would not be a problem.
-- Or,
or, or so, part of, part of this argument, I think as well is so
I can forgive an organization that doesn't want to
deal with Miter to get Cve because it is,
they've historically been very difficult and I would
say they've upgraded to just mostly difficult.
-- I would
-- say it's not so much miter. The problem is CVE was born before 2000.
I'm blaming
mier though.
So,
but change is difficult because part of the problem is there's a lot
-- of organizations that like cve the way it is
-- and that's probably fair.
And I bet half of them are on the board. So,
but anyway, anyway,
we're not, we're not going to spend this podcast ring on CV,
either we can do that another time.
But the point being so
like you should have some sort of security messaging even if you're a service.
And obviously in Slack's case, they have the service, but they,
they push hard into their apps.
I'm looking at, I finally found their change luck, which was not easy.
It's buried as an article slash 1, 1 5 0 0 4 8 4 6 0 6 8 dash blah, blah, blah, blah, blah,
and the word secure and security occur in it.
But so far never as like we fixed a security flaw.
It's like we added a layer of security or we
added a plug in that uses this security feature,
but there's nothing like we fix this security flaw.
Yeah.
And I, I bet they don't, they don't announce it publicly and, and I feel like,
so this is again,
that whole signaling discussion of there are,
I, it's critical infrastructure.
There are companies running your software that are running outdated versions.
They don't know, they're running outdated versions and so they're,
they're assuming a certain level of risk that they
even know about this is completely blind.
So there is the one argument I've seen from some major
companies now that like we don't need to do CV,
because our software auto updates and it forces
you to update and that is somewhat true.
But here's the problem,
-- I would like to be able to make an informed choice
-- or I
think the important thing is so any time you have a fleet of users
and a fleet, I'm going to
is more than 10, there's going to be reasons things don't update. So,
I mean, one of the stories I always like to tell is I was, this was,
this was back when Microsoft and Red Hat hated each other.
I was at Red Hat and I went out for dinner with some Microsoft people
one time and we were just talking about like security updates and all this stuff.
And this guy, one of their people said something that is like, it haunts me of
on the, on patch Tuesday.
Actually, I don't think they might, they might not have had patch Tuesday back then.
It was so long ago, but basically when they released security updates, they would,
they had a dashboard showing what happened.
And he said generally speaking, 10% of Windows users,
the update wouldn't install for, who knows what?
Right, 10% that was like literally tens of millions of computers.
And so part of part of managing a fleet of users is you have to be able to say, ok,
who has, who has updated Slack, who hasn't updated Slack?
And
how, how much should we care?
Because if, if you have no security insight into what, what's in an update,
maybe it was a critical fix, maybe it wasn't, right.
That is incredibly important.
I agree.
And I'm just looking at it and it,
it Slack will show me what version of Slack I've installed
but it doesn't have like a check for updates button that I can find.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. And so anyway, this is, but this is a problem, I think across
the, the consumer ecosystem and the business ecosystem.
-- Oh,
-- I've had, I've had on my Mac, I've had Mac
updates fail and that should like, never happen because I'm running,
it's not like I'm running some strange hardware combination.
I'm like running on a Mac. I bought from the Apple store. I mean, it happens, man.
Yeah. Like literally where I've had it like where it fails to install the update.
So I'm like, ok,
I turn it all the way off, leave it off for 10 seconds, turn it all the way on and, like,
reinstall the update and it works and most
users aren't going to bother doing that because,
like, I mean, I know when we did a, we did a bit of an audit of, like,
making sure everybody's computers up to date and, like, yeah,
some people's computers weren't because,
like, they had
to, and they didn't want to do the whole install an Os update and run the risk of stuff.
Getting screwed up.
My, I just bought my wife a new Macbook, a Macbook air and then we did, like, the, like,
let's move some computers around and shovel them
and the old Macbook that the kids were using
it was, it was a 2012 Macbook. The things, like, still supported.
I'm, like, shocked. But anyway,
they got the old, the less old Macbook
as their, their, like, computer now to play games on. And
so I looked at what they'd been doing.
They haven't installed any updates on that Macbook in like,
years because they just turned off automatic updates
because they kept getting in their way.
-- But what's the benefit to them of it?
-- Nothing.
But I'm like, you can't do, not turn these off. Like, I, we had a talk.
-- But,
-- yeah, well, but that's the thing.
What is the actual benefit to a user of
installing updates and the answer is almost never,
-- it
-- annoyed them.
So they turned it off and I'm like, oh, my goodness, like whose Children are you?
And in some ways it makes it worse.
Um, going back to ipads,
I tried to run an app on my son's ipad that he likes or he used to, like
we talked about this last week. No, no, there's a different one. T Mu
Mizumi, it's still installed on his ipad and it says, oh,
I OS
is too new. I can't run on this.
You need to install the updated app and the updated app is also gone off the store.
And again,
it's
interesting.
Yeah. So I OS
version whatever. I think we're up to 13.61 or something is
so different from like 10, but
stuff just doesn't work.
So anyway, signaling
we're not
gonna,
I
feel, I feel like we just complain.
Well, see what's interesting to me is like, I want to make an informed choice
about software.
And so one of those choices to me for software, it boils down to two things.
One I know your software and service is going to have flaws.
That's just the reality of it.
So I want to get a sense of how many flaws, like, how bad is it like,
is it going to be like one or two bad flaws a year or one or two bad flaws a week?
And then secondly,
so like what what does the vendor then? Do, do they fix them quickly or slowly?
You know, because remember the bad old days, like back in the two thousands where,
you know,
people would post those vendor disclosure timelines that
were like three or four years long.
Yes.
You know,
and now you're seeing vendor disclosure timelines
where it's like contacted vendor emergency on Friday
-- fixed on Saturday. Cool. That's, that's the vendor I want.
-- Right. I, I agree. It is.
But again, how, how do you know? Right. How do you figure this out?
-- Well, you don't unless they have a CV database and change logs and, and,
-- and
I think those are not common at all.
No, no, no.
I mean, I,
I remember like I came to elastic and before I got here they were inconsistent.
-- Well,
-- and that's, that's a big part of it. Yeah.
Is consistency is a sign of maturity being able to
do something reproducibly and reliably because if it's broken,
you can then fix it and change it.
Right? Because if you do something consistently,
you can then do it a different way consistently.
Whereas if it's all the right place, like, I,
I remember vendors where they would just a security report would go
in and it would just get randomly handed to some developer,
like straight up that was their process
and, you know, and for a small firm or something, it's kind of like, well,
I guess what else are they gonna do
but then when you see, like, major firms it's like, no, you,
you need a security team that
at least tracks this because I remember this one vendor didn't
know how many sort of security flaws they were handling.
And I'm like, what do you mean? You don't know?
And they're like, well, it's not in the ticketing system. Well, where is it?
Well, you know, the does have it? Oh, ok.
Right.
Like, is it 5 5500? Right. And that's
so, I think a lot of this boils down to is,
I hate to say it's about process, but it is about process and it's about boring,
like spreadsheet ticketing kind of processes.
Yeah.
Oh, I agree. I think security is accounting
in terms of its excitement level and I have no doubt this is part of the
problem that has kind of got us to where we are is for a long time.
We were the special snowflakes that were exciting.
And
I think the more we, we mature, the more we realize
that the fact that we were snowflakes is just
a symbol of how broken everything really was.
I mean, we're not special security
is, should be boring because if your security isn't boring, like,
something terrible is probably going on.
Well,
the one thing I will say is that security incidents tend to have an emotional impact
but other incidents don't have as much.
Yeah, I do agree with that. It's Well, it makes a mess, man. I mean,
so like my wife just got a mail,
an email from some company she works with that was saying, oh,
your data has been breached but, but you know, here's my favorite part of it, it says,
but your, your credit card information was encrypted. So that's safe.
I'm like, I guarantee you this is a fake statement like there is, I bet you anything.
Well, no, no, no, they're not lying. It was encrypted.
But did they say whether or not the encryption keys were protected?
-- They didn't
-- say anything about that and I,
right.
Exactly. We know what's going on. Right.
But anyway, the point is that business is no doubt, completely up
ended and disrupted because of a security event.
Yeah, it's like a natural disaster.
I mean, honestly that's what a security event is.
Like, it's the same caliber, like you're unprepared. There's nothing you can do.
There are places in the world where they're
common enough that they just deal with it.
Like, I remember this one town in Germany where they have a river, you know,
like most towns are on a river because that's where the water is.
And so it floods often enough that they installed those removable flood barriers.
But, you know, they just
install them like in an afternoon and they hold, you know, four or 5 ft of water
and they wait for the river to go down and they just pull out.
It's like these aluminum panels.
Right.
Yeah, and that's fine until the river gets so high it goes over your emergency.
But, yeah, at that point, you know, like they, they've, they've solved, you know,
for 95% of the flood cases they've turned them into non events.
Well, but that's the thing. Right. And, and this is going to be true of security is
you can, you can account for certain events, but there's always,
there's always going to be something bigger,
there's always going to be something new.
Oh,
-- yeah,
-- there's always a bigger fish. Yeah.
And I mean, like my favorite comparison here is like Florida, right?
They just keep building stronger and stronger houses and
we keep getting strong and stronger hurricanes like it,
it's one of those things.
Right.
Yeah,
I don't know.
But back to signaling, I mean,
part of it too is there are signals that
are signals and there are signals that are effective.
So it always kind of reminds me of plumage in the wild,
right?
Where there are,
there are signals animals give out and some of them are
actually more effective for that animal being fitter for its environment.
And some are like having bright plumage means well,
like I'm strong enough that I don't get eaten.
So in and of itself is not a good thing,
but it basically proves something else.
So, for example,
if you have a bug bounty that consistently pays out like 100 grand for R CS.
Well, then one of two things is true. Either one you don't have a lot of R CS
or two. You're big enough and mature enough that, like, cool.
Yeah, we're going to pay out millions of dollars a year in security flaws because,
like Microsoft and Google, we can.
Yeah, but those, those places have.
So, actually this is, this is a good line of line of discussion because I don't think
it's ever going to be the case of. We just have plenty of money.
I think it's always going to be the case of our security
is so good now that we have to pay ridiculous sums of money
for people to justify spending the time and effort on our stuff.
And that's a great sign.
Oh, yeah. Here we go. This is from a few, this is from what, two years ago,
Google has paid out
over $21 million
since 2010, which is a lot of freaking money, $2 million a year. That,
that's actually some real money.
However, however, I will say,
I guarantee you if they had internal people looking for the
same kind of bugs and doing the same kind of work,
-- I bet they would have paid out 10 times that
-- much,
easily.
Well, more to the point
they can't because
-- do you know any security people without a job?
-- No, there are none.
And
actually one of my favorite, favorite comparisons here is.
So if you pay to get a pen test done against your site,
there is a high probability, if you're competent they will find nothing.
And then you just paid them 100 grand for a report that says good job. Everybody like
that sucks.
-- Yeah.
-- But that's valuable.
Like, I mean, we, we have a service now that looks at our D MARK reports for our email.
And it's funny because we had like 98 point something
percent of our email is DKIM and SPF compliant.
And I'm like, oh, that's not bad.
And I found like, two or three things where I could fix it.
Like, you know, sales force is emailing it
reports as us and, you know, not set up. Right. So I'm like, oh, good.
You know, it's a couple of 100 emails a week that we can fix
and another contact piece of software.
And it's funny though then talking to the vendor, I'm like, yeah, you know,
like we're at 98 point whatever percent, you know,
and I think I can get this down to about two or three per 1000 you know, and I,
and I feel like though I can't get it any lower
than that because just there's email systems that are broken,
right?
And he's like, yeah,
and I'm like, what is it kind of your average vendor go for? And he's like,
5 to 90%.
But when you think about a major vendor
sending out millions and millions of marketing emails.
You know, like, like one thing I realized is like at the cloud screen lines,
there was like five, we had about five or six ways.
I knew that we were supposed to be sending out email, like Google mailchimp,
stuff like that.
But like I said, there was a couple of surprises like, oh, Salesforce is emailing out
us us. Why? What? Oh, these automated reports like a daily report? Ok, cool.
And so
you think about a fortune 100 company?
Oh man, I mean,
we're not even that big and we have similar problems where we actually,
so it's weird that you're, I don't know why the D
mark is getting hip right now because we, we had an internal project.
-- What
-- I love about D Mark is it's helping me improve
my email deliverability and as a side effect I get better security
and that's exactly what we're experiencing at work as well.
It's like we're starting to clean up some D Mark stuff and people are like, wait,
what, where like, where did this even come from?
Well, I I'm like, why we have one email from one
subdomain and I'm like, that should never send an email
because
that doesn't
exist
like this doesn't exist as a thing. How is it? It's an S3 bucket. How is it?
Why is there an email from it?
-- But
-- at the same time,
I think this is what makes Demark so cool because
it's giving a window into some of this madness.
So, anyway, anyway, all right, we need, we need to wrap this one up.
So I feel like we talked about bug bunnies a lot, even though that wasn't the intent.
But I do think there is a lot of interesting lessons to learn.
And I think this is one of those instances where reading between
the lines of what a company says versus how they act is,
I mean, this is true of just humans in general.
There's a lot of power in that slack does. I think in general a fair job.
I don't want to make it sound like I'm anti Slack or anything. I use it every day.
But I do think it, one of those instances where
you don't have a lot of excuses at this point
to not have a lot of this figured out.
Well, I think they could definitely do better
and well, that certainly it's true of everybody.
But I think also more importantly, they should do better because like you said,
this is now critical infrastructure people, you know,
work from home is now the new normal.
Like people like me and Josh, we're not trendsetters anymore. We're boring,
boring for years.
But yeah, I, I, yeah, absolutely. And this is, I mean,
we could probably throw actually before we go, I'm going to end on. This is so
funny enough.
I'll pick on Zoom who just had, like, their stock is last, I looked,
was up $100 today because they had, like, ridiculous earnings yesterday.
But,
yeah,
exactly.
We just wait, they're like,
anyway, anyway,
it's
up 37.7%.
I'm sad. I didn't buy their stock.
But
anyway,
here, here's the thing though, right?
Like, they had a signaling problem at the beginning and then they're like, oh,
we're going to fix all this,
what we should do at some point is like we should follow up on what they've done.
I, I actually did, I,
I looked at them as part of my slack research and
I decided to set them aside as their own special thing.
A, let's just say it looks like they haven't done squat.
Oh, that would be my assumption. Yeah, they've done the public lip service.
-- But
-- it was apr stunt and now it's back to normal
as
far as I know they haven't become a CV numbering authority.
They haven't. There's, there's so much again.
Zoom is another topic,
I think because it's a big one and there's a lot of stuff they haven't done.
And this is what I love is everybody throws, you know,
everybody got so upset and stressed out about it and it's like they don't even, yeah,
on their hacker one page.
They don't even tell you what their bounties are.
That hacker one has links to companies that isn't like the Zoom
hacker one bug bounty that is hacker one's link to Zoom.
Oh,
-- yes. Right.
-- That's part of the story, part of the story. Anyway,
we're not going to do this right now.
Intrigued.
Yeah, exactly. Like I said, I said it off to the so.
Ok.
No more. No more.
I will stop looking
at
it. Alright. Thank you everyone for listening. You can go to open
source security podcast dot
I
can't even talk today.
You all know what to do, you know how to find us. We're on Twitter.
I'm going to end it there. All right, Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks
-- everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.