Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in accepting that
nothing's gonna get better on this issue,
-- Josh
-- Pressers.
All right. So I just literally realized this moment that it is Easter Sunday.
We are recording a podcast and many of us have been working
-- quite a lot over the last couple of days which
-- I find comical
on many levels.
If all goes.
Well, this episode is going to come out on April 1st, which is hilarious for so,
so all of you listen, listeners are going to get a two first special this,
this week where we've got the,
I don't even remember what the topic is now.
The podcast literally coming out in 45 minutes from the time we're
recording this because I have it all on auto and then,
and then the special April 1st, which is incredibly appropriate XZ.
Spectacular.
Well, the thing is like when you do something a lot,
like when I wrote a monthly magazine column every month for eight years, I,
I would write the column and then like literally an hour after I submitted it, it,
it was out of my brain.
Same thing with the podcast, right? Like, no, we record a podcast.
And if you ask me in the afternoon, like, what did you talk about this morning?
Like, because I've had people ask me that, like,
what did you record with Josh this week?
And I'm like,
I don't know, I, I don't remember. I just,
it's like asking me to remember like that email I sent four hours ago.
It, well, this happens all the time where Kurt's like, oh, we should talk about this.
I'm like, Kurt, we just literally just did that.
We talked about that two weeks ago and he's like, oh, I don't remember like, yeah,
whatever.
Well, because part of it is I don't like flush,
like I use feed to organize all my links for reading RSS, right?
And it's not like I flushed them out.
Ok. Anyway, before, while we could talk for hours about that topic.
The X thing amuses me on so many levels because I
like people have been saying this could happen for
and it
probably
happened before but not been
ok.
-- And this is
-- before you go on.
I want to explain what's going on because there's an enormous
number of people who are going to wake up on Monday morning
-- and be like, what the heck is going on. So
-- what happened is somebody wrote,
-- I
-- would have started at the beginning,
I was going way back to the beginning.
-- I'm going to the very start like we're
-- gonna,
yeah, I was about to say somebody wrote a useful piece of software called
before.
Before you can create what before you can bake a pie? You have to invent the universe.
Is that what it is?
Because you need an oven,
we need
to invent the universe.
So what is Xz Kurt? Do you want to talk about it?
And I should say the letter X letter, the letter X and the letter Z, right?
Two letters.
OK.
So there are compression algorithms,
there are lossy and lossless compression algorithms,
lossy compression algorithms.
A good example would be J peg quite lovely because you can make a picture smaller and
often that's OK because you're displaying it on
a small screen like back in the eighties
doesn't matter.
Then there are lossless data compression algorithms which really matter.
For example,
if you're compressing a piece of text like a report or an
email because you can't just start randomly removing letters and words,
it could have an impact. There's a lot of lossless compression algorithms like
a lot, a lot.
And
to make some general hand wavy terms,
there are a variety of tradeoffs you can make in a lossless compression algorithm.
You can usually,
and the general rule of thumb is you
can spend more time compressing and less time decompressing
or less time compressing and more time decompressing.
Pretty much. Yes.
And generally speaking as a rule you want that if
you spend more time compressing for it to get smaller
because if it doesn't get smaller, then what's the point of spending more
time compressing it. If,
you know, if you spend twice as much compute,
time compressing it and it's the same size, then
don't,
it's not,
most of us are probably used to like G zip, for example. Right.
That's the old historical one.
And for anyone who kind of plays in the sandbox of open source XZ appears to be the
spiritual successor of G zip where you're seeing a
lot of things instead of it being dot TGZ,
you're seeing dot Tar dot XZ on many, many archives.
And one of the things that we've sort of realized is in the past,
you really cared about data size because
like bandwidth and storage was horrifically expensive.
-- Well, it still is, I mean, honestly,
-- well, not compared to the eighties.
Well, no, but I mean,
compared to everything else going on bandwidth and storage
are generally the big cost in the cloud.
Right.
Exactly.
But what's actually really interesting though is the amount of stuff
that is compressed once and decompressed many and by many,
I mean, probably on the order of millions, if not billions of times.
And so there it really makes sense to spend a lot of work up front,
compressing the heck out of something,
spending a ton of compute time, compressing it
so that the clients can get it faster over the network, spend less space,
storing it and decompress it because the thing to remember too is like,
you're sending compressed files to embedded systems now.
Sure,
whatever.
So there's a real payoff if you can have sort of like,
do a lot of work upfront and then have the clients
less work. So
XC is, it was uh one of the leaders uh probably a decade or two ago,
like when it first came out, it was like, wow, this thing is slow.
Like I would use it and I'm like, oh my, is my computer broken? Like what the heck?
-- Well,
-- it, so I just looked it, it, the initial release of XZ
is from 2009
0 2009.
Yeah, like that's not that old in the world. I mean, J
is probably from what, like the freaking nineties or maybe in the eighties,
I don't know.
Oh, no, it would be dot Z dot Capital Z compress would be before that.
Well, that's compressed, that's different for sure. So like
this is not, we'll say enormously old in the context of computing
and back, even in 2009,
like you'd compress a file on your workstation and it would be like,
is this thing broken?
Because it would just take so
long
you get stuff that was like 20% smaller, which if you're the Linux kernel, it was
awesome.
Well, back,
remember when a Linux kernel had to fit on a fluffy
like you literally couldn't build it if it didn't fit,
fit on a fluffy anyway.
Ok.
So,
so
Xz,
let's pretend that was a good enough explanation
for everyone to understand what's going on.
So now in 2024 on March 31st, when we're talking about this,
there has been what I will call the most impressive
attack
that has been mounted against open source.
We know of, we know of being the key because I we we'll explain why, what,
why we know of is important in this.
Well, and here's what I love is, I have often said
that one character security flaw. Is it
-- a backdoor or is it a
-- whoopsie?
I mean, well, in this instance, it was definitely not a whoopsie. We'll say that.
Yeah. So this, this is
-- literally a one character backdoor. It's a dot It's
-- beautiful. No, no, no. Oh no, no.
The dot is different.
The dot is part of a longer story.
This is
like, that's, that's part of the beauty of this is like there's a dot
There's a period on one line.
-- Let's,
-- let's start with, there's a link I'm going to open from a guy on.
Do we want to work? Let's work backwards.
Let's just uh chronologically, let's work backwards.
Sure, because I think that's more
interesting.
So what, first of all,
what's really interesting to me and amusing to me
is this flaw was not found through code review.
Or somebody auditing code
it was found because SSH was running really slow and so
no,
sorry,
0.4 seconds slower
when a,
a post Chris Dev was trying to log in 0.4 seconds when you or I notice 0.4 seconds.
No, absolutely not.
Well, I, as a human, I wouldn't notice it but I,
I do often say people should have telemetry in their code
so they can spot that 95th percentile stuff because that indicates
regressions, right?
So anyway,
so he spotted it, profiled it and,
and basically found this problem in the latest version
of XC which is used by OPEN SSH
for compression.
It's not.
No,
I I've only skimmed the thing. I actually haven't read the details yet.
Let me explain the attack because this is
beyond insane. OK.
-- Oh
-- It's the Yeah, never mind. Yeah.
So here's what happens
on certain Linux distribution specifically. Red Hat
Debian and Collie Linux are the three that are often pointed out.
But obviously Ubuntu and some others will be similar.
They have patched open SSH to specifically hook into system D to do system D things
as these big distributions tend to do
it.
Oh So open SSH doesn't natively support system D.
Why would it, those people probably hate the system.
Why do they do that
thing?
Open BD?
And
here's where it gets completely banana. So,
so system D
uses
XZ, the, the lib lz ma part of the XZ specifically, right?
It, it loads it into its process space
and it does stuff with it. Right?
Just because it needs a compression library as every everything
does and system D does literally everything. So, whatever
now. So what happens is, here's where it gets weird. So here's what's gonna happen.
So let's say, I mean, normal running system, right?
I've got open SSH, loading some system D things
and then they're going to interact in whatever ways they interact.
But fundamentally you've got like open SSH, on one side,
you've got system D on the other and things are, are supposed to get along.
Right.
And what's interesting is system D and open SSH are essentially the only generally
cross distribution, default components of a Linux district.
No, really? Because you have to be able to log into the system.
So that's open SSH right there.
-- And the system has to be able to boot.
-- There's,
there's tons of shared libraries, but here's where it's gonna get sillier.
-- No,
-- no. But I mean, from a service point of view,
it's gonna get wacky. Don't worry.
We, we go off the rails more than once
in a normal running system.
We got open ssh, you've got it talking to system D and these are
like C binaries, right? This is we're talking about like low
level binary libraries and, and interaction of applications on A L system
when you have a process
and it loads a library on the disk like a binary library
they share, they have like a global memory space. OK?
And so what happens is like if something needs to call a function,
it has to go through the, the whole LD universe and be like,
I need to call this function somebody and magic happens and it gets called OK?
And so what happens in this attack?
And we'll,
we'll explain how the attack is loaded
because the that's completely bananas by itself.
And basically what's happening is the Lib Lz Ma
has a function that exists in open SSH. So what happens is Lib Lz Ma
has a function
that
is, is hidden inside of itself now
that is designed to run in place of a function open SSH has
and that's it. But here's the thing.
So here's where here's the just completely banana part of this backdoor.
You have a library
at least three,
three levels deep
that has been backdoor to attack open SSH that in
a normal context isn't even linked into open SSH.
Well, and see this is something
I've been worried and wondered about for a long time is how do I put it this way?
Linux systems are what you call highly interconnected
open source.
I mean, the way operationally that it runs
and to put it bluntly, this is why
when I, when I talk about containers,
I'm like you do one thing per container and you expose it through a network port
because if it's running in the same container or
like, it's just they can go touch each other way too much.
There's way too many
ways for stuff to touch each other. And this is a perfect example of it.
I don't know if I would agree with that.
What you said is not incorrect where in there's processes have
some ability to kind of cross over into one another.
But once you start loading binary libraries, it's like there's no,
there's no anything between each other.
However, here's where the dot you mentioned earlier comes into play.
So apparently, Lib Lz Ma
has a concept of a sandbox they were working on which has the ability to kind of,
you know,
like let's push this off into the corner and and not let it
like trample all of the process memory space and all this stuff,
right?
And one of the additions the attacker added
was a.in a file that disabled the sandbox
and it looked you could,
you can't even tell it's there if you don't know what to look for.
It's
-- wild.
-- If you're using the wrong font,
if you're using the wrong font in your code editor,
you might not even physically notice it.
It
it's yes, this is like
the people who did this attack,
they, they know what they're doing, right? This was not an amateur by any means. Now
we will link to a post by Gussie.
The dog who is famous for creating the log
for shell logo which Jerry Bell created the log
for
shell. Lo
Jerry Bell created an XZ for SHELL logo for this, which is,
it's, it's the logo for the show. It's, it's so good. I can't not use it.
But anyway,
goss the dog posted a really nice blog post and I'll put a link in the
show notes to it where he kind of mentions that one of the things happening here
was system D was removing the like automatically loading of the XZ libraries
by default. And this was a change that had gone into upstream system D already.
And they think that caused the attacker to try to force
the new XZ into like redhead and Debbie and
-- other things and they got sloppy because they were
-- rushing
to move.
Ah,
so the classic, they had a plan, they had a timeline
and then the world changed and they had to move up the timeline and
like every heist film has ever shown us. No, I'm serious.
Like I'm not being facetious, but like every heist film ever,
you move up the timeline and yeah, things go all to heck in a handbasket.
Exactly. That, that is exactly what appears to have happened now. OK.
That was a lot to, to unwrap. But basically
if, if you were talking about sophistication of attacks, this is really high.
Now we should go through this picture from uh Frogger where they detail kind of
the timeline of how this happened and we're gonna go back all the way to 2021
on this timeline.
Well, actually, I think we should go backwards. So,
so we've, we've had this happen in the last few days
and
what's really interesting to me is so, yeah, like you said, uh here we go. 2023 0708
pr opened an OS S fuzz to disable if funk
for fuzzing builds allegedly to mass the malicious changes,
right?
So they made
so they're basically like
this is a multi, like not just a multistage
effort and attack, but it was done over a period of several years, a
year and a half.
Well, OK, so if we start
at the beginning
2021 the user which is
Gaya Tan, if I'm pronouncing that incorrectly, I apologize
but they created their github
-- account in 20 21.
-- Interesting note, their SSH key,
there were also some other SSH keys created like a day or so part
with related to other accounts that were also egging on this whole thing.
So
later, basically, uh he,
he gets involved in the mail and this is like, I kind of want to help,
maybe kind of take over or whatever, whatever.
And it looks like he had some sock puppets that were like, yeah, you know,
you should let this guy help blah, blah, blah and like to put it bluntly, they,
they kind of bullied and manipulated
the XC
contain uh maintainer sorry, I almost said container, sorry about that
into allowing this, which I,
yeah, I mean, the the this person is,
you know,
it's that back to that XK CD thing with the one little
wedge with the person in Nebraska and living out in a cornfield,
you know, maintaining this thing that
Western civilization relies upon to work.
So
this, yeah, this is not like AAA little happenstance for. No,
this is,
this was planned.
It's very well coordinate
the timeline.
You used the word coordinate. I'm gonna disagree with you there.
This could easily be one person.
It probably is one person, but I think they were.
Here's the story, I don't know,
related to their day job like they are.
-- So
-- here's, here's what I will explain to kind of go on here.
There is a story I saw and master on that. I don't know if I'll be able to find it.
I will try to find it, but I don't think I will where this person talked about.
They said
I at one time worked for one of the, this was in the nineties,
one of the largest cell phone manufacturers on the on the planet, right?
So you can imagine in the nineties, there were basically two.
They said I work for one of the largest cell phone manufacture, actors on the planet.
And they had a person who came into the company as a contractor
and they worked with this, the, the as a contractor for two months and they were like
an exceptional programmer, like, phenomenally better
than really anyone even on staff.
And so they, uh, logically hired the person on full time,
the person worked at the company for approximately six months as a full
time employee and were just one of the best programmers on staff bar.
None. Right.
They stopped coming into work one day.
Then they found out
when they looked,
the person had accessed all of the source code for all of the products.
They sent a wellness check to the person's apartment.
It was an empty apartment. There was nothing in it.
See, they
had never cashed a single paycheck. They had been issued as an employee
and they basically had no, like real record of this human being.
-- They could even find,
-- see,
this makes no sense to me because you do all that work and you don't
have like, you don't cash the paychecks. That makes no damn sense.
-- It
-- was clearly some sort of like
the
Russian state espionage,
-- but that's
-- sloppy because not cashing paychecks.
That would be an immediate red flag.
Like I'll be blunt if I don't know, like,
if I had somebody working for me and they didn't cash your paycheck,
I would immediately
-- be suspicious or something's wrong.
-- No one knew this in the nineties.
People cash their paychecks.
Yes.
But I bet you in the nineties it would take a year or more
-- for the payroll departments to figure that I'm also saying
-- is it's sloppy from,
if this was a so called spy
act, which obviously it indicates it was or possibly mental illness.
But anyways ignoring that, for example,
they could have easily cashed the paychecks,
they could have easily had an apartment full of crap.
Ok. Whatever.
I, I don't want to dwell on that point because that point is irrelevant to the story.
Well, but that kind of leads actually.
Well, it is relative to this one because they clearly, they set up sock puppets,
but they set up the accounts within a day or two of each other, which
is probably ok in the open source world because
until after the fact,
you know, you're not gonna know to look. Yeah, no one, no one knew.
Like I'm always reminded of the world's biggest diamond heist in Holland.
You know how they caught them.
The guy was supposed to burn their garbage and he
just threw it out by the side of the road.
And from that they got, I forget it was either a fingerprint or a DNA and
unraveled the whole thing,
right? It's like
just
like,
ok,
regardless we have this attack starts in 2021
there's an enormous amount of effort put in by
this fake account to get into the XZ project.
I would say enormous amount of effort. Like
tens of
actually, you're right.
It wasn't an enormous amount of effort, but I think that's an important point.
People put more work into a defcon talk than this.
No, I'm serious. This could be just literally somebody staging a defcon talk.
I don't think it is,
but I'm saying it's I've seen and I've worked with
people who've put more work into stuff than this.
OK?
I won't disagree with that.
I think that is a very reasonable point.
And I think the fact that the bar is so low to
mount an attack like this is noteworthy as a data point.
-- Remember
-- when that Nation State attacked D DNS and took down the entire internet
and then it turned out to be a bunch of teenagers having a beef about Minecraft.
Right. That's, that's what I'm saying. Like here, I'm sorry. Yes,
this smells like a nation State,
but it literally could be a rather clever 16 year old with way too much spare time,
-- I
-- think because it occurred over the course of three years.
I'm inclined to say it is not a singular attacker
because a
three
year game like this is,
-- that is a long game.
-- It
is. But I mean,
to have this on your resume as a defcon talk,
not anymore. You're gonna get freaking arrested. Now,
pause,
-- arrested for what
-- I was wondering that is, does this break any laws?
-- And it might
-- not, they didn't access any computer systems.
I like until they, if they exploited this flaw,
then they definitely violated the uh computer fraud and misuse.
Uh What is it? This, I forget C
FAA,
C FAA in America and whatever
it is in other countries.
But
no offense if people go to jail for writing bad code,
-- but
-- it's not bad code. Like the level of no, it is not bad code.
-- This is a clearly malicious
-- b
there's
unquestionably
uh
and PP has blocked signups recently because they're getting so much malicious
junk and same with N PM and same with github like,
yeah, that's, I mean, if it is against the law somewhere somehow,
then we got a lot of people that need to go to jail.
I agree with that. I think that is a very interesting question.
-- As
-- far as I know, it doesn't violate any laws. I've never seen a law remotely.
Yeah. My suspicion is, this is not illegal because it was not,
nothing was like, well to our knowledge,
nothing was successfully attacked with this.
Was it University of Minnesota doing the Linux kernel thing?
Yes,
it
was
unethical
but it was not illegal.
I don't know if that one was illegal or not.
One of the smart open source lawyers would have chimed in if it was illegal.
That's true. They would have absolutely brought up some random,
you know, statute that you're not allowed to
whatever. But as, as
I cannot imagine this being
illegal in any way, shape or form.
So let me, I,
I want to now explain what the literal attack is and how
this worked because this is also on this timeline from Froger,
which is really good and it's amazing.
So,
one of the things that not everyone understands
when you're distributing like tar balls of stuff
is
you un tar the archive and you'd often run dot slash configure,
which every old person just shuddered a little bit when they heard those words
because
it's not like when you do like an N PM install something,
you have to run dot slash configure and you
might have to provide it with various flags about
where some libraries live on your system and where
-- you want to install the stuff or
-- populate like half
a gigabyte of stuff and slash
art.
Ask
me
how
I know
I just user
lib. I just had a tweet. Oh,
sorry people, I shouldn't have said that.
-- So,
-- but anyway,
it was very common for a tar that the tar ball of source to have some things in it
that aren't in
-- the, well, I'll say get repo but we all know that's not what it
-- was
is having zip so that it compiles on windows.
Well, no, no, not even that, not even that. I'm just saying the configure script
and there would be like, maybe some macros that could come with
things. There be this
weird stuff you would generate as,
as like just a polite service to the person accepting your source code and that,
that has, that still exists that's still a thing, right?
And so this also contains and M four. Macro M four. Is this weird macro language that
sadly is still used.
I mean, send mail was based on it.
And again, Twitching because I wrote send mail to fax gateway and M four.
So, ok, so anyway,
so
it had this malicious
M four script
is script the right word.
It's a Macro
M
four script
that
that only existed in the Tar ball
and it was in the git ignore.
So like this person wanted to make sure we didn't accidentally include it
because the code scanner might have caught it or
somebody might have seen this weird looking thing.
Right.
Right. That's right. That's right.
So it took this um this build the host M four
macro and then that thing would basically take one of the
a test, a test case.
That was, it was the, the test case was called bad three corrupt LZ ma two dot XZ.
So the idea being what you have test cases, you have good test cases,
you have bad test cases.
Obviously you need, you need tests that are supposed to fail. Uh Yeah. Uh
That's not obvious to most people. Actually, I have actually,
I've had to spend a lot of time explaining that to some people where I'm like,
I tested this both. So it works and it fails and they're like, what?
And I'm like, well, it's supposed to fail when you do XY and Z and they're like,
-- I guess, and I'm like, no, it, it actually really should fail and it does that
-- fair.
Well, and so for things like compression libraries,
you want to make sure like we're not overflowing a buffer when it
tells me that it's going to decompress a bazillion bites or whatever.
There's a, there's many reasons. Ok. So anyway,
it is a, a corrupted XZ file. Then this M four script swaps a bunch of bites,
right? To, to turn it from a corrupted
XZ file into an uncorrupted XZ file
into a bash
file.
Once we uncompress the XZ file, now we have a
bash file
which then does some more wacky stuff, right?
And we end up eventually after all these stages of running
all this bash crap and doing all these weird substitutions.
So we're talking like
probably what, four or five layers of obfuscation.
But what I love is it also lives off the land by using XZ
because of course it does. It is.
But I mean, that's clever.
That's smart because it's basically, it's, it's essentially encryption
by, by literally flipping
well, it, but until you flip those few bytes correctly,
it doesn't like you could flip those bytes to a bajillion well,
to literally every other value
-- and it would still be a broken file. Is that
-- encryption?
I don't know, I don't want to argue this
ethics at that point.
But,
but what I'm saying is like statistically
nobody's ever going to accidentally find out.
No, no. Well, till now. OK. But anyway, we've got all these layers of
abstraction.
We eventually, eventually
we end up with a, a
bunch of binary code A 0.0
file functionally.
The in fact, oh, here's the name of it.
It's Lib Lz Ma underscore L A dash CRC
64 dash fast 0.0 which is a very plausible sounding
object file and then that gets added into the linking process for the final library.
So basically, now we've added in
the attacker's code
that does not exist a source anywhere we can find
and was confiscated until the build happened.
-- And then we linked it in,
-- I have a question for you.
Are there any S bomb tools that would catch this in
the sense of they would take this tar ball and go.
Where on earth does this file come from?
No, that's not what, what s bomb
would do. So the way S
bomb can help with this actually, and it's not worthless.
I know there've been, there've been,
it's funny because there's two camps in this where you've got one camp that's like,
oh s
bomb could solve this another camp. That's like, no, it can't.
But and the but is important because this is an example where
one of the usages for
SBA
is like during the BUILD,
you kind of take like snapshots of what's going on at various points.
This file gets written to disk at some point.
And this is a good example where if you, you would
a very, very mature process and I don't think anyone has a process, it mature today.
But you could, for example, look at that file and be like,
how did this 0.0
file get built?
I've never seen this before.
Where did it come from? And then you could start asking questions.
But that is like incredibly, incredibly advanced.
I think for most of us, the value in SP
would bring is just to say, OK,
do I have any instances of a build that have a
0.0 with this name I have ever seen in my infrastructure?
And that has value.
The question to me that I find interesting is
there are legitimate cases where you have a G
repo with a pile of files and you have a distribution mechanism that is
not compiled. So let's simplify things greatly, not compiled.
But it is for example, a tar ball distributed in a way where there are,
I'm gonna say the word built artifacts in it.
But
the general view would be it's a tarball its source.
But there are these kind of built or compiled or generated, that's the word I want.
There are generated artifacts in it
that are then distributed as part of that. And that
is normal like that is
we've been doing that for since forever.
It's been normal. I think
we're going to start asking the question if it should be normal from now on.
Well, and, and so that raises the question, for example, you know, should these,
the contents of these tar balls, should everything
either be basically, should we have a, a link of like,
here's the stuff from the get up in the tar ball,
here's the stuff that was generated and at least make sure that's checked into the
get up rep on a slash build or slash or whatever generated director something,
right?
-- So that it's visible,
-- I think we should stop generating anything.
I think it needs to come from
github. I think if it doesn't come from github,
like it doesn't exist.
Yeah, I think, yeah, because I mean,
there are use cases where you have to have stuff that like there's
the source code plus this generated artifact for it to kind of work.
But I think that generated thing has to be,
it has to have provenance. It can't just be like
like a red hat. You know where I remember I unpacked an R PM once
and it was like
the build host was workstation dash something. And I'm like,
-- it's not even a full domain
-- and look, this is one of, I mean,
this is one of the complaints.
Toma
De
Pierre has like consistently is
there's so much of this stuff is happening like
on random people's machines in random people ways and
let it happen.
It's
like you need some provenance here. We don't have it. Ok?
So I wanna,
I wanna steer this conversation because I think
there's a lot of technical details and I have
a,
we're recording this on a Sunday.
I'm releasing this on a Monday and I bet you by the time anyone listens to this,
the things we know right now are changed because that's how this stuff works.
However, I think there's some meta topics to discuss
and I'm just gonna ask you the first question that I know how you're gonna answer.
I'm asking anyway, is this going to change anything?
There will be some racial.
Now, here's the beauty
and I'm not saying it's because people are bad or dumb or lazy or anything.
It's, this will raise some awareness,
but there is nothing we can do at this scale to fix this. So for example,
when a person comes to a project,
are we going to somehow vet we can't even vet who they are let alone their intention?
Sure. That's right. Right.
So number one, we can't do that.
It's, it's, I mean, in the sense of it's not physically possible,
like there's also privacy laws and everything,
right. The best we could shoot for is pseudo anonymity.
But we also probably need to support an anonymity because to, to quote myself,
I personally will never ever participate in open
source software with my real name ever again.
Moving forward because of the abuse I've received and passed from certain people.
That's fair. That's fair. Yeah. Anyway, so have that number two. Let's assume
we somehow magically have the resources to vet
new people coming in and make sure they're,
like, not bad, which, like,
people have gotten top secret clearances and had deep background checks and, like,
I'm just going to throw out the name Eric Ames or locally.
We have an RC MP officer that was selling data to the Rwandan government. Like what?
No, I'm serious. Right. It was in the news a few weeks ago.
The RC MP is like we pat really thought like, and anyway, that's
going off.
So
then this lovely, let's assume we can do that for all the new people.
Well, what about all the existing people?
How do we know somebody's not in there playing the long game and by long game?
And, and we don't, I don't want to dwell on that point too much because you're right.
We cannot,
we cannot and,
and someone could be malicious and still pass all the checks
or somebody could decide to be malicious after the fact.
So we
let's
duh,
let's do code reviews.
Well, yeah, we've tried that for 50 years.
Uh
Right. We can't do code reviews, not with humans at least.
And even when we do code reviews with humans,
like there are new classes of attacks that people come up with.
Like, I remember the web before cross site scripting, which in hindsight is like,
so stupidly obvious.
It's ridiculous. But now it's like,
OK, so we can't code review, we can't audit, we can't
fuzz, we can't, like,
we can't technology or process our way out of this because of scale.
And this raised the issue.
A simple nomad uh you know, from git lab was talking about this. And I'm like,
but basically if somebody does actually have a solution for this,
they're not going to give it for free to the open source community,
they're going to sell it for a lot of money.
They would try except there isn't one.
Well, actually enterprise is probably not willing to pay for this either.
So that's the beauty of this is even if we do
learn from this and even if we had good recommendations,
we, we're going to implement them with what magical resources
here's I think the,
the way I would kind of frame this and I wrote some blog
stuff for work because they wanted it as these things tend to go.
I've been trying to figure out how to summarize
this in half a page that isn't depressing.
Here's what I basically said. I'm like, number one,
this problem is unsolvable.
-- Anyone who tells you they can solve this problem is 100% lying to you.
-- OK.
Pause for a second when you say solvable. Do you mean
like, it's obviously not 100% solvable, like
whatever? But is it even remotely that we can make this better.
-- No,
-- and I'm not sure we can even
-- do
-- that.
We can't, today,
we lack the knowledge and understanding of this sort of
attack to even do anything remotely educated at this point.
So anyone claiming
like
we got you like, no, they're either they're lying to you or they're,
they're beyond dumb.
It could be both.
But
so, but however,
I, I hearken the, the theme I think to the observable universe, right Where I've got,
I was at Elastic for a while and I've got some observable background behind me
where if you think about like deploying services at scale, right?
You no one says we're going to build a service that will never crash, right?
No one would imagine saying that because that's beyond stupid, right?
So what the observable people do is they start with the
assumption
we are going to have problems inside of our infrastructure.
So we are going to augment our infrastructure in ways
that let us observe what's happening inside of it.
And ideally, we can identify problems we or they come catastrophic, right?
And I think this is kind of what we have to think about in the
context of security is we have to have the ability to look at our software,
like
we have to know what we're running. If, if you are a company,
any organization, let's say of, of even remote size,
if someone comes to you and says,
I want to know every version of XZ we have running in our infrastructure,
you should be able to answer that question in 10 minutes or less.
And if you can't like,
-- go figure out how to do it.
-- Well, no, but we learned from Log for Jay that
with people. It was a heroic effort for months.
So I'm gonna, I just want to raise one thing quickly to knock it out of the way
there is.
In theory, you can make bulletproof software,
but you have to have unlimited money and a very constrained use case.
So the example being like NASA, where they'd have like,
they would literally write the software like
twice using totally different teams and methods
that
basically cannot work anymore.
Because software, this isn't,
the seventies software is too complicated and big and complex
for that to ever be a thing.
And it certainly can't happen in the open source world
where we have zero resourcing because if we had resourcing,
well, yeah, we,
we wouldn't be just grabbing random open source libraries and hoping for the best.
That's the second thing is this actually raises something that I've been,
I need to write an article about this.
It's all to do it.
You can't have security unless you can die gracefully. And by that, I mean,
if you can't shut a system down to like reboot it,
you can't have security because how are you going to operationally
update it?
You can't have operations without that ability,
but a lot of people don't have that ability or when they do have to shut stuff down.
It's a total nightmare.
Well, then the universe has planed your downtime for you.
How often do you get an email from a cloud provider?
Maybe you don't because like, I run all the cloud services at the CS A,
I get an email at least once every month or two saying, you know,
we're going to have an outage window on day X
to like, basically do some upgrades or maintenance or whatever.
And I'm kind of like you're a major, like
I would say like a tier one sass like Atlassian,
-- why do you need an outage window of like two hours? Uh I
-- don't ask questions.
-- I, I don't, I know it's hard but I'm,
-- I'm just saying like, clearly
as we've learned, like when they do actually have an oopsie,
then it's really ugly and bad,
you know?
Ok.
So what I'm saying is we, these, these traditional solutions, they don't,
they can't work in the modern world.
No, no. And that's, that's kind of the point, right? Is
in order for us to tackle problems like this,
we need to change
everything and I know this is sounds ridiculous and it's never gonna happen,
but like we need to change almost everything.
But what we do from the way we build the software to the way we're,
we're sourcing our components to the way we're
dealing with the software as it's being built,
as it's being deployed as it's being run as it's being end of life.
Like these are all important stages of the software like life
cycle and we basically just YOLO all of them today.
Let me ask you a question.
How is a company like Red Hat building a distribution differently than say
Slackware? One point? Oh, did it?
What is,
no, no. What is fundamentally different? And
I
can, no, it is. It's no, no, no, that's, that's
conceptually,
I'm going to tell you to stop talking and you're going
to put on your Dunce cap for a few minutes.
I'm going to explain something that happened. That's really important.
And it's about what Debian has done for this incident
because what Debian has done is the gold standard for
the way everyone should have handled this particular problem.
Now,
Debian unstable had
a the the two vulnerable versions of XZ in it.
So and and this specifically could target Debian systems,
right? This exploit worked on Debian systems. We know that for a fact.
So what Debian did is Debian has, we'll say mostly reproducible builds.
They're not fully reproducible builds, but they're pretty close,
they're close enough.
So what they did is Debian shut down
all of their build infrastructure, right?
They shut it all down because obviously when an incident like
this happens and we didn't yet know what this exploit was doing
-- could be solar winds,
-- right?
The, the correct thing to do is to literally just like shut it all down, right?
We'll figure it out later. Then what happened
was the Debian security team worked with their BUILD team and a lot.
And remember this is Debian, this is a bunch of freaking volunteers. This isn't like
some crazy, you know, company with billions of dollars.
But
so Debian shuts it all down.
Then their,
their security team and their build team basically start rebuilding unstable.
Now you can't just rebuild unstable because here's the
thing to remember when you're building a Linux distribution,
you have to build things in an order and you have to sometimes go
back to older things and rebuild those and things get built in certain ways,
right?
So it's really hard.
Well, like you need to build a compiler before you can like compile the things with
libraries.
But sorry to backtrack what I'm in is conceptually a distribution goes out,
grabs a bunch of software, builds it and ships it
that hasn't changed.
No. But the things Debian
is doing, I think is important, right?
Because they had to start with stable and they
had to get themselves back to unstable using not
the official build infrastructure because the official build
infrastructure wasn't an unknown state at this point,
right?
They start rebuilding things.
They're, they're making, they're, they're,
they're close enough to reproducible build that they
can do verification to say like the thing I
built is exactly the thing that was an unstable so that they can prove it right.
And they basically got themselves back to the point
where minus
a particular version of XZ
in unstable,
they could, they put unstable back together
and they're like, this is, this is correct. This is it.
So now what they're doing is they're turning it up back on and they're just
treating it like a normal security update where
they can basically yank the old packages,
put new packages in place and continue back on.
That level of due diligence is amazing to me. And I,
I promise you there are in a, a lot of Linux distributions
that have not
cannot and will not do this. So like Debian, holy crap, you,
that actually, I mean, that speaks to the one of being able to turn it off and on again.
That's literally no
seriously
like
to be the ability to bootstrap yourself,
right?
Like I actually have like a bootstrap process for my home network,
which is pretty simple.
That's, this feels bigger than bootstrapping even.
This is like this is you have to invent boots first and then like, uh just,
it's amazing.
But this also speaks to,
you know, being able to find where every single, like basically,
if I provide you a set of files,
I
should be able to show where they came from,
right?
I think you would agree.
And that I think was what's interesting to me here is that we have this history of,
well, I can show you where most of them came from.
But like,
you know,
and that's where this reproducible building comes from.
Whereas it's, I can't really show it's like, well,
basically I shove this into GCC version X and like out pops this thing and like,
man,
but if now,
but if you have that same version of GCC and you do it and you get the same thing.
Oh OK. Cool.
And that's I think why reproducible builds are important is
for that is for that bootstrap slash validation piece where
you don't have to have your build infrastructure be this like fortress.
It's like no,
I have the same build infrastructure on my laptop and
I get the same binary bit for bit cool.
Like I think
for
however,
so
there are two things I want to explain about reproducible builds.
So reproducible builds
would not stop this particular attack because
-- if you built XZ twice, you're gonna get the same thing. Both times
-- stupido
would reproducible builds.
I can't think of a single specific CV E that would have been addressed by this.
The only thing reproducible builds would potentially catch
is where the build infrastructure itself is compromised.
Like
that, that is
what
the
but that no,
-- there's a
-- buffer overflow
theoretical given the current situation.
But that is exactly the situation that
Debbie and security team was trying to address
when they were saying are our build hosts
still trustworthy and they proved they are.
That is the question. Reproducible builds don't solve security problems.
-- They solve trustworthiness problems, which
-- is a security problem.
-- Well, I guess
-- because if I need to, like, for example, if I have to rebuild my house,
I can get concrete that is known to be good.
No, this, that, that tangents boring.
I want to bring up another point.
Now, you just mentioned about how many CD ES could this solve?
CD E doesn't cover malicious software. Kurt,
why did this get a CV E?
Well, it doesn't cover intentional backdoors.
So,
and, and thank
Red Hat. Thank you Red Hat for doing this because holy crap.
If this didn't have a CV E,
all of our lives would be like 10 times worse than they are now.
But technically speaking, Red Hat broke the rules.
-- Thank you Red Hat for breaking the rules.
-- I was actually checking.
I have a, I have a long email thread thread from when I was still on the C uh ve board
back in 2018
where basically the consensus was.
Well, if, if we gave a back door a CV E,
-- we'd have to give all the malware A CV E and I'm like,
-- good, do that.
Yeah. Are we gonna run out of numbers? Like, do we not have infinity numbers?
And so someone actually asked this question as they said
N PM removed like 245,000 malicious packages last year.
Should they all get CV ES? They should,
but
the thing is there should be machine readable data in there so that you can easily
it.
Right? I love these people that are like,
and they're like, I'm like, are you reading these by yourself?
Like the same thing with the Linux kernel thing where they're like,
but it's too many CV S and I'm like, well, if you're on the Linux kernel,
should you not be concerned about this?
Now, I, I will say that the, uh uh uh uh what is it? The,
-- the github vulnerability database,
-- github
security advisories, GHS A.
-- Yeah,
-- GHSAGH SAS have a, like malicious
software
ca
and they track all this stuff like it's, it's in there.
So if you're, if you're pulling from their API, you can, you can get that stuff,
which is great and it's important.
Ok. Ok.
So we've got, we covered what Debian's doing.
We covered the fact that maybe it should or shouldn't have a CV E.
-- Well,
-- and this only affected rolling releases.
So essentially for most people, it did not affect prod,
not yet.
It would have though,
-- had this made it from Debbie and unstable into Debbie and stable,
-- right?
Had it not been caught? Absolutely. Yes. It would have gone from Fedora Tyrell
and from
-- blah, blah, blah.
-- That's right.
That's right. Ok.
There's one more piece of this, I think I wanna discuss kind of in,
in terms of doing some, you know, we,
we it's always easy to talk about what just happened
with the eyes of reality in front of us.
You were talking about verifying people, right? And how hard that is
and we can't do it,
right. I think one of the things to think about in the context of software today
is
you have to almost assume that any dependency you're using is malicious.
And what does that mean?
And I don't just mean from a trust perspective,
but like this is like a giant risk equation now, right?
Where I'm going to assume
every piece of software I depend on is malicious in some way.
So how do we make sure that using a malicious piece of software doesn't like
completely break the entire system and we don't know the answer to this yet.
-- But I think that is the question.
-- We have a good peril.
Number one, you said verifying people and that's step one,
step one is verifying the person.
Step two is ongoing verification because what if they sell their account?
-- But
-- we can't verify open source.
Well, and that's what I'm saying is
so number one, you don't have to just verify the person, you have to ongoing,
verify them and make sure they don't sell their account or something.
And number two or number three rather, you'd have to kind of verify their intent.
And this leads Ashley there is now a thing that
monitors chrome extensions to see if they have a new owner
because it has come up now
that
people have been offered quite reasonably,
not great but reasonable sums of money to sell their chrome extensions
so that like tracking code and stuff can be jammed into them
and well, and then potentially some really most malicious stuff could happen.
And so we've already seen this where
this is where somebody like transfers their account because in Google
to transfer a chrome extension from one user to another,
it's like three or four clicks,
it's pretty easy
and it, it's, there's like a record of it happening. But if I were to just
hand over my github
user name, well, which is, you know,
obviously Kurt siefried and my credentials and, you know, and,
and I guess mail a copy of or I'm not a copy, mail my two fa hardware token or,
or update it to a software one and send them the seed
like GTO would be like, well, you know,
he's using a new IP address which I'm doing all the time now because of my VPN.
But
there's,
there's no way to do this.
You would need like literal
NSA level of
like 10 minutes long. We
know. But the point is people think this can be done because they keep suggesting it.
I'm
a people I know, but a lot of people think that it can be done,
which
I want to address that as well. Let's just say, um
there's a lot of brain dead takes about this.
And I'm gonna throw the open SSF under the bus here because II,
I don't know, I'll, I'll, I'll see if archive.org has this blog post they wrote,
but it is
the most insensitive moronic blog post I've seen in a long time.
And it basically says, oh, if we run
open SSF scorecard against XZ, it gets a really low score.
So if they would have run scorecard, they could have avoided this. And it's like,
what? No,
no,
but it's just, you know, it's like pull your hair out, stupid thing to say.
And I think here's the thing, but here's the thing, Kurt,
this is the freaking open SSF these are supposed to
be the people that are like helping defend open source.
They're, they clearly have no idea what's even going on.
Well, they're also trying to advance their own agenda, but it also raises,
I can't live without XC.
Like I have to be able to uncompress XC data for my system to work.
Yes.
The world needs this library 100% like, OK,
here's one of the other terrifying things.
So when you build a Linux kernel,
you can compress the kernel with XZ
and this particular attacker was trying to get themselves added as
one of the XZ like maintainers to the Linux kernel.
So think about that one, if they had pulled that off.
Now, that's the long game.
Literally, you need a one bit flip in the Linux kernel.
And that would be a remotely exploitable. Like you send a wonky TCP packet and boop
because we've seen that.
Like, we've had those flaws. This is not
theory.
-- There have been like literal.
-- And now here's the uncomfortable reality.
I think we should end this show on
which is we found out this attack,
there is a 0% chance. This is the only one
and we only found out this attack by literally winning the lottery.
-- It was very much winning the lottery.
-- Yes. Like I'm actually almost,
it's almost
improbable
that that person found and did enough research to track down this regression.
But like the Cuckoo's Nest, you know, Clifford stole where uh what was it,
a 26 cent accounting
issue?
You know, it led them to these German hackers in the system, right?
But I mean, and that's the thing is like,
well, we've won the lottery once this year. Great.
I don't know that this is a sustainable way of doing it. It,
it obviously is not, we need.
And what to do is like, there's people saying, oh, we should pay maintainers.
There's people saying we need, we need to put this stuff in foundations.
There's,
there's all these hot takes about how to solve this problem by doing this one thing.
And there isn't going to be one easy answer.
Like I would love to say we should pay every maintainer and I agree with that.
-- We should,
-- but some of them don't even want to be paid or can't legally be paid.
And there's a guy again, I've seen the thread unmasked it now for everything.
You can imagine. There's a guy who runs, it's called like S TB.
It's a single, is it SS TB image, I think? Um, let me just look it up quick.
Um, yeah. Yeah. It's called S TB.
It's single file, public domain libraries for CN C++.
It's used by like a lot of game devs
like images and whatnot. And, and if you look at this, the STV uh uh github
repo, I'll put a link to it in the show notes
and they've got a freaking giant warning at the top. I'm just gonna read it.
This is in like bold huge text is,
this project discusses security relevant bugs in public in github
issues and full request.
And it may take significant time for security fixes to be implemented or merged
if this poses an unreasonable risk to your project, do not use STV library.
And the reason is, it's this guy said like it's him and his friend
and they do it
for fun.
They don't want to be paid even if they were paid,
they probably won't be paid enough to matter.
Like they,
they, they, they, they do this a week a year.
Basically, they work on this library and they're happy with that.
But anyway, the point is
we do not know
what to do about this problem. That is the honest to God reality of where we are.
We don't know how to solve the maintainer problems.
We don't know how to solve the technical problems.
We don't know how to solve like the downstream
user problems.
This is a million problems that, that quite frankly,
uh many open source people have realized.
-- But now everyone is learning about,
-- I'm gonna disagree with you there.
We are only seeing the tip of the iceberg. Literally,
we have no idea. Like you said, there's a million problems. Yes, they're,
they're,
we're into the unknown.
Like we're,
most people aren't even acknowledging that there's the unknown unknowns yet.
And they're like, oh we saw this dragon. So there's a dragon cool. But like you said,
our
do we need to go through all the new developers in the last two years, five years,
10 years, 20 years
when you're talking about that is idiotic.
You're wasting your time to even bring that up as a one.
But
people are bringing this up.
People have been saying, remember the Google blog where they literally were like,
we need to identify everybody in open source and blah, blah, blah,
that's Google. They want to do that for a different reason.
You know,
like people serious people have seriously proposed
this type of solution in the past
and
current.
No, I I know I get that and, and look, here's what I would say as,
as this will be kind of my,
my closing thought on this is so I know like people like Toma de
Pierre. Toma is out in front of a lot of people all the time
and he has
his advice is often hard to accept, but it's, it's pretty good and I think he gets it.
But here's the thing, he's someone doing the work. He's not a talking head
that's being paid by some giant company
to push an agenda.
Like this is a guy doing the Lord's work for free.
Essentially, there are a lot of people like Toma
and those are the people we need to listen to
because the people who solve this problem are
not the people running the open ssf clearly,
it's not the people working for some big company.
It's going to be the people doing this for fun because they understand the problems
and to just
clarify a bit,
the people that are going to solve this problem for the open source world
because there will be people that want to and perhaps do solve this problem.
And it's a commercial product which doesn't help the open source world even a tiny,
little bit.
In most cases,
it has
-- to
-- be and that's compatible
source.
So,
and, and Kurt, the open
source world is just called the world.
Exactly.
I I'm excited by this because nothing will change.
-- So I have job security, which is fantastic.
-- That's true. Good news.
Security people were all still employed.
But some of the stuff I've been saying for a long time is kind of like, see, like I said,
so and I'm, I'm gonna, I think here's how I'm gonna end the show.
How about this as a goal?
We are able to look at any file
on the file system that is from
the distro, let's say, or from pi pie
or you whacked it in with N PM.
And I think it's not unreasonable to say as a goal, not a short term goal,
mind you but a long term goal.
But any file on the file system that is essentially from
some software distribution thing.
I should be able to track it down and figure out how and when it got to be there.
And the
like how like how did this happen? Like, oh, it's not in the tar ball.
Oh It's part of the build process. Oh It's
blah, blah, blah.
And we're nowhere near that.
Not even a tiny bit
like I got dot Wheels all over my system.
And if you ask me where they're from,
there's no is there does pipe pie have like an R PM
verify equivalent in PP for me to see where those wheels came from
that still what solve this problem?
No, no, but I'm saying that would be a step in the right direction.
It's one of the steps and I think, I mean,
there's people working on like reproducible build,
things like Debbie is doing a great job
and, and definitely,
well, but what I'm pointing out is pi pie and wheels.
Like I ran into the problem with the pi pie uh lip uh the,
the Python curl library interface thing on a jigger
can't find my certificates
because it's
the Python Pi pie.
The curl
stuff is built on an arch Linux distribution
and there's no way to fix that.
So it looks in one spot.
And so I have a bunch of, you know, hack together code and I put breadcrumbs in all the
spaces where people were complaining about this being broken.
So they can see the curl, you know, the, the Python code to fix this.
But the point is like even something as quote unquote,
air quotes as simple as pi P install lip curl.
I think it's lip curl. I wanna say anyways, whatever.
I don't know where that stuff came from or how it got to be there or what it was built on.
-- Well, I, I think that's a lot of a goal
-- and I'm not saying this will solve it,
but as a goal, that would be a good step.
I, I agree.
And I think my one other piece to that is like I just interrupted and said,
this wouldn't solve the problem we're talking about and it wouldn't, but
just because something doesn't solve one problem doesn't mean it's not valuable.
And as we saw the the work Debian did.
The,
the reproducible builds are extremely valuable in this sort of situation
even though they aren't directly related to the issue at hand.
So, ok, we've been going on about this for darn near an hour already
and I think we've covered more things than I can
count and I have to edit this freaking episode still.
So
it's,
that's gonna be neat.
This, this 1 may be a little, this one will be a little rougher than most I think at the,
at the editing table.
But it look at the end of the day.
Here's the thing, I'm sure we're gonna talk about this again.
I'm actually leaving for, for
Bides Milwaukee in Cipher Con on, on Tuesday night
to go. I'm sure this will be the talk of the hallway for the,
all the, all the shows and I can't wait to see what I learn.
Like,
I'm trying to figure out how do I express this in a half page to a
page for like high level people that isn't
utterly depressing and so terrible that they like,
immediately dismiss it.
So here's what I did for my kid,
my, my wife and kid were like, because I'm, I was, I, so every, no,
no one else knows this.
I've just spent, I literally got home like an hour before Kurt Knight's hit record,
which has been like two hours at this point.
I was visiting colleges with my oldest
and at one point during the trip, I obviously got really weird.
They're like, what's going on? I'm like, just Google for something called XZ.
They're like, what does that even mean? I'm like, I'm, I'll tell you some other day.
Like, that's the most you're getting out of me right now.
And they, my, my wife is like, I have no idea what this is.
My kid was like, this looks bad. I was like, yes, yes. It is.
This is the scene from what's the mutant fungus TV show?
I'm spacing out among us.
No, not among us. Um The last of us,
this is the scene from the last of us
where the military general is talking to the expert
and she's like, can I please go home to my family? And he's like,
but what do we do? And she's like, can I please go home to my family?
And he's like, but we have to solve this. She's like, yeah. No, we can't.
Can I please go home to my family? So I can say goodbye to them basically.
And he's like, what do you mean? She's like, we can't solve this. We can't fix this.
We're doomed,
right?
We're not doomed. But I mean, this is this level like I feel like that expert.
Do you feel like that expert where it's just like
all these things we've been anticipating with Pandora?
All right.
Damn it, Kurt, you're just made this episode longer than a show.
Here's, here's what I want to end this on.
We should not lose hope over this happening.
This is
I think a natural progression of
what is we call open source.
I do not think we should lose hope.
I do not think that we should necessarily make any drastic actions due to this.
I think this is an opportunity to learn new things and to solve new problems.
I am not hopeless at all. I think open source is going to be fine.
I think society is going to be fine,
-- to be clear. I'm not hopeless either.
-- This is,
this is a big deal
and I don't think we're gonna learn as many lessons as we should,
but I think we will learn some lessons from this.
Well, I I'm not saying it's hopeless. I'm just saying for example,
same thing with Log for J what happened? Not really a lot. And you know what?
It's ok like life goes on.
No, I'm serious. Like it
is
-- crap
-- from Log for J.
I,
like I would say as an industry, we didn't learn anything.
But I think as individuals, a lot of smart people learned a lot of smart people things
and I
think,
but if we done anything actionable,
like started washing our hands to prevent the plague
from happening and the answer is not really.
And that's ok like
it, that just life goes on.
-- Like
-- I'm hopeful
this will cause some lawmakers to take some
actions because I think Log for Jay did compel some lawmakers to take some actions.
But we now come back to the issue of lawmakers are going to talk to people like the
open ssf and giant corporations when the people they
actually need to go talk to are Toma de
Pierre.
And that
is the challenge.
All right, I'm ending this. This has been, we're over an hour now. Good job.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you, everyone who made it this far. Go to
our security podcast.com.
Hit up the, we'll have a bunch of show notes to a bunch of crazy stuff.
Uh I guess, yeah, I have what
yon
do I says podcast hashtag hit us
on Mastodon, I guess. Happy April fools everybody.
What a
what a what a week. All right. Thanks Kurt. I talk to you later, man.
-- Thanks
-- everybody. Bye bye.
Bye bye.