Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 183 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
-- So, what's new?
-- Well, today, I'm working from home.
-- We work from home every day.
-- Kurt
only for the last 22 years for me.
Has it been that long for me? I don't, I started working from home in 2004.
-- You're a late adopter.
-- It is 2020 now
it is 2020. Actually, I keep forgetting that
I know and yet the world still hasn't ended inexplicably
to
all the evidence we've seen so far.
Yeah, I know.
Apparently the world's largest work from home experiment is happening
as we record this.
Yeah, you, you sent me that link and I'll of course, put it in the show notes.
There's this fascinating hacker news discussion and Kurt sends me an email
and I hadn't really thought about this, but
uh for kind of future reference for anyone listening across the sands of time,
the Coronavirus outbreak.
The
novel
Coronavirus.
The what
I believe the official name is the novel Coronavirus.
Coronavirus.
-- Oh,
-- is it? I don't know. I don't know anything about viruses.
Well, computer viruses. I know a little bit, but,
ok,
so we're just going to call it Coronavirus for the rest of the show because
I'm not going to say novel Coronavirus over
and over again because that sounds annoying.
It is what it like, like a month old,
-- maybe at this point a
-- month and a half to almost two months old it looks like because,
yeah, some information might have been.
Well,
we'll say
widespread panic is about a month old.
Oh, yeah, we're firmly, we're definitely like on the Gartner hype curve,
we're definitely at the peak of inflated expectations.
The only difference being is that pandemics sometimes
it's not like a tech product where it's like, oh, it didn't work, right? And didn't
succeed.
It's like pandemics have this bad habit of, yeah,
sometimes wiping out a good chunk of humanity.
Let's hope this one doesn't work. Right.
But anyway,
because of just kind of everything,
an enormous number of people are starting to work from home, especially in China.
It's not so much that it's the, the, the country is largely being shut down. Like to
put it bluntly,
the easiest way to stop a pandemic is social distancing which
you and I are good at because we work from home.
We don't like people. So we already do this naturally.
Right. Exactly.
You know,
you and I tend not to go to big meetings of people and big groups and rock concerts and
whatnot.
But that's the reality. Right. You get
somebody with something like this coughing and sneezing in
a crowd of a couple of 1000 people and,
well, like, honestly go watch the movie Contagion.
It's actually
-- reasonably well done. I
-- don't know if I've seen that one, I've watched
with the disease. Movies were hip. What was that, like, 5, 10 years ago?
And
I watched some of them.
Not all
but. Right.
Right. Right.
And I mean, I,
I suffer from this on a regular basis where I will go
to a conference and then I come home with the con flu
and
it blows. And actually one time I legitimately caught the flu on a business trip.
And that was like the worst thing ever. And
the,
we knew who patient zero was because like, 10 of us caught the flu.
It was,
it was
an unenjoyable experience. I will say so.
Yeah, I mean, basically all major public events have been shut down and
Google has shut down all their offices.
Apple has shut down all their offices and stores in China. I mean,
a
lot of companies that it apparently got so bad that some
of the major Chinese tech companies were saying not only are
you working from home today but don't use the VPN because
we need to reserve what little bandwidth we have left for the
sad mins to make sure they can get in and keep everything from burning down.
I saw that. That's mind
boggling in a lot of ways.
Well, ok, it's a cloud provider by definition like Aws or something or, or
Azure has a ton of bandwidth going into their data centers, but the majority of
corporate on premises networks don't have a lot of bandwidth,
like maybe a gigabit at most.
Yeah, you're probably right, I suppose.
Which sounds like a lot until you get like 1000 people all trying to use it and
video conference at the same time,
right? And
additionally,
most of the people are probably using
some pretty heavy applications, right?
When you're transferring files, you might be doing some citric sort of operation,
you know, remote desktop and whatever
and
you're absolutely right.
Where if people are generally doing a lot of this in house,
you can have really fast networks in house
and then have we'll say less fast networks to the outside. Right?
Well, and there's a lot of applications that are web delivered and quite heavy,
right?
I mean, the front page of CNN is like what three megabytes now
and you look at a lot of web application delivery platforms and you know,
they have big fat heavy stalking web pages,
which who cares when you're on a local gigabit network.
So actually,
I have a funny story I can tell you about that is so obviously I
work at elastic and we have a kind of front end to your data called Cabana
and you can do all this interesting stuff with it and it's
a lot of javascript on the back end and the front end.
And the first time you connect to Cabana,
you download about five megabytes of stuff.
That's just all the javascript you need to basically make it work.
And I always chuckle because I will get these people love running those, you know,
blanket security scanners that look for all kinds of stuff.
And like these scanning companies, obviously,
the bigger the scanner report is the better it must be right kids.
And so you'll get these phone book scans and people will say, oh you're, you know,
you're using, you're,
you're sending me data that's being stored in my web browser cache.
We're like, yeah, because if you don't,
you got to download five megabytes every freaking time you
click something like you don't want to do that.
-- Like, oh no, my security team said I need it. Well,
-- it's also static data.
-- I mean, it's content delivery. That's how this is supposed to work.
-- That's right.
It literally never changes. And I'm like, fine, you know what?
Great, disable the cash. Go right ahead
like
this is really slow and like, yeah,
we know like you're downloading five megabytes of
crap every time you click a button.
I mean, what did you expect to happen?
And uh
yes. So anyway, no, I totally get that and I can,
I'm sure there are plenty of applications that are in
this exact same situation where the security team was,
like, oh, you can't cash anything because that's insecure.
So, like, hm. Ok.
And when you're on a corporate network,
downloading five megabytes might take half a second.
But when you're,
when you're on the internet it might take 10 seconds.
Well, the biggest thing too is when you're on the corporate network, your,
your latency to your on premises stuff is measured in like
single digit milliseconds.
But when you're VPN in, from your, like,
internet connection at home,
yeah, it's going to be tens or hundreds of milliseconds. And,
you know,
I remember
using an app that had something like 10 or
20 round trips to the database for each page request
again.
Absolutely fine when you're on the corporate network because it's, you know,
like five or 10 milliseconds per round trip.
No big deal.
But when you're some dumb schmuck up in Canada, like me.
And the round trip time is like 300 milliseconds.
Right.
You know. Yeah. Not so good.
Right. Right. Exactly.
Yeah.
Well,
and the other brutal thing is how many of these places do you think have ever done,
like a real world test of this?
Like, you know, Netflix has their chaos, monkey and chaos gorilla and they do their,
like, ok, we're turning, like everything in Amazon East one off.
Let's see what breaks.
You know, most companies don't do that.
Especially like, ok, everybody's gonna work from home today.
I,
I'm actually trying to think of a single place
I've ever heard of doing a drill that way.
And nothing comes to mind
-- to my
-- knowledge,
I've never heard of it and I'm going through things in my brain and it's coming up dry
or an even more extreme. Ok. Everybody's working from home this week.
No, like straight up.
Like we're like, we're locking the office doors and none of you get to, like,
let's pretend we found asbestos in the carpets or something.
Right. Like the, the off,
you know, there are events that shut down offices,
like somebody has a fire or smoke damage or somebody spills something toxic.
Like, I don't know, like, for the sake of argument, like a big thing of, I don't know,
floor cleaner fluid or something, whatever.
Right.
So, or there's a gas leak or whatever, you know. And so how
places have actually done a real world disaster recovery scenario of like,
ok, let's pretend like our head office is gone for a week.
Well,
most places probably don't have to because let's
face it in the vast majority of situations.
The odds of this happening for more than one day are very
low and you could view it like a snow day where,
like, local places around here and I'm sure you have it too if you get, I mean,
we have to get a lot of snow but it'll happen.
-- Uh,
-- we generally don't we? Yeah, we,
you're expected to, you know?
Yeah, city plows get out and
-- you go to work
-- right where, where we live. But it does happen
where occasionally
people will say don't come into work because it's a mess.
And actually ice, ice is an easy one where you'll get freezing rain.
And we've actually had a lot of that this year because, like, the climate's broken.
-- Yeah. Sorry about that. Kids.
-- We've had a lot of freezing rain with ice.
There's like, there's nothing you can do. And so people just say
you just drive slowly, don't come.
Even if you drive Kurt, you have to get to a parking lot that is an ice rink and then get,
like,
not crash into anyone parking your car and then get from your car
to the office door without getting run over or falling and dying.
I remember one of my favorite memories is a few years ago
we had a really good freezing rain slash freeze thaw melt cycle.
And so I went to the, actually, uh, the best buy parking lot because they,
they have a really nice big flat parking lot.
And, uh, I was just doing lovely donuts in it at about five kilometers an hour.
Like, my speedometer wasn't even registering speed
and I was just kind of doing Piro, what's on the parking lot at two in the morning.
Yeah, that's how you get arrested. Kurt.
-- It was actually quite fun
-- because even if you're not blindingly drunk,
they're gonna assume there's something wrong with you
and they're pulling you in.
-- So, don't, don't,
-- I wasn't the only person I saw doing it.
-- It, it's just fun to take your car skating once
-- in a while. I won't disagree with you.
But,
yeah, anyway, anyway.
But, yeah, so this is, and, and clearly, you know,
for a lot of these companies and whatnot,
they don't have the technology to support everybody working from home.
They don't have
the business process.
And what makes me laugh is all these people are like, oh, but if people work from home,
how do we know they're actually working and it's like,
pretty sure that statement also applies when they're, like,
physically in the office and, like reading Reddit on the computer.
-- Right.
-- Right. Well, so this is,
this is one of the points
I feel like it's always interesting because when you, like, when I go to the office,
you might as well just count that as like, vacation days because I get nothing done
because I, I screw around
and
let's hope no one I work with listens to this.
But,
but right, there's, but when you work from home and you go to the office,
it's like getting nothing done.
And so I can see that as being kind of an opposite action when you
work in an office and now you go to work from home if you're not disciplined
and
I mean, I remember from, I,
I luckily I haven't had this problem in a very long
time but there would be instances where people would say,
oh, I want to be your own employee
and they become a remote employee and then they would just stop being an
employee after a little while because it's like you're not getting anything done.
What's the deal here?
Well, and somebody pointed out quite fairly in this instance it's
-- a little different too because everybody's kids are at home.
-- Oh, that's true.
That's a good point.
Right. Because nobody can go anywhere and, and
I will say
that when my,
it's better now that my kids are a little older because
they just go and play like video games or whatever.
But when they were young and I work from home and they were home,
there were times it was a nuisance and it'd be like, I'm shutting my door
and you're gonna leave me alone and then they're like, banging on the door.
Like, what are you doing in there? I'm like, I'm trying to,
I can get paid by doing my job,
like, get out of here.
So, I mean, that's fair.
But I,
I feel like there are probably places that will treat this
as maybe a disaster scenario from this point forward because I
think the odds of making people work from home for long
periods of time is not unrealistic as it's happening now.
But I mean, practically speaking,
I,
I
think prior to this, has it,
has anything really happened that would create a situation like this?
Well, SARS,
I don't feel like that one
-- was as bad.
-- Well, they didn't shut down the country.
-- I
-- remember we were, we were traveling, we both had a trip. I think we were in London.
We had a work trip in London when we worked together during the SARS epidemic.
I got hired after the London trip.
You were not in London. Ok.
But I, I remember it,
we,
I was traveling internationally during this and there was a crazy amount of
documents and signs and everything everywhere you went like it was bananas.
Well, I mean, you know, they're predicting that this is, well,
this has already hit global oil markets, right?
Demand has fallen and the
price of oil has dropped. Like
that's,
yeah, like that's,
wow.
Actually, you know what I realized about that, that got me thinking is
it's been a month and we're already concerned about
oil demand and oil supply
which tells you just how kind of
this is like on demand supply chain, right? Where in a month?
-- Well, everything's on demand now it's efficient,
-- right? That, that's pretty cool.
Well, and, and this is one of the things that kind of freaks me out about modern
disaster preparedness is here's the reality, right?
And UPS even has commercials for this, you know, let Brown be your warehouse.
If you have, let's say $50 million in medical supply,
sitting in a warehouse just in case something bad happens,
that's $50 million of capital sitting there depreciating.
Plus you have to pay for storage and whatnot.
Now,
it's great when a hurricane hits and you can just haul
it all out of the warehouse and get going real fast.
But, but most companies
have to be efficient now. And a great example of this is like Power Line repair.
Most companies have cut back on Power Line repair and maintenance.
And so now when there's natural disaster,
like there are literally Canadian Power Line crews going
down to the Carolinas and stuff to help after hurricanes
because it's part of they have like a mutual assistance set up, which is great.
But you know, this, if you want efficiency,
then you don't have like $10,000 of canned food
in your basement because that is not efficient.
I mean, this is an interesting discussion also,
especially in the context of security
because
you can make the argument
that investing in your infrastructure isn't necessarily efficient,
-- having a hot disaster recovery site.
-- I mean. Right.
-- Yes, that's a great example
-- until you need it. It's just a waste of money.
Right.
It absolutely is. And
when you need it, you need it.
And if you don't have one,
your dr plan might be, get a new job.
So this is a tough one, man. I mean, it's always difficult to, to juggle.
What's a good investment?
Well, so this is why, for example,
I've always tried to sort of get dual purpose disaster gear, like
camping gear because occasionally I do go camping or
actually I did buy a bit of extra food that
will last a long time because they had steak
canned chili on sale and craft dinner on sale.
And the stuff lasts long enough that I'll eventually eat it regardless
of it being.
But I was looking online at, you know, like Mountain House and whatnot, you know,
the dried food buckets and it's like, man, I'm never gonna eat that, like,
as much as I enjoy, you know, like watching Steve, uh MRE info on youtube,
I don't really have a great desire to eat 50 kg of, you know, freeze dried vegetables.
And
what I love is the one place had freeze dried buckets of uh variety meat.
So I'm assuming it's just like whatever random
scraps they can get at whatever cheap price,
you know, be it pork or beef that week?
Is it called variety meat? Is that the name?
That's phenomenal?
Oh, my goodness.
-- Yeah,
-- if you Google, yes, it's,
it's the nutri store freeze dried meat variety bucket.
Part of me wants to buy one just to see what the heck is going on in there.
-- You'd probably just go eat at Taco Bell or something.
-- Here we go.
They're 200 bucks and they're out of stock
probably because everybody
Well, right now, I bet, I bet the prepper people are going crazy.
Not even prepper people but like, just people trying to buy N95 masks.
Yeah, that's probably true.
Oh, my goodness. The mask, the masks are a great one.
Especially from a security perspective because
I believe it's the, the, well,
I'm sure multiple disease organizations have said this but
legitimate
-- ones like the
-- CDC. Right.
I know in the US, the CDC, the Center for Disease Control, I believe it's called
plural.
OK. Whatever.
It's fine. CDC.
The CDC gave advice that basically said washing your
hands is more effective than wearing those masks.
And I'm not shocked to learn this,
but I feel like this is the ultimate security lesson of is
anyone going to wash their hands more instead of buying masks?
I am but probably no one else.
And the reality is wearing a mask has a couple of effects. It's a very active thing.
So you can feel like you're doing something, it
shows off to other people, you're doing something
and
you're spending money
on a new thing that's going to make you feel better. Like
I have soap, I have a sink. I have hands just
use it all more than you did yesterday.
Well, there is one rather ironic benefit of wearing a mask and,
or glasses or face shield, which is people touch their face less,
which really helps when they're not washing their hands enough.
-- And
-- that's true. That probably does.
I'll agree with that because I'm like, I'm notorious,
-- basically
-- boils down to it.
You are better off washing your hands like some crazed little raccoon.
Which is
again,
but again, at the same time, how many, I mean,
we can all say this where we've gone into the bathroom,
we're standing there washing our hands and we see a guy just like, leave
the worst is the airports because it's like you're gonna now touch
all the things I'm going to touch to your filthy ape.
Just this is terrible.
I've considered wearing gloves in public, but you know,
especially when you wear latex or nitro gloves, your hands get super sweaty
because by definition you're wearing gloves.
But I,
I actually have been thinking about wearing gloves out in public again because
not because I'm so worried about Coronavirus.
But again, yeah, I literally see people like use a toilet
come out of the toilet and like walk out of the bathroom and it's like, uh,
you know, like
they,
they pulled the door open and now I have to, you know, I,
I'll do the thing where I like get my sleeve over my hand and you know,
hook it with two fingers with the sleeve over it.
Right.
I,
you know, that's one thing. Shout out to Costco. Their bathrooms don't have doors.
I love that.
Do they not? I haven't been to their bathroom.
They have like a 90 degree bend and you're in the bathroom.
I mean, and I'm, I prefer that I don't want to touch a gross door.
It's also faster and you don't get a door in the face.
-- It's like they know what they're doing or something.
-- It's ironic. Right.
Because if you look at bathroom technology,
we've been the steady march of progress of not
having to actually touch stuff in the bathroom.
Right. Like sensors for the urinals and the toilets to flush it automatically.
So you don't have to touch the handle,
which by
definition you can't have washed your hands yet.
I'm going to complain about this because every time I go,
especially for whatever reason,
airports are the worst offenders of this where you go to use it.
And the stupid thing just flushes like 30
times and it's like shooting water everywhere.
It's like this is gross. You're wasting water
-- and like, you're just making everything worse for everyone. In
-- most places.
Water is a renewable resource. So you're not really wasting it.
It's, I mean, if you're using groundwater and pulling it from an aqui,
yeah, the, the, the replenishment time on those things is,
well, it's geological
but like for example, where I live, we have a river, we pull water out of the river,
we use it, we treat it, we throw it back in and that's how most places work.
No,
no, they don't. I get my water from Lake Michigan.
I know.
Yeah. And then you treat it and put it back in.
Yes.
But most places don't,
the vast majority of places in the United States that I know of have wells.
And you can imagine
they just keep drilling them deeper and deeper and deeper.
I would be curious to see that because I know like in Jakarta, for example, yeah,
it's such a problem that the whole city is sinking.
And Indonesia is actually talking about relocating
-- their capital, which is, that's just bonkers.
-- Right.
Well, in Cape Town is run out of water. They were using wells.
No, they had a rain and dams
and various reservoirs that are dried out.
This thing has water sources but the font is too small to read. That's
well. Ok. I should say, I'm pretty sure most major cities draw water, not from wells,
-- but the smaller towns definitely have are primarily wells.
-- So, yeah.
No,
I definitely don't want to be wasting that water
because it takes a long time to replenish.
But
I mean, back to this, that there is the reality is that's just a crap
sensor technology that could work, right? And should work. Right.
And I do love that more and more bathrooms.
Like there's less stuff I have to touch in there.
You know, because you do see a lot of people who are not the cleanest,
like they don't wash their hands or they don't wash their hands properly
because like washing your hands correctly is actually a nontrivial task.
Well, it's trivial if you know what to do.
-- Well,
-- but I mean, it's like brushing your teeth.
It actually takes one or two minutes and you have to, you know, get
kind of everything. Right.
You have to wiggle your fingers together and get all that.
Whereas most people kind of rub their hands together and rinse them.
I know.
I'm not, no,
I'm not going to go on this rant because I could
rant for a really long time about people washing their hands.
But I won't, I won't.
So we'll, I'll find a youtube video,
put it in the show notes that tells you how to wash your hands.
That is another classic security problem is that the,
the thing that is most effective is
something that takes constant vigilance and effort.
You know, it's like, it's like being a good driver, being a,
the driver means you're always paying attention and trying to
anticipate what's going to happen as opposed to like,
you know, twittering while you're making a left hand turn into a traffic circle.
Except we have acknowledged on multiple occasions that the only solution
to better drivers is not to let people do it.
And so for example,
hospitals and some places now are experimenting
with different door handles that have,
you know,
um what is it? Oh yeah.
Titanium dioxide when light hits it, it creates, I forget what it was,
but it basically kills germs and bacteria.
Quite effectively.
Brass also has, you know, properties of being sort of,
what is the word I want germicide or something.
Antimicrobial.
Thank you.
But I've seen, you know,
like you can buy Japanese toilet seats that have like a lid that
comes down and shines a UV light on the thing to sanitize it.
-- I mean, that's pretty
-- cool.
And I saw one cool concept.
It was a sort of a clear glass door handle with like a UV light inside of it.
Interesting.
But then
that only solves the micro problem.
It doesn't solve the fecal matter on your
hands problem because you didn't wash your hands.
Well, it renders it hopefully sterile and safe.
-- Yeah,
-- that's probably fair.
So,
but yeah, I mean,
it's,
well, yeah, washing your hands is a classic, I mean,
and then there's the extreme case, for example,
there was an air Canada flight coming out of China
with no working water on the flight.
So apparently they just put a whole bunch of hand sanitizer
and wipes in the bathroom which they ran out of like,
four hours into the flight or something stupid.
That seems terrible.
-- I'm shocked that was legal.
-- How would it be illegal?
-- What's,
-- there's all kinds of regulations that talk about, like,
like you have to have a working bathroom for the airplane to take
off and I would think that doesn't count as a working bathroom.
Oh,
no, the bathroom worked. It's just, there was no running water.
-- No,
-- no running water is part of having a working bathroom.
Well, I mean, this is from literally yesterday, you know,
an Air Canada flight took off from Beijing to Toronto with no
running water on board last week amid the worsening novel Coronavirus outbreak.
A
move that has angered the union representing flight attendants.
I love that it's the flight attendants that are grumpy about this.
I mean as they should be. But
anyways it was a 13 hour flight, the washrooms ran out of antiseptic wipes
meant to replace the traditional hand washing after about four hours.
Anyways, blah, blah, blah, blah.
But um
yeah, I mean
now they're saying that they're not going,
oh Air Canada says it will no
longer operate international flights with water issues.
Like
good job guys.
You know what's funny is I remember flying on an Air Canada
flight from Toronto to Sao Paulo and onwards to Buenos Aires.
And I noticed like the curtain rod at the back was
broken and I like pointed that out to one of the flights
like then they're like, oh, ok and they like wrote it down.
I'm like, oh, you know, they're going to fix that and he's like, yes,
we have a zero defect policy and I'm like, no, you don't like I noticed a defect.
Well, no, you can have a policy.
You just don't have to enforce it.
But I'm like, clearly you don't have a proper zero defect policy because
I'm noticing this broken thing,
your cleaning crew should have caught that you'd think.
And it's one of those things that look like it
-- had been broken for a while and
-- that could be,
it wouldn't, it wouldn't surprise me.
-- God bless
-- airline. Why do we think business would, taking a plane out of services?
That's a lot of money.
And they have regular maintenance. They're probably, I mean,
and, and that's how it's going to work. Right. If they have a zero
defect policy, they aren't going to like,
take a plane out of rotation to fix a curtain rod, they're going to say,
fix it next time you're getting maintenance done,
which I'm sure happens like once a month or once a quarter or whatever.
Yeah,
I get that. I mean, I would imagine unless the defect is something that ground
the plane, it's not getting fixed.
Well, I mean, there's now been what,
two cases of Air Canada flights with the wheels falling off of it,
that's safe.
Well, I mean, in the one case the wheel fell off and, um,
but the good news is that the way that it's like a turbo prop and it's got two,
you know, two main landing gear on each side with two Ws each.
And so it's actually like,
you know, this is why I love engineers because
engineers occasionally ask awkward questions. Like what if a wheel falls off and?
Ok, well, let's put two on each side so one can fall off and we're still ok.
That's wasting money on backup infrastructure.
Yeah.
Um,
well, plus it makes it easier to change tires and stuff. There's other benefits
too.
But, um, regardless and then there was, I think a more recent one.
but, uh,
no, I mean, it's,
it's clear that maintenance and disaster preparedness typically costs money.
That is just sort of,
I don't want to say wasted,
but it's wasted unless you need it and you may never need it.
Right. And I mean, that's the ultimate
kind of security problem to solve is what is the right amount of investment
in terms of your secure? Let's assuming your security investment is a cost.
Where do you draw that line? Because obviously you could have no security
and then you're,
there's a very high probability you're going to have a problem
that's going to cost you a lot of money to fix.
But if you have too much security,
you're basically wasting money because you've made it to the
point where you're spending money on problems that aren't real.
You may not be because for example,
let's say you spend a whole bunch of extra money on physical security
and you never get a break in.
Well,
is it because nobody ever tried to break in or is it
literally like people were going to try and break in every day?
Went to your property?
Oh, wow. They have so much physical security, I give up.
I'm not even going to try and it worked.
One of the biggest problems with security is you don't actually know,
kind of how often it worked or didn't work necessarily.
Although I would bet you in terms of physical security,
I bet the insurance industry has those numbers where they know if you have
like a camera in your lobby,
this is what it means in terms of having physical security issues.
-- Well,
-- the classic, you know, what's the best home security thing? A big loud dog?
Right?
Because every, like, every time I've read an interview or seen a documentary about,
you know, house break ins and burglary, every single one of them is like, yeah,
I don't want to deal with that dog.
It's loud and it might bite me.
My dog would betray me for a hot dog.
And I guarantee he is very loud though, when,
when someone shows up at the house he makes any noise.
And he's actually really funny because he's a really big,
really scary sounding dog.
But, yeah, like for real, if you gave him a hot dog,
you now have a best friend for life guaranteed.
It's, yeah.
Yep. Yep. Which whatever, please don't rob me. Now, people,
I don't know, I, I, I'm willing to bet quite a lot of money but this
pandemic, even if it is
quite bad
will have no real appreciable
effect on sort of how we do things long term,
like,
will hand washing rates go up probably in the low single
-- digit percentages
-- for a little while it'll go back down.
I mean, this is human nature, I think is we are creatures
of enormous inaction
and you can look at countless things that have happened before in
the past and we have a remarkable skill for ignoring problems.
I mean, SARS happen,
well, especially if they go away for a bit.
Right. Right. Yeah. Like, because SARS happens, do we do anything?
No,
-- in
-- fairness.
One thing I have seen is there's more and
more hand sanitizer stations all over the place,
like, especially at grocery stores and other stores.
Although, I mean, that's,
that's an example of studies are showing that
overuse of hand sanitizer has a similar kind of
effect on the universe as overuse of antibiotics
do where we're basically killing the weak bacteria.
-- So the strong can survive
-- actually worse than that. The overuse of it.
The alcohol dries out your skin cracks and makes you more susceptible to infection.
Of course it does.
And, but again, this comes back to that human problem of,
we feel like we're doing something.
So let's keep doing that some more when the reality is actually no,
you're not helping at all by doing that thing even though it makes you feel better.
And, I mean,
this is like the eternal challenge for just security people dealing with humans is
we are notoriously bad at actually understanding
any sort of real risk and knowing what to do about it and I mean, pick on anything.
You know, I've, I've done my, that research where you've got, you know,
automobile safety, you have airline safety, you have mine safety,
you have pollution
and like we have literally waited till people were getting killed, left and right,
and things were lighting on fire before we cared.
And it's because like, it got so bad, we couldn't ignore it. And
in, in this particular case,
the Coronavirus might get so bad
that we can't ignore it. And I think it is in some places.
Well, it's already been declared a global health emergency slash pandemic.
-- Like it, it looks like it's not going to be like a fizzle.
-- It's,
but, but at the same time, like where I live and I don't know about where,
where you're at, but like where I live it has not had a drastic effect on
anyone's behavior yet because we don't have it here yet.
As soon as it shows up.
Well, there's nothing you can really do to be honest.
-- Well,
-- not right now, but as soon as it shows up, man,
I bet you all the canned meat at the grocery store is going to be gone in 15 minutes.
-- Well, on all the gloves and masks.
-- That's right.
That's true.
I should,
I should start hoarding masks and then I can sell them for an enormous markup
then probably get beaten to death by a can of meat or something. But
anyway,
we should wrap this one up.
I
think we've,
we've rattled enough for one episode.
It's, yeah, I don't know.
I guess it will be, it'll be interesting to see if any long term changes happen.
But I'm,
I, I have faith in humanity's ability to ignore everything.
So I don't think, I don't think it will.
This isn't our first rodeo.
That's right.
We,
we have thousands of years of ignoring problems behind us as prior art. So,
yeah. Yeah. I mean, well, we'll see, I guess,
I, I
-- don't know, I don't know what else to say. I guess. Go working from
-- home
and wash your hands
and wash your hands. That's right. You can't wash your hands too much.
Oh, the other thing I, and this is funny,
I've actually been very conscious about not shaking hands and,
and it was not really the Coronavirus.
It was more that again, I see people not washing their hands in the bathroom
when I'm at like a conference.
And it's like, so statistically I'm just gonna have to shake hands with somebody who
just went to the bathroom.
Yeah.
So, as we've discussed on previous shows, I'm now offering to do the elbow bump.
Oh, elbow bump. That sounds weird.
Well,
it's so even a fist bump can have transmission
whereas an elbow bump typically because you're wearing clothing
and you're not touching your elbows much like,
people generally don't touch their elbows.
It's kind of odd when you think about it.
I'm going to make a point to touch my elbows more now.
But, um,
so that's what health professionals are increasingly
doing apparently is the elbow bump?
Ok.
So,
yeah, so I don't shake hands anymore.
And like I said, it's also, it's just more that like,
what my favorite thing is when I see people covering their sneeze, it's like yay.
And then I see them covering their knees with their hand and it's like, oh,
now I'm a little sad.
Makes it easier to transfer the disease particles everywhere you go.
Anyway, all I'm calling it. So, thank you. Thank you for listening. You can go to open
source security podcast.com.
Look up what is going to be probably a horrific list of show notes you
pound
podcast.
Hashtag do hit us up on social media and Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Stay safe, everybody.
-- Yep.
-- Good luck. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.