Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in rock crime.
Josh, bro.
Hey, Kurt, and I am so excited today.
We have Alyssa Miller who is an application security advocate from Sneak.
So welcome to the show, Alyssa.
Hey guys, thanks so much. I'm super excited to be here.
We are very excited to have you and you're actually here for a reason,
not just because we like sneak, which we do but
sneak released their state of open source report, not, not terribly long ago now,
which is a really cool report and why don't you tell us all about it?
And we'll kind of go from there.
Yeah, sure.
So our state of open source security report is something that we do annually.
It's kind of honestly, it's one of our flagship projects outside of, of course, our,
our main product that we're constantly working on,
but it's, it's really a big research project.
So we go out and we pull a lot of data from a lot of places in the open source community,
aggregated data from our own tooling as well as our vulnerability database.
And we also run a survey
and from that, we draw a lot of different information we're able to analyze that. And
really, it's the goal is just to create a,
a really comprehensive picture of what is the security
posture of open source these days as we look at
modern day development and the ecosystems that people are
using and our use of dependencies and so forth.
It's really hard to get away from open source.
So having a better understanding of it, what's good, what's bad?
What do we need to be looking at? What are things that we're getting better at?
-- That's really the goal of the report.
-- Awesome. Awesome. And
I will put a link to the report in the show notes for anyone who hasn't seen it yet.
It's, it's quite good. I like it.
Now, I'm gonna,
I've got one really hard question I want to lead with is the pages in the report
are widescreen instead of like normal human readable pages.
I'm curious if there's a reason for that
or if it's just something that that happened.
I
think honestly it's something that just our creative team did to, I,
I think partially to format it easier given
the way the contact the contents laid out.
And I, and it does, we do actually convert it to a physical book as well.
There's a smaller booklet that we, you know,
we hand out at conferences if we ever get back to doing those again.
Things like that. So I, I think it's more that, that standpoint than anything else.
Um, it just allows us to bring the content that all goes together on the same page.
I was gonna say I prefer it because it actually fits on my monitor.
I like to read things on my kindle and this was unpleasant, we'll say on a kindle.
I'm just trying to think now if my can't,
-- you can change your screen orientation on a
-- kindle.
I don't know, I'm too lazy to do that. Kind of. I'm sure you can.
I wasn't to say anything but yeah,
it's ok. Yeah, like laziness always wins for me.
I'm not even going to pretend, laziness and stupidity are pretty much my,
my two primary traits.
So. All right, cool, cool, cool. Let's, let's jump right into the data.
My first question is I'm just looking like the one graph
that really jumps out at me is on page 10.
Is that new packages created by ecosystem per year?
And like,
how to put this nicely N PM with like a
huge bar and then everybody else is tiny and like,
I know there's a lot of N PM packages but
like, they're seriously creating over 200,000 new packages a year.
Yeah.
And this is a trend, I mean, as you can see on the graph we've seen this trend for years.
Yeah. It, it keeps, yeah, and it's going up.
Yeah, and that's, I'm looking at this and I'm like,
-- I hope that was a typo because like, no,
-- unfortunately it's not.
Yeah, it's not at all. And that's that, I mean, good and bad.
I think honestly looking at the way that the N PM, you know, that whole,
no Js ecosystem works in general.
The, they tend to be very granular with their packages.
Like, I just, I saw something the other day where someone wrote and I'm gonna,
I don't remember the exact package, but I, I'll throw this out there.
It's not really right.
But imagine somebody wrote a, not a number package they had basically based that off
of a,
-- is a number package I was
-- gonna say, isn't it like a built in function? Yeah.
Right.
That, that wasn't the exact,
I don't remember the exact scenario but it was along those lines like, you know,
so it was like, you know, is this a string?
Well, is it not a string, you know, kind of thing?
So the package was like 33 lines of code long, but it had a dependency and,
and I, you know, I think we see more of that the,
the very granular functionality within those packages
within that particular eco
ecosystem than we do in others.
Like, you know, if you go out to, I mean, Java or.net, people are writing, you know,
if they're open source package writing, they're, they're writing, you know, a,
a large module that has different functionality,
different functions in it the whole nine yards.
We'll see a lot more with a note where it's like
this one function that does this one thing.
Here's our package added as your dependency.
I mean, shift left is the famous example here, right? Which we,
it feels like it was probably 100 years ago now.
But I mean that was, we talked about that for a whole show because the, you know,
the maintainer got mad and pulled his package and everyone used it and it broke N PM,
which is a wild problem.
Oh, sure.
So like me and Josh, you know,
we're both old UNIX farts who come from a world where like, oh,
my operating system has like 500 packages in total,
you
know, way more than that. Well, now it is.
Yeah, now it's a couple 1000 but like back in the day, you know, Slackware,
1.1 fit on 50 what, four floppy disks and I'm just look like, and I, again,
I know sort of in the back of my head that there's a lot of activity going on.
And on the one hand part of me is like the fact that
N PM can scale out like they have the processes to actually,
again, I'm used to things like Pearl CP Pan where it's like, oh,
we had like 1000 new packages this year.
Like, wow, that was an amazing year. Now, these numbers are like 300,000 a year,
like that's 1000 new packages a day.
And I'm just thinking like,
and these are also all centrally registered on that website, you know, and they,
the infrastructure supports this now pretty painlessly.
Right.
Yeah, I mean, it's well painlessly. It depends on who you ask.
I mean, everybody who has developed and know it knows the mantra.
Like you open up your project
N PM goes out and starts pulling dependencies.
You go get coffee, maybe dinner, maybe, you know, build a shed while you're at it.
I don't know, you know, it's some of the so and that's honestly,
that's part of the challenge with open source
in general, but in particular with M PM is, hey, you know, I built this project, I
added these seven dependencies to it.
But, oh, wait, yeah,
those seven dependencies all have their sub dependencies and
then those sub dependencies have their own dependencies.
And for, you know, what you like, what was seven dependencies?
Suddenly you've got a couple of 100 you know, dependencies in that whole tree
and knowing what's in your software is, is epically difficult.
And so, yeah, you know, I don't know that it's, it supports it in that.
Yeah, it does a great job.
You fire up a project N PM is gonna go out and find everything.
It's gonna find its location in github.
It's going to bring it in, import it to your project.
It does all that but yeah, it, it definitely has its challenges as well.
So I'm gonna kind of take you to task on this one a little bit.
Is there's two problems here, I think.
And you said knowing what's in your project is really difficult. It's actually not.
And this is something N PM gets right,
I think is they make it trivial to just give you a list of all the crap.
Even the transitive dependencies that happen to be in your project. Right?
That's the easy part.
The hard part is knowing which of those dependencies are a tire fire of, you know,
bad support and security problems.
And that's not something N PM can do.
-- They kind of can do it today, but it's not
-- very good in fairness.
So, like I ran into a similar thing and the thing I found was, yeah,
like N PM and stuff will give me a list of all the packages.
But like, what are they
like?
How big are they, how, you know, I remember looking at this one,
it was a ruby gems thing and it was like American date and I'm like,
what the hell is this?
Right? Because it hadn't been maintained in like the last update was five years ago.
And I'm like, oh my God,
five years and it literally just took a date and converted
it to your broken American format of month and year.
And I'm like,
I'm just going to pretend like I didn't see this
because number one that's offensive to me as a Canadian.
And number two,
I'm hoping there's no security flaw in it. Right. Because, and it's,
and it should be safe. But
that's the thing I'm finding is what is this thing?
Like, how big is it, like, is it 10 lines of code? Is it
100,000 lines of code? Because that's
the other thing I'm, I'm seeing with N PM and all these guys is there's no,
there's no hints on that.
-- No,
-- not at all. And I mean, you're right. Yeah, M PM. Will you, you can
pull the, your whole catalog, right?
I mean,
you can see that tree but you're trying to make
sense of that as you said and really understand,
OK, what is here?
Where are the duplicates? OK. I don't need to know that this, you know, same
jquery dependency shows up across, you know,
10 of my other dependencies obviously.
Well, unless you know,
the version is pinned in a few of them and not pinned in
-- a few them because I've seen that which
-- makes life even more fun.
Yeah, exactly.
And, and that, but that's so that's goes to then the point that you're,
you brought up of, how do I know, you know, even OK,
if they've pinned a particular version,
now I've got to be aware of all those different versions that I've got.
And if you know, vulnerability shows up, is it vulnerable or not. And,
and all of this really goes to this idea of like package health,
how do we actually measure package health?
And that's,
that's a challenge in and of itself there's data points out there.
Like you mentioned, you can look at, you know,
the last commit date or how many commits are out there?
How many upvotes does it have? How many maintainers are active in it?
How many poll requests have been accepted? All those things?
But
not none of them. Can you look at and say, well, if this is high, it's bad,
right? I mean, if you've got a lot of poll requests that have been committed.
OK. Is that because there's a lot of issues
and people are, you know, having to make a lot of changes to fix them,
even that alone could be good or bad, right?
I mean, bad because why does it have so many issues?
But good because oh my gosh,
people are actually finding and fixing them versus
that other project that has like no activity
and then you find out it's fraught with
vulnerabilities because no one's looking at it.
And so yeah, I mean, again, when we think about
even just what we're trying to do with this report,
it's how can we start to look at open source and understand what are the concerns?
So on page 45 of your report,
you have a graph
where you ask developers how they vet open source packages.
I would, I would classify it as witchcraft essentially of
it's like cargo, cult security where they,
they're doing things and I give people credit for trying to get this right.
But it is definitely a very hard problem.
And obviously the answers are heavily reliant on
the first layer, not the 10th layer of dependencies because you,
you have no control over that, right?
You could have a super active community.
But if they have a dependency that hasn't been updated in 10 years,
who cares if the community is active?
Exactly.
And that's why, you know, back to our firmer issue of being able to understand
that whole tree because you're right. I mean, I can
and yeah, I, I love that graph. It is the most of it.
It's probably one of the more boring graphs in the report
because all those bars are like almost even except for like one
and,
but that's exactly what I was expecting and it's actually kind of what
I wanted to highlight and why I put that question in the survey
because it's like, OK, what are people doing? Well, the fact of the matter is
everybody's got their own theories on this
and what we there, there's, I mean, I've seen,
we've seen talks done on this at developer conferences, I've seen them at
apps, a conferences,
you know, people are proposing lots of ideas but there really isn't an answer.
And I think, you know what to me is important here is it has whatever you're gonna do
and this, this kind of goes for all metrics. It's you gotta have a model, right?
Like you gotta understand how those different
individual metrics relate to each other. And based on this,
in a relationship of all of them, I can say, yeah,
this is a good package or this is a package.
-- I might want to stay away from
-- stupid question.
But in all this time, I've never actually seen anyone define what package health is.
Does sneak actually have a definition that you use.
I don't know that we have a formal definition,
but I know for us it's really just trying to find some form of objective scoring
to rate the overall risk of a particular package.
And, and we're doing a lot of work in that right now.
I know we've got a whole data team doing a
lot of stuff with some ML trying to really develop models
that we can then plug into the tool. Let's say, hey,
you know, you, you're using this package,
we found these vulnerabilities in it today.
But understand from a package health perspective,
you know, either you keep going with this one, it it's being well maintained.
Yeah, there's some vulnerabilities but it's good or hey,
we found these vulnerabilities, this thing looks pretty risky.
Maybe you want to consider a different way
-- to implement that functionality
-- because I I'd always looked
at more from the outcome of how quickly can
they fix a vulnerability assuming they even can.
You know, because I've literally dealt with packages that are just so dead
that I,
I ended up actually having to take ownership of two
for Fedora to get security updates put in them.
-- Yeah.
-- And, and we hear stories like that from the developer community a lot
and that's unfortunate, but that's really what we're trying to identify with PAC.
I mean, you think about large organizations who have this software and,
and you know, they're worried about, OK.
Am I gonna base, you know,
my developers creating software that has uh open source dependency
and that maintainer just kind of disappears and that project,
you know, kind of goes to pot or whatever, what do we do then
how are we going to deal with it? And yeah, are we gonna absorb that? Now we have to make
open source software,
we can't close it and make it our own
proprietary software because it is still open source,
it's licensed that way.
I I know a lot of organizations are actually kind of
resistant to that idea of creating open source for the community.
So that's where package health really comes into play and
just understanding how much of a risk is there,
we'll never get it perfect because it's,
it's risk and I don't know anyone that's figured out a way to perfectly measure risk.
Now, I have a counter story actually for this, which is
I it always peaks some interest when, when I tell it. So you, you mentioned,
you know,
you could use an open source library and the
upstream goes away for a variety of reasons.
And now as say, a company, I'm stuck with it. And what do I do?
I worked at a company a long time ago
that had a binary library.
No one knew where it came from, no one, right? Like we literally had no idea.
We just knew
it was, we had to use this
and we needed it because it was like, it was literally critical path to the software,
but
it was a mystery to everybody.
And that's on the other side of things.
At least with open source, you can point at it and say here it is, here's a code,
here's where this came from versus
this is a mystery meat package.
Nobody knows what it is, right? So there, there is definitely risk.
-- But I think conversely there's some anti risks as well.
-- Sure.
Yeah, I, I wish I could say I'm unfamiliar with stories like that, but I work for a uh a
fintech company way back in the day.
And yeah, we, we went through a acquisition, we brought in a third party company and
it's kind of the same thing, right? We got into the software.
We, we find these libraries uh
long and short of, I mean,
we did at least find out that it was written by
a consulting company that they had come in and write this,
but that company was gone. They, they were defunct.
We couldn't find anyone who would work for them.
So we didn't have the source code for this library. And it's like,
what are you? And how do you do that right now? You have, you have no source code.
You think, you know what it does,
but what are we gonna miss and especially in
a banking world where things can get really tucked
away and hidden and you don't find out about them for a long time until you know,
somebody's million dollar account is down to zero or something.
And, you know, I mean, it's so, yeah, I'm very familiar with that scary situation.
I have no doubt we have all dealt with it at least once.
Another thing I'm really curious about is the security
practices in the delivery pipeline for the open source.
Yes. Some of the bars are not terribly surprising.
The one that made me sad is the security test cases in Q A was only at 28%.
And I would have thought that would be a little bit higher.
But then what was really
hot?
I want to say shocking because it's not shocking, shocking, but none of these is 26%.
And I would have actually guessed that would be a lot higher because for example,
those 300,000 node packages, I'm guessing the majority of them have, like,
like that American date function I was looking at like,
there's no security test in there and, and nor would I ever expect there to be one?
Right. No, and I hear you. And it's,
I mean, it's good and bad. Right.
I mean, one in four is still kind of scary that one in four aren't doing anything.
But
at the same time when you consider the audience for the, the survey,
it is kind of interesting that at least it's only at 26%.
This survey, we looked at demographics as part of it too. And
66% of the respondents were developers
now, they, you know, a lot of them probably work in organizations,
but many of them are probably maintained
as well.
And so, unfortunately, that's one data point I don't have is, you know, are they,
are they maintainers, are they working in an organization? Are they doing both?
Who knows? Unfortunately. But yeah, it's,
I was actually shocked by that graph too and I saw
sat leading by such a wide margin over the next one.
I mean, there's, you know,
50 7% versus uh security test in Q A which is only 28 which again,
I agree with you too is a little disappointing.
Well, considering almost all of this stuff is network facing now, like, I mean,
back in the day, it's one thing, you know,
you have a bunch of software sitting on ad OS box grinding away.
But in my experience now, pretty much all of this stuff is, you know,
you touch it with the rest api
but how else would you talk to it?
So I have a theory behind this graph and I would be curious
to get your thoughts on this elicit given you you're in space.
So I, I work for elastic and I do product security at elastic.
And one of the things that I deal with and I have complained at length about this on,
on the podcast is
many customers
will run
the SAT
scanners
and then send them to us and say, please fix all of these problems, which is of course,
never going to happen.
And then I spend an enormous amount of
time helping to educate and explain what's actually
going on with these because obviously sending me
a scan with 300 findings saying fix them all
is
I don't have the time to explain what's wrong with that right now. Right. Right.
But the thing is, the thing is I see is
S
a,
is a thing security people can do
and get a measurable result out of they know they can run a scan
and then
I can say, oh, we fixed a bunch of stuff, run it again and the number goes down.
And so I think it, it's, it's an interesting metric for people.
Not because
I think it's necessarily useful in the way a
lot of them think it is but because it gives
them something to look at and understand which I
think none of the other options in that list.
-- They're a little more squishy.
-- Yeah. I think that's fair.
I also think there's, there's two other things that I actually, as I look at this,
I kind of
think play into it. One,
there is some developer heavy bias, right.
With it being 66% developers responding.
Yeah, they're they're gonna see the fact that SAS T is running.
They may not necessarily be aware that someone at some point is doing a dynamic test.
They may not fully be aware of security test cases that are built into their Q A.
But I think the other thing that does happen here, I think SAS T is well enough known
and built,
most of the SAS solutions are built now in a way that they fairly easily integrate
to the pipeline, right?
They're either integrated into build tools
or they're integrated into repository.
So either when they do a commit or they do a build,
the SAS tool kicks off and does its thing now what they do with the results of that,
who knows, right?
They may or may not be leveraging it but it it it's easier to plug that in than say ad A
S tool where you have to, you know,
it has to go out and spider a website and find all the page
and know how to interact with all the input forms.
And if you're doing URL rewriting and other things, it screws it all up, you know,
or Threat modeling, which I am.
I'm a lover of Threat modeling and it saddens me deeply to see 19%.
In fact,
I had an analyst who I met with yesterday suggest to
me that their numbers say it's even lower than that.
Yeah, I was gonna say 19 seems pretty high to me.
-- So
-- that, that, that saddens me, but that's, you know, what we're working toward.
And I think some of that,
that I have all sorts of theories on what we can do to make that better.
But yeah, I think
overall, I think S
A
is probably one of those ones that's easier to integrate.
SC A is actually pretty easy to integrate too.
What is SC A, so that's software composition analysis ie you know,
like what we do here at sneak, you know, and,
and we do make it very easy to integrate that into the pipeline.
And I think some of the other tools that are in that same space, do you know,
are there as well?
It's just, I think that
that particular solution, the idea of SCA I is a little bit younger.
SAT, I mean, we've been doing SAT for TW
years in some form or another. At least
I can think back 15 years ago
running
the vulnerability management program for that fintech company I was
talking about and that was one of our big initiatives,
was bringing in SAS tools and,
and getting them automated and integrated into our SDLC.
So I think that probably has a lot to do with it as well that, you know,
SAS is well established and it's, it's well integrated.
-- Sure,
-- I, I think that's fair. Now, I I will say
one of one of my opinions is that
I think
composition analysis
has a much brighter future than
SAT because I feel like, you know, you mentioned SAS has been around for 20 plus years
and it still sucks pretty hard.
And I'm not gonna say composition analysis is awesome because I think it's,
it's got a long road,
but I feel like it's as bad as Sass
and it's brand new, which gives me tons of hope, right?
And I know that doesn't sound like the most
compelling way to describe a AAA tool.
But if you understood how I usually talk about
this stuff that is high praise coming from me.
-- So
-- sure. No, but I get what you're saying, right? I mean, we look at S A and
one of the biggest complexities S
A
is you're asking an automated tool to do a lot of really complex stuff.
And the end result is
where I know you were going with that story before
is people send you these scan results at elastic.
Hey, here's all your problems, fix them all it's like,
yeah, probably 90% of these are false positives.
Like,
right.
I mean,
so we all get that and I think anybody who's run
a SASS tool understands the complexity and the trouble with that.
In fact, I always tell people too, it's like
if you're gonna launch a SAS solution, you gotta look at that.
Like, and this is, this is where I date myself, but back when web application,
firewalls were coming out,
it was the same thing like people thought, oh,
we're just gonna plug this in and it's gonna work.
I'm like, no, you're gonna plug that in and it's gonna break everything
and you're going to spend a year just getting it configured.
So you have to plan for that year to get it configured
and then you have to plan that you're gonna be managing that
reconfiguring it and optimizing it
for the rest of the time that you own it.
So figure all that into your ro I because it's gonna be part of it.
And I think we see that with SAT, I'm hoping SC A is a little more concrete
in that.
There's a little bit easier capability,
especially with these ecosystems and package managers to tie into that
and get a lot of information really quickly in one place.
Problem with that with
S A is you have no roadmap to follow at all. Right.
I mean,
people can write code in a million different ways and
they do write code in a million different ways.
I've been there.
I'm ashamed of some of the stuff that I
know is still sitting in a production environment somewhere.
But, hey, you know, I mean, that's, that's part of the fun of it. I guess so.
Yeah, I, I definitely hear where you're, you're coming from there and I,
I think that it's,
we have the opportunity to make ac, a pretty,
a pretty strong compelling tool obviously.
Again, you know, I mean, my, my sneak bias here,
that's where I'm hoping to see it go because I mean, this,
that's what we're focused on is how do we,
how do we get developers in a position where they understand this?
And it's a tool that works easily and all that happy stuff so that
it's not that s
a tool that they know they're gonna run it through and it's gonna, you know,
come back to them with 8 billion results that now they have to sift
through and figure out which ones are
actually anything of exploitable in their code.
Well, I mean, you, you kind of have that problem as well.
Well, with, with SC A just because
it, it, the example I always use is and this is absurd. But let's say you have a library
that
is an HTTP client and encodes MP threes, right?
And you're not encoding MP threes.
So you don't care about security issues in that part of it. But
today an sc A tool will tell you all about them
even though you aren't technically calling that code at all.
Yeah.
So what we call that is smart prioritization.
I'm trying to avoid turning into a commercial here,
but it is something that we've started to build as well, that ability to.
All right, how do we prioritize these, if, if I'm using this package,
but I'm not calling that vulnerable function.
Obviously, it may be a critical
severity vulnerability
in out of context within just the context of that package,
but within the context of my particular software,
yeah, it's not an issue
and I even look at what our research team does because you know,
we've got a research team out there discovering new vulnerabilities all the time.
And that's one of the things they do is, you know,
they'll look at the context of the package though.
How is this being used? OK.
It's not sanitizing this input but is the context of this package?
Is it expected that something downstream is
responsible for doing that input validation?
And in which case?
-- All right, that's not an issue then of of any significant importance
-- and,
and that's even cooler than anything I'd expect.
I mean, so my poster child for this is something called Jackson data bomb,
which I imagine
it is basically it kind of it parses objects in some weird ways in Java.
And it has a concept called Polymorphic de serialization,
which is an extremely difficult thing to say basically what it comes
down to is you can just disable it because it is dangerous.
-- I mean, any time you're deserializing an object
-- well, and not many people use it.
Right. Right. And like
for example, in elastic search,
we have Jackson data bind and we explicitly disable all of that functionality.
But you can imagine what our, our SC A scans look like because we also can't upgrade it
because there's some performance aggressions in the library.
And obviously, when you have a performance,
you know, document store,
that's a big deal. And that's an easy one, right?
You just have to be like is this function being called in a certain way? Yes, it is. OK.
Great. None of these,
you
know.
-- Yeah,
-- exactly.
And that's, and I think that's one of the motions where SC A
does have to continue to get better.
Um And like I said, I know it's something that we're looking at and, and,
and building solutions around.
You brought up another interesting point there though too. And that's this
the mantra from the security folks.
And I say this is a 15 year security person after, you know,
being a developer for a decade.
God, I'm old. Holy cow.
Yeah, we, we got you beat there, I think.
But no, I mean, the mantra from security has always been get the latest and greatest,
always upgrade to the latest and greatest fix your vil
by getting the latest and greatest.
Well, the fact of the matter is the latest and greatest isn't always the best.
And, you know, I, I think that's a,
that's something that we're becoming more aware of.
The developer community has understood it for years.
I think the security community is starting to appreciate and understand
that this is the way things need to work too though,
that,
you know, sometimes you have to pick the least
new vulnerable version or a non vulnerable version. So what is that version?
What's the minimum version I can go to that gets rid of that vulnerability
but has the least chance of breaking
the functionality that I'm using or introducing
issues with performance or other things.
And I think we're, we're getting there from a security community perspective,
but
-- we still need to keep developing that empathy too.
-- Absolutely.
My,
my favorite example here is someone will hand me one of these large reports with say,
let's say there are 50 findings and they'll say you got to fix these and I'll say
we have the resources to fix 10. Which 10 do you want me to fix?
Then? Then now it's hard right now. It's not.
Oh wait, I have to think about this and I,
and of course you're going to fix the 10 that actually matter the most,
not the 10 at the top of the list or not the 10, even the,
the scanner tells you are the most important
so
definitely, definitely. All right,
we are about out of time and so I will let you close us down.
Give us your final thoughts to Lisa.
Yeah.
So my final thoughts, I'll really quickly summarize the report, I guess is that,
you know, we saw a lot of good, right.
There were a lot of good things.
We saw declining numbers in terms of new vulnerabilities discovered.
We see better attitudes in dev
sec ops and people really seeing security as
a shared responsibility across those different disciplines,
the developers, the security teams, the ops team,
we also see a lot of the same old issues coming to light, you know,
the same troubles we had with securing physical servers.
We're seeing with containers, you know,
the assumptions being made that an official image is secure is not valid.
And there's there's some challenges from
a security perspective when we think about
OK.
Yeah,
one of the things we saw is there's a cross
site scripting vulnerabilities are discovered
more than any other vulnerability.
But then we looked at how many projects did that actually impact.
And there's no correlation, the most
the most projects impacted were impacted by a
small number of vulnerabilities of a particular type
that were just happened to be discovered in really popular low dash and
Jquery libraries.
And so as a result, you know, you have this wide span impact.
And so we need to continue to think about how we look
at those metrics and those you know how we define our KPIS.
And like I was saying earlier in the call
really start to form our image of this not as a function of any one data point,
but look at the modeling of that data and how the different
data points interact and what they tell us about each other.
So
I think we see there's a lot of good, there's of course,
as you would expect a lot of work to continue to do, I think.
Yeah, open source. We're doing exciting things. You can't get away from it.
So at least
we're seeing
the, the efforts and the attitudes coming around on that. And I think devs psychs
-- is kind of leading the way with that.
-- Definitely awesome.
That was, that was marvelous. So
I will have links in the show notes to the report. I'll have a link to Alyssa's Twitter
and obviously get in touch if this is something that
interests you because it's a fascinating and awesome topic.
And I want to thank sneak for doing this work because it's completely
thankless and you probably get more complaints than anything about the report.
But it is definitely valuable, I think.
And I have no doubt
in a couple of years as we have more time to understand and develop these models
and the data itself, it's going to be
a wonderful resource for all of us. So awesome.
Thank you so much Alyssa for joining us.
-- You have been an absolutely wonderful guest.
-- I appreciate it.
Thank you for having me on.
Great.
So for those of you listening, you go to open source security podcast.com,
hit up our show notes, you
pound Os S podcast. Hashtag You hit us up on social media and
Alyssa
and Kurt have fantastic rest of your days. Thanks everybody. All right.
Thanks, everybody. Marvelous. Thank you, everyone. Bye bye.