Hello and welcome to the open source security
podcast episode 35 and three quarters with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime, Josh Bresser.
You know, I figured you'd pick on me for that.
So the reason it's 35 and three quarters is we
tried to record this a couple of days ago and
due to,
ok, fine.
So I screwed up and I, I messed up the recording and we have to rerecord this show,
which I think is actually a gift because there
have been a handful of new bits of information
about the sha one attack and the cloud bleed or whatever is,
are we officially calling it?
Well, that's what everybody else
clouded.
You know, I guess, ironically, we don't have AC B ID for this, do we? We have to say
-- we can't because CV doesn't cover services yet.
-- Right. So, wow, interesting.
Without clouded,
we'd have to call it that cloud flare issue, which could actually mean last
week,
last week, which in,
in a couple of weeks won't be last week and it will also potentially
not be the cloud flare issue anymore because there could certainly be another one
so interesting.
Yeah.
Well,
considering it was just literally equals equals versus what was it equals more than
it was? Well, I mean,
it wasn't,
it was
a,
well, they were using, um, like, what was it? It was generated code.
Well,
let's back it up a bit maybe and explain to people
because here's the point we've already talked about this one.
So, in our minds it's all fresh and in your minds you're like,
what the hell are these people talking about?
Crazy people.
Although if you haven't read the news in the last week and this is new to you.
Um, wow, you might want to go change some passwords. Uh Yeah.
Yeah,
you might,
maybe we don't know which ones. So
good luck changing them all.
You know, just a tangent and I don't want to do a commercial plug, but this,
this one password manager, I'm looking at, uh, for a variety of sites and stuff.
It understands.
You can actually just hit a button in the password app saying
-- change my password
-- and it will do it magically for you.
That is amazing. Can I ask which one that is? Because
last pass does that? I will.
That might sell me on this because,
well, I don't, I don't know if I've talked about this, but I,
I use something called PW safe on
and
it's very manual. And so the passwords I have to change.
I'm dreading because it's going to literally take me hours of my
life to go through a bunch of sites and change them.
So last passing, I,
it might, I don't know, the, the cost of changing might outweigh
the cost of changing all my passwords.
If it has a magic button.
I
just, to me there's, you know, there's the passwords I really care about.
Like, say my icloud password and my Google password.
Uh, and funnily enough.
I would then put my banking in the second tier of passwords because, I mean,
it's important, it's my money but it's not as important as,
like my entire online identity and all my files.
Well, right. And not only that the bank, there are certain legal obligations.
Like, if someone steals all my money, they have to give it back to me
if someone steals my Twitter account, like it's gone.
Yeah,
there's a well understood legal framework
for dealing with shenanigans around that.
Whereas with icloud it's, I don't even want to think about that. So,
and, um, you know, and then there's like the third tier stuff which is like, you know,
um, just all those websites that made me make an account
-- and
-- all
those are the dangerous ones because, you know, their security is terrible
and most people will just use the same
-- password for those they
-- use
what
they have. Right. I mean,
I have over 1000 passwords at this point.
I don't, I think last time I looked, I have 300
I bet I could get rid of 20 or 30 of those
because they're just like old crap accounts I never use anymore.
But I'm too lazy to prune my password database.
Well, speaking of passwords, uh, sha one had a bit of a rough week. Last week.
-- It
-- did sha one. Well, ok.
So it, it didn't, I don't, how do we want to see this? This is,
-- we've known
-- Shaman
Falls downstairs.
That might be the most accurate headline for the sha one thing ever.
So, ok, let, let's back it up, I guess. Is
there is an attack called Shattered
that
the, the website leads off with. We have broken Sha One in practice.
And the importance of that is we've known Sha One
has certain weaknesses for
like, almost, I think 10 years now. I mean, this is not new.
We knew someday someone was going to break Sha
one and I won't say it's totally broken yet,
but like,
it's falling down the stairs right now,
you know, that's
that where we're standing at the bottom and, and we're, you know, it's that
bizarrely horrific slow motion, you know, trip down the stairs, you've fallen.
And that's what sha one is doing right now where
it's, I wouldn't say these attacks are in the realm of practical for,
we'll say non state actors, but it is
unquestionably
stop using Sha One. Right.
Well, we'll get to that later.
But I, I do think there are a couple of potential real world attacks where
it, it would
within, you know, generally speaking, it actually wouldn't be a,
-- probably a super successful attack, but it would be one hell of a huge mess
-- maybe.
I mean, so actually let's start
even farther back than that is. So
there are
what we talked about kind of three types of attacks, three types of collisions, ok.
And
-- the first type
-- is
stages of collision attacks
from
bad to worse to like, oh dear, this is terrible.
And,
and what's happened here is essentially researchers
with a massive amount of compute resources
generated two PDF S
that have the same sha
check
and they generate
or sea
one. Sorry. Yes,
they generated them at the same time.
And the importance of that is
when you're the way this attack, the current known attack works is
you basically can, can start figuring out
the internal state of the sha
hatching algorithm. And by
basically generating two files at the same time, it makes it easier.
And when I say easier,
I'm talking about
these guys use the amount of compute power and energy for that matter
that it basically takes to generate a Bitcoin block right now.
And so that's a crazy amount of power to say the least
six. It was over 6000 years of GP U time and something like about.
Well, if you bought it on the spot market,
it would be just over $100,000 us at current Amazon rates.
And that's so, it's, it's, that's a real world cost on this attack.
You're looking at 100 grand for now.
And obviously, and not only that,
this isn't a super useful attack because generating two files at the same time,
obviously isn't super useful. The attack that people are actually going to want
is when you have one file that has a certain checksum
and you can generate a separate file with the same checksum,
right? And that's dangerous.
Yeah,
that's where you get things like I signed a
contract and now that contract says something different,
right? Or in the context of things like certificates, right?
I mean, and now on that note though,
all of the browsers at this point should be banning sha one
uh well, sort of, they're in the process of banning Shaw.
And I mean, that's, that's what I, that's what I love about this attack, right?
Is like, like literally literally Microsoft's blog from last week was like,
yeah, sha one is like falling down the stairs. This is bad.
Um But we've already like us with our long term plans, you know, we're, we're,
we started phasing Sha one out in the end of January 2017,
you know,
so it's um they're slowly phasing shaw one out for certificates and right now it's um
uh you can't have it for uh what is it? You cannot have it for root certificates.
But you can have it for intermediate certificates
or manually installed root certificates on a system. Right.
Because there's still a lot of technologies and people like interception
proxies and stuff like that that you sha one certificates.
Um, but even, and that stuff too has been,
it's been planned to phase that out over the next like two or
three years and it looks like that will be sped up now,
whatever, you know, a bunch of these security products,
we're going to put the word security in air quotes here
that a bunch of these security products are probably still using MD five
in, in terms of their, their certificate signing for these middle,
in the middle things they do.
It's
I, I expect those to lag horribly behind and, and this is actually a place where
if we had an easy way to assign CV I DS for things like this,
I could maybe poke them in the eye a little bit and, and get things moving faster.
Well, that's something I've actually been working on is,
is so with classic security vulnerabilities, like say something resulting in,
you know, code execution clearly, that's a vulnerability with crypto.
It's a little harder because the, the bar keeps moving, you know, for example,
this attack today in real world terms costs about $100,000 in compute time,
10 years from now. It'll,
I don't know, take what, half an hour on your cell phone, right? I mean,
you know, so at some point it moves from being like, yeah, this is a problem to like,
no, this is a real problem too.
This is an actual security vulnerability because it's so easy to break.
Kind of like um
uh WP a encryption on wireless.
Sorry.
Wep, the even older one web,
you know,
we got to the point where you could break it literally in real time on a laptop.
So OK, clearly, if anybody, you know, is using web, that's just you can't, it,
it provides no protection anymore, you know, it's like des 5650 my laptop
will do that
in like minutes, single digit minutes,
you know.
Um
And so, yeah, at what point do these sort of, especially with hashing,
it's a little bit more subtle because the attacks aren't as like direct,
you know, even if I can create a hash collision.
Well, I still have to kind of do something with that,
you know, it's not like that directly gets me code execution
except in the case of things like say, you know, update systems,
right? But, you know,
anyways.
But um so I've been pushing for that for a
while for us to actually start defining in cryptographic terms,
both for hashing
and encryption functions.
Sort of, where's that line like today? OK.
Des, clearly not acceptable MD five, not acceptable generally
sha one where does that fall now?
Is it not acceptable anymore or do we start moving because it's the use cases too,
like root certificates.
Sha One would clearly be a problem
whereas, like using sha one in say, well,
great real world example being git git still uses sha One
uses it in a way that's
-- not as easily attacked.
-- Well,
-- that's actually kind of complicated.
-- It's,
yeah,
-- it's not a good answer. As Doom
-- does root certificates using Sha one.
Right.
It is not.
And in many cases they're using it as an integrity check.
Not a security check, except for the places they're using it as a security check.
I was gonna say, yeah.
And so, and that's the problem is, you know, defining these, where these bars is,
is a, is a lot harder with encryption and, you know, hashing and, you know,
it's something I want to get because, yeah, we do need at some point, like,
I don't want to buy stuff or have companies buying stuff that,
like uses this sha one or MD five or whatever in a vulnerable manner.
And, and
I,
so here's the way I always look at this is even if they're
not using it in what we would call a vulnerable manner today,
they should still stop because someday someone's gonna get a good idea
and they're gonna be like, oh, look, it already does sha one. I'll just use that
and then all of a sudden now you have a problem.
Yeah. And I would be even more concerned.
My biggest concern would be, is like,
what's their software update process look like?
Right.
Like how, because if they're using sha one, they're clearly not staying up to date
with stuff
or if they're using MD five, you know,
updates were signed with their MD five.
so I almost for fun.
Bought a, uh, they had, um, at Staples, they had, um, like no name, a
bunch of no name, products like pens and pencils and, you know,
and $20 wireless routers.
Oh,
man,
-- I almost
-- bought
one
but my girlfriend was like, no, you don't need that.
And I'm like, I know I don't need it, but I want to play with it and she's like, no,
put it, put it back.
You know, it's the same discussion I had with my kids and candy.
It's like I want this, it's not good for you.
It's, you, you will regret this purchase.
I know.
You know, I know this is a terrible thing but,
and,
and I literally wanted to buy it just to see what the update software stuff was like.
Oh,
yeah. You know,
you know, it's terrible.
I couldn't, you know, here's the best part.
I couldn't even find the model number online.
I have no doubt.
-- I have no doubt. It's, I want, oh man, part of me wants this now just to like
-- start
key
Kee Wi
fi.com is the maker and it was like the, what was it? Wr 1014 or something like that.
It's at staples and, and yeah, it's a $20 router but,
you know, going back to the sort of CV E for crypto stuff. I, at
this point,
I kind of want like health food labels, you know,
where it gives you like the calorie count and the ingredient list.
And I would love to see like
an ingredient list for software saying like,
you know, this product uses Linux kernel version X last updated,
you know, at this date,
you know,
because maybe it's an old version that they back port
fixes to or maybe it's just an old version,
right?
Those are two very different things,
you know,
um, what's, you know, what ciphers and, you know, does it support WP A two,
does it support, you know, TLS version 1.3?
I guarantee you almost no products on the
market right now. Support TLS version 1.3
-- in the
-- hardware space
in their defense. It's still not out of the standards committee.
But yes, I understand what you're saying.
Well, it's, it's darn close. I mean,
-- supports,
-- it
is special.
-- Well, except for
-- that
because they want to get it adopted and moving
and this is the chicken and egg problem.
Yeah.
Well, and from their perspective,
you figure TLS 13 is going to save them buckets of transfer
data more to the point it's going to save people time.
Yeah, that's true.
You know, that, those,
those when you think about how many round trips are made for TLS,
every day on the planet.
That's going to be an absurdly huge number.
It probably is. And that, that's actually one of the, we, we, we'll get to that.
Yeah.
Well, and the other thing too is you can, you can provide TLS version 1.3
and clients that don't support it. That's cool. Right.
-- They just talk TLS 1.1 or 1.0 or whatever, stop using
-- TLS one point. Oh,
they, they should be talking about 12 or whatever.
And, well, you know,
that's actually related to this conversation about sha one is that I think we
need to get better about just drawing a line in the sand and saying
that's enough.
This doesn't, it's not supported, it doesn't work.
And the browser makers are basically going to do this
where
they're just gonna say, screw it. No way.
Instead of sort of supporting something for like 20
plus years and you get yourself into trouble.
Yeah.
No, we need to start killing these things otherwise they just linger on for
and they're
dangerous, right. How many attacks are we starting to see because of this stuff?
Yeah,
I think in general and, and this is one of the things where I think CV can help a lot is
if we assign CV S to these issues.
And, you know, like, for example, product uses MD five blah, blah, blah, blah blah,
then most organizations, if a product has a CV E,
they have to deal with it in some way and, and that way can be, you know, replacing it,
updating it, whatever.
But it can also be, we accept the risk and we accept that we cannot fix this but,
you know, due to business needs or whatever,
you know, at this time,
we don't have the money to replace it and we'll just eat the risk.
But at least then they are aware of
the risk and they're making a somewhat informed decision
rather than just, oh, we have a bunch of stuff sitting in a closet doing stuff.
I'm sure it's fine.
No, absolutely. That's absolutely correct.
And that's what II I like.
It kind of goes back again to this, you know, product labeling of like,
what is in this product?
How updated is it, you know, does this,
does this manufacturer still even exist or are they still in business?
No? Seriously. Like,
you know, some of these Chinese makers,
it's not that they go out of business but they, like, kill off a product line.
Oh, right. Well, everyone kills off product lines.
You can't support a product forever. That's just the reality of it.
Yeah, exactly. So,
you know, again, I want to make, you know, this is, I hate to say it.
This is one of, this is one of the core reasons I buy
Apple phones because I know for a fact, based on historical precedent,
I will get 3 to 4 years of support from Apple on software updates.
That
is,
you know, with an Android phone, I'm up, I'm at the mercy of a random carrier.
Typically, unless I get an unlocked phone, which
in Canada is very difficult to get a hold of.
I run a Nexus phone from Google and I would,
I would not buy anything else. I would buy an iphone if I didn't have a Nexus.
And due to a variety of reasons, I sort of wish I had an iphone today but that's,
it's
us,
whatever man. It's
you, you and your cult.
Yeah.
Yeah, just like
Costco,
you know, actually I went to Costco the other day just to go in to look around.
It was
less impressive than you make it out to be, but very nice.
Did you try the hot dog?
I did not have a hot dog.
Should have a hot
dog
anyway.
Moving on.
So actually I,
I have one other really interesting thing about the Shah attack
that I found is so uh the Z cash guys,
which is Z cash is a digital currency,
which is supposed to be more exciting and interesting than Bitcoin.
But they kind of document
a whole bunch of things around attacks on secure hash functions. And one of the
results if you read this
is that
the current hashes that are being developed today are being designed
in a way to specifically be resistant to collision attacks.
And so it is conceivable at some point in the future,
the concept of basically like attacking a hash function in a manner looking
for collisions will not be practical and you would have to rely on
something very brute force oriented, which is not reasonable to do.
Yeah, I mean, I think the, the reality is as sort of so the,
the those talking about those three stages of attacks, you know,
where you can create two files with the same hash, you can create eight, a new file
with the same hash as an existing file.
And then the third step which is given a hash, here's a file that matches it.
That first attack is actually quite
potentially bad with some cryptocurrencies because for example,
you get into areas of double spend.
Uh yeah, that, that's probably fair, you know, and, and these are like,
this is literally if I can,
you can basically fake currency
and, and that's a real world problem for a currency,
you know, having fake currency running around, you know,
with these consensus protocols and stuff like it would,
it would probably not be a very great attack, but it would be one huge headache,
you know, to deal with it.
And what really gets me about this attack is that everybody, I mean, Shaw is,
you know, it's a pretty good hash, 1 60 100 and 60 bits.
So two to the 160th, which is a very large number with a lot of zeros, I'm sure.
And um,
but fundamentally what's, what's amusing to me is
some software that relies on sha one hashes to uh for the lack of a better term,
identify an object or a file
made the assumption that there will never be a collision, not even accidental.
And so, uh you remember the, the web KT thing, right?
So
there's subversion repo.
Yeah. So web kit has a Subversion repository
and they have a get to subversion sort of gateway.
And so some bright spark checked both these PDF files into the G
you know, totally reasonable, right?
Like I should be able to safely check in some files to get, you know,
as an example of the sha one attack, right?
And then when it went through their get to SVN uh gateway and into the SVNSVN just
apparently just barfed itself horribly horribly and like and
destroyed its internal database because of these matching sha
one hashes.
I
I've yet to properly understand that problem
because it,
I don't know, part of me gets it. And it's funny.
But another part of me,
like we check in files with the same check on all the time because, well,
granted they're the same file usually, you know what I mean?
I don't know, something crazy is going on obviously.
But I think fundamentally this points out a really good security
concept of you have to design with failure in mind.
And I'm guessing almost no software that uses shaw one to,
for example, identify objects
actually does. So
-- with, you know, this like actual,
-- why wouldn't
the
different objects,
the whole point of using sha one is you don't have to worry about collisions.
-- Well,
-- you know,
until now.
Yeah,
exactly.
Um, you know, it's just,
I feel like it's one of those design choices that if you design around that.
It also, then, you know,
you're buying yourself also some breathing room for
when the inevitable does happen or you know,
some crazy cosmic accident,
crazy
accidents. Those are the best kind.
Yeah,
so yeah.
No, this, I think the the good news,
like you said with Shaw one is the browsers are killing
it and hopefully more on the back end will kill it.
And then ideally, you know, we'll get CV S assigned to the stuff.
So people will know and be able to make an informed decision and, you know,
hopefully on the next equipment refresh,
I,
I blame MD five for making this a lot easier because I mean,
I remember when MD five finally died is
we knew it was bad and we're like,
it's not that bad and then the flame malware came out, it was like, yeah,
it's worse than we thought.
And so I think people understand
that is going to happen here eventually.
So,
so just to convert the flame hour, that was the one where it
was creating like hostile binaries with the same MD five or that was
the sign.
I think it was
doing something.
-- Right. It
-- was the sign.
Right. It's, yes, I remember this now. Yeah.
And that one was even really interesting because that was
a completely unknown attack prior to the malware being found,
which is obviously,
that's terrifying.
And that's also another thing to think about is just because there's no
public research around the sha one attacks
doesn't mean it doesn't exist somewhere.
Well, something to keep in mind. I mean, this Shatter attack was done by, what was it?
Two guys at Google
and three guys at a university.
And they, but they also, I mean, they stood on research that came before them.
But the point is you, you think some government doesn't have five smart guys?
They have more than five.
Yeah, exactly.
You know, so the reality is this is, you know, like,
that's what always gets me is a lot of these attacks they come out
and it's,
it's not like the Manhattan project where you had thousands of people involved.
It's like five guys.
I, I know what you mean.
Well, not only that the, the fewer people you have working on something like this,
the easier it is to keep secret,
which is
in hindsight.
Like it's a,
can you imagine if something like the Manhattan
project was done today with social media?
Like, no, like I give it two hours
before it's leaked.
Right. Like someone taking a selfie next to the reactor and
it would be the
horrifying man. I mean,
look at what's going on now.
Like there's,
there's all these crackdowns and all these governments where they're
trying to keep information locked up and it's like guys,
you can't win this unless you lock these people
in vaults with no electronics of any sort.
You, you're going to fail.
Well, and they've done that like, uh what was it that one piece of legislation,
the TT P or whatever,
or the TPP, the Trans Pacific Partnership.
If memory serves the uh the European members of parliament, we're trying to like,
read it and the process to read it
is you have to give up all your electronic devices, go into a locked room,
you're not allowed to even bring paper and pen with you
and you're allowed to like spend half an hour reading this document,
then you have to leave the room and it's like, wow, that's,
yeah.
Right.
I mean, apart from the,
like you guys are clearly trying to hide something aspect of that is like,
people can still remember and they can sum it up later.
Like people are the problem, right? That, that's
-- pretty much how
-- we,
you know, and I think this,
this talking about the small security team
and small security research thing really brings up
our next topic quite nicely. I mean,
because now we're talking about a guy Tavis
Ormandy.
Yeah, granted he is a very smart man. Very, very smart at security
but, you know, yeah, on his own, he um basically discovered that like,
what is it about 130 of the internet is um
vulnerable to leaked passwords, session data,
you know,
if it's that high. But why don't,
does about 30% of the website?
But it's not every site they've got to have some Janky html to really
-- trigger it. But
-- no
uh no, no, no, no,
no, no,
no.
Ok.
A bunch of enhancements. So for example, I can have cloud
floor automatically rewrite all requests to http S
have cloud
-- ate email addresses, right?
-- The,
the
the problem is more nuanced than this. It's the,
your data could be snarfed out from a request to a Janky site is what the problem is
and that's the real issue. And so why don't, do you want to explain this one?
Let's, let's let's start at the beginning
-- for people who might not
-- Cloud
Flare is a content delivery network service,
maybe not that far in the beginning.
-- So basically everyone
-- knows who cloud flare is, man. Come on.
But so they actually terminate the TLS and SSL connection
on their end and then send a further request to your server,
either encrypted or non encrypted depending on what you configured
to actually get the content and serve it up.
So that means the Cloud flare servers actually have
you know, the unencrypted raw
actual contents of the request because they also then are able to do things like
say email obfuscation where they like replace email addresses in the web page with,
uh I think it's like a picture or something so that, you know,
it can't be scraped as easily
or they do things like, um
you can um insert content or remove content, whatever, you know,
you can do some real cool stuff.
And the problem is they had like a little tiny, like literally a one character flaw
that meant that memory segments weren't aligned correctly in the application.
It was written in C
and so when it was
doing certain things, it could essentially insert data from
random parts of other memory on that server
and send that
in the request, you know, response.
And the problem is that those bits of data could be things like,
uh, cookie or a password or the actual web page itself
and it's sent to some random third party
and
ok, you know, that's bad.
But whatever, but the real problem becomes is now that, um, a lot of web caches
like
Google Bing Yahoo, you know, the big web crawler guys
have this content in the web pages, they have indexed and cached,
but that they also make available, right?
Like archived pages.
So,
and that's one thing Tavis had to work on is
he apparently had to write like a cleaner to like,
you know, the go through all of Google's data and like
basically clean the stuff out as best they could.
Um But we're talking like, what is it?
4.3 million domains are served through cloud flare, some of them pretty big.
And so this data is scattered all over, you know, God's green earth,
literally, who knows where and, and the real problem is we can't, you know,
I can't say with certainty that you're affected or not because
a couple of things had to happen. One, you know,
you,
you had to have your sensitive data in the cloud flare servers memory
while some other person made a request to a site with this,
you know,
um
flaw to be triggered and then randomly grab a chunk
of your memory that gets sent to an attacker.
Then the attacker would actually have to look at it and
process it and figure out what the heck this is for,
you know, like given just a cookie like, well, which website is this for which,
you know, is this an account?
Is this a session like,
you know?
And so that's the real problem is we're now at this place where like um well,
we think sort of like most of the internet is affected, but we don't really know
right, that
the unknown is the problem. And I remember it was very similar with heart bleed,
which is a very similar issue
and
it's just that unknown of did something bad happen, did something bad not happen.
We don't exactly know. And so from the security perspective,
-- it's always best to err on the side of caution. Well,
-- but there's a cost with that.
Like,
are you gonna reset every single password
with every single cloud flare served website?
I,
-- do you even know which
-- one? I have no idea.
-- And
-- you're not gonna,
you're not gonna go through your password manager and, like,
compare it to that list of 4.3 million domains.
And then
there is
a
lot,
I'll put it in the show notes
impressively large to say the least.
Yeah.
So, well, part of it is like for example,
wordpress.com and a bunch of other sites like that have like
an automatic kind of ability for you to use Cloudflare,
you like hit a button and boom, you're using cloud flare,
you know, things like that.
There's a lot of applications now that like have a button to use cloud flare.
But yeah, so this basically it comes back to this uncertainty of like, well,
are we affected or are we not affected?
And
you know, even some sites that use cloud flare for serving stuff like for example,
-- explicitly did not use cloud flare for like their authentication stuff,
-- right?
So they're not affected probably,
well, it's complicated because
just because you off against the site doesn't
mean there aren't cookies and various other authentication tokens
traveling between the cloud
servers and the resources you're trying to access. Right.
Exactly. So,
you know, that's really where it boils down to and more to the point. There's no,
well, there's very, uh,
the sort of the evidence and the artifacts of this problem that we do have, like,
stuff in, say Google's cash or Bing's cash,
you know,
going through and processing that to figure out
who actually got vulnerable and who didn't,
would just, it would be a,
you know, an expensive herculean task. But,
you know, they're not going to do probably, it's just too much of a pain in the butt
and on cloud flare side, you know, they don't,
I'm guessing, don't dump the contents of server memory every five seconds.
They, they couldn't,
they couldn't, they just, they, they process too much data and, and zeroing out.
Well, let's face it in a properly functioning system.
You don't need to zero out the memory because
the way you use it
does it correctly and takes care of that.
It's,
it's an unfortunate bug. Well, it's not so. Ok. C sucks. All right.
I love c more than, more than anything in the world, but I feel like it's,
it's that drug addict child you have that you love but you just, you know, you know,
you, you can't keep enabling them
to live that this lifestyle they have.
So, but the problem is
I, it wasn't really C's fault.
They had a parser generating C code and they had
basically made a mistake in their parser and the parser,
I guess, was dumb enough to generate
bad sea which then created this issue. And ironically,
the problem from what I've gathered is the bug had been there for years.
It was just when they made some recent change, it became easier to trigger.
Yeah.
Essentially my understanding is Tavis made some
requests and noticed this wonky garbage data,
looked at the wonky garbage data
and, you know, found out whoops,
right?
But even then I've,
I've read a handful of people who are criticizing
Tavis for kind of the project Zero response,
which is very aggressive compared to many.
But I will say that having been on both sides of this more times than I can count,
I think these guys did it right? I think being aggressive and honest is
the Google Project zero guys,
right?
Well, and especially since this is a real world attack that is,
you know,
-- it had a significant impact and
-- even the Clown
Flare guys though they published a great blog.
-- Well, they did downplay the severity of it.
-- They, they did a bit and
I'm sensitive to that because when you're the one getting kicked,
it's
it's difficult to be brutally honest. But I think,
I think for the most part they did what was right? And I think Tavis did what was right?
And so I think anyone criticizing either side is
kind of a fool. I've seen issues go way worse than this.
-- Right.
-- Yeah.
Well, I do have one concern and that is, you know,
cloud flare runs apparently a bug bounty program.
But, like, even for an epically terrible problem, like this,
the best Tavis could do is a T shirt.
And so there were some comments that,
yeah,
and apparently there were some people commenting that
people are withholding flaws from cloud flare because of
the lack of reward. And
I part of me,
you know, I'm of two minds of that.
On the one hand,
I think that these companies should maybe spend a little bit on bug bounties and,
you know, provide that incentive for researchers.
But at the same time, I think like, like generally speaking,
white hat researchers in my opinion, should try to do the right thing
regardless of reward. You know, it's,
if I,
you know,
if I'm working in public health and I discover some new strain of super gonorrhea,
you know, I shouldn't report that to the government because I get a reward.
I should report to the government because I don't want
to live in a world full of super gonorrhea.
-- I understand what you're saying and I struggle with
-- this
issue.
It, it, it doesn't have an easy answer and
we could argue about this for hours in, in either direction.
And I think
at the end of the day,
the current socially acceptable,
I guess solution
is the bug bounty system and is as flawed as it is and
it certainly is flawed,
but it is kind of the way it works now and
whether you like it or not,
that is
the way it is.
And I think, rather than argue about the phys
philosophical
or technical merits of it, it's just
if you're not running a bug bounty, you're probably behind the times.
It's just the unfortunate reality.
It reminds me a lot of like democracy.
You know, it's not pretty, it doesn't always work well,
but of all the systems we've tried so far, it's the least worst
or it used to be at least words.
Yeah.
But um, no, I mean, that's what, what really gets me is um
just, you know, yeah, companies need to at a minimum, make it,
make it easy to report stuff.
And number two for the really bad stuff,
you actually have to do something in a
reasonably timely manner like this whole thing,
you know, vendors used to sit on stuff like this for years,
literally,
you know, there's disclosure timelines from back in the, you know,
uh I hate to say this, the odds,
you know, the 2000 through 2010
or nine, whatever, whatever the odds were,
you know,
there's stuff that like you look at the disclosure
timeline and it's like two or three years.
Yeah, I, I remember those days, man, I remember
trying to do disclosure with certain organizations and
it was a total nightmare and they would,
they would bully you
because
they figured, well, we'll threaten to sue or we'll say this or that or another.
And so,
I mean,
it was, it was terrible. I'm not gonna lie. It was not good.
And this is where
I, I feel like the bug bounty programs,
they, they kind of have two effects is, first of all,
they give researchers a certain incentive,
ok? Which is
right or wrong. It exists, ok?
But it also on the company side or the organization side, I won't say company.
It,
it makes you put certain things in place for dealing with this stuff because I mean,
well, you remember, it's still, actually, it's not even remember.
It's still a problem. I mean,
there are organizations that if you had to report a security flaw to,
you couldn't
because,
you know,
you go to their website and you look for security stuff and there's nothing there.
I mean, that's a huge problem.
I remember horror stories of people like, you know, contacting organizations,
software or service providers and like trying to work their way
through sport and the ever classic one with the banks,
you know,
do you have an account with us? No click.
Yeah. Right.
You know, it's like I'm trying to help you guys, like,
I keep reaching out to this one bank and they're like on Twitter and I'm like, hey,
I just got, you know, because I keep getting text messages for like,
a couple of Canadian banks that I don't have account that saying, you know,
go to like Banken
online.com or whatever to like, you know,
reset your password or
those
messages and not like spammers trying to steal account information from you.
Well, that's exactly what they are. Right. They're spammers, right?
And so II I then, you know, take a screenshot and like, tweet it at,
uh, you know, at bank security or at bank or whatever.
And they're always like, oh, can you please report it through this, blah, blah,
blah.
And I'm like, no, no, I'm not,
I'm not jumping through hoops to report something to you. I,
I sent you a screenshot on Twitter with a domain.
You, you need to deal with this now and route it internally.
I'm not going to do that for you.
Yeah.
You know, and that's the thing, right? It's,
you know, all those times like somebody, you know,
when you don't make it hard for people to speak up
that drives me nuts. You know, I, I agree completely.
I was at the library and I saw somebody browsing porn.
So I went up to the library and I'm like, oh, hey, uh, you know, the guy in station nine,
he's, uh, browsing pornography.
She's like, oh, ok. Thank you. We'll deal with it
done.
You know, they, they're not gonna make me fill out a form and trip it or whatever.
-- I'm
-- sure there's organizations and libraries that would,
nothing would surprise me.
And that's, you know, and that's the thing,
that's the biggest signal to me with a bug
bounty is chances are you're not gonna sue me
and chances are you're gonna have a point of contact I can talk to that won't be like,
have you tried turning it off and on?
Yeah, I'm, oh, man, I know what you mean.
Sometimes when you try to deal with nonsecurity people,
they don't quite understand what's going on.
You know, I'll never forget is this is, I love this story. So I was,
but a we lay
out fresh out of college and I was working for an organization
that was
in the process of cloud washing their product.
And
all right,
I remember they had one point where there was like the login user name,
password and they had a sequel injection on the login.
And
of course, you know, I'm like, look here, we, we can have to fix this because if,
you know, if I type in this look, I can, you know, show the, the total layout
of the database, right? No, I did not drop the tables.
But anyway, and I remember the, the developer looked at me, he's like,
why would anyone do that?
And I said I just did that, you know, come on and it,
they did not understand what was going on and
they just kept saying nobody's gonna do that.
And I remember
with
SS
Exactly they, but I mean, I get that right.
And this is unfortunately what can happen is if you have a security guy try
to report a security flaw and someone doesn't quite understand the nuance of it.
And let's face it, like, in this case with cloud flare, this was fairly nuanced.
I think
it would be easy for a, a very, we'll say, um, I, I hesitate to say uninformed but,
you know,
someone who maybe isn't hip with security to understand exactly
what is happening here and why it is so serious.
Yeah.
Oh man, it's
remember when things were easy, Kurt.
Yeah.
Well, so I have some good news for you.
Um This just came into my mailbox. Uh The CV newsletter from Miter just popped in
feature story CV E 2005 4900 is sha one collision attack shattered.
-- Uh from 2005,
-- this vulnerability in sha one was assigned CV ID 2005 4900 in 2016.
Uh They don't say why they use 2005, but
I think it's probably because this attack was first posited in 2005.
Probably when the research came out
for this. I know it was a long time ago.
-- Yeah.
-- And now it's, this is the actual proof of concept part, right?
Because we do that all the time, right? Like
somebody will come up with a Linux kernel flaw and it's
not for like a year or two until somebody bothers,
try and exploit for it.
-- You know,
-- actually you say that this is even
look at physics.
How long was the Higgs
boson a thing?
And in fact,
actually the Higgs boson is a great analogy here because you think about it,
the Higgs
boson.
So Higgs is the name of the,
the physicist who kind of predicted the existence of the boson.
And then he was widely ridiculed for a long time as being a crazy person
and then they build the large Hadron Collider and it's like, oh, yeah, look,
we found it and it took, you know, like 30 years to go from essentially research
and, and theory to ridicule
to,
oh,
yeah,
it's,
uh, I
don't think anyone criticized Einstein.
-- Well, they kind of did
-- for me,
it was not well accepted because, you know, God does not play dice with the universe,
I think.
Well, that was his quote.
Right. But, I
mean, you know,
anytime people have come up with new
theories that fundamentally view the world differently,
that's true.
I mean, that's,
that's
not
the
thing to
do and then eventually
it's proven
and, and I guess that that's part of this and this is true.
Security is there's always someone who will deny this is
a problem until it is proven beyond a reasonable doubt.
At which point. It's like, oh, crap. Now, I've got to get on this bus
and,
yeah, that's, that's really interesting. And I guess ironically as well is
the trick for like the Higgs boson is we had to wait for technology
and someone to build a giant machine capable of actually doing this work,
which is not unlike the shaw problem is we had to wait for
a massive cloud infrastructure to exist.
So we,
right. So we could do it.
It's, oh,
wow. I need to, I need to do some research on this.
This could be a really fun topic to, to compare
the I guess world of,
of science and physics to the world of security going from theory to practice.
And I guess more importantly though is once we've proven something in practice,
how does it change the work that happens after that point?
Because obviously for, for, I mean relativity is a great example is once Einstein,
you know, came up with the theory of relativity,
it kind of went through its peer review and was accepted,
it dramatically changed
literally all of science for forever
because
I mean
concrete level a member of the RS A show
there was a quantum level random number generator.
Oh yeah, that's uh Richard Mold
and the white wood encryption guys. They, they're super
cool dudes and
I love talking to them because my joke is always, you know, there, there's all this,
all these people talk about randomness and whatnot.
And I'm like,
and I, I told Richard this and I said,
you're one of like the five people in the
world that's actually qualified to talk about randomness.
You know, it's,
it's one of those things everyone thinks they can talk about.
I mean, heck, we've done
more than once. Like, we're totally unqualified.
We don't really know what we're talking about.
Yeah. I just remember the look on the astrophysicist face there.
She was so excited when she realized because I was wearing my suit. Right.
And I think everybody assumes I'm a market droid when I'm in my suit
and then she realized I was technical and just the look on her face was just such a joy.
There you go.
You know. But uh yeah. No, it's, it's, you're right like this,
you know, the sha one is a great example.
Are we gonna like all the world stop using
sha one tomorrow and start transitioning off of it?
Oh, no,
sadly not.
But
yeah, I, I sha
three is gonna be a ways away.
Uh
Yeah, probably.
Which is sad. But, oh, well, it is what it is.
There's not a lot we can do about it.
Well, you know, it reminds me a lot of the I PV four I PV six network thing
in the, I
don't think I'll ever have a native I PV
six network experience until my kids have like grandkids.
I,
yes,
I know.
I'm still terrified of the security flaws. We are going to discover
I PV six.
-- Well, you think about it? I mean,
-- it's already been horrifying.
It hasn't been that bad. Honestly, I, I've
advertisement stuff has been pretty bad because most
people just pretended like it wasn't a problem.
-- Implementation.
-- Explain
the problem for the listeners who don't know what you're talking about.
-- So,
-- one of the, one of the,
one of the things with I PV six is that, you know, let's make configuration easier. So
you don't necessarily need to run like a DH CP server to hand out addresses and stuff.
You can just, for example, here's your prefix staple on your MAC address. Boom.
Done, right?
Uh So things like that and then there's this idea of like a route advertisement,
Damon where a machine can basically advertise like, hey, I'm a route for X, right?
So that stuff, routing and whatnot just sort of magically happens.
Well, the problem is anybody can advertise that crap on the network.
So if you have a network with a malicious computer, it can advertise, hey,
I'm the default route.
And then of course, it actually,
you know,
becomes a default route for everything
and then sends the traffic on through the actual default route.
And man in the middle is everything,
you know, things like that. So uh a quick search for um
the CV database shows 263 CV entries that match the term I PV six.
How many match I PV for
uh a lot.
Uh It is
0 100 and 55
it.
Well,
there's probably more than that because I'm
sure a lot of things aren't specifically denoted
as IP four and I'm sure a lot of these problems happened before CV.
E was really even a thing
CV, started in 1999. So, yes, I PV
T
four has been around forever.
Forever.
Yeah. But fundamentally like it's, I PV six is going to have to go, like,
-- the sad reality is we don't seem to learn the lessons of the past.
-- We never will.
And, well, not only that, the bigger problem I see with I PV six is
if you, if you think about the level of complexity,
I PV six is like magnitudes more complex than I PV four.
I
try to read the specs to fully understand it and I gave up.
It's,
and that's gonna be the problem and that's what's gonna be the challenge
for security is there's the issues of being complete according to standards which
no one will be because they're too complicated.
There's gonna be issues of implementing
the standards because they're incomplete and
it's just crazy complex. So there's going to be mistakes because
there's
different
and that, that will probably happen also where one person will do it one way,
the other person will do it the other way and
who knows what that's going to result in.
And so I imagine once I PV SIX becomes
way more widely used than it is today and it's actually it's getting there.
But I suspect
once the researchers start hitting it hard
we're gonna find a lot of crazy problems.
Oh,
yeah. Yeah. No, that's a given, um,
for us.
Yeah. So,
anyway,
I guess encrypt everything just and make sure you don't use sha one.
Yes.
That will fix everything.
Indeed. Oh, man, it's,
I love it. Welcome to the internet. It's complicated and hard and weird
and we don't know what to do.
Oh, well, such is life
but it works pretty well. It, it does.
Yeah,
it's been, oh, man. Let's hope.
Let's hope this week isn't anything like last week because, well,
there was also that Linux kernel root privilege escalation
issue that we totally didn't talk about at all,
which ironically would have been exciting news.
Had Sean not been broken and Claude Flair kind of had their issue.
Well, and the thing, it kind of reminds me of like, like bank security that, you know,
I hate to say this but like
local privilege escalation in the Linux kernel are bad, but
-- this isn't our first rodeo.
-- It isn't.
We basically know what to do at this point.
Well, not only that, I think at this point if you have a system
that isn't doing some sort of sand boxing and you are allowing multiple users on it,
you're doing something wrong.
Well, just from a, I
mean, who the heck runs on bear hardware anymore?
Like V MS are way easier to manage and provision.
Yes. And
I mean, it's just, we're at that point where it's like,
it's, you know,
it's like all the people that I remember back in the day people didn't use DH P,
they would manually configure everything.
And I discovered DH P and I'm like, oh, my sweet goodness.
Wow.
I just, I,
I do one config file on one server and bam everything
-- you turn it on and it works in their
-- defense.
I don't know if you've ever set up I PV or not. IP A DH CP.
Way back in the day. It was a nightmare to get working correctly.
This is actually,
this is where Microsoft as much as I complained about them back in the 2000, early,
two thousands,
they got a lot of this stuff, right? Because they made it very pointy, clicky.
Anyone can figure this out and, and if you're on using a UNIX system
and trying to configure your network,
you had to be some sort of insane wizard to make it work.
And you remember all the books, like, remember the o'reilly books?
They were all like phone books,
all of them,
right? I, oh man, I, I still have them. They're in my basement and I keep thinking,
I don't want to throw them out, but they have no value.
I do want to throw them out.
I actually, my accountant asked me, I remember one year he's like, do you,
do you really have to spend this much on computer books.
And I'm like, yeah, and he's like, you realize you spent, like,
$5000 on computer books.
And I'm like, uh,
I believe that I, well, and they were expensive, man.
Like, the good books were 100 bucks.
Some of them were more than that.
Well, I remember buying, uh, not that this isn't really related but it's, uh,
Knuth's the art of computer programming.
It was like 300 bucks for that.
There were, what, four books back then, or three books.
I, for, I forget the name of it is, it is very nice.
There's a new book now though and I don't have it and
part of me wants it and part of me is like,
uh, I don't know.
So we'll see, maybe I'll break down some day and get it.
I decided not to buy physical books anymore. I just,
-- I don't space constraints.
-- I agree with that. I don't care for real books.
Real books are big and they take up a lot of space and
I love the fact that I get on an airplane now
and I have
hundreds of books in my bag.
And I remember traveling where,
where occasionally you'd be almost done with one book and she'd
bring two books and it took an insane amount of room.
So,
yeah, I'm quite happy. That's not a problem.
Yeah.
No, I, I think I only buy about 10 or 20 physical books a year now,
which is down from like, hundreds.
I don't even know. Well, I, if you count my kids, my kids like physical books.
So we use them there. But, yeah, I don't think I've bought a real book in forever.
I can't even remember the last one.
-- Which is good. That's good. I'm happy.
-- So, you heard it here?
First folks, books are dead
on
the
internet.
Yeah.
Right. Anyway,
we'll say dead trees are dead,
right.
Dead trees are dead.
That's what we'll say.
Books are awesome.
All right.
They, they are the best thing. I agree. I do love books anyway. All right. All right.
So,
thank you everyone for listening.
It's been fun.
If you want to see any of the show notes,
any of the links for the crazy things we talked about.
You can go to open source security podcast.com
and there you can find a link to Twitter to hassle. Kurt and myself.
There is a link to a Facebook group. You are welcome to join and interact.
If nothing else, Kurt,
you have a Marvelous day and thank you everyone for listening.
Thanks everybody.
That's it. Just thanks. Usually you say something ridiculous.
Well, it's, it's that whole pause where II,
I feel like you were staring at me over the internet.
I am staring at you over the internet.