Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner enjoying the web browsing experience.
Josh Pressers. We'll get to that.
All right, before we start part of the research I did for this episode.
Do you know how to spell the word Wildebeest? Wildebe Est? Ok. So you got it right.
Be Est. I was like, there's no way. That's right.
I thought it must be some weird British spelling or something.
No, that's like the actual way you spell Wildebeest be Est.
And that's apparently how the Dutch spell beast.
It's a Dutch origin.
The Dutch are even cooler now, in my opinion than they were before this.
You just called the Dutch? Cool. They are. The Dutch are very cool.
Come on, I'm German. So like,
uh
I'm very Dutch. I'm very Dutch and the Dutch are cool because they have good cheese.
Amsterdam is a lovely city and now they spell beast. Be Est.
Yeah. Well, that's how you spell the word beast
in, in Dutch.
Anyway. All right.
So we're gonna talk about
Google's
insane web browser proposal, but
I'm going to make it much bigger than this. Well, actually, it's worse than that. OK.
You start with why it's worse and then we'll go. Well, no, let's start.
I actually, there are some elements of their proposal that I enjoy in the sense of.
So in cloud computing, for example,
we're finally making inroads with confidential computing,
which means I can compute a workload
and I don't have to worry about Amazon sticking
their grubby little paws in it in theory.
Yes. And
some thing along
those lines would be good for the web where the browser could attest
to certain capabilities or like I am a public computer for the love of God.
You should never log into your bank on me,
right?
Or something like where it could block stuff like that or conversely,
I am a very private computer, very secure.
So like
stop harassing Kurt with his BS two fa and just let
him log into his bank and pay a bill also.
He has no money. So if anybody breaks in, it's fine.
The problem is
that's my banking security strategy man. I'm just, I don't have any money in there.
I
spend it all on bills. There you go.
So Google had this idea for the web environment integrity.
Oh no, it,
it we I web environment integrity which like on the surface is like honestly, we,
the industry as a whole needs to move to the level
of maturity where things can attest to what they are.
Am I a human. Am I a bot?
Am I
do? I maybe theoretically have an ad blocker installed. And, aha,
here's where things start to go off the rails. Right. Because
everybody views this
and Google gives the example of, you know, websites,
some websites are expensive to run and, like,
supported by ads and if you have an ad blocker then
they can't afford to run it. Like, I wonder who that's geared at.
Yeah.
So, Google, everybody's like Google, this sounds a lot like DRM to lock people out of
using ad blockers and Google's like, no, no, no, no, no.
We, we would never do that except,
except for the time they did last year with
the V three manifest and the extensions ignoring that.
But as you said,
none of that matters for a simple reason. And can I
read the reason if I said no, would it matter?
Well, you can always edit it out of the show.
So Google,
so Google dropped their financial results today. I've not seen these.
This is completely new to me. Uh
OK. So
from 2020 to 2021 because of COVID,
there was a massive surge in online advertising like 40%.
So
sorry. Um Google's numbers.
So they went from 146 point 92 billion to 209.49 billion.
So like a 41 point whatever percent bump like, wow,
some people got some bonuses that year.
Uh But from 2021 to 2022 209 to 224.
Ok, I mean low single digits improvements. It's still respectable.
I would say this year's looking maybe not as good.
Is it flat or is it going down? It's probably still going up but
less.
And that's,
this is,
but this is for a business
in
tech
with the pe ratio of whatever Google's pe ratio for their stock is
this is the apocalypse.
The view of the, the companies like Google and Facebook and, well, I'll,
I'll say Twitter cheekily,
but
it was always like that double
digit. I love that. You meant meta and a
like you're, you're like now six years behind renames. I am, I'm, I'm old now.
I could do that.
But get off by law, you kids,
these companies have experienced like 10 and 20% growth forever.
Well, and that's the thing. So
Google, Amazon and Microsoft
Azure. So their cloud stuff is still growing between 16 and 28%
year on
which is nice and healthy. But here's the problem.
How much money roughly did Google make
off advertising last in their financial results?
I bet it was 80% or more. Well, yeah, exactly.
And so the problem is they made like 56 billion off advertising and
about 6 billion off cloud and about 6 billion off other stuff.
So
like, yeah, 26 or 20% increase. That's great.
But a 20 26% increase on and I say only 6 billion, like I have any money.
Right. But, but for these companies, that's,
that's not a lot of money I get. That's one or 2 billion a year in growth. That's,
that's a, that's literally a rounding error on their advertising revenue.
Oh, yeah, for sure, for sure.
But, but here's,
and that's the thing I love is they're trying to technology their
way out of an economics and it's not even an economics problem.
It's a human behavior
problem. Yes, that is exactly where we were going to end up.
Or at least I, I hoped we would, I can never guarantee anything
but
like, no
bottles.
They paid my
street,
no
straight up. They paid like two blocks of the street. That was really bad.
It's lovely. Now, it's like as flat as a pancake
here is why I was looking up Wildebeests
because I didn't know how to spell it.
You didn't watch Wild Mutual of Omaha as a kid. I did.
But it's not like I knew how to spell Wildebeest.
I assumed Wildebeest
was W
I LDA beast
because I'm from the Midwest and we spell everything the way it sounds
and if it's not, we, we change the pronunciation to match what we think it should be.
I was about to say
like, welcome to the Midwest. Everyone come to our French towns
like
anyway.
So I think we are experiencing
the end of what we'll call web two, which was the advertising fueled everything.
And I think the behavior we're seeing everything,
literally everything.
I think the, the behavior we're seeing from the likes of Meta and X and Google
and
Amazon and literally everyone because a lot of these companies,
it looks like they're being run by lunatics,
they're making decisions that are bizarre
and they're clearly, they don't have like a good solid direction,
they don't know what's happening.
And I think this is my, my,
my comparison is that the people in charge
and the investors and the venture capitalists,
some of them know what, what is happening.
I bet a lot of them don't. It's kind of like how, when you have a herd of wildebeest,
they don't know what they're doing, they go where the food is.
Right. And I think that is what we're seeing is this ad revenue
is starting to dry up
and you're seeing investment in things moving somewhere else.
And a lot of people don't know what's happening and they don't know why
it's not that it's drying up. It's that it's growing
slower and it's slowing down enough that while it's technically not flatlining it,
anything less than 5% growth a year is basically dead.
Right.
And so
it doesn't have to flatline or even be that bad.
It just if it's less than 5% growth a year, you have a real problem.
The other thing
I think that's happening is a lot of
these subscription services are increasing their prices too
and offering, you know, like lower tier
ad supported ones because,
well,
to put it bluntly getting $10 a month from somebody
and showing them ads is a lot better than getting
nothing from them.
Right.
Because like you, let's be real, your incremental costs on digital goods are
as close to zero as they can be without,
you know, needing a math degree to express.
No. Really? Right.
Like I know.
So,
and
the other thing is I, I feel like one of the things I think you missed
and that just occurred to me is we also have a new generation coming in
a generation that has grown up with web two and advertising
and the minute they see it without the, without the ads with an A blocker and stuff,
they're like, oh, I like that more.
But
my son still,
like he just has muscle memory for that skip button is on, on youtube
because when he's at school and it's on the digital projector,
he literally will just like shuffle over to where that button's gonna show
up because they're not logged like they're not logged into a premium account
and, and it's funny because
like the other kid be like, you're blocking the way and, and the teacher will be like,
he's going to hit the ad skip button.
They're like, oh, ok.
Right.
You know,
they're,
they're, these kids are digital native, like
they've had ipads and high speed internet since
they were in diapers. Oh, yeah. They don't know any better. Absolutely. I really, I
can't help but think the advertising doesn't work as well
to some degree on them and more to the point
they're savvier at blocking it well, and not only that they don't have any money.
I mean, I don't want to be, like, in a hole or anything but, like,
the young generation is totally being hosed over
by the old people between rent and all.
Oh, my God. I bought two potatoes today and I, well, I texted you. So or I signaled you.
So
this sounds like the most Russian story ever. Yeah.
So I bought two large potatoes today to do baked potato skins and they cost $7.47
and minimum wage locally is $15.
So half an hour of work at minimum wage to buy two large russet potatoes.
That's
insane. That sounds like some like communist Russia stuff right there. I know.
But it, it literally means I could buy 16 potatoes a day if I worked minimum wage. And
that doesn't include rent or anything.
Like, yeah, the,
the younger generation advertising is not going to work on them because
they don't have two Kopec
to rub together or two potatoes. In this case.
I think this is, oh,
my goodness.
Again,
I think this comes back to not a lot of people don't understand what's
going on and they don't know why they're doing things and I think this,
this Google proposal is a great example.
Right. Well, first of all,
they did it with a
non
Google Github
repository. Right. Then
they got some hilarious issues filed, like one that's like, are,
are you the bad guys?
They lock it.
So, first of all, if your open source project has to have the,
the repository locked from external contributors,
like you're doing something wrong,
but then
they had a hacker news thread where they basically did their best to say, oh, no, no,
we're not the bad guys here like we're the good guys.
And here's the thing.
I have no doubt
the people who put this proposal together
think they're doing the right thing
because I think they are stuck in the middle of
the herd and they don't understand what's happening around them.
I think they have nothing but good intentions.
But obviously anyone on the outside looks at this and you
see exactly what the cliff they're all going to jump off of
this will be the literal death of Web two because all of a sudden we'll be locked. Like
when I browse the web on my mobile phone,
I try not to because I don't run an ad blocker
on my phone and it is horrifying like it is,
it
is almost impossible to navigate some of these sites. And I'm pretty nimble,
you know, you can install the duck, duck go Browser on your phone.
And it does a pretty good job.
But, I mean, more to the point I don't want to go to those sites really.
And I'm trying to be a bit anyways.
The majority of sites I actually go to are like
people's blogs and stuff that actually don't have advertising.
It's quite lovely.
No, I get it for sure.
That's why I love, like, lemme and Mastodon have become my favorite sites because
I give Jerry Bell money and he gives me
amusement.
And I mean, how do you explain people's $100 cable bill? That's
people will pay for
you pay for ads.
So I know, right, remember called the whole premise of cable TV,
early on was it's you pay for it.
So there's no ads and that's,
I think that's part of the challenge is the cult like I've been looking at the,
what's fascinating to me is
so we have now the cloud, the hyper cloud players, right?
There's three of them Google,
Amazon and Microsoft and they are three different companies, right?
Google is an advertising company that happens to have cloud, right?
Amazon is a merchant, right? They're all about that high volume sales.
That's their culture
that happens to have a cloud and their cloud really does reflect that.
And then Microsoft of course,
is the classic business solutions to the point of throwing chairs at people
and their cloud really reflects that right? It's all about Business Solutions.
Right.
And well, let me put it this way. Like
Gmail will Gmail still be around in 50 years. Would you bet a kidney on it?
I would not bet a kidney on that. I would not take that bet. Ok,
Microsoft Outlook. Will it be around in 100 years?
For sure. Absolutely. Absolutely.
It'll probably still be named Outlook, but it'll be like, oh, look 1000
and you'll probably still have to rebuild those PST files
for
sure.
And, you know, and,
and looking at
like the whole A I thing and the, the web two thing and where all this is headed.
I mean, fundamentally, here's the thing we have tried for 20 years
to find a way to make websites, make money. Right. Right. That's right.
The answer is advertising. Well, even then it was a tall hill decline.
Yeah.
But, I mean, we tried micropayments many, many times.
We've tried it again with Blockchain
and
ignoring the technology that doesn't work.
But let's assume for a moment that somehow
micro payment technology works and it's efficient enough that
you can actually do a one penny transaction
without paying like a dollar in transaction fees.
But the cognitive load for a human being
to, like, like I said to you earlier, like, people,
I, the thing I find most offensive about tipping is I have to think about it a lot.
Like,
and I've come to the conclusion that, like,
if I'm asked for a tip before I'm given service.
I'm not tipping because how do I know how good service will be?
Well, it's going to be bad if you don't give him a tip.
Right? But that's the thing, right?
So there's this cognitive load and I just, you want spit in your coffee,
Kirk because that's how you get spit in your coffee pretty much.
So, when I think about, if I had to like cognitively think about,
do I want to see this web page or not for a penny?
Oh,
man.
Problem though is,
is that we don't have any other path to monetization for websites.
That's OK. So this, I think is part of the discussion
and this is something I've been thinking about. So
the old way of the internet is going to die.
The,
the way Google and Facebook and Twitter and all these
services have worked in the past is going to,
it is failing.
We are watching it unravel. That is why
it
ignoring that. Like it feels like
no one is driving the bus
and they are,
they just don't know what they're doing because the
way they used to work no longer functions.
And so they're just literally throwing spaghetti at the wall.
Now something is going to
replace
all of these things.
And like it's funny because people talk about,
oh I need a Twitter replacement like no Twitter is dead forever.
You, you're never going to replace it. Mastodon is not a Twitter replacement.
Mastodon is a totally different thing. That's ok.
And it's never going to replace, nothing will ever replace Twitter,
which may be good or bad.
But anyway,
what comes in and, and kind of, I guess takes over now,
we don't know because it doesn't exist and
it's going to be something we can't imagine
because the reality is, if you looked at the internet in 1997
right? Like it was very new, it was very different.
I mean, I remember the dial up and Netscape one point. Oh, and all the stuff
we could not have even explained
where we are today. How would you explain an iphone to somebody from 20 years ago?
Whatever man, I would have like literally sold my siblings for an iphone back then.
Like I would have given anything to have the internet in my pocket.
I think most of us would sell our siblings for a sandwich.
It did have to be an ok sandwich. Like, but
anyway,
but anyway,
anyway, oh my goodness. I
think about sandwiches.
You have to, you have to sell something you actually care about.
Ok. Ok.
So
I
do like my dog a lot. I just, anyway, that's another story. So. Right.
You've derailed me. But anyway, so something is going to replace these things.
We don't know what it is and we can't imagine what it is at this point.
And so I dare not speculate.
Well, and the beautiful thing too is, is Facebook and Google and all that won't
like they can actually die, die because they're a company.
But something like Irc still chugging along like
there are still Irc networks now there,
I would call them dead even though they actually have tens
or hundreds of thousands of people using them every day.
But in the global context of like half of all adults owning a smartphone
that it's a,
it's not even a rounding error. It's zero, it's zero for sure.
And I think Mastodon is going to be the same thing where the people who
use Mastodon are going to love it and they're going to be very successful with it
from the perspective of how you define success in the context of Twitter,
Mastodon is a failure.
But luckily Mastodon doesn't care what you think. Exactly.
And so that's one thing I find fascinating
is something like Google can actually die,
die.
And whereas protocols can't, and that I think is the other thing is
still exists. Exactly. You know, and like, dig is a weird music site now. It's
super,
like I went through the, I went through like a couple of years ago
and I was like, what even is this?
Oh, it's no, it's not a music. What is this?
Oh, it's buzzfeed. Ok. Never
mind that explains it. Yeah. It's basically,
I think based on the whatever it doesn't matter, quit, quit browsing the web on
a pod.
The thing is the problem though is in this sort of death throes and thrashing around.
Are they going to hurt you people
and make things worse or maybe, you know,
just hasten their demise or are they actually going
to maybe take out something good with them?
I mean, it,
one of my concerns
is like we've,
I think we've firmly as a species decided that the web browser is the thing.
It's cool like it,
it is a thing. So actually, on that note, I literally just found out
right before we hit record,
there is a new thing. You'll have to look it up and we'll talk about it some other day.
It's called the island browser.
It's claiming it's an enterprise web browser that has all these
like weird enterprise features about like at a station and,
and some other details.
So like Microsoft Edge with GPO.
Um
I don't know, does edge do that? I don't know,
Microsoft edge is integrated with
windows and you can apply group policy objects to it.
There you go.
But anyway, we were
doing
15 years ago.
OK. I mean that could be, I don't know. I'm, I'm not hip with enterprises
Microsoft proxy one point. Oh
I passed that exam.
I I don't want to.
But anyway, though,
your point being right about kind of all
this enterprise stuff and what's coming next.
Yeah,
I, I don't know. It's, it's fascinating
and it's terrifying
because we live through the.com crash. Which I think was the death of Web one
point. Oh,
now we see the rise of Web two point.
Oh, I'm not going to talk about Web three because that's a poison term. Now,
I don't know what we'll call the next thing,
but it's going to be fascinating. It might not be the web. That's the crazy thing.
No, that's true. Actually, that's a good point.
Like there might be a new protocol that comes out. That is no, you know what?
I don't think there is. I think HTTP is too good to replace
it, solves too many problems that are hard and it does it well.
And I mean, you've already got all this
instructure where you can pay or not even pay cloud
flare to distribute all your junk without getting attacked.
And that's a big thing people underestimate
is like there's not even the chicken and the egg problem of getting people to
install the client because there's no service and
there's no service because there's no clients.
But like
just
running a site and doing global data delivery
is hard.
Yeah. No, look, I firmly believe
so. Here's
one way to look at this when the birth of sites like Google
and Facebook and all this,
you had a massive amount of venture capital come in
and it funded
this essentially giant R and D division
that for whatever reason landed on ads as the revenue source.
And I don't know if they tried other things. I think it's because it's easy
because
it's easy to convince people to spend money on advertising through just a,
simply a different channel.
Sure. And, uh, probably,
and a
lot of companies had
the infrastructure and mindset for spending money that way exists. Right. Right.
They're not selling them a new thing. It's ads on the internet. It's, that's right.
According to the patent, it's ads with a computer system and they had budgets,
right?
They had budgets for ads like, ok,
let's just take some of our ad budget and give it to these
people over here and they say they're doing things and maybe they are,
we don't know.
And then that led to a virtuous cycle of like, oh, we can do more,
targeted, targeted advertising by knowing that you're a white male that whatever,
whatever.
And of course, that has led to one or two problems but, you know, nothing too major.
But now, now here's, here's the thing and I don't want to burst any bubbles.
But I'm gonna,
because there are people who think
things like the Fetta verse are going to be the next thing.
And I love the Fetta verse more than I should.
Yeah,
I don't think it's gonna be that the, the, the thing that pisses me off.
We've had the Federer.
Like, do you not remember Irc Federer
is cooler?
But I'm saying like we, it's a similar concept, right? The
defer
multiple servers, blah, blah, blah. And, and here's the reason I say this though,
there was a story, I read one time about this guy who was creating a company
and he was doing it
entirely self funded, right? Where he had a good idea
and he was controlling costs and he was hiring slow
and he had a couple of customers and he was making money and doing well.
And then one day the CEO of a competitor shows up and says I'm going to,
you can sell to me now or I'll kill you in a year.
And the guy was like, what do you mean?
And he said, look, I've got venture capitalists behind me lined up.
I'm gonna hire more sales people in a month than you have employees.
We're going to go to every one of your customers. We're gonna undercut, you
know, more than you can even reasonably fathom.
We're going to steal all of your customers in six months.
You'll have zero revenue in a year, like sell to me now or go out of business.
And that is what is going to happen because you're going to see some company
a merge that's venture capital funded, that can afford to do
weird things like they don't need ads with A I
now you can do super tar like I'm looking ok,
I'm gonna do a little disclosure of private stuff I have,
I'm kind of incubating a product, um, a project I'm calling concierge at the CS A.
And the idea is
so, for example,
I could take your resume, go through it with you,
talk to you about what you want to do with your career. Do you want to work from home?
Do you want to have a family?
And we could figure out like, what is an ideal sort of job for you?
And so what do you need to do to get that job?
What certifications, what training, what,
how do you need to bump your resume on all that?
Right. We could do that today.
The problem is it would take me two or three hours and so it doesn't scale, right?
I am 99.7. 3%. Sure. We can design some chat GP T prompts that will do most of that work.
I mean, that could be, and then basically,
like, sell that, for example, for 100 bucks
and make a lot of money. Like, there would be a good margin on that product.
Well, the margin is $100.
Well, no, no, no, the API calls are actually quite not cheap.
Are they really?
Yeah, it'd be like five bucks.
Um,
you know, but that's the point.
Like if, if, if you had a service that could really, like, there are career coaches,
they charge a lot of money.
But if you could have something that would actually, like,
help you in the infosec industry, get a much better job
with a, like, even a 10% chance of that working. And it only costs 100 bucks,
like a lot of people jump on that.
And that's an example. I'm not, I don't think we'll maybe do that. But the point is
with A I, you can scale out really complicated heavy tasks.
And I think that is gonna,
that is what's going to be coming next because somebody's
going to figure out the killer app where the A I
tells you a personalized bedtime story or
tells you a personalized newspaper based on,
I, I don't know.
Right. But it's,
there's, there
are
things that are capable. Right. Exactly.
But the point is there are things that are capable now that we couldn't even imagine.
But, but here's the challenge.
So the challenge though Kurt, and this is what is going to be the issue. We see
the challenge is always going to be, what is the road to monetization? Exactly.
Exactly.
If it's not ads, which
I don't know if, I mean, it is completely conceivable.
There will be a new company that invents, I'll put in events in quotes, air quotes,
invents a new way to sell online advertising that all
the advertisers flock to and say this is it,
this makes sense.
Well,
advertising reminds me of let's encrypt in the
sense of even if our concierge projects,
whatever charge a penny,
that's a massive amount of money and hassle for everybody versus advertising.
Is just,
you consume the advertising but you, you can't,
most of this,
like, web scale stuff you can't charge for because
when your target audience is in the billions of people, billions of people
can't spend money.
Well, they don't have credit cards even if they have money.
Yeah. Right. Right.
It's, it's just not practical and, and that's why ads have been the key.
But of course, we've also, like,
all of our personal details are now in Mark Zuckerberg's basement and like
this sucks and everyone knows everything about me and I hate it.
I don't know,
maybe it's just,
no, it sucks. People used
to small villages and everybody knew everything
that's,
that's totally different.
Yeah.
But uh no, I think the thing that's gonna happen is I think fundamentally,
like you said, the problem is not the technology, it's
the path to monetization and how that interacts with basic human behaviors
because
not just that
just that people to make any decisions is hard.
That's not, that's not even the issue. The issue is
many good ideas
won't be back for venture capital
and the things that venture capital backs will murder the other stuff.
Well, I shouldn't say murder,
murder is the wrong word because things like the Fetta verse,
the Fetta verse is going to be fine,
but the Fed
Averse is never going to have 6 billion people using it.
Average people will hear about threats because
they have an advertising budget and even people
in tech still don't know what the heck Mastodon is or the Fed Averse is.
Sure. Right. Exactly. There's no advertising budget. Absolutely. And it,
you know, again, Mastodon doesn't care like it's hard to use. I don't care.
Not my problem
to me. That's a feature.
No,
seriously, because I
disagree.
I don't mean to be a jerk. But like Irc, remember Eternal September back in what?
9899?
Well, that was use net eternal September was useless.
Irc definitely had its own set of complications we'll say
over the,
oh my goodness. I remember some of the trolls you do on Irc. It was so good. Hunter two.
Hunter two comes
IC
I will put a link to Hunter Two
in the show notes if you don't know what that is
like, I I know like no one clicks, show notes.
You want to click this one because Hunter Two is the best story you will ever read.
I think it goes back to the defining success.
And what like fundamentally people have a basic human need for connection,
storytelling, story, listening, connecting, eating food together,
sitting together on a park bench, holding hands, right?
Basic human connection.
And that
if you look at sort of these killer apps,
they've always been kind of wrapped around human connection, right?
The fax machine, email, social media.
And one of the things I kind of hope for is I worry that these things end up getting,
like, really mangled and perverted, like Facebook started out.
No, I'm not going to say Facebook started with good intentions. But,
you know, you chat with your family and stuff and now it's become
the horror show that Facebook is.
Oh, well, Twitter is a better example where Twitter went from,
like something that was kind of cool
to like,
oh my God, it's,
I don't know what happened to you.
Well, no, we know exactly what happened, but
the right wing moved in and nobody kicked them out
and then that's the owner like, and now they're, now they're X
Yeah.
And I love that.
There's so somebody was like, oh,
Facebook owns the trademark X as it pertains to social media.
And then somebody else was like, oh, but also Microsoft and then somebody's like,
no, don't worry about it.
There are 700
registered ex trademarks of which a bunch of them are social media
and
companies that are, I was gonna say on par with
X or Twitter or whatever.
But no, they're actually a lot larger now,
Twitter fired half of their people
or more.
And my first thought when I read that was like,
I'm shocked the lawyers let them do that.
And I was like, oh, wait, there are no lawyers anymore.
Did you hear there apparently something like $700 million in pending
lawsuits regarding severance pay? I have no doubt. Like the number was, I think,
I think it was 700. It was a big number.
So,
I mean, just now when I
die alone, let's, let's bring this one home. We're out of time. To me.
The hopeful news is things like the fetters.
Now, somebody like Jerry Bell can run
a system
with multiple servers for tens of thousands of people affordably
like a less than a buck a month per user.
And so if even like 10% of his users donate a bit of money,
it's sustainable.
And
that
I don't know if it's sustainable. I think Jerry's still paying a lot out of pocket,
but regardless, just have him turn it off for an hour and screen test everybody. No.
Seriously. Right. Like,
like just screen test.
Like the thing is like Wikipedia, for example,
is at the point now where they actually have a huge endowment,
like an absurdly large endowment over $100 million. I know we talked about this.
I'm ok with that.
So
it's, it's,
I, I think
that
I
think a lot of fed uh,
servers or systems will be sustainable. Either
they'll make enough money to pay for themselves or they'll be somebody just like,
I don't care about wasting 50 or 100 bucks a month.
I mean, maybe, I don't know this podcast. It's a hobby.
You waste money on it.
It's so what some people earn in a month. Waste is a generous description. But,
well, I mean,
but the money you spend on this podcast is what some people earn in a month.
Uh That could be, that could be. But regardless, I am excited to see what comes next
and I'm
apprehensive for what the destruction will bring with it
because
no,
when you, when destruction happens, there are always side effects.
And that is what scares me a little bit.
But I'm also, it will be,
it will be very interesting to see what rises from these ashes.
So
time will tell and I learned how to spell wildebeest. So all in all pretty good day.
I'm curious, what would have happened if I'd gotten it wrong?
Would you have laughed?
No, actually, I wouldn't have, I wouldn't have because I didn't know either.
And I was hoping you would have gotten it wrong
because I feel like it's a very strange word.
And I was going to use that as part of my anecdote of such a strange word.
But lo and behold, you know how to spell it. You ruined my day.
But you also got to remember I speak some German. So that's kind of
what is, what is the quote? My disappointment is immeasurable. My day is ruined
him.
I like his reviews.
At least it's the end of my day. So only a little bit of day is ruined. But anyway.
All right. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you both for listening.
Go to open social security podcast.com,
UZ Podos
says podcast hashtag on Mastodon
to hit us up. Kurt. Have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye
-- bye.