Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Sidewalk Crime.
Josh Pressers Sidewalk.
This was a marvelous opportunity to make a joke
about Mr rogers' neighborhood and you blew it.
-- I don't
-- want to drag Mr Rogers into this. He's, he's better than us.
-- That's
-- true.
-- He's a lovely person.
-- I was going to say he's better than this, but he's better than us
actually. So I have a little side tangent story. I'll tell it is
there was, I,
I don't know if there was some anniversary or
birthday or something that happened with Mr Rogers,
but there was
a number of specials on my local public television station about Mr Rogers.
And of course,
during these, they're doing their usual pledge drive. Like please give us money and
as someone who they call them sustaining members
where I just give them a monthly amount
annoy me to no end because I'm like, I'm already giving you money.
-- Like give me a secret channel or something.
-- Skip a skip a
seriously.
-- Both
-- of my
Children, they're doing this little, you know,
send us money and they have a Mr Rogers tote bag you can get.
Which of course, if you ever watch any public television,
like a tote bag is like the default gift for donating.
And
my kids thought I was nuts because I literally, like, went and got my computer
and gave them more money just to get this tote
bag because I really liked it and I wanted it.
-- So I paid an enormous amount of money for a tote
-- bag.
I paid 100 bucks for a coffee cup for the, uh, for the reading Rainbow Kickstarter.
Why not? Right. I did not do that. Which makes me sad. But in
fairness they raised
was it $6 million in a week?
-- And they wanted a million. So
-- everybody loves reading
Rainbow
Levar.
Burton is almost as cool as Mr Rogers.
All right. All right. Anyway,
today we're going to talk about Amazon Sidewalk, which is, we'll say the opposite
of the neighborhood of make believe in every possible way.
And what's interesting is
I think it's only available in America because I cannot find it
on my account to disable. I don't think they're doing it
outside of America right now.
We should explain what this is before we start bashing it.
Ok.
So long story short, Apple, very cleverly realized
we have the world's largest distributed network
iphones
and so they can do things like find my iphone
and originally find my iphone, you know,
worked over Wi Fi and the internet and stuff.
So I can see, you know, I can see, oh, like I left my ipad.
Oh, funny story once I visited my sister and we accidentally swapped ipads.
So I guess the moral of the story is if you
have the exact same case on your ipad as someone else,
maybe make sure it's actually your ipad before you pack it in your bag.
-- Whatever, that's easier said than done. Nobody checks that
-- anyways.
But then Apple realized, you know, with, through some cryptographic pokey,
jiggery and magic,
we could have all these Bluetooth devices that we've deployed A K A iphones,
uh essentially report their Bluetooth ID securely and thus
vastly improve the effectiveness and the coverage of like
find my iphone. Well, also find my ipad, find my computer, whatever.
And they've even extended that now to those Apple
tags. I forget what they're called air
tags, air
-- tags. Thank you. Right. Because like I have tile tags.
-- Amazon owns tile now. Right.
Well, exactly.
And so, you know, Amazon is jealous of Apple
and they're,
well, Apple has
again,
like the world's largest network for coverage of
looking for Bluetooth items that have been lost.
And so Amazon wanted to do this and of course,
what's interesting to me is nobody seemed to really mind Apple doing this,
but I think Apple did it in a way that was,
you know, much lower bandwidth and much less intrusive.
Amazon, of course, did not do that.
Amazon is like, oh, it'll only use up to 500 megabytes per month of your data
on your internet. Which,
well, ok. Hang on. We,
I think we're missing an important piece of this is you, you dove into Apple.
But fundamentally what Amazon is doing is
they've created this program called Amazon Sidewalk,
which basically is going to turn
a bunch of Amazon devices like your echoes and your rings
and that's sort of thing
into a large mesh network. The intent of this I don't think is totally clear.
It's to support their iot devices and to support their lost stuff.
And, but the problem is,
and historically, Amazon has a lot of my purchasing data
and while they don't really share it externally,
they do use it to harass me to buy stuff.
I, I think there's some other pieces to this though.
Amazon is basically, people have these devices, they're opting you into this.
You have to opt out. There's no like, sort of opt in
because
it's like we've discovered with organ donors and blood donors that, you know,
you got to make people opt out otherwise only 3% will opt in.
Right. Well, and, and I love how
in the Apple Universe
they're basically blocking a bunch of information
to advertisers unless, unless you opt in and Facebook is having a conniption.
-- Yes,
-- it is the end of the western world as we know
it. It's absolutely hilarious.
I love it. It's so good.
But so anyway, anyway,
so Amazon has sidewalk and a bunch of people are kind of making a big deal about it.
I think your parallels drawn with Apple are very interesting and fair
because you're right,
Apple's doing very similar things and no one seems to care but Amazon
-- does it and everyone starts losing their mind
-- and Amazon has stated that,
you know, the data will only go to their Amazon services.
-- It's not like they're providing general internet access to these devices,
-- right?
And so my favorite part is if you look on the Amazon sidewalk,
they talk about how secure it is because it's encrypted.
And it's like the thing I keep thinking of is
I'm not worried about hackers stealing this in transit.
I'm worried about you having it
when it gets there.
And there was that tweet about that guy who, you know,
visited his mother and now he's getting ads for his mother's toothpaste brand.
And some people on hacker news pointed out, look, I mean,
if you think you have privacy, no, you know, geolocation of your phone,
it's tied to your credit card, it's tied to your accounts.
I mean,
I I remember the kind of data that choice point had on me 1015 years ago
and that's only vastly improved, right?
Data storage is effectively free at scale now like
to store a makeup by on every American
you can buy a single compute device for under $10,000 that will do that.
Right.
You know, we talked about this in the magic of Santa Claus or the,
the crime of Santa Claus or whatever that
the point is like
the amount of data and data correlation going on is amazing.
And I fully trust and expect Amazon
to try to use it to jam more ads and more junk down my throat.
I mean, there's recently the, the Amazon Prime controversy where
they're apparently inflating prices on prime
items because I'll probably buy it because, hey, prime shipping,
it will just arrive here quickly because
I needed a new copy of, uh, The Hungry Caterpillar. And
the one on Prime is like $10 more than the one on, you know, the, the chapters.
It's like our big Canadian white bookseller.
Yeah. But, and I, I was kind of looking at it and I'm like, 35 bucks. Seems
like a lot like, I don't remember this book costing more than about 20 bucks.
So I look at chapters and it's like, no, it's like 2025 bucks.
Free shipping.
Not as fast as prime, but
am I gonna pay $10 extra for prime shipping, basically?
Well, no, I'm, you know,
and so I, I fully anticipate like I like you.
I actually broke down and bought two apple TV. S to get rid of my fires sticks because
I am tired of the host style user experience in the firestick.
Yeah.
Did you get the, the new one with the nice remote.
I got the four K with the, I, I just went for the,
the one that was most expensive was like,
30 bucks more than the slightly cheaper one.
So, I was like,
whatever. Just buy the, the biggest one
-- times two
-- is your remote. Aluminum or black.
-- It's aluminum.
-- That's
-- the
-- good remote.
Yeah, it's,
it's quite nice. But again, you know, it's,
I'm ok with buying stuff. I do need to buy stuff. I'm a North American.
That's how we function.
But
at the same time I'm sort of getting tired of Amazon trying to
constantly just shove stuff down my throat and tricking me like that,
that prime, like the hungry Caterpillar does not cost 35 bucks.
-- It
-- does now.
I mean,
you know,
I, I didn't know that. That's interesting because I won't lie is I rarely
look past Amazon if I need something quick where it's just like I load up Amazon.
I buy what I need and whatever. I don't think twice about it.
But I'm going to maybe pay attention to some of this now because that's interesting.
And the thing is, again, yeah, I tend to,
when I'm shopping I tend to click that prime button because I don't want to
because, you know, again, the scam aspect of you order something and it's,
it ships in 6 to 8 months
like you with your laptop.
It's down to August 31st as the date now
that it's supposed to ship.
So we'll see it, it, every, every couple of weeks they decrease it a little bit.
So, anyway, anyway, we're talking about sidewalk here. So
I guess here is
the question I have in my brain that I don't have an
answer to because I don't know how I feel about this is
Google has created a massive surveillance network with devices.
Apple has created a massive surveillance network with devices. Amazon wants one
and now we're losing our minds. Why do we care?
Amazon is doing this when countless other companies have already done it,
-- I
-- think because historically Apple has not grossly abused
their position of trust and knowledge over consumers,
but Google has Google has, but,
ah,
-- people have given up, I think with Google
-- maybe.
Well, what's the alternative use?
-- Bing? So
-- actually I have been using duck duck go for
probably three or four months exclusively now for my searching.
And I will say that when I started using,
I would try it every now and then about maybe one or two years ago.
I, I would, every now and then I'd give it a go and be like, all right, it's, it's ok.
It's ok.
But now like, it's pretty good.
I would highly recommend duck duck go as a, as an acceptable replacement.
I do think Google is slightly better in certain instances,
but generally speaking for my usual searches, I am having
-- complete success with duck. Duck go
-- so
stupid question. But looking at this, how does duck duck go make money?
And it's advertising and affiliate marketing?
They do have some ads but they're, they claim a bunch of privacy.
Are they clearly marked? Unlike, say Google? Where?
-- Yes,
-- the duck duck go ads have a very nice little ad
in the corner. It
is, it is, it is where Google used to be and I have no doubt
they will travel the same road
but for the moment
I find them to be an acceptable alternative.
Oh, their ad button is just the same as Google.
It's not super, it's just a little tiny thing at the corner.
-- It's,
-- yeah, it's not like blaring the obvious but whatever. It's, it's good enough.
I can easily tell the difference.
Yeah, because like I'm at the point where like
usually the first page of Google results for
just skip. That stuff
is just.
But anyway, anyway.
Ok, so back to my question, why do we care that Amazon is doing this?
-- But we don't care that Apple and
-- Google,
I suspect part of it is because people actually own Amazon devices,
people own Google devices.
I mean, every freaking Google phone is just like, like it's a,
it's a fire hose of data straight to
Google about everything you've done in your life.
I don't know. It's a good question. Maybe because people here's the thing.
I have a direct relationship with Amazon in a way that I
do not with Google and I am actually a paying Google customer.
The majority of people do not have
a customer relationship with Google. They don't pay Google for services,
right.
They don't buy Google works suite or whatever the
-- hell it's called this
-- week to a degree.
And, and that's sort of a fair argument is I did pay Amazon
for
my fire TV. S and my echo dots and all of those things.
And now suddenly they're abusing that device.
-- Do
-- I truly own this device? If they can
quickly opt me into,
you know, it's one thing to,
to get automated software updates, but to get opted into a, you know,
this global surveillance network and it literally is,
it's meant to be a surveillance network to like find lost Bluetooth devices,
right. I'm not trying to be hyperbolic and crazy and paranoid, but
this is literally what this thing is supposed to be doing.
Right. Right.
Also, historically, Amazon's and Google, well,
Amazon's behavior historically has been incredibly abusive of their workers.
Well, not just that, look at how they are partnering with law enforcement,
with Ring and there, there, it's super sketchy what's going on there. I mean,
I feel like Google is stupid,
evil and Amazon is true evil in many of these discussions, you know what I mean?
Well,
I feel like Google still has a lot of
influence by engineers who will please don't be evil,
sort of try and do the right thing. But
let's be clear, Amazon is Amazon is Jeff Bezos.
That's it. Like, don't pretend otherwise.
No, I, I, that's true. And he's a ruthless gentleman, for sure.
He makes bond villains look grossly incompetent.
-- He's
-- got the look like Goldfinger
was, you know, ridiculous compared to him.
I mean, I don't know. I really wonder about this.
I do know I've made a decision now that I'm not going to be buying more Google products
and, and it's not because of the privacy issue even.
It's because none of them work with my Google account.
And people are like, what, what do you mean? They don't work with your Google app?
Well, I have a Google works Suite account.
So my nest stuff,
I can't do two of a with it because it's not supported with a paid Google account.
I pay for youtube premium because I bought
youtube premium hoping to get the family plan.
-- You can't do that with a paid Google account.
-- I know that's so ridiculous.
Same thing with my Google Home Wi Fi.
I have to use the Google home app now which lacks functionality,
including some big stuff. Like what is the speed to my devices?
Well, in the old app, it would test it and say like 27 megabits up,
three megabits down whatever, right?
In the new one, it says good, sometimes excellent.
And I'm like, what is that?
So,
so actually
I have a for, for anyone listening.
I also have some Google devices and I would very much like to get rid of them and I
was going to go ubiquity at one point and I feel like they're maybe kind of on the air.
I'm not so sure about this. And so
I don't know what to get if someone has suggestions,
like tweet them at me please or send me an email because I would absolutely
love to get some suggestions on like good solid home wi fi slash networking,
but also not like a fire hose of stealing my data to some terrible company.
-- Well,
-- or a fire hose of, oh, you know,
we added advertising to the interface and also we
took away these features and now they're paid and,
you know, it's
anyway.
Yeah,
I don't know because I do like the aspect
like the Google wifi does do some things well,
-- in that it ros packets and it just works, it
-- does just work, which is convenient.
And when I got mine just work was
-- we'll say a difficult proposition at the time, especially
-- with mesh networking.
Right. Right. So, ok.
So anyway, anyway,
here is where I'm going to interject a great deal of opinion into this conversation.
Here is my thought on this whole Amazon debacle
and everyone has their own pet opinions and things like that.
And I think what has happened is the world is starting
to, we'll say pay attention to privacy like it has never done before.
I think this is where Apple found itself in a convenient position and
it always amuses me that Apple appears to be this privacy champion.
And I think
my, the reality is Apple probably doesn't give two craps about privacy.
They just happen to find themselves in the right
place at the right time and they're like,
well, you know, hell yeah, like sign me up for this.
But the thing is, I think people are paying attention to this and I think
we,
to a certain degree, subconsciously recognize that
Facebook and Google are lost causes. They've gone too far.
-- There's nothing we can do. There's no turning back. I think
-- it's worse than that.
It's the bait and switch aspect of
apple doesn't
do a lot of bait and switch. But Google and Amazon
constantly do bait and switch well.
-- But,
-- but Google has bait and switched us to death.
I mean, that's all like my favorite is my kids.
Anytime Google releases a product they joke about when Google is going to kill it.
I think
we've reached this point where people are fed up
and we can now complain about something.
Now, not everyone will because I'm sure like there's,
my parents will never hear of what Amazon is doing with their echo dots.
You know, it's just that sort of thing.
But I think people are truly starting to pay attention and that, that gives me hope.
I think we have a long way to go.
But I think
this is less about Amazon and more about just I'm
effing tired of all of this. Please stop.
And I think that's a big part of it is
this bait and switch aspect from Google and Amazon.
And
it's now an understandable privacy problem of, oh, wait,
you're just gonna randomly opt me into my network to be part of your
-- global mothership surveillance thing of a jigger.
-- One positive aspect of this I saw
is for example, let's say you have internet in your house
and you have a camera on your garage, but your garage camera can't see
your house internet, but it can see the echo.in your kitchen or whatever.
You know what I mean?
-- So like there can be value in this mesh network.
-- Absolutely.
Like I had um originally with my previous wireless network,
my ring doorbell on the front door is sitting on a big chunk of metal channel,
which is very good at blocking Wi Fi from inside the house.
And so I actually had to put it a Wi Fi extender
in the garage like 10 ft away from the doorbell because just
otherwise it was just getting like one or two megabits per second.
And then I deployed Google mesh Wi Fi
and it's actually connected to the Wi Fi unit up on the upstairs bedroom,
which is kind of at a nice anyways, the angles work out basically, right
and the problem
though
it's on a chunk, like most
door frames have
like metal on the outside, you know, flashing or siding or whatever.
Because, well, yeah, that's what you do so that it doesn't rot and, oh, yeah.
No, it's, it's stuff like this.
I, it would be nice to, you know, if every echo in my house did proper mesh Wi Fi,
I could throw my Google stuff out basically.
Right.
Yeah. No, if Amazon's gonna opt me into, to being
part of, maybe it's because there's this clear benefit to them.
There's like a clear line of Amazon doesn't want to pay to deploy this.
So they're just opting me in. Maybe that's why people are so upset.
That could certainly be, I don't know. It's, it's interesting.
This is, I think one of those just aspects of human behavior that,
that no one will ever understand that we get upset about one thing and not another.
-- It's,
-- and it's just, it's not just one aspect of this, right?
For many people, like I know for myself,
there's sort of three or four things I'm annoyed about with respect to this
and I suspect there's probably a constellation of
20 or 30 reasons in total if you interviewed
1000 people.
But yeah, no, that's a good point why,
because Apple has opted us into a whole bunch of
this tracking stuff with not a lot of consent.
So, I mean, in all serious, this air tags.
That's how air tags literally work.
They, so one thing that's really interesting is there's,
I think it might have been the eff published a story about air tags where basically
the reporter, someone put an airtag and someone,
-- it was using it as a stalking tracker thing.
-- Right. Right. Right. Right.
And there's so what's wild is
like if I put an air tag in your bag, I can obviously track it.
Now if you have an Apple device,
your Apple device because this happens because my wife has an Airtag,
my phone will be like, hey,
there's an Airtag following you around
and I'm like, yes, it's fine.
Right? And I can't be like, yes, it's fine. Never like never show up again.
It says don't show up for a while and then like a week or two later.
-- And,
-- and that's one thing Apple got right on those things is they,
their engineers are trying to do the right thing because for example,
I own some tile devices and they, they do nothing like that.
Right. Right. And so, I mean, I totally get the whole stalker aspect of this because
like historically, a lot of these devices were
push the button, make a beep.
And if it's not near you,
you're sol there's value in having the ability to track things for long distances.
But obviously the whole like just
-- tracking and spying angle is disturbing.
-- I'm divorced.
My kids live in two households there was a case where my son lost,
he put his phone in a basket of his mother's house and it was quote unquote,
lost.
And I'm like, well, I know it's at your house,
like, I'm not trying to be difficult but it's at your house, like,
and, but the battery just died. So I can't make it ping otherwise I would make it ping
and they eventually found it under a, you know, a thing of wool, like it had
kind of slipped under something
ball of yarn or whatever,
you know. And so, but so there's, there is a lot of,
there are a lot of common use cases where people,
Children live in multiple households.
Uh, you know, I remember in the before time there was a lot of people who went to,
I forget how to pronounce it.
W
it was like these big buildings that, where people would congregate and,
and, and do stuff together
to get paid
and, you know, sometimes they forget their stuff there.
I think there's huge value in this.
But yeah, it's, it's, are we making it hard for stalkers to abuse?
Are we making it privacy friendly? And
in Apple's case, they seem to be trying. And in Amazon's case,
I don't trust them.
-- I mean,
-- I, I agree. I, I feel like
trust Apple slightly more. I mean, for now don't get me wrong.
It would not shock me if at some point
in the near future, Apple does a total 180
goes full Google.
But so far, Apple has gradually ratcheted up and improved privacy.
And Amazon and Google have sort of done the opposite, at
least perceptually.
Yeah.
But again, I think we kind of come back to the situation of
Apple sells me devices which I gladly keep purchasing
and Google and, and I think Amazon may be slightly less,
but I feel like they're heading in the
wrong direction of like you are Google's product,
right?
We are their cattle
and I think Amazon is starting to treat us in a similar way.
I went to buy some AAA batteries because I finally ran out of the AAA batteries.
I bought three years ago
and by default, Amazon had it set as a subscription, not a one time purchase.
Yeah, but
like once every three years,
are they going to send you a case of batteries every month?
Go to Amazon type in AAA batteries. Choose the Amazon brand.
-- If you need a battery subscription, you're doing something wrong.
-- And by default,
there's a gray box at the top that says one time purchase
and below it
selected by default is subscribe and say 5%
say 5% now and up to 15% on repeat deliveries cancel at any time.
So it's,
you know, it's and it's delivery every six months, which is perfect because I'll,
I'll absolutely forget about this in six months and then get
another package of batteries in the mail that I don't need.
So now when I shop at Amazon,
I have to be super careful to make sure I'm
only buying one of them and not a subscription.
Uh,
I don't, I don't need to worry about this crap.
I don't,
and that's why I'm just like, oh man, Amazon. Not cool, man.
I need to find somewhere to order things on the internet easily.
I tried. There's, there's Amazon, that's it.
But Costco will only, you know,
sell me certain things in historically large amounts.
I love it, which is good though,
you know, for certain things. But yeah,
I, so and this is a perfect example, right?
This, this kind of constant bait and switch and trying to trick,
I feel like Amazon and Google are trying to constantly trick
me into clicking an ad or buying something I don't need.
Yeah, I'll agree anyway. It's frustrating.
Here's my ending thought on this and this is
something I've been thinking about a generous amount lately.
So
there when, when you and I were Children,
do you remember all the reduced reuse,
recycle messaging that we had like just shoveled into our brains where it was like,
oh everyone needs to do their part.
And then we've recently discovered that something like 80% of
pollution is coming from like 15 companies on the planet.
-- And it's like, wait a minute what
-- I have a problem with that because like it's,
I need to buy a lot of that stuff that they make.
-- Well. Well,
-- but here's the point. Right. Ok.
Here's the point is there's been this historic trend
of
kind of almost victim blaming for
a
large number of the world's problems and I think even things like privacy
were part of that
where it was. Oh, don't click links. Don't do this on the internet. Don't type.
And it's like you just, it doesn't work that way. Like you can't,
you can't defend yourself against these adversaries.
They're too big and they're too powerful. And I think,
I mean, to a degree, this is what we're kind of seeing with Amazon is, yeah,
you can opt out a sidewalk but most people won't and
they're clearly taking an adversarial stamps from the perspective of the users.
And so I think in the context of privacy on the internet and just in general, right?
Not even with Amazon or without or whatever is the only
way we're going to solve a lot of these problems is when
the governments of the world start to care about these problems because as a human,
there's just nothing you can do. There's no way to stop Google from spying on you.
There just isn't, even if you don't use the internet,
they're spying on you. Right. There's like there is no way,
let's say about 10% of people who are Google and Amazon users to stop,
which would be a massive ridiculous amount of success. Right.
It's just not possible. It, it, I
guess it would show up on their end of year spreadsheets, but that's about
-- it.
-- They siphon this data from everything.
I mean, it, it's coming from purchases you make in meet space,
it's coming from purchases you make online, it's coming from websites you visit.
It's just
we exist in this massive surveillance universe.
And so I'm hopeful that more and more people pay
attention and we see a push in the right direction because
I think
for a long time
there was, I don't know if I'd even say it was apathy.
It's just,
I don't think people understood and I think we're starting to figure it out.
It reminds me of like the Edward Snowden revelations where everybody's like, oh,
he's paranoid crackpot and now here we are 5, 10 years later and we're like, oh,
oh my goodness,
never forget that.
Where for a long time, all the security people were like, yeah,
the NSA is totally doing this and like, oh, you're all just paranoid nuts.
I worked for a company full of ex-military people and I, you know, was just talking,
I'm like, oh, yeah, it's too bad.
We can't do something like echelon and just monitor
all the RC networks and the guy's like,
you can't say that on the phone.
I'm like, say what on the phone? Like,
he's like, you can't say that word and I'm like, which word Irc like, no, like, come
on, he's like, yeah, don't say that on the phone. I'm like, God, I mean,
yeah.
And, but I remember telling people about stuff like echelon, they're like,
you're just a nut then.
I'm like, oh, ha ha, not a nut. And they're like, shut up nerd. We still don't care.
Well, the NSA using Danish telecoms to spy on the German Chancellor and
Merkel, like,
yeah, that,
I mean, and that's, this is just new stuff in the last week.
I, I know, I know it's,
I guess the thing
I will hopefully fill us all with some hope is that
I think a lot of this went unchecked for a long time
and I think we have a very long way to go.
I think this is the beginning of the beginning,
you know, to steal the Churchill quote.
But I think
I feel it feels like
we're starting to at least look in the right direction
here versus before where I feel like no one knew
-- like
-- awareness is step one because
for the longest time, you know,
the NSA and all this warrantless surveillance and
FISA courts and everything was going on just
behind closed doors literally.
And same thing with these companies like Choicepoint and Experian and
Transunion and all these places that have massive amounts of data on
everyone. Like not most of us, literally, everyone
and we were blissfully unaware and well, now we're aware.
So that's step you know, it's to quote, uh, what is it, Dan Aykroyd, you know, you,
now you've discovered the source of the smell.
What are you gonna do about it?
You know, from?
Well, I don't know the answer to that yet, but we'll see.
All right, I'm going to end it.
I guess if anyone has suggestions or insights or any details that could be useful,
let us know.
And if this is a topic
you're working on, let us know we'd love to talk to you. But thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. Go to open source security, podcast.com.
Head to Pando.
It says podcast hashtag do hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the.