Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
-- Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh
-- Bresser.
So, what's new,
-- ah,
-- spring was here? And then it went away.
As you can see from that chart, I showed you earlier freeze thaw days and I,
oh
my goodness. I, I
don't even know what to say. It's so bad. It's so comically bad.
We'll put, we'll put a link to the chart.
Kurt tweeted about in the show notes,
but like it's indescribably bad is all I can say.
Yeah.
And, and I think it's actually, well,
it actually ties in with what we want to talk about today,
which is the container scanning and, and the train wreck.
That is most container scanning reports.
Oh, I thought you meant indescribably bad.
But
-- also
-- that
I think you can describe how bad it is by
words.
All right. So yes, we transition nicely out of our before the topic banter.
And so basically, by the time this podcast is published,
I will have released a seven part blog series
on
security scanners
and
I work
well. No, not just containers specifically.
I mean, containers are an aspect of this.
But I I cover kind of the gamut of scanning from. I talk about code scanning.
I talk about
I call it composition scanning,
but that's kind of what a container scanner would would be by most definitions.
And I also talk about application scanning which is
code scanning and application scanning have been around for a while.
Composition scanning is something kind of
and I think it's more interesting and I think
it has the potential to not completely suck.
The other two kind of suck.
But uh I apologize in advance if any of you listening,
work for any of the scanning companies.
I don't, I don't dislike you all. I, I don't like some of you though.
Uh So anyway, anyway, the reason I did this is
in my day job, I am getting these security scan reports from customers
that run them
often
uh across who knows what, sometimes they're using, you know,
containers that might be years old,
sometimes they're running versions of an application that are very old,
sometimes it's very new and
I get a report and usually I get something like please fix this by Friday. It's like
no. And so
the reason I started writing these blog posts is
because there's a huge knowledge gap in terms of what
these scanners are actually doing and what we as
kind of humans need to be doing about them.
And of course the vendors are
in some cases, peddling snake oil
and in some cases, like they have good intentions,
but they're still not quite doing what we actually need.
And so I figured it is time to start an education campaign because
grown weary of explaining this over and over and over every single day of the week.
Well,
my other thought would be also what are these scanners actually capable of now,
you know, both in terms of technology, but also in terms,
a lot of people forget about the data feeds that these scanners consume and need
are, you know, because that was actually the first part of my career was working at
defense and isight or sorry, isight partners.
And then I defense, you know, where we produced that kind of data and speaking from,
you know, over a decade's experience and also as the CV guy that
-- a very excruciatingly nontrivial task,
-- it is very difficult.
And I mean, this is a topic
in the series. You haven't read it yet because I haven't published them all yet.
I'm going to stagger them every couple days just because I don't
want to like dump them all on the planet all at once.
But basically, this is, this is a problem.
And one of the things I talk about is the
fact that if your scanner vendor isn't a CV ECNA,
a CD E numbering authority, if they can't assign C vs, like what are they doing?
And I've seen some are any of them?
Yeah, Well, Snick is, I'm trying to think,
I think Aqua might be also now those two for sure.
And I feel like there might be some more. But
what I see from a lot of these, I think white sources too, actually,
now that I think of it, but white source also,
I know assigns their own I DS and I run into white source, I DS on a regular basis.
White source is not AC N A unless they have a different name.
OK, then maybe they're not, I'm running off memory here.
-- So by all means, yeah,
-- Nike is,
but it's also S NKE, for example, is only AC N A for stuff they discover,
which is
a start
we'll say,
oh yeah. No.
Well, and part of that too is, is a, is a consequence of how the CN A system is set up,
right?
That the ideally you want people to kind of cover their own stuff as it
were not be like some jerk like Kurt who covers like all of open source.
Right. Right. So, so anyway, these scanners, some will just assign their own I DS.
And when, when the security finding will call
doesn't have a CD E ID. It is generally of dubious quality.
And like, for example, I,
I know there's a handful of white source ID
si found that are actually duplicates of one another.
And so I'm trying to report it to them. I have no idea how to do it.
I I if someone listening has a contact or works for white source
and you know how I can like officially report dupes in your,
your scanning feed.
Like please let me know I'm not your customer but I parse a lot of your reports.
That's annoying to me. But that's, that's a thing. I also
see there, there are some scanners using, we'll say private databases,
we call them where they are not open to the public
and the quality of the data coming from them is hot.
Garbage is the nice way I will describe them.
Well, the thing I always ran into is, you know, the numbers sell, right?
People want a phone book of vulnerabilities,
not like a thinly properly curated list.
Yeah, except your phone book is full of garbage. Like
because like how many people keep saying, you know, oh, this part
because more CV S than this product. Therefore, it's more bad.
It's like, oh wow, that's
that
happen. But you're not right. But yeah, if you have a private database,
-- it probably sucks that that's what I'm going to say
-- there.
Well, I just also love because then,
then they share this report with you and it's kind of like, well, cool, what is this?
And they're like, it's in this private database and it's like,
I don't have access to it,
you know, what makes it even worse is I'll get findings from a scanner that says, oh,
this, this finding has this idea.
I'm like, I don't know what that means. And then I go back to the customer
and I say, unless you give me
something I can look at to identify what this even is like, I can't help you.
And then occasionally they will come back with the information I
need and then I look them up and I'm like,
this is terrible.
Like these findings are beyond terrible.
And I just II I tell the customers, I'm like, look, these findings are, are trash,
like they're not security issues.
I don't know what to tell you. Right?
If your scanners reporting them, your scanners broke, that's the answer.
Well, and I think that's a big part of the problem, right?
Is, is the scanners technology itself can be
or decent
or whatever, somewhere in between,
-- but it doesn't matter if the data feed is
-- crap and, and yes, I mean, that's really,
that's very, very true because like I,
I'll kind of give you an example of what I see is there are
scanners that do a very nice job of identifying what is in the application,
right?
There's still the questionable aspect of,
am I actually using the feature in the dependency in the application?
But that's a harder problem and I will, I won't give them a pass,
but I'll say I understand.
But then there's also vendors that have scanners that like they'll just detect,
you're running a patchy http D somewhere they have no
knowledge of version numbers and they just be like,
here's every http D vulnerability for the last 20
years and it's like this is beyond useless.
-- Can't parse this
-- list. Yeah. No, I think alarm fatigue is a real thing. Like
the other problem too is how do you separate the wheat from the chaff? Right.
Like, if I give you here's 10 vulnerabilities.
I found that that's actually a human addressable number of vulnerabilities.
But if I give you something with 1000
and I mean, I've seen scan reports that were clearly
not good because I remember this one came in
and it was, it was big with an Excel file
and it listed all these things about like how
our product didn't safely store credit card numbers.
And I went to the product team. I'm like sweet.
Like our product now takes credit cards and people can buy updates and
stuff because I don't remember that being mentioned as a feature anytime soon,
although it's really cool
and they're like, yeah, no, we don't. This product doesn't let you buy stuff.
And I'm like, that's what I thought. OK, never mind then.
And they literally just cut and paste like an Ecommerce template report and
I guess left the original findings or something.
My suspicion is that's an application scanner.
I see that a lot where someone will run
a scanner
for like I, I won't, I won't pick on a specific vendor.
But like you have your, your website running,
essentially you point a scanner at it and it, it scans it.
And one of the issues I see is it will, for example,
let's say if they put like my favorite example
is in and this happens in Cabana actually,
which is something
plastic builds is if you put a slash at the end of any URL,
it gives you an error message in
JSON because basically, once you put a slash on the end,
it's trying to do some api magic on the back end and whatever,
it's just how it's built.
And the scanner interprets that as you allow directory listings.
And so it literally will have like 300 findings that
all say you allow directory listings on these end points.
It's like, oh my goodness, no, like look at the freaking output.
You worthless piece of trash.
-- We don't.
-- Well, see.
And that's I think where we get into one of the core problems of scanners is
they are actually incentivized to generate false positives. Right? It looks good.
Right. Actually, I,
I had this come up,
I was talking to a company that does like third party security
audits and they were saying last time we reviewed your product,
we didn't find a lot of stuff.
I'm like, that's good. I don't, you know, that means we're doing it well. Right.
I don't want a phone book of findings from you people. That means we suck.
You know, I want
a
findings and it's this kind of the same deal with
these scanners where if you send me a phone book,
it's more likely your scanner sucks.
It's not that I'm doing a bad job.
You know, this all reminds me of is house inspections. Right.
Every time I've, like, been involved in buying a house, you know,
you get the house inspector for like, cost 2,
300 bucks and every time they come at you with like some, you know, half inch,
two inch thick printout with like,
you know, it's like thermal scans to show where the heat's leaking out.
And in every case they've
missed like major, easily found deficiencies that I, you know, like,
I remember in the last house I lived there were gas
lines that were not capped off like they were turned off
because there had been like a gas dryer and a gas stove which had been removed,
obviously because, you know, they're crazy,
dangerous and expensive and they never put a cap on the gas line.
Right. Costs like a buck. I love my gas stove.
So, but, you know, these are things that are easily found and of course,
it makes me doubt the whole competency and the whole, just the process
because every single time it's just been like,
like, what was the value in this again?
It. Right. Right. And I mean, home inspections are, I hate them.
-- Well,
-- they'll find like gross deficiencies.
But, like, usually it's kind of like stuff you would have noticed, like, oh,
look at this two inch crack in the foundation.
Right.
I've had, but, I mean, I know people that had inspections done and like,
a year later they realize that the
inspector missed something substantial about the house.
-- Like, it totally happens.
-- Oh, I think that's the rule. Not the exception.
Yeah.
Yeah. I mean,
I,
I, uh, I, I'll never forget the first time I bought a house,
I was handed the inspection report and it was of
course enormous and I went through it and I'm like,
yeah, I don't care about any of this stuff.
And the, and the realtor was like,
what do you mean you're not going to have them fixed?
And I'm like, I don't care, this is all stupid. It doesn't matter.
And then I'll never forget I went to sell that house and they got an inspection of it.
Like you have to fix all these things in a week.
And I remember I just went back with like, I'm not fixing any of this.
You're not buying my house anymore. And then they're like, oh, wait, wait, wait. Ok.
Ok, we, we won't make you fix everything.
I'm like, I'm literally fixing none of this stuff, right? If you're not the house,
buy it, like none of this matters.
They were like, ok, fine. But it's like, yeah, like this is a crap report.
-- I'm not, I'm not accepting this.
-- So OK.
So scanners, container, scanners and all these applications.
So because there's several different kinds of
scanning that is actually going on here,
right?
Like there's the sort of I'm going to call it the underlying operating system.
And that can mean like an actual bare metal
virtual machine slash all the stuff we chuck into a container nowadays, right?
And I guess even to a point you would see that in serverless, even
serverless, right? You have underlying operating system
bits somewhere to some degree, right?
Whether or not they're exposed, who knows?
Well, there's the blob of the application and whatever it pulls in.
So the dependencies basically and that's
you were mentioning the composition scanning.
Well, composition scanning is kind of what's in it.
So you've got, I split it up into three pieces.
There's code scanning which is like static code analysis, right?
And that's been around for a long time like scanning CN C++ and Java work. OK? But
once you get into things like javascript and Python, it's, it's not good at all.
And even scanning C and C++ are not great,
but we say they're not completely terrible,
which is the highest praise I can give for,
for scanners. And and then you've got composition scanning,
which is where you scan the like everything, right?
That's where you're scanning the operating system in the container,
you're scanning the application you put in, you're scanning like everything
in the thing. OK.
Be it dependencies, be it the code you wrote whatever.
And then you've got what I call application scanning.
And that's like what we just talked about where,
you know, you might have a scanner that scans your website and then it reports,
I've never seen an application scanner report anything resembling good findings.
The only thing I've ever seen is where they
catch some really obviously out of date server.
But usually that finding is buried in with, you know, 3000 other things.
-- I
-- mean, maybe, but like
I'm not in an environment where we're running anything out of date in that regard.
So the findings I'm seeing are, are bad.
Now at the same time, I will say composition scanning
is, I think
it has a future
and it actually it's going to be useful is what I say.
I don't think I would describe it as it
is useful today necessarily because it has value.
But people don't understand what it does
is the challenge. And so
I'll, I'll give you the example of what I I'm seeing. So people will run a scanner
and I mean, pick one. I don't, I don't care which one
they run it on a container
that has a product that obviously they're expected
to deploy in their environment in some way.
And then it's going to report on all of
the findings from the operating system because obviously,
if you're running a container, your container is built on top of something, right?
And for example, in the case of what I'm dealing with, it's just
generally
sent os which is basically Red Hat Enterprise. Linux is kind of the foundation here.
-- I
-- forget how they redid the upstream. But yeah, basically
fundamentally, let's just say that
right? Because it, it makes it easier.
I'm sure there's Red Hat people screaming at their podcast player right now. But
I, I love you all keep, keep up the good work.
And then there's the thing you put on top of the container base image, right?
And this is basically, you know, like the value add of, of the organ
where obviously, in our case,
we have the elastic stack and we put pieces
of it into a container and it gets configured
and then it gets sent to the container registries
and then people take those and they scan them.
So you've got,
you scan the operating system and obviously scanning operating systems.
We basically understand today where you can say here's a CV E ID
and the operating system vendor did or didn't fix it.
Most. I, I think we
agree that most vendors now have rational
and same package management systems with updates.
-- Yeah,
-- it's, it's pretty good.
But the one thing the container scanners are starting to do
that
was the big secret of open source that you and I have
known for years and it's not well known outside of kind of
the operating systems is there are more security issues than
a distribution can fix in a reasonable amount of time.
And so every, every open source,
every Linux distribution has to pick and choose and
say we're going to fix these security issues,
we're not going to fix these security issues.
Well, also a lot of these issues don't
really matter that much.
I mean, yeah, they can be chained together to do something maybe a bit naughtier.
But like so many of them,
like I remember my first sort of one of the major vulnerabilities I found was the,
what was it?
The I
cuzzy.com file was world readable and it had like
your user name and password or whatever for your
I
Izzy configuration, right?
Izzy was this like network attached file storage thing?
We were talking like 20 some years ago, the vendor of it lipped out
borderline legal threats, flip their stuff and I literally was
puzzled. I was like an 18 or 19 year old and I'm like, just chow in the file or see
it
like it's,
well, no ch model because it's world readable, right?
Just it still works like I tested it, it still works with the, you know,
other minus re I was, I was mystified as to why they were so hostile.
But then I realized because, you know,
for them to fix this little thing properly was going to be, you know,
probably the equivalent of several man years of effort in total.
Right, to ship an update just to do a chow of a file. Right.
It was, it was a very large vendor that's, you know, if I name them,
everybody would be like, oh, yeah, then they, they,
they are known to take a while and have rather
-- slow updates.
-- That's all the vendors.
Well, some more so than others, although 20 years ago,
that was all the vendors actually.
Yes, the reality is with a lot of open source projects, fixing some of these flaws is,
is quite, you know, labor intensive
and quite frankly, a lot of them, you know,
they'll just get it on the next update of the operating system or whatever, right?
So they, they're kind of like whatever, we'll fix this 3 to 6 months.
If you, if you really care, go fix it,
I would view it as return on investment
where fixing important issues is very important,
obviously, right, where you want
like heart bleeds to be fixed quickly,
but you don't care so much about a trivial issue that let's say is only
exploitable under certain circumstances that also probably has
a workaround that if you really care,
you can, you know, change file permissions or, or delete execute or whatever.
And so kind of the
the big secret
is that there are probably hundreds or thousands of unfixed,
crappy security issues in every Linux distribution on the planet.
And some of these scanners are starting to find them and in fact,
I just got one the other day where I get a report at 600 CV ES, I'm like,
there's no way this is real, right?
Like, tell me what you did, you screwed something up.
The guy's like, no, no, this one's real. I'm like, I don't know.
And I, I, so I started looking at it, every one of them was valid.
Like, well, let me explain to you why this happened
and they were like, oh, ok, that's fine because, I mean,
most of the people when I talked to them are very reasonable.
Every now and then you get someone that's like, no, you have to fix them all.
I'm like, well, you can tell me that but not going to happen.
It's weird to me that we have this, I, like,
there's so many people in software that want the software to be perfectly fixed.
Every bug, every hole squashed. And it's like,
but we don't, that's not how the world works.
-- Like every road I've ever driven on is not perfect.
-- Right. Right. Exactly.
-- And that's
-- ok. And,
well, not only that, I mean, look,
we all have finite resources if you expect a product to have a completely clean scan,
that either means all I'm doing is fixing scan results.
So I'm not making the product better or I've done something to trick the scanner,
which is even worse because people do that though.
See that where people will do something just to shut up the scanner,
not because it's better.
And one of the examples I use actually is in one of the posts talking about.
Do you remember when Debbie and screwed up their open SSL?
And it, and produced predictable random numbers?
The reason that happened is because someone wanted to shut up a compiler warning.
And so they basically mailed the open SSL list saying, hey, I want to do this.
So the compiler stops complaining and basically no one replied to like, oh,
it must be fine then.
And they did, it's like, whoops, that was wrong.
Yeah. Yeah. It just went based on process ideas, the seed for the randomness.
And so you had a grand total of 64 K keys,
-- right?
-- I remember dealing with that issue
-- but,
-- but, and, and I call these maybe positives where if you don't know,
doing nothing is better than screwing something up, right?
Like,
don't do something just to shut up your
scanner because that's worse than nothing unquestionably.
-- Well,
-- I mean, by definition, if you knew what was going on,
you probably would have fixed it by now.
So, you know, a scanner is triggering this thing.
And if it's like if it was a really serious important thing,
-- somebody other than the scanner would have already, you,
-- you'd think, I mean,
and that's a lot of it too.
So anyway, we've got the operating system problem and there's lots of cvs,
but here's the deal, right.
If you look at, we'll pick on Red Hat or
Tu or D
or so
or any of these, they have stellar security teams that are on top of all of this.
And so in all seriousness,
if you're running a version of any of the major
Linux distributions that's basically updated within a couple of days
or even weeks. In many cases,
you're in good shape.
Well, I would say that's true of almost any operating system at this point.
Like even Microsoft Apple, they generally crank out security updates.
But then you run into the situation where literally,
I've seen people running things still on Windows XP or even Windows 95 or 98 because,
you know, embedded hardware,
but that's a different problem from this and that's ok.
Well, it's a different problem from this until, you know,
somebody's running a containerized piece of software that they don't ever update.
Actually, I wonder,
I'm going to see about scanning something comically
old because I bet that would be funny.
But
not today anyway. Anyway.
So we'll move up a level and now we have the thing
I added to the container and this is where the scanners also.
And now the quality starts to vary greatly
because once you're dealing with the operating system,
there's usually like package manifests and things like that.
Right.
So the,
the scanners do a great job of understanding what's there
and the versions they screw up back parts a lot.
But that's another story. Now,
once you get to my application, things start to get hairy because for example,
you may or may not be including code,
you copy and paste it out of something inside of your application.
Some of the scanners find that some of them don't.
I might be including dependencies.
I downloaded random files from off the internet.
Some of the scanners will find that some of them won't.
So for example, are they finding copies?
Because the one thing I remember when I started was uh
a
lot of Windows or a lot of open source software
embeds copies of uh there's this one XML dot C
file and this one G zip dot C file they
include so that it compiles cleanly on windows without whatever.
And so you're talking about instances where people have cut
and paste that code actually into their application sometimes.
I mean,
it will you stack overflow man.
You know what this reminds me now that we actually had a discussion on
the CV board about signing a CV E to like essentially a textbook example.
I think it was SQL injection or something because
example is so egregiously terrible and,
and really widely used.
-- Yeah.
-- Yeah, I mean, it happens all the time.
And so these vary now if you're using something like the N PM package manager,
they do a pretty good job when you're using something like
that because there is kind of well defined dependency lists.
It can understand what the manifests are that got downloaded,
-- ignoring
-- that those ecosystems have up to,
they have people updating the code and taking care of it.
Yeah. Well. Right. Right. They do.
But now at the same time,
nearly every application will run into if I update this library,
everything breaks.
So it's easier for me to just say, screw it, pin it on an old version for now.
I'll update it later and then we never update it. And so,
no, because that would break things. Yeah, that's pretty common now.
That is a place though that these scanners have
a lot of power actually because they can say,
oh, you're running this, you know,
six month old version of this library and now it has a CV E ID,
you should really think about fixing it
and like that's cool. Right.
Because now I know I need to go look at this and I need to do something about it.
Unfortunately, one of the problems you get is if you've never run one of these before
and you have an application that's a couple of years old,
-- you're going to get a lot of findings
-- when
you write a piece of software that has dependencies,
you immediately start diverging from the rest of reality because, you know,
especially if it's something big with, say a couple 100 or
a couple 1000 dependencies. Right.
-- Yeah, one of them is going to get updated tomorrow.
-- Right.
And, and working beats, I guess, more secure or updated or whatever every time.
Right. So pinning my dependencies solves a real problem.
So I get that right. I'm not going, I'm not going to tell anyone don't do that.
I understand how it works. Like you need to eat. You need a product that works well.
And see my take on this with my web Dev team is like, I try to,
I encourage them to stay as up to date
as possible because we're going to eventually face breakage
and I'd rather them face breakage one at a time than like 20 at a time because ok,
now we have all these pinned things.
It's
been six months, let's update everything and of course,
-- everything breaks. Right, because there's like six months of changes.
-- Right.
Right. And I, I think that's where
the development culture is going to end up in the
near future is on a very fast update schedule,
but like none of us are there yet and some of us never will be.
And that's ok. It's, it is what it is.
Well, I'm not sure I want my pacemaker doing that.
-- To be honest, no
-- medical meds
is different. We're not talking about that today.
So
here's
-- my car.
-- Yeah, whatever, whatever, too hard, stop changing the subject.
So now here's where things get even crazier.
So I run a scan and it gives me back a phone book of results
and I go in and look and say, OK, like for example,
-- this library
-- story to intro for a second.
Has any of these reports ever had a confidence score attached to the finding?
I don't think I've ever seen that.
I don't think I've seen them either.
I just realized like not a single one,
some of them will have severity and by severity, I mean,
they like go scrape the CV SS scoring, the severity are terrible,
which is useless because again, yeah,
there's things where we don't use that or we use it differently in this product or,
or we use it in a way that's actually even more dangerous.
But I've never seen anything with a confidence score.
They just assume everything is correct.
I think they assume everything's correct, which is, which is a problem.
And,
and actually here's where the confidence score would be really interesting is so,
so I've got my phone book of results.
I'm going to look at them and say, OK, so this application, let's say,
uh parses XML and adds integers, which is a ridiculous example,
but let's just go with it and I'm only using it to parse XML.
But the security issue is only in the part that adds integers.
So obviously, from my perspective, that's a false positive.
Should I fix it someday?
Yes,
but I'm going to go fix a thing that's actually like
the critical cross site scripting flaw now because that matters.
Whereas this integer problem
-- doesn't matter. Right.
-- Or go out a new feature that customers are demanding. Yes.
Exactly. Right.
People,
it drives me nuts that somehow people pretend like security is
just like this effort that just exists all on its own.
It's like, no, I mean, if, if you told a vendor, like,
you can spend a million bucks on security or 10 million bucks on security,
but if you spend the
$1 million security now you got like $9 million for features.
Well,
as a customer even do I want 10 million on security and
zero features or do I want $9 million worth of features?
-- Well, I kind of want features
-- mean it's going to depend, right?
If this is an airplane like,
yeah,
-- but I mean, in general, I'm going to want more features.
-- Yeah, seriously.
And actually this is something that I talk about in the post is the fact that like
why are you doing this if just running a
scanner is the reason you're running a scanner,
that's a terrible reason you need to be
running these with some reasonable outcome in mind.
That isn't I have a scanner to have a scanner?
Well, I mean, so many of these regulations now require scanning
and you know, again, the road to hell is paved with good intentions,
but now here we are with, I have to have a scanner.
So you, you know, you get a scanner, you run it and
the other thing is some of these regulations say once you're
aware of a vulnerability or a fly you have like,
what is it, like 30 or 90 days or whatever to fix it?
Tik Tok?
You know, and, and that's when these companies get real grumpy. And,
yeah, do that irrational. Like here's a phone book of scan results.
I need this to come back clean and it's like, well, sorry, computer says no.
-- And
-- well, what makes it even more fun is they might say, well, I'm on this old version.
It's like, well, you need to upgrade, but I'm on an old version, like, well,
you need to upgrade.
I'm on an old version. It's like this is, I think Evan and Costello did this, you
know,
and, and it's hard though, right? I get it and you're absolutely right.
There's definitely some of that aspect to it. But in all serious
this,
I think this is a great example of
the regulation needs to accommodate reality because today,
reality and regulation are kind of butting heads
in an incompatible way and that happens sometimes,
right?
Where something new comes out, there's some new feature,
there's some new way of work and now we have to deal with it.
Like open source is a great example,
regulated industry couldn't even run open source for a long time because there was
no way to deal with like the supply chain questions or the vendor questions.
And now they can, it'll come. Right. It's going to come. It's going to get,
I,
I have no doubt so. Anyway. Anyway. All right.
Well, we'll kind of keep telling the story.
So we've got our false positives,
we'll say of things that either aren't there in some cases or things I'm not using.
And I'm, I, I believe
100% that if I'm not using a feature and it
gets reported on a scan that is a false positive.
-- And obviously the scanner vendors will argue with me.
-- I would agree.
But the problem is that's a gnarly problem to solve because is there even a way for
vendor to rationally notify other
like the scanner vendors of this
-- sort of?
-- And like, so here's my point though is the reason I call it a false positive.
And the reason I'm pushing back on every scanner vendor I talk to about this
is because if we accept those results and say this is the way it is,
we've created an incentive again for the scanner
vendors to just report lots of stuff.
Whereas if I say I want you to tell me which of these findings,
I'm actually using the code.
That is the CV.
Now we're talking about a very useful feature and if
we don't push back on them saying I want this,
they're never going to do it because it's a really, really hard problem.
Well, you know,
I remember because I had this exact issue with Jackson data bind where we weren't
using the serialization stuff.
And so the problem though is, is, is there number one,
I'm not even aware of all the scanner vendors.
So even if I was willing to spend time reaching
out to them via phone and email or whatever,
I I are there 10 or 100 or 1000 scanner vendors globally that matter.
I,
I I've dealt with more than 10 we'll say.
And so, I mean, like what I do now is when people send me a scan,
I say I need this in a machine readable format.
Be it like XML or
JSON, preferably
JSON or whatever.
And then I scrape out all the I DS and then I have
a tool I run that basically says I've seen all these before.
I have statements explaining why we're not vulnerable or I've seen, you know,
I've seen these, I haven't seen this and I'll be like, oh,
we're vulnerable to this one.
Let's actually go fix it, you know, something like that. But like that sucks.
And it's not sustainable in the long term.
I'm wondering because you remember when we talked with the, the S
bomb, you know, software bill of materials guy and all that,
Alan.
Yeah, they, I don't remember but I,
I don't think it came up the whole idea of you have a bill,
not just a bill of materials but a bill of materials and how we're using them.
We don't have that today.
Honestly,
I don't think anyone thought about it before now because why would we care?
Well,
-- you
-- didn't
-- have these giant dependencies with 6 million features that you use?
-- Three of
-- right. And, and honestly, I don't think anyone who
cared before now.
And like obviously the the story the scanner vendors will tell you is, oh,
just as long as you run our scanner and you keep updating fast enough,
this will never be a problem.
So you don't have to worry about it.
But the reality is no one's ever going to get there.
You're always going to be behind some amount
and you're always going to have to prioritize work and you know,
updating dependencies is work.
And not only that it's work that no one cares about because no one really sees.
So you need to be able to prioritize,
well, you rarely benefit from it other than to make
things like scanner,
like reports and
maybe some bugs go away. It's, you know, a
lot of it. Yeah, that's most of it. And I'm not going to lie to you.
Like there's been many internal discussions where we're
quite frank about the fact that the only
reason we're investigating this particular thing we're working
on is to shut up the scanners.
We realize there's literally zero other value than making the scanners go away.
I view that as a scanner bug.
-- Yeah,
-- I remember doing that where I was at a point where I was like,
if we fix this one XS, we'll have a bunch of customers stop complains in
which actually will probably be cheaper in the long run.
Cause support costs of those poor support.
People listening to these customers complain about this one CV.
-- Jackson
-- data bind is exactly that for me right now where the
Jackson data bind vulnerabilities are reported as critical by scanner vendors.
And in all seriousness, if you're using those features at Jackson data bind,
it actually is.
-- I'm actually
-- just looking at the CV list for it.
-- I didn't realize there was a new crop of them last year and
-- this year, last year,
correct.
It's constant.
Like every week there's a new one it seems like and it's,
the feature is basically just fun
broken on every level and,
and like what's funny is they basically just keep removing the vulnerable de
serialization methods from the list of OK, things to do.
And it's like you guys are, you're not gonna have anything left eventually.
Just why don't you just blacklist everything like
problem solved.
But anyway, anyway, people obviously freak out because their scanners say,
oh my goodness, you have like 10 critical issues in this,
this container and they're like, oh my goodness, you have to fix this.
Like right now right now we need you on the phone right now and it's like, OK,
let me explain to you what's going on
and
the thing is most people get it where you say we're not using these features.
And if they say we prove it, I say I can prove it.
Here's the line of code where we like literally don't enable that feature.
And then most people are like, OK, fine. I'll, I want you to fix it.
Like yes, we want to fix it too,
but we actually don't upgrade Jackson data bind
right now because there's some serious performance regressions.
And obviously when you have a very performance search engine,
-- that's a pretty big deal,
-- right?
Well, and that's a great example of, I mean, that's a real cost,
right? Like electricity, people's time,
you know,
oh, we need 10% more servers because we had a 10% service degradation.
That's I mean, if you're my vendor and you're like, well,
we went through this with Intel, right where they're like, oh, here's the fix for,
what was the first or second one
where the performance was like atrociously terrible.
Yeah, I don't, I don't
remember the name of it
and
attacks.
-- And
-- I remember looking at that performance metric changes and I'm like, we,
we can't ship that.
There's not enough spare server capacity in the world
to make up for what this performance degradation will do.
No, I I know. But yeah, anyway,
you get, it's a complicated and difficult problem and we're,
we're basically out of time for today and I know we
could talk about this for hours and hours and hours.
I will spare you all. I've got
a,
so a funny thing to my, my blog series is seven parts.
It started out as one and it got out of hand and I, I capped it at seven.
I could have gone more, but I decided this is already ridiculous,
but I will put links to it in the show notes, like go read it.
I value comments from everyone if you're a scanner vendor, like by all means,
get in touch.
I love talking about this stuff.
I'm going to, I'm going to hold you to a high standard though.
Like as a warning, I'm not going to let you like steamroll me into agreeing that.
Oh, I guess it's good enough.
Like, no, I have very,
very high expectations and I'm going to expect you to live up to them.
Well, for what this stuff costs it should I, from what I've seen,
it should be doing a better job.
It's very expensive
and I know it's a hard job. I get it. It's a hard job, but
-- that's why people are paying you money.
-- Well, and
it's going to get better. Right. It's going to get better.
-- Well, some of them are going to get better. Well,
-- ok. Yes.
But, but the whole point and the big thing,
the big takeaway I have in this is that if we do nothing,
we aren't going to see these scanners get better in a way we want them to get better.
They're going to get better in the way the market incentivizes them to get better,
which is going to be bigger scanner ports, more noise,
-- super
-- annoying and it just becomes useless.
Yes. Exactly. Exactly. That.
So it is up to us to hold these vendors accountable and make it better.
So, all right, I'm ending it there. That is where we are so awesome. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you
for listening. You can go to open social
security podcast.com, hit up the show notes and you can use the Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag You hit us up on social media and Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.