Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 161 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
-- What's
-- new man?
-- Uh
-- Not much, not much just uh enjoying my kids being back in school.
It's beautiful, isn't
it? It's so nice.
No, I know I have the same joy.
Right?
So 161 take two, we, we had technical difficulties yesterday.
So we shall try again.
-- So anyway,
-- well, technically we were fine. It was the cloud that
the cloud who can trust it, right?
Well, you see this is one of the things I love and hate about the cloud is
effectively, I'm outsourcing something to the cloud,
which means on the one hand, I don't have to care about that thing.
Like it just hopefully works in the cloud.
But conversely like when you outsource something, if it doesn't work,
it doesn't work and there's like nothing you can do
to fix it other than like stare at it and
you know, try reconnecting or whatever
and,
and to be fair if you choose good cloud providers like Gmail is a great example.
Like Gmail goes out so rarely that it
literally makes international news when they have like,
you know,
0.003% of all Gmail users were affected for 17 minutes on like last Thursday.
Now in fairness, 0.00 17% of all Gmail users is like
a million people.
You know,
like the last time when the admin console
went down and I noticed immediately and then,
like, nobody could log in.
So I'm like,
well,
-- I guess we just take a 30 minute coffee break.
-- Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. I mean, it,
although I guess I,
I feel this as a human
because I remember when things would break, you had something to do,
I'm going to fix it. I'm busy. Leave me alone, I'm fixing the internet, it's broken
and now
I
will just sit here and do nothing.
You know, it really reminds me of is the exact same parallel between
people who feel safe driving in a car
and those same people feel unsafe riding in an airplane
because that perception of control. Right.
Even though the car is statistically way insanely more dangerous than getting in a,
like commercial plane.
You know, there's that perception of control.
I'm driving a car, I'm in control of the car. You know, where was on an airplane?
It's like you're strapped in your seat,
shut up or we're going to have the air marshal tase you.
-- Right.
-- Right. Exactly. Exactly.
And in fact, I'm a person who did not care for flying for a very long time.
And, like I knew in my brain it was statistically safer, like,
driving to the airport was
1000 times more.
Bathroom at the airport is more dangerous.
Right. Seriously.
But, like, I did not like being on an airplane and now,
granted I've flown so many times, I just don't care anymore.
But,
I mean, I remember that and it's,
it's the same thing with security. Right.
Where people think, oh, if I run, I run the server myself, it's more secure.
Or if I generate the, the, you know, private keys, it's more secure.
And the reality is,
you know what? It probably isn't.
Well, and especially, I hate to use Best of Breed,
but we are getting to a point where we have Best
of Breed solutions where let's put it bluntly hands up who here
has Intel build custom silicon into their CPU for that,
you know, the answers. Almost nobody. And, uh, this is a podcast.
-- You can't see them raising their hands.
-- Exactly, because it doesn't matter.
Um, ok.
Number two,
who here is building their own custom silicon
security code processors to put in their server.
Apple,
Apple, Microsoft and Google.
-- Maybe Amazon,
-- you
know.
But, yeah, you're definitely,
you're in the top 10 companies on the planet if you can do that.
Yeah, I'm pretty sure that's outside my budget. It,
skill set.
Well, not even skill set.
Like I couldn't even hire those people because
they're all busy working at those other places.
Right. Yes. That's exactly right.
-- I, I don't know any chip people who need jobs.
-- Yeah.
Yeah.
It's like every time I see, like,
why do logistics companies charge so much money for X?
And then it's like, but no, seriously, how do you ship an elephant,
like overnight one to Germany like that? That's complicated.
It, it amuses me to no end when people think
something is super easy and, and it's very like Dunning Kruger, right? Where it's,
oh, but if you only did this, it would be super simple.
And like my favorite example right now is
when people talk about running like a modern
internet architecture for a company where it's like,
oh, you just need a couple of servers.
It's like holy cow. That's not how anything works anymore.
And just a quick phone call to Comcast.
Yeah.
No, no, you're not. I remember we just did an episode of a hotel
doing those things. So the answer to that is absolutely not
it. And it, right anyway,
I mean, this is just
in security is the same way, right? Where it's always, oh, but if you just do this or,
well,
there was that really interesting thread on Twitter
where the GRC was talking about how,
you know,
he believes Android phones are more secure than Apple phones and that
he has some sort of bespoke android phones that he's locked down
completely.
And I'm inclined to believe him because he's a, he's generally a
competent individual. Yeah, competent and smart.
But, um, well, a couple of problems, one,
how do we know that he's done it correctly? Like, what has he done? Right.
I, I didn't go bother looking for documentation, like,
you know, like, for example, the, um, oh, what is it?
The, the desa stig, you know, the secure technical implementation guidelines
with them,
you know, they, they have those for like Firefox web servers phones.
And, and honestly, like when I read the one for Mac O West, many years ago,
it was I learned a lot because I was like, wait, there's a guest count by default
that's enabled by default.
I did not know that prior to reading that because it,
it doesn't show up in the login screen.
Like when you go to the user account,
it's there and you're like guest account. What's this?
Um So obviously, you know, disable that things like that.
And so these decent sts are pretty good and,
and I assume that's kind of what the GRC is doing.
Like he's,
I assume he's not doing custom software firmware
-- or like a custom version of Android
-- O
it might be custom actually because I've been watching
some of his comments about this and I,
I haven't found any concrete details,
but it sounds like it is not connected to Google's
servers and he has his own like custom app store.
Couldn't you just firewall that, like,
have like a little firewall app in there that blocks access to Google servers.
I mean, well, you could, or if you build your own version of Android,
it doesn't come with the Google Play anything installed.
In fact, I've,
I've done more Android modding than I ever want to remember some years back.
And
when you build your own version of Android, like,
none of the Google Play stuff is in it.
You actually have to side
note it all to make it work.
But anyways, like, even, even if you get one of those phones, I, you know,
does it just does everything work or do you have to
jump through all these hoops to get stuff to work?
You know, like I had the same experience with the, um, I bought some Android.
Um, what do you call them fire tablets?
Uh, quite lovely.
But, you know, they don't have the Google App store and I wanted, uh, oh, yeah,
it was Minecraft, right?
Because like kids love Minecraft
and like I got the Google App store loaded, side loaded, whatever and it
got Minecraft onto it.
And then like two weeks later, it just broke horribly and it, like,
wanted the App Store to update and I just couldn't.
So I gave up and luckily at that point, Minecraft was available in the Amazon store.
So problem solved.
But, um, you know, I'm a pretty technical user and even for me, I was like, I gave up.
It's not easy. I did it once. I, so some years back it's been, it's been a while.
I bought uh, one of the, the cheapest
fire tablet because Amazon makes them and I
just needed it to literally read books on.
And
I thought I'll try this instead of
the Kindle, the, the
thing. Right.
And, and yeah, I tried sideloading the Google play stuff and it was, it was terrible.
Like it was unbelievably bad.
What gets me, I mean, back to the cloud.
This is the whole thing of, I don't want to be an expert in all things.
-- That's right.
-- Right. And more to the point, I don't have the time for it. Like, like
I,
I can, I can do
DKIM, I can do SPF I can set all that up but man
maintaining all the DKIM keys and making
sure they're
actually signing because I had it set up on one server
and then it just stopped signing the email for some reason.
-- I still don't understand
-- why
email is one of those things that I think is notorious for people saying, oh,
it's super easy to run your own email server and like
it's super easy to run
a email server.
-- It's super hard to actually manage an email infrastructure
-- and
to get everybody talking to your server and vice versa.
You know, like I had problems where we were running email servers. We still do
and because we don't send enough email,
there's a couple of spam appliances that are like, you might be spamming,
you might not be spamming.
We haven't seen enough email from you to tell one way or the other.
And I'm like, right,
I,
I literally at one point considered telling marketing
to send more email and I'm like,
that might not be the answer.
Um
But right, like I'm like, how do I solve that problem? I can't.
Well, I remember the the spam is what ended me.
I ran my own email server for decades and,
and I just, I couldn't, I got sick of fighting spam and I was like, you win spam.
I'm switching to gmail and that was the end of that. And like,
do I wish I had more control over everything? I'm doing well? Sure.
But I also like having free time
because I
spam is a full time job.
-- Yeah.
-- So I,
yeah, on the one hand, I really hate this centralization, you know,
and I hate this like, I, I will never like,
I'm terrified that one day I do something weird
and Google boots me out of their system.
Oh,
I know, man. I know actually. So it's funny you say that is.
So to give you an idea how paranoid I am.
My Android phone backs my pictures up to Google and I back them up to Amazon
because I figure getting kicked off both services at the same time is probably,
I, I won't say it's out of the question but I think the odds are low.
Don't, don't, don't say that
famous
last words.
Yeah.
So, and, but, but, and I get it though because especially,
you know,
there's a lot of industries and
government that have regulations about maintaining,
not perceived control,
but actually maintaining control of their data and their stuff.
And
you're asking them to like, oh yeah, trust this like company in the US to just do it.
So
there's a couple
and not to pick on the US.
-- But like all the major cloud providers mostly are out of the
-- US.
No, no, they are. Absolutely. And
so, I mean, so my argument with this is
I'll pick on the,
the department of Defense because there's actually a ton of news right now.
There's this big cloud project they're doing
called Jedi because they love their fancy acronyms
and basically it,
it sounds like it's coming down to kind of Amazon and Microsoft as the two possible.
Right.
Anyway,
like
-- it's not gonna be
-- just run it on Facebook. It'll be fine. Everyone,
let everyone friend each other.
But the thing is when you look at an organization like that,
they literally have basically like thousands of little data centers everywhere,
right?
And there's tons of duplication of effort and there's,
you're constantly, I mean, you know, people coming and going constantly, I mean,
in some cases people are like,
you know, they're, they're going out into the field and they may never come back
just, you know, it's like, it's crazy to think about. And so
in some instances,
they require a certain amount of control,
but they also struggle to have it because
of just all the disparity in their environment.
So, I don't know, I can kind of see it both ways.
I think you can make an argument
in either direction to be perfectly honest.
Well, I think what will happen is like any industry, it will mature to the point where
the vast majority of people
just by grid power.
And if they absolutely need,
you know, backups to make sure, you know, like,
because there's a lot of machinery and stuff out there that if you kill power to it,
it basically eats itself or something terrible happens, you know,
so you really want it on battery backup or generator or whatever.
Well, look at hospitals,
hospitals.
Yeah.
And so yeah, there's a legit need for, you know, handling that half hour hour outage.
But by and large,
everybody just buys grid power unless you're like
so far out in the middle of nowhere that
they're, you know, they're just not going to run a wire to you.
Conversely, even the solutions for that use case have become much
like, uh did you read uh what was it? I think it was Zimbabwe
is deploying Tesla power walls to a lot of their cellphone infrastructure.
I
did not hear these power walls are about 6500 bucks a pop.
There's two per cell phone base station.
It's going to about a third of their base stations across the whole country
because the Zimbabwean Minister of, I think it was tech or economics.
Anyways, basically, he's like,
yeah, we need mobile because that's our economy.
That's how everybody pays each other.
And that makes sense.
So if it breaks we, it, like, you just turned our economy off and that's a problem.
And so what I love though is like in past,
imagine 20 years ago I go, Josh, I, I have a, I have a project for you. I need you
to get uninterruptable power supplies that will run for about, you know,
10 or 12 hours
at a bunch of cell phone based stations with me so far and you're like, sure,
whatever.
And then I'm like, but they're in Zimbabwe.
Right. And at that point you probably quit and go home.
Right.
The logistics of handling that and the technology to do that would, would have been,
yeah, like just, it would have been and, and the cost would have been a ridiculous.
So, and, and now it's just like, yeah, we need a couple of 1000 power walls,
drag them in, on trucks, not even big trucks
and, and you're done,
you know,
and, and I see that's where cloud is headed.
You know, there's so many of these cloud services where
you know, the outages are becoming rarer.
And also, uh, like,
one thing I really like about cloud flare
is their outages are always kind of interesting.
You know, they're never like, sort of a silly, silly thing. They're actually
something kind of interesting.
And where, what's, what I really love though is,
is cloud flare seems to be one of those
providers that does all like a really solid post mortem
and well, hopefully like the airline industry then fixes it.
So it never happens again and ideally fixes
it so that other things never happen again.
You know, those near misses
or, you know, because basically every failure is not just a failure,
it's a chain of failures, right?
That resulted in something horrible.
Um, pretty much in any industrial or it setting. Right.
It's almost never just one
thing
definitely, you know,
um,
like Google their control plane pooped out and then
they couldn't talk to each other and they're like,
well, how do we resolve this issue when we can't talk to each other?
You know, things like that,
same thing with cloud flare.
And so
that's the thing, you know, if, if this industry matures like
air travel has, I mean,
cool.
That's what we want, right.
This boring service that you buy that just works.
And then when they have an outage it's so rare. It makes
-- news
-- and
I, I think that has to be the future of security also
because today's security is like a snowflake in a lot of organizations and
even products
and it should just be like the boring thing. That's always there.
It's like, if, if, if you rent,
I, I don't know, let's say you're renting space like an office somewhere, right.
Are you going to worry about all the locks on the doors?
Are you going to put your own locks on the door? You know, generally speaking. No,
with, with some people. Yeah. Sure. But most people, nah, they don't really care.
It's not even that they don't care.
They don't even know that it's a thing you need to make.
We do well, and they don't have to care. Right?
Because it's just, you,
you assume if I'm renting office space in a building that like the front
door isn't flapping open all night long and they have some reasonable controls,
keeping my stuff relatively safe.
Yeah. No, a great example, Firefox just did a version,
uh that enables a whole bunch of privacy stuff by default.
And then they're actually apparently going to be deploying
that those defaults to existing versions of the browser
they need. I mean,
I,
I'm always torn over this because I, I mean, I run Firefox. I love Firefox and
they,
I'm, I'm,
I think they could do more. I think they're doing ok.
And one of the challenges though I see is
if they try to set themselves up as the Anti
Google, which I think they kind of are,
that's a weird place to be in. Right.
Don't they get a lot of their funding from?
Yes, they do.
Awkward.
Well, and unfortunately if you look at Firefox usage it's,
it's been declining now for, for a long time.
And
I, I feel like just being the anti
Google isn't enough.
Well, I mean, yeah.
Yeah.
No, you have to,
you have to offer something better and more like what got
me initially with Chrome was just the performance and stability.
Holy cow.
I, I mean, I remember when Chrome came out, like I was,
I was fairly involved in helping Firefox or security stuff back then
and like Chrome was doing some amazing things where they were,
you know, they were spawning lots of processes and they were doing
all different
kind of
magic rendering things inside of there.
And, and I mean, this was back when like your browser crashed like five times a day.
That's what browser did.
I would run like multiple instances of Firefox separately
effectively to get one process per tab.
And I mean, now they all kind of do this, Firefox does it as well and they do,
they do great, right?
It's I I run Firefox uh for days at a time
and I have no issues with it.
And in fact,
I think Firefox has been more stable lately
than Chrome was when I was running Chrome,
which is, which is awesome.
I love that. But yeah, I, I feel like you need, you need more anti
Google isn't enough yet
yet. Give it time.
Anyway,
all you need to tell me you've been claiming there's a topic of open source ads
and you won't tell me what it is though.
-- And this is driving me insane and you must tell me.
-- OK,
-- so the deal was there is N PM
-- node package manager.
-- Yeah,
-- it's for managing javascript libraries.
All the website people are using it.
This developer maintains this package called Standard.
Literally, that's the name of the package.
He does this for free, which is nice of him.
But like a lot of people doing stuff for free, they also need to have money to buy food
and internet.
Yeah.
So he did an advertising thing in
the standard library
that advertised like on the terminal when you were like using it and installing it.
And he got uh two who was it?
He got two companies to buy advertising space on it and they
obviously backed it when this whole thing went south real fast.
Um
But yeah, you know, it's like because,
you know, we, we,
we ended up with uh advertising on what was it use net with the
cantor and Segel green card thing way back in the day and then email
and then, you know, advertising on the web. And,
but you know, we've never really had advertising on your text based terminal.
Thank goodness.
And, and to be clear. I don't want advertising on my text based terminal either.
Uh, no, I detest ads
also that there's a good reason this podcast doesn't have ads.
But if you have enough money, we're open to sponsorship.
-- To be clear,
-- it would have to be a huge bag of money and we won't put ads on our podcast.
You'll just have to give it to us. So,
you're still open to that though.
But,
yeah,
but anyway, so yeah, I mean, he put ads in the terminal and
how did I miss?
I generally keep up on this
kind
of
like,
well, anyway,
so anyways N PM has come out and banned ads.
So what's interesting is like because talking about software freedoms, right?
The open source software freedoms thing.
Like shouldn't the author of a package have the freedom to put ads into his thing.
-- But conversely N PM doesn't have to distribute
-- you.
Right. That, that's fair.
So I think this is a reasonable trade off. But more to the point,
I just, I,
I question how effective or useful these ads would be and what really gets me is just
the amount of time and effort they're going to waste
and people either trying to turn them off or like,
what's this weird junk in my file in my log files
or whatever? You know, because like I run this one,
I use this one package called gam. It's a Google account manager or something.
It's a really nice set of uh apps to connect to your Google account and like, run,
like export all your Google groups and who's in them and what the settings are.
Right? Really handy.
And it does this one thing that I love and drives me nuts is
when you run it, it checks if it's up to date and if it's not up to date,
it updates itself and then it runs the command you told it to which I love, right?
Once in a while, it means I get a really slow run.
But the problem is I pipe all the output into files so I can record this.
And so every once in a while my parsing breaks because at the top of it is like this,
you know,
G
A version 5.46 detected is old, you know, installing 547, blah, blah, blah.
It's like, it's like about 78 lines of text.
And so now what I do is I just run G A manually
and then I run my reports,
you know, so I don't if it has to updated updates and,
but I'm ok with that because the trade off is I get an up to date version of G.
That's right. That's a benefit to me. That's a major benefit to me.
And I could totally get my script to ignore those front lines. I just whatever.
But um but like advertising, generally speaking,
advertising is not a benefit to me.
I'm like the, literally the number of ads I've seen where I'm like, oh, wow.
I'm, I'm really glad I found out about that.
I think the number of times that's happened in my life is about three times in total.
So, especially when you start, like, it's one thing for me to have to spend
the cognitive load of like, oh, that's an ad I can ignore it
versus now I have to like,
I'm going through my log files or whatever and like the
stuff is getting mangled and chewed up because there's like an,
there's an ad stuck in there with the URL that I, I just, I feel like the,
the benefit to the cost is just the, the that equation is out of whack and no one and
more to the point you're,
you're assaulting for that one last place where tech people don't have to see ads.
And yeah, I'm, I'm guessing they're going to defend it staunchly.
Oh, man. I, I feel like there's so much wrong with this.
Now,
I will also say there's the aspect of people who
write open source are underappreciated and often aren't paid.
And there's many arguments in many different directions here.
I mean, you could argue that, well, that's just the way it works, you know, and, and,
and, and it is, and, and that's part of it.
And of course,
this is also one of those situations where this guy's
library would never be popular if it was close.
I mean, that's just the reality of it.
The slippery slope, I guess I keep thinking of is so,
if you go and you put ads in your library in some way
and it generates you revenue, uh, I bet you can make a lot more money
-- if somebody paid you to put a back door in your library.
-- Crypto mining.
Right. Right. Exactly. Exactly. That, I mean, in fact, what was it?
The Pirate Bay was doing that at one point where you'd go
to their website and they would start mining crypto in your browser.
That's one of the new protections.
The latest version of Firefox has is protections against crypto mining, which,
yeah, it's uh 2019 folks.
That's the thing now,
like it's common enough that Firefox is actually fixing it by default
and, and you know what else I will say about Firefox?
Here's the other thing kind of on this ad.
I, I guess complaining session here is
like on my Android phone,
Google Chrome, you, you cannot make it block ads.
Whereas Firefox on, on your Android phone, you can install an ad blocker.
And I think like
that's a place where being kind of the anti
Google is a huge plus because you can say, look,
you can block ads because ads are terrible.
It's not even that ads are terrible. I found on mobile. I can't,
I can read the news on the CBC, the
broadcast corporation because it's, we don't really have ads on that site.
But I go to, when I go to American news sites, I, I can't read the content.
Some of them are terrible.
And in fact, I was, I was trying to use chrome and for some reason,
chrome on my phone opened some link and I was
like looking through the site and at one point like a
video literally appeared in the middle of the screen and I
could not figure out how to make it go away.
I assume I had to just watch it all.
And that's when I just copied the link
and pasted it into Firefox and everything was great
and just odd.
It's like we are living in an ad dystopia and it's infecting open source now.
Well, it's, it's
ads, I mean, they've, they've essentially done as much as they can on TV,
on radio in the physical world.
You know, uh,
it's one thing I want to visit Hawaii.
-- You know, one of the reasons I want to visit Hawaii, they outlawed
-- billboards.
Right.
Long time ago,
-- I
-- think
-- Vermont did
-- too.
I would like to know what does the world actually look like
without billboards because I've never experienced
that outside of a national park.
Right. Right. And you're not wrong,
you know.
No, II, I know, I feel like it is ridiculous and I would love to get rid of it,
-- but I don't know
-- how I'm, you know what,
I'm super hopeful for augmented reality glasses.
A
black
straight up, just put the mono lease over everything or hell anything.
Literally,
I want to see pictures of dogs
when,
-- when there's an ad
-- just like go through Reddit slash R slash R
and, you know, and
I use that to fill the ad space.
Yeah. Right. Right. I would love that.
It is. I don't know.
I feel like it's frustrating and it's, it's one of those things where
I, I, you know,
so much research has been done where
all these ad networks keep distributing malware
on the systems.
And, I mean, I don't know how these ads worked in the standard library.
But imagine if you're like, if you install a library and it ends up,
like downloading arbitrary garbage
from some ad network,
like that's probably really bad.
Yeah.
Well, I, yeah, I know, it really calls the trustworthiness of it into question.
And also like, does your build fail because the ad network doesn't serve you an ad?
It would be.
-- Oh, my goodness.
-- The future is now, man,
I just, the thought of that makes me
just,
yeah. Yeah. I want to go brush my teeth. Yeah. No, it's just, and it's so,
like I said, I just can't imagine that the advertising made
anywhere near enough money to justify this.
I have no idea.
It, it probably not because, I mean, I know most of these ads,
people are selling and going through our paltry where it's like a couple of bucks.
-- It's never, it's never a lot of money.
-- Oh, yeah.
I mean,
when I ran Google ads on my personal website back in the day
when I actually had a lot of traffic and it paid quite well.
I mean, I was at most making one or $200 a month.
Yeah. I, I believe that.
I think you need, like, literally hundreds of millions of views
on a consistent basis to actually pull in any revenue.
And, and these days I know, like, for example, in, in like the podcast world
where what happens is you get like a, you know, a magic link or something or, you know,
enter this code
and, and these advertisers are obviously they,
they're analyzing that data heavily to understand, you know,
what's paying off and what's not,
what a lot of them are doing is linking, you know, like we, we will pay you for each sale
five bucks
or
whatever,
you
know.
Yeah.
And
the ads I hate ads, I hate them so much.
So, I don't know. And, and, but I do worry about this encroaching
of advertising into,
you know, like max headroom, you know, blip
Verts, it's like, well,
if we slow down their heads stop exploding so we
just push up right to that line and we're good.
Yeah. Right. What's Max headroom?
That's got to be like 30 plus years at this
point.
Oh,
-- Lord. Wow. Now, I feel
-- old
and actually it's funny because they had to dress up a real person to look like a
computer generated like avatar because they actually didn't
have the technology to make a computer generated avatar
at the time.
That's like, I, I love when, when people talk about like, the fake mood landings.
And I remember I watched a youtube video of this, like, uh, uh,
video producer one time there was basically like, look,
the technology didn't exist to do this in the sixties.
Like, let's break it down.
And it's like, even if they wanted to fake it, they couldn't have just because
you couldn't,
you couldn't do those things in a studio no matter how much money you had.
Ok. So anyway, we should, we should wrap this one up.
So I guess, and an open source, I feel sad for learning about this.
I feel sad that the guy felt he had no other options.
That's, that's a story for another day. And I agree with that.
I mean, there's organizations starting to look into some of this.
Like Tide Lift is one, for example, where they're trying to pay
some open source contributors. But I mean, even then
I, I'm suspicious
that anyone's going to feed their family
on just open source in, in that way.
It's II I think, I, I don't know, I feel like there's something has to change here.
I, I'm not sure because,
well, long story short, there are a lot of people who do get paid to do this,
just maybe not
100% of their day job or it's a, it's a big enough chunk of their day job that they,
they do make a living doing this.
But it, I, I always come back to sort of the whole art thing and oh, we need copyright.
So artists will make art. No, we don't need copyright.
So artists will make art because people will make
art no matter what because there's people out there who
have to make art otherwise they get like all
twitchy and weird and they go and they make art
now ideally should people who create something of value
that so many people use and also get value from
and that like in some cases literally underpins a lot of the world.
Should we maybe make sure they can feed themselves well. Yeah.
Yeah, that should be sustainable, you know, back to the old red hat thing, you know,
is this sustainable
it?
Well, it better be because like we need G lip C, whether we like it or not, we need,
you know, Firefox, whether we like it or not.
I, I think that's, that's a fine place to end it. So thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. You go to open social security podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes,
you can use the Pound Os S podcast hashtag to hit us up
-- on social media and Kurt have a fantastic rest of your
-- day.
You too, thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.