Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast
episode 146 with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime,
Josh Bresser.
What's new Kurt? Well,
-- uh
-- I don't know how to say this but
Microsoft may not be the baddies anymore.
-- I would not call them
-- compared to where they were 20 years ago,
even 10 years ago,
maybe.
But I would agree.
I think from the context of open source, Microsoft is no longer the enemy,
which is weird to say.
-- And
-- so at a very high level, before we get into details,
there's all these people talking about these various topics with the classic.
What is it? Embrace extend and extinguish.
But I'll be blunt, like the amount of money they spent on github.
If they were to extinguish that
the problem is people would just move somewhere else.
They would. And I don't think they have any intention of extinguishing
github. It is a phenomenal resource. And in fact, if you look at the github
top contributors list that they publish once a year
and they just published it maybe a month ago.
Microsoft is number one by a generous lead
Yeah. Well, the other thing is too, people forget Microsoft also owns linkedin.
So between linkedin and
if they can get those two things working together, that's pretty phenomenal.
-- They know everything about us.
-- Yes.
So,
yeah. So, ok. Well, where do you even start? Ok.
Well, let's start with the really, obviously,
uh,
they're shipping a Linux kernel
in Windows, like, not shipping the Linux kernel that everybody does that, you know,
if you do IOT stuff but no, like in Windows,
right? Boom.
Yeah,
exactly. Exactly.
Yeah. Like I remember when the Halloween memos came out and like
-- 20 years from now, I would know that. What?
-- No.
So actually,
you know what this reminded me of and I looked it up this morning and it
was Linus Torvalds has a quote that says
when Microsoft start shipping apps on Linux,
I know I've won
like this is so far past that line of win. It's just
holy crap.
And what I was thinking about is is, it's, it's pretty clear
that Microsoft has been working towards this for a long time, obviously.
Um But even more so that because like when you like, for example,
Microsoft shipped SQL server
on Linux, like several years ago,
I have a t-shirt from them. Actually, it's quite nice
-- and
-- also.net
on Linux some years ago.
And, and what somebody pointed out to me is if you have to port something.
First of all, if you write it for a platform you're probably screwed.
If you write it for two platforms,
you're probably like 80% of the way there of having it run everywhere.
And so by, you know, by having the, like, what's interesting is,
I
mean, to me it makes sense, because.net and SQL Server, those two go hand in hand.
Like that's how companies build apps, like
big boring apps that nobody ever sees, you know, that run in the back end.
And so by having
it kind of reminds me of um I think it was it Comcast or Verizon,
they wanted to deploy I PV six
and they picked their billing system to deploy
I PV six because it touches everything.
And that's also true of, you know, SQL server, and.net, right?
The SQL server and.net are so big and complex that if you can get those ported,
then number one, you've got them ported, which is cool.
But number two, you're going to gain so much
knowledge
about,
oh, you know, like when you do interrupts in windows this way,
you got to do them in Linux this other way,
except in this corner case because then everything tips over and like
dies or whatever, right?
I'm assuming they have some massive internal knowledge base.
Now of like here's how you make things work on Linux without like blowing up, right?
Because the other thing to remember is these, these aren't like bad ports
like these aren't like, oh, it's ported. It kind of works.
These are like, full functioning legit.
No, because there's gonna be support stuff and it's like,
like some of those console ports of games where it's like, yeah, the game will run
for like, 12 seconds.
Uh, even actually the Linux port of most games are atrociously bad where, I mean,
I've, I've had Linux ports, I've purchased
that.
Like,
they only start 20% of the time and the rest of the time it just explodes and crash.
It's sad.
-- Yeah. So,
-- ok. So I think they, and, and they've also done some other just cool stuff.
Like they've got a new windows terminal
and it's not that
I want,
I want to back up for one moment before we get to the
terminal and just say we were discussing the Linux kernel being in windows and
there's something really,
I guess unique about this that struck me when I learned
about it is so Microsoft has had what they call it.
The, the Linux subsystem for windows, I think
windows subsystem
for Linux
-- WSL.
-- Oh,
ok. Whatever.
That's fair.
But basically they've been able to run
certain Linux binaries kind of natively on windows for, I bet it's been, what,
three or four years, at least, maybe more.
And it worked well enough, but it wasn't quite right.
And I tried running a bunch of stuff like containers that work.
For example, there was a lot of when you try to run Java,
often you end up tripping over some weird CIS call
that wasn't implemented or you'd get back strange results.
That didn't make sense.
And, I mean,
it was obvious they had a significant investment into supporting
Linux applications on Windows by all this effort they did.
But I found it,
I guess, intriguing
that rather than kind of continue down the path they were on,
somebody must have just stood up and been, like, screw it.
Let's just take the kernel and do that.
And the advantage though is now everything works.
Yeah.
Well, it's actually a bit more subtle than that.
Somebody was pointing out on hacker news that when Satya Nadella came out,
uh, and took over Microsoft, that one of the things he did is he folded the,
the Windows team into,
uh, like another team. Like, basically there's no more like, how do I put it?
Windows isn't really a first class citizen at Microsoft anymore.
Azure is
and, you know, the cloud stuff is and the programming languages are,
but let's face it. The operating system. Who cares?
Like I, yeah, you need one to run stuff, you know.
But in the same way that, like my,
my car engine has a bunch of parts that I don't know or care about.
I really don't, you know, I had to get a new alternator a few months ago.
And quite frankly, it's like,
you know, oh, I need a new alternator. Great. Ok. Replace it.
I didn't even ask what brand name it was. I don't care.
It, it alternates and makes electricity. Right. That's all you need.
And that's kind of where operating systems we call that a commodity.
Yeah. And that's kind of where operating systems are. It's like,
well, no, we wrote an accounting application. It needs to work reliably.
I don't care that it runs on.
So, or Linux or Windows,
I just need a platform that it will run reliably on for the next 10 years.
No, if, if anything runs on Sko, don't, don't run that, that's, that's a bad choice.
And more to the point that
that underlying platform now is more likely going
to be something like Azure and not,
you know, a PC sitting in a closet, collecting dust somewhere in a small business or,
or a data center.
That's a larger company.
Absolutely. And, and I think this has been,
it's been obvious for a while that the operating system
is kind of becoming a commodity and in most cases,
it's Linux
and I have a strong suspicion,
Microsoft has known this forever and they know that at least by doing this,
they can maintain some level of relevance for
Windows that they potentially because let's face it,
man.
I bet five years ago, maybe even seven or to 10,
it was looking like windows wasn't in good shape for a long future, right?
Where it was just, it was becoming stodgy
windows vista
-- and 787 was Ok. Eight was a train wreck.
-- Eight was awful.
It was awful.
10 was better but
-- still.
-- Right.
And I remember there were a lot of people for a long time that were basically saying,
you know, Windows is done.
There's no future here anymore.
And I don't feel like I'm hearing that.
Like I was, in fact, if anything, I think I'm hearing Mac Os might be done.
But that's another story.
Yeah.
What, what's interesting to me is Microsoft is basically,
I think saying Windows is done
but not done.
Like it's dead but done in the sense of it just, it's commodity, it doesn't matter.
It's like your electricity.
-- Yes. Right.
-- Who cares? As long as it makes things go and work.
That's right.
Turn on switch light, turns on everyone's happy.
Yeah.
So,
yeah. No. And I mean,
I think what will also happen is apparently.net will now
be able to build apps natively for and the list was quite long.
This isn't complete but it was I OS, it was Android,
it was Mac Os, it was Windows, it was Linux and a
couple other things.
So basically everything
really.
And so if I can actually build an app
with one tool chain, one code base
and support
everything, that's pretty amazing.
It's like the promise of Java.
Yeah.
That's exactly it. Yeah.
Yeah. And, and as far as the embrace, extend extinct or embrace
it, embrace, extend, extinguish,
you embrace. Yes. Extend. Yes. But extinguish doesn't work anymore.
And I think Microsoft gets that there's more money to be made in
selling these tool chains and stuff than trying to kill off Linux. Because
the other thing I'm thinking of,
we know how much effort went into the Linux kernel just to make simple and by s well,
not simple but like file IO you know, network io device drivers, all that stuff work.
And Microsoft has to do all that work as well in house.
Right.
That's a huge cost, billions of dollars over years.
And if they can actually make the switch to
a Linux kernel natively with running windows on top,
which
there's no technical reason they can't,
I would be shocked if that happens. Windows and Linux do some
things in very different ways on a very low level that could,
I'm not saying it's impossible, but I have a suspicion the,
it is easier for them to make a Linux kernel run on
windows than it would be to kind of turn windows into Linux.
Right.
Well, and the other problem is, I mean,
they are aware of all the technical debt they have with
windows and the technical debt with Linux is something that's,
you know, that's a whole different ballpark and a whole different,
I mean, it's, it's pretty massive, but
at
this point,
the fact that we're even discussing it and not just outright dismissing it
is kind of,
I agree. And, and here's the other thing
that
makes me excited and interested in
this
kind of New Microsoft will say is
for those of you who aren't old,
like curt and myself kind of starting in the early two thousands.
And even in the late 19 nineties,
I was about to say late 19 hundreds, which I guess is not wrong
but
not
make
me sound older than I am.
But
in the late 19 nineties, early two thousands,
Microsoft was getting their backsides handed to themselves because their
security was garbage and they treated security researchers as adversaries.
And honestly,
this is a very similar story to what we're seeing with Linux where it was basically,
we're going to fight you with everything we have.
And then one day they're like, hey, you're cool, come on in
and,
and, and I mean, it was very much like that.
But anyway, due to Microsoft just getting like pummeled in the industry,
they have some really impressive security controls inside of windows itself that,
that even Linux doesn't have to a certain degree.
And I know that's always say, oh, Linux is more secure and
I'm not going to say it's more secure. I'm not going to say it's less secure.
I'm just going to say it's different.
And so I think if you can bring some of this stuff together, you know,
it's like our powers combined, we form whatever and, and I think it could leave a,
in some instances, a better situation.
But I'm still not gonna run Linux on Windows myself because I do, I do.
There's a windows computer in the basement, the kids play games on.
But like, yeah, I'm not, I'm not running windows. So
it's, it's an interesting thought though.
Well, I'm just thinking from a developer's point of view, man,
this makes their life so much easier
if they run windows.
Ah,
now there's one other important thing we should specify is I would bet you
the vast majority of people who listen to us when we say developers,
they imagine like a dude in a coffee shop with maybe a Linux computer or a Mac.
And the reality is like 99% of developers are people who go into a corporate office.
They sit down at a Windows computer,
they do not have the ability to install software, they do their job and they go home.
Those people are going to experience
an incredible enlightenment from this.
But no, like people like us who just have like Linux computers, we schlep around
whatever we don't really care.
-- No,
-- it's, and I mean, speaking of this, the tools that they're gonna have,
what amazes me is not that Windows or Microsoft released a cool new terminal
but that they actually managed to make a video
of it that makes it look cool.
Uh It does actually, it does look very nice and for anyone who's ever run the,
what is it?
Windows, subsys,
whatever the heck. It is
Windows subsystem for Linux.
Thank you.
Anyone who's ever run the old terminal. It was kind of a piece of crap.
-- It was basically like a glorified D OS prompt and you couldn't do a lot
-- with it.
It was 19 eighties.
Uh I
would
-- sure
-- that was
-- no tab completion. No. Right.
-- Right.
Well, no, no, you could get tab completion when you ran bash, for example,
in the terminal.
But it wasn't like there were no tabs.
It was a very one screen environment, it was copy and paste was weird.
And, but anyway,
they kind of built a new terminal that interfaces
with all this stuff and it looks like a,
a terminal running on a souped up Linux distro, which is pretty sweet.
And here's what's most interesting to me. OK.
But what about contributing to an existing open source terminal app project
said?
And this is, this is on microsoft.com, right? This is their official DEV blog thing.
So we carefully explored this option during planning
and determined our involvement in an existing project
would require changing the project's requirements and architecture
in ways that would be too disruptive.
Yeah, that's probably a vast understatement
instead by creating a new open source
terminal application and open sourcing windows console.
Oh, yeah. Did we mention that this terminal is open source? I don't think we did,
but it's open
source. We did not again,
like,
you know, I'm reminded of that.
Are we the baddies video, except in this case, it's like,
-- is Microsoft the good guys
-- and, and in fact, so it's really funny as you said,
did we mention it's open source?
And
it,
it never occurred to me in my brain to mention it
because I just assumed that would be an obvious fact.
But yeah, totally.
Yeah, this isn't the Microsoft 20 years ago. That's, that's pretty brutal.
And here's another one, here's a like it's, it's been a,
they've had a very busy day yesterday.
Microsoft is building their new Chromium edge browser.
Now I said Chromium edge, not Chromium but Chromium edge.
So they have their edge browser, which is as far as I understand it, a Flaming Turd
-- like most web browsers that are not chrome,
-- that's, that's a little harsh,
it's not great, but it's not terrible.
It's no,
I'll say that.
Well,
yeah.
So they're going to a chrome based web browser but you know,
Chrome and edge and they're building an explorer into it.
So they're essentially, you know,
I guess they understand again, you know,
building a web browser are very nontrivial.
There's basically now two people doing it, you know, Chrome and Firefox, right?
And then there's a bunch of smaller players like safari and opera and whatnot.
I I would like to point out
in the context of this though is the
real reason Microsoft started doing this is because
of just there have been multiple shenanigans pulled
by the large web properties that have made
edge difficult for them.
And so it was kind of one of those,
we're gonna stop doing it our way because you guys keep
screwing us over and we'll just take our stuff and,
and do it
and it would not shock me to see Microsoft become
the la the largest contributor to chromium in the very near future.
And then also Microsoft announced a new open source project for react
native developers who want to target Windows react native for Windows.
-- Like dude,
-- I hate React native.
I I do too. But
if you want to write an app quickly and easily for multiple platforms,
react native is actually not that bad of a choice, you can actually get stuff done.
People hate
it,
you know, I get that people hate it like PHP but it does allow people to get stuff done.
Well, my biggest complaint is it's just such a resource hog.
Yeah. And in five years, your computer will be faster,
man,
whatever. That's the same. We had the same thing with Java. Remember
we still do.
Yeah.
Well, people proposing to build Java specific chips and it's like, wait a second,
what's the whole point of Java to be like independent
of all this crap and like just run everywhere.
And now you're proposing for performance that we build a Java chip.
They, they, they did it with cell phones, man.
Like the feature phones are essentially running
like a Magic Java operating system,
something
which whatever, I don't know
anyway. Anyway.
But, uh, and then finally just a total random thing that they announced yesterday,
they're doing some sort of secure verifiable voting for, you know,
democratic elections,
which now personally I'm not a big fan of electronic elections because
the, the, even as a technical person, the effort to validate
but things have not been shenanigan
is very difficult.
And so I like my little, you know, make your X or check mark on the circle in the paper,
fold it and shove it in the ballot box and
you know, you can teach a 10 year old to,
to scrutineer the election and make sure no shenanigans happened.
But at the same time, I get it because like, let's face it whether or not we like it,
electronic voting is coming and it's going
to be
a more normal thing and it's gonna be probably the default within 20 years.
I, I don't think you're wrong
and I guess this is one of those things, we'll just have to wait and see
what they're talking about because from the things I read, it sounded very
fluffy and nondescript and, and obviously, this is one of those places,
this is kind of like encryption where good enough isn't good enough.
It sounds good. Uh They're releasing it open source this summer on github
obviously, because where else would you release open source nowadays?
-- Especially if you're Microsoft.
-- Well, and that's a super important thing too.
Right? Because
I think releasing it is open source gives obviously the world can inspect it,
but it also gives a certain air of legitimacy that we've been lacking.
Where I know there have been instances where someone has tried suing an
electronic voting machine maker saying give us your source code and they're like,
no, no, I won't,
-- I don't want to
-- same thing for breathalyzers and some other devices where, you know,
there's,
there's real world implications if these things are not
calibrated correctly or have like a little error.
And yeah,
mostly these companies have gotten away with not showing their
uh their source code or their process or anything,
-- right?
-- In effect.
I remember reading of a case with the Breathalyzer where the, the defendant
said,
I want to see the source code and make sure this is like the real deal
and they basically let the case get thrown
out instead of handing over the source code,
which is
like, what, what that doesn't? That's nuts to me. What are you, why are you doing?
Well, what that indicates to me is that it probably is a flaming train wreck.
So rather than they'd rather just chuck out one
court case than risk because the thing you remember,
this guy sees if this guy sees the source code and can prove that it's all wonky.
Then every single court case based on that result,
which would basically be like every
driving intoxication case in that state or whatever would then
be called into question,
right? And companies have a rich history of this.
Like,
remember the Toyota unintended acceleration where they fought it and
they tried to blame people and people went to jail
-- when it turns out it was their car that messed up.
-- No, I hear you.
It's, this is where I love. Just default to open makes so many things so much easier.
And it's one of those, those things I think you and I have talked about this.
I don't remember if we've done it on the podcast ever.
But like the easiest example is saying if Amazon open sourced all of Aws tomorrow,
could anyone build Aws?
And the answer is no, no, they couldn't.
Well, what just worries me is when you introduce profit motive to things like
running an election,
I find that a bit worrying
and,
you know, open sourcing obviously is orthogonal to that.
But these companies that refuse to open source their stuff, do
you know, to this, perceived, wanting to protect their profits and stuff
that does freak me out a bit.
And so I'm, I'm glad that, you know, like elections, Canada and you know,
Alberta elections run the elections and it's not,
they're,
they're generally not buying a whole bunch
of wonky computer equipment from private companies
or Alberta elections
are not Alberta election. Was it the municipal election?
I forget which one I voted in, but they did have an electronic thing, but it generated
a paper.
-- And were you allowed to, like, look at the paper and make sure the right
-- thing?
I had to, I had to take the paper out of the machine and then shove the ballot box.
Right. And so I'm ok with that. Right. Because,
I mean, as long as it's, you know, making, you know,
like,
what was that one classic one in Florida where it's like
you can actually press the button and it would like,
choose the other person.
And it wasn't clear if that was like an error or a screen calibration issue. But
like using this electronic system, it was clear that man,
-- these screens suck and they need to be calibrated more because
-- they're,
they're really bad.
I've,
I've never voted on a screen like that for voting,
but I've used enough touch screens in enough
situations to know that they are terrible.
And in fact, no, you know what?
-- I just did this and I, I went to, there's a restaurant chain in the US called Red
-- Robin.
-- Oh, yeah, we have them here. Oh, ok.
-- Cool.
Anyway, I wanted to go because they just started the Impossible Burger,
which is a meatless hamburger that looks and tastes like a real hamburger.
And it was surprisingly similar.
I, I did find though when I took a bite of the meat, the,
the Impossible Burger and then I took a bite of like an actual real hamburger.
-- You could tell. So,
-- did you actually order two burgers to do a B testing?
No, I ate my kid's burger.
He,
he didn't finish it because like a freaking kid
he orders like the largest milkshake on the menu.
Eats the whole thing first and then is like,
I'm full after taking two bites of your hamburger.
Yeah.
My kids do the exact same thing.
They'll, they'll do their milkshake and they eat some French fries.
That's right.
And the only reason I didn't do it is because
they didn't have giant milkshakes at most of the restaurants when
I was a kid.
No. But anyway, anyway, and they have like, these little touchscreen table
things on the tables and you can pay at them. And I thought this amuses me.
I'm going to pay at this
and it took me
probably 10 minutes of screwing around to finally, like, the
touch screen wouldn't register clicks or I'd hit it
and then I'd, like, hit it again and the screen had just flipped at that point and I,
like, clicked the wrong thing.
-- And I'm like, oh, my goodness, this is a nightmare.
-- This really drives home to me why?
Apple tablets cost more money because the quality of the screen,
the touchscreen they use is fantastic.
Like, I've never had a calibration issue.
I've never had to calibrate my kids' ipads.
Well, and for what it's worth though, I've,
I've bought some cheap tablets and I've never had, I had an issue with them.
I think the problem becomes when they're in any sort of commercial environment,
they get dropped, they get kicked.
You've got kids, like banging on it with the forks. And, you know,
that's the real problem is just kind of the longevity and I'm
sure an ipod in that environment would not fare much better.
Well, this is why mill spec gear costs so much because yeah,
you can drop and it still works.
You can run it over with a tank. It's fine.
Like I literally just had
my computer stopped talking to my keyboard.
I turned my keyboard off, it disconnected.
I turned it on it connected but,
and I button mashed and something happened but like not keypresses.
So I restarted the computer. Still same problem.
I turned the computer all the way off and all the way on in magic. It works again.
It's like voodoo, right?
I'm a computer guy.
I'm not even going to pretend to be able to fix these things anymore.
So, but back to Microsoft. So it's, it's pretty clear, Microsoft gets open source.
It's like, OK, they've embraced open source that hold
on,
hold
on
before we go on.
You miss the most important news story about Microsoft that
I think is from the day before we're recording.
Solitaire was inducted into the video game Hall of Fame.
So, uh I can do you one better. My mom still has her Sony Vio super slim laptop from
mid two thousands
that she uses to play Solitaire on Windows XP.
Because all the other versions of solitaire on the
App store and stuff just aren't good enough.
-- Yeah,
-- they're bad. They're bad. The old solitaire is like my favorite.
In fact, you could, you could, you know, you could buy her a new computer.
You can go, I think it's, I
think archive.org or some,
you can like, run Windows 31 and play the Solitaire. Like the Solitaire.
-- Not these terrible remakes. No,
-- this is, she likes the Windows XP version.
And so this machine has no internet connectivity and that's awesome.
That's all it does. It just runs Solitaire once in a while for her and, and, you know?
Yeah,
that is fantastic.
I love that.
But, but anyway, back to your point.
Yes, Microsoft gets open source now, which, like,
I don't know what to think about that.
Yeah. Oh,
the world has changed very fundamentally
that, that's one thing that's clear, like open source one. It's, it's just
like all these companies that build apps and they're like, oh,
we don't do open source and it's like, well, but you're writing this in.
No Js. So, yeah. Yeah, you're, you're sucking down like 1000 dependencies, right?
Like all these, like, what is it, these software companies that do,
like the automated audits of, like, what's in your software and they're like,
here's a list. It's really long, you know, it reminded me when I went to, um
uh what was it, Mercedes, right.
They,
they have these web pages where you can get a list
of all the open source software in that model of car.
Remember we did a show on this
and there was like the one model of car had like 1200 entries,
like 1200 projects,
you know, from image parsing libraries and audio parsing libraries to,
to whatever.
Well, now here's, here's something else that's really important I think is so
the computers in cars
have always contained a bunch of crap.
The car manufacturers did not write, you know, the,
the whole dependency universe we see today, this is not new, it's just,
it was very hidden before.
And I think this is also one of the big advantages you get
with open source is there are a handful of licenses that basically say,
you know,
you have to publish this license with the source
code if you're going to use our stuff.
And I think one of the really cool defaults is that a lot of companies were just like,
screw it.
We're just going to publish everything.
We're not going to figure out which ones we do or don't have to do this with.
And that's really cool and I don't think they did that out of
altruistic intent.
I think it was just more of a, this is easier than digging through it.
Well, having one process versus multiple processes. Right.
And plus you're more likely to not mess it up and get sued,
-- but you're
-- going to mess it up.
Guarantee. I guarantee they mess it up.
Now, I guarantee there are things in those cars
that they don't realize are there and should we have licenses published?
They just haven't figured it out and maybe they will someday, maybe they won't. But
I guarantee it.
-- No,
-- it's a, it's a brave new world. And
honestly, I'm kind of looking at this.
It's, it's pretty clear, like I, I literally, the only reason I use Macs is because
I have an iphone and so the whole ecosystem just sort of plays
well with itself and I don't have to do any setup or
really much in the way of maintenance or configuration.
Whereas, you know, if I had an Android phone in the Windows
PC,
you know,
I'd have to spend a little time and effort getting them to play well with each other.
-- Right.
-- I just don't let my phone talk to anything else because why,
-- like I, I don't have a purpose to it. Honestly,
-- I use omni
-- focus to, to basically run and organize my life, right?
-- And that's fair.
Having that synchronized with all my devices is pretty critical
or I'm going to end up naked outside and starve.
Yeah.
There you go. I actually started using Google Keep for some, some reasons
and one of the cool things is obviously I can access
it from everything because it's just a web browser plug in
something or other.
And I like it too because I can share lists.
So, like, if I ever go pick this up at the grocery store, I can share it with my wife and
she can add all the stuff I'm supposed to get
and otherwise would forget and just come home with,
you know, 70 bags of potato chips.
Don't laugh. I do that and I've mostly been banned from going to the store. So
I, I sometimes I'm,
I love to go to Costco.
-- I,
-- I'm allowed to actually,
I'm better than she is at Costco because I try to
-- keep my bill under $200 and she does not
-- see,
I find the trick is,
is to eat right before you go to Costco so that you actually want to get out of there.
Uh That's fair. That's fair.
But
yeah, anyway, I still, I still come home with, although when I go to Costco,
I just come home with three bags of chips that
are the equivalent of 75 regular bags of chips.
So there is that.
But anyway, anyway,
uh Right. So yeah, I,
I don't even know what to say, man. I feel like
this is a new exciting territory and
I look forward to where it goes.
This is going to bring open source to the masses like all
the people stuck in open plan cubicles will be open source users.
Uh, and, and they'll know it, I guess, is the key because they already are
and they'll be happy about it too because it'll be, it's, it's officially blessed.
It,
like my experience of Microsoft is they generally don't
release stuff until it actually works reasonably well.
You know.
And, uh, it,
it's just gonna mostly work. It's gonna,
it's basically, they're gonna remove a lot of pain points,
make things easier, make these people more productive.
Um, they're not going to have to relearn a whole bunch of stuff. You know.
That's one thing I always got with open source is
that if you wanted to make the switch from,
like to open source from windows, like, ok, cool, forget everything,
you know about windows and now go learn Linux
right
straight up, you know, and nobody wants to do that,
-- you know, that's
-- a pain unless you're 13 and you have infinite time.
But
even then 13 year olds don't have time anymore. They're all busy playing Fortnite.
-- So, uh,
-- I heard Fortnite was out and Apex Legends is in,
that's what I was. I was actually told by another parent. Apparently.
-- Apparently I missed the whole fortnight train.
-- My, my kids have played them both
and they've been falling back to Fortnite lately because they just
a
bunch of, uh, marvel content into Fortnite,
the
Avengers
movie.
-- Right. So that's hip again.
-- So they're taking the legal approach,
right? And good for them, I'm all whatever. I'm all for it.
But it's, uh, yeah, it's like, you know,
kids are fickle and they're going to do whatever.
So, yeah, we'll see.
I have, I have no doubt in three months it'll be something else
and that's fine. That's fine. It's, uh,
right.
Anyway, although I will say one of the cool things with Fortnite is I'll,
I'll play it with my kids and of course I lose real bad.
But, well,
you can turn on like sandbox mode where you just like hang out and build things and,
and mess around
the building mechanics. Look fun.
It's, it's all right,
but it's really buggy. So it's really fun.
Like we'll figure out ways to clip into things and get under the floor and all that
and that, like that kind of stuff I love and the kids think it's awesome, like,
-- oh look what's going on, you know,
-- and I,
I actively Felix is now at the point where he'll,
he'll come running into the room holding his ipad saying I glitched it,
I glitched it.
And also, and this is going to make you laugh. He's playing ticket to ride.
And he was basically trying to work out the traveling
salesman problem so that he could unlock these achievements,
like, you know, connecting all the Russian cities.
And he actually had like a piece of paper and he's like, you know, II I was like,
no step back or don't start talking about graph theory, shut up and do it his way.
Right. But uh
he like, literally was, you know,
he was basically starting to discover the primitives of graph theory, you know,
and the traveling salesman problem and why
this is actually a pretty complicated problem.
Oh,
that's hilarious.
You know, and I asked him the one simple question, like,
do you actually have enough trains to physically connect all the cities?
And he went,
oh,
you know, and you could see the wheels turning in his head.
So I love that these games can really
have an impact on kids and really encourage them.
And that's the other thing I love, you know,
is all these kids that have windows on their desktop,
assuming they don't have a chromebook.
Now all of a sudden they have access to, how do I put it nicely?
An actual proper tool chain
that doesn't cost a lot of money because that was the thing that always got me right
is especially in the Windows world is if you wanted a proper development tool chain,
not cheap.
And, and I'm not gonna lie to you.
That's what got me into Linux back in the day was they,
I got a free C compiler and that was back when even I could afford the tools, right?
Even as a student,
uh visual visual studio, student price when I was in,
in high school and college was 100 bucks.
And
I didn't have $100 at the time.
So I'm like, I'm just going to run this Linux thing and yeah, it no regrets.
But anyway, all right, man,
I think it's time
I'm gonna call it. So I guess thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up the show notes. You can use E
Poland
O
as podcast hashtag to get our attention on social media.
-- Yeah, Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks,
-- everyone. Bye bye
the.