Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt
Siefried and my partner wearing socks. Josh Bresser.
-- I do actually have socks on today. I don't always have socks when we record
-- though.
See, I don't wear socks from May until the middle of September.
I try to avoid socks whenever possible.
Mhm.
Anyway, that's a weird topic.
-- That's
-- not really a fair, like, I don't have that option in winter here.
It's not a pleasant experience necessarily. I have fuzz
slippers. I wear and
stuff,
but I don't know why I just don't like wearing socks.
It's always funny when I go to conferences
because socks are really popular right now.
People are like, oh, take a pair of socks and I'm like, no, I don't want your socks.
Like, I won't take those.
-- I'm like, what socks are popular?
-- What?
Yeah, like socks at conferences are
when, when, when I go to a conference, I'm serious. This is completely honest to God.
When I was at a conference
we were giving away socks
and people were, like, seeking us out to get the socks and I'm like, what's
wrong with you people? I mean, no, they're just like crappy conference socks.
They're not even high quality or anything. It's
-- because I'm, I'm pretty, it's
-- conference
swag ever since I did ballroom dancing,
I'm actually quite
particular about what I put on my feet anyway.
All right. This is weird.
No, it's, it's, well, it's, it's kind of the exact same
-- thing is today's topic.
-- I can't wait to see how you tie them together.
This person posts. Linux is a nightmare.
It's only 0.8% of our sales, but it's over 50% of the reported technical issues,
some game or something.
And, and,
and this is generally true across a lot of different platforms and Softwares.
Sure. Sure. And so then there's the,
the, the, the classic hacker news article, you know, of
the, the Linux bashing followed by the not Linux bashing, followed by the blah,
blah, blah, blah,
blah,
obviously.
But um,
one thing and so like, let's ignore,
see,
the one thing that always gets me is people
treat these bug reports and problem reports as something like
that they
have to deal with.
And if you've ever bought software from a large entity, like let's pick on oracle
-- and you have a major problem with it. Well, no, let's not
-- pick on or
they're a bad example. Let's pick on Red Hat because we were there.
We have experience and there's literally public bugs to point
to this Red Hat publishes all of their security vulnerability information
in a very easy to consume way. They have an API they have flat files.
It's very, very nice.
And there is a high percentage of security vulnerabilities.
They just mark as won't fix like we
are never fixing this vulnerability in our product.
-- Well, on purpose unless
-- we accidentally update
this.
So sometimes they accidentally fix it. But
you get the idea
and the intent behind this is,
and this was always funny having this conversation with people is
I can fix the important security bugs
or I could fix this crap and ignore the important bugs,
which would you rather have me do?
Well, actually it's worse than that because
-- why do people buy Red Hat? Well, for stability and boringness?
-- Right. Exactly.
Ok.
So you want me to start making a bunch
of code changes that aren't strictly speaking necessary?
-- Right. Right.
-- And
sometimes have pretty deep impacts.
Yeah. Yeah, for sure.
You know,
and it always amused me because it seems like the patches for the low
severity vulnerabilities are vastly more complicated than
the patches for the critical vulnerabilities,
which
I love because the critical stuff is usually like an integer overflow
and the low severity stuff is like, oh,
we have to completely revamp the way our temp handling works,
which is a 7000 line commit.
But, um, I, what I was thinking was more interesting to me is,
is kind of less about the whole,
like Linux users find a lot of bugs that are actually cross platform, right?
This is one of the reasons Open BS D traditionally
wanted to support a lot of big and small Indian architectures
is because it would bubble up bugs that
-- otherwise wouldn't bubble up.
-- That's right.
-- You know.
I mean, this was why I remember when, when I helped out the Fedora people
gen two because gen two users would find the
gnarliest bugs because they would create these like,
bizarre combinations of software that no one ever
thought of and it would uncover ludicrous problems.
-- And
-- so what I'm kind of wondering is like, I'm a Windows user,
a Mac user and a Linux user.
And
the way I react to a bug in these systems is very different.
Like on the apple side, it's like, well, I'm holding it wrong.
No, I, I'm serious
that,
yes, that's how I deal with bugs on my.
Like, I'll reboot the system and then I'm like, well,
I need to learn a new way to hold this.
It's,
it's my fault.
I,
I clearly didn't pay Apple enough money or I should have bought a
Macbook instead of a Mac Air because what else can I really do?
-- Yes, that is correct.
-- You know, like I could file a bug.
Can you, can you file?
I don't, I don't know, I don't know how to file.
I know when my Mac crashes, it has the, would you like to send us a report?
And that's the,
-- all I've seen
-- developer feedback using the feedback assistant.
Oh, this is for actually getting, like, feedback and bugs in your stuff, I think.
Anyway, we don't have
this right now
and then, like, with Windows kind of
the assumption is if it's a minor bug, whatever, that's just how it works.
And if it's a major bug, yeah,
probably some enterprise user will report this to Microsoft and they'll fix it.
Maybe eventually
I'll complain on, on
Mastodon.
If there's a windows bug I hit, which is, I don't,
I don't hit a lot because I don't like windows.
But,
and then with Linux,
I
-- might file a bug,
-- I file lots of bugs on Linux. Yeah.
Part of it is
I can actually file,
I don't wanna say just a good bug in the sense of like, hey,
this exact version with this exact command line, you know, blah, blah, blah.
But for example, I can file it very concisely against
the correct person.
Whereas if I file a bug in windows,
it's kind of like I just sort of fired off into Microsoft and I'm like,
goodbye, have fun at college.
But like, it's just,
you know, it's like going on a transatlantic voyage like I hope you get there.
-- I have no idea.
-- So, OK, so there's, there's two pieces to this.
I, I and I, I have a fun example to give, but
I think
there is also a myth in the world of open source that like, oh anyone can contribute,
anyone can file bugs.
But the reality is they can't.
And there's a lot of reasons for that
and I'll, I'll give a really good example.
So
I
was running X Windows for a long time because I was using the Audacity
audio editor literally for the podcast.
And audacity on Wayland
basically made Wayland like come to this crushing
halt where it was just whatever they were doing
was in, we'll say incompatible with what however Wayland worked, right?
But if I ran it in X Windows, it worked fine.
So I was running
modern Fedora
modern
Gnome
in X Windows.
Gnome.
Yeah, it's called Gnome.
That's its
name.
No,
it's funny because there's AAA board game shop in
town called Gnome Games and I always call it Gnome
games and everyone thinks I'm a freak.
But I'm like, this is just literally decades of abuse.
-- Yeah,
-- that's how, that's how you pronounce it can.
And so now, yeah, like the people who own the shop, they think I'm a weirdo which I am.
But I mean, anyway,
-- we
-- can spend money there. So it's OK.
I guess that's fair. They're nice. But so anyway, I am running Audacity. I'm using
Gnome
with X Windows
and obviously a lot of the developers for Gnome have been using
Wayland and so a lot of the features are in Wayland and
you can tell X Windows is kind of a second class citizen now. It's not quite as right.
And I found this weird bug where c I forget what they call it.
You know, how,
like you have the windows now where they put all the decoration crap in,
like the title bar.
Like, like if you run a
month
web browser instead of having like the old school title bar at the very top,
it has like the tabs and all that crap in it Now,
whatever you, you you, I I promise you your browser is doing this.
-- You just don't realize it.
-- Yeah.
-- Yeah, the tabs at the top,
-- right?
Instead of having the like empty window bar
-- because that's just dumb wasted space.
-- I disagree. But anyway,
I need somewhere to click to move things. Kurt, I move things a lot
anyway.
That's, that's
fair.
So anyway,
I use Windows power toys to solve that problem.
Like I literally
-- have a piece of software to explicitly solve that problem. So yes, you are
-- correct.
Use windows anyway.
OK.
So
I realize that there is a problem
in
Geno
on next windows where if I have a traditional window that is in the
background because I also use focus follows
mouse because I'll just move something,
my mouse and into a window type things,
move it back to the other window type things which which I
found like windows and apple do a terrible job at that,
which is one of the other reasons I detest them.
But anyway.
So I've got focus follows mouse and I find if I have something in the background
and I click on the, the menu bar, not menu bar, the title bar thing.
No, it doesn't, it doesn't come to the top.
I have to grab it and move it for it to come to the top.
-- Oh,
-- you actually have to like, you have to move it a pixel at least.
But then,
so I, I'm like, OK, this is annoying and this is bugging me.
And so I start doing some research
and I find a bug in the genome
bug tracker
and someone had reported this, but they, the, the developers asked some questions
and they had no idea what to do next. And I find that I'm like,
I know exactly what to do here.
So I spent like literally like two hours figuring out exactly
what was happening and it turned out it only affected the,
I don't know the lingo and I even said this at the beginning like,
I don't know your fancy words.
So please excuse my like horrible caveman speech.
-- But
-- the fact that you know that you don't know
is already putting you in the top percent of bug reporters
probably. But anyway, I found out this only affected
the like traditional windows, the new, like, like fancy decorations,
-- those worked
-- fine
legacy
code.
Yeah. Right. Exactly. Exactly what it was.
And I did like all this work, I thought I fill out all this information b
for the developers. Like, oh, I know exactly what's wrong with this.
And of course, I, I think,
I don't know if it's fixed now because actually I switch audio
editors to a tool called Reaper and Reaper works fine in Wayland.
So I'm like, whatever Fux windows I'm out.
So I, I actually don't know if it's fixed. I, I suppose I could go check.
But,
yeah, like this is one of those examples where
the, the I, I think it is a, I don't know if I'd call it a myth or a lie.
But saying anyone can contribute to open source
is for, for a lot of people
submitting bug reports to open source is no different than submitting bug
reports to Microsoft because it's outside of the realm of possibility.
No.
You know what it's like saying, it's like saying if your car has a problem,
you tell the mechanic what it is and they'll fix it.
-- Oh, yeah, that's fair
-- too. Yeah,
like
if you could actually diagnose a modern car problem,
you're basically a mechanic.
And I think that's part of the challenge here is
this is stuff that is like, ok, if a, if a fence board has a crack in it,
the fence board has a crack in it.
That's very sort of simple, direct and relatable and
visible
cause and effect. But software is complex. Cars are complex
and so there isn't
like there are some car noises where I'm like, ok, I know what that means.
Like a timing belt or something.
But there's a lot of stuff where, like,
a friend of mine has a car that will randomly just choose not to start,
but all the lights and dash and everything come on.
And so they replaced their battery that didn't solve it.
It's still like, it'll just randomly
not start and then 10 minutes later it'll start fine and it'll work and then it'll
right. And it's like,
yeah, that sounds like it's gonna be expensive for a mechanic to track down.
Probably.
I mean, it's funny, I, I had that with my old pickup truck.
I drove the check engine light was on for about a decade
and the mechanic I go to said, look,
I could figure out why this check engine lights on,
but it's gonna probably cost you as much as this truck is worth.
So, as long as the truck runs and there's nothing terribly wrong with it.
Like, let's just pretend it's fine.
I'm ok with that.
Yeah.
So
that's the thing is just
number one fixing a software bug means you have to understand
the software notice. I didn't say the software bug.
-- I said you have to understand the software,
-- uh, to a degree.
I would, I would agree with that.
-- Yeah,
-- because otherwise you're gonna make co changes that
impact the software in ways that are negative.
Right. How many times? Oh, perfect. So how many times have we seen Linne Torvalds
go? This patch is followed by a very, like,
-- apparently he's getting therapy now and he's like, nicer creative
-- string of
words.
But in fairness if they did put that patch in, it would be
horrific
for some reason, like either performance or security or whatever.
Like, like,
I'm always reminded of uh what was the one where the
patches had a 30% performance impact for the CPU bug?
-- Was it heart bleed or whatever it was?
-- It was like shell shock or something, right?
-- No, not
-- shell shock. That was the bash stuff, but the, the CPU stuff. Uh
Ghost
and
anyways the CPU stuff.
Uh Yeah, Ghost or whatever.
I know what you mean
-- though. Yeah.
-- Yeah.
And it's like, yeah, we can fix this but there's a 30% performance impact.
I remember that.
Yeah, we
can't do that. Like those people running
servers that are running at like anywhere more than 65
ish percent capacity,
whatever.
Amazon
probably loved it. Like
I still maintain like this patch sponsored by Amazon.
So,
but that's 30% more aws. Now, everybody.
Like, if there's a board in my fence that's broken,
it's actually a nontrivial fix because I have to take
some of the fence apart to get the board,
the new board in.
But it's,
but it's doable.
But
like, you're bugging gnome,
like,
right? Like, I, I don't know, like, I don't know
gnome and it's, it's in the tens of millions of lines of code
size.
And now now look, no, no, no.
So the point is I'm saying is complexity
matters and just understanding the software, let alone understanding the bug,
let alone understanding how to fix the bug
properly. Now, sometimes it's easy. It's like, oh, we didn't escape HTML,
escape HTML. We good or an integer overflow.
But a lot of times these bugs are not simple or especially if it's old legacy code.
It's kind of like a logic error in which case.
What is the correct logic? Like every time there's AAA TCP/IP problem
and somebody determines like, oh, the specs unclear.
Well, now what?
No, like
because
the correct behavior is not specified.
Um OK. What do we do now?
I mean,
and over the years we've accrued.
Sure.
I think that's a vaguely different problem.
And I, I want to tie this back to security bugs though.
I think security bugs are a great example of this
where I remember
there was a time I
did a bunch of fuzzing. This was back when fuzzing was brand new.
I wrote a Fuzz to Fuzz true type fonts.
I submitted patches to the, the true type. What is, what is free type?
I think it was called the free type project
because I'd fuzzed all these fonts. I had a bunch of reproducers.
I tracked down the integer overflows. I added the checks
and I sent them, it was like 15 different bugs
and I sent it to their mailing list and they were like, oh, this is all the same bug.
You actually are fixing the wrong integer overflow.
If you fix this one up here, it solves all these problems. I was like, holy crap.
That's freaking amazing.
But that's an example of these people understood the code.
Really, really well, I did not understand the code really, really well.
So I was working within the confines of my knowledge, but it was wrong.
And so one patch instead of 15 patches, that's a huge deal, you know,
well,
-- and
-- more to the point fixing it correctly versus like how
many times have we seen a place try to band aid?
The symptom like windows was famous for this. Remember, Windows would fix a bug
and then literally two hours later on Microsoft Tuesday, somebody would be like,
-- I got it.
-- I mean,
that's the story of shell shock.
Like I mean, shell shock is I'll,
I'll tell the story for anyone who hasn't heard it before.
But
Shellshock was a problem in bash where,
what was it? Certain environment variables I think could end up executing bash
arbitrary code.
And the correct solution was to just basically escape
all of the environment variables in a certain way.
But by doing that, you would break backwards compatibility.
So the bash people,
their first patch was to only
address the specific environment variable in question
and I remember
-- I was at Red Hat at the time and we were, we were, we were coordinating
-- this.
-- I remember thinking there might be more.
-- Yeah.
And I remember we even said this, we're like,
we're pretty sure this is gonna be there's
other variables that this can be done with.
They're like, no, no, we're not going to touch it. We're only doing this.
They released their patch and I think it was Tavis
Ormandy like literally two hours later found another one.
They fixed that one
then literally like two hours after the next release.
I think it was Tavis found another one
-- and then I think it was um
-- um Michael
-- Zaleski also found a bunch.
-- Yeah,
Zaleski. Yeah, he ended up running
a
fuzz against it, I think and found a lot.
-- And that's when Bash was like, OK, we're gonna actually have to do this, right?
-- And
there was also Florian and uh Florian Weimer
and then Toss
-- Sabine also found a couple in the parser code
-- that that could
be because Florian is doing a ton of work on this.
-- I know
-- he found 21 with Todd and another on his own.
Yeah, that guy's scary, smart
and that's a perfect example of like Florian is
the kind of human being where you're like,
just you can go fix the
pa the thing yourself. And he's like, yes, yes, I can.
But
there's like six of him on the planet. If that.
Right. Like,
you know.
Yeah. Yeah, for sure. But,
I mean, anyway,
-- so, but
-- I think at least with open source there's the chance of it. And also I think,
and I've said this before on the show, there's this accountability piece of, like,
there's a public bug filed.
It's been ignored for a year or two and,
you know, uh,
you at least get some validation that you're not
the only one that ran into this and cares.
That's kind of nice. Right.
I mean, it, it can be, but at the same time I also take issue with people who think
if you file a bug with an open source project, they should fix it.
Like there's nothing wrong with the project, won't fixing a bug.
-- I, I think that's a good attitude.
-- Mo Dash
just declared a bug bankruptcy.
And, yeah, so if you go is issue,
uh, so basically in their current issue, Tracker and github
-- they have two open and 4166 closed.
-- You know what? I don't, I don't blame them.
You know what that feels like
if you ever come back from vacation and you just have so much email, you're just like,
select all delete.
I, I can't deal with this. There's nothing I can do and sometimes that's ok.
Well, I mean, at some point
I think, uh, going back to accepting reality for what it is.
Oh, we have 4000 open bugs and three developers
for sure. And part of the challenge is it's just, it's distracting.
Like, what is the mo ok. Just triaging.
It's just rating,
just reading the titles of 4000 bugs is gonna take you
-- hours
-- just knowing you have 4000 bugs is mentally exhausting.
It's in the back of your mind all the time. I have 4000 bugs.
That sucks.
Yeah. And so I think, but one thing it proves is that no,
you can't just fix it if you find a bug because,
I mean,
there's 4000 bugs that have been closed.
Obviously, some of them are closed, you know, fixed or whatever it has.
But looking at this, like, some of them are not that complicated,
but
I mean, there's,
there's no chance of them fixing it. Like, oh, here's a perfect one.
I didn't find the Conca dot Js and file and master.
Change the name. Question mark.
-- That's the bug.
-- That's it.
And then followed up with, could you please tell me the answer from another person?
What
I don't? Well, I, I probably, I'm lacking knowledge.
I'm sure that might make sense to someone who uses it. But
so, but now, now
there's always going to be the people who say, oh,
just send a patch upstream for the bug you have.
-- And that's not always simple either.
-- Well, and that's almost worse in a way because
I mean, if you think A I produces bad code quality,
you should see the random patches people send into open source projects.
Well, it's, it's not, I mean,
so there's that aspect but even let's pretend I'm a good developer for a minute.
If I want to submit a patch to a project,
you go to the project and they often have like a developing
section where they talk about here is how we develop the software.
And it's often you need to obviously clone the repository,
you need to install these dependencies,
you need to run these test cases, you need to do all this and that and other. And like
I remember when I started at anchor,
one of the first things I did
is I took our open source project Sift and Gripe, I cloned the repositories.
And then I was like, I'm going to build these and I'm going to see what it takes.
And then as I went, I,
I fixed the developing documentation because I knew it was wrong.
And like
I obviously had
financial motivation to do this because I want,
I obviously I wanted to learn the projects, but I also wanted to make it more,
you know, like approachable by others.
But how many projects have outdated,
like developing documentation that is completely wrong for
one reason or another because I mean,
developers are legendary for never upgrading the docs, you know,
that's just how it is.
But I, I think that's one of the challenges open source has is just the fact that
you look at this documentation on how to submit a patch
and it's often extremely complicated and, and usually out of date.
And so if I'm a new developer,
do I have two days to get this project up and running on my local environment?
So I can create a patch so I can send a patch in.
No,
-- you probably
-- don't only to be told it
doesn't meet their cultural standards for coding.
Well, that too.
Yeah, I mean, that's ignoring the angle of dealing with the,
the developers on the other end of that.
I mean,
imagine like sending a patch to the Linux kernel
with no background or history or understanding what's going on.
Like, oh my goodness, you'd be run out of town,
you know.
Well, and in a way, I have to say kind of rightly so because
you can't just be taking random people's patches and shoving
them into the Linux kernel and hoping for the best,
like
-- for sure,
-- for sure. Actually.
Did you hear that at the, there's the open source summit was going on this week.
Uh Jonathan Corbett
gave a talk about the long term Linux kernel versions and they're reducing the,
the lifetime from six years to two because they're having maintenance issues,
finding developers to work on it.
Like
-- I get it.
-- So
that's so weird because like, like when we were at red hat,
it was so easy to find Linux kernel maintainer developers.
It was
super easy.
I know. I'm being sarcastic.
This is,
see, I'm really bad at that.
This is what, like, two or three episodes in a row that,
-- that your sarcasm has flown over my head,
-- dude.
Like Red Hat has money to pay people to do this
and even Red Hat is struggling and drowning
in the Linux kernel
who has
to work on old stuff
is
worse than that.
The level of expertise needed to work on that and do the
old stuff is the same level of expertise needed to work on.
Cool new things.
Yeah. Oh, yeah.
And if you have that level of expertise, unless I don't know what
you, you'd probably want to work on new stuff and not do maintenance, patching.
I mean,
yeah,
I don't want, I don't want to do old kernel patches
-- like that sounds terrible. So,
-- yeah.
No, it's, I,
I'm actually always kind of surprised at how long some
of these LTs life cycles are for free software because
especially something with the complexity of the Linux kernel. Like, oh, yes.
Like I remember
building Slackware 1.0 with the Linux fal
0.99 or nine, I think we started about 91 or 92 and then
-- 99 patch level infinity
-- probably fit on a floppy back then
a couple of floppies.
But yeah, like, I mean,
and even back then, like, it was a much simpler thing. Like I knew the config file.
-- Like there was only a couple, like 200 options.
-- I remember, I
remember the Linux config file and that's like a blast from that.
-- I wonder what it looks like now. It's got to be insane.
-- It's machine generated.
It's, but
uh
like going back to this, like the skill,
like,
even,
I
don't want to say trivial software because there's not a
lot of trivial software anymore because even something that is trivial
is typically interacting with non-trivial things.
Like your gen two
example, where they're smushing this stuff together in weird ways.
And it's like, oh, I guess what I found,
you know?
Yeah,
-- I mean, yeah, that's fair.
-- And so
I just,
I keep coming back to the fact that just because somebody reports a bug or a problem,
like,
maybe you should,
if that's your entire business model and you want to keep them happy,
but that's not a business model.
Most projects have.
Well, that's a business model for businesses, not for projects
that's fair. And that's true because
I know
obviously every product company I've ever worked with,
there were bugs customers would report. You know, here's the thing
customers would rather have you tell them we will not fix this
than have you pretend you might someday maybe,
right. That way they at least understand like we can work around this
or we can wait for the fix.
You know what I mean?
And, and I know that's always one of the challenges is like,
where do we draw that line?
What do we say?
Like, we're not fixing this bug, but we are fixing that bug and that's hard to do.
And some of it was also educating them, right?
Because I remember one bank reported across that scripting vulnerability in a
product and was freaking out and wanted daily updates and I'm like,
nope.
And they're like, what do you mean? No. And I'm like, no.
And they were flipping out and then I was like, well, here's the exact same
type of bug severity
mark does
won't like, maybe we'll fix it and it's,
and, and that actually calmed them down.
I think that got their internal people because my suspicion
is that they had some security person who was like,
really like I found this bug and I want the credit and I
want to make a big deal out of this and chicken little it
and to be blunt, probably the higher ups were like, yeah, we whatever, man, like
what is cross
site scripting again?
You know, for them to have this kind of answer of like, oh,
here's another one that's public and been public for months.
I,
I always felt bad when a security researcher would report like a
trivial security bug like that and it's like your bug is valid.
Thank you for the report.
-- We're never fixing this.
-- Well, I mean, we've had to go that far with like,
how many bug. How many website bug bounties now explicitly say,
like best practice hardening tips around like
Deam
and SPF and TLS and all that stuff. We just weren't. No.
Right. Because how many people are reporting that kind of simple stuff,
you know, for sure.
Or like, uh Daniel from Curl just posted one where somebody,
was it a no point or d reference, I want to say,
and after a lot of back and forth, the,
the person finally understood that this is not exploitable or a security block
and it took a while, but they finally got educated
and basically like kind of Daniel got through this person by
forcing them to explain how it was exploitable.
And initially they were just like, it's an all point or D reference.
E says it's a bad
type of flaw and traditionally there are blah, blah, blah and he's like,
that's cool.
But like, what about this bug? Explain how this bug is exploitable.
And eventually the person came back basically saying like, yeah, I tried to like,
kind of figure out how it was exploitable and it's not.
Yeah. Yeah. Right. Yeah. But how much time was spent,
you know what I mean? And that's tough.
That's really tough. You can't,
how do I say this nicely?
You can maybe think of asking this of someone who is a programmer for a full time job
but anybody else that is an unreasonable ridiculous thing
to even think about asking them to do.
-- Yeah.
-- Yeah. That's fair. That's fair.
You know.
And, and in fairness that goes also to,
that's the thing that worries me though is like, there's often that, you know,
a very unsophisticated person who wants to report a bug and kind of can't.
And my, my concern is always, like,
are they the one person that decides to speak up
and there's thousands of people suffering from this bug?
I mean,
there's probably more than one and I think that's one of
the angles that I find very interesting in the open source universe
is,
uh,
it's a, it's a, it's all statistics, right? It's all giant numbers.
You have millions of users, maybe billions of users in some cases.
And if 10 people speak up it,
you probably need to multiply that by a pretty big number to get
an idea of how many people are actually affected by a particular issue,
you know,
and it's kind of like this is one of the
things that hacker news thread brings up for that whole,
like what 0.8% of our users are Linux,
but they're 80% of our bugs or whatever.
But
yeah,
one of the people in the hacker news thread is like, look,
Linux users are really good at filing bugs.
So of course, they're filing more bugs than Windows users are
Netflix. I don't know if that's technically true though.
I mean, I've run games on Linux
and they're super flaky and it's because my Linux
installation is like some like nightmarish Frankenstein monster.
And that's fine.
Go ask anybody at your company who's not a
developer to go file a bug against your products.
I mean, they do that all the time,
-- like, like a salesperson.
-- Uh So
our
sales people, we're really small. So sales people are shockingly competent. But,
ok,
but like when I, when I joined Red Hat, you know,
you go through your one day induction or your Yeah, one or was it two day induction?
Yeah, two day induction. You know, you fly down
two days and um
there was me another technical person and then like uh over a dozen sales people that
-- really did not understand what the GP L was. I mean,
-- that's fair.
Why
-- would they,
-- so
they're gonna file a bug hat?
-- Well, they
-- don't, they, this is why. So I mean, look
in the context of a company like Red Hat salespeople don't file bugs.
Salespeople talk to
support people and support people, file bugs.
But what I'm saying is this is an example of where these
people are like asking a regular user to file a bug.
That's fair.
Like if that regular user is a full time programmer, that's maybe a fair ask.
-- But if that regular user is my mother, like come on.
-- OK. So II I actually have a good
kind of example for this. So
there are new Arduinos out. They are four Right. They have an arm chip in them now.
They're very cool.
And I've been doing a bunch of like, electronics project work and I'm, I,
I only have one Arduino left that's not broken now.
And so I'm like, I should buy some more. I, I break things cart. It's what I do like
putting a lot of voltage into an Arduino is a bad idea.
Just saying
I would love to tell you, I won't do that, but I make no guarantees anyway.
So I buy two, right? And they come, one of them works fine.
The other one doesn't work at all.
And it looks like the USB port is missing some solder joints on it.
That is my suspicion.
I'm not going to try to fix it because like,
I'll probably just make it worse and I literally just bought this thing.
So I'm like, I'm going to contact Arduino support and see what happens. And
we've reached the point after giving them basically a very detailed explanation
of everything I've done of why this is definitely a broken Arduino.
And they send me this huge questionnaire with all this stuff.
They want me to do like do this and then take a screenshot,
do this and then take a screenshot.
And I'm like
part of me is offended
because the data I've already sent you
is vastly more valuable than this questionnaire.
It's like a resume
-- processing site, right? Like we need it in a standardized format for our.
-- Exactly.
And, and that's the thing, dealing with a normal person,
they probably already are going to be able to barely fill this thing out.
And I get that because it's, I'm basically filing a bug report with Arduino
and they're trying to validate my bug.
And so they're asking for this enormous list of information
to verify. I do, in fact have a broken Arduino
and I'm not holding it wrong, so to speak.
Right.
And in my particular instance, I have two arduinos, one of them works flawlessly.
One of them like does not work at all.
And it's funny because when I plug it into windows, I have no idea what's going on.
So I plug it into Linux and I can look at the output of logs and stuff.
I'm like, oh, I see what's happening. I understand completely.
And it's funny because they're like, we want the windows output.
I'm like, whatever.
So you're gonna get it because I want my,
we're gonna see if we can get this thing replaced.
But
anyway, anyway, it's, I guess the thing I would sum this all up as is the whole,
like anyone can contribute to open source is probably a lie.
And
I think the, the amusement
of
going through normal people processes when you're,
we'll say moderately technical,
I find entertaining because it's like a peek behind the curtain of what must be
-- just madness for the most part.
-- Have you turned it off and on.
Yes. Yes, I did several times.
But
in fact, I even, I,
I found out this is one thing I was disappointed
in is the chip they're using in the new Arduino
is from some French company.
And there, it, it's very unfriendly to open source.
Their software only runs on windows for like, like the building and flashing the,
the boot rom inside of it.
And
I will say Windows now has like a rollback feature.
I, I set a rollback point and then I installed this awful software that did,
who knows what to my computer
and none of it worked obviously because it was just completely trashed.
The Arduino doesn't work and of course, this is not,
this is not in the Arduino's instructions.
This is me just like going off the rails trying to fix this thing
and then I, I restored my windows install and I'm like,
thank goodness for that because that thing installed,
you know, that whole like, oh, this program is trying to do something scary.
You have to click. Yes, that popped up like 20 times to
install. But it's what Kurt, it's like, it's an IOT type software suite of stuff.
Oh, no, I know.
But they,
they don't need to be written that poorly and
-- it's
-- installing drivers and who knows what else.
Like, I don't want to know what it did to the system,
but it occurs to me if I was like, an actual, like, like, you know,
embedded type developer.
I would basically have a plague system just
for running all this software because there's like,
no way I would trust my computer ever again.
It's cute that you think these developers work for
a company that will pay for two systems.
I, I probably not, but I mean, it's just like, oh, I can't believe how
it's just horrible that world is anyway. Anyway,
-- I'll give you the last word, man. Then we'll call it.
-- I don't know.
I don't really have a last word here.
It's just, I wish, I guess, you know what my biggest thing is.
I wish people would actually look at how the world is and not how it should be.
Like those people on, mastered,
on arguing about software updates saying if people basically
observed semantic versioning then updates would be safe.
-- And I'm like,
-- yes,
sure.
Like, just,
they'll magically have the resources to do long term support for some old version.
That's, that's a topic we'll have to bring up again soon.
-- Yeah,
-- I just, and I understand we should strive for a better world. Absolutely.
-- But we should also probably tell the truth about reality. I,
-- well, it's ok.
-- I like
-- low dash declaring a bug bankruptcy. That's true.
-- Yeah,
-- that's it. It is. It's very true.
And this is, we'll have to make this a topic at some point in the near future.
But, yeah, I think it comes back to like that whole,
the open source we have versus the open source people pretend we have, right?
And like,
like, oh, all these projects have a lot of contributors and super healthy,
like, looking at low dash 287 contributors.
All right. So number one, hasn't contributed since 2007 18.
Number two hasn't contributed since 2012.
And then everybody else is like 77 commits or less.
So. Oh yeah, low dash basically has not had really any activity since 2000, mid 2017.
That's
wow. Holy cow.
Yeah.
So like there's literally been
-- no activity since 2021. There's been no activity since 2021 wild
-- man wild.
But again,
like this is these are the kind of things like there's that prevailing attitude
of open source health
and is that a healthy project? Maybe it is, maybe it isn't.
-- I'm not going to say one way or the other.
-- Uh No, actually. OK. So the last commit was in
uh April 23rd of 2021.
-- What? To Low
-- Dash?
And then there's a commit from September 17th, 2023.
Formatting some
nits
horrifying, I
mean, and
bugs.
It's, well,
it's
-- hasn't been developed in two years.
-- I should look at that because that
anyway,
if you're running a node project, LO Dash
is in it,
probably 20 or 30 copies of low dash are in it.
Not even just one anyway. I am calling this one. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you for listening. Go up social security podcast.com.
Hit up the show, Not Su Podos
Podcast hashtag on Mastodon Kurt and have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye bye.