Hello and welcome to episode 67 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt
Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime. Josh Pressers.
I feel like 67 should be an important number.
And I don't know why
is it prime? I
-- wonder if it's prime because
-- 7890, yeah. No, that's why,
why is six
of 7789
-- maybe that's what you're thinking of. The
-- seven did eat nine
apparently.
So I'm told, I don't know,
I 63 to 7 and it's also a prime number. I just looked it up.
-- So
-- primes are pretty awesome.
-- Primes are awesome.
-- Speaking
of.
So, yeah, my, my partner,
I'm not allowed to fold
towels or she basically, I'm only allowed to fold washcloths
because wash cloths are folded in halves.
But she folds everything else into divisions of three or other prime numbers,
which I'm not good at, I fold by hat,
which is not acceptable apparently.
Ok.
Ok. Go on.
Well, just speaking of primes. Right.
And, and I do have to admit in an aesthetic sense,
like most towels do look nicer folded into thirds
rather than halves because you get that nice,
sort of doubled over effect.
It's true.
Is that
-- more of a golden ratio?
-- Right. Right.
And that was going to be my question, is that because it's a prime,
or is it like one of the Fibonacci type series numbers?
Which is
my
-- golden ratio type deal?
-- Right. Right. Which I
guess ironically the first couple of Fibonacci numbers
are primed but regardless it doesn't matter.
So.
Right.
Nothing happened this week. Right.
Um, nothing of terrible.
I honestly,
you know, I think part of it is,
things have to be so bad before I even notice them anymore.
Yes, I feel the same way. I feel like everything is just so on fire at this point.
Like, eh, whatever.
Yeah, I can't think of any massive data breaches.
I mean, the, the, the,
the sort of one of the biggest on and this is
an ongoing train wreck is that classic bit of legislation about,
you know, allowing companies to hack back.
Oh,
my goodness. That thing
-- go away.
-- But the thing is, it's,
I think the problem is
if you think of the internet as a series of tubes, that makes sense.
But the pro
right
is that, you know, these,
uh, I
mean,
we don't even allow this in the physical world.
Like you can't, for example, rig up a shotgun on a trip wire in your house because,
like, what if there's a fire and some poor fireman comes in?
Yes. Right. So, we have well established doctrine in the real world
of, there are like, very
strict limits even in jurisdictions where, like,
um,
what do you have? It's called Castle Doctrine, right?
Where your home is your castle and, like,
you are legally allowed to shoot people coming in
and in some jurisdictions, I know
you're even allowed to shoot people in the back when
they're fleeing if they've taken your property because you,
you're allowed to, you know, essentially recover your property.
Um,
I live in Canada. So that's really not the case here.
We're, we're like, no, in Canada we're not allowed
to, to do these things. Right.
It's, we're expected to essentially, our strategy is to flee.
You know, you're not allowed to stand your ground.
That's not a valid defense if you murder somebody in your house.
I mean, you can try but it's, it's not like the US where it's
in some places. That's ok. Great. You know, done deal
even in the physical world,
even in the jurisdictions where we do allow that sort of attack back scenario.
It's still incredibly limited,
right?
And, uh, like a great example that's actually somewhat applicable is drones,
Uh, those people flying drones over other people's properties.
Well, you can't just
get out your skeet shotgun and start blasting away.
I mean, you can, but you shouldn't.
Um, and actually this week you put in the show
there was actually wire. Was it wired?
Did a really there was a little, uh, company that did, um,
a review of some anti drone technologies and one of them was actually,
that works. Surprisingly all was a 12 gauge shotgun shell with like a little net net
that you shot at the drone and it tangled up the rotors and,
you know, wall out
and is that legal?
It depends where you live
here.
My general understanding is, is that shooting any firearm in the city is, you know,
frowned upon
heavily
for some reason.
Well,
I'm not even legally allowed to use air pellet guns or bow and arrow in the backyard,
which I'm kind of angry about.
But whatever, I don't know,
windows
-- and
-- other
-- people I live in the US, I'm sure I can do whatever I want.
But I mean, you know, in a dense urban area,
it kind of maybe makes sense not to be using like a 400 pound crossbow
in a suburban neighborhood, one would think.
But so this hack back idea, even in the physical world where we have some very,
you know, things are, I mean,
for example, if somebody's waddling out your front door with a 32 inch TV,
you know, chances are they didn't accidentally get the wrong house.
You know, there are some TV,
repairman who got the wrong house and the door was unlocked and I,
well, you know, this TV is broken.
-- So like I'm just taking it out to the truck to take it to the shop to fix it. Right.
-- Like
I, I found it on the ground.
Right.
Exactly.
Yeah. So,
and then we enter the cyber
world. Oh, God, I hate that word.
-- But anyways we enter the, you know, the online cyber world where,
-- like,
I'm going to say it now,
cyber one and as much as I hate it, like it just, it, it won and we have to use it and it's,
it is what it is.
Yeah.
Yeah. Exactly. Right. Remember cracking and hacking how that was like a huge thing.
And you know what I've given,
I gave up on cracking a long time ago and I gave up on Cyber a long time ago.
Cyber 10, well,
well, language evolves. Right.
So, in the cyber world, you know,
just because host a attacks me doesn't mean the person
who actually owns host a is involved at all other than
they maybe have a poorly secured system
or somebody spoofed them.
Right. Because Lord knows we've never had, you know, d
OS amplification attacks where you spoof
a
target
-- and get them slammed. Right.
-- I think it's even more, more simple than that.
The fact is
when, when somebody hacks you, it's not like if, if I'm coking your Pepsi,
that Pepsi is gonna hack you from their corporate network.
Right. That's not how this works,
you know?
And I think that's what people don't realize. It's not like
if Russia is hacking
the
United States, it's really easy to track down an attacker,
which is truth, the attacker is really not savvy.
But if the attacker is that not savvy,
-- chances are their attacks not going to be successful.
-- Right. Exactly. Exactly.
Or it's, it's the kind of thing where it's like, I'm sorry, but, you know,
somebody just randomly emails corporate execs saying
please pay this invoice to this bank account
and then,
and then what do you do? You hack them back? Like I know, let's hack the bank, right?
It's the bank's fault. Let's, let's get that.
Well, that actually raises a good point.
You know what if the attacker uses some offshore
bank to transfer millions of dollars out and,
and that's part of where this whole hacking thing then really starts to fall apart.
Ignoring, let's ignore the fact. It's a terrible idea.
But let's, let's just for a moment, think about the practicalities of it. Right?
Like
what, you know, the, the most recent bill talks about not hitting intermediaries.
Ok, good. So, like I'm not allowed to hack, you know,
the I SPS between him and me or whatever. Right.
Well, or not, not allowed. It's, it's, it's,
you're not supposed to, you're supposed to avoid that,
you know.
Um, so, yeah, what if the end point is a bank and I want to get my money back from them
then I guess
I, I guess
that that seems to be the answer,
-- you know,
-- and of course, my favorite scenario in all of this is, you know, um, ok,
who's, there's Coke and Pepsi, who's the third one?
Uh, we're going to go with a w root beer.
I
think they're separate. I don't know.
But for the sake of argument
a and w root beer is hell bent on world domination.
So they break into Pepsi and, or Coke or both
and then attack the other one from their corporate network and, you know,
they essentially, you get this like mutually assured destruction,
standoff scenario.
Yeah. No, I, I know it. It's kind of like that false flag concept when you're
dealing with espionage,
make things better. Even if it works, it won't make things better.
You know, I think that's really the most important point, isn't it?
Is, you're right.
Even if, even if the bad guys always attacked from their correct place of origin
and even if we could properly attribute this stuff with, with 0%
failure,
-- what is it gonna, it isn't going to fix anything?
-- You're right. Yeah.
Well, so best case scenario, let's say you delete all their data, all their backups,
you delete everything they stole and you break their systems.
Cool. But like they can be back up running in 12 hours,
12 hours, like 15 minutes.
Right?
It take a while for the Amazon delivery guy to come back, you know,
new
laptops
one hour delivery man. Come on.
-- Yeah.
-- True.
So, you know, and that's the problem. Right.
Is, I think these people are also basing this on the fact that, like,
with traditional sort of crime and war,
when you do an attack, you sort of consume a whole bunch of stuff.
Right. And that's not how the whole cyber thing works. That's kind of why,
that's the impression I get where I, I feel like these are people trying to apply
real world principles to the cyberspace. I see what I did there
to cyber
and,
and they do not understand how things work and like, you know what this is,
what I always think of it. This
is,
is like in the, in the
there's comedy movies and things where they, you know, they, they're like, oh,
you know, I have the file or something, you know, it's like it's not
right or, or, or,
or they, they, they steal the document, you know, it's like I have the only copy.
It's like, no, you don't, you know,
you can't prove that and they probably had backups.
It's just like a man.
It's funny in a comedy movie.
This is real life.
Well, like every time there's like the black male scenario where it's like, OK,
we'll return the, the photos and the negatives,
you can copy negatives,
you've been able to do that since forever. It's called a camera.
No, I know. I know. And it like,
oh
anyways
um so yeah, anyways, this whole hack back thing is just such a train wreck. And
I don't think it'll ever get implemented.
Here.
Here's the thing I keep thinking of and let's
ignore the fact that it just can't be implemented.
But
-- there
-- are,
well,
I think it basically they have to be seen to be
doing something and this is a piece of legislation that all,
like, unsophisticated people think that they understand and think is a good idea.
So it's, they're seen to be doing something and then when it doesn't pass, you know,
which anybody's policymaker who's clued into their underlings is going to be like,
oh, thank God, it didn't pass.
But they can be like, oh, it didn't pass because Xy and Z those, you know, blah, blah,
blah and then, you know,
but they seem to be doing something and they're not on the hook when it
doesn't pass, you know,
-- but you know
-- what, you know what I wonder what if it does pass?
The thing is, it would be so easy to manufacture excuses to hack other people
because by definition, if you're a bad guy,
you're going to hack into that person and then use them to hack into
your legitimate company and then your legitimate company can
hack them back for whatever gain and legally legitimate.
-- But
-- then I'm wondering, like,
are there going to be consultancies that set up hack back
groups? Like,
but those already exist?
Like they're just not well known. I mean,
there are groups that will do things that are, you know, questionable legality
for money,
you know. So those, that, that capability and that, well, let's face it.
Penetration testing. Except,
ok, you're paying us to hack you now you're paying us to hack them
like that. Literally, it's like
please write down the domain name. You want us to hack?
Oh, that's not your domain name. 00, ok.
I'm gonna need a log file showing that they are, they part scanned you once?
That's the other beauty. Yeah. What do you count as a cyber attack?
Like, like login attempts? Because if I check my SSH logs for login attempts.
Well, I don't see any because it's firewalled. But
if it were open to the world, I would see, I'm assuming 10 to 100 attempts.
-- I,
-- I have a system that, that is running SSH D
and
I have it set up so you can only log in with a key
and I've quit reading the log because it's such a train wreck.
And I'm like, at the same time,
I know there's a million bots trying to log in constantly.
And what am I going to do about it right there. There's nothing I can't. Well,
that's right.
-- I'll log into their systems because
-- the thing to remember
too is a lot of these devices that are scanning,
for example, remember like the Marai bot
net, you can hack it back and hose them and break them and make the attack go away.
But, you know, at what point? Like here's the problem. Right.
A lot of that is gonna,
well, there's the innocent bystander problem of, you know,
my IP camera got hacked it in turn, tried to hack other stuff.
Somebody went into my IP camera and bricked it. I figured out who it was.
Do I now wish to attack them back?
Right.
Like an eye for an eye and the whole world goes
blind is literally the scenario potentially that we're looking at.
Yes.
You know, do I have to go get like a is it like um oh, what are those old things like,
do I have to go to the government?
Get like a letter of mark so I can go, you know, be a privateer and like enforce
law in the cyber realm and hack people or you know,
does is just anybody allowed to do this and if comes up in court,
you just have to have some paperwork to show like, hey, look,
here's a bunch of log files I printed out totally legit, you know,
showing that these IP s hacked me because as the other guy,
how do I prove I didn't attack him.
I really hope I can register as a cyber privateer,
right?
And we can go after the cyber pirates.
Yeah, I mean, manufacturing fake attacks
is easy in the sense of you just create like
you just do a real attack from somebody else.
I know, man,
the whole thing is just so bad and like, where does it stop? That's the other thing.
Right. Like, so,
you know, Coke sees Pepsi hacking them, do they then in turn, get to hack
Pepsi or are they supposed to go? Like, oh, Pepsi's trying to hack us.
We must have done something bad
and, and. Right. Well, I'm sure history has shown us that feuds always end well.
Right.
And this is one of the biggest arguments for, you know,
the state holding a monopoly on violence
is so that the state has the monopoly on violence.
And hopefully things like bureaucracy go slow enough that we don't have, you know,
wild excesses of said use of force.
Right.
So we'll just, you know, the, the cyber unit of the FBI hack back for us. Right.
Yeah, because if you look at, like, if you go online and look at any of those, like,
online witch hunt things, they almost always go wrong.
They got the wrong person or speak up innocent people or
like the, the Las Vegas shooter thing with the guy's girlfriend.
I, you know, I don't know what the deal with that is anymore, but the point is like
that had the potential to go horribly, horribly wrong with some, you know,
crazy person.
Oh, yeah. No, I, I know, I know. Whatever.
I guess my, my parting thought here is vigilante justice isn't justice. Right?
Hacking back or whatever. It just the world
cannot function
-- in a society run by vigilantes more
-- to the point. It won't make things better.
It would make them at best. Nothing would change.
But the reality is, it would probably make it worse.
It's one of those classic things where it's like,
why are we arguing about whether or not this thing is something that should be done
when it's clear that this thing won't
help,
it won't make things better. Right. That, that's what really frustrates me about.
This whole hack back thing is like,
fundamentally, even if you get really awesome legislation and even if you,
like you said,
you get a 0% false positive rate and even if
you hack the bejesus out of all these Attackers,
-- that's not gonna make a big difference.
-- No, no, it won't matter. And I guess,
well, this is one of the challenges with
anytime you have technology in government I think is
I, I don't know where this is coming from. Exactly.
And I don't think anybody really understands, but like this thing just won't die.
It's the same thing with encryption backdoors, right?
Like these, these concepts won't die even though they are totally impractical.
And unfortunately, the lawmakers, like, they don't have a clue, they don't know.
-- It is
-- pretty,
there are some really sophisticated reasons as to why these
things fundamentally don't work because it sounds like on paper.
Ok? You have encryption, that's like a key. Ok? Why can't we have backdoor keys.
Right. Right.
Right there. Now for you to
unpack that and explain it properly, we, well,
we need another two hour show at least.
Right.
You know, I was talking to somebody about signing code and they're like, well,
why don't we just automate signing code?
I'm like, yes, we can definitely do that
and that will accomplish almost nothing. He's like,
well, Bonobo, we'll have signed code and I'm like,
yes, we will have signed code. But what does that signature mean or represent?
He's like, what do you mean?
I'm like,
does that signature mean that we've verified the code that we validated it,
that we confirmed?
There's no flaws in it. And he's like,
yeah, couldn't we do that? And I'm like, no, because there's too much great,
right?
You know, like we can't like Ruby gems.org or whatever, pp you know,
50 to 100,000 gems or
Python modules or whatever, right? Like,
and even, you know,
no offense to all the good security teams that do audit their code.
These guys still have
like open BS D still have security flaws.
Oh,
yeah.
No, there's,
there's never going to be a way around security
flaws as long as humans are writing code.
I mean, I think that's, that's kind of one of the things you have to,
you
-- have to accept, I
-- suspect even with a is and computers writing code,
even with formal proofs
that show the system is correct that also assumes
that the system's purpose and design was correct.
Sure.
You know what I'm saying is you can
have semantically correct code that implements a logic problem
or just fundamentally
does something that turns out
was a really bad idea.
No, it's, it's certainly a possibility.
Yes. Yes. Well, ok. So, you know, you know, what you made me think of here is
I had some, I had some discussions about this.
I was in Germany last week for some meetings and
there were various security topics that, that came up.
And one of the things that kept happening was we would say,
you know, we let's talk about this feature
and co signing is a great example because it's actually one of the features.
And then of course,
you can pull calls every which way into this idea of why are we signing it and
how are we signing it and how are we protecting keys and what are we doing?
And there's like 400 layers to this.
But then, and, and people hated it when I always ask questions,
what's the actual problem we're trying to solve here? Right?
Like what are we actually protecting against?
And I think code signing is a great example where
if the intent is to say, like
I built this thing
in my BUILD system,
then you're OK.
And you can say that it doesn't mean it's trustworthy, it doesn't mean it was built,
right?
It doesn't mean it doesn't have security issues.
It just means this is the thing I built,
right?
Because there are countless examples of people, you know,
hacking into code signing systems or back door something before it gets signed or,
you know what I mean?
It doesn't solve all the problem
or just buying code signing
it solves
a
bad stuff.
And, and this is one of those examples where
you need to really understand what you are doing
and what your security solution is actually solving because
it's generally something extremely narrow.
But it's easy to think that. Ok, so Josh signed this code. So it's secure.
Like no, no, it is not
in no way. Should you infer that?
But it's also hard to explain to people what that mean.
Well, I mean, we have the same problem with CV E and the, you know, what is a CV?
I mean, well, in theory, it's supposed to mean that this is a vulnerability.
And I mean, to be honest,
we don't always validate every vulnerability as being actually exploitable.
You know, if you come to me and show me a good null point or D ref in the Linux kernel,
my response more often than not is here's your CV E,
I'm not gonna make you actually write an exploit code that
exploits it because quite frankly,
that's a total pain
and
probably it's possible, you know, it's more to the point,
let's just fix this move on.
-- So how many
-- CV S have exploits, what, maybe 10% maybe.
Uh I think it's like 30 or 40.
-- Oh, really? That's way higher than I expected.
-- Well,
-- not,
-- well, but
you got to remember too.
A lot of this is really low hanging fruit,
like stuff like cross site scripting exploits
or, you know,
uh The, the definition
is like, um, it says it enforces password security X and it does not,
you know, so it's not that there's an exploit per se,
but there's like a stated security property that that is then not done.
Um
Or you know,
the the issue is so trivially exploitable that you don't need exploit code,
right? Like
I've had ones where it's like it just
like I remember this one,
it's just like it calls this temporary file and runs at his root.
Oops,
that is great. So if that file is present, it'll just get executed
aru you know. Oops.
Um Now granted that the scenario for actually exploiting this is pretty tricky but
you know,
um
Yeah, most,
well and a lot of CV S like there's no way we can validate these things because we
don't have access to these commercial products or especially
as we move into like the internet of things.
-- I don't want to have 764 IP cameras in my
-- basement. Super
exciting, man.
I
-- think my kids would love that.
-- Here's, here's the bigger part of it though.
And this is actually a really good example is who cares?
Right? Who cares if you can prove it is an exploit or not?
I think just having a reference.
Well, you do want to keep out the noise
because we do actually just now have an example of a researcher who's
spamming hundreds of CV U requests and they are of incredible low quality.
The majority are probably garbage.
And when he's asked for more details,
he doesn't come up with them or even the
reference links end up getting deleted and stuff.
So it's pretty clear that this guy is
not doing quality work,
possibly trying to abuse
the system.
You know, because that's clearly
a
well, exactly. We're just going to ban him until he shapes up
because, you know, in the open source world, my life is a bit easier in that.
I'm like, OK, I don't believe you your request.
So like show me the vulnerable code and explain it
like I'm five.
And if you can't do that, you know, to quote Einstein,
you probably don't understand the problem very well.
I will man, how many people just run like crappy scanner
-- and then copy and paste the results.
-- Oh, it's the worst is not the scanners.
It's the fuzz
here. I found this crash exploit.
Cool it crashes. Yeah, I have no idea if that's exploitable or not. More the
point. I'm not going to figure it out.
I remember when people would do that.
I, I haven't looked at anything like this in years.
But when they'd send over, you know, here's 2000 PDF s that crash
X PDF.
It's like, well, ok, and then they said, well, yeah, these are exploitable.
It's like,
no, they're not.
Maybe one or two of them are and, and I remember you'd end up with like,
two legitimate bugs
and after, like,
the poor people that did the real work and then these bozos would get the credit
that just, they ticked me off to no end.
Yeah, that's one reason, I don't know.
I'm kind of on the one hand,
I like giving attribution to the person who requested the CV,
because more to the point if there's an issue with the CV,
then you can figure out who asked for it and you can go
poke them with a stick and figure out kind of what happened,
hopefully.
But at the same time there's a reason there's no credit in CV, in the official CV.
Database is because, I mean, that's just not,
it's just that something people do try to gain and it, it will end up being a mess.
And part of me too would like to see actually more credit given for the people
who came up with the code patch or tested it or actually ship the fix.
Yes, I agree.
Fixing it is the heroes are the ones who are doing the actual fixing in a lot of cases.
Now that said though,
I know like when, when project Zero reports issues, they often come with a patch
which is super cool and that's totally the right way to do it.
Well, I mean, implicit, well, the majority of code is not so complicated, but
-- once you understand the security flaw, you can't
-- actually, however, I will say so,
I've,
I've produced many security patches in my day
and I would bet you
less than 10 of them out of probably more than 100 were accepted
because in the vast majority of instances I would
fix like the security issue because it was missing,
say, you know, a check on a return value or something.
When in reality, the problem was somewhere else because it was doing, you know,
some incorrect calculation, three functions up from where I was at.
And that's where actually working with the open source project
is huge because they understand what their application is doing.
Whereas in my case, like
I was seeing
the one line that was causing the problem. That was my obsession.
Yeah.
Yeah. And that's fair. And I mean, at least,
uh but like I said,
the majority of these fixes are not so complicated or terrible that, you know,
they can't be done by another party.
But yeah, it is generally well, and I've also seen ones where they're like,
oh thank you for pointing that out.
The patch is good. But what we're actually going to do is you know, this patch that
also fixes Xy and Z and cleans up the photo.
Definitely,
you know, or the ever classic,
we're not going to fix the code.
We're removing that feature because it's a terrible,
like,
assuming you're not using that feature.
I've been in a situation where we have a, you know,
had a product that used that feature
so we couldn't just blindly remove it.
Um,
not for a while anyways.
Um, but yeah, so it's, yeah. No, it's, it's, it's definitely tough. So,
well,
one thing I did see last week was a
couple of interesting articles on sort of attack detection.
Explain the context here.
So the idea is,
well, let's be blunt, if somebody targets you to hack you, they will win
unquestionably pretty much as long as they have enough budget. Right?
If I give you a budget of $7 maybe not to give you a budget of $700,000.
Chances are you're gonna get it somehow,
you know, man,
you could go a long way in seven bucks, I bet.
Just saying. Uh,
yeah, it's like three packs of gum
and people. Oh, yeah.
No, people were willing to give up their passwords for candy bars in the UK.
Remember they did that study a few years ago.
Hopefully they get fake passwords. I really do hope. But anyways, um,
so this one was a, it's a,
it's a company that basically makes like a whole bunch of
fake sort of end points on your servers and networks.
So they make like a whole bunch of fake file shares and stuff like that.
That essentially if they're ever accessed then you
-- know that it's
-- like honey pot type something.
It basically, yeah, it's like automated honey potting.
Um, with just the idea being that like, oh, you know,
uh your regular users aren't gonna be end map scanning
your network and looking for funky services to connect to,
they're just gonna be trying to get their job
done talking to what they need to talk to.
The Attackers will be the ones, you know, and mapping it and like,
oh, hey, there's something on port 80 here. Let's go poke at it. Right.
Yeah.
And then another one that's similar to this is um from Atlassian. It's open source.
And the idea is actually pretty elegant in that.
Uh one of the things people look for nowadays is uh Amazon web service, you know,
um access keys and tokens, right?
Because if you get those,
then you have access to their computer resources and you can run stuff.
And so the idea is you basically create a whole pile of fake and by fake, I mean,
they're actually real
Aws tokens, but they're like attached to an account or a system that essentially
should never be used, right? And then you can use the various
Aws tooling or I guess you could use your own
to monitor them for usage and then you scatter these fake keys around your systems,
your code, your say docs
and you know, then if somebody uses those keys,
-- you know what part of your system has been breached by a bad guy.
-- I love these ideas.
I think this makes total sense because
let's face it. You're never going to create an infrastructure that's
impervious to
penetration by a bad guy
and
tools like this. Help you understand that?
All right, it's happened guys like time to go.
-- Well,
-- it's, it's that motion sensor sort of tripwire idea of, you know.
Yeah, you know,
you've been breached and ideally now you have an idea of where and how to some degree,
you know, and you can start the, the clean up
and removal
statistic.
The average attacker has something like 300 days before they're detected.
I mean, the number is insane.
Now, granted there's, this is kind of a double edged blade
because if you do this,
the bad guys are like, like let's say you implement this, then you say, hey, look,
I I rolled out project spacecraft in my infrastructure like for example, I lass
and no doubt has done this. So the bad guys know to watch out for this.
Right?
Well, but on the flip side too, that means that maybe they don't use your real
Aws keys to access your real Aws resources.
Maybe it's maybe I'm, I'm not going to say yes or no,
-- but like for example, oh, there's
-- definite overhead with this.
That's the biggest thing I'd be worried about is the overhead and
-- if there are false positives
-- and there will be right, there's totally going to be.
But at the same time, I think this is a fantastic idea.
Well, it kind of reminds me of that whole,
that guy that had a system that responded to all spam
and started to use Markov chaining to generate replies and, you know,
suck up these spammers time and that they would, you know,
because like sort of that spammers, you know,
the first level is all automated and then as you kind of get deeper and deeper into it,
it gets more and more human, right?
Because,
you know,
you're actually talking to a person and trying
to convince them to give up like 100 grand
for whatever reason, right?
And luckily most people aren't stupid enough that
they'll fall for like automated scripted stuff.
You know, you do need a little bit of a human touch.
So the guy's idea was essentially to have an A I waste spammer time,
you know, by saying, yeah, I'm super interested in this. Tell me more.
OK. That sounds totally awesome.
Can you please explain this detail or, you know, whatever, right?
I love that.
-- That's because at
-- some point, the Attackers,
I'm not going to say have infinite resources, but I mean,
they have nearly infinite resources sort of on the front end
but on the back end they, they're, they're people just like us.
It is true.
You know, it, it kind of reminds me of the whole Wikileaks thing and that,
you know, great.
You know, I just got like, how many hundreds of gigabytes of whatever,
of classified stuff?
-- Ok. Now I have to have, like, humans read through them.
-- Uh, speaking of that,
did you know that the JFK assassination documents are to be released in
it at the end of October?
Oh the end of October. Yeah, I was wonder when that would
-- happen
-- a couple of days, probably after this comes out and
-- think about that
-- man.
And of course, the conspiracy theorist to me says, of course,
they would say that and release some sort of documents that are f
whatever
the point being that you know,
they're going to release like a mountain of crap and then
how are people going to get through it? Right. It's gonna be crazy.
-- Well,
-- crowd
source, there will be a subreddit dedicated to weeding through these documents.
-- Yeah,
-- I don't know. It's,
yeah, the whole thing, I mean,
I would like to think if there was somebody evil and competent
enough to actually pull that off in some sort of grand conspiracy sense
that they would probably also be able to
monkey with the documentation and stuff that was
after the
fact, the
reality
of
it
is
the human beings cannot keep secrets
right? There is basically nothing
that has happened ever in history. That has truly been a secret.
Right. It always leaks guarantee.
Like
if this was an actual conspiracy,
it would have been leaked
years ago.
-- Right.
-- Exactly.
You know,
-- I love that one.
-- I love the Michelin Webb fake moon landing
where basically they,
they determine it would cost more to fake the moon
landing than it would be to go to the moon.
Yeah.
Well, probably would cost more because you have to pay off so many people
that I read some guy did this analysis of the moon landing and basically said,
like the technology to fake this literally did not exist
in 1969. Like,
even if you had infinite money, you couldn't have done it.
There was just no way.
It's, yeah.
Anyway.
Well, I feel like a lot of security is like that,
you know, like,
like this whole password thing where we're trying to debunk all these, you know,
even the guy who came up with these recommendations is now like, I'm so sorry,
please don't do this
and trying to get that sort of people to wrap their head around it.
Like, ok, you know,
password security is a lot less important than
say you having proper two factor authentication,
right? But I, I think about this a lot actually is
we think we can understand password security,
something like passwords with lots of characters seems to make sense to us and
things like changing your password every two weeks seems to make sense to us.
But the reality is the data proves that's wrong.
Right.
And we know that something like
two factor authentication makes probably more difference
in the security for normal people than anything else you can do.
But as security people,
we still obsess over all these crazy things that don't really matter and,
and the thing I keep coming back to is just the fact that
we don't measure anything we do, the vast majority of security is cargo,
cult security.
And,
and it's one of those things that let's say you're
going to turn on some security feature for your organization,
find a metric,
measure it before you do it and then measure it after you do it
and look if, if it doesn't help, like you have to be willing to give up.
And I think we suck at that.
Well, great example is in Canada.
Um What do you think our laws are like around uh disclosing data breach?
Do you have laws?
Correct?
-- Yes,
-- that is the correct answer.
That's voluntary, self
-- reporting.
-- We all know has never failed society
ever once.
Yeah,
because we're just going through a bit of a stink right now where a
bunch of uh people are beginning to realize that a lot of companies like,
for example, well, TD uh bank
has started outsourcing things like the fraud
to
people in foreign countries, like the uh the, the, the fraud, um
uh detection office and dealing with fraud.
You know, as a customer, traditionally, you dealt with people in Canada,
but of course, call center people.
Well, I hate to say it, but chances are, you know, we're chasing that
dollar down to the bottom of the barrel. So
that stuff's being outsourced, you know, to, um, I think it was in this case, India
and of course, t D's response is, well,
in our cardholder agreement and in all these agreements,
we do have that your data may be processed in foreign countries.
And of course,
as a consumer, I can't make a truly informed decision because I, I,
-- if I had to guess I would say all of these contracts,
-- say that.
Yeah, that phone book,
what did I just do the other day? I, I don't even remember now.
It was, I was using some service
and they made me, it was one of those scroll to the bottom before you can hit,
accept sort of things that I remember.
It was like,
it must have been
100 pages and I'm like,
no human is going to read this.
I remember that like I couldn't and paste some of
them into word docs just to see what was like,
how big it was.
Yeah, 100 pages or 100 screens
come on. Nobody even lawyers probably give up after a little while.
Here's the best part.
I also got a credit card from another bank.
Never actually signed anything.
I was mailed a copy of the cardholder agreement that basically said by like,
using this credit card, you agree to this, you know,
it was like five or six pages of really tiny print.
But I actually never s like, physically signed anything because I was like, I,
I remember leaving the bank and getting home and I'm like, wait a minute.
Oh, I gotta go back and sign something. Right, Because
that's usually how bank stuff works, right? You sign things.
So,
yeah. Well, apparently not anymore.
So, yeah, I mean, this whole thing is like,
how am I supposed to have really informed consent?
Especially when. Yeah, I mean,
you know, what did that guy point out?
Like,
if you actually hired a lawyer to read through all
the agreements you deal with on a daily basis,
it would be tens of millions of dollars.
So,
yeah, I don't know.
I don't know what the takeaway for this show is
other than maybe looking into stuff like space crab.
Which awesome name, by the way.
Yeah. No, it is. I agree.
Um, and like those decoy servers, you know, the other thing I always love was, uh,
like Decoy records in the database,
right?
You have Decoy records in the database and then have your,
uh I DS system looking out for,
you know, the, whatever alphanumeric strings and stuff or 123 F street.
Because, yeah, I think fundamentally at this point.
It's, it's more about like if you can,
like if you can detect,
uh you may not
detect the attack. But for example, if you can detect the data x filtration
in near real time and then ideally block it,
hey, that's, well as eco
facts learned, that would have been a good thing.
Yeah. No kidding, man.
Oh,
I know. I know exactly what you mean.
May maybe that, that's where we ended is, is what the parting thought of the fact that
we spend a lot of time obsessing over
making things right?
And making it Impenetrable when in reality, I suspect detection
and, and what's the old saying? Like an ounce of prevention?
It's worth a pound of cure or something.
But in reality,
uh prevention
is going to fail us.
Whereas detection is something we,
we do understand and we know we can do something with it.
So,
-- yeah, I, I, well,
-- remediation,
I mean,
you know, um most buildings either have a, you know, well,
most buildings now by code have a sprinkler system, right?
We don't want to burn them down, but
it happens.
No, I agree. I agree. You know.
All right, cool, man. I'm gonna, I'm gonna call it. So, thank you, Kurt. Thank you
for, for listening.
If you want the show notes, you can go to open source security podcast.com.
Hit us up on Twitter with the Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag You can join our Facebook group and have a chat and yeah, if nothing else,
I guess Kurt, you have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too, thanks.