Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in not writing legislation.
-- Josh Pressers,
-- were those pauses on purpose or they just weird
slammed into a brick wall and I was like,
what is this called again? I'm like, I should know this, but
-- apparently I don't.
-- It's fine.
Yes,
we're going to talk about the exciting topic of legislation
today which I'm sure all of us are riveted for
and more specifically the E ID
A
S
and E ID, which are separate things.
So E ID A S is like the UK thing. E ID is the European Union thing,
but they're basically the same thing. The idea is
no, the,
the Mozilla website says the recent changes to E U's new E ID A
S regulation will dramatically expand the capability
of eu governments to surveil the citizens.
So basically E ID is the digital ID, the thing and the EIE
ID A s are the services.
-- OK. Right.
-- So a perfect example here in Alberta
and in Canada,
um in Alberta, we have a uh my digital ID that we can use with the government,
for example, to renew our drivers or to update our driver's license information.
Uh renewal is done through a registry of which is a private company typically.
Um But more importantly, for example,
my health link I can access through that so I can
see all my test results and like my prescriptions and everything.
It's quite lovely.
And so for example,
because it's the provincial government providing this and doing this,
they piggyback off of either your driver's license,
Alberta identity card or passport.
And then they send you a pin code in the mail
to make sure you actually live there and you know,
boom, you got your digital ID.
Interesting.
And so for example, at the federal level, when I interact with revenue, Canada,
they use the banks.
So for example, when you go to revenue Canada to log in,
you get a choice of a of a essentially a trusted authentication partner.
And it's like all the banks, there's like 20 banks
with the assumption that if they go to TD and are
like this person claims to be curtsey free date of birth X
is this
and I logged into my TD bank account and say, you know,
approve the authentication request that the bank has done their uh KYC,
they know your customer regulations.
And so TD is essentially a trust ID entity because they're a regulated bank
and they can say that yes, this is indeed curtsey free date of birth
after that very long explanation.
-- What are we talking about?
-- So, the idea is this all sucks.
This is terrible because what you really want is something like Estonia
where you have a card with a smart chip and that's you.
And here's the clever thing Estonia did. That is so beyond brilliant.
When they originally set all this up, they made a rule.
The government can only ask you for
that piece of identification or information once
and once they've asked you another department that wants it can't.
So they have to share and it forced all their
systems to be compatible and to share and to interoperate
with.
Because how many times have you gone to a government
office and had to refill all your information every time?
All right. So what is Europe doing?
I'm not super, I only know about the Mozilla website that I'll put in the show notes.
But so the problem is E ID
as an idea I think is good. The problem is
they slipped something into the legislation
that is worrying to say the least. And that worrying piece is, is that they can force
vendors like browser vendors
to install a root certificate, whether they like it or not.
Now, ostensibly this is so that for example, they can have, well,
if you look at the root certificate list that is widely accepted, you know,
the one that's
all over the place. Let's start at the beginning.
So Europe wants to create one electronic ID for the entirety of the EU.
Is that an accurate statement?
That is part of what they want?
That's,
that's the tip of the
iceberg.
But now the reason we're talking about this is
there is a website that I read from Mozilla
talking about
the, this
A,
I don't know how to pronounce it. E ID A S
law
that no one has seen yet
because it's not written
well. OK.
But we know it's going to include some sort of language talking about
a magic route C A
that would let the European Union
Regulators basically de decrypt any browser traffic
-- they want. Is that all accurate so far?
-- No
ish sort of kind of, it's, it's one of those,
technically, it's potentially true, but
-- it's very complicated which is show content where they
-- can't decrypt it,
they have to man in the middle of it.
Right. Yes, exactly.
Ok. Ok. Well, basically
they would be able to force root certificates into the browsers and devices
normally the way it works is you have to ask nicely
and it
takes
what is a root certificate?
Why do we care about this?
So the way web browsers work is we have public key encryption.
Cool.
-- Right.
-- How do I know this thing from walmart.com is, in fact
walmart.com and not a man in the middle presenting a certificate they signed.
Does walmart.com?
Well, we have a trusted third party sign it
and that trusted third party has a certificate that they,
you basically, I'm going to grossly simplify,
but the trusted third party has a certificate
that is the public key is registered with your browser.
You know, in trust Faris, sign all the usual suspects
and then they use their private key
to sign certificates. Like let's encrypt us. Right. Let's encrypt. That's
right.
It's not a root C A and this is where things are complicated. Like let's encrypt is a,
not a root certificate authority.
They're, you know, hanging off of a root authority,
but they're allowed to assign their own certificates.
So
there are a number of governments like uh I know Taiwan, I forget the rest.
I think Denmark
have government root certificate, authorities
that have a root certificate
widely accepted in, you know, Safari, Firefox edge brave
all domains or only certain domains.
OK.
So you're asking so in theory,
a certificate can have what are called restrictions placed on it.
And quite commonly,
the restrictions that are placed on it are like this can only sign web certificates,
this can sign email certificates, this can only sign code, signing certificates.
And there is the potential for restrictions based on domain
and I think there's one or two that use it. Oh, so not very many. OK.
-- Well, by not very many, I mean, there's, I think one or two
-- and how many certificates,
how many root certificates are in
-- a typical browser trust store?
-- About 100 and 40 to 100 and 50.
That seems like a lot.
No, it's actually not a lot because the thing is there are an unknown number of
entities like lets and
crypt
that are able to sign certificates. See, normally if I go to
Verisign and I say I want you to sign
cre.org,
they sign the certificate for seared.org and that certificate is limited to just
being
creed.org http S basically,
or I can use it on my email server for,
uh,
MTPTLS or whatever.
And I cannot use that certificate to further sign other certificates because
those
clients would look at it and be like, you're not allowed to do that.
I'm going to ignore this. Right. That's right.
And, but there are, I, I, I've heard numbers somewhere between maybe six and 8000
certificates floating around that can be used to sign more certificates
and some of them like l
encrypt are well known and very well behaved and are, like,
straight up if all the certificate, authorities could behave like LS and Crypt,
uh, we'd be much better off
well. And this is like when you use Amazon web services,
they can host TLS traffic for you.
They have this ability.
Yeah, they sign, yeah, exactly.
Yeah, they can,
yeah, they,
they can sign, uh, same with cloud flare. Cloud flare.
They
don't,
they don't have like cloud flare and Amazon don't have root certificates. Right.
-- I don't think so. They're, they're
-- ok.
Let's pretend they don't, for the sake of this conversation.
I think they're intermediate certificates.
Now, then there's a concept called the root of trust
where I say I have Kurt's certificate
that's signed by
Verisign certificate and that's signed by this other
certificate and that's in the root C A.
Yeah.
Or in this case, far
sign is the root
-- is one of the old granddaddy root. The
-- idea though.
And so that's the chain of trust.
So, having,
see the problem though is, is to get a root certificate in, takes like two years.
So that's,
and, and you're not guaranteed to, I mean,
-- you're pretty much
-- unless you pass a law that tells the browser manufacturers,
you have to include their certificate
and to be clear,
the number of people that fail to get
their root certificate in is quite minuscule and
they have to be grossly inadequately insecure like
two of the ones that got booted were
-- you've pointed this out in the past and it's hilarious
-- and like,
like this one was using a,
they were doing DNS lookups using a who is service that has on their front page.
Do not use this for anything that matters for security.
They were using a third party,
right? Or another one was signing certificates for
like you're only supposed to sign web certificates for host names
like cer.org or brester.net or whatever
breast.net. Sorry.
And they had signed certificates for IP addresses, which is very much a no, no.
And they have signed certificates for like, like words.
Awesome. Like, just a word.
Yeah.
Yeah. If you go check this, we can link to the cert.
I, I honestly, I was involved in the cert DB stuff on the mailing list and stuff again.
I was involved, like, 1015 years ago and I tried getting involved again a year ago
and I gave up again
because it's just so fundamentally broken.
I cannot
fix it or change it or have any.
And,
and the best part is like when uh there
was another researcher from an academic institution that like essentially
God to c A booted out because they were so insecure and bad.
And people are like, why did you do that? Why are you so mean to that company?
And it's like
we're not the bad guys here, like they're the bad guys anyways,
let's talk about what a
European Union
root certificate
kind of means for security and privacy of everybody.
-- Not just European citizens,
-- it means they can do whatever they want.
That's not.
-- Well, and this is where things get. So here's let me qualify
-- that.
-- OK. All
-- right.
So here's the thing we've already encountered this problem, right?
Remember we did that show with uh I want to say it was Kazakhstan,
the
man in the middle.
Yeah.
So
funnily enough.
There are a lot of nation states that have been trying to do this.
Well, not trying have been doing this for 1015 years.
And so there's a bunch of technologies to help prevent this. So,
so there are protections I can do, for example, I run s.org
and even if you as a client have a malicious certificate from, well Kazakhstan,
let's pick on them
I can use, for example, something called like essentially C A pinning where I say
the seared.org certificate should only ever be signed by these root certificates.
And I want to say it's like Komodo and something else,
it's whatever cloud flare uses because I use cloud flare.
And so even if Kazakhstan,
you know, does a man in the middle
signs a fake certificate for
cre.org
in theory, the browser should be like, hey, whoa time out
like the c.org,
it's signed by
Kazakhstan.
Not,
you know, Komodo,
that's bad. I'm not gonna let you go there.
-- And
-- I know like I think I believe Google does this as well and
a
lot of vs
do big companies.
Yeah,
it's not, I remember looking into it.
Uh and not a lot of people do it, but it's,
it's becoming more and more common because it's kind of,
it's like kind of like DNS se where
in cloud floor, at least it's like a button you push and it just works.
Right.
But it has to be that button that works, it doesn't
break.
So what this means
for
people on the internet is if the eu and my understanding is
this is like the typical we need to protect you from yourself,
sort of nonsense.
Right. No, no, no, this is legitimately. We need digital ID and I support digital.
How does digital ID have anything to do with
-- installing a root certificate in the browser
-- store?
How do you validate the digital I DS
in a web browser? How do you use them?
What
you don't need a certificate in the, in the root trust store to validate a digital ID.
Well, not
if I want to validate your digital ID. I need some way to get to the root
that signed your digital id.
And
the problem is I can always manually install that certificate,
but the government doesn't want to deal with that.
So they're like, we just want it jammed in there.
And that's,
that's literally why a lot of these
root certificate authorities that are not commercial.
So let, let's broadly break this up.
There are two kinds of certificate authorities at the root level.
There's commercial ones who want to sell certificates like
Verisign and Komodo.
And I'm also going to lump the service providers
in there like Amazon and cloud flare where they like
want to sign certificates, you know, for money purposes.
-- Ok. Hold on.
-- And then
there's the
government
stop, stop, stop.
-- And
-- see that's part of the problem is they technically don't need to do this.
Hold on.
If they put a certificate in the root store of my web browser,
all TLS traffic could be essentially the chain of trust could end up there.
So someone could man in the middle of me, right? With this root store
as opposed to, can't they restrict a certificate for only
signing data, for example,
although I guess this is signing data when you're doing that.
Oh
-- I hate all this stuff.
-- See, it gets complicated. This
is so stupid.
So the problem is fundamentally
the reason they want this is it will make their life slightly easier
and it will make the rest of our lives vastly probably, maybe not worse.
-- But maybe
-- my understanding from reading,
this is this was partially about being able to decrypt web traffic,
not solely about having the ability.
Well, there is a little, a bit of that. Yeah, there's a little bit of that
and, and look, 00 my goodness, this is so stupid.
This is even dumber than I thought it was.
Well,
it's the thing is if you have a nice piece of
legislation going forward that talks about digital identity and certificates,
why not slip in that little extra bit, you know, for law enforcement to kind of
have a look with the person
idiotic.
Ok.
So here's the problem for anyone who's made
it this far over this nonsensical journey of stupidity
is
if an entity
that will say has nefarious intent,
has access to a root certificate or that
-- certificate gets stolen because that does happen
-- and,
and well,
that will happen that 100% will happen in
this instance because the government is just there,
we've talked about this at length about like backing encryption technology,
it
is going to get lost or stolen or some other dumb thing is going to happen
where the key in question is going to make it
into the hands of someone who shouldn't have it 100%.
Especially because the traditional process is you have
to jump through a whole bunch of hoops,
get a security audit, blah, blah, blah.
And, and speaking of that, that's all garbage because for example,
there was one auditor who appears to be an
accountant who doesn't have any technical knowledge who signed
off on a whole bunch of these that were then later found to be run so badly,
they had to be booted out.
But for example, if you look at
finding out who audited these people and approve them,
number one is difficult and number two,
there's no way to verify the auditor even in Canada,
they had a registry of the auditors,
but then they kind of took it offline and hit it after an incident.
Of course they did. So that's the thing is like it
means any government of the, what is it?
I want to say, 29 countries, 27 countries, I always forget how many are in the United.
But any of them can use this. If this law passes as it is suggested, it will and it
formatted
they, you know,
some brand like Denmark or France or Germany
could be like here's a root certificate,
OK?
Browsers put this in or else
and there's no audit controls.
-- There's like we don't know if that certificate is protected. I
-- mean,
OK, but we're still not
talking about
the importance of this.
If this happens, let's say you've got a certificate put into the trust store
and the key leaks.
And now you have a nefarious individual with the certificate,
it gives them the ability to man in the middle web traffic
in a
mostly transparent way.
I know there's things like certificate pinning and all that kind of stuff,
which is important.
But this is,
this is just beyond dumb because it's the same thing as backdoor
like all of the encrypted chat programs which we, I know we did that show about it,
you cannot
backdoor and this is functionally a backdoor into the web browser.
You cannot backdoor technology
in a way that doesn't just make it insecure for literally everyone
or a new government comes along in four years and decides
that we really need to make sure everybody's not buying cigarettes online
or whatever governments change.
And so yeah, I mean, the problem is this is
a grossly
negative externality and the government's like, yeah, it's,
but it's not our negative externality.
Well, and so that's, this is what I've been thinking about
for the last couple of hours
is
this is completely
somebody else's problem.
Right. If I am a government and I,
first of all get to tell the web browsers you have to do this. That's not my problem.
Then
if a user gets popped because of my key leaked,
well, that's not my problem because it's the user's problem. And like
this is just uh uh this is like a giant freaking circus of not my problem.
Do me a quick favor. I've got an iphone, sadly,
go into certificates and remove one
fun fact.
Fun fact. No, no, it's better.
So in most web browsers like Firefox, Microsoft and Explorer,
you can go on market certificate is untrusted.
You can go manually essentially remove trust from it.
And if you do this for like 80% of the certificates in there,
you will not notice because like, I'm pretty sure here's a fun fact.
There's like over half a dozen
Turkish certificate authorities. That seems good. And I'm like,
I'm pretty sure if I disable them all, I will not notice.
-- And the answer is, yeah, I did not notice.
-- That would be interesting.
I should see if I can track the certificates. Like I actually hit,
ok, we can talk about that.
Uh The guy, the, the academic researcher out of Calgary has done that and
you can sort of track um activity in your cert database.
There's some ways to do it in Linux, for example, with um pie notifying anyway,
I've actually gone through this with somebody. So yes.
But long story short in newer versions of I OS, you can't,
the Trust store is the trust store and you cannot edit it.
I mean,
what are the legitimate reasons people have to edit the trust star
-- because I don't trust all these weird certificate authorities
-- in to.
But I'm saying like
-- the vast majority of people
-- but why take that away from me
because it's Apple Cart, you're holding it wrong, you do it their way.
-- Or else like it's not a debate
-- and there's also no easy, good way to kind of like
you can sort of do this on windows through group policy
objects and you can do certificates at the Os level,
but like Firefox and safari kind of do their own thing.
And so it gets
the long and the short of it is
saying to people remove the certificates you don't trust or blah, blah, blah,
that's not a solution anymore.
It's just not
that ship sailed and sunk.
So
the reality is this makes the government's life
a little bit easier for handling digital identity
and it makes it a lot easier if they want to do,
like I'm gonna say lawful intercept as the phrase uh that has been used for 20 years,
you know,
and, and,
and like, how is this?
Why wouldn't they,
if you're a government, why wouldn't you do this
-- because
-- you're going to make the world worse?
-- So again, why is the government would I not do this? But
-- no, no, no.
This is the difficulty of security and public policy is
the nuance behind it.
I'm sure we got loads wrong and by all means like
at Kurt on Mastodon and tell them all about it,
but like, I'm sure we got loads wrong
and
we're definitely more technical than probably most lawmakers.
I'm co I'm comfortable saying I am more technical than 99% of lawmakers.
-- It's probably higher than that. But trick
-- question, who
is the most important person in the certificate world?
-- There's a very simple answer.
-- Is there a person
-- Kathleen
-- Wilson who
-- is? I don't even know who that is.
-- Exactly.
She is the person at Mozilla that runs the root C A program
and Mozilla's Root C A program is essentially what everybody else piggybacks off of
and uses. I mean, it's technically now its own separate entity or TV, for
thing, but fundamentally
like she is the load bearing support beam in that XK CD Comic.
Um
And like straight up like she's been the person doing it for like going on 20 years.
But
I,
that's nuts.
Who's gonna do it?
And she's done a good
job
and to be
with
us,
she's done a good job. But it's, it's
what's wild to me is like, this seems like something that, you know,
a government should maybe spend a million bucks a year on funding.
-- But
-- look at how much, how much infrastructure
you look at,
you've got like open source runs the world. No one's funding that
you've got Mozilla, he handles the root C A is the time zone guy.
Like, there's so much stuff that's like
that, that I, so I, I took the, I, I'll, I'll put a link, I'll just put a link,
I'll maybe put it on as something.
But
I
think I gave a presentation
about like the state of open source to uh
I, I forget who it even was now.
But anyway, I took the XKC comic and I was like, you've all seen this comic, I fixed it
and I changed it from like the one thing on the side to just
one long line of like single package maintainers because that's really what it is.
Like all of this stuff is
there,
there's so many things that if the right person got
hit by a bus society would collapse and that's horrifying,
it wouldn't collapse.
But it would be one of those things where it was.
Here's the thing, let's say,
certificate proms happen and everybody wastes, oh,
-- 60 seconds a day.
-- Ok. Anyway. All right. I wanna, I wanna pull us back to the,
the point I was trying to make about policymakers in all this, right?
The policymakers behind this don't understand what they're doing.
-- That's just the reality of it.
-- Well, they have a view of the world that
-- may or may not be correct.
-- It doesn't matter.
They need someone to explain to them what's going on
and you can't explain this to normal people.
You just can't, we, I don't think we're getting most of it right.
And we're definitely not normal people.
And so the challenge becomes,
how do you possibly see something at this technical detail end up in law, in the law,
not be utterly trash.
And I have a suspicion. You can't.
So it's funny, I was just reading.
Um, so number one is there's prescriptive versus outcome based legislation.
So prescriptive legislation would be you
have to transport tomatoes at this temperature
to make sure they don't go bad.
Whereas outcome based would be like you need to
transport tomatoes appropriately so they don't go bad.
How do you do that is left up to you?
And so for example, here, this is very
prescriptive in the,
the brown
have to allow a root certificate like that's,
that's pretty invasive. Like prescriptive tends to be invasive. It, it's a,
it's, you have to do something like the law says I have to stop at red lights.
That is very prescriptive as it should be.
And in this case, they could have gone with outcome based.
But like, again, that negative externality, it's not my problem.
Plus there's the side effect of like, hey, these law enforcement people are like,
really happy with it now
and my national spy agency is like saying, you know, good job
and OK, cool.
And the reality is
the number of men in the middle attacks that are
going to be launched by governments against people is,
uh,
with most Western European governments probably not going to be that high.
Now, I say that and there's countries like Hungary where, you know,
if you read about what's going on there, it's been a bit ugly.
-- I mean.
-- Right. That's different though.
Well, but that's part of the problem is the government we have today
in four years might not be as
compassionate or forgiving about people who drive slowly
-- and maybe, you know, who knows
-- that is a dangerous path to take. You have to assume.
But the problem is now they have this capability is this capability can be abused,
will it be abused?
It will be abused not, can be. The reality is any time
a government entity has the ability to overreach they overreach
and even when they don't have the ability to overreach,
they overreach.
I mean, this is the perpetual checks and balances in democracy.
Well, I mean,
the challenge is government is people and some of them are nice
and some of them are jerks is this capability worth having.
So for example, I would say having a capability like the police
that can
to abuse is worth having because I've seen what happens
to countries where they don't have police and it's pretty ugly
now is having this capability a net benefit.
A net win, is it or does it fulfill some thing that solves an existential threat.
I don't think so.
I mean, and that's the thing, like, what is the benefit?
What is the po like if we don't do this,
what bad thing happens or what good thing do we miss out on?
And the answer is like, yeah, you can still do digital ID.
It'll be a little bit more awkward for the governments to implement.
They'll have to get buy in from the browsers like everybody else.
And they've already been like, like I said, Taiwan Denmark,
there's a bunch of
countries in there and post offices in there
for this exact reason for doing digital identity.
So it's
there, it's not like this can't be done the proper way.
They just want to short circuit it.
And
oops, we also got the capability for a national spy agency to spy on people.
Well, and there's,
I mean, how are they going to protect the keys?
-- How are they going to the way everybody
-- else
does you have hardware security modules and oversight,
blah, blah, blah.
They,
it's easy to say that but will they, I mean,
look, this is one of those instances where
if you just say, oh you need a private key, it's like, oh yeah, hey,
intern we need a private key.
Go make one.
It's like, oh dude on my Windows laptop while I run Steam play these G
like
you look at the DNS sec key signing and key generation ceremonies, right?
Where they went through all the theater,
you know, and I remember I loved watching that theater because they're like, oh,
the, the surface of the, uh the safe is shining.
You could potentially see him putting in the code and so on and so forth.
-- And it's like this is security theater. It's fun to watch.
-- It's
not fun to,
it's fun to watch. It's stupidity.
Like, uh
anyway.
-- All right,
-- What I really love is how do we deal with major key compromises?
And the answer is
we ship a browser update basically
like
key
-- revocation. No, we ship a browser update,
-- isn't there?
What is the, there's a key revocation protocol, isn't there built into the browser?
I forget the name.
The old one was CRL certificate, revocation list.
-- It's
-- just a static list,
OS CP,
online certificate, something protocol,
security protocol.
The problem with OS CP is, is that you, you did this, remember you and I
know
everything
because like half the like
Os C
OS CP responders couldn't maintain like 90% of the time, let alone 99.999 now.
And I remember, I think cloud
was doing some work here where they were going to host it and they're like,
we're cloud flare.
We can probably do a better job than all of you,
right?
But
then there's the privacy issue of whoever runs the OS C OS
CP or OC, whatever, whatever runs that knows. All the post names you're going to.
That's
all
I want to bring this
one
thing.
I don't,
I, I'm more confused now than when we started. I,
I would say
root certificates
that are trusted by
widely used browsers should be rare
and they should be so secure and wonderful and well run that.
Like there's never the chance of them being booted out
of the program because they're so bad and that happens
so clearly, this is not great, but like most things in security, it kind of works.
We're ok.
It does.
-- It mostly works. I mean,
-- you know, but my fridge is running
the
problem.
I see is if the eu does this in law and they get away with it,
everyone's going to freaking do this.
You know, that
every country will just pass a law that like, oh,
you have to also include our certificate because we passed the law.
Here's the only actionable thing I can take away from this. There is a website
from Mozilla
that I will put a link in the show notes too
and like go read it
and there's really, it sounds like there's not a lot we can do.
If you live in Europe,
you might be able to call your lawmakers and complain about this at least.
-- But even I, I don't
-- know, also a link to the eff they have an article on
it.
Of course
it's uh
oh
my goodness.
-- Like the stupid, it burns. That's all I can say.
-- Well, you know, I,
the thing is this is this like this,
this is how the Certificate Authority World has worked for 20 years.
I've been involved in it. I've tried to fix it.
I've tried to get involved at various times
-- and I've given up twice now and I don't think I'm gonna be trying a
-- third time.
I don't know how this could possibly be fixed. That's the reality of it.
Anyway,
let's just put, let's encrypt in charge of everything. It's fine.
That is not the worst idea.
Probably until somebody takes.
But the problem is too, is there's, here's here. Ok, we're gonna end the show on this.
But
let's say you're not competent enough to get a root certificate.
Well, you can buy one, they're companies
-- and that has happened.
-- That's true.
-- You could just, the eu could just buy a company like it's fine.
-- Yeah.
And some of them are pretty small and weird looking and like are hard to find online.
You think they'd be kind of easy to find online
being that they are a root certificate in your browser.
I'm not even a little bit surprised. All right.
Anyway, I'm gonna
basically, the more you look at this,
the worse it is.
I'm just gonna go cry in the corner for the rest of the day. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. Go to open
source security, podcast.com. Please go there and, and read the
Mozilla and eff links.
You can use a Pondo
podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on Mastodon
KT. Have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks
-- everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.