This whole podcast is just one giant happy accident.
Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Curtsey Fried
and my partner in award less winning podcasting, Josh Pressers. Well,
-- we haven't won any awards, so we're award less.
-- Are we award less?
I don't know.
Somebody gave us an award and didn't tell us which would be quite fitting.
Let's award ourselves.
I'm going to award us the open source security best open source security podcast
-- in all of 2020.
-- I would
-- have
-- said longest running. But
sure.
Yeah, sure we can that two awards. Now, there we go.
That always reminds me of when I looked at, what was it?
I think it was Domino's Pizza and you know what it said on Google Maps,
a pizza chain known for late night delivery.
Uh
They're not wrong.
I agree with that 100%. Yes.
Anyway, that's like, actually,
you know what's funny you say that is so just a tangent.
When I was in college,
I lived across the street from a 7-Eleven and
obviously 7-Eleven is open 24 hours a day.
-- It is
-- the best convenience store.
It is a marvelous store.
And I used to go there, we'll say late night and buy their nachos on a regular basis.
-- And I went there one time during the day.
-- Did they, did they do the unlimited cheese?
They do.
You have like a little, little thing,
you can push the plunger and get as much cheese and chili as you want.
Anyway, I went during the day one time when it wasn't like 3 a.m. to get and I thought,
oh, I'll get some nachos.
Those are the worst nachos I've ever had in my life. But,
but at 3 a.m. when you're done at the pub, they are the best nachos you will ever eat.
Yeah,
there was a Chinese restaurant here that was open till 4 a.m. off the main bar strip.
And, yeah, I ate there once during the day and it was just like, wow.
Yeah,
it's
funny how that works
anyway. Anyway. All right. I have a serious topic.
I want to bring up because this is something I've been thinking
about and then we'll get to the real topic after that.
But
so
I had someone contact me on Twitter the other day and they basically said, you know,
I'm a fan of the podcast.
I really want to get into security. Where do I start? And I spent a long time, run away.
No, no, no, no, not at all. I mean, that's our old man silly answer.
I thought about this a lot.
And the thing that I realized,
I think I've not realized in the past necessarily when we've,
we've discussed some of this is
there's no such thing as security anymore.
And I mean,
there kind of wasn't in the past but the reason I say that
is security isn't a thing what we call security is like 100 things.
Well, it's like saying I want to get into business. How do I get into business
or art or literature? This is a,
even, even 20 years ago, security was quite a broad scope.
-- Like,
-- well, it was, it was, I think a little more common
where, for example, what I would say today is, I would,
I would split it quickly into two pieces
of operational security and application security now.
Whereas I think like back in the day there was way less,
it was much fuzzier between the two things because for example,
I worked at an ISP
and when we needed something fixed,
we would just start editing C code and stuff like that.
-- You know,
-- you and I are biased coming from the open source world.
Well, yeah, I understand that. And that's, that's a
-- good point.
-- And I think that's a big part.
I would look at the old security industry and a lot of
it was compensating for the fact that these vendors wouldn't do stuff.
Right?
Like,
how many timeliness did we see on bug track postings where it was like notified?
Well, I'm going to say it out loud,
notified oracle and then the timeline I'm looking at it and I'm like,
this is four years ago.
I know, like straight up or even Microsoft one or two years,
I don't want to rattle on this.
So, you're absolutely right. But I guess here's the thing that,
that I ended up instead of telling someone, oh,
you should go read this or read this or do that or something.
It was like, what are you interested in? What do you want to do? And
I've never,
that was never the first question I asked people where
they said I would like to get into security.
I kind of always asked that because, you know,
the difference between running a corporate network and doing
pen testing and doing application security and blah,
blah, blah is, is night and day, the hours are different.
-- The fundamental focus and culture is different.
-- No, I agree.
And some people want to be auditors.
Some people want to be cool hackers and, you know,
some people want to do bug bounties.
-- It takes all kinds.
-- Exactly that.
And so anyway,
I've been really thinking about this a lot and I feel like I have
no doubt my views and opinions on this matter will evolve with time.
-- So
-- one thing that's interesting,
there was a thing on hacker news a day
or two ago about how to answer questions usefully.
And one common kind of thing in the, in the hacker news thread was this habit of
somebody asks question X and you go, well, did you really mean question Y or,
you know, and I,
but I do think it is important for questions that
are this broad or this sort of soft and squishy
that there is some clarification.
Like when somebody says I want to be a doctor, it's like
YP podiatrist, you know, you want to do like vaccine cures.
-- Like you got to narrow it down a little bit.
-- I think at the same time
it is,
it's like any kind of just journey through a topic
is you obviously start saying I want to be a doctor
and you might not even know how many kinds of doctors there are,
there's probably thousands of types of doctors if I had to guess.
And as you start learning, you can say, oh, well,
I really like this or I don't really like that,
you know, and I think security is exactly the same thing of what do you like to do?
What are your interests?
You know, what it reminds me of is the hero's journey story arc, right?
So you have the call to adventure, right?
Person wants to get into security and then they get supernatural aid like
the old wise woman or the old wise man or you know,
the talking bird or Josh Presser's.
No. And then no, no, no.
And then it starts to get ugly because it really does start to sound like our life.
-- Then there's the threshold guardians.
-- I
-- know. Yeah,
-- there's, there's absolutely no geek keeping in security.
-- We are a happy, warm, inclusive community.
-- No, I
-- like that 100 percent.
-- So then there's that threshold, they get past the threshold.
There's, you know, the helper, the mentor and then there's, you know,
they reach the abyss, right?
-- So there's that whole death and rebirth thing. And
-- I would argue
ever left the abyss.
Well,
that's where I was going with this because I worked for uh two companies.
I say partners in i defense,
it was like a technical analyst and the average burnout and I don't mean
it so much average is like everybody but me burnt out within about 2,
2.5 years.
And just they,
it was a combination of the type of work being it's like the postal system,
no matter how much mail you deliver today,
there's more mail tomorrow,
it never ends.
And I remember having a call with one of the higher level sea levels.
And he's like, yeah, he's like Kurt. So you've been here a while.
I'm like, yeah, and he's like, how come you haven't burned out, burnt out?
And I'm like,
I imagine my job is like washing rocks in a river, you know, and I,
I walk into the river and I wash a rock and then I put it down,
then I wash another rock and I put it down by the time I get to the bottom of the river,
I have to walk back to the top of the river
to start washing rocks again and it just never ends.
And there's really no point to it. And he went,
oh,
he's like,
that's not really helpful advice. Is it?
I'm like, no, no, it's probably not really helpful for most people,
but it works for me.
And,
you know, so I would, I would say for a lot of people,
there's, there's two big abysses in security world.
There's number one, there's the, oh my God,
this is so big and like we have to boil the
ocean to make the world a better place combined with.
And even if we do that today, it's gonna possibly burn down tomorrow, right?
Like we fixed every possible security shoot today,
somebody would find something new tomorrow.
-- Sure. I mean, except that we can't fix them all
-- today.
Exactly. Exactly.
So anyways, and that's that abyss and the death and the rebirth, the Phoenix, the,
you know, the transformation piece, which is next in the, in the story arc.
And then you have atonement, right? And
literally you and I are, you know, you and I both remember when we went from like
who we were to, oh my God, who the hell was I?
What a horrible human being I was, it is true. You know,
-- and, and sadly, some people never get there
-- I think most people never get there.
And then you go back into the known and you have the return, you know,
the gift of the goddess,
ideally in our industry means, you know, you start sort of mentoring like,
like a great example would be Mudge comes to mind because that tweet from yesterday.
But Mudge, you know, this, he's like one of the like foundational hackers
of computer security, like he testified before Congress or the Senate.
I forget which one
like with his hacker name, right?
And long
hair.
I love that.
And you know, and now he's like,
just found 6000 vulnerabilities that we're gonna tell the Linux community about.
We're gonna see, let's say I'm not going to comment on that now,
but disclosing 6000 vulnerability, I think it's 3000 whatever.
It's a lot. Uh
That's the edge of a knife and we're gonna see if he, if he walks in
and I don't, we'll,
we'll wait till he discloses it and then we will
discuss if he did it right or did it wrong.
That's like when you,
-- you're digging in your backyard and you find a 55 gallon barrel
-- in and I will say this,
I have never seen anyone do anything like this correctly before.
So
-- I, I am cautiously optimistic.
-- I would settle for not messy, let alone, correct.
But anyways, this is the foundational element of,
of stories and movies is this hero's journey story arc.
You know, where you go from the known to the unknown and back.
And I think like, honestly it works in life.
Well, it's just kind of how we as humans operate, right?
Very few people can do it themselves. You need some external influences, right?
-- Nobody exists in a vacuum.
-- Nobody can do anything themselves. Ok?
I want to focus on that point because what
you just said is very insightful and important.
You said most people can't do it themselves. Nobody can do it themselves.
And I think there is definitely a we'll say cultural aspect of it in general,
but especially security of
I can fix this.
-- No, you cannot even
-- worse. You couldn't fix this.
Like how many people are like, oh user ha ha.
It's so simple and then, you know,
yeah,
like literally yesterday. Oh This is fantastic.
I was playing Minecraft yesterday.
I was showing my son how to play Minecraft on the PC, right.
He's only ever played on the ipad and on the ipad wasd sure. I know that,
you know, space bar to jump. I had to look up the shift to like when you
in creative mode start flying, how do I was like, space bar goes up?
How do I get down? Right. So shift.
So I was helping him and I accidentally hit f
and all of a sudden there's like an extra block
next to my inventory with the block I want in it and it's like not placing and I'm like,
what did I do now?
Because I've played video games,
especially like keyboard based video games for long enough.
And I saw the screen, I'm like, oh, you know what it looks like?
I have one thing in each hand. OK. So I Google, you know, like,
literally, you know, holding two things in Minecraft, how to fix it, blah, blah,
blah.
OK. The term is dual wielding, blah, blah, blah. Look it up.
I have to put the item back in my inventory in an empty
and that will fix this.
Can you imagine a normal person is playing
Minecraft on the PC accidentally hits F and
all of a sudden the block is in the wrong hand and won't place properly.
I've done this and I had, I had to do the same thing you did.
-- It's super annoying and you and I
-- have 20 years of background and
experience and how to Google and what words to Google and like,
you know, we, we've both played D and D so we know what dual wielding is like,
I don't need to explain that
right?
Whereas to my mother, I was like, OK, so dual wielding is like,
and I literally took my phone and I'm like, D
and I passed back and forth to make it more physical, you know, because
like my mom has never played video games. She's just not a thing that she grew up with.
Yeah, there's there's this habit of like, oh,
you should have backed up every time something bad happens to these poor users.
No. Absolutely. Absolutely. And it is easy.
My favorite example ever, actually, I like to tell is
I was talking to someone one time about configuring and enabling TLS on a service
and this is a very difficult thing for people to do. And they said it,
it's so easy. You just make a certificate and copy it into a directory.
And I'm like, oh, my goodness.
Well, actually it's even simpler that you just need to, you know,
to generate a key and then generate a CRT with the correct fields and then, you know,
send it into the signing, get it back,
copied into the right location, make sure the file permissions are correct.
And then if it's hopefully something saying like Apache,
you can basically say like TLS security equals high and just
leave it at that or if you're not so lucky,
then you actually have to specify which ciphers and handshakes and
protocols are used.
-- But yeah, it's pretty easy.
-- Exactly this,
it's hard to mess up.
-- You know, you
-- know what I actually, so I'm a big fan of the painter Bob Ross.
He has a show called Joy of Painting. He's a Happy Trees guy.
And any time I see him on TV, when I'm like, looking at channels,
I stop and I watch whatever he's doing.
And he actually had a really cool comment the other day is someone asked him,
how long does it take you to paint one of these paintings?
Because he does them on a show? And his answer was 20 years plus 20 minutes.
-- It's so true.
-- How many paintings does he do on his show?
-- When you're watching him paint a painting? Well,
-- one, obviously every show.
Well, no, no, on the show he does one. I know he's painted it three times before that.
But that's another story.
But again, 20 years of talent is how he does it.
I mean,
I guess that's the advantage of being an air force guy
stuck out in the middle of Alaska some spare times.
Right?
-- You know, there's your 10,000 hours and then
-- exactly. Anyway, OK. So
point is the point is we'll wrap this one up if you are new to this
industry or even if you're not and you
want to investigate something new and different.
I would encourage you, make sure you educate yourself, go in with,
with maybe some questions.
But I think most importantly is find someone to talk to about all this and just talk.
And honestly,
even I've noticed a couple threads now
on Twitter where somebody asked that question,
like, how do I get into this or what about this?
And there's like hundreds of replies kind of spanning the whole old gamut, you know,
that's useful and helpful to some degree.
But
I do believe you're right.
-- That it needs to be more of a one on one conversation and relationship.
-- Yeah.
I would, I would find a person, find a person,
find someone to talk to and just ask them questions
and if someone comes to you and ask questions,
don't answer their questions, ask them questions as you know what I mean?
-- Socratic Method.
-- Yeah, exactly.
Like, don't answer questions, ask more questions because that's more valuable.
Well, yes and no,
I actually had somebody come to me on Twitter and I'm like, oh, what you want is,
you know, actually the CN A guidelines 2.0 page 11.
Bottom half.
He's like, oh,
holy crap. That's exactly what I need to say.
I'm talking about, like, life advice here now.
C
N
A question.
-- Yeah.
-- Well, yeah, for life advice.
The Socratic Method is the way to go because partly that helps you
-- mask your biases.
-- Totally. Totally. All right. Let's move on.
-- What's our topic? I'll let you tell it
-- web kit being the foundational
or
do hickey for,
well, basically everything now except,
well, no, I was going to say, except for Microsoft. But even they,
-- yeah, everyone's, everyone's using it. Well, Firefox isn't. Oh,
-- yeah. Yeah.
Yeah, Firefox.
That's the one anyways and a couple of weird ones from God knows where.
But anyways they're, they're adding Face ID and Touch ID for the web,
which is pretty epic.
Number one just doing that is pretty epic.
But number two, doing it with heavy,
heavy privacy considerations because obviously, if I,
if you're using your faces ID, then tracking you becomes potentially a problem.
Yes, for touch ID,
your fingerprints and they've got a ton of privacy protections
in there to make sure that that doesn't happen.
And I just think this is the coolest thing ever because, you know,
now that I've got a newer ipad that does face ID, like I just love that.
I kind of like touch my ipad and it looks at me and says, OK,
you're curt and like lets me access it.
And so you know, the lock time on that thing is real short because I can just,
it's so easy to unlock, right? I just pick it up, right?
Same thing with my laptop with touch ID.
And also I love it from an accessibility point of view
because almost everybody has a face that doesn't change much.
Well, like I've had the occasion with my kids' photos because I have twin boys,
they're fraternal, not identical, even as fraternal twins.
Like when apple the face photo recognition thing in a jigger goes back enough,
it starts to get confused between the two of them.
Interesting, right? Because they're just basically a pink potato.
Like you can basically the
shape is slightly different, but you know, they kind of look the same.
I think this is great because this is, this is so accessible.
-- This is so easy and it's secure
-- Well, so here's, here's my take on this.
I'm shocked Apple is letting this happen because Apple's obviously
the one pushing this because Face ID is Apple's thing.
And of course,
Google and everyone will have their equivalent
technologies and it'll come with time.
But Apple has been pushing
hard into making things work the way they want them to work in their app ecosystem.
Like Fortnite is a good example of the fact that like there's all these like HBO go
in the NBC streaming service whose name I don't
remember and don't really care about isn't there,
there's all this stuff, right?
And Apple's taking this hard line.
And for example, Microsoft has a streaming service for games
that
Apple has told them, you can't come in
story. Do you know what their solution is?
Their solution is to just make it work in Safari, which is a marvelous workaround.
But here's the thing, Apple obviously, that's not in their best interest.
-- No,
-- they want that 30% cut.
I kind of view this in the same light of making web
apps more accessible is going to damage them from a business perspective.
And I'm shocked they let that happen.
Well, but if you look at Apple, they have taken a super
-- hard line on privacy and security,
-- they have done that.
What happens when somebody finds a security bypass
that lets you dump all the phone data?
Well, Apple comes up with T two silicon, which
also conversely means people like Luis Rossman
can't repair your laptop now because you,
you know, t two chip locks to your SSD and blah, blah, blah.
And they can't recover the data. It's gone. Sorry.
And then on the flip side, like I've noticed on my phone and my ipad, you know,
when I log into it, like I have lastpass and I've been a, you know, I like lastpass.
But the,
the Safari experience of password generation and password storage now
is I love that.
I'm, I'm getting to the point where I don't have a clue what any of my passwords are.
Don't know, don't care because the browser slash lastpass just take care of it.
And, but here's the thing
Safari because it's integrated with the I OS.
It will also do the passwords in the mobile apps which lastpass can't do natively.
So for example, if I open up the Reddit app on my phone,
it gets the password from the back end password store that you know,
got in there from Safari and it just works.
So even for apps, I don't have to go cut and paste passwords anymore.
It just works right from a user perspective is
so much more usable
and incidentally way more secure because, you know, I've looked at the passwords,
it's generating and it's like five or six random characters,
dash five or six random characters, you know, four puns, like they're just,
they're basically, you know, globally unique I DS at this point, you know,
100 and 28 bits of, you know, complete entropy randomness
or more probably.
And
what I'm looking at, you know, I've come to this conclusion of, like,
security is good but doing stuff for just the sake of security is almost never good.
Doing stuff that makes the world better, easier, faster, more efficient
-- and has the effect of better security. That's the way to go.
-- Oh, I mean, well, yes.
But,
-- yeah,
-- but you and I used to be like, security for the sake of security.
Well, there's some of that but I think there's also just the fact that, you know,
being, being a cynic,
there is an enormous amount of
just technology right now. That's basically the analogy. I love.
Someone told me once was a self looking ice cream cone.
I mean, these companies like Google and Apple and Facebook and Twitter,
they're basically like tautologies at this point and they,
they do things to do things for themselves.
I bought this Google Home Nest. Number one.
-- It comes with a custom power plug, not a USB plug.
-- I mean, the Alexis
come with that though too.
Uh, no, all the, all the new Alexas come with a USB plug. The old spot, do they?
Yeah, I have a pile of them. They're all
USB and the fabric it's covered in is weirdly scratchy.
Like that episode of Better Off Ted where they make that insanely scratchy.
Fabric and then make chairs out of it and everybody works hard until they snap,
setting this thing up was like,
I had to skip or cancel or bypass more than 10,
but less than 20 prompts where it was trying to, you know,
hook up accounts or identify me or, oh,
it absolutely had to have access to location services
so it could identify Bluetooth and Wi Fi networks.
And I'm like, what? No, you don't.
You know, I'm like, you need to know what city you're in so you can give me the weather.
That's it. But it's Google. I know. And it was, it was a very googly experience
and I'm, I'm actually at the point now where
I've got it showing as like a desk clock with, you know, the old timey, like,
uh black squares with the white numbers on them. That kind of flip over.
That might be all this thing ever does.
-- And how much did you pay for a clock?
-- It was like 60 bucks at Costco Canadian.
So, honestly, for a nice desk clock, that's what I would have paid anyways, I guess.
I don't know.
Yeah.
Like it's just,
it's such a horrifyingly terrible device from a usability perspective,
but it's Google and I kind of expect
you're the product.
Yes, I know.
Get in line sheep.
I,
I mean, this is, this is just my, my eternal frustration and,
and I guess this is why I see enabling more
I guess just functionality in web apps fills me with hope
because
all of these devices and all of these app ecosystems are train wrecks.
And,
and now at the same time, like very few companies are saying, oh,
we should make this a web accessible service versus here,
install our garbage app so we can spy on you
and it's, it's horrifying.
-- Well,
-- and so you have stickiness and you can send them notifications.
right?
-- And I don't want any of that
-- crap again to poop on Domino's right.
I installed their app so I could order pizza
and it's like it has like a watch component and I'm like, cool,
like it'll tell me when my pizza's coming, which it did.
And then like two days later, I randomly get my watch beeping at me,
offering me a Domino's coup and I'm like, oh, ok.
I have to go disable notifications for this and uninstall it.
So, you know what I do is my kids love little Caesars, which is depressing to me.
Pizza.
It literally is,
but they love it. And so whatever they, but what's really cool they do.
This is, this is really neat. Is so they have this thing in the store now.
I think they call it the pizza portal where I just, yeah, that's its name.
I scan a barcode and like a little door opens up and my order is in it.
So I literally don't have to talk to or interact with a human.
So it's like, it's like the Amazon delivery boxes at 7-Eleven, but with fresh pizza,
right?
-- Ok.
-- I can get behind that. I'm ok with it in the times of COVID obviously.
And so anyway, you know. Yeah, the app's the same deal.
I literally, I will install the app, order my pizza,
pick up my pizza and then I uninstall the app
as soon as get back home because it's like,
I don't want to deal with any of this garbage.
I'm guessing that Apple will probably do that in a future version
of IOS because right now they've already done the thing where,
you know, this thing wants access to your photo gallery.
Do you want to give it access to all of
your photo gallery just for now or just specific pictures?
Same thing with location? Yeah, I appreciate that.
And I assume at some point they're going to do that for notifications
where it's like this app can send you notifications while
the app is open otherwise like shut up or,
you know,
for half an hour after the app is closed because like for food delivery would be,
that would be ok.
-- But
-- now obviously Apple might do this. I don't know if they will or not. We'll see.
But, but
someone like Google, for example, no way, like Google's Bread and Butter is,
is just scraping as much data off of you as they possibly can
and then getting up in your face as much as possible with advertising.
Right. Exactly. And so, I mean, this is where just that, that it's, it's such a mess
in terms of what the incentives are for a lot of these companies.
Well, I mean, that's what's interesting to me is Apple is,
I have seen Apple commercials where they talk
about just privacy for five or 10 seconds.
Yeah.
Yeah, I don't think Facebook or Google could run that without.
Well, first of all, it would make the news and it would just end poorly for them.
But I don't think even if they wanted to, they,
I think internally nobody would let them
because they don't fundamentally believe in privacy.
Well, they can't, they, I mean, if you look at Facebook or Google,
they've tried how many times to branch off into other business models.
-- Well,
-- or
Facebook just now talking about how, you know,
it's bad for consumers that Apple is, you know,
making it easier to block ads and that, yes, it's terrible.
I read the letter and I'm like, oh my, I'm like, whoever, like I get it,
this is your job.
You have to come up with these talking points and you have to write them down,
you know, logically.
-- But like, man, I just want to slap you with a fish.
-- I know. I know. I hear you, man.
I hear you.
It's so, anyway, anyway, now I will say, I know we, we,
we actually talk about how much we like Apple more than I prefer on this podcast.
-- But I,
-- it's not that I like Apple more. It's that I
-- dislike them less. They
-- suck less.
-- Exactly
-- that their incentives appear to be more aligned with me than say
Google.
Maybe I'm still not convinced they're doing this for the right reasons.
Well, no, Apple's incentive is simple.
I pay them like a grand every two or three years for a phone.
I pay them a grand every two or three years for a laptop.
I pay them, you know, X dollars a month for extra icloud. I pay them for apps
and I'm ok with that because I feel like I get value for it.
You know, just like I'm happy every month when I pay my, you know,
I have a combined for my power, water, sewage, garbage pickup
and natural gas and all of these things. Like I love it.
I flush my toilet and don't know, don't care. It's just, it's gone.
Now, here's the problem though is if, if web apps become more and more popular,
then you're going to pay Apple less and less money because you're going to pay the
-- web app owner. Yeah.
-- And I've had that happen with Story Bots, right?
Story Bots app went off the store and now
they want a monthly subscription on the web and,
-- and
-- that's frustrating for obvious reasons.
Now,
what's really wild is I donated to a political campaign recently.
I won't tell you which one, but you can probably figure it out.
But I went to their website, I was on my phone. They sent an email.
They're like, will you give us some money? I'm like, whatever.
I'm feeling happy, I'll give you some money. Right. I click the button
and it says you can use apple pay to pay on the website. It was amazing.
And it worked and like, I scanned my fingerprint, it sent them money.
I'd obviously give them some information and they're like, oh,
now that you've paid us, you should sign up for an account.
And I was like, no, but,
but anyway, like I was flabbergasted that Apple Pay just worked on a website.
It was amazing.
I use it for when I order my Chinese food. My local Chinese place takes
-- Apple Pay square and on the
-- website.
Yeah,
that's awesome.
Yeah, they take Apple Square
and Google Pay and you can also, like, plug in your credit card manually.
I didn't know that was a thing on websites
because I think they go through Shopify,
I want to say
or something like that. They go through one of those big providers where it's just,
just all works. That's awesome.
Right. Well, that's the future, right? Like I get it.
Why people again, like the whole cloud thing. I'm a little biased but,
you know, people who set up their own ecommerce website. Great. Cool.
Now you're going to get hacked and all your data is going to go.
Ah, yes, seriously.
Versus you just, I'm going to say Shopify because I'm a Canadian.
Shopify is a Canadian company and they're actually pretty decent.
You know, you just do it on Shopify, they take their cut
monthly, blah, blah, blah, and, but everything just works and,
but you get access to all these insane features and again,
no offense. Shop.
If I can do more security than like Bob running his web server with ecommerce on it.
I'm sorry, that's just how that works.
Like, I'll never forget locally.
I remember when the first secure web server to the best of my knowledge
was deployed in Monton and it was a company called the Running Room.
They sell like jogging
stuff and like sport equipment and they, I don't know what they paid,
but they had a son,
microsystems server running the Netscape Secure web
server thing with an online store.
And yeah, a few years later it went away.
But I was,
I'm just thinking back to those days like there's no
way they were competent to run that thing securely.
I remember building an online shop.
This was in nineties and let's just say corners were cut.
I don't think PC I existed, but we would have definitely failed our PC I audit.
If it, if it was a thing,
we were storing like credit cards unencrypted in a mysql database.
-- It was terrible.
-- My solution.
We, we couldn't afford a secure web server for a project. So I called it secure
server dot
dot com.
And then we gave people the option of faxing on their
order and we got like two or three faxes a month,
but most people ordered online.
At least we had a TLS enabled web server. But holy cow.
Well, but I mean, this is literally back in like the nineties. So
we've rat holed marvelously and we're basically out of time.
So I guess in summary,
I love to see that these web frameworks
are picking up all of these interesting features.
But I also, I'm terrified
that these companies are going to realize
as they enrich
the web browsers, they are going to be relinquishing control.
We've already seen this happen with media, right? Where
you used to just pay your cable bill, but now you've got Netflix, Hulu
youtube wants, what is it like nine bucks a month or whatever?
And what we're then seeing now is a bit of consolidation
because I don't want to pay for seven streaming services,
right?
And that's going to happen with these web apps is I
don't want to pay 17 different companies for my thing.
I just, you know, I want to pay for games
-- for my kids. I
-- mean, maybe I, I'm, we'll see, it's,
I don't know, I don't know how this ends but, but it regardless,
I'm glad Apple is doing it and I have a strong suspicion.
Someone in a certain place in the company hasn't connected the dots that,
that are going to connect at some point
-- or
-- they're just transitioning to their next Apple
-- self.
-- I would be shocked if that's the case.
They did it once with Steve jobs.
And honestly, when Tim Cook came in, I was like, oh,
-- well that, you know, Apple was nice while it lasted.
-- That is also true.
-- I said the same thing.
-- I am pleasantly surprised at how that's
worked out.
They are still a company and I think they're doing
acceptable.
I feel like they understand the innovation trap of
-- where they do have to eat their
-- young.
What have they eaten lately though
-- iphone se the fact that they came up with an iphone se two.
-- That is true. And I bought an
-- E because I am a cheapskate
-- and on the flip side too, the iphone se two,
as I understand,
it actually has a thicker profit margin for
them because it's like reusing components and stuff.
It's literally an iphone eight with a better chip in it. My son has an iphone eight.
The cases are the same. Every, the buttons are all the same. The screen is the same.
-- It's just mine has a slightly nicer chip and more ram like that's it.
-- I don't know.
I feel like, I mean,
I look at Google and Facebook and they are sadly like Google has gone
so far as to create alphabet to try and re invent themselves and they've,
from what I've seen failed spectacularly there.
Like none of that has worked out.
-- I mean,
-- it's very, how many big companies have ever reinvented themselves though.
I mean, Apple and Microsoft come to mind, but that's about
-- it.
-- Lots of companies have reinvented themselves and then cratered out.
Well. Right. Right. Exactly.
So, anyway, anyway, all right, we are fresh out of time, so I'm going to call it.
So, thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening. Go to open social
security podcast.com. Head up to show
notes, UZ Pound O says podcast. Hashtag You hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too, I guess. Try to be more like Bob Ross. Everybody.
We don't,
we don't make mistakes, we make happy accidents.
We'll say that this whole podcast is just one giant happy accident.
-- I don't
-- think the PC I auditors are going to like that one.
Whatever. Nobody likes those guys. Anyway.