Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
-- and my partner in getting it done. Right. Josh Pressers.
-- Well, we really f ked up.
-- Episode 300 didn't we?
-- Yeah.
Well, in fairness though, all the,
the few articles we found that mentioned sort of the strategy was
they mentioned copyright,
but I went back to the original Apple Press release and
it does not mention C FAA or copyright or anything.
It's funny you say that because
I got an email early in the morning from someone named DJ. Hi DJ.
And it was basically like, where did you find this?
And I went to look and it was all gone
and my first thought was, oh, I just have to look harder.
And then it occurred to me
that
we screwed this up and the more looking I did, the more it was screwed up.
And at first I think the very human reaction is
I'm going to double down and find
the stories and the information we based our conversation off of.
And then I realized after like five minutes of like furiously searching,
like we just screwed this up.
Well, even if I find
-- the original articles it's still wrong.
-- Oh, yeah.
And what am I gonna do?
And in fairness there, there's a whole pile of tweets around this in copyright.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So, yeah. No, it was definitely in some of the articles.
But like I said, well, I would say the biggest mistake we made is I,
I honestly did not go to the original Apple press release and read it.
I did
and there was nothing in there about what the suit was and whatever here's,
I guess here's the lesson I'm taking away from all of this.
All right. So first of all,
I think it's a very human reaction to try to defend a bad decision.
And this is actually ties nicely into what we're going
to talk about in a moment for the show.
But it's a very human reaction. And I think at the same time
by not trying to defend our mistakes and just being like, well,
you screwed this one up like
that's it. The story's done.
-- Well,
-- there's a difference between defending and going like, oh,
did I get that wrong?
Right? Because
no, like right, you should double check. Like did I actually get that wrong?
The answer is yes, yes, we did.
We totally screwed this one up and actually I'll put a link in the show notes.
Uh I think in Law Fair did a podcast I listened to about this
and they do a marvelous job dissecting what Apple is trying to do.
Who knew a lawyer's podcast is better than us at law
or, or just in general? I mean,
yeah, why don't you
-- go listen to a better podcast
-- and no, no, don't be sending people off.
We, we need the likes and subscribes. Oh, no, it's not coming out.
-- We know
-- those internet points for
-- reasons.
-- That's
right.
We'll tell you later what they're for.
There's a plan, right.
Anyway. All right. All right. What are we talking about today?
So you're holding it wrong.
And I don't mean just iphones. That would be too easy. But bananas and
Tetris,
I hate that banana story.
-- It's true though because
-- I, I did not learn how to peel a banana properly until I was
in my late thirties
-- and I saw that video of a monkey at the zoo.
-- No. Look,
if you are holding a banana
and when you are done
the, the inside of the banana is
in you and the heel is in your hand. You have not failed at eating a banana.
-- But
-- there's such an easier way.
I mean, so you open it backwards. Who cares? I don't care.
It's,
I think this is a very, so, so here's where we're gonna start.
There is
a story from, it's kind of old now. It's from like April or something.
But basically
the,
there are people who play Tetris
and, and I hesitate, I competitively, I think it's a fair description.
And basically these people get these bonkers
scores and they're ridiculously good at it.
Well, and
the one caveat
they play Tetris
using the original Nes controllers.
It's
kind of a
-- big part
-- of it.
I would compare it to like, if you watched Kurt and I play hockey,
no one would be impressed.
But when you
s,
-- there's no end of Tetris, Kurt, there's no end of
-- Tetris there is in the game, boy,
-- you
-- played whatever, what you played.
The, the B mode where you just have to complete it.
These people play endless for Paul.
This is,
this is
matter.
It's amazing to watch. It's like watching the speed runners play their games.
They have a talent.
I do not possess the interesting thing. So, so
in the Tetris world,
there's kind of these two ways to hold the controllers and now
there's a third and the third way is destroying the first two.
And I think this really became interesting
when Kurt and I were discussing it because
if you look at the world of just tech in general, but especially security,
there's always new ways to do something and sometimes they're better,
sometimes they're not, but it's
as humans, it can be difficult to give up that old familiar way
when we see a fire superior way.
Well, you know, it reminds me it's like CS go on,
on console with controller versus on PC with a computer and mouse.
There's no comparison Yeah.
Yeah, you,
you literally cannot have those two groups
compete because there is no competition,
they kind of can so they cheat a little bit. There's a story I will try to find.
But back in the, I think it might have been the original Xbox days,
Microsoft envisioned the concept of crossplay where you have
PC players playing console players. And I think this was for Halo
and they found that basically even the crappiest players on PC
because they have a mouse were destroying the console players.
And what they do now is a console kind of cheats where it has like an aim assist.
I think they call it.
So if you're, if you're close to someone, it kind of jerks over to him. Right.
Basically an aim bot. Yes. But you need that because
-- playing any of these games on a console is very hard.
-- My favorite. Uh
there's a video somebody tried to play Starcraft like a,
I think it was a high level cast or like maybe pig or something.
Um or no, no, no, it was Maximus Black, I think playing Starcraft with a,
with a controller.
That, that sounds
like when you,
when you hear those people beating like Super
Mario brothers with the dance pad or something.
Exactly. Those are really fun to watch too. But anyway, anyway,
the topic, the actual topic is
kind of discussing that very human aspect of.
There are sometimes new and better ways and it can be very difficult for us.
You, you have to, the problem is people define a problem
and they define that problem within a context and
then they often get locked into that context.
So
the problem with Tetris is you need to and I'm gonna say this
the way most people say you need to tap the button quickly,
right? Like 10 to 20 times a second
to get the piece to move fast enough. So that,
right? But what I'm saying is
well, but what I'm saying is
inherently in that statement,
I've now locked this into the context of interacting with the button.
And the trick is you don't actually
you need the button to interact with the controller.
So
essentially you can move the button or,
and this is kind of the clever part where they figured out some things
you hold the button but move the controller.
-- Uh
-- Basically, yes,
-- that is what's happening
-- because the controller is
much bigger and it's got more surface area.
And so like you basically drum on like you kind of drum it with your fingers
to get. Well, they were in the video was like 16 or 20 Hertz.
So like 16 or 20 button presses a second, which is, it's a lot. Yeah,
like again, Starcraft, you know, those pro players with 600 A PM actions per minute
and
II
I pop out at like 90.
I don't know how fast I can press a button.
It's,
but there's the difference also between pressing a button really fast and
actually pressing multiple buttons very quickly to accomplish an actual thing.
Right.
So, anyway, I don't want to talk about Tetris anymore.
We're going to, we're going to slide this conversation into.
I like that. Oh, I didn't even do that on purpose. How funny.
But I, I think as security people and I'll, I'll, I'll throw some examples out there.
If we look at the adoption of cloud.
I think it mimics a lot of this where cloud comes out
and there were tons of people who were like, oh, it's somebody else's computer.
You can't trust what's going on in cloud. And the reality is it was so much better.
You had no choice. Right.
Well, you have a choice but you're hobbling yourself.
It's like, oh, these new cars, they're,
they're just somebody else's internal combustion engine.
Like, no, no, they're better than horses.
And that's the thing with cloud, right? Is
there's just, yes, you like, I buy my power from the city. I give up a lot of control.
Um,
I live in an area now with underground lines but with overground lines,
the rule of thumb was, you know, one outage per summer per squirrel.
Right.
And
that's just the thing, you know, the squirrel chooses
-- to not live anymore and you lose power for a few minutes or an
-- hour or days.
Not a lot.
So, I,
so, so I, I had a house. It was the first house I ever owned way back long, long ago.
Imagine there's like a weird little
island
and, and basically we had this strange shaped block
that was a, a kidney bean shaped and all of the houses on that,
we had one line connecting maybe like 10 houses on this strangely shaped block.
And any time we lost power because it only affected a small number of houses.
It took them forever to come, help us. It was
nuts
and it was so frustrating. I I detested that
but uh no, that's cloud, I mean,
and and in the beginning, especially with the lower tier cloud players, it was
kind of basically a poorly managed colo,
I mean, sure and and clouds just one example, right?
There's there's so many other examples other than cloud. And I think
we as security people exist in this weird space. And I think like especially now
there's so much disruption happening.
And I would say the biggest focus we're seeing today is like around tooling
where there's all this new tooling around logging and
event monitoring and performance monitoring in some cases.
And like all the supply chain, everything we're talking about now and
the focus of a lot of this has become tools
and I think this is so comparable to that Tetris story because
when you if you have a better tool,
it's easy to be like ah whatever that's not as good as what I do,
but sometimes it's
way better.
Well, it's funny because this kind of, I'm going to go off on this tangent.
Simon Wardley Worldly Mapping. Look it up. It's awesome.
But one of the things is that
when it's immature, it's bespoke or custom made.
And
I think part of the challenge there is people who
make custom things get very emotionally attached to that.
And so when you,
for example,
almost any mechanical watch that costs less than a car
is probably not going to keep time as reliably as a $5 digital quartz watch.
Hilariously. Yes.
Right. That's just so if your, if your requirement is timekeeping,
then go buy a $5
cassio does
-- Cassio still exist? I don't know,
-- they do.
I don't know if they still make watches, but I know they,
because actually I just bought a Cassio piano for my daughter for Christmas.
They, it was funny because
we, I told her I'm like, we, she wanted like a portable keyboard
and she, she plays like real piano. She's quite good.
And
so I, what I was on Saturday, I think of before we were recording this.
I told her I'm like, get in the car regarding the music store and we get there,
I'm like, pick out a keyboard
and she goes what I'm like, it's gonna be your Christmas present. Pick it out.
She's like, what do you mean? I'm like, look, I don't know how to buy this thing.
I need you to not hate it.
And you're gonna act surprised on Christmas Day. Ok.
See, this is the thing, like this is the thing. Never buy,
don't buy people something for their hobby because
chances are you're going to buy the wrong thing
or they already have it or they already have a better one.
Like, never buy Kurt or Josh, a computer related thing. Dude.
Just give us an Amazon gift card.
You know, I mean, it depends, I I won't say no
no but like memory of CPU
you know,
whatever anyways point back to this.
So I think part of the challenge is people get really
emotionally invested in the things that they built and they like,
for example,
I built a really slick mailman list server with two front end post
fix and two back end post fix servers like a crank out email,
like just super fast.
And I was so happy to export that list of users and dump it into mailchimp.
You know, whereas I know people that would have fought that tooth and nail.
I mean, there was a time
I remember fighting many things, tooth and nail.
I mean, so one of my favorite examples I I use of this is
back when Kurt and I were working at Red Hat on vulnerabilities and open source.
It was completely bespoke.
It was,
it was humans looking at lists of vulnerabilities, looking at code.
There was nowhere to even keep our notes publicly or to share.
Yeah, it was, it was really hard. I mean, and it was very, very manual and
-- it was one of those things. Like, I remember being really proud of
-- that.
I have some bad news for you. It still is.
I mean, a lot of it is, I know we're working on it
but like, I mean, I remember
talking to a bunch of Microsoft people one day and I'm like, oh yes,
we fixed 400 vulnerabilities
last year in, in this, in, in, I think it was Fedora or something.
And they looked at me like I was a freak and in hindsight,
I kind of was
but you know, like we thought that was amazing and it was amazing given the tooling.
But in hindsight
like that was not the end all be all of dealing with this stuff.
Like you need tooling, you need automation.
Humans need not apply. There are better ways to do this.
Yeah. No, it's, I mean, that's what
like I see all the the current dev
se
ops uh
crowd of and I use the term kids, not, not in a negative way,
but literally these people are young and
they have to be because the old people just won't change their ways,
generally speaking,
right? But so these dev se
people kids
are,
they don't really need to care about security
that much because they're pushing out updates like
one or more times a week and they're using things like bundle
audit where it just magically is like, oh, you got some CV S there in your code.
Hey, uh, you wanna, you wanna fix that?
Yeah. Yeah, you do. Ok, click
I, I take, I take issue with your statement about,
they don't have to care about security, they have to care,
but it's different.
The problem they're dealing with is very different
than what we think of as security.
Well, what I mean,
they don't have to care is they don't have to do all this hand tooling, tracking,
reading, bug track reading, oss
se
it's,
it's in their tool chain now and it literally every time they do a build,
they get a warning on any outstanding cvs which they can override or just be like,
yeah, let's update that and see if it breaks anything.
It didn't break anything. Cool that CV is now squished
and they don't have to track it because it's in the tooling,
it's tracked in the tooling if they have a regression or something, it's
just, it's gonna magically pop out.
And that's what I mean is like, I hate to say this, but at Red Hat, we had to,
is this patch still included in this R PM?
I
-- remember that. Right?
-- Because if, and, and sometimes things would progress.
It somehow happened every now and then
it's because you'd upgrade. I mean, so the reason it would happen is
there would be a security vulnerability,
we would apply the patch to an R PM doing the red hat back port thing.
And then for whatever reason,
upstream might have applied the patch and then reverted it
or something happened that the patch didn't go upstream.
Then red hat upgrades the package to the next version.
They don't carry the patch over.
Because when you upgrade versions,
the intent is all of the patches in the old version are in the new upstream version.
So you don't need those patch files except
sometimes it got reverted and it wasn't there.
And I mean, it, it was pretty rare. I I'm not going to pretend that happened a lot.
But anyway, I mean, so like on the topic of the tooling,
we're talking about here where developers run a tool and it'll tell you like,
what's wrong with all your stuff.
I remember back in maybe 10 years ago,
we mocked these kind of tools because we were like, oh these tools,
they make so many mistakes, they're not, they were terrible
but they got better.
We didn't,
but we didn't get better
humans.
The thing is generally speaking, humans,
how do I put this? Humans
have topped out at whatever their level of ability is either for
the simple reason is that is the maximum level of ability,
like an Olympic athlete
or
like on a statistical level.
For example, drivers of cars globally, I'm going to say this is as good as it gets.
Like people are not going to go take remedial
driving lessons and learn how to parallel park properly.
No,
right now now, actually, I, I have an anecdote to add to that comment.
I cannot parallel park.
When I took my driving test in the United States,
you, they make you parallel park.
That's the only thing I lost points on because I, I never could do it.
But now my car has cameras like, all over it and I can see everything.
I can totally parallel park now.
But it's because I have a tool that basically does all the real work for me.
I
say
if you have a, a modern enough car, you, you just have a button for that.
Yeah, mine doesn't do that yet.
I, I, that's like the dream though.
Having a car that will park itself is one of my dreams
because I'm, I can't even pull into a parking space straight.
-- Like it's embarrassing. I'm so bad. Is it
-- like a spatial thing
or?
I don't know, I'm a bag of meat that sucks at driving.
-- That's what it is I think
-- because I definitely get that some people, you know,
lack spatial awareness of where their car is.
You know,
you see them driving on one side or the other of the lane instead of in the middle.
I don't have problems with that.
It's just literally pulling in straight to a parking
space for whatever reason I am incapable of doing.
Yeah. I don't know. I can't explain it but like a
gene
for that I acknowledge
as a human.
I am a bad driver. If you ask me if I love it. What is it?
80% of people say they're above average drivers. Like, no, not me.
I, well, I probably am because I'm willing to admit I'm not, you know what I,
that's what I always think of because I watch some people drive and it's like, oh,
my goodness.
Well, and that's, I think, and that's again,
I'm going to pop up Simon World here because stuff starts in Genesis,
then it moves to custom made and it's,
it's not reproducible, it's fragile, it's not very great,
but it's better than nothing.
And then you get to the product stage
where,
ok, things are starting to move along here and then eventually,
hopefully you maybe get to the or not, hopefully,
but you get to the utility stage where it's just a thing that exists and works and,
you know,
it's just
you, but the thing is once it gets to everything
as it matures, allows a higher order system to be built upon it.
But at a lower level. So for example, if you have a utility system like electricity,
well, now you can just plug stuff into the wall without worrying about
whether or not the power will,
you know, surge and fry it or something,
which is a real concern in a lot of countries in the world.
And so with cloud, for example,
with Amazon Elastic compute EC2,
it, I remember 10 years ago, man, like it,
uh I would notice the server was degrading and then
two days later I'd get an email from Amazon saying,
hey, the server you're on is degrading
and you know, constant problems like that at least every couple of months and now
those problems went away.
Yeah.
You know,
or you get a warning well, in advance that it's going to fail. And so
when EC2 was not reliable, I had to do things like,
have a load bounce or have multiple servers have all the shenanigans.
But once it became sort of more utility, more, excuse me, more reliable,
I could ignore that stuff and I could build higher level stuff and just
like electricity
just,
I could,
well, like the yesterday's Amazon outage.
Yes, there will be outages once in a while, like about once a year it seems.
And, well, that's ok. Just eat the cost of it. Right. It's
not really that bad.
Whereas if I try to build a super 99.6 nines or four nines reliable system myself,
that's going to cost so much money
and be so much hassle and more to the point
that the, the time and effort I'm gonna spend
building these things and like building these tools,
doing it myself manually compared to even using
a not a great tool,
right? There's, there's no comparison, right? Tools.
And the other thing is once you start using tools,
even if you're doing it bad,
you're doing it consistently bad and you can fix consistently bad,
you cannot fix inconsistent,
-- but we're talking about doing it wrong
-- well.
And even, but the thing is even if you're doing it wrong,
but you're doing it wrong consistently,
you can then fix that process and do it right consistently.
You can make it
-- necessarily.
-- I mean, look, if we put back in the context of Tetris,
if you're holding the controller the old way,
you will not beat the people doing the new,
the new ways.
But I mean, I think that's the thing is people embracing tools when they're new.
Yeah, they're,
they're probably going to be like I can build a
better hamburger than I can buy at mcdonald's maybe,
I don't know, I've never had your hamburgers.
Uh They're pretty sweet. But um
that's the thing like
in using somebody else's tool.
It's kind of like why open source took a long time to
catch on is using open source at 1st 20 years ago.
A lot of it was maybe not as good as what you could have built,
but
that chip has now sailed. The open source is matured, it's been improved.
It's gone to this utility space of,
I mean, like image parsing libraries or web servers. Like if you think you can build
a web client,
go talk to, you know, Mr Curl,
-- you, no, you cannot build as good a web client as curl
-- well and, and look,
I think open source is another good example where when you
and I were getting to the world of open source,
it was not
the obvious winner. It is today.
I remember people telling me that I was throwing
my career away by getting involved in open source.
And of course, being a young person with all my altruistic ideals, I was like, no, no,
this is, this is the right way.
This is the future. Everything will be this.
And of course, from my perspective, I thought it was the
altruistic right thing. And that's why it would succeed.
It actually turns out that businesses love lots of free software,
but that's kind of another story.
But you know what I mean? I I think
that's another example of once everyone started using open source, it became
something you couldn't ignore
because your competitors are doing it better.
If you don't,
-- you just fail, you cannot beat them by definition,
-- pace of innovation,
change like the change rate of innovation, right?
You look at those graphs of like how fast
were TV S radio versus electricity versus whatever adopted,
right?
And every single technology adoption curve keeps getting steeper and steeper.
And
what gets me is the one of the biggest problems is
time is a finite resource.
So if you are spending time and especially effort and money
and other less finite resources like money.
You know,
some companies have a lot of money and they
can just throw money at problems and burn it.
It's fine.
But time is not like we all have 24 hours in a day and,
you know, you can do something to buy time, like get a cleaner.
But fundamentally if you're doing it yourself and you're,
if you're giving up time by building stuff,
you're gonna lose on the pace of innovation
and somebody else is going out innovate you,
right?
Like what always gets me is Amazon's
constant fire hose of new
services
for Aws.
And what gets me is like, I remember, I think it was this year
2021 Digital Ocean announced managed databases like
Amazon R DS relational database service.
And I'm like,
wait, you, you just got that now in 2020 or 2021.
Like, are you kidding me?
Yeah. But I bet Amazon's
probably their,
their security team is three or four times the size of Digital Ocean's workforce.
I
know, but the problem is like Digital Ocean,
they're innovating at like one or two new services a month.
Whereas Amazon's doing 10 or 20
Amazon's also building stuff that then lets them build on top of that, right? So,
like if you are internal at Amazon and
you build a service that requires data storage.
Cool. You just use S3
or
elastic block store or whatever.
Like, you don't have to build that part as evidenced by yesterday's outage where,
you know, one thing failed and it took out a huge pile of
Amazon stuff
and then that in turn took out like Disney and Netflix and Amazon's delivery and,
you know, all that stuff.
But that's a great example, this hacker news thread.
It's like, oh, why didn't the Amazon Flex app, you know,
that they use for their delivery drivers have
like fail over and redundancy and blah,
blah, blah.
And they're like, because you have like one outage a year,
just eat the loss and don't spend time.
Like
if my Devs said, oh, we're gonna, we're gonna start,
we're gonna spend a couple of sprints engineering for reliability in case Hiroko
fails. I'd be like, no, you're not
like, no, don't do that. That's a waste of time.
-- I
-- mean, in most instances, I would agree now, I,
I think there's something really important.
We need to be mindful of it.
It's easy to talk about how Amazon is
currently outpacing a great number of their competitors.
But at the same time,
just because they're, they're big and they can move pretty quickly,
doesn't mean they can't be disrupted because you also have to admit
that a lot of Amazon services are kind of crappy and stupid.
Amazon themselves disrupted everything 20 years ago.
-- I mean,
-- they did,
they were like a weird little online bookstore
and well, here we are
and, and that's the thing, somebody,
somebody will come up with.
So we've already agreed that, you know,
serverless and function as a service is probably the way to go along.
Like that's the next generation. But kind of what comes after that.
And the answer is, well, I don't know,
but some people are going to figure stuff out, try stuff and
one of them is gonna work probably a lot better than what we have.
So something else to think about here
is it's possible nothing comes next.
Look at electricity like there's interesting
things happening where you generate electricity.
There's interesting
things happening how you consume electricity. Like I now plug my car into the wall.
That's interesting. That's not something I would have imagined 20 or 30 years ago.
But the point is like
the utility of the grid is relative
relatively static.
I mean, I know there's smart grid and a lot of work going on. But you know what I mean?
Like
it's not the place you're seeing the innovation,
you're seeing the innovation on the ends.
And I think when you think of utility computing,
it's kind of a similar thing where the utility computing is becoming the power grid.
It's what you're building on either side of that, that I think becomes interesting.
Those utility systems allow higher order behavior.
Right. Right. Because I now have a utility
compute grid. Like if I don't like Amazon, I can go use Azure or Google or
Tencent Baidu or whatever.
Like, I just,
I was just like 20 years ago. What would you do if you had to build a web server?
Well, the answer is you had to hire at least one competent admin.
Go by about 20 to 40 units of rack mount gear. Find a colo, get it all up and running.
Good luck.
-- And
-- now that's like the old way of playing Tetris.
And now if you just hold the controller a little different, but now there's,
I guess there's one other piece of this that we should kind of,
we'll bring ourselves home on is
just knowing how to hold the controller
isn't enough.
Because if I handed you a controller and told you this new way, they,
they call it rolling
to play Tetris,
you couldn't do it.
You probably have to practice for hundreds and hundreds of hours.
And I think this is another thing that becomes intimidating
when you're someone who already knows a certain way.
Like if all of my knowledge is focused on
servers
in data centers that you have to ssh into or whatever right there,
when you look at Cloud, it is terrifyingly complex and different.
And so do you also have to have to accept and acknowledge that
there's a certain amount of learning
and difficulty in failing that's gonna come with that.
Well, and, and even more I think,
difficult and this goes back to our show on being an expert is you also have to take
your existing knowledge and separate out which of your
existing knowledge can still be used but applied differently.
So, like I know a ton about email delivery
and I apply that to cloud services.
Now, I will never ever hand to, you know, a Bible, ever run a mail server.
Again, it's just not gonna happen. I will always use like an API or something.
Um And secondly,
if that information is still useful and can be applied great,
but you'll have a bunch of information that is not useful and cannot be applied like
um
oh, I know how to basically recover like a crashed hard drive.
Yeah, it doesn't matter anymore. Back blaze.
Like I have stuff in the cloud or I have back blaze.
And so like I realized when I, when I reinstalled,
I installed Windows 11 clean on my son's computer
and I realized there's nothing to worry about.
Like he's like, oh, I need my chrome to work and I'm like, yeah, you just log in,
it'll be fine,
right? There's like steam. Ok? Steam will just all his games will be there.
Like everything
-- will just magically work.
-- I have a great,
I have a great example of this is so
my son built his own computer, right? And he was using one of mine
as his like gaming PC. And he's like, I want to build my own.
And so he buys all the parts and he built it and that's like,
you know, and of course, because they all, all the kids watch Linus Tech tips.
Now they want to like, it's all pristine on the inside.
It's nothing like the rat's nest. Everything's got RG BS and whatever.
And then I told him, I said, hey,
do you want me to yank the hard drive on
this old computer so you can copy your data over?
And he looks at me, he's like, why would I do that?
I was like, oh
right,
all in the cloud.
And then
he spent a couple of days red downloading his games and like that was it. Yeah.
-- No, it's, it's, yeah, it's a brave new world.
-- It's so different. I love it.
And, and that's the thing is
not only do you have to use this new tool and, and
practice with it and get better at it to get to where
you were assuming you're like a proficient carpenter or infosec professional.
And see that's the secret.
Most people are not a good carpenter and
most people are not a good infosec professional.
Most developers are developers, not
infosec people.
And so even a not great, like I have a Swiss army cyber knife,
which I love my mom gave it to me.
Oh God, probably two decades ago.
-- And it's got really great torque bits on it, which
-- it's called a Cyberknife.
It's called the Cyberknife because it had like,
it's got like the perfect actual little screwdriver with
the four bits for actually taking laptops apart.
Like it is,
it's magical. It's not the one with the USB Cyberknife.
I think it was called the Cyberknife.
Or maybe I'm thinking of the one with the USB drive built into it.
Right.
But anyways, the point is,
um, even like I, I use, like,
it sits on my desk and I use it probably once a week to
take a screw out of something or put a screw back into something.
And is it as good as, like, I actually have a set of real screwdrivers and everything?
No, it's not as good as those, but it's on my desk and it's handy
and it's infinitely better than trying to use a butter knife to get a, you know,
a flathead screw out of a electrical socket, you know,
to change the wall plate or whatever.
So that's the thing. Right? Most people even given, not a great tool
are gonna be so, like, ok,
me with my chop saw, like my arm saw versus a,
like a really skilled person with a handsaw.
Will I be as perfect as in him or her?
No, but will I probably get a lot more wood cut a lot faster? That's close enough?
-- Well, I, I would, ok. And
-- once I practice
with it I'll get really good with it.
-- I,
-- I think this is a good example but I don't think you have the right
outcome.
I think if you compare a professional with a handsaw,
they could say cut a very straight cut.
But they've also been doing it for like 20 years.
I, you can take,
you know, a fancy power saw
and you could make a straight cut with like three minutes of understanding.
And I think that's the difference and that's actually
a marvelous example that I will end on is
this tooling
in the right context?
Can,
can take someone who maybe doesn't have 20 years
of knowledge and make them proficient right away.
And more importantly,
I don't have 20 years to become proficient. I want to be productive now.
Yeah. Right. Yeah. Imagine, I mean, imagine any of us in the computing world.
Two years of knowledge is
ridiculous to think about at the, at the rate we move. Absolutely. I'm calling it
Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening. Go to open our
security podcast.com. Hit up our show
notes, use a
Pound Os podcast. Hashtag Do hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too.
-- Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.