Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
and my partner in commentary, Josh Bresser
-- commentary. I thought it was Thought Crime. Well, I
-- thought
-- that
-- was the
-- today's theme. Is
-- it?
I guess it is commentary. It, it's a number of comment related topics
-- that we want to discuss. Let's set the stage, shall we?
-- So several?
I actually just, I'm looking it up. When was the whole FCC comment
controversy?
It's always been going on.
So there is an article from Schneier that we will put in the show notes,
basically pointing out the fact that in one of the recent FCC.
-- So it was 2017.
-- Was it 27? That's pretty recent. It was like
a decade ago,
-- a decade
-- ago,
years.
Oh, in COVID years, that's fair.
But basically what happened was anytime I shouldn't say any time,
but it is quite normal in the FCC world and in a lot of the government in
general where they will have like public comments
where people can voice their opposition or agreement,
stakeholders can voice there.
You got to remember stakeholders,
whatever humans are stakeholders in most of these.
-- No
-- Well, no, you're thinking of corporations,
well, corporations ultimately get to make the decisions.
But basically the idea is that comments come from humans
and then the FCC can weigh those comments one way or the other
and then
decide, well, take that into account where obviously the intent being,
if there's a lot of we'll say comments for or
-- against that could help sway the decision making
-- well,
or people bringing up a topic or an issue that wasn't thought to be as bad as it is or.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, that's fair. You know, like a lot of people, I,
for example,
I think a lot of people misunderstand how completely crap rural broadband is.
And I know a lot of people who live early and have, you know,
those long range wi Fi connections and for example,
they can't do more than one video call at a time
or more than one sort of major activity at a time
because the jitter is so bad,
you're sure they're getting, you know, 10 or 20 megabits per second download.
But the minute they start uploading or, you know, using it heavily, it,
it basically falls apart,
you know.
And so a lot of people like, oh, but, or, you know,
they have satellite internet and it's like you,
you can't video over a half second delay
and in some cases, you know,
people have been posting their stats and it's multiple seconds. So
I think comments are really valuable in a, in some cases where,
oh, no, it actually like 80% of people have this problem.
It's not just once in a while, it's actually the majority, you know,
or even it's just maybe 10% but still 10% is a lot.
-- That's right. That's right. And that's where a lot of this comes in.
-- Right. Right.
And so what, what Schneier's story covers
is basically there are groups
that have used A I
to we'll say mask that these comments
are all coming from one place.
It's more one layer of abstraction.
These,
these groups use services and in past the services used people and bad scripts
and now they use increasingly
better tools
that look, you know, and appear more human and allow the few humans,
they do have to do a better job because this stuff is a service.
This is a business.
Yeah, absolutely. Which is terrifying. But
I mean, so the reason this matters is historically,
when we'll say you've had these like comment mills,
it has been trivial to figure out where it's coming from.
-- Well, to separate the wheat from the chaff. Right.
-- Right.
One of my favorite examples is the FCC allows
the public to complain about things on the airwaves
and something like 90% of the complaints come from like six groups
and they know this because it's basically just form letters,
people are mailing it to the FCC.
So they have the ability to pretty trivially be like, yeah, whatever,
put it in the pile.
And of course,
when it's six groups complaining that has less weight
when it's say 6000 or 60,000 groups complaining.
But now because of this
A I that has the ability to, you know,
basically make subtle changes to the message in a
way that looks like it's coming from multiple people.
Now, the game is completely different.
Well, it's not even, it's more that they're completely,
they're generating completely
unique in different messages and different viewpoints or different topics.
The Ac Lu did a Reddit A ma
Oh,
my goodness. Yes.
And it got obviously brigade because
the questions basically boil down to.
So the Ac Lu used to be a good organization
but now that you're killing puppies all the time.
Yeah, exactly.
Can you please explain how much of your
budget is going to buying methamphetamines and,
you know, assault rifles with which to blah, blah, blah.
Right. It's just the comments you read them
and it's
obviously
they're, they're inflammatory at, at, at
-- best. Yeah,
-- absolutely.
-- And, and there will obviously be a link to this in the show notes
-- and they're,
they're voted up like it got
Brided. That's true. Right. There's,
there's obviously some sort of, we'll say large scale
effort going on here in terms of what happened on Reddit and
it's,
it's frustrating as a human
to look at stuff like this because obviously we want to think that
like social media works and the comments the government asked for works and
if the AC lu does an A ma that they're going
to get reasonable questions and not get barraged by trolls.
Well, and even worse than trolls organized trolls,
trolls with a strong agenda to discredit the AC lu for example, in this case.
-- Right. Right.
-- And do long term harm.
I mean, in, in their particular instance, I'm hopeful they went so far.
Anyone with any sense will look at it and be like, holy cow.
This is clearly not some people angry with the ac lu, but I mean, it won't,
it won't work for everyone, of course, but it this,
I keep turning this over in my mind and thinking
about it and it's like with all this public,
everything we see right now and like I let,
let's use open source as our example just because it's,
it's one of those things I love to think about what would stop a we'll say,
motivated adversary
from
mounting a similar attack against an open source community like Freno maybe,
right.
Like, but you know what I mean?
-- Well,
-- so that's an interesting thing. So
there are sort of two separate issues here. One, you have sort of the content issue
and number two, did a human being actually generate this?
Now,
the problem with this stuff is that it's high value enough in that you
can have somebody jump through any capcha
hoops or whatever So the question becomes,
how do you strongly prove that a comment was written by a human and not, for example,
copy and pasted by a human working in a troll factory from an A I
system and you can't.
Well, I want to head off one thing right now before we move on is
if you look at any of the comments in any of this stuff, you get a lot of, oh,
-- but if we all had a digital ID that would solve all of the problems,
-- no,
it wouldn't because they'd still be cutting and pasting the
comments generated by the A I to be more efficient.
And that's see, that's,
-- but
-- there's also the angle of trying to assign every human like a unique digital ID
is
fraught with complications and unforeseen problems.
And so I would never condone this as
-- a long term solution for the planet
-- more to the 0.1 that
is accessible enough for other people to make use of it.
Right?
And that's where it goes into Blockchain, digital, you know,
sovereign identity and all that.
But we'll leave that for another day.
Flaming tire fire.
Yes.
But you don't actually see here's the problem.
Even if you did have super strong digital ID mapping,
they would just hire people and for a penny to cut and paste,
right?
And that's the problem is a lot of this
stuff is valuable enough for the bad guys to spend
thousands or tens of thousands of dollars on what is effectively lobbying.
Um, like a great example is, you know,
the thought experiment who benefits from weakening or hurting the AC Lu.
Well, there's a lot of organizations, the AC Lu has sued a lot of governments,
for example.
Well, ok, they're not going to probably do this but a lot of, more by definition,
you know, these private entities that they've sued are
-- by many definitions. Generally not very nice.
-- Right. Right. Absolutely.
And they would happily spend 10 grand to hurt the C the AC Lu or the eff or whatever
these rights organizations are often held up as boogeymen by
other groups of like these groups are the problem,
right?
And so if you can say, oh, my group spent $45,000 to make the AC lu look bad.
-- That's a feather in their hat,
-- the long and the short of it.
Even if we do something like cloud Fflur had
a good thing about using cryptographic attestation of personhood,
using
keys. And it's like,
ok, cool. You can actually map it to the specific
key and that would kind of, you know,
you could tie it an a persona or identity or whatever to a specific piece of
hardware that is typically not shared or easy to share or should not be shared.
Cool.
But again,
you still have the problem with these people
cutting and pasting everything and being like,
you know, I am
every time I look at Twitter
and the the replies, you know,
there's some obvious trolls where they have like three replies, no followers,
no following.
There are all these bot accounts and then some are sometimes some are,
it's hard to tell like this doesn't look like a human
but it's, you know, goes back a couple of years, it has followers, it has followed,
it has like a lot of comments,
but then you start to look at the comments and they're kind of, oh,
this is like machine generated, kind of just weirdness,
you know,
like I'm increasingly noticing just because I've been doing
some Google searches and there's a bunch of unique
terms that are now showing up on these sort
of randomly generated web pages for seo spam.
I actually, I have an example of this is, I don't know if you got the mail,
but we recently got
a couple of males from seemingly different organizations basically saying, oh,
we, we put your podcast on our like top podcast list for the year
and,
and I replied, I replied to them with like,
OK, you put us on a list like
you, I can't find like there's no social media, there's like nothing here.
Like I want
want more, like show me more
and there's been no replies and they emailed me multiple times and I'm like,
this is clearly some sort of like link farming bot
organization and they're looking for back links to them I'm not,
I'm not playing this game
but like you look at the website and it looks like a real news site.
It's clear someone put some effort into this and
at the same time it's like there's something wrong,
you can put some effort into a bot that then generates all the content.
But as a human being,
I can't tell the difference between bot generated content and real human content.
I mean,
aren't something like almost all the baseball stories
in America now written by a bot.
-- I know some of them are
-- right.
I don't follow baseball,
but I know a lot of earnings stories are now bot written where they feed like the
support into the bat and it spits out just it's a lame story.
But obviously if you're being first is probably
better than being right in that instance.
Well, and is there any, I mean, this, this is an earnings, it's like a baseball game.
There's really kind of only so much that happens short of a UFO landing on the field.
One baseball game is much like the other is,
and I know real baseball fans are gonna like
wanna burn me at the stake for saying this.
But my understanding of baseball is
outside of some corner cases, it's a baseball game is a baseball game.
-- Sorry guys,
-- they can be amusing.
-- Well, yeah,
-- but I mean, there's, there's not going to,
it's not going to be like a political event where it can go completely sideways.
It, I mean, it's, let's say it's rare.
There are instances where there's some excitement at the end of the game.
-- But generally speaking, I would say it's not, it's
-- structured and it's, there's,
there's really only a couple of vote,
there's generally about
a couple of widely accepted outcomes and you can account for those in your bo
same thing with an earnings report.
So that's the thing that gets me about all this is so we
can forcibly map comments and force them to be from a human.
And let's even say we managed to dial it down to an individual human.
So that, you know,
somebody can't submit 50,000 comments as being from 50,000 different people.
But we'd actually know it was from one person.
Well,
then we still have the problem where they hire dozens or hundreds of
people to appear as a authorities on the subject and you know,
spam the bejesus out of whatever forum or commentary or whatever.
So I I part of me thinks the answer here is maybe more transparency.
I would not disagree with that because
we've already established in the finance industry.
Generally speaking, if you write in the finance industry,
you have to disclose any positions held in relation to that company.
Right? I can't, I can't write articles that are pro company a
and I secretly hold, you know, a long positioning company or conversely I write,
you know,
articles dissing company a and I'm shorting their stock because then
it becomes really obvious as to why I'm writing those articles.
Now. I mean, in that context, let's say
I write a letter to the FCC
and I work for a media company. How can you,
I feel like you should have to disclose who you work for.
How do you, how do you enforce that as the problem?
Well, you'd have to spot check these, I mean,
and that becomes part of the challenge too is how do you, you know,
whenever there's a petition, for example,
and people write their name and address and phone number.
Well, you either check some of them or all of them to verify that, you know,
IP freely at 123456 Street actually exists or not
because if you're going to solicit public comment,
isn't it sort of also then incumbent on you to ensure that it's somewhat good?
It's clearly not.
Well, depending on the situation, there are, there are, you know,
regulated industries where they have to solicit com, you know, uh feedback.
So for example, here in Alberta, we have a thing, I,
I know a lot about this because my mother worked for the government.
But the environmental impact and assessment where essentially,
let's say you want to build something like a pulp mill or an oil refinery,
you have to solicit feedback from the community
in a structured way, meaning you hold public meetings
and basically the public gets to go up and Kvetch about things like,
whatever they get to ask questions and, you know, I remember one pulp mill it was,
they basically were like, oh, you know, yeah,
there's going to a lot of logging trucks on this road
but it won't be a big deal because it's about,
you know, it's only one logging truck every, like, 30 minutes or whatever.
And I'm, like, whispering to my mom. I'm like, hang on a second.
Like, do they run logging trucks 24 7?
Because I don't think that's how logging trucks work. She's like, no, they don't.
I'm like, so wait, if they're running for, like, 12 hours a day,
that's one every 15 minutes
and these things are big and loud, she's like, yep. Yes, they are.
You know.
And so, like, the company's not lying,
but they're misdirecting and a great example being
orphaned wells in Alberta right now,
we have this huge tens of thousands of orphaned
oil and gas wells that have been abandoned.
I read about this. It made the news around here.
-- Yeah,
-- it's going to be in probably long term.
It's probably going to be in the tens of
billions of dollars to clean up and remediate.
You know, the oil and gas industry has basically managed to kind of astroturf this,
that it's not that big of a deal, but of course,
landowners are starting to speak up now and increasingly, it's like
they haven't been paid for the usage of this
and there's like bad smells,
there's noise complaints from like the motors and stuff.
There's health concerns, like hydrocarbons are not good to breathe in
and, you know, groundwater pollution, things like that.
A lot of these guys, you know, they have wells for water, right.
They're out in the middle of nowhere.
So,
but the oil and gas industry has basically managed to
kind of publicly kind of make this go away.
Like people aren't really all that freaked out about it.
Well, and now from what I read,
there's a bunch of wells that are done because they became unprofitable.
And the companies were like, oh, well, we're bankrupt now.
-- Sorry that
-- well, no, no, no.
What they do is they typically sell those
wells to another entity that then declares bankruptcy.
Oh, I see. I see.
It's not our, we, we sold it to, you know, Xyz Corp and Xyz Corp is gone tough. Uh
I know, I know.
And so that's, that's one of the challenge with all these things is
again, you know,
is it 99% of land own with these wells on
their properties are concerned or is it only 1%?
We don't know.
The point is if we solicited these comments publicly, guess what would happen,
right?
-- The people with money to kind of abuse this would do so.
-- Almost definitely.
Ok, let's, let's reel ourselves back into talk about A I one comment
that I don't know and someone else might know and I can probably look this up later is
I do not know if the FCC asks
if I work for a media company
when I fill this stuff out.
But now at the same time,
if a media company is paying another company to pay people to copy and paste A I,
they can probably click.
I don't work for a media company because they technically don't.
Oh no, there's all sorts of ways around this.
Basically, none of this matters because whatever barriers a roadblock they put up
there, there's an incentive to engineer around them,
right? Just like GDPR. GDPR was like this.
Hail hailed as the solution to, you know, privacy and data, whatever.
But wait a minute, why aren't Google and Facebook worried at all?
Oh, this is toothless, you know,
and now we have cookie warnings that eat up two minutes of your day,
-- every day for the rest of your life
-- right now.
Now, here's one of the
I think important aspects of especially like GDPR is, it is not perfect,
it has holes so big you can drive a truck through,
but it is the first step of a long journey.
And so I think one of the one of the challenges we face as humans is we like to say, oh,
that didn't work,
we should give up instead of saying that didn't work.
How do we slowly fix it to get to where we want to be.
And like all these FCC comments are the same deal. It's like, oh A is can,
can astroturf FCC comments like it's all broken. It's like, no, it's not.
The comment stuff makes sense.
And the FCC soliciting comments from humans is a good idea.
But how do we, how do we turn the knob in a way
that makes it
useful again? Because it's clear that the bad guys have
surpassed our ability to figure out what they're doing.
And one simple example of this is the my understanding
now is the majority of politicians don't care about email,
right?
They get a million emails on an issue. They don't care,
they care about voice, phone calls and physical letters,
right?
There's even, it's funny, there's one,
I think it's an ML A or a member of parliament to forget which locally that
refuses to do email and everybody's like, oh,
but how do their constituents contact this person, blah, blah.
And he's like, basically emails a cesspool. It's just,
it's, it's always like just garbage.
You can contact me via and I'm pretty sure it's an
MP because you can physically mail your MP for free.
Like literally, you, you put their address on it and it goes there for free.
It's, it's, that's clever.
It's, it's, well,
it's been written into law for since the beginning or you
can phone the person and leave a voicemail or whatever,
which
-- you know what that seems reasonable. So
-- I call my representatives a lot.
I'm highly opinionated as should surprise nobody.
I would say 80% of the time a human picks up and even when they don't,
they call me back and my voicemails will say are are clearly not on the will say
the side of the issue,
many of my representatives are known to be on and they still will call me back.
Yeah,
I always get like a response letter that's like we value your response and we blah,
blah, blah.
-- And I live in a Yeah, I live in a writing but
-- the letters I won't,
the letters are always basically like f off and die. We don't care what you think.
But I would say the phone calls are a bit more pleasant
and receptive and then they probably hang up and be
like you won't believe the person I just talked to.
Pretty much part of me wonders maybe if the solution
is to require physical letters and phone calls because we've
seen online brigade is you get 100 people and even
100 people with no tooling and just mashing their keyboards
can have an outsized
appearance
-- of hundreds of thousands of comments. Right.
-- Oh, definitely, definitely.
I mean, one of my favorites always
is where
there will be some sort of we'll say Twitter thread or Reddit thread or Facebook,
whatever
and
someone especially a politician says something
and then
they clearly meant to log out and log back in as, like, one of their al
counts.
And then they're like, and it's so funny because it's like, ah,
you're just so dumb and
I would guarantee
an enormous number of people have multiple alt accounts. Like, I'm not going to lie.
Like, I've got two Reddit accounts.
One, like, is my nice reddit account and the other one is just, if I want to be a troll,
that's where it goes.
You know, I just
said a long time ago, just not to spend any time or effort doing that.
I generally don't. But every now and then it's like
I need to add a comment to this.
I
agree because there are also people in a lot of situations who need privacy.
You know, for example, somebody has a crazy abusive stalker.
Should they be allowed to go online and use a pseudonym? Absolutely.
More to the point. You know, people have nicknames in real life.
Like we've like, I literally worked for,
nobody explained to me, Richard and Dick. I didn't know about that. So I was,
I was on site, you know, under the foreman, Richard who I knew was Richard
and somebody came into the office and said, where's Dick? And I'm like, I don't know.
And so for like three days,
all these electricians basically thought I was a complete moron because
he's sitting like 10 ft behind me in a you know,
in a little off other space.
And then finally
somebody was like, hey, Dick and Richard was like, yeah, what do you want?
I'm like, wait, is your name Richard or Dick?
And he's like, no, my name is Richard but you know,
everybody calls me Dick. And I'm like,
why,
why is that your nickname? He's like, no, that's, it's like William and Bill,
what's
how, what John and Jack
were two that went together as well?
See, this is, this hurts my brain
like
John. So John F Kennedy was often called Jack Kennedy.
And in fact,
what's really funny is the reason I know
Richard and Dick is because of Richard Nixon.
Yeah.
Well, and in hindsight now it's, it's, yeah, it's like,
-- oh tricky dicky
-- and you know why I know they called Richard Nixon
Dick is because when I was in like seventh or eighth grade,
my history teacher told us
the media would call him tricky dick.
And when you tell that to a bunch of teenagers, holy cow,
the class lost it.
It's tough because on the one hand,
I want to allow people to submit good anonymous comments.
I want people to be allowed to use pseudonyms and you know,
pseudo anonymous
accounts and I want people to be able to use their real name if they want to
and, and strongly attribute their comment to what, you know,
like I see with a lot of this COVID related commentary where on the news it's,
you know,
so, and so doctor of epidemiology, it's like,
oh, that's good to know.
You know,
this isn't just some random nut big spewing off.
Exactly.
And so I, but how do you do this digitally? And the answer is like, we have no idea.
No, we don't, we don't know today.
And
so,
so here's the question and here's where we should
kind of bring this one back home is so,
so we don't know how to necessarily identify people digitally today.
So what it
is it more beneficial to society to just shut down on digital comments or do
we accept the fact that digital comments are going to be like 80% toxic waste
and start to work out a way to sort them
sort through them and kind of pick out the real ones
worried about the toxic waste.
And I'm more worried about the attempts at manipulation. Same thing, same thing.
No, no, no, no toxic waste and trolling and abuse online.
Cool, whatever, it's whatever. But when for example, a group like
Russia
starts fiddling with your elections.
-- That's a problem, right? And so I would separate that.
-- OK. Ignore toxic.
Then take pretend I never said that. And let's just focus on manipulation.
I think with the manipulation,
the best thing I've ever seen for kind of all of that is that transparency piece.
Who said this? Why did you say this?
You know, for example, another thing I've seen that I like is
some forums require you to not just sort of make a comment but explain why
or cite some evidence, you know, have some sort of
academic standard if you will to,
to cut out all the low hanging fruit and maybe that's part of the solution, you know,
you have to have citations.
Have you ever read Twitter?
Yeah.
Well, exactly.
And, and there are people, like, for example, I post those tweets with and you
-- the shell script to verify the numbers I just posted.
-- I truly appreciate that.
-- But what I suspect also no one, no one
-- runs it. I'm trying to do the best I can. And so
I think transparency is a big piece and I think the problem is that
the people reading this and that are affected by this don't care generally,
you know, that I hate to lump it in.
But you know, the kind of person who listens to Fox news incessantly,
right?
And all the studies when they've tested
people's knowledge of current events and news,
all the Fox news viewers score at the bottom.
I've I've seen those studies as well.
We can post them in the link or you can Google it whatever citation I'm not
-- posting
-- links to that.
Yeah, but I mean, that's the point,
right is I I tend to try and ensure what I'm saying is correct.
The problem is the people spewing this
manipulative stuff have the exact opposite incentive.
Right. Right.
Think a big part of it would be for, would be transparency and where possible,
allowing people to strongly tie an identity to it so that, you know,
I don't like arguing from authority, but if we're going to talk about medical stuff,
I'm going to probably listen to the people who are medical doctors more so than
everybody else.
I mean, look me and that's a great example though. Right?
Because you've got in the COVID pandemic, you've had literal doctors
talking
and then you've got Big Don Internet 16 saying, oh, well,
I read this on a website and an enormous number of people are being like doctors.
What do they know
exactly? Medical science.
I don't even know what to say about some of these conversations
I've seen people have where it's like I have no comment.
It's like,
I feel like
this is a situation where it's like this is the color blue,
this thing here is blue. Do you see they're the same? And then someone else is like,
nope, that's not right. And you're like,
I agree with that guy. He has no evidence. He's not.
I don't even, you know, he clearly has never seen color in his life before,
but I'm going to agree with him.
And it's like, how do you, how do you deal with that? You know? Yeah.
-- Well,
-- and then to one of the waters is again back to, you know,
even if you get consensus still.
There's going to be one or two outliers who disagree.
Like there are medical doctors who are against masking and it's kind of like, oh,
dear.
And then so they cherry pick their evidence,
you know, it's like global climate change, right?
The vast,
vast majority of anybody with an ounce of scientific knowledge agrees with this.
You know, the evidence all agrees with this,
but there's a few outliers and of course they go, what about this guy?
You know, he's right.
And then they use the famous, like Albert Einstein argument of like, yeah,
they're going against the flow and you'll be proven wrong
in a decade and you'll see how right we were.
It's like, I don't think so, but whatever, II, I don't know, I, I do think
the ease of which manipulation now occurs, especially on places like Facebook.
So I think in recent times,
Facebook is probably about the worst thing that has
happened to Western democracy and democracy in general.
And, you know, but at the same time, it's, it's clear that we can't shut it off
-- or even fix it. Maybe
-- it is a delicate balance.
Now, I did read something the other day that I will try to locate,
but I don't think I can, it was talking about the fact that
if you look at a lot of the minority communities and getting messages out, like,
for example, the, the level of we'll say
police misconduct in the United States
is
it has been an enormous story for the last probably year.
And the fundamental reason for that is these minorities
communities have found a voice in social media.
And so it's, it's one side to say like Facebook is bad for a functional democracy,
but on the other side,
it's also empowering these groups because they
have social media to amplify their message.
And so
-- it's such a complex ridiculous problem.
-- I don't know.
How do we make it harder for people to do the,
how do we basically implement the evil bit? That's what we need. We need the evil bit.
Well, and, and not just that, like
all of the vast majority of what we've talked
about so far today is really been people driven,
but once we unleash the robots,
it becomes an entirely different problem.
And now I have no doubt someone is going to
send me a comment
of the weird
system in the book, Dodge or what is it Dodge or burn in hell.
-- Oh, yeah. Yeah, I know what you mean
-- where they, they basically just,
they astroturf the internet
to make social media comments worthless. And like I'm not saying
that's the wrong answer.
They use masking where they just flood it with so much other crap. But
you can't,
-- you can't see it and it's fall or Dodge and
-- hell fall or dodgin hell. That's it.
That's it.
And I've often thought about that because I you know,
there's only four Curt
Seares on the planet. So it's pretty easy to find me online.
And
obviously, if you do things like minus security, then you get, you know,
it narrows it down quite a bit
and I kind of wondered about writing a bot
that floods Facebook with a constant stream
of gibberish and Twitter with gibberish and
all these other places because there are
professional services that will do this for you
in order to make things like, you know,
that one time I drove over a, you know, I,
I drove a busload of nuns into a river and killed them all.
You know, I'd like, I can't make that go away,
but I can put so much other junk on the internet that it's hard to find.
It's on page 17.
That's what, that's what Boris Johnson did with his, his, I paint buses. Right.
He got the press to Astroturf away his bad stories. Exactly.
And so
I,
the one
answer would be using artificial intelligence to process this
and maybe summarize it or maybe kind of help.
But the problem is there's no real strong market for that.
I'm not going to pay for that.
No, I, I agree.
And I mean,
that's maybe one of the challenges and now we just need competing like a I turf wars
and
I don't know, I don't know, we've, we've run ourselves out of time
and I feel
probably more confused now. Than I thought I was when we started this conversation.
So I, I guess, you know what, you know, it gives me hope and, and here's how I'll, I'll,
I'll end it is, this is a hard problem and there's not going to be an easy answer for it.
But I feel like
as long as it's discussed and understood
that there will, we will find an answer.
It's when we throw our hands in the air and say it's too hard. I give up that it is over.
-- I have no doubt we can solve this.
-- I love that right now.
And A I ethics and morality is becoming a real issue.
And you know,
some of the kerfuffle around Google and that retracted paper and all that.
But the fact that that's happening publicly and we're discussing it, that's,
that's a,
that's a step forward.
Yes, it is. It is how we start.
So.
All
right, I'm,
I'm calling it. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
If you made it this far. Congratulations. Go to open source security podcast.com.
Hit the show
notes,
Pound
Os S podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media. Kurt.
You have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You
-- too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the