Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast
episode 149 with myself Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime,
Josh Bresser.
-- Hey,
-- Kurt.
And today we have a guest, we have Michael Coats,
who is the CEO and co-founder of Altitude.
Say hello, Michael.
-- Hey, everyone.
-- This is Michael here.
Awesome. So why don't you tell us a little bit about yourself, man?
Yeah. Yeah, definitely.
Well, man, I've, I've been in the security industry for, uh,
it feels like a long time now.
Probably I think 15 years.
Nice.
Yeah, I'm really happy to have seen security from so many different angles.
I really got my appreciation and cut my teeth.
Uh, you know, back in the day as, as a, as a red teamer, external,
external and internal penetration tests for
governments and banks every week going
out and doing a different assessment was such a lot of fun,
such a learning experience.
Um But yeah, I've been in the industry a long time, um,
had the opportunity to do some exciting things along the way.
Um, you know, led security for Mozilla for
about four years
was the c soft Twitter most recently.
And then, uh,
yeah, just about a year ago, uh, finally made the big jump and said, hey,
there's a big gap in the security space for a solution.
Uh, I personally needed it real bad before. And so did my peers. So
why not jump in and go build it?
And that's, uh, that was the beginning of altitude networks. Yeah.
So that's what I've been up to, traveled.
The world worked in security, have a great family
out here in San Francisco and
like we all are living in the good.
Awesome. So why don't you tell us a little bit about altitude?
I'm I'm intrigued by what you're up to.
Yeah, you know, I had this,
this realization when I was at Twitter and we kept adopting
a
applications from Google Drive to Box and, and, and the like,
and the problem kept coming up was how do we extend our visibility and control
into the SAS application space?
Um You know, every company has solid investments in their on prem security,
uh you know, positioning.
But when you have situations where all of your
sensitive data is out there in the cloud,
how do you start to control that?
How do you know when
people are making mistakes and sharing documents with people
inside the company or out that they shouldn't be
um or maybe an employee um is compromised
and downloads thousands of documents or a contractor leaves
but still has access via their old uh work email account.
You can't just cut off that work email from the contractor, the other account.
And so this started to really become a big pain and
a big sense of a big source of risk for us.
Looking at the solutions out there,
there was really nothing that was integrating and providing the
value that we were looking for at the time.
And when I talked to my peers, um
I'll tell you, the cio cio groups are the best.
If nothing else, they're a support group.
Um But we had
fantastic co group out here in San Francisco and as I talk to them,
uh they weren't, you know, tell me, oh,
just go use this product or go go use this approach.
They're saying the same things like man, we are,
we are equally concerned about this. It's a, it's a rat's nest in there.
We have no idea what's going on, no way to fix it.
And so I said, well, you know,
we could do the standard Silicon Valley thing and build another in-house tool and,
and, and do that.
But I thought, you know,
there's probably a lot of other companies that need this solution.
And so that was the beginning, jumped out there to,
to found altitude networks.
My, my co founder came out of capital one and a good friend of mine. Yeah.
And together we're solving that problem of how do you integrate into
all these SAS applications uh understand what's happening with your data,
uh
continuous evaluation style and then have integrated control to both fix issues
and uh integrate policies to prevent them from happening again.
So it's,
it's been a wild ride so far and we're
pretty excited about the excitement our customers are having,
we have a product out there already, which is pretty awesome.
Yeah, I know, I know. The uh the cloud Secure Alliance is 100% cloud based and that's,
it's been an ongoing challenge to see
what's going on in box.com, what's going on in Google Drive.
-- It's very nontrivial problem to solve.
-- Yeah.
And then even once you start to understand it,
you get back to some of our classic security
paradigms where like look at the target breach,
they had a SIM installed, they had all the data flowing into their SIM,
but just having the data does not help you.
It was one log, you know, of tens of thousands and it was missed.
Uh And so there's really the shift and this is something we experienced
in other things we did at Twitter, which was
automate everything.
If you're operating at a human scale, you don't, you don't have a chance.
And so that's kind of one of the,
the principles that we've taken to what we're doing is how
do we remove as much as possible humans from the equation?
-- That,
-- that's huge.
I agree with that because I would, I, I know that everyone always says, you know,
you humans can scale linearly,
-- but I have suspicion they actually scale logarithmically, not
-- linearly,
logarithmically bad.
Right. And this is something I've had to explain to people.
Like, I, it's funny, I actually had my devs come to me and they're like, oh, you know,
Kurt, should we be monitoring all the CV S?
Right. Because they kind of think of me as the CV guy
and I was like, no, actually, no, we shouldn't. And they were quite shocked, right?
Because, well, we have to monitor these, don't we? And I'm like, no, because
how often do you guys update the software and pull new depths and they're like,
you know, 23 times a week.
-- And I'm like, ok, so like you're updating the software every two days.
-- Yeah.
Yeah.
And if your,
if your patching policy is all issues are patched within max 72 hours average 30.
Like, that's incredible. Like people aspire to that in their dreams.
But man, then you get into that other,
other kind of thing that's biting everybody was, which is,
you know, we think about all these really crazy uh security exploits,
these esoteric issues.
But
inventory management,
like just knowing which machines and software you have to even patch them.
Like your patch policy policy is amazing provided,
you know about all the software to patch.
Well, yeah, the Equifax breach, the classic example of that.
Yeah, exactly.
And that's what's so weird is you get people
talking about all sorts of crazy new things.
Like
we just need to know what systems you have and,
uh,
and people are blown away. They're like, what do you mean?
You don't have a good inventory?
Like, nope, that's probably the dirty little secret of security and every sea
knows it. It's,
we don't really know where everything is and we wish we did and could.
It's not very easy to do.
This is actually one advantage I'm finding of, of
sort of the monthly billing cycle requirements for all the other service things is
we can actually track down like we can basically see, ok,
money is going out to the service provider.
I guess that means we're using it now.
Whereas with, you know, hardware and software, somebody installs it,
plops it on an IP and it's,
it's a ghost.
Yeah. Yeah, definitely.
You know, back to the cloud space, the CASB vendors are really good at that, uh,
that shadow it and reporting problem.
It's a kind of
a,
it's an interesting space.
That's the, uh, the, again, inventory management or what not of, of security,
but it's a good one to have those players,
you know, telling you which new services you signed up for is a, is a good,
good play for them.
So let, let me ask you kind of two things here.
You just said CASB, which I'll have you to find for people who might not know, but then
how is, what you're doing different from AC
A SB?
Oh, yeah. Yeah, great question. Yeah, I think
at
the uh or at the infancy of uh cloud security.
So when you say even cloud security people will correctly say, well,
do you mean is or pass or SAS or, you know?
And so that's good. Um
But yeah, CASB stands for cloud access security broker,
as I kind of mentioned to you before, they were a,
a space that was created at least in my opinion, you know,
share your thoughts but was created in response to the
uh explosion of, of cloud services and cloud platforms that companies could adopt.
Employees would go and use their personal credit cards or maybe
their work credit cards and just sign up for things,
bypassing internal processes and then start expensing them back to the business.
And the business said, wait a minute, what is all this stuff?
You know, you can't just skip our procurement,
you can't just skip security and governance.
Yes,
they can. And so
exactly, exactly. They, they did it could.
And so in response to that, you know, uh some vendors said, hey,
we can put a device on your perimeter, we can monitor all these transactions.
They've since combined perimeters with API S
and, and they do a great job on, on that shadow it problem.
Um They have of course expanded into um other spaces in
cloud security but to your question of what's the difference is,
is very much like talking about
network security as a whole versus a very targeted
solution that's finding a very specific and hard problem.
And that's really where we are,
we are going deep into this data security inside of SAS applications.
And so we can find things that are
very granular and very important to your organization.
Like
did this employee just share this board deck with their personal email account
all of that context that connects those dots that says, oh, that is incredibly bad.
That small needle in this massive haystack is incredibly important to us.
And thank God you pulled that out very accurately.
And so we go deep into what is the type of information, what is the sensitivity,
what is the relationship graphs?
So we can start to do all that analysis to find,
find those problems surface them accurately and
then have integration paths into your workflows.
And and that's another interesting point because integration
workflows goes back to the orchestration security space.
And so I see these, these interesting trends where
we have explosions of investment and technology in areas that
people need solutions and some of them are workflow related,
some of them are inventory related, some of them are
uh almost deep specific problems.
Um And so we're excited to focus on that, that new problem of
who is collaborating with whom
and what data is being exchanged and then bringing in the best of the other areas,
which is how do you have intelligent workflow automation so that the system can work
-- at the scale of a security program?
-- Nice.
Now, now, does,
do you guys integrate with other like SIM style solutions
or are you kind of stand alone right now?
Well, we're early, you know, we're like I said, we're one year in.
So we're, we've got the uh the engine running, we can come in,
walk in the door and give you,
uh I would say a surprising amount of value.
This is kind of an untapped green field and people are like, wait,
who is sharing what you like?
Oh my God.
I can only imagine the first conversations you have
where
people don't even have a clue what's going on.
And oh my goodness, it's got to be epic.
It's exciting from our kind of security mind, exciting. It's really not as
you know, I can see on the other side, you kind of have mixed emotions like, oh,
this is, this is bad.
I'm glad I know it. And from our side, like our job is to find these things. So success.
-- Let's
-- shift gears a little bit.
I've got a question that I've been thinking about a week knowing
I get to talk to you is I feel like we're seeing
this weird nexus point
of privacy and data security and like GDPR
comes into play here and there's companies worried about
their secrets getting out of the internet and companies
are uploading essentially confidential information to third parties,
you know, like in Google Docs and things like that.
And I'm just curious to get your opinion of your,
your general thoughts of the data landscape and if you have any,
I guess, insights into where you might think we're headed.
Oh, yeah, that's a fantastic, fantastic question.
Um I think it is so apropos because as I have talked about the change in security,
um I think there's a massive shift from the way we used to think about security,
which was
perimeters, internal and external attacker, putting your layers of defenses,
all of those things are fine and they're not wrong now, but they are not the focus.
And I think everything is shifting towards what I
like to call a data first security program.
And this was something that I put into practice at
Twitter.
And the nexus of that thinking is
why are we making these arbitrary boundaries where
we think Attackers live like a perimeter?
Because
when you say we have a strong perimeter, but we kind of have a soft internal center,
but that's OK.
There's not really internal Attackers,
one that's a false premise.
So one, you've got just a false premise to begin with. Exactly.
So the laughter correct.
Um But two,
the other thing you're saying is that if anyone breaches our perimeter,
they're like one vulnerability or one exploit away from totally owning
everything because we can't do anything once they're on the inside.
And so if you combine that, that breakdown of that thinking with the new reality,
which is, you know, business partners outsource workers,
um interconnected systems,
uh cloud use all of those things like the whole thing just totally falls apart.
And so the shift has to be to data first security.
And so what that means is wherever your most
sensitive data lives that matters to your company,
you start right there and you say,
how do we know who's accessing that data in its current spot?
And that's deep inside your internal network
and you have internal services access in it
like, all right. Well, we can figure out these services that access.
Well, who's calling the services? How do you know if those are being abused?
And so you work from concentric circles outward,
so there's no need to spend tons of time on your perimeter with the next latest,
next gen whatever if you can't tell me who
internal to your company is even accessing the data.
Uh And this is,
this makes perfect sense with the shift in the overall landscape like privacy.
Uh GDPR
uh the expectations of on companies on how they
protect data is rising to the level that is
reasonable.
We've been in a state for many years where
it's unreasonable people are just like uh whatever,
like please don't get breached generally,
but
now we're at the right spot
now, we are saying you cannot have your data breach.
You cannot not even know where your data is flowing.
And that was one of the great things with GDPR is
it forced companies to do an inventory management exercise of
who actually touches your data. Do you even know where it is? And the answer to that?
Just like the other inventory thing before was no people did not know.
Uh And so this was another great forcing function. So
I'm super excited about where we're going. It's hard, do not get me wrong.
This is a hard thing for companies,
but it's the right thing that lets us take technology to
the next level and hopefully lets us use data responsibly.
Uh I'm a big proponent of users having control of their data and being in charge.
I think we're at a constant grappling point between how that plays out with,
with companies and use of data.
But
our, our current forcing functions are, are the right ones that are good.
Yeah.
No, I mean,
that's been the focus of a lot of my work at the CS A is you can give users privacy
but how do we give them privacy but still let
them use and control their data in a useful way,
right?
I mean,
uh I deal with a lot of people in
the financial industry and they can't access Google Drive,
right?
So because their security policy has been, well,
we don't know how to lock this down and prevent
you from downloading Lord knows what from it or putting,
knows what into it.
So we're just blocking drive.google.com.
Yeah, and that's the perfect example of when security can't enable business,
business disabled technology.
And so security is an enabler and can unlock a lot of things.
Um Your your comment about privacy choices
in different um platforms is really interesting
that that was like an instant throwback to one of the big lessons I saw from my time at
Mozilla.
Um and this is,
it's interesting as we secure data and we think about
options for the more uh informed security or privacy aware individuals
because what I found and learned from from my time at Mozilla was that
defaults rule the world
and you can make this sort of skeleton claim
that you support user privacy by having these options.
But if they default off,
then what you're doing is saying the people that really want
it can go and figure out how to use it maybe
and then the rest of you,
I'm going to mine all of your data and you're going to
think I'm doing you a favor of privacy because of my announcement,
but really
you have not figured this out.
And so we saw that the defaults, you know,
99% of the time defaults are what's what's chosen.
And so we,
we really have to avoid this trap of thinking that empowering people with choice
is actually
letting them make an informed choice.
Um Because again, the defaults you pick are what matters the most.
I think you're entirely correct with the defaults because part of it too is
understanding these privacy controls as well is incredibly nontrivial,
even for people in the industry, let alone, you know, my parents or my kids.
So I watched your
Abs
se keynote in 2018, I'll put a link in the show notes and you at one point
point out that it should be easier to do the
secure thing than it is to do the insecure thing,
which I think is basically the opposite of
most things today, right?
Yeah,
I enjoyed that talk.
Thanks for watching it and thanks for anyone who goes and watches it.
It's great talk, man.
Yeah.
You know, the longer I've been in security, you know, I started very,
very deep and very technical
and the longer that I'm in it,
the more I look at other fields like
economics and psychology and
human behavior analysis and think about,
wow, these things have huge impacts on security. And so in that talk, I go into this,
this, this notion of, you know,
what I call academic security and I kind of do
some air quotes which for lack of a better word
like that doesn't buy us a lot if it isn't practically usable.
And my example in the talk is like P GP,
-- it is awesome on paper.
-- I've actually given up on
it,
sadly,
-- after 20 years of trying.
-- Yeah. But on paper, it's amazing.
You know, like there's, you can't fault it. It's totally right,
but nobody uses it. It doesn't actually provide security to humans
because it's not usable and sure there are other use cases, machine to machine,
etcetera.
But
that really gets to me. And when I looked at a security program, you know,
Mozilla and Twitter,
it was really about how do we build these workflows, these paths and in many cases,
these technologies that
make it.
So we're getting security to your point before
security by default because that's the easy path.
And
I think the more we can move technology in a direction of creating
uh reusable components or, you know,
almost bricks that you can build a building um knowing that they have the,
the security built in by default,
that will let people scale and do things securely because it's just not
possible to know all the different iterations of what you should be doing.
And so if we look at that analogy, you know,
you build a building out of bricks or, or whatever, but you know,
each of those components are structurally sound because you bought them
from the right people that have the right test in place,
you don't have to go and retest your bricks
each time you use it.
Um So you just know if you use them in the right way, you get all their guarantees.
And that's kind of the model we have to move to.
That was actually something I did at Mozilla in my first couple of years there.
I sat down with the uh the web team
and said, look,
let's look at your framework and there seems to be some
recurring security problems that are
happening some opportunities we're missing.
Why don't we go in and flip it on its head so that we turn on all the,
the different security settings that we know we need
and have that be your standard build.
And that was a great situation where I came to them
as a security individual from almost a products perspective and said,
here's the objectives we want to achieve.
Those engineers said. All right. Well, we're the engineers, we're the best at this.
Don't tell us how to do it. Just tell us what you want to accomplish.
And together we,
we flipped that
and it worked great.
Then they use this new building and out of the box, they get, you know,
HSTS turned on or,
um, the correct, uh, flags for cross site scripting protection, um,
or whatever it was at the time.
And that was great because when you build it,
that turned out by default, it's a quick fix.
If you have a bug that comes from that setting versus of course,
everyone here knows if you go ahead and try and switch that afterwards,
you have all sorts of cascading failures.
To try and get back up to speed.
So, yeah, this, this whole notion of we have to have the easy path, be the secure path
and there's a lot of ways to get there.
But if we're not aspiring to that, we're going to keep being in this,
this spiral of security challenges, we'll say for lack of a better word.
-- I think,
-- I think we just call it normal now. Right.
Well, I have to say in general web browsers,
especially Firefox and Chrome have gotten
vastly
more secure.
And I mean, and a great example for Firefox is a few, I think it was two weeks ago,
they had that little
uh certificate, whoopsie
um with the extensions, you know, being signed essentially, you know,
Firefox used.
Well, they've had extensions I think pretty much since almost day one or very early.
And, you know, there were a lot of malicious extensions and so with the signing,
they then, you know,
were able to well essentially clean up
the landscape very quickly and very effectively
problem solved.
Yeah, I mean, a signing
to some degree identity or at least a culpability is kind of a huge, a
huge issue in, in a marketplace.
But what,
what's really interesting though is we see the add on marketplace for Firefox,
you know, the chrome extensions.
And then we see of course, the apps in both I Os and Android
and that whole dynamic is,
is really interesting and I'm actually surprised we haven't had people dive in
more and start to tackle it.
I have this lingering fear that there's a ton of scary applications out there,
maybe signed or otherwise.
Um, not specifically in, in Firefox add ons, but,
but when you look at the uh the marketplace, the Android marketplace
and back to the, you know, looping back just a few topics ago,
we were talking about user choice and
informed, informed decision making.
We see that playing out as,
as a classic case study between the two permission models of android and I OS
uh android. Um
you know, had this very, here's all the permissions, you know,
do you want to prove access to this access to that, et cetera?
And I OS has the very
uh we're gonna do all the work for you, um you know, install it or don't install it.
Um And I think that's a really interesting journey to see which one of those works
works better.
And what are the outcomes and what do users even understand is, is going on?
I, I would guess most people have no clue and they just click allow
when you're asked because I mean, I see, I,
I have an Android phone and I get that question all the time, you know,
do you want to this app access your contacts?
And of course, I, I always say no for the most part, but I,
I guarantee someone like my parents,
they don't even know what that means.
Right. And I think that's one of those usability challenges.
Well, the other problem too is, I mean,
either the user is going to choose to use the app or not.
And if they choose to use the app, I've noticed a bunch of apps now that, for example,
uh I actually noticed this really, uh,
last time my kids went and I went to the cabin and they,
they had their ipads but no internet
and some of the games were fine, like Minecraft and all that stuff.
Kind of, the big titles were fine,
but there was a lot of sort of dodgier games they'd
installed that refused to run without access to their ad network,
right? They just flat out refute, like I can't show you ads, I'm not going to run.
All right. So we're, we're kind of approaching the end of our time here, Michael.
So I'm curious if you want to
fill this in with any parting thoughts or ideas or,
or things you think we should watch out for coming or kind of
it? It's your floor for the next couple of minutes. How about?
Yeah.
Yeah, I think,
I think I'd love to, to bring a few of the threads for that we talked about before.
I
think that if we're not adopting this data first security approach,
we're going to be in a lot of trouble.
Um
I, it isn't necessary as you think about
regulations put put upon companies.
Um you know, GDPR, California Data Privacy Act.
Um But, but two that notion of the insider insider attacker,
um definitely, you know, listeners remember that thing.
If, if you're not thinking about insider Attackers,
then you're just saying an external attacker can never get in
which we know is going to fail at some point.
But I was, I was, I don't know if happy is the word,
but I noted in the uh the Verizon data breach report from this year
that they say
privileged misuse in air by insider attack.
Uh Insider accounts accounted for 30% of breaches in one space.
Uh That's a very compelling number, you know, a third.
And what's, it's both insider that's interesting also misuse and,
and this,
this is a very interesting space because
the spectrum of things we need to worry about on one end is the um expert attacker.
And that's a very small percentage. Um You know, when, when
we're saying advanced, you know, threats,
um we don't need to focus on those first.
Those are the toughest of the tough and they're going to take the easiest path.
So, but move back on that spectrum and say, all right, there's casual malice,
there's poor risk decision making
and there's just mistakes.
And so we have to think about that entire spectrum.
Um both focusing on insiders um and thinking about outsiders.
But I think if we pull that together while we think about data for security.
I think that's the way to go and of course, you can Sprinkle in some other nuggets.
We talked about like, uh, secure by default and easy to use,
but maybe not, let's not get ahead of ourselves.
But, um, but I think those are some really important takeaways. And,
uh, you know, if we don't start to think about things in that, in that way,
you run into the risk of what I've seen in other security programs, which is,
you know, you're running around hair on fire. What's the latest headline?
What random, you know,
uh Zero Day came out
and does all of that really matter more than,
I don't even know who touches our most sensitive data every single day.
And so you really got to put it in perspective, which is hard,
it's hard as a security person to do that.
I think that's the way forward through our
very conscious decision making on our strategies around.
What is our plan for data security?
That is an awesome ending.
I,
I love your data for security approach.
That is I'm totally stealing that and I'm going to use
in the future because it's awesome.
I like it.
Wonderful.
Well, thank you so much, man. Thank you, Michael. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. This has been
one of my favorite episodes. I think it's been awesome.
So, yeah, I guess for the listeners you can go to open source security podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes.
You can use the Pound Os S podcast hashtag
to hit us up on social media. Uh, give Michael a follow on Twitter.
His, his tweets are super interesting.
-- Yeah, I guess gentlemen have fabulous rest of your days.
-- Thanks so much.
-- This is wonderful.
-- Thanks, everybody.
Awesome. Thank you, everyone. Bye bye.