Hello and welcome to the hash walk for
she
special of the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
and my partner in.
Thank goodness,
not actually having to update software and ship fixes Josh Pressers.
So
I'm not on the receiving end of this one, but I'm definitely on the other side of it.
Oh, you're on the giving in now at
Encor.
-- Well, kind
-- of, I mean, it's,
it's been a very interesting experience because historically,
anytime something like this happens, I've, I've been part of
company that has to like patch the software and
understand what's going on and kind of all this.
And from the Anchor
perspective, we're helping people detect
what's happening because
Anchor
-- has tools that can like crack open the jar files and look inside
-- Gripe and
uh or something
and gripe are the open source tools and then we have the enterprise tools
and, and some other stuff. And
so it's been really interesting, I think, I mean,
I'm still working like a mule for sure, but I don't feel like the, the impending dread
-- that I would get when I was on the other side of this. We'll
-- say
you know what always got me was, it was no matter and see the problem is, well, ok,
let's name names.
We both worked at Red Hat. Red Hat has a huge software portfolio.
-- Right.
-- It had
over 100 products
higher than that. Now, I'm sure.
Well,
and when I say products I'm talking like all
product would be Red Hat Enterprise Linux with,
what was it?
8000 source RP MS.
Right.
So these aren't like,
like notepad dot exe or something like these are some massive monstrosities.
And what always got me was
no matter how
much time and effort we spent, you know, hunting down, say the XML hash do
or
like a log for J type vulnerability.
It was always in the back of my mind. Did we miss one?
And you know, and the answer is yes. Oh, yeah. Yeah. Of course.
When you have that much software,
the answer is yes.
And
you know. Oh, yeah. I'm so glad I, I
hate to say this but, you know, I got 99 problems and because it's all in the cloud,
they're somebody else's, you know, I outsourced all of that.
Yeah. Right. Right. And I gave up that control and you know what?
It's great because I don't get yelled at for it if it does go bad.
Well, you can still get yelled at, I'm sure. But,
well, I feel like Brad Pitt, you know, it's like I've been chewed out before.
-- It's not that bad.
-- That's
right. That's right.
-- Exactly.
-- But the best part is
because we provide training the CCS K training to companies.
We're getting these vendor supplier questionnaires from like,
like
companies that are really freaked out about
their suppliers being affected by this.
And I just, I love saying it's like
we don't have any Java Code.
Right?
And
we are affected by CV 2021 44 228. We had to update our ubiquity gear,
like we got wireless gear in one office and we had to, we had to run the update
and that's it. We're good.
And I'm just, and to be able to say that with 100% confidence and just to be like,
then I'm done with this,
you know. Oh,
-- I love it.
-- No, I know.
And now I wanna, I wanna start out, we'll say with the kindness hat on
if you're one of the defenders dealing with this, like, God bless you.
God bless you all because this is terrible and it's hard and it's scary
and
it, it,
especially in this particular instance and Kurt
and I will argue about this momentarily.
But like,
I feel like there has been a vacuum of leadership
which means everyone is kind of on their own.
There has. Well, ok, that's true. We both agree. There's a vacuum of leadership.
We don't agree who to blame.
Yes.
Yeah.
But it's,
I, I know what this is like
and you know, peace be with you all.
Well, it's funny, I hate to say this when people are comparing this to heartbleed.
I'm like, when I say I lived through heartbeat, like me and Josh
lived through heartbleed on the sharp end of the stick, like on the,
like my boss almost ended up on the news because he's the guy.
When you report a vulnerability to open a cell, it ends up in his mailbox.
Right? And so like, I hate to say this, but
no heartbleed is like
I would have said in the past heartbleed was a 10 out of 10.
Now, I'd say it's like maybe a good solid seven.
No, I think you can easily say heartbleed was a 10 out of 10. This is an 11 out of 10.
Oh, I'd say it's worse. I'd say it's probably a 12.
That's
fair. And those of the embedded nature of Java, right? That's what kills me.
You can't fix this in half the cases. Like with a heartbeat.
Stick it to less proxy in front. Boom. Done
with this. Oh, just
update Java Jar files that nobody knows where they came from.
They came out of a, made a
repository five years ago
and that's disappeared now.
-- But
-- there's even a more bizarre angle to this that not everyone understands.
So all that has to happen is log for Jay has the parts, a string
that has this goofy JND. I,
you know, we'll say
decorations around it.
And the thing is
you can talk about, oh, sanitize your inputs and all this.
But like these are valid inputs, these are just normal keyboard characters.
And the thing is like you could have a log server, you know,
three layers deep in the corporate network
that
nothing is affected until it hits the log server. And kaboom,
that's exactly like the heart bleed was on the exterior. This one is everywhere.
It's like,
you know what kind of reminds me of it.
It's like the difference between getting a cut on your skin
-- and something like the A I DS virus that hijacks your immune system.
-- Right. Right.
Exactly. And it's just,
it,
that's what makes it so scary is
with heart bleed, you could just be like,
what's everything facing the internet with this one?
It's like, what's everything? Well
and worse, what's everything with Java? Because
here,
if you have a Java application,
I think odds are good that it does some sort of logging.
I think we can all agree on that. It's,
yeah, log for J is very, very widely used.
And then if it does logging, does it use log for J? And the answer is probably, yes,
probably. And by, probably, yes, I mean, almost certainly. Yes.
Just
so. Anyway, anyway,
I want to start
with the, what I will call the perceived leadership vacuum on this issue
and I'm going to pick on the Apache Software foundation. A little bit here
because it's on.
But
I, I think if
there's been a lot of talk about log for Jay is just two
volunteers and they do this in their free time and all this.
But, but it is part of the Apache Software foundation.
The Apache Software Foundation is a real organization
with people working with it
that
know how to do this stuff.
And I feel like they had an amazing opportunity to stand up and say, all right,
everyone here's what's going on, here's what we're going to do about it.
And I feel like they just kind of crapped out an advisory and ran away. Like, come on,
they absolutely did.
And I'm going to read a paragraph literally from my
blog post that will probably come up before the show.
I suspect the reason they operate in this manner is simple.
The Apache Software foundation budget in 2019 was $2.26 million.
In other words,
a foundation that literally underpins our modern technology driven world is
operating on less than the coffee budget of a major corporation.
The Apache Software Foundation handles roughly 140 to
150 vulnerabilities with CV identifiers per year.
And it's not like they can spend a lot of their budget on security
you statement I will say is technically correct. However,
I don't think that's an excuse.
I think this is an example of the Apache Software
foundation and all of the people using it after Harple
should have said we have to make sure we have
this in order and that clearly did not happen.
Well, it's worse than that because
I'm looking at this because this is part of the post mortem. I'm working on. And it's
so these, you know, all these people on Twitter are like, oh my God,
all these companies use this free open
source software and don't return anything back.
And it's like, yes, that's exactly how open sources worked for 20 plus years.
Yeah. Why do you think Linux won
anyways? And
I think part of it honestly needs to be that these,
these things that underpin the internet and I don't mean just log for Jay.
But like those, you know, the Apache Software foundation,
they need to maybe be a little more
noisy about, hey, here's all the insane value we're providing
for like
74 cents a day,
you know,
or in some cases, $0 per day, like, like curl
like literally a world without curl would
curls just everywhere.
I don't, I don't even know what to say about a world without curl.
I can, I can explain this in a way that I think you can like explain it.
Like I'm five, go get your car's user manual, turn to the back
and it's going to list curl
like it's in your car. I guarantee it.
I don't know what the answer is here because obviously companies don't want
to pay money for stuff that they don't have to pay money for.
And open source explicitly allows this, which is fine. But,
but the sustainability issue comes to mind where this company, you know,
if they'd done a slightly better job here, let's put it this way.
How many companies spent more than 2.26 million over the weekend on overtime?
All of them. Yeah. Like every fortune 100 company on the planet.
I mean,
I think the way I would think about this is there's a couple of different layers,
there's the layer of just understanding what you have.
And I think a lot of organizations now know what
they have and they didn't on Thursday of last week,
I, I think a lot of them, not all but a lot of them.
Do
they understand superficially.
They, they,
this is like saying this is like saying I have half inch plumbing in my house.
Is it copper or PEX? I'm not entirely sure. But
the first step though,
I think we need to be mindful because in security,
we are notorious for pulling the perfect or nothing.
And step one is saying,
do I have plumbing in my house? Oh, I do. You know, like
a professional, like people like us, we know the answer to this
but we're not there.
So some of these people need to solve this one on their own and it's a multi
step process.
Well, it's a maturity piece thing, right? Like a lot of places, literally,
if you ask them for a list of ingredients and SBM
of what is in the software, not just that you ship, but that you use and rely upon.
I don't
know.
Right. Right. And, and that, that's ok.
I think that is going to become much more normal after this
one thing. There's tools that actually allow to happen now because,
I mean, up until a few years ago, if you did this,
it would take a heroic amount of manual effort
and then it would be immediately out of date.
Well, and when we used to do this at Red Hat, it was 100% manual back in the day.
I mean, we literally had humans cracking open,
you know, so
first tar balls looking inside of them and then
we would have another list
of security vulnerabilities.
We would basically grap for, you know,
like is this package name somewhere in this list?
Oh, it's not, oh, they misspelled it. We missed it, you know,
and
that happened.
So anyway,
there's kind of that first layer that I'll
say just it's understanding what you have,
but then
you're going to move your way up.
And if we think about it kind of like on the hierarchy of need scale,
I think knowing what you have and then being willing
to fund it is a little high on the list.
-- And I think
-- a lot of that's right at the top. It's
probably very close to the top.
I agree. But I think we've reached a point where now
a lot of organizations are recognizing
we have open source everywhere, we have to know what we have.
And then we also have to make sure that there's like a coherent plan in place for,
for maintaining this stuff and keeping track of it because, I mean, at the same time,
like one of the challenges.
OK. So let's say everyone on the planet says here here A F here's a million dollars.
Now, the A F has billions of dollars. And
what now? Right, let's say they hire a ton of people.
But oh wait, the next vulnerability.
Oh That came from this weird little project over here.
That is literally a person in Nebraska.
Well, see, and, and this is again, uh I'll just recycle content.
I've already created.
I'm doing a post mortem on this and, and here's,
I want to give a timeline of actually how the flaw came to be.
So
uh log for J version one lived its life and then log for
J version two came along and it had a whole pile of enhancements.
And in log for J uh version 2.0 beta nine,
here we go log for J 2-303 J and
look up plug in support. Currently, look up plugins don't support J and D resources.
It would be really convenient to support J and
resource. Look up in the configuration. One use case with J and
look up plug in as it falls blah blah, blah blah blah
uh 2013, July 17th. Cool
now
uh two years later, two years, two months later,
log for J 2-11 33 in page configuration section,
property substitution add JND I context.
So literally two years, two months later, somebody's like, hey, could,
could you add this to the documentation that it does this thing?
OK. So, so in
fairness, people who grab log for J in the first two years, unless they, I
guess read the source code or something
or look like
they wouldn't have known this even existed unless
they explicitly knew to look for it.
I mean, I don't think anyone knew this existed as it is.
The documentation for log for J is quite large and
well, you're not going to sit down and read it,
you're going to look for the section you need
-- and that's what you're going to read.
-- Yeah.
And then,
and you're not going to read the change log
between versions and catch this minor minor documentation.
So then two years and two months again later in 2017, November 9th,
uh log for J dash 2109 add property to disable message pattern converter lookups. So
as opposed to setting percent M no lookups in all pattern definitions,
I would like to globally disable the feature.
And so this is the,
the feature that was added in log for J
version 2.10 that allows you to globally turn it off
that. So basically they added a feature
and it's on by default.
And then they didn't add even a global off switch for over four years.
And that's the thing if this feature had been added and
disabled by default and you had to explicitly enable it,
this vulnerability would have come out and people would have been like, oh,
these seven people are affected, go fix it, like go turn the switch on. Right. Right.
Exactly. And of course, that's easy to say in hindsight.
Well, and, and I want to add one other thing to your timeline in 2016.
There was a black hat talk that basically pointed out
that maybe this JND I thing is kind of dangerous.
Well, and that's part of my timeline. Um
But anyways,
so
I just want to stop here also and say, like
I'm incredibly tempted at this point to name this episode. Kurt reads his blog.
Yeah, pretty much. I love it.
So,
and actually I like that you bring up the black hat thing because
it brings up one of the fundamental failures of this whole system,
which is we have a many to many communications problem.
Most of the men
don't
know about each other because how do I put this nicely?
You can't expect a project like log for J, even if it was 20 fully funded people
to somehow track every security
presentation on the planet in case their name pops up
-- and, and even if it doesn't, even if Log for J
-- wasn't specifically name.
Right. Exactly. Like how would you make that connection even? You know what I mean?
Because how many people actually really knew this was in Log for J? I mean,
I
think the two people that wrote it, I had been,
I've been doing stuff with log for J for literally four years
before this point and I had no idea it could do this.
Exactly.
So
yeah. Um
And the other thing is, it's funny, I was talking with somebody and they're like, oh,
you know, the answer to this partly is uh developer education.
I'm like, no, it's not. And they're like what I'm like, no, no, go deeper.
Here's the problem,
especially in the corporate world.
You have a choice. You'll find resources. I want you to add a feature.
Now, if you add just the feature and move on, we it costs say 10 hours.
But if you add the feature properly document it disable it by default,
have a switch to enable it blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Now it's taking 10 or 20 or 30 hours and people have
to turn stuff on to make it work and blah blah blah
versus I have my developers just crank out features that are poorly documented.
And we get 2 to 4 times as many features done.
Yeah, exactly.
And
uh in the corporate world, obviously that's going to win
and in the open source world,
well, developers kind of want to work on features and not,
you know,
spackle cracks
and make sure everything's absolutely perfect. It's like,
well, we, it's open source, we can fix that later,
help you can fix it if you don't like it.
Right
again, Back to open
nothing.
Yeah.
Right. Right.
And, and OK, so before we just keep beating this horse, I also want to mention
that
at
the time of recording, this is improving greatly.
But I feel like at the very beginning of this,
I think some of the, the like
security organizations like CT and Cisa
and whoever else,
like they were also remarkably silent for
almost a week before they really started doing anything.
I think the first thing I saw was the, whatever the Dutch version of Sisa is.
I'm not even going to try to, to say your name. I apologize. But I,
I'll,
I'll put a link in the show notes, but
they started putting together this amazing list of all the software.
But now they have one and Cisa has one.
-- Actually,
-- no, the thing is you don't need to put in the show notes,
just tell people to go to the GSD entry.
And it's,
it's explicitly remember I picked the winning URL
S because that's another part of this CV,
EGSD and all that.
It's not just enough to have a giant list of URL S.
Now we have to curate and pick the winners. And I, I literally did like a log for Shell.
Here's the winning URL S for detection for exploitation for hot patch for blah,
blah, blah
and, and I mean, I'm going to pick on CD E also as part of this, I mean, like,
so CV E the, the story is hilarious.
They first published the data from the A SF which had an incorrect mitigation in it
and then that got retracted.
No, didn't get retracted. It got silently deleted.
That is true. It was silently deleted
and then
there was no NVD score or I'm sorry. There was, yeah, there was no NVD CV SS score.
There was no C pe names attached by NVD until like I think it was late Monday,
early Tuesday.
Then CV added some random
URLS that doesn't seem to have any rhyme or reason to
-- it
-- in fairness. One of them is a link to my tweet, which is true.
The tweet is the link to the GSD with all the data. So that was good of them.
I'm going to argue linking a tweet is
the worst reference.
No,
you know what the worst reference is linking
to somebody's Twitter account and not a specific tweet
-- anyway. Anyway.
-- Ok.
Ok.
But then,
but then it gets sillier because the original text of the
CV E issue with the bad mitigation ends up back in
the CV E data set and that it was again taken
back out after Will Dorman pointed it out to them.
And I feel like it is clear
that no one is in charge.
-- The
-- problem is the way they use GIT is broken, right?
They, they, they take data into github,
shove it into their backend system and then shove it back out of the backend system.
And it's so that's every single GIT commit
in the CV list that says synchronized data.
That's it.
That's there's one of those synchronized data commits
every hour on the hour no matter what,
which is useless anyways.
But what's really fascinating about this timeline is
uh I don't have the data in front of me, so I'm just gonna wing it. But basically
the, the series of events as I've been best able to parse
is that this first cropped up
on Discord servers talking about Minecraft servers where
Minecraft servers were getting popped through chat.
People were putting this J and D I string
into chat and popping Minecraft servers and hijacking them.
It then
went into that uh issue number 608
in the log for J thing where it's like essentially this person was like, you know,
this bad stuff is happening with this JND I LDA look up.
So can we restrict LDA access to local host only?
Right? Which
realistic, like
realistically if you're actually using this feature,
you probably should be running an LT A server locally to handle the lookups.
You think so?
So, and, and ok, this would be good and safe, you know,
you don't have to worry about payloads being delivered
from some random IP address on the internet.
And so what's interesting is, um,
in that issue 608, it's kind of like, ok,
we get that this is a security issue but we're,
we're at first it's kind of like it's not that bad, whatever, blah, blah, blah.
But then it very quickly is like, 00, this is bad. We need a CV.
We need to blah, blah, blah.
There's a quote
I think it is,
it is very surprising that this critical security issue
does not seem to have received due attention.
It was reported to Apache half a month ago,
but it was not fixed until five days ago. Even today.
It was not released a new stable version to solve it.
And then one of the replies is, oh,
so glad you show such appreciation for the work of volunteers like, yeah, true.
A little bit of snark is not totally unwarranted here.
Right? Again, open
source. Do nothing. But
basically,
I don't want to say they dropped the ball.
But if I hand you a ball,
it may not be clear that it's a nice happy red rubber ball or what was that?
Saturday Night live, you know, do not annoy,
-- happy fun
-- ball,
ball, you know, do not expose happy fun ball to sunlight,
small Children or pregnant women.
If it starts smoking, sit down and run away.
That was, that was, oh man, that was such a good commercial.
And that's the thing about these issues is like, oh,
I got this weird little glitchy thing.
Can we just, you know,
restrict
look ups to local host turns into the worst security vulnerability in 20 years.
Now, there's also another interesting angle to this.
So the issue was reported to the ASF on November 24th
and it was
added to their get on December 6th
and now I say get because they don't use github, but that's whatever.
I, I don't like that, but I'll let it go.
But there are people who are now looking back in time and their logs
and there's some instances of this on December 1st,
people have found and it won't shock me if it might go back even farther.
Like one of the questions is
why was this scene on December 1st? Did someone leak it?
Was it already in the wild? Like what is going on?
Yeah, I mean, and, and again,
I'm just going to read from my blog because it's just easier than
doing
it. It's like I, so
hang on a second. Here we go. Ok.
So blah, blah, blah Apache dropped this
to say the announcement of CV 2021 44228 land
like a bombshell is an understatement on Twitter.
The activity on December 9th and 10th
alone with several 100,000,
I got bored of waiting for them all to load and it went up from there.
She went and got the first hashtag log
for
Shell and hashtag log for
uh J tweets about this.
And what's interesting is there was
a tweet on December 9th
early in the day
that basically said hashtag log for J dollar sign squiggly bracket J and D
focal and L
dot
focal
and slash slash XXXX dot DNS
log.cn/exp,
squiggly bracket.
Now, in hindsight, of course, looking at that, we're like, OK,
that's patient zero on Twitter, so to speak.
So
in theory,
so which contains enough information to craft an exploit
but lacks contact and then later tweets gain steam.
But unless you're monitoring Chinese language
tweets for random technology terms,
you know,
chances are you didn't see this until the Apache
software foundation announced it or the CV was released.
Except even that's old.
It appears that the Minecraft community of all
things was experiencing exploitation of this issue.
And then I have a, a link to a thread at high pixel.net,
they're talking about this
except even that stale. So Matthew Prince Ceo of Klauber
reported that
um what was the date he said that they started seeing exploitation was I think, yeah,
it was it December 1st or whatever
they went through their logs
and yeah, on December 1st at 436 UTC.
They, they saw exploitation of this.
So
it's clear
it's one of those things where
when somebody finds a security vulnerability, you know,
it doesn't immediately get
-- pushed up the chain to the right people right away.
-- Right.
Well, you know what's really funny is this came up Thursday night on Friday morning,
I had a meeting with one of our marketing people that we just have a normal meeting.
Friday morning. I'm like, hey, this doesn't look that bad.
I said it, it might, I think this
might be a flash in the pan. Let's not do anything crazy yet.
And literally less than two hours later. I was like, yeah, this one's a big deal.
Like we definitely need to pay attention.
And that's the problem is there's,
I can't think of too many things that are analogous
in the real world where it goes from like,
oh, this could be bad to, you know, 17 minutes later.
-- We're like, and we have an extinction level event.
-- Right. Right.
I mean, asteroid impact. I don't know. Yeah.
Anyway, it's, it's definitely been
an interesting challenge,
we can say,
well,
and I love that this is going to be
with us forever because here's the thing people don't get
is the way Java software is built and shipped and deployed
is I'm not going to say fundamentally different than other software,
but it is quite different than other software
in the sense of there is the expectation, the culture of having these binary blobs
so that you just get this giant binary bla of software and you turn it on and it works.
That's how everyone used to distribute software,
but they still do it in the Java world.
Well, not, not exactly, not exactly.
So there's the old way of Java where, for example, let's say you needed a jar,
you just like literally embed all the jars in your jar
and now it's jars all the way down.
And a lot of scanners have a hard time cracking those open and looking
gripe doesn't by the way, but like so
subtle
as
it is a hard problem to solve it.
So
those are useful tools, especially
-- when they're free.
-- Exactly. But anyway,
and now the new way you deal with this in Java
is basically all of the dependencies live at like one level.
So if you need,
if something needs log for J,
it ends up like in the application in like the global name space.
So it's like there is the new way, but there's so much of stuff that used the old way
of
20 years of software.
-- 20. When did Java come out about
-- 20 years ago?
years
older than that, I was in college more than 20 years ago.
But,
you
know,
um
anyways,
-- 19
-- 96 KT
Java was released on January 23rd, 1996 which was what seven years ago Right. Like,
so
the thing is
because of this,
it's not clear that people can fix this in traditional ways because
there are Maven repos
and packages that just no longer exist. You can't get an update for them.
How many, how many companies built an app or a library? And they're so long gone.
It's not even funny,
you
know,
-- that happens.
-- And, and what I love here is
like in past the using a hot patch that
does like binary modifications or whatever to your software was just we,
we talked about it theoretically at times, remember,
but it like never was something that we
could actually really realistically do really dangerous.
Well, in this case,
not only has it been done, there's three different main packages.
Uh probably the best one is the Coretta one
but Amazon web services has a blog posting saying you should go do this
if you can't patch right away.
-- Normally, I would say don't do that. But in this particular instance,
-- absolutely.
I think it's all right.
So yeah, I mean,
that, that alone is a, is a significant change
which is, you know,
for desperate measures, I mean,
yeah,
but
so
what, what gets me too is
the the the fundamental my fundamental like root cause analysis of this is
it speaks to the culture of feature first, not safety first,
which is how the majority of software works, right?
The majority of software culture is let's add features and cool stuff. And
yeah, like, I mean, that's how we got here.
I'm staring at, you know, Windows 11 is gorgeous. Mac Os is gorgeous.
Linux is gorgeous now,
you know, the apps, the richness of the apps and the web browsers is,
it just blows my mind.
I don't have to spell or even get which, which is,
which correct anymore because like, there's things like grammarly,
like the world is amazing.
Like software has
made our lives infinitely better with all this functionality, right?
And yeah,
so occasionally we have these, you know, sort of like whoopsies moments where
Attackers can hijack every single thing running Java on the planet.
And
you know what,
it's really not the end of the world.
Like I, I love that people blow up these incidents to be somehow the end of the world.
And it's like,
and yet we're life is kind of just chugging along as far as I can tell.
So I think the important thing to remember here is I
won't say nobody died because of this because it's conceivable.
Something happened somewhere.
But I mean,
practically speaking as humans, we freak out when there's an incident that causes
a lot of, a lot of
we'll say casualties very quickly
and this isn't one of those.
I mean, look at, look at like the pandemic, it's a slow burn.
So it's not receiving the level of attention I think it should.
-- Well, that's whatever. And as
-- we record this Al
Ma has taken off
and
my premier is literally as we speak, having a an uh
he was supposed to have a pressure yesterday to announce
less restrictions for Christmas and then that got canceled.
They spoke with the Prime Minister of Canada and apparently,
yeah, we might be canceling Christmas this year
-- and I fully support it. We'll
-- just blame Log for Jay if Christmas gets canceled.
But you know what I mean? I mean, I think
that's the difference is, is it we are, it is Wednesday right now and this, we're,
we're like, what, 76 days into this basically.
And
it's starting to feel less terrible.
I would say, I feel like we can finally breathe a little bit.
There's still a lot of work to do and there's a long, long road ahead of us, you know,
but I feel like the worst is behind us.
-- Now.
-- I feel like a lot of this is similar to the pandemic in thought.
We got lucky and ignored biosecurity for way too long.
Like people just didn't wash their hands enough
or cover their coughs and sneezes enough,
right?
That, that Asian culture thing of wearing a surgical mask when you're sick,
so you don't spread your germs.
Yeah, we should probably do that as a species. Seems like a nice idea.
And that's a
thing is I think part of the fatigue and the stress is Log
for J forces people to acknowledge things that they have been cheerfully ignoring,
like s
balm, like, knowing what software they're running, like,
knowing what version of software they're running.
Like, knowing what configuration switches. Like, here's the thing. If,
uh, if somebody said I'm allergic to tree nuts,
every,
every reputable food manufacturer on the planet can say, oh, yeah,
you're going to die if you eat our product or you're going
to be fine if you eat our product in literally seconds.
You know, one of my sons has a very high sensitivity to Aloe
uh like his mother.
And so buying diapers that don't have Aloe in them and
buying skincare products that don't have Aloe in them is tricky,
but you can literally phone the 1 800 number on those things
and get an answer in less than a minute.
But now I, I will say
that is because the government made them do it.
-- It's not because they wanted to.
-- Exactly.
But now it's become
a
normal part of how those industries work and it's not stressful for them
and it blows my mind that in it if you ask me, hey, Kurt, like, what software do you do
upon? And I'm like,
I actually don't know,
but I consciously don't know because we picked cloud
providers and we outsourced that problem and we accepted that
there's an interesting angle to this that I think is coming to light that
I've had some people contact me and I've just noticed in the universe is.
A
lot of people went looking for log for Jay
and they noticed all the other vulnerabilities
in their stuff and they're saying, wait a minute.
So I think what's, what part of the slow burn of this will be?
We need to get log for J under control.
And then we need to say, all right, what about all this other stuff I found while I,
because it feels kind of like, you know,
when you clean your basement and you're like, oh, that was there, you know,
-- and this is very similar to that
-- I think,
and it's almost worse in a way because there'll be stuff that has CV S for sure.
But
how do I put this nicely if you have a
Java library that hasn't been updated in over a year,
I guarantee you there's a vulnerability in there.
Yeah, probably
present and, and
the good news is like security bugs are high and bugs in the sense
-- of they don't exist until somebody finds them and starts exploiting them
-- usually.
Yes.
Right.
-- Right.
-- Right. They usually don't kind of get exploited by accident.
Now, now I want to say too, I want to before we end this show which we're getting close.
I want to, I want to be very clear,
this isn't just a Java problem.
There are people running node applications
that have multi year old vulnerabilities.
There are people running Python applications like
literally pick a language this is everywhere.
This isn't just Java, even though we've obviously picked on Java a lot today, it
is everywhere. So if you literally have an application, I don't care what kind it is.
Go build an S bomb.
Yeah, or a service. Also services.
If you're providing services,
you need to have an S bomb for what is backing those services
because it's not just the software but the
operating system and what services it relies upon.
Right.
I remember, for example,
once we had an outage of the main CS a website because it wanted to load
a piece of data from the blog and it didn't essentially have a time out set.
So it just sort of like the blog went down
because reasons.
And so the main website crashed and it was like, wow,
I the way most have crashed and it's like, oh, because, well, the blog is down
and I, you know, once, once we did a root cause analysis,
it took me three minutes to fix.
But finding like it
like, because what happened is the blog went down and then two minutes later,
the main website went down.
And so I focused on fixing the main website,
obviously.
Right. Right. Of course.
And it turns out if I just fixed the blog, it would have been over.
Um And that's the thing, right?
So is getting those rich that, that data about that,
that rich ecosystem that you have
and, and you do have it, whether you like it or not.
-- Yep.
-- Yep. Absolutely.
All right. I'm gonna, I'm gonna call this one, I guess,
uh, when we're recording this things feel like they're getting better.
I truly hope. I don't regret saying that
when I hit the publish button,
they did find that secondary denial of service in non-standard config,
which I'm like,
what I find more scary is
this could be warm
and if it's worm,
it could get really, really ugly.
But we're gonna, we're gonna hope
that that doesn't happen.
Let's hope that future Josh doesn't have to put
a little note at the beginning of this episode.
So.
All right. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to open source security podcast.com for our show Note, Suzy
Pound Os S Podcast. Hashtag to hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks, everyone and good luck.