Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 174 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner Thought Crime, Josh Pressers.
-- Hey, Kurt.
-- And I am pleased to say today we are joined by Rob Shell.
He is a software engineer at github and Rob is
here to talk to us about the awesome things github
-- is doing with security. So say hello, Rob. Hello.
-- And it's great to be here.
-- Thank you for having me.
-- No, thank you, man.
It's been so the, the audience doesn't know this,
but we've had enormous technical difficulties and Kurt and
I look like incompetent idiots at this point,
but I'm hoping this one will stick.
-- So here we go.
-- The internet works sometimes it's, it's amazing.
You know, it's funny, I always think about this is like 10 years ago,
this would be unheard of being able to
record three people in different parts of the world
and
in, in a manner that that's useful for podcasting,
-- obviously with high quality
-- without
-- installed software.
-- Yeah. Right. Right.
And now we're like, I feel like I'm banging rocks together today anyway.
Thank you so much, Rob.
So why don't you give us a little intro and then we'll go from there.
Yeah, absolutely. I've been a software engineer at github
for about 2.5 years now and a lot of what I have worked on there is around our
github security Advisory Database and this is a database
that is driving a lot of features at github
and beyond. It's actually externally available.
So I want to talk a lot about the advisory database.
Yeah, we've just added a brand new feature.
Uh So for a long time, github
has been reading the CV E feed, we might,
should talk about what CV ES even are uh upfront.
But if you have a public repo on github and you maintain a open source package,
we will assign CV ES to you for your package if you
ask us for them and we'll do that through our whole github
advisory database feature set.
That's so freaking cool. You have no idea.
-- Like I'm, I'm
-- giddy and even some, I mean github
made a couple of subtle changes to the interface.
The one where you can now have, as I understand,
you can have private issues and sort of private
conversations about these issues in a public github.
-- Is that
-- correct? That is true. And we're not calling them private issues.
We've called it a private fork. So it's a little bit interesting.
So private issues are something,
a lot of people want github to make for a lot of reasons
and
it's difficult. One of the main challenges around that is sort of abuse factor. So
we have custom made something just for the security
case where a maintainer becomes aware that there is
a security problem with their open source package that
maintainer can create something called a draft security advisory.
It's under the security tab on your repo
and from that draft security advisory, uh they can create something,
a private fork which gives them a space to fix this issue
with others.
Um in a way where it never touches their public commit history until they are ready
-- to disclose this issue publicly.
-- That is OK. Let's before we,
before we go down this rathole because I, I know we're going to get there.
I let's start at the beginning and I wanna kind of dwell on
what? So first of all, we mentioned CV E we mentioned github
security advisories and now we're,
we're on to something called private forks and I
feel like let's start at the very beginning,
right.
Let's just talk about
github
added the ability to publish security advisory.
This has been more at least a year now. I think it's been, it feels like forever, but
let's just,
let's start there and then we'll weave this tapestry
which is going to eventually end with private repos.
Why don't, why don't you explain to us what a github
-- security advisor is?
-- Well, let me even back up just a little bit more.
If you think about the state of open source before github
existed,
the open source wasn't thing.
Um There were people doing it, there were places like source forge CV S yo. Right.
Yeah.
And github
came along and it kind of standard. OK. You want to participate in open source.
Here's how you do it. You can put your code here.
Other people will come and help you write the code.
If you're doing something interesting,
that's been Github's bread and butter for 10 years now,
we're trying to do the same thing for security.
So the the state of security ecosystem these days
is that there's many players with many different interests.
And if you're an open source maintainer,
you will interact with security researchers. You may want to get a CD.
All these things are not easy or straightforward to do until last month when github
announced these features.
Uh
No, I can't.
I mean, I, I've assigned 6000 CV S so, and I've helped a lot of people and so is Josh. And
-- yeah, we can't argue with you on that one, but you are correct. I
-- know,
I love the work you guys have done with. Uh it was the old Distributed Weakness
Foundation was that
FDWF? Um
So for your listeners who may know what DWF is or was github
is fulfilling a lot of the same function in the CBE ecosystem?
So Josh backing up,
Github
introduced security advisories Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
So that is our attempt to do it for security,
-- what github uh initially did for open source,
-- which is huge.
And in fact, this is something Kurt and I have talked about at length is the fact that
when Kurt created the DWF, there was a lot of effort put forth mostly by him
to try to make this a thing in the open source universe.
And it was, I think it was partially
people, I won't say they don't care, but they kind of don't care.
And additionally, there's just a lot of friction there.
Whereas like they're already in
github,
-- that's, this is huge. I
-- think the, the tooling issue is a huge problem because
literally
if you ask somebody to do something that not only requires additional effort, but
there's additional tooling.
Now they have to install that tooling, maintain that tooling.
Understand that tooling,
it's just not going to fly.
And one thing for most of our listeners that I don't think maybe is
quite clear is the majority of open source security projects have security flaws,
but typically it's so few. It's, you know, a literally a handful per year.
So it's not,
you know, it's like a, it's like fixing a flat tire,
you do it once every five years and,
and everybody's terrible at it except for the tow truck guy who
five times a day.
That's right. And we're trying to be that tow truck guy.
So when your open source package gets a vulnerability,
we'll show up and help you get that CV E published into the system.
The CV E system has been amazing. It's been around since 1999
and it's done a great job of like centralizing a list of
vulnerabilities in not just software but devices that run on software and,
and a lot of things in CBE,
one of the main challenges for open source specifically
has been just getting access to that CBE system.
Like, oh, I've got a vulnerability,
I'd like to let people know that about this vulnerability.
I'd like to let people know that I fixed it. How do I get the CBE?
Uh Kurt and I both know the answer to that and the, the, the,
there's a variety of answers. The,
the, the worst is become uh AC N A with Miter and
I don't know how involved you are in the github process of doing that,
but it is not an activity for the timid to say the least.
Yeah, and understandably.
So the CV E database is really standardized and
there's rules about what can be included in it,
rules about how to count.
Like,
yy,
if you
make 10
cross site scripting attacks in your N PM, do you file 10 CV S or do you file one? That's
-- usually it's around three or four,
-- right?
It's in the middle.
So these rules can be a little bit arcane and,
and possibly hard to understand for someone who's just basically trying to say,
hey, I fixed a security hole.
No, there, there, it's not. Possibly, there's no possibly about it.
They are incredibly difficult and I know a huge number of people
in the open source world that gave up because they were like,
screw it.
This isn't worth the effort. I don't care.
I don't want to see the ID and I, I understand, I totally get it.
-- You know, it's like Kurt's tire analogy.
-- Yeah. So we, we offer that feature.
All right. So, so let's, let's explain.
I, I want to understand this feature because I've read all your documentation.
I've actually never done it, which is,
I, I don't want to,
I guess, be a pest.
We'll say like just playing around and saying like, I wonder what this button does.
We, we encourage people to test all the time. You're welcome to
make fake security advisories in your refund
and send CBE requests in, please. Not too many because
-- we do read each one. Right.
-- Right. Ok. So, and, and this is where I guess
I'm most curious.
So it sounds like,
and why don't I will tell the story and then you can correct me
because I think it'll be more amusing that way because I'm wrong a lot.
So, from what I understand,
you have the ability to create a private fork if you want
for kind of fixing and dealing with your security issue.
Now, let's say I don't want to do that because for a variety of reasons
I think we embargo too much stuff in security and that's
the topic for another day and it's in the archives.
So, go look it up. So, anyway, let's say, I say uh this fix is a security issue.
So I go into
github. I can,
II, I don't even remember how to do it.
There's, do I click a button to say I need a new security issue for my project.
How does that
work?
Yeah. So on your repo, there's a security tab,
-- right?
-- And
under that tab, there's something called advisories.
OK?
-- And within that tab, there's a button called Open New Draft advisory,
-- right? Right.
OK. Now this is coming back to me and this is, this is where I was
becoming concerned. I was gonna
annoy you guys.
So you kind of fill everything out and you guys have done
a nice job of giving me some kind of templated formatting here.
Right?
And I think this is one of the challenges in the advisory world
is understanding what should I say and how should I say it?
And
you guys have done a nice job here from what I've gathered.
So I fill it out
and then I hit submit
and that goes, but it doesn't get published and I hit submit, right?
It goes to you guys first,
-- right? OK.
-- So
you are close.
Yes,
close is good. I can live with close.
So you're gonna open your draft security advisory just like you said,
you're presented with a form we're gonna ask you some information, you know,
what is a short summary of this vulnerability?
What are the affected packages? What are the affected versions?
You might not know this information yet.
So much of it's optional, but you do have to type in at least the description
and
hit enter and it creates a draft security advisory.
So at that point, nothing's happened except there's this record in your repo, at
that point, you as a maintainer get to decide. Ok.
Am I gonna fix it or do I just want to let people know, hey,
this exists and I'm not gonna fix it.
That's good though. That's
II I just got into this argument yesterday actually, with somebody is the fact that
just saying no is better than maybe, right. Yes or no are where you want to be.
You don't want this and maybe it's there, maybe I'll fix it someday. I don't know.
I don't really care. Right?
-- That is the worst possible answer to any question
-- totally with you.
And someone can see that, you know, advisory and say,
oh there's an open security issue.
It's unfixed. I'm not gonna use that package. I'm gonna look for an alternative.
It's important
you're sitting there with this draft advisory and let's say in the simple case,
you decide, you know what I'm not gonna fix it.
At that point, you have two options.
You can publish the advisory and it goes to
github and we'll publicly publish it in github.com/advisories,
which is our advisory database that's public.
Awesome. And what if I decide to fix it?
-- What does that look like?
-- Right. So if you decide to fix it, there's a lot of options.
If you're a big popular package, you might want to prepare your fix in private,
get it ready, write a draft blog post,
your blog that says, hey, we've got a big security advisory.
We just published version 1.2 0.3.
Please go download it and, and that's sort of the, the full featured case.
Like you're gonna totally fix this issue in private,
get everything ready and then with one bang one button, push,
it's all gonna go public at the same time.
Nice. So that's what the private fork is for and this is getting all complicated.
Now, option B you may be a small project and maybe your fix is just a one line fix.
The private fork is
overkill for that kind of case.
So what you could go ahead and do is just do your fix, put it in your master branch.
You know, it's public.
If someone's really watching your repo, they can say, oh,
they just fixed the security issue and once you've made your fix,
you can publish at that time.
The key here is when the advisory goes
public is totally within the maintainer control.
OK,
github's not gonna tell you when you should publish.
OK. Which is good. Which is cool.
And, and I guess
how much, when, when you guys get a hold of this,
do you, I, I assume
in there's some sort of
review stage, be it humans or machines or whatever and how often do you have to make,
maybe ask questions or make suggestions to these projects?
Yes. So there is absolutely a human review stage. So we screen everything
that comes in from advisories
to a make sure it's on topic. So it's not offensive or an ad or something like that.
Oh, that's true, I suppose because it, you have like a big github
advisory page. That'd be a marvelous place to put an ad.
I've had, I have had people try and stuff, the CV database with advertising
-- and making requests and stuff.
-- I've seen some questionable CV ES in the list. Uh,
I read quite a few.
It happens so we're gonna screen it to make sure it's on topic.
We're gonna screen it to make sure that, you know what,
this isn't just some bug you're fixing.
It's a legitimate security issue that gets pretty fuzzy.
Yeah. No, really. I mean, it, it's a hard question is something, a security issue and
you know what, you know, what kills me here always is
the really bad security issues are always very clear
cut where usually the fix is easy to understand.
The problem is easy to understand everyone's on the same page.
But then there's like this weird middle squishy area where it's like, it sort of is,
it sort of isn't and the patch is terrible and it's gonna take me three times as long to
deal with this stupid low severity issue than it
did to take care of that critical last week.
You know.
That's right. And a lot of what's in the CBE database or things like
denial of service attacks,
you kind of have to look at each one individually and decide.
Is that really a security issue or is this just
we are going to generally trust maintainers?
So when a maintainer says, hey, you know what,
this is a security vulnerability and I want to tell my users about it,
we're gonna more often trust you than not
where things get messy is when they're coming from
non maintainers, like security research from the community,
which is a quick point.
We might want to come back to that, but we are not supporting researchers directly
at this time in github.
So
all the features we're talking about are for open source maintainers only.
OK. That's actually good to know.
And I, I also don't disagree with that that point because I run a bike bounty
and
it is very kind people always, you know,
I
won't say everyone but most researchers are, they file their issue as critical.
It's like
not critical. And then you argue with them why it's not critical.
It's like no, your denial of service issue in this, like,
unused website over here is not a critical issue.
Just no.
And, and I, that that's always going to be the challenge, right?
Is these researchers find,
we will say probably borderline security issues and they want to
pretend it's huge and I get it because it's their baby.
-- But from your perspective, like,
-- don't do that and they're trying to build a career.
Yeah. Right. Right.
Well,
I would say the one thing here is at least
these discussions are starting to happen more in public because,
I mean, I remember 5, 10 years ago,
nobody really got to see discussions of security bugs, right?
You would only ever see the advisory with the timeline at the bottom.
It was like, terrible. It took like two years.
But
there was never the discussion of, you know,
and that's something I tried to capture and make public is like because, yeah,
denial service is a great example.
The ping of death, right?
You send a oversized pink packet and windows and everything just fell over,
like died twitching.
You know, clearly that that's a problem
on the flip side, you know, something like maybe, well,
I opened up a million connections to the Apache
web server and it got a little bit slow.
Well,
yeah, but on the flip side, you know, I've had cases where somebody is like, well, no,
no, but this is a security plan.
So specifically says it can handle that kind of load
without getting slow. And I'm like, oh, ok. Well, I think, you know,
intended for this to work.
And so I, I think part of the benefit here is we're,
we're starting to have these discussions more in public.
And I think that will be probably one of the best things
actually to come from this get up thing is all these,
you know, in the issue, trackers and stuff. There'll be that
conversation where, you know, you can then refer to later to educate people.
Absolutely. And
I really like that point. The rough guideline we're using
to determine whether something is a security vulnerability or not.
Is, does this bug have consequences in the real world?
-- No, I,
-- I
-- like
-- that. Well, I mean, it's better than that.
Does it violate a trust boundary? Which is the, the current official CV E is the
ability or not? And I'm like,
what's the trust boundary? And they're like, yeah, shut up Kurt.
It's everyone's favorite catchphrase, Kurt.
Yeah.
So one question because I'm just looking at this.
So it says, quote unquote,
this process may take up to three working days
and we may contact you for more information,
learn more.
I'm curious is that three days actually like a maximum sl a like for example,
what if you get like 1000 issues reported in one day?
We have not crossed that bridge yet. So please don't go write a script to do that to us.
That sounds like a challenge. Everybody.
The 72 hours we're gonna do our very best to live by that.
If we should get something like 1000 requests,
we're gonna employ some tools to try and filter out what,
what was automatically generated and what is legitimate.
And github has a whole suite of tools for
finding that kind of we call it spammy interactions.
So we'll go down that road and hopefully we'll be able
to filter out the legitimate ones from the non-legitimate ones and,
and prioritize those, the 72 hour window is gonna be a challenge for us.
So we picked that with the idea that
we can still have weekends. Right.
Well, you have to be
good three working days, which I think is very fair
for something that's free.
That's true.
We are gonna read that request when it comes in and that is a new kind of job at
github and it's been an interesting one to carve out.
So this has been the bulk of what I've been doing at
github.
Github really likes processes that operate operationalize into software.
-- Well,
-- it has
to, I mean, the current, you know, the current CV database is heavily
on capacity by the fact that each CV E is artisan
-- handcrafted.
-- Yep.
So as we're doing all this curation,
we're building out our tooling internally to try and make that
process of curating these requests as efficient as possible for us.
And that's a really big part of operating at
the scale we operate at.
It is still a new thing in github to kind of outside of the support
organization to kind of have requests that come in that we have to look at
one with a person and I don't think we'll ever completely
get away from having a human in the loop here.
Sure.
Well, I, I think you kind of always need that because, well, I mean, the,
the classic example is, you know, Tavis
Ormandy hits you up on Twitter on Friday saying, you know,
can company X please send me their security contact now,
-- you know, and then it's like uh oh,
-- better run the coffee everyone.
It's gonna be a long weekend.
We're looking really hard at the broader ecosystem and
how
we best support researchers. So I do want to talk about that side of the things.
-- All right,
-- let
-- me,
-- let me back this up for one second first before we move on.
So we were talking about filing advisories.
Now, how do I make sure I get a CV E when I'm filing an advisory with github.
Indeed. Right now today, you have to ask us for one.
So when you make your draft advisory, like we described,
there is a option to do two things.
One is publish the advisory and the other is request the CBE.
Gotch,
you publish an advisory is a one time thing that's
gonna make the quote draft advisory public on your repository.
Only once you've published, you can still request the CBE if you have not yet.
Ok, good, good.
So that's how it works today.
You have to basically hit the request CBE button from an advisory,
whether it's draft or published and then we get the CBE
request and we get back to you within 72 hours.
Got you in the future. We do feel like
it's our duty as AC N A to assign CBES to
any repository advisory. Oh man, it gets published
that meets the requirements for A CV E ID.
That is
that, that,
that's the question I was waiting to ask and that's awesome. Now,
there's a lot of asterisks, I'd put next to that. That's awesome.
But I think that is what the world needs.
I think for CV E to become truly useful across the entire industry.
And so that is amazing. Well done on that lofty goal. I love it.
Really glad to hear that you like it.
Uh
I'm not sure some maintainers will like it.
I'm sure some maintainers will like it,
it may be controversial on some level fundamentally.
I mean, it's a spectrum, right?
I've literally had projects argue with me that they want more CV S and I'm like, dude,
that's not a security issue.
I'm like
you to split and merge like I have to combine these, I'm sorry,
you can't have all these TV S you want.
And conversely, I've dealt with projects, you know, that are incredibly hostile
CV. S.
And I was going to ask about that because I've also on the,
we've only been thinking about the sort of supply side here on the consumption side.
I've met a lot of people where to put it bluntly,
it's not a security vulnerability until it has a CV.
And then for a lot of these people,
a clock starts ticking and have you heard from them?
So, on the consumer side,
github has for about two years offered what we call security alerts based on CV S
and those are cool too. Yes. And they have not been without some controversy.
So just really quick,
there has been some cases where we've issued security alerts based on
a CV E and the maintainers has then gotten a lot of
requests from their users, the users come to them and say, hey,
we got this security alert.
What are we gonna do about it?
Um It might be unpatched and that has ruined a maintainer day more than once.
Yeah, but I would argue
that
having an unpatched vulnerability that can be exploited
is going to ruin your day way worse than
just having people complain that you may or may not be vulnerable to a CV ID.
That's right.
So I think in some of the past cases the maintainers have
had a legitimate case that the CBE should not have existed.
Now, this was, of course not a CV E github
made,
of course not.
And they were not looped in when the CBE was made.
So we're working really hard to walk that line between,
if it's a legit security issue, we're gonna put a CV E on it.
We're gonna tell people about it through security alerts
and if it's not a legit security issue,
we're not gonna do that because we want to
protect maintainers sanity and keep them in the open
source
system.
It
occurs.
I mean,
you fundamentally have one advantage that and I've done this where I've assigned
CV S and then the project came to me and they're like,
why didn't you talk to us?
I'm like,
I didn't know you exist really? Like I'm, you know, I'm not gonna chase you down
you.
Whereas github
inherently,
yeah, you can contact the, the, I want to say owners of the code.
I don't mean owners, owners, but you know, the,
the core maintainers or whatever you want to call it.
And, and another thing you can do on
github is if you run a package, you can create a security dot MD file in your github
repo.
And that's a way to tell the public.
Hey, here's how I want you to report security vulnerabilities to me.
If you're a maintainer,
please go create a security MD file today
for real do that. Absolutely. That's,
that is fantastic. I love that.
And so we were talking about the consumption side.
Well, just, is there been much pushback or is it just, it hasn't happened yet?
So people haven't freaked out because,
like,
I've done back in the envelope calculations
and for the English speaking software world,
I'm
estimating we need between one and 10 million CV
S per year to have reasonably full coverage.
And when I tell people that they look at me, they go what?
And I'm like, well, yeah, because the CV database right now,
you're looking about what, 1015, 18,000 CV S a year.
And it's, it's
a, there's just a hair over 100 CV number of authorities globally.
There's a lot more software vendors than 100 I think.
So,
our CV assignment program has been around for about two weeks
and we have assigned 10 CV E I DS so far.
Um So we have not seen a huge impact yet.
We're seeing the amount of requests coming in going up and we are
expecting some big packages to be requesting CV ES from us soon.
-- So I think your question is gonna be answered very soon.
-- I feel like
you are dead on there and I would expect the uptake of this particular
project to be very slow because I think unless you're in a very,
very small group of people, you don't even know what this means yet.
But it's going to be awesome.
That's right.
It's a really powerful feature and it is intended for
a small percentage of github users as it is.
Yeah.
-- Yeah.
-- Yeah. Now I wanna
let you finish your previous thought that I rudely interrupted you earlier.
Were you discussing kind of uh how researchers can
benefit from some of the tooling at play here?
-- Yeah.
-- So we should talk about just the greater ecosystem a little bit.
So I want to talk about github
security lab, which is a new project
at
github.
-- I was gonna say I've never heard of this. It
-- looks cool.
OK? So github.com/security dash
-- lab and, and
-- I'll make sure I put links to all this stuff in the show notes.
-- So if, if you're scribbling feverishly right now, you can stop
-- and
-- I apologize. It's uh github.com security.
-- We just say go to the show notes.
Right.
Exactly.
So this comes from our acquisition of a company called
Semel a couple months ago,
which is another topic we should discuss but
not today because we're running out of time.
So I really only want to touch on this briefly,
but I'd love for your listeners who are security
research to go check out our code QL offering.
This is a way we're trying to give researchers
more leverage and more ways to get bounties.
And what code QL is.
If you think about a traditional software vulnerability,
you identify a specific sort of piece of code that's bad.
And you say here's how it's bad. Here's the bad thing that can happen.
What code QL does is it lets you write
a query that searches code repositories for bad code.
Yep. Yep. And
github.
If,
if you are a researcher who learns to use the
code QL product and you create a code QL query
that can find
security vulnerabilities. Get hub will pay you a bounty for that. Oh, cool.
-- I
-- didn't know that.
That's awesome.
So this is basically automation of the,
because there's a couple of projects where they don't when they
are reported to security vulnerability instead of just fixing it,
they also audit their code for all
other possible instances of that class of vulnerability
and try and stomp it.
And so you're saying basically you, you're automated
-- the discovery of those flaws.
-- Yep, that's completely right.
So now researchers have two ways to get bounties.
Each instance of an uh vulnerability they
find can potentially be eligible for a bounty
and the query they've used to find them can itself be eligible for a bounty.
That is so cool.
OK. Just like that.
That is literally blowing my mind.
No, because this is the kind of automation tooling. I wish I'd had other jobs.
We're not the only ones offering bounties on Co QL
uh Mozilla is also doing the same basic bounty program.
Nice. Nice.
I love that.
Yeah.
So the way this all sort of ties into my work
is my researcher could use CO QL to find some vulnerabilities.
They tell the maintainer about them.
Maintainer is gonna create a repository advisory.
And then from that repository advisory request, the CV E,
we'll sign them A CV E and there's going to be an advisory in the github
Advisory Database and there's going to be a CV for it.
-- That
-- is
-- awesome. That is like
the, the, this is, this is the circle we've always needed
that.
I, we've never had,
it's always been like pieces of something you tape together and hope it works.
So
-- I'm, this is so cool. Well, and
-- everybody has a slightly different, I mean, oh,
-- you know, it doesn't even be worth talking about. It's so terrible.
-- Right. Right.
No, I, I agree. I agree completely. So
I guess some of my like research I've done into this,
it sounds like right now you guys have
like a capture the flag going on for code QL, which I think ends at the end of the year,
the year 2019 because obviously that's one of the disadvantages
to podcasts is who knows when people will listen.
But that looks super cool. You've got what I, I saw,
you've got a Twitter handle for your security lab that it tweets various things out.
Actually, I saw you have a, a slack instance that I just signed up for,
which is awesome.
OK, cool. So we are, we are nearly out of time.
And I feel I have so many more questions for you, Rob, but I,
I wanna respect your time as well as the listeners,
but I guess I will give you the last word on all of this and I'll let you take us out.
But
man, this is all so freaking cool. I love it.
Uh Yeah, I'd like to say thank you, Kurt and Josh for
having us on the uh open source security podcast to talk about all these github
features and the work we're doing to support security and open source.
The main takeaway, I'd love for your listeners to take away
is that these tools are there for them to get involved.
So if you're a maintainer of an open source package,
go ahead and give out the security advisory feature.
A try. It's under the security tab of your repo. It's nice to just know it's there.
So when the day comes along, when someone does shout you on Twitter and say, hey,
I found a big security problem.
Can I have your email?
Right?
You'll know that this feature is there and that we can help you,
get your CV E and get your users alerted once you have your patch ready.
And another thing is if you have ideas about how github can
help researchers, we do offer an email address.
It's security dash advisories at github.com.
That's our public CN A email. You can find that on the miter website.
So if you ever want to give us feedback about AC be we issued
or give us feedback about how we could make our CV E program better.
That's a place you can reach out. Awesome.
And lastly, like we talked about, I think the github
security lab,
if you're a security researcher is something you should definitely check out.
I'm planning to dig into the code QL product myself.
It looks really powerful and like it could be a
game changer for how we do security and open source.
I, I have no doubt it will be awesome. Wonderful. Thank you so much, Rob.
It has been an absolute pleasure and we shall definitely have to have you back soon.
Likewise, we'd love to come back and I can get you some more uh people from github
-- to uh talk about some other security features.
-- I will totally take you up on that.
All right, cool. So, thank you, Rob. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com, hit up the show notes,
UZ pound Os S podcast hashtag to hit us up on social
media and Rob and Kurt have fantastic rest of your days.
-- You too. Thanks everybody. Thank
-- you. Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the