Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast
with myself, Kurt
Siefried and my Permanent Thought Crime, Josh Bress
Bonjour,
the new
podcast to Security. Open
Source of
Kurtz
et
partner
dance,
Josh,
er
the episode to continue.
All right.
So this is the Canadian content episode.
And if you remove that French, I will get a fine.
I totally not figuring it out. It's funny you did that.
So for those of you who don't know, obviously Kurt and I talk a lot every day
and any time the Canadian Prime Minister speaks,
Kurt usually sends me a link to the youtube video
and I do enjoy watching because I enjoy seeing leadership
that is leading in this time of crisis as opposed
to a significant amount of leadership in the world,
which is basically just like a clown car at the circus that's on fire.
Yeah, seriously.
But anyway, when the Canadian Prime Minister speaks in Canada,
they have two official languages,
there's English and French and so he always speaks
in English and then he speaks in French.
And what I think is extra funny about that is they translate the French.
So you hear him speak English.
And then I hear his translated French back into
the exact same thing he just said in English.
And I'm like, this seems needlessly complicated but whatever, whatever,
it's fine.
Well, it's, it's because he's a francophone, right?
So he, he, his French is impeccable.
But I'll be blunt, like the majority of Canadians such as myself,
jean
la
francais.
I, I do not speak French. Like I have.
-- Did you have to write that down when you, when you said it,
-- I did run,
I ran it through Google translate and then I
did actually manually tweak a few things because like
the uh the thought crime Google put in uh
like the literal words for like thought and crime.
And I'm like, no, I'm pretty sure there's like a French expression.
That's why I check that.
Like anybody who actually speaks French will be just like I apologize.
I'm so horrified.
And the
problem is,
is this
Canadian French is not French. Canadian French is Canadian French,
right? Like American English is not English.
No. American English is not Queen's English. You all
right.
So yeah, so this is the Canadian content episode.
Can con I wasn't able to find the percentages because they they changed it recently.
But basically I figure you owe me at least
about 20 to 50 episodes of Canadian content.
-- I'm comfortable with that. And who doesn't love Canada,
-- right?
Quebec
and I am just quoting Maximus Black from youtube.
You know,
I love Canada, man.
Everyone's friendly and you have poutine, which are like the only two things I know.
-- You know
-- what's weird to me?
So, like poutine, like you live in Wisconsin and you guys don't have it.
And I'm like, but you guys, I know you wear
-- on your head,
-- right?
And, and cheese curd are so actually a funny story is Wisconsin in the United States.
It is probably the closest thing you can get
to like another country within the United States where
everything here is really weird and you don't know
that until you kind of grow up and leave.
I've been to Texas and New York. Trust me, they're all different.
-- There's 52 countries in the US as far as I'm concerned
-- that that's probably fair.
Wisconsin seems especially strange though for whatever reason.
And like,
my favorite example is something called cheese curd where
a lot of people don't know what this is,
-- but like when you make cheese and they make a lot of cheese here
-- as a Canadian,
I'm so offended that people wouldn't know what cheese curs are
maybe. I mean, but they're everywhere here right now. I was a kid.
I just assumed everyone had cheese curd all the time. And in fact, we'll even go to
the Cheese Factory and get them like,
so they're fresh and they're still like dripping with milk,
which is when they're the best because they're warm as well.
Like, like literally this milk was in a cow, like, four hours ago and now I'm eating it
and normal people when I left for college, they were like,
we don't even know what you're talking about.
-- What you, you eat.
-- What
a part of it is.
I think the problem with food is people somehow think like, oh,
there's a cow and now there's like a tray, a styrofoam tray of ground hamburger
or like there's a cow and now there's a wheel of cheese in my, in the store.
-- Like no, there's a few steps in between.
-- Right. Right. Exactly.
And yeah, like growing up in Wisconsin, it was just, it's, it's part of life.
Like I, I literally can ride my bike to the cheese factory down the way,
buy cheese curd.
I am a fan of cheese,
but I don't even have that much cheese and I would say I probably only have like five,
six kinds of cheese in my fridge.
Oh, my goodness. I bet we have more than six right now. At least,
probably more than that. No, no, I bet I got 10. At least. I
love cheese, man. It's like, it's one of those things.
I love the concept of being a vegan, but I could never give up cheese.
Like cheese is my thing. I love it so much.
Good cheese is like a seven year old aged Quebec cheddar. Like there's,
yeah, you can't be it, man. It's this combination of smooth and sharp and
the
mouth feel the umami and like the, the richness to it.
Or like a good Jarlsberg or, or a camel bear like baked, you know,
with a little bit of syrup and crushed walnuts
right
now. I need to go
anyway.
But so
debating how to start this episode.
So well, we did that, we did the French translation and that's all you're doing.
Sorry folks.
But here's the question, you know who John Candy is, right?
The
-- actor and
-- Eugene Levy.
Eugene Levy is awesome. Yeah,
-- he's got the eyebrows. I love his
-- eyebrows
and you know, Martin short
and what do those three people have in common?
-- Well, I assume they're Canadian if you're asking me this question, some
-- of them,
a bunch of them are Canadian or Canadian American
-- Eugene
-- Levy is I know that
or Catherine o'hara,
what do they all have in common?
-- Like really strongly
-- home alone
like
C TV,
-- SC TV is
-- what? Second city TV.
It was like one of the pioneering Canadian TV comedies on from 76 to 81.
And then again, in the eighties, a few more times, but basically it was,
it was kind of an incubator for
comedy in Canada with about a dozen people, about half of whom
went on.
Well, you know, their names like,
and this is basically the point of Canada is that Canadian content laws
exist because
as people may or may not know, Canada is next to the US.
Dude.
I don't take anything for granted when it comes to American geography anymore.
That, that's fair. And not only that it is the longest land border in the world.
-- No, five 1000 miles,
-- the longest undefended land border in the world.
What's the longest land border in the world?
I thought there was a longer one.
No, no, I, I'm sure like Russia has a longer border,
-- right? But it's not shared with one country.
-- Oh, that's true.
Yeah, actually, no, you're right, Canada, the USA is the longest land border.
Oh, you know,
I always forget about Alaska and that's like another 1500 kilometers right there.
So it's
gigantic. 2893 kilometers or an American. It's about
5500 miles. Which,
that's a
lot. Yeah, it's Russia. I was thinking Russia,
which is 6800 kilometers.
Which,
so if you take from Canada to the lower U
si think it's slightly less than the Russian Kazakhstan one.
That could be because that's fair.
Yeah,
because Alaska has that straight part and then it goes down the coastline a bunch.
All right.
So I need to ask just because you,
Kurt has been annoyingly enigmatic about this episode since last week.
-- What does any of this have to do with security?
-- Well, so the idea is that,
that
Canada has to protect its culture.
Otherwise we're just like the US is gonna like, roll over and like,
and not, like, intentionally crush us but just accidentally crush us because,
you know, you have 10 times as many people and Hollywood.
So the amount of culture that you guys put out in the world is ridiculous. Like
the number of, you know, major movies, TV, shows
all that kind of stuff coming out of the US is over 9000.
And of course,
it's like
the majority of what our TV networks put on because, you know,
they just license it and it's cheap to license because, you know, some Americans,
like, as far as they're concerned, Canada might as well be Kazakhstan for, you know,
for licensing fees.
Right.
Well, and it's the right language.
-- Yeah,
-- exactly. You don't even have to subtitle it or dub it.
So we have these laws that say you have to produce or no,
that you don't have to produce, but you have to show
Canadian content on radio and on TV networks a certain percentage.
And then of course, people started gaining it by,
like showing all the Canadian content in summer or like between 6 p.m. and 6 a.m.
So they passed a bunch of, you know, they amended the law a few times to,
you know, that you actually have to put Canadian content home and people can, like,
actually watch it and see it.
But the beauty is because of this
Canada has this
by world standards, actually quite healthy
but very,
-- very vibrant and strange and awesome content production like Schitt's
-- Creek.
-- I love that show so much
-- even you know about
like, which is a great example. I mean, it's Eugene Levy, his son
Daniel Levy who is awesome,
-- you know,
-- and his daughter,
his daughter plays a character named Twyla and Catherine o'hara is in it too.
-- She plays his wife and
-- Eugene Levy
and Catherine o'hara have been doing comedy together
since literally before I was born
1976 right? Like that's literally older than me. So
it's funny you bring this up and
I,
I knew this actually because one of my friends said
you have to go watch a show called Shit's Creek.
It's on Netflix and I started watching it with my wife and we were like,
this is amazing
and we watched them all.
Well, there's, I mean, there's one more season,
the last season isn't on Netflix yet.
So I don't have it. And
this is actually funny because Curt and I talked about this the
other day is you can't acquire Schitt's Creek on the normal places.
One would acquire a show, we'll say
because it turns out it's streaming in Canada on the CBC website,
which I can't access in the United States.
It's annoying because so CBC GM makes the current season available for free
and I, I think you can get the previous seasons and you just need to be logged in.
You don't actually need to pay.
It's not like you have to have a Comcast or a Shaw
or I'm going to use American terms because nobody knows what Shaw
is.
That's right.
Yeah.
So it's,
it's actually really hard to find through the usual channels
because it is so freely available in Canada that,
well, why would I pirate it when I can just go to
the
-- broadcast
-- corporation?
And that's ok. I will, I will wait.
I'm,
I'm very excited for the last season because it is enthralled me and captivated
me the way they've been developing the characters over the course of what,
like this is 66 season maybe.
And it's, I, I do enjoy it. But,
so you've got me thinking now, obviously this is a security podcast
and I think your, your technical definition of why this is a security topic is,
is maybe a little bit of a stretch we'll say.
But, well, you know what it reminds me of is Israel,
look at Israel and their computer security industry.
That is exactly what I was going to talk about. So well done.
-- Yeah,
-- they like, they are batting way above their size.
They're, they're punching above their weight,
-- they're
-- punching outside of their
sport.
-- They, they're, they're like, they're beating
-- up,
they're like Brazilian jiu jitsu versus dodgeball.
Explain why though, right? Because
there's a lot of people who have no idea what we're about to talk about.
-- So let's like, set the stage for us,
-- Kurt. Ok. So as people may or may not know.
Israel is a relatively small country, basically founded on the idea of
-- that's
-- enough of the politics.
Exactly.
But, so that, but what's interesting,
there's this thing in Israel where you have
mandatory military service and like many militaries,
the Israeli military has some stuff to do with computer security.
And they have this thing called unit 8200. That is their intelligence, corpse unit.
And they essentially, it's, it's your classic
sind computer hacking NSA style shenanigans type thing, which is cool.
But the beauty is, it's essentially, again, it's an incubator.
They, they basically take a bunch of like, they take,
they don't just take people like me and Josh were, you know, off the street,
they take the best of the best and then they, you know,
teach them whatever the current techniques and
also the new techniques they're developing are
right.
And then these people essentially age out of the military because,
because it's mandatory, you know, military service a lot.
Well, everybody goes through the military basically, but not everybody stays,
you know, some of them have normal jobs.
But the beauty is they, they have this,
they take this
talent pool, train it up a whole bunch
and then release it back into society and they don't just like,
release them back into society.
But it's like,
no, like you can instantly get a job at a security place or even better.
-- You can start a company,
-- right. Right.
And that's exactly what I was going to talk about is if you look at some of the,
the craziest cybersecurity start ups right now,
it is mostly Israeli companies or companies heavily connected to Israel
and, and this is why. And it's actually really interesting. So there's,
there's a friend and I have, his name is Jason Calloway and he, he, he was at redhead.
He's gone to Google now and he, like, this is a topic that he's very passionate about.
And he's got this group called Red Team and I'll put a link in the show notes.
But like one of his goals is like,
he wants to create content and ability to help people learn these kind of skills.
Because
in the United States and especially in the United States military,
there's currently AAA weakness.
They have, you know, their cyber command, they can do certain things,
but generally speaking,
it's nothing like what Israel is up to.
Well, I just checked and so this one site, 383 security companies in Israel,
right.
That
might be more than America.
I'm sure per capita they're probably blowing everyone out of the water, like,
seriously.
And what also gets me is just their degree of
professionalism and competency, right?
Because I mean, we're not just talking like start ups because no offense.
There's start ups all over the world
and most of them are you've never heard of and never will because they cratered out
-- real things.
-- That's how start ups work.
I mean, but, you know, you look at the Israeli market and it's,
yeah, like, wow,
what I was kind of trying to figure out is
how do you build a
comedy incubator? Like SC TV.
How do you build,
like,
because nobody intentionally built San Francisco
and the whole Silicon Valley thing.
It just sort of happened,
like, finance in New York.
-- Like, it just sort of, it's not like the government had some plan.
-- Well, ok.
No, they didn't just sort of happen.
There were, it was not a government. Well, the government sort of planned New York.
That's a long story.
But like Silicon Valley was just, I think the fact that you had, like, Steve Jobs,
you had Steve Wozniak, you had
the xerox people were all there, the HP people.
Well, it came out of World War I, I,
and all the radar technology stuff happening in World War.
I, I, right. And all the transistors. Yeah. Ok.
That was kind of what got it kick started is, you know,
Fairchild Semiconductor and all those guys were
in California building radar sets and stuff.
And so you kind of hit that weird critical mass where it just snowballed
and I guess it's like that first mover advantage where,
because you look around the world and there's just these odd places where it's like,
that's the place for whatever technology,
you know,
and it's just totally kind of weirdly
random and strange kind of quasi inexplicable.
And you do the history research and it, like, kind of boils down to, like,
it just so happened that there were like five guys there
and,
and probably in some other place were three guys
but they just didn't hit that critical mass.
But there's, there's two sides to this, right?
So you can pick on New York and San Francisco for example.
And those are places that I think it was happenstance.
But then you look at Israel and say Canadian television.
-- Oh yeah, that was not happenstance.
-- Those were not happenstance.
Those were actual efforts by governments to say we want to make this better.
Well, with the CBC, obviously, it's somewhat intentional because, you know, we,
we literally, it's taxpayer funded the Canadian broadcast Corporation.
But I'll be blunt like
they,
it's a combination of, of skill and, and a bit of luck because
to put it bluntly, things like SC TV or shit's creek like, yeah, they,
they hit a home run
like,
you know, they were trying to get into second or third base and they got lucky.
Well, and look for every Schitt's Creek.
There's probably 10 shows we've never heard of.
I wouldn't say it's that bad because there's also like, honestly,
right now we've got another one called Kim's Convenience.
I have not watched and I've seen outtake and things on youtube and it is a plus.
It's brutally amazingly funny.
And and, and here's the thing, it's not a Canadian show. It's a Torontonian show.
Let's be
like, speaking as well.
Briner, you know, Born and Bred.
It's a Toronto show and I love it for that.
-- It's like a
-- little car
of Canada.
It's a caricature
of Toronto. Let's be very clear. That is Toronto like no, seriously.
Like you put those people, if you transferred those characters even to Vancouver,
the show would make no damn sense.
Like, it just wouldn't work
really. So, it's like, have you ever seen Portlandia?
It's the Portlandia of Canada.
It would not work in New York or Texas.
Exactly.
And so,
yeah, so,
because, you know, I keep coming,
like, all these governments are like, oh, we want to encourage innovation and blah,
blah, blah,
blah
and like they
occasionally do tax breaks or whatever.
But like, fundamentally, I, I really think it has to be this really holistic.
Well,
it kind of reminds me of women in tech where
people are talking about women in tech and it's like,
cool, but like,
we need to start really early because by the time you get to university,
like a lot of them have dropped out because
essentially the environment is so terrible
to put
a blunt way.
No, I agree.
I agree completely.
And I think that's the advantage Israel has is they have that approach, you know,
starting when you turn 18, we're going to take the ones that did really well, in,
you know, their computer courses and, yeah, here we go.
Well, not only that there is
an atmosphere of coolness surrounding all this as well in Israel where obviously,
like, it's different now in the United States.
But like, when I was a kid growing up I was a nerd,
I got beat up a lot because I was a nerd and I liked computers and now, like,
computers are cool.
Well, to some people, there's a lot of video games and stuff.
We were working from home before. It was cool.
That's right. That's
-- right. We were,
-- you
know,
but
my life has literally not changed at all significantly.
Like
my kids are around a lot,
but it's,
it's actually funny. I want to tell my funny story now that you just reminded me.
So before we hit record, Kurt was complaining about his chair
and
he,
well, so is mine.
He commented that there's people on Twitter complaining
about their sore backs because they're using their,
like, you know, $12 Walmart chair that they bought 15 years ago now to work from home.
And
that's right.
And so my funny story is I used to buy cheap chairs where I
would spend less than $100 on a chair for probably the first five years.
I work from home. I bet. Like, now I've been doing this for almost 20.
Mind you, but for the first couple of years because I was young and I'm like, oh,
whatever.
I don't want to spend that much money on a chair. I'll be fine.
And there was one time that there was this critical issue
in Firefox and I literally worked for 28 hours straight.
I'll never forget this.
And after I was done,
I, I remember I, like, I couldn't sit because, like I had,
I had so many medical problems after that from
sitting for that long in my cheap chair.
I literally, before that, I'd be like $1000 chair. That's not worth it.
And I, I was like a $1000 chair, like, sign me up.
Yeah,
exactly. Like I have, I bought a Herman Miller Air on task chair
about 19 or 20 years ago. I've had to, since I have to, I had to replace the piston
and I have to replace it again because it's gone again.
But I also have like a sit stand desk that cost it was not cheap,
but it will lift 350 pounds.
And I actually had to teach my kids not to ride it
because my one guy basically just wanted to hang on to the edge and, like, up and down.
-- Right.
-- Well, and you know what?
Actually, this is totally related to the podcast topic is the fact that
there are certain investments that a very expensive chair on
the surface feels like you're wasting money on a chair.
But when you use it every day for eight hours a day. Like, holy crap.
You need a good chair.
Gets me people and mattresses when people try to go cheap on a mattress.
And I'm like, you spend one third of your life on this thing. Like, it's like shoes.
Right.
I used to whatever. Shoes, whatever. Right. If they fit, they fit.
And then I did ballroom dancing and like, my feet would
like, I own shoes that cost four or 500 bucks and they are so nice.
I don't own any shoes that expensive.
But the one thing I started doing that came from,
uh, someone I know who sells shoes, told me to do this.
The shoes you buy. Yeah, just buy, I buy really expensive. Like sliding insole
Deos
and that makes
all the difference.
So I, I like, I, I don't buy the cheapest shoes I can buy,
but I don't buy the nicest and then I just buy really, I honestly,
half the time I'm paying as much for my insoles as I have for shoes.
-- But it's totally worth it.
-- Folks.
If I can say one thing in life, be nice to your lower back and feet.
When you're 80 you will.
No one's going to listen to you.
No one's gonna listen to you because you're an old man. What do you know?
All I know now is every time I move my left shoulder it makes this weird noise.
Yeah, that's just part of getting old man. Everyone has that.
It's,
yeah,
and
-- brush your teeth.
-- That's all.
Floss, flossing is so important. You have no idea.
Right. No, I know. I know. I know. But, but again, ok, so
we're comically off topic again.
But, so the point is about
investing in these things that eventually reap rewards.
Well, it's, it's the buy one, cry ones. Right.
Because even back in the day, you know,
they talk about how poor people can only buy a pair of boots that
last year and they have to buy a new pair of boots every year.
And then, you know, over five years they spend more than they would have on
a
decent.
I remember when I was buying winter tires for my car.
I'm like, yeah, I kind of want cheap ones because, like, I basically drive my kids
to and from school and I, like, run errands in my car.
Like, I don't drive, drive and they're like, well,
we have winter tires that are like 74 bucks and I'm like,
no, I think we can spend a little more than that for four tires.
No, each, like, per tire. Yeah.
No, no.
-- Yeah. 74 bucks for four tires.
-- Wow.
-- What are these made of
-- chewing gum?
-- Um, but I pay
-- more than that for my bicycle.
Exactly. Exactly.
So, you know,
I ended up getting slightly better winter tires than the $74 Canadian option.
But I was like,
but my one thought was like, yeah, I guess some people, you know,
money's tight and honestly, cheap winter tires are still better than summer tires.
Or even
honestly, even
cheap winter tires are generally probably better than all seasons.
And, and I live in a place where, like, like right now.
Ok, we have, I think only three days. Uh, let's see. 00, no, it's not gonna snow.
Uh, it's gonna snow tomorrow and Tuesday
and then that should hopefully be the last snow for the year.
Uh, we've got lows of minus 20 °C.
That's
pretty
cool and highs of like, minus 10 on Wednesday. So, that's,
well, the good news is
that weather will keep people indoors.
-- Uh, that is true. And that's
-- important. It's not a bad thing right now.
Yeah. But
I,
I think you have to hit this weird critical mass and the
problem is it has to be a critical mass of everything.
It has to be money and investment and it has to be mentorship and it has to be
not just, I don't want to say, like, mentorship but it has to be like
the ability to,
you know, have a weird question and be like, oh,
I know a guy that knows a guy that knows about that.
Let's just ask him and, like, we'll take him out for coffee and pick his brain about,
like,
whatever strange topic.
I, I think you're right.
But I think there's a really important part is
I think if you let this grow holistically,
there's gonna be a lot of failed starts where
you need like the right combination of ingredients.
But if you look at like, what Canada has done and what Israel has done,
which are very different topics.
But the fact is
they were basically willing to just money,
fire this problem for as long as they needed to
and, but sometimes that's OK. Right.
Well, dude, that's how you guys got to the moon before the end of the decade.
Remember, like, literally JFK was like, you know, it's,
we're doing this in by the end of the decade and NASA is like, cool,
-- give us all your money and
-- you know what's really funny about that?
So I read, I forget one of the, one of the early astronauts I think it might have been.
Was it Jim Lovell? I don't remember which one.
Now, I read a book he wrote, I'll, I'll, I'll figure it out and put it in the show notes.
But basically
they were talking about the space program and Kennedy
before Sputnik, he didn't care, he was like, whatever nerds.
I don't care about space. This is stupid.
Well, and the thing is until Sputnik he wasn't wrong
and
Yeah. Right.
But after Sputnik all of a sudden it was like, all right, how do we get to the moon?
They're like, wait, what? And then he was like, yeah, like, get us there now.
And it was, of course, it was kind of bananas.
Oh,
the amount of money they spent that if they'd even taken one or two
more years that they could have saved like 30 or 40% of their budget.
But they had
stake in the ground and they made it happen because they
were willing to literally put any resources possible into this problem.
Well, and the thing is that the ironic thing too though
is I say if they'd spent like one or two more years,
they could have saved a significant amount of budget.
But on the flip side by making it happen now,
they made a whole bunch of like electronics and, you know,
just all sorts of amazing computer stuff happened.
Well, no,
just
happened one or two years earlier, which
got us one or two more years of internet, which honestly in the long term, sure means
they probably should have spent twice as much money in taking six months
off the project because we would have had six more months of internet.
Right.
Well, not only that the Russians would have gotten to the moon first,
which was basically
like, that is the only thing they cared about was getting there first.
But it is sad though because I look at that and think, look at all this progress we had,
we got there and we were like, well, screw it.
-- That's good
-- enough at the time though.
Technologically speaking, there was nothing more you could do.
However, now, now we're at a point where, ok, you know, we found ice on the moon.
That means we can make rocket fuel. That's interesting.
There,
there's a really interesting concept behind this and I forget who I was reading
that talked about this. But you think about it.
We went to the moon in the sixties because
we could right where like the technology existed,
but it was an enormous amount of work to actually make it all work together.
And again,
this is where like the government just shoveling money
in the fire is what made it happen.
Whereas now we actually have the technology to actually
go to the moon in an economical and reasonable.
SpaceX
is getting there, right? Elon Musk talks about this.
He's like you can build the first one, you just make your engineers do it easy.
The second one, yeah, you can kind of make them do it
but you want to produce one of these a week,
you can't have your engineers
and the worst problem. And he talked about this
is your engineers then have to build
horrendously complex systems to make
the thing you want to make.
And the the thing is
to build the systems that make the thing you want to make.
They have to be horrendously complex and amazing so
that like people like me and Josh can operate them
because
you know, like I, I like to watch machining videos like a shout out to a VE ABC guy,
French Canadian or he speaks, his French is beautiful anyways
and
the way the guy does
machine,
his videos are amazing.
I've learned so much about power tools and how
to just how to think about mechanical systems.
And it's just brutal to think the difference between him and me and Josh,
like me and Josh.
If you put us in front of a lathe
piece of metal, we would. Best case scenario, we only maim ourselves,
I'm losing a finger for sure.
The
best,
that's the best case scenario.
Worst case scenario is we kill ourselves and burn down the shop.
-- There's a good possibility that would happen also.
-- Yeah. And shrapnel,
you know, when you think about a piece of metal spinning at like one or 2000 R PM.
Uh
-- Yeah,
-- that's, that's a bit of kinetic energy.
I love watching
the, the metal lathe
when they do that one,
when they do that smoothing cut and it goes from all rough to just mirror.
I
know it's so beautiful, isn't it?
So they don't get like any chowder marks or any,
like all of a sudden it goes from rough to like just mirror and it's just
all,
there's a video I'll try to find a la.
There's this guy who goes and like digs out tree
roots and then makes things out of them on a lathe
and it's the most,
but the lathe is like bouncing up and down while he's like trying to, you know,
trim it down.
I'm like
this
guy,
this guy is nuts. Right? Because it's,
you know, the center of gravity is not where the lathe is turned
and, but when he's done it's beautiful.
-- But I just, every time I watch this guy I think like, this is the day you die, man.
-- Well,
what also gets me about fever
like that is like the differences in densities in different parts of the
world like that just,
and now I know that from watching these youtube videos,
like I know that like you will never catch me putting
anything on a lathe that like,
I don't know exactly what it is because like I understand how dangerous it is now.
Yeah, it's, it's something, it's something for sure.
Yep. Yep. Alright.
Anyway, anyway, we, we, we were at hold again, we're nearing the end. So
I, I guess let, let's tie this one all up and
my, my thought on this topic is that
what you really need to kind of push the needle in some of these places?
And this is true of an organization. It can be true of yourself personally.
It can be true of a country of a government of the planet.
If there's something you want to do,
you're gonna have to invest in it and sometimes it's gonna
suck and sometimes it's gonna feel like you're throwing money
or time or anything in the fire and you are,
but that's ok.
And it's even worse than that. You're not only going to have to invest in that thing
but all the things that touch it.
Yeah, that's probably true too. Like, no offense.
You can't have Silicon Valley without potable water, reliable electrical grid,
good
roads. Good. Take out.
I was reading something where you can't ship stuff to a lot
of places in the world because it gets stolen on the way.
And I was thinking, I'm like, oh, that actually makes sense because, you know,
I'm thinking like, I,
I buy stuff online all the time and these just completely random people, like,
drop it off on my doorstep and I'm trying to think of the last time
-- I ordered a package and didn't get it
-- every time I have that problem.
It's because someone down the street got it actually.
So it's funny, I live at 519 and there's a 915 down the street and it's
very common. We get each other's packages.
Well,
and I think that's more an indication of how
many people have numeric dyslexia than anything else.
Humans. Exactly. Whatever. And we just, you know, go walk it down the street.
Yeah, exactly. That's like,
yeah, last mile problems. But,
but fundamentally, like, I honestly, if I had to send 1000 bucks to somebody,
I couldn't email it to them, I would just put it in an envelope like Canada Post.
Honestly, Canada Post is like,
the,
literally the only thing they've ever done is I
once got my mail with like treads on it,
like tire tread marks.
I've
got that
and I'm like, ok, well, somebody dropped it, whatever it was flat to begin with.
Have you ever heard the story of how they shipped
the Hope Diamond in a brown box in the mail?
-- And
-- after making a big to do of a security production, security theater of like,
oh this big lock box
it was gonna get stolen.
And they like,
and they mailed the real one like just in the post,
which is perfect and nobody knew no one cared and whatever,
it's just another box in the post.
So a funny story,
a friend of mine ordered me some uh food and didn't
tell me because they wanted to do something nice for me.
So this guy shows up at the door like two days ago,
he only gives me the the street number, not the street.
And I'm like, yeah, and he's like, I have, you know, skip the dishes.
I'm like, it's not my food. Sorry.
He's like,
ok and he leaves and then I get this text
like 20 minutes later saying did the food arrive?
-- And I'm like,
-- what, you know what? That's one thing I've learned over the years is
it's lovely doing nice things for people but like tell them
it's coming because that exact thing happens more often than not.
Well, especially right now, I'm like, I'm literally at the point where, like,
if you're not the mailman,
get out of my, get off my lawn. Anyway.
Anyway,
I think the moral of the story is, is that
it's, you know what, this reminds me of a lot is dependencies in software
because you can't just build Silicon Valley with like a bunch of computer geeks.
You also need people to feed them
and to house them and to like provide them with, you know,
pinball bars so they can go hang out and like
whatever
-- we will call it the supply chain. Ah
-- It's more than the supply chain.
-- It's the, I hate to say this. It's the ecosystem. Yeah.
-- Yeah. You know.
-- Yeah, exactly. I, I'll agree with that. I'll agree with that.
-- Right.
I, I'm sorry, I hate to use that word because it's overused,
but I'm not wrong.
You
hear
it,
folks,
I'm gonna end on that.
It's
the ecosystem. Everybody
-- that's, it's anyway. All right,
-- we'll put a link to the IT crowd.
Yeah.
All right. Awesome. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up the show. Not easy
Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag
to hit us up on social media
and I have one added thing I'm going to throw in at the end of this one is,
these are horrible times for many of us.
So if you have a fun topic or something.
You think that would be enjoyable by all means,
let us know because we are doing our best to not talk
about terrible news because there's already enough of that in the world.
-- So next week we're going to talk about assembling a treadmill.
-- You can't say that.
Now I'm gonna put these out of order. You can't say that I'm gonna do it wrong.
No, I'm not. I'm leaving it in there
and I'm gonna purposely not do next week as
a treadmill just to teach you a valuable lesson.
Kurt.
So.
All right.
Thank you, everyone. Thank you, Kurt. Have a fantastic rest of your day. You too.
Stay safe. Everybody. That's right. Thanks everyone. Bye bye
that.