Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
and my partner in playing video games. Occasionally, Josh Pressers.
I play video games a lot. Not occasionally
I don't have time for it anymore.
Plus whenever I play a multiplayer game,
I just get killed in the first like five minutes.
I don't play multiplayer games. I'm too bad.
I, I mostly play single player, Nintendo games and I, I really like to actually
have a switch.
The switch is a marvelous device because I
can play for like five minutes and then just
put it to sleep and set it to the side and not touch it again for sometimes days.
I get the feel like Nintendo
came out with the Game Boy
and
I feel like they're one of those few companies that are like, OK,
what did we do everything right with the game boy?
OK, let's just do that again.
-- But with like a color screen
-- and that was the game boy color.
And then,
and then like, let's add some haptic controls and like
accelerometers and stuff and like maybe a little bit of Wi Fi
-- and that's the switch.
-- It it's very good though. Yes.
No, I'm just saying, like, Nintendo's smart enough not to f it up.
It is funny because I remember
probably 10 years ago everyone was like, Nintendo is a joke and they're done
and now
they have outs sold. Like, so
it's at,
at this moment in time there's a Nintendo Switch PS five and
the Xbox one or I don't even know what they call it.
Xbox X series X,
whatever the switch I believe has outs sold the other two put together
because they kind of, they just created like their own market of like we're not the,
the big fancy game system.
We're the game system everyone owns plus their big fancy game system.
And so they've captured
Xbox
P CS.
Uh No, no, no, it's OK.
So the switch has sold 36 and a quarter million units in the last 29 months worldwide.
The PS five sold 35.8 million and the Xbox Series Xs sold 21.35 million.
So it's
ok. OK.
-- It's doing well.
-- It's doing very well,
but
that's not.
Our topic is not the Nintendo Switch,
even though I would love to talk about it for hours.
So it's, it's
cap
con did a thing that I think is,
well, basically Capon
thinks PC game modeling is no different than cheating,
right? And I love this conversation because I think it ties in
with a lot of security things
marvelously
-- Well, and so first of all,
-- summarize the story first, before you go on,
summarize the story about capcom.
So
for years now fans have been using mods to alter games in weird and wonderful ways.
Like a great one is um what is it Skyrim? Right. Apparently.
Well, somebody tied in open A I to the N PC so that you can actually talk to them now,
right?
Seems kind of cool.
Uh
oh, So basically they did a presentation shared in the cap on R and D youtube
channel
and the video talks about cheating and piracy and
PC games and the impact they can have.
As Capcom sees that mods are part of the problem. So, uh here we go
during the presentation around the 14 minute mark.
Capcom suggests that mods are no different than cheats.
All mods are defined as cheats except when they are officially supported. It says
what they are doing internally is no different than cheating. It's not that
the company is staunchly against players using mods
to enhance or switch up the experience.
It does acknowledge that the majority of mods can have a positive impact on the game.
Still from a business perspective.
It warns that they can be detrimental both in terms of the
reputational damage that offensive mods can cause and the extra workload,
players who've installed buggy mods can generate for the support team.
This the company argues can ultimately lead to
delays in the games production higher development costs.
No stop pause. How does support in a release game
effect
building a new game,
like supporting a already released game?
Those people have nothing to do with building a new game.
I think their justification is that
when people install dodgy mods and it breaks their game and then
they're gonna email Capcom support and say my game is broken.
Please help me and so they have to spend more money on
support people which would take away R and D money for new
-- games.
-- You and I both know that's BS because like Linux
taint, I'm just
like the Linux kernel taint mode. Like we're not supporting that,
like come back with a crash dump that isn't tainted.
So for those of you that don't know, the Linux kernel has modules has since a
lot.
My favorite being the um, the Intel Ether Express pro 10 driver very stable mod.
After that NASA guy fixed it all up anyways.
So the deal is you have mods module, sorry, not mods.
And
this way a hardware company could build a close source module for the Linux kernel.
That's right. Right.
For example, or, or you could just build your own open source module and,
and it doesn't, it's not good enough to get into the Linux kernel or something.
So basically the way it works is
when they,
they also encountered this problem where people are running weird and
crappy modules causing crashes and problems and then they're like,
hey, Linux des fix this and they're like,
we can't, like when they finally figure out what's going on, like, we,
we can't fix this.
So they introduced taint and basically taint to summarize it.
If you're running a clean, officially supported, everything is correct.
Linux kernel, it's not tainted.
And the minute you add anything that little taint flake gets set
and the Linux kernel developers tell you to go away.
Yeah. Well, re reproduce it without whatever dodgy crap you haven't
installed.
I mean,
I
get that
you just do that.
-- I know, I know
-- this is
-- just
-- a company being like,
well, no, no. OK. OK. Hold on, hold on. I wanna, I wanna bring this all back.
So the article also Capcom has a bunch of
comments about piracy and how piracy is ruining everything.
And my favorite,
my favorite quote
here is basically
they call piracy and immediately loss a profit.
But then
the next sentence
says then again,
Capcom admits that the size of this profit loss is unobservable
because there is no suitable control case to compare it to.
Here is I think the fundamental conversation around this whole situation.
This is the equality versus equity
discussion
where
as humans,
we have this like
inherent need for equality, right? Where we think
I paid off my student loans. It's not fair.
That person doesn't have to pay off theirs.
I did this, it's not fair. That person doesn't have to do that
-- and there are millions of discussions. We see
-- this, everybody else is speeding.
-- Why did you pull me over?
-- Right. Exactly.
We see this in security where security, like,
we obsess over these minute details and we don't look at like, big picture,
we don't say
every single welfare system in North America that
spends how much money trying to prevent fraud
versus the actual fraud amounts.
It's,
I've, I've read some reports that point out that it's just bonkers.
Yes. Exactly. Exactly. That
versus,
but more equitable situations where you could say like, OK,
I know there's going to be some piracy.
Some of the people are just genuinely thieves.
Some of the people can't afford it, you know, the whatever,
there's a million reasons
rather than trying to say it's an even playing field.
Let's just deal with what we've got and go from there
and similar situations like insecurity where
you see these obsessions over like zero vulnerabilities or we
have to meet all the controls or we can't have
anyone,
-- you know, failing the fishing test or whatever.
-- My favorite is capas
now where the computers are better at captures than you.
I know. Right.
Because I, and I'm straight up like, oh perfect example,
I'm gonna throw CV under the bus here.
The CV form has a capa
it's visual only. It's not,
there's no
accessible option
and the capture was so bad that I failed it several times
before I succeeded.
Apparently.
Like, it was,
it was dang near unreadable.
And I'm, I, like,
I have a big monitor and like the thought of doing this on a phone or a mobile device.
I don't,
I could barely do it on my PC.
And so it's just,
yeah, so
bizarre that we like, and I get that abuse and all these things do happen at scale.
Like we had some spammers come through our
social platform and like register bad accounts.
But,
but yeah, in general, especially with piracy and you know,
like the traditional view is piracy takes something away in the form of revenue.
The traditional thing is like the traditional argument is like,
you're not allowed to take somebody's car, use it and return it
because, well,
you didn't get permission and also wear and tear and you might crash it or whatever.
Well, sure
piracy doesn't have that problem.
It's digital bits that were copied, right?
The original copy is still healthy and safe and fine. Wherever it is.
Number two,
you can make the argument that like if somebody has a
Pirated copy and they phone in for support that increases cost.
But that's
ok. I don't want to dwell on piracy. I don't think piracy is important here, I think.
-- Well,
-- it's
-- so
-- weird that it's still,
I think what gets me about piracy is that we're still seeing the exact same argument
that we saw 30 years ago.
-- But
-- no, no, this, this makes sense No, no. And it is, look at security,
we see security arguments that are decades old that we know they don't work,
but we still do it that way.
I mean,
-- the password rotation. Yeah, passwords
-- are one of my favorite where
like Nist has just said that these, this is not how it works
yet.
There is pervasive attitudes of how passwords should work because I mean,
passwords are a perfect example where
as squishy humans,
it feels like complicated passwords are better
and changing passwords more often is better,
right?
Like these are things that feel right to us as people.
And I think,
you know, focusing on modding software or, or whatever
it feels like someone is taking my hard work
and they're ruining it,
right? I mean, this is like,
like derivative works and art and, and remember when
I forget the name of it,
it was like the Andy Warhol crew where they were all about
like art should be reproducible and modifiable and all this stuff.
-- And
-- a lot of, well, the Campbell's, oh the the prince, prince,
the art is formerly known as Prince, right?
Princes of him and the ownership of that photo
and the reproduction of it and all that mess.
Tons of artists were like these people are nuts. Like this is an art, art,
art is what I make and if you touch my art, you're ruining it.
Well, I'm pretty sure like, you know,
when somebody built a paint brush instead of using their fingers.
Everybody else was like, oh,
that's cheating. Like you can't, you can't use animal hair on a stick.
That's how you use your finger.
You can only smear various substances with your fingers,
right? Like,
well that's, that's like, remember like my favorite is Tron
Great movie
10 effects for special effects because it was essentially they used computers
for the special effects and this had never been done before.
Therefore,
you're like,
yeah, you're cheating. Like, we can't give you
the award for special effects,
even though clearly the movie has really
good special effects and it's awesome movie.
And we're still talking about 40 years later
-- because
-- it's still awesome.
Yeah, like, even my son loves it.
I mean, you know what's funny is I watched the new Tron not too long ago
and I was like,
this isn't a bad movie but like the, the first one is just like,
so good and I feel like it's still good.
The second one almost made it, especially with having
the music and, you know,
the, the crew and cast. But
yeah, it just kind of, and it was like,
it was like the first one was a sandwich from a really small place
with people who yell at each other because they're
family and the second sandwich was from like subway.
Yeah. Yeah, that's fair. It was a good sandwich but it could have been better
anyway. Ok.
I want to bring us back to the,
the bigger conversation right around modding and
cheating and piracy and all this stuff.
And here's the thing,
the one thing I also want to, uh,
because we talked about this in a previous episode with the Minecraft stuff.
But in my mind, if you are playing a single player game by yourself,
who cares what you do? Who like, like,
I'm sure people play solitaire with physical cards and cheat. Who cares?
But when you sit down at a table in Vegas and are playing poker,
you're not allowed to look at the cards because that would be cheating in a way
that like for a game that matters with money on the line or against other people.
And so I would say I would, I would bucket it into three big buckets.
Number one playing
yourself sort of unranked. Doesn't matter.
Number two, playing with others ranked
cheating.
Their kind of a dick move like this happens a lot in chess.com where
people will start using a chess engine to play chess and stomp everybody.
And it kind of like,
well, I'm like 1100 elo, I want to play an 1100 elo game and have fun. I don't
want to get stomped by somebody using a chess ball, you know, playing at 3000 delo.
And then the third bucket where cheating is clearly cannot be
allowed is where you have like tournament play or play for money
where you actually have
rules because there's money on the line and regulations,
right? So I would say those are the three main buckets of kind of how games are played.
And for the first bucket, single player
don't care
for the second bucket. I would argue
you should be allowed to cheat in a cheating loud and acknowledged.
You should have a stream for people who want to play moded games or cheat.
And you see this with like Age of Empires, like,
there's people playing modded Age of Empires in
-- multiplayer and they all agree to play
-- it
and they, I assume they have the same mods and things like that then.
-- Yeah. Well,
-- yeah, otherwise that would not go well,
-- I mean, I, I agree.
-- Right.
Same with Starcraft. Starcraft has mods. Now there's three additional races,
different mechanics. Kind of cool. They also
portals in one which is really funky.
So, like people that's not cheating, it's like you have to, yeah,
you have both have to install the mods and agree to play this moded game.
Sure. That's fair. I mean, and portals make everything better
to put it bluntly.
This is like saying everybody cheats at monopoly because
everybody plays it not according to the rules.
-- Does anyone play monopoly according
-- to the rules? Exactly.
Right. Does anyone know the rules to monopoly?
It's not cheating if everybody agrees that those are the rules?
I mean, well, it,
-- uh, there
-- are games with cheating mechanics built in.
But
you can say that saying it's not cheating if everyone agrees to the rules
is
counter to the current copyright holder versus receiver
-- Digital Universe we live in.
-- Let's take monopoly as an example.
So if I want to play monopoly online with my house
rules and I mod the game that's like D MC,
a circumvention and illegal.
But if we're playing over the table O TB
to grab a chess term that I've learned because I'm
otg
-- over the table, like physically present over the
-- table would be O tt
-- you said ot over the board?
-- Sorry.
So I would apply monopoly as well.
So if we're playing over the board and we agreed to change rule like free parking,
you win money,
right?
That's legal
rule. Like,
-- but that's what
-- I,
if we
do
this,
it's like a massive fine and like jail time.
And if we just do it over the board, it's like,
well,
you
can
agree
to
digital rights on content. If I have a bunch of MP threes, I can't sell them to you
legally. But if I have a CD or a record, I can sell that thing to you,
right?
And I think this is kind of similar where Capcom is complaining about cheaters and
mos
because
it's changing the thing they made and they obviously don't like people doing that.
It, it just,
it seems to always boil down to this weird version
of like they want to just control it all.
But
I feel like, like security teams come. Right.
But the thing that also gets me is like, a lot of these games
do much better because of the mods,
I think, yes, if Skyrim didn't have mods,
I don't think we'd still be talking about Skyrim.
-- What, like 20 years later, you know what
-- it reminds me of?
It reminds me of Twitter where, yeah, like only 0.000001% of people actually
really post interesting content
and that's why they need access to the API because yeah,
the vast majority of people want API access.
But if you shut off that API access as we like,
well, at the cloud security lines,
we can't use our third party social media management tool anymore.
Ah
Right. Like, because we have an account
that is
like
more than one or two people need to post to on a schedule
with, combined with other things to linkedin and everything. Right?
And that's the other thing that gets me is like by taking
away this ability to kind of personalize or modify or whatever the game
you're telling all the power users to go away. And
if you lose that community, I
that's, I would agree.
But I think that comes back to the equality versus equitable discussion
is if you want to say everyone is equal,
we're going to crack down on everyone using this thing versus saying
there's a group of people,
we need to be doing this and we know there's going
to be some abusers that sneak in for spam or whatever.
But we can't let do that small number, ruin the experience for everyone else.
And I get it because, like, you know, I'm, well, the, like the whole
Tarkoff cheating thing where it's ruining it for everybody. Right.
Because cheaters are just rampantly running around and, you know,
ging everybody.
But again, like there's, there's ways to,
you know, to go back to Starcraft,
there's a really good way to know if you're cheating on the ladder.
And that is, if your r weight is over, then if your win rate is more than 50%
then you're ranked too low.
-- It's that simple now. And
-- obviously you get ranked higher, then if that happens,
you get ranked higher as you win.
And so people will intentionally join a game and immediately quit it to like, lose it
right to bring down their mmr to go smurfing.
But again, that's pretty, you know, stuff like that is easy to detect.
And so
I like what gets me is also is I suspect it's not about equality and equity.
It's about we want control.
What story can we tell? That's better than
we want control.
Oh, we're trying to make it fair.
-- That's a much better story than I want to control this.
-- I mean, that's fair.
That's II I won't disagree with you. I think so. This is where I'm going.
I want to bring this right back to
security because we're a security podcast after all.
I feel like I say that too often,
but
are we, no one knows,
anyone
could have started on healthcare.
-- Not
-- today,
not today.
But so I, I think
the control aspect is important because
like security teams
want to control their environments.
We just had a vendor submit a questionnaire to us of all the usual stuff
and they've come back and they're like freaking out and it's like, yeah, we like,
you don't have 100% antivirus coverage of all user devices.
And I'm like, no, not even a little bit because
bring your own device buddy.
And I point out that we're,
we're actually pretty close to having good coverage of all our
computers, but like
there's no good antivirus product for mobile. So I'm like,
and I don't think it's necessary.
So, yeah. No, not doing it
right.
And like they're freaking out about it like they,
and now they apparently want some financial details about us and I'm like,
no, like
they have
all billing contact,
you know,
like this. Yeah, anyways.
So
I feel like a lot of companies just, they're stuck in those old mindsets of like,
yeah, we want to control this.
We don't want any negative, you know,
we don't want negative mods floating around of like,
you know, or like GT A remember when people were like beating up the prostitutes to,
what was it?
Oh,
they would use the prostitute to gain health and then they
would beat them up to steal their money and stuff.
And everybody's like, that's socially terrible. And it's like,
well, I mean,
it's GT a four.
Yeah, it's socially GT a, the premise of the game is to be socially terrible. Like,
did I,
like, you're literally grand.
It's the name.
-- Yeah.
-- You're the bad guy.
Like, it's Grand Theft auto. Like that is,
there's
what?
And yeah. Yeah.
And I'm like, and they're worried about their reputation. What?
I don't know if rock
-- star cares,
-- like, you don't get well, but you know,
you don't get to make that argument.
Like
anyways, I, I,
-- this conversation has gone off the rails but
-- I, well, but no, you're right.
There are so many parallels with security where people want to control stuff.
And the question is
I would always have is
why do you want to control it?
And they always come back with oil to reduce risk and to manage it.
-- And I'm like, but does it actually do that?
-- No, almost never. Rarely. Yeah, for sure.
I mean, my favorite example is I think fishing training.
I love,
I love beating on fishing training because there's so many people that obsess over
fishing training and it's like studies have
consistently shown fishing training while it might have
minor differences between tests where you could say, oh,
we have 10% less fishing in our, our testing now and whatnot.
Like
the entire intent behind fishing
is to exploit the very thing that makes us human.
Like you can't, you can't, if people are people, they can be fished like that's all.
Yeah.
And I would say there's putting in actually effective security controls like multi
factor Fido based authentication where you can't give it to the wrong site.
That's what you see.
But that,
but see that actually requires the it crew to do something that's hard
whereas they can externalize the cost of fishing by putting it on to the users,
bad users.
Right. Exactly.
Or another way to sort of externalize the cost
but is somewhat useful is to teach them.
Like if Bob asks you to do X reach out back to Bob on a good,
like known good email or whatever,
like don't just let Bob at gmail.com email you
saying like change the payment details for this check,
please?
Right. Exactly.
Like that's an example of you're still sort of Externalizing the cost,
but at least it has the possibility of working
and see this is what frustrates me is.
It's like spanking your kids.
I was spanked as a child.
I grew up kind of thinking that was normal.
And then when I had kids, my now ex-wife was like, yeah, we're not spanking, right?
And I'm like, what do you mean we're not spanking?
Of course, we're spanking, spank your kids and she's like,
it's bad for kids. And I'm like, huh, what do you mean? She's, like, study show.
It's bad for your kids. So, I actually went and checked
the current literature on it
and I'm like,
oh, so spanking is, it is actually bad for your kids.
And my favorite part doesn't work.
And the simplest argument I would have is,
did you get spanked more than once as a child?
Yes, of course. You did.
You get spanked
more?
So then
how's that working?
Right. If it works for sure.
Right.
And so I'm like, ok, so it emotionally damages your child and it doesn't work.
Ok, we're not spanking our kids. And I remember actually when Felix was eight,
uh, we were talking about it and he's like, what's spanking? And I'm like, wow,
ok, that's,
I feel a bit better as a parent today,
you know, and I had to explain to him what spanking was and he's like,
that sounds like you're hitting them and I'm like
that,
like it is kind of a bit assaulting
a
little bit.
Like if I did that in public to a stranger, I feel like the cops might yell at me.
Right. Like, that's, that's kind of my yardstick for a lot of behaviors.
Now, it's like if I or better yet,
if I did that to a cop in public without their consent,
-- how is that gonna go?
-- Well,
but again, again,
this comes back to that idea of as humans
if
there's a very,
I have done a thing and I feel like it has changed the situation for the better.
Well,
I can't help but wonder too if people hang on to these things as effective because
they would have to admit they're wrong. Like the password thing, like the,
for
sure he can.
And he's like,
and,
but people would have to admit they were wrong.
And how often do people say, you know what
that thing I spent 10 years saying to do? Yeah, it was wrong.
A lot of people don't ever like to admit they're wrong. I mean, for sure.
And that's like a whole different discussion.
But I, I think
this is where like, like, so Capcom, I'm gonna, I'll,
I'll go back to them for a moment
with their cheating and their piracy and everything.
It would be marvelous
if they did
like an an in depth investigation to understand
like,
look at how much piracy a game has, look at how much revenue the game has,
look at how much modding the game has and correlating some of this data
instead of saying we feel like it's bad.
Well, and so, you know, Microsoft was famously said,
people said Microsoft should do that, right?
And Microsoft kind of didn't that they gave away Windows 7 to 11 upgrades,
right? Like
they, you know, essentially made Windows like, yeah,
you want to download the iso it used to be a very big process.
Now, it's like two clicks
and you just need a valid key
and you can just straight up plug in your, well, you used to be able to straight up,
plug it.
Like,
I'd have to go find the DVD and like look at
the key and plug it in to my windows 11 install.
That's like what I'm currently sitting on. So,
but then the problem becomes too, is a smart company will
encourage piracy
and dominate the market.
And then because here's the thing,
if let's say 1% of people are going to buy your product.
Well, if you give it away for free, for one or two revisions
and they get 1% of the total market versus just like the few people willing to pay
you, you potentially make a lot more money in the long term. And
I'm not sure that that's such a bad thing for the company because the company is not
like they're selling their product and they're allowing piracy. I
it's funny to me that people get angry
when companies do allow piracy because it's like,
but they're going to take over the market and then they're going to
sell it and crack down on piracy and it's kind of like,
so don't use them.
So, so there is an actual
parallel we recently discussed all about this.
Remember Hay
Corp changing their license,
you could argue it was the same tactic as encouraging piracy of your application
and then one day deciding we're going to actually start going after people.
-- It is suspiciously parallel. And
-- if you look at hashy
Corp,
let's just say they're not having a great time right now.
They lost them.
What is the phrase they use? Oh, yeah.
Uh The, the that shows up on the sec reports,
the measure of goodwill and that number like,
yeah, I'm glad I'm not a hashy corps shareholder. That's pretty much what I see
here.
But I, I think again, this is that whole
a quality versus equitable, right? Where
when you're hatching
Corp and you're doing all this work in open source and
it feels like people are taking advantage of your work,
which that's a different argument, right?
-- Versus saying like we understand,
-- see that's the thing.
If they didn't want people to take advantage of their work,
they shouldn't have released it under an open source license.
I agree.
However, the hip
start up business model
is,
I'm going to release a bunch of stuff open source because now I can get attention
for my open source and then I'm going to chain pull the rug out someday.
Well, the thing is,
it basically allows a company to gather a whole bunch of free value,
right? They get to harvest a whole bunch of free value for zero cost or very low cost
-- and then lock it up.
-- Sounds like the modern community to me,
right?
So I don't know I just, I do wish,
like, I,
I do wish that there was sort of,
let's stop pretending and have ranked play for cheaters.
Kind of like the same thing with, like,
you know, there's always that argument that, like,
I want to see the Olympics but with no drug testing and it's like, you know,
like, yeah, those people are going to wreck their bodies.
But if you look at the average Olympic athlete, like a lot of them,
they, they don't have, they have a lot of health problems long term.
Yeah. Yeah,
for
sure,
sure.
So
I kind of wish we would stop this game and like,
if people want to cheat or they want to play Skyrim with everybody.
But,
and the other thing too is this totally ignores the issue of accessibility where,
like,
maybe I don't have arms but I still want to play video games.
Yeah,
like there's mouse mice for your feet and stuff and,
you know, control inputs that track your head and your eye movement and stuff.
-- There's
-- actually, so there's like, I don't know if, do you remember Ben? Heck
did
he ring a bell? He had a, he used to do an Element 14 show called Ben Heck Hacks.
And he would do like amazing projects.
So he's since
I don't know why he's not with Element 14 anymore, I have a suspicion.
It wasn't a particularly pleasant departure, but
he still has a youtube channel and I love watching him.
And one of the things he does is Ben
heck mods controllers to be like one handed devices.
And like his videos are fascinating and he talks all about the process and he,
and it's amazing
and that's a great example of him, like literally taking a thing, someone made,
he's changing it and then he's reselling it,
like in the digital world
that's
100% off limits.
You know, it cracks me up like you see cars, like, um,
I had a neighbor who was in a wheelchair and he
had a pickup truck with like a little crane in the back
so that he could like,
get into his truck and then have the little crane kind of grab his wheelchair and
swing it and throw it in the back of his
truck because funnily enough when you don't have working legs,
it's really hard to get into a truck and then put your wheelchair
like
somewhere
in the truck.
Right. Right. Who knew? Right.
And
yeah, so
I, I don't know, I just, it, it really also comes back to like I bought this game,
do I not own this game?
And I get that there's a bit of a gray area
if I'm using an online service to play multiplayer games,
blah, blah, blah.
But fundamentally,
yeah, I feel like,
like the biggest thing I've noticed, I buy apps for my kids, I buy them.
I spend the money.
Right.
And then they either stop working on newer versions
of I OS because of security permission stuff.
Right.
Or in the case of I'm gonna call Lego out like I haven't
passed their duple game was awesome and then they made it suck.
And my son is still sad about it and still wants to watch
the videos on youtube over the playthroughs because he just wants that poor
little bunny rabbit to get his ice cream to share with his friends.
I'm dead serious. That's all he wants.
I mean,
it's a valid
-- concern and it's a,
-- it's,
and the worst part is the Lego Juniors game, for example, has been now.
It's not even that they modified Lego Juniors so that it sucks.
They took it off the store. So we have it running on one ipad.
Gotcha.
That
orange.
Don't ever get rid of that thing now. Right.
Yeah,
it's a fun game.
I don't, I don't have an answer to this but I think the one,
the one takeaway and I think the way we should end this one is just
there
any time we are involved in a situation similar to
like security policy and process or piracy and modding or
you know how we're distributing content, whatever is going on.
I think our human nature is to default to equality
instead of defaulting to like what is actually
equitable and makes sense because sometimes the bad guys
that they, you can't stop them all.
But sometimes trying to stop them all ruins it for everyone else.
Well, and it's back to that famous argument of like,
if Google affects 0.1% of their user base for an hour.
Yeah, that sucks.
But what if they affect
10,000 people forever?
Right.
That's right.
You know,
and so part of what I've been looking at is like,
what is the actual outcome we want here?
And the actual,
and this is what drives me nuts is the actual outcome is it's not that we want to stop
the bad or abusive behavior. We want to enable the good behavior
and have like a clean public park without
it being covered in trash and dog poop and stuff, right?
So that means we do want people to pick up after their dog or whatever and
there might be other ways to accomplish that
than just trying to like make everybody,
you know, handcuff them when they come to the park.
No. Like you know what I'm saying?
Like that's, that's literally what some scared does like this whole capture thing.
Like I'm so glad that we're sort of slowly getting rid of it.
Like pasy
scare me because they are so much better. But at the same time,
if you don't have a compute device,
like if Google, like there's a difference between pas
keys being an additional option
and being a mandatory thing and if they're a mandatory thing,
you're going to lock out a ton of people.
-- I mean, that's a discussion for another day then
-- on
in unsupported account scenarios, which is free services,
we will probably discuss that eventually.
So anyway, I'm, I'm, I'm cutting us off. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. Go to open
our security podcast.com. Head up the show. Not two Z pound do says podcast.
Hashtag Find us on social media. Well, I ma
it on Really,
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks
-- everybody.
Thanks, everyone. Bye bye.