Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Curtsy Fried and my partner in hiding that unsubscribed button.
-- Josh Pressers,
-- do we have an unsubscribe button?
I think we barely have a subscribe button.
I would assume it's done through the apps like Spotify and stuff,
but they don't actually make it hard to get rid of podcasts.
But I've noticed increasingly in email that the unsubscribed
link is like dark gray on black or,
you know,
it says like click here to change your email preferences or you know what I mean?
-- Like,
-- yeah,
you know what I started doing in those instances is I just click the spam button
and that takes care of it.
So, all right, before we start ranting about the terrible experience
subscribing from junk mail, why don't you explain the topic of the day?
It's about literal dark patterns.
So here's the unfortunate thing is companies have
realized there's a lot of things you can do
that are,
are not illegal but they're,
they don't, you know, they're not very nice or they're kind of,
yeah, they're,
-- they're questionable. This
-- is not new mind you.
-- No,
-- this is not new but this is now,
it's kind of like social media where now they're
hiring people to explicitly come up with this stuff.
Well, a great example is GDPR, right.
GDPR got released and I was like, oh my God, this is going to make things better.
And this guy I know who actually used to work for a European regulator.
He's like, no, I'm like, what do you mean? He's like,
is Facebook or Google worried about this? And I'm like, well, not really.
And he's like, yeah, so it's not going to work.
So let's, I wanna,
I wanna explain what the dark pattern is a little better
first because this is probably not something everyone's familiar with.
So
the concept here
is
obviously humans have to interact with everything, right?
Be it a a website to buy things, be it
an app, whatever, right?
And we all have those experiences where let's say an ad appears
and when you click the close button,
it actually opens the website for the ad because, oh,
it wasn't a close button after all,
it was something the ad put on the ad to trick you into thinking you could close it,
right?
That is called a dark pattern.
The idea being this is something that its sole
-- purpose is to deceive for some reason to
-- deceive,
to trick, to manipulate,
to make it more difficult. So
like a classic dark pattern is gym memberships easy to
-- sign up for trying to unsubscribe is good
-- luck.
It's usually easier to just get a new credit card than it is to cancel the
gym membership. Right. Exactly.
And the reason we're talking about this is in the United States,
the Federal Trade Commission, the FTC put out a,
like a request for comment on dark patterns and they're going
to have kind of like a mini conference about dark patterns.
I fear that this is going to become a how to,
for the industry as opposed to let's try and make things better.
-- I don't
-- think they need a, how to, I think they're pretty good at what they're doing.
I mean, but anyway,
this kind of piqued our interest because obviously this is one of those
things that just feels like it's more and more annoying than ever.
And I'm pleased that regulators are looking at it.
There's like a real cost like these are essentially attacks that are, are,
it's an attempt to monetize people in almost all cases. Yeah, and,
-- or manipulate them to do something that can be monetized. I mean,
-- right.
That's, that's basically the idea.
I mean, like a great example is right now when you go to purchase a Humble bundle,
which I love humble bundles and they just had a
Lego humble bundle I bought about a week ago.
And the idea is you pay some reasonable amount of money,
you get this big bundle of games, some money goes to charity.
But now what they're doing is they're automatically trying to get you
to buy their monthly subscription by when you click buy bundle.
It's also automatically adding that to my cart and then I have to take that out.
Didn't that happen to, to the donations for Trump where you made a donation to Trump?
-- And it signed you up for a monthly?
-- Yes,
-- I remember that.
-- You know, and these people are going bankrupt or something.
I don't know.
-- I'll cry river
-- over that one. Yeah.
No, I've, I've seen even businesses that I respect doing that.
So there's a local science museum.
I'm not going to name because I actually do like them. But
they have, when you buy something from them now they have this like donation screen
and there's no option for zero,
there's an option to write in an amount and if you write in zero,
it says invalid amount.
So
you, if you buy something from them, you literally have to donate like a dollar.
That's low.
You know, it's, and it's just like I love this science museum and I love this place.
My kids love it. But man, whoever made that decision that, uh,
like shame on you?
Ok. Ok. So anyway, anyway, let's, let's get ourselves back on track for a minute.
Now is I like this topic because
there's the specific instances of dark patterns
which I'm sure everyone has a million examples
of because we've all been hosed by this more than once in the past,
but then there's just kind of this idea of and, and you're going to laugh at me.
But before reading what the F DC wrote about this,
I never really put it into my head that this sort of deception
is something that regulators should really look at and do something about it.
II, I guess just coming from the, like the, the internet universe,
I just assumed this is how it works and like that's wrong.
Well, I mean, we, we have long standing ideas and
laws in most countries around advertising a product
and that you can only say truthful things about
it,
right? Because
the problem is otherwise you end up with literal snake oil salesmen.
No, literally, I mean, that's all this came to be like, and please don't do this.
But you know,
the people that have made money telling other people
to drink bleach to avoid or cure their COVID.
And so this isn't like, oh, you know, ha ha ha funny or even, oh, you know, damn it,
somebody lost a bunch of money.
Like we're talking,
people
have historically been willing to do things that
will kill other people for a few dollars.
That's
right.
And so, well,
the reality is we clearly do need laws and regulation around this because,
-- well, it's a problem.
-- Well, look, this is, I mean, this is a great example of
the,
the virtual world lagging behind the physical world because this
was a huge problem for a long time in,
in meet space.
-- And so one of the, one of the,
-- in
the meat space.
Yeah.
No, literally, I mean, we can get to, no,
I'm not talking about meat packing plants at the turn of the century because it's no,
it's just read, read Slaughterhouse Five.
-- It's horrible. Yeah.
-- Or you know what my favorite is.
So the book The Jungle, which Upton Sinclair wrote is like his socialist manifesto.
Sorry, that was the one I was thinking of. Yeah,
-- that one.
-- So I did not know this until I happened to accidentally read it.
And then I verified this. The Jungle is like a 250 page book. Ish 300 pages.
Give or take.
13 pages are dedicated to the slaughterhouses and
that's all anyone talks about from that book.
So think about that.
I, I remember I read it once and I'm like, this is horrifying.
But anyway, OK, the, the thing I always think of in, in,
in regards to this and the reason it's top of mind is because
is anyone who listens to the podcast knows about a year ago?
Give or take?
I acquired an iphone because I was furious with Google for only
giving three years of support on their Android wasn't a nexus.
I forget what the model was. Anyway. Right. Switched to iphone.
I ordered a bunch of stuff from Apple and they
sent me two of everything none of the iphones unfortunately.
But like the cases and chargers and stuff. Right. So
I ordered two, I got four of them. So I've got all these extra charges and cases
and I'm like,
I don't legally have to send these back because what happened was companies
used to send people stuff and then send them bills for the stuff.
Right.
And the government was like, no, if you send someone something they didn't ask for,
-- they get to keep
-- it.
-- It was unsolicited stuff.
-- Right. Right. Exactly.
I contact Apple because I'm like, I'm going to do the right thing and I basically,
I get a hold of someone.
I'm like, this is what you did.
They're like, oh, we'll check into that and get back to you in a couple of days,
a couple of days.
I'm,
hey, what's up? Nothing. I'm like, you know what? It's mine.
Now, I give up like you've lost your right to claim any and honestly,
it would probably cost them more to get that stuff back than it was worth.
-- But,
-- like, I once had a similar experience, I, I bought a really nice, uh,
saw Blade at Home Depot.
It was like an $80 saw blade.
I get home and I, I start, you know, to cut it open and there's actually,
it's two saw blades in two packages, like, kind of
long together
because it's like one of those plastic clamshell packs that kind of snap together.
For ship, I guess because they, like, you can fit a dozen of these in like,
two inches anyway.
And I'm like, well cool, you know, but I don't need two saw blades. I only paid for one.
And so, yeah, I took the one saw blade back and the lady at the returns desk was
just so confused and I ended up basically just
leaving it on the desk and walking away.
I've done that more than once and I've never,
I don't know if I've done it at Home Depot, but I brought stuff back to like, oh,
I kind of accidentally stole this, you know, here you go.
And they're like, oh, well, thank you. And they just go put it back.
What's fascinating to me about Doug Patters is part of the challenges
is
if you do dark patterns, you know,
you can increase your revenue rate by like 0.1 of a percent by being a real dirt bag.
I assume it has a positive effect on revenue because I
have a suspicion you wouldn't see so many people doing it.
A perfect example. Here Dell selling pre built systems has a 10
dollar a month hidden warranty on their systems.
Essentially the way it works is you get the first
month of warranty free and then you pay for it.
And that is the default selection.
You have to find this hidden thing and like uncheck it and,
and turn it off to get rid of it.
But you, like, you have to know that this exists and go looking for it
and, you know, and there's, I think it's on Linus Tech tips and uh, oh man,
what's the guy with the long hair, his name?
Um, he, he does, hw. News.
I have no idea. They, they, they showed the web page for this and it's,
I probably would have missed it.
Like, if I was buying a prebuilt from Dell,
not that I ever would because that's the thing, right, that $10 a month for one year,
that's 100 like when I bought my used car,
they tried to sell me on a warranty package and
additional theft insurance and I'm like the warranty package.
No, like, because I know you're going to screw me on the warranty
and the theft package, I'm like, hang on. Like I have car insurance.
Like, I'm, I'm legally obligated to have car insurance.
So like what he's like, oh, well, you know,
normal car insurance only pays you the value of your car, not what you paid for it.
And I'm like, yeah, cars depreciate. I, I know that they suck.
And he's like, yeah, so this car theft insurance will, you know, if your car,
you pay $10,000 for it and it's worth $5000 when it gets stolen,
it'll top you off the other $5000.
And I'm like, no, like
cars, do you know how often cars get stolen and not recovered here.
-- I bet
-- it's pretty low these days.
It's pretty damn rare. Like cars get stolen.
Absolutely.
But they get recovered because most car thefts here are honestly,
they steal trucks to then go steal trailers
and other equipment that they can actually resell
because the problem with stealing a car
is it's got like a VIN number and stuff. You can't just
sell it to somebody for, you know,
um, there's a great vice news thing where they show these, uh,
chop shops in California where they basically rebuild the car
using, uh, a chassis from, you know, like a,
like a, a junked car with a clean, like legal chassis
and they basically strip the chassis and put all of the stolen car in the chassis
and they do this like overnight. It was insane.
But you also need a car worth something like my car is
worthless.
No
one's going to steal. In fact, I don't lock the doors just so no one breaks the window.
Like, if you want to root around in my car, great. Like go for it.
Don't break my window.
-- The window would cost more than the car
-- by definition of buying a used car.
It's probably not worth stealing.
-- Yeah,
-- exactly. Exactly.
So,
but I mean, this is an example where they pushed it really hard and I was just like,
no man.
And I, I wish I actually, in hindsight,
I wish I'd walked out of there because it turned out the car needed new brakes.
-- Oh, right. I remember you told this
-- story. 1500 bucks, Canadian and new brakes.
So, yeah, that's
right.
Honestly, go auto
shame on them. Like they, they're just,
they're no, they're scam artists.
-- That's just
-- used cars, man. It's, it's rough buying used cars.
Well, and that's the thing. Right. It's becoming.
So I checked Google a bit and it's funny because
basically everybody agrees and even when I went to,
uh, get my brakes done,
the lady's like, oh, yeah.
You know, like you just got this car and I'm like, yeah, and she's like, oh,
where did you get it from?
She's, I'm like the goal
in the west and she's like, oh, yeah, that one's terrible.
Like, we've had a lot of complaints about it.
I mean, used cars have,
I should say used car salesmen have a long history of ripping people off.
Right.
So, anyway, let's, I don't want, I don't want to start complaining about cards.
-- Well,
-- and now, unfortunately though
the software industry and the, and the worst,
the services industry is learning about this
and,
and they're executing on it because you know what it works,
it makes money.
Exactly.
I mean,
you know what I was reminded of when I started reading
about all this is in the Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy.
I forget which book it is.
It's the Cricket Wars book,
but they're in the Hall of Illusion Hall of Information Illusions.
I think they call it in the book.
And one of the things is they, the,
the like announcer keeps trying to get you to accidentally
agree to buy merchandise from them as part of their like,
infomercial thing that you're, you're paying attention to,
to learn about the cricket wars.
And
that was written what in like the seventies or eighties?
Probably like this is so not new.
I mean, I love how technology, you know,
now cruise ships and Disneyland you get that RF
ID bracelet that can just auto pay for everything,
hooked up your credit card, bing bing
and you end up spending a couple 100 bucks a day that you didn't mean to.
-- I mean, I,
-- ok, look, I,
that is potentially a dark pattern but that one I feel
less bad for because you should know what you're doing.
At least this isn't like they're not tricking you.
But that argument can be made with virtually every dark patter.
I was buying a used car. I should know I was going to get ripped off.
No, we, no, we should have openness and honesty and transparency.
I, I feel like that's different. I'm talking about
the context of like you go to buy a computer from Dell and
you don't click the opt me out of your crappy monthly insurance.
You know what I mean?
Like that feels different than here's a bracelet that has magic money on it.
Good luck.
We know for a fact that people spend more money when they're not, like,
spending physical cash and it's electronic and they're not aware of it.
I mean, let me put it this way. I,
my, my current credit card, every time I spend money on my credit card I get an email.
That's interesting.
Like, and usually within a few seconds which, and then when I pay my credit card bill,
it takes like 3 to 4 days.
But, hey, whatever, that's like, of course
it does. That's another example of, kind of not a dark
but of an abuse of like, why does it anyways?
And so I'm a lot more aware of the money I'm
spending because I get this email instantly to my phone saying,
and it's
pretty well.
And part of it too is like,
I'll order stuff online and sometimes it'll clear immediately.
Sometimes it'll clear when it ships. Sometimes,
you know, with a, with a service, it'll clear a day or two before the service occurs.
Whatever, it's interesting to see,
kind of how these companies do it. Right.
Right. Right.
I, I think part of the challenge with dark patterns is, is they've,
they've gone to that
space of, well, it's not illegal. Maybe you should have known about it.
Like you should have known to inspect source and go and look for this hidden option.
Speaking of hitchhiker's guide to the galaxy, you know,
we we did file plans for the uh the bypass
that we were going to build through your house,
you know, and it's like they were at the,
you know,
filing cabinet at
the bottom of the stairs with a wine saying beware of the leopard
in the dark, you know,
in 3 ft of water or whatever. Right?
-- And it's a
-- little tangent is I was talking
to someone the other day about this exact thing
and I looked at, I looked it up. You can buy beware of leopard signs,
which
-- amuses me to no end.
-- You can legally own a leopard in the US,
right? In the US. You can legally own wild animals.
-- You can't do that in Canada,
-- in certain places. I believe where I live, I could own one
but I don't want to,
-- it would take care of your squirrel problem
-- maybe. Or
it could take care of my being a live problem too
that solves both problems.
-- Then I guess
-- then I don't have to worry
about squirrels anymore because a leopard ate me.
-- Yeah,
-- a leopard ate your face.
Yeah. So, I mean, that's, you know, at what point?
Like I buy stuff on Amazon now and especially electronics.
-- It tries to offer me extended warranties.
-- Yeah. They're getting kind of weaselly.
I agree with that.
I was buying something that costs like $9 and
it tried to offer me an extended warranty.
That's so embarrassing
whenever somebody tries to Upsell me on an electronics warranty,
especially for something like a laptop.
I'm like,
oh,
so you're saying this thing tends to fail after the 90 day manufacturer warranty.
And they're like, I'm like, so you're saying that this thing is so unreliable,
I need to buy an extended warranty.
And they're like, I'm like, wow, it really sounds, I shouldn't buy this.
Well, like, which is it?
-- Right. Either I need the warranty or I don't,
-- we know you don't.
And I think even like consumer reports in the United
-- States has said multiple times don't buy those terrible
-- warranties.
That is something like 90% of profit in
electronic stores now is their extended warranty sales.
And, you know, again, as much as I hate on large companies,
sometimes Costco one year we don't care.
Just give us most of the thing back and here's your money.
-- Yeah, they're
-- really solid and, well, in fact,
just bought, I don't, I don't remember if I said this on the podcast yet.
I bought an Apple TV because Amazon Fire TV
has updated their interface and they added like a bunch of ads and I
was just super angry and I thought I'm going to buy an Apple TV.
And I bought it at Costco for the simple reason, I knew if it didn't work,
I could just bring back like the pile of stuff in a paper bag and they'd take it
and it did work and I absolutely love it because there's no ads anywhere.
-- And
-- then a week later they announced the new one.
Uh, it was about a month. I don't care.
Well, no, here's, here's what's wild about that actually. And this is again
where, like, as much as I love to hate on Apple sometimes,
like they get some of this stuff.
Right. So they announce a new Apple TV.
The new one has obviously big, slightly better chip more.
You can buy a bigger one with more storage, which I don't care, like,
never going to use the storage anyway.
But here's the thing is the remote on the Apple TV. Kind of sucks.
So they have a new remote,
but I can buy a, I can buy a new remote, which I,
I ordered one to just to see if I like it because I have two of them now.
So I'll buy the second one if I want, but they upgraded the
I OS or whatever runs on Apple TV.
And all of the features they talked about in the new one are working on the old one.
Like what? Who does that
well? And that's the thing, right. Apple, apple, apple, apple does that.
Right. Right.
But here's the thing is I feel like I'm so trapped in this ecosystem
of customer hostility when I find a company that doesn't treat me like,
like a freaking piece of cattle, you know, traveling down the conveyor belt.
-- I don't know what to do
-- I think. And this is one thing I like about Apple.
Apple is very upfront and honest about, we're going to charge you a lot of money
upfront and
you're probably gonna pay us a lot of money on a monthly basis for things like,
you know, maybe a bit of extra icloud storage,
uh apps.
Um You, you know, you,
you want some nice headphones,
like I went through a couple of sets of Bluetooth headphones and then it was just like
I give up and I bought the Apple
ones and they're so much better the experience, right? They just work,
buy a new ipad, got to buy a new Apple pencil because why not?
That's because the,
the old one is incompatible with the new ipad and vice versa because screw you.
Ok. Uh I, I don't, I don't care for that but,
but I mean, overall,
you know, yeah,
my phone will work and get security and software updates for 5 to 7 years.
And so ironically, I'll,
I'll spend a lot less because I'll use these ipads and iphones for
-- probably a good five years
-- probably.
And you know what I just realized too,
like both of my Apple purchases have been like rage fueled
anti
customers
reasons where it was first.
Google murdered my Nexus phone, which I was out of, out of hate. I ordered an iphone
and now Amazon ruined the fire TV. And so out of hate. I,
-- yeah, the interface.
-- It's so bad.
The
look on my kid's face when they saw the new interface. I'm like, yeah, that's the,
yeah.
And the best part is you can only have, what is it,
five or six things on there and then you have to, like, go to the more items, menu.
-- They,
-- they're apps. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. It's, it's super,
it's horrible. Anyway,
doesn't matter. Don't care. Not my problem.
Yeah.
So,
no, these dark patterns, I feel like it's, it's like loot boxes, you know,
loot boxes were well.
-- Oh, hey, you know, definitely
-- not gambling.
Yeah, definitely not gambling.
But man, rats love pulling that lever for, you know, nondeterministic rewards.
Right?
And
yeah,
my,
my kids have spent hundreds of dollars on loot boxes and
I kind of have the opinion of it's your money.
I'm not going to tell you how to spend it, but you're definitely wasting it.
Well, I mean, the same could be said about a lot of things like candy
anyway anyway. Ok. Ok. So we,
-- we've rambled on for the better part of 20 minutes now.
-- So here's a question.
How do we solve dark patterns?
Cause so there is an actual dark patterns website with sort of a name and shame.
So here's something really interesting is I will put a link in the show notes.
So one of the things the FTC did that's really wild is they have a comment system
where people can submit comments.
Now,
the vast majority of comments are exactly what you
would expect in comments to a government website.
Also, their interface is beyond terrible, but
they're trying,
I found one that was really interesting that I
will link to in the show notes where this
person pointed out the fact that kind of the
the web and app ecosystem we exist in today
would could be compared to like
building stuff before building codes existed
where it's just like whatever random garbage
people decide to do they do
and it could be unsafe, it could be dangerous. It could be stupid.
-- And I mean, some is good,
-- sorry side topic.
This guy made an early app for the early iphone because
it had like the accelerometer and gyroscope sensors and stuff.
And the app was essentially you got scored for, if you threw your air,
you threw your iphone up in the air and it, like, recorded how long it was in the air for
and,
and you get like the high score for that and then Apple ended up banning it because,
you know, people of course,
are throwing their iphones up in the air and they're getting smashed.
And then there was another iphone app that I thought was brilliant.
-- It was the $999 iphone.
-- Oh,
-- I remember that one.
-- Yeah,
-- that was brilliant.
-- Right. And that guy made a good chunk of money off that.
I don't know how much he made I would be surprised
that a
good chunk of money.
-- It's not like that app took a long time to develop.
-- It was just a picture.
It probably took 10 minutes to make.
-- But, but anyway,
-- now should stuff like that be illegal or should it be like, oh,
you know, you should know what you're doing when you throw your phone up in the air.
No, I mean,
we probably shouldn't encourage people to throw their phone up in the air.
I agree with that. I, I feel like there are definite lines you could draw
and encouraging people to throw their phone in the air.
It's kind of like one of those. Oh, I'm special.
I'll catch it until you don't and then it's broke and,
and it's just a bad user experience because then people are going to blame Apple.
Well, why'd you let this app in your store if you knew it would break my phone?
There's a definite element of, yeah, Apple had their hand in this,
I
mean, right.
So anyway, anyway, back to your question about kind of what do we do about this?
And I'm always hesitant to say that like regulation is the answer.
We'll just engineer around it.
-- But
-- I think there's certain,
there's certain places where regulation is appropriate.
I'm not saying we don't regulate.
-- I'm just saying if we do regulate, they'll engineer around it
-- and they will,
and it's a constant game of cat and mouse.
Right. Where there's always going to be people who try to abuse the regulations.
But I think the thing is the legitimate real companies are going to
make enough of an effort. We'll say to not engineer around this in weaselly ways.
Right.
I don't know.
In past I would have sort of agreed but seeing like what Dell did, it's like, man,
that is super.
Oh, right.
I'll,
I'll tell my story that Kurt wouldn't let me tell
him earlier because he insisted it was show content.
So I, I ordered a new laptop for work. It, it's time for the new one.
Right?
And I ordered a thinkpad because think pads can run Linux and I, I get like whatever,
a bunch of ra M and all that, you know.
So it's a little customized. It's not just like the off the rack think pad
and
I get the email and the ship date is June 1st of 2024. Now we are recording this in
May of 2021
that well, and I'm like, ok, this is clearly a placeholder. They don't know right
after about a week they update it to October 31st 2021 which is what,
like five months away from now, I think
so. It's the video card. Hey,
I don't know.
But the point is like, obviously it's hilarious because when it was ordered,
there was no like, oh, by the way, this isn't shipping for four years.
Well, and even if they don't take your money, that's just ridiculous because,
I mean, if you're ordering a nuclear reactor, you know,
Westinghouse or G is going to be like, yeah, that's, that's,
you know, it's not going out the door on Monday, it's gonna take a while,
but this is not a nuclear reactor.
-- This is a consumer laptop and,
-- and now at the same time,
I don't know if they charge the, the corporate credit card.
I don't care either, obviously. But like
this is, I mean, this is another great example of, we don't know.
And this is shipping. Good luck.
You know what I wonder because we had that
experience where I was on the show before where we
bought a couch and they didn't ship it and because
we had the ship date that they blew through,
we, I was very easily able to do a charge back.
So I'm wondering what if I open up an online store and sell stuff
and give a
future ship date years out in advance.
And then my business becomes,
I buy the thing used in three years on ebay for
like pennies on the dollar and ship it to you.
I'm pretty sure that's fraud.
No, because what if I sell it to you? And I say, look, it's not shipping till 2024.
I mean,
I don't know. I feel like that's wrong.
I, I would agree because,
but then the question becomes, how do you, how do you cancel it or do a charge back?
Because
you know, is the, is the credit card company going to be sane and be like, yeah,
that a ship date of 2024 is stupid.
So no,
I mean, because in my minor defense but October of this year,
that's
no like this is not some custom gaming rig with massive amounts of, you know,
you're not asking for a custom milled water block or something.
It's like, I want a laptop that you had on your website that
-- you're supposed to be selling thousands of these
-- maybe
and more to the point,
-- it's clearly not in stock and they should have said
-- so maybe.
I mean, I'm also getting a bunch of ram shoved in it so I don't know which it is.
It's clearly not in stock if it's going to take a minimum of six months to get to you.
And, you know, here's so, here's the other thing though,
Kurt is when this was ordered.
Like,
maybe it said that, I don't know.
You know what I mean? Like, I don't care, there's so
much
on these things. Right. I mean, every time I buy something there's tons of
stuff and it's like, I'm not going to read all this.
Right. Right. Exactly.
And again, like, I don't really care if it was,
if it was a personal purchase I would have obviously been like, no,
this is not acceptable and I would have probably just canceled the order.
But,
like, in my case, I'm like, yeah, whatever it's for work. It doesn't matter.
One of my frustrations too is this is one reason I'm
more likely to buy stuff with Amazon because of Amazon Prime.
But what I've noticed again, speaking of dark patterns,
there's Amazon Prime. Amazon prime one day and Amazon Prime shipping,
which means I get the free shipping from some schmuck.
Lord knows where
and it's going to take weeks or months to arrive.
Now in Fairness,
Amazon will show me the expected ship date before
I actually like commit to paying for it,
but they don't show the expected ship date early in the process. So quite often,
what I find happens now is, you know, I try to buy something online.
I look at the ship date and I'm like
that is how many weeks from now or how many months from now? No.
So you know what I've done more than once and I mean,
you could blame myself for this maybe,
but I've ordered things from Amazon and then I'm like, where did my thing?
Where's my thing? It hasn't come yet.
And then I look and it's like, oh crap, the ship date is like in two months
and then usually I cancel it, everything's fine.
And I order one that can actually ship, you know, tomorrow,
but we exist in this world where we
are bombarded by information from every possible direction.
There is no way you can expect humans
to reasonably deal with kind of just everything.
You know what I mean?
There's so many easy ways to either omit something or slip something in, like, oh,
by the way there's, you know.
Yeah, on page 27 of the EU L A you didn't read.
Yeah, it explicitly states
in three point font,
-- you know. Yeah,
-- it's, I mean, I don't know, I feel like I am glad
the government is at least starting to talk about this.
I don't expect anything drastic to change for the foreseeable future, maybe ever.
But I think just the fact that
this now that I've read about this more,
I'm seeing it in my brain and I feel like this is how it starts.
-- Here's
-- a thought. So we have ad blockers for your web browser.
Should we have something?
Because a lot of these dark patterns are pretty like they
don't change a lot like they hide the subscribe button or?
Oh, perfect example.
We, we're,
we're shopping for a new password manager at the CS A and we're trying one out
and
you can only export your data through the desktop app.
You can't export your data from through the
website interface or from the browser plug in.
-- I mean,
-- that doesn't surprise me.
The desktop app is basically useless.
It for example, cannot import data unless it's in one specific format.
Whereas if you want to import data, you have to go through the web interface
and we actually made the decision that if we do go with this vendor,
we absolutely will be actively avoiding the desktop app
for all our users because it's so bad.
I mean, every desktop app
-- sucks, like look at slack. But
-- this is an example, you know, like what is it?
I'm just looking at the types of dark pants here.
This is, I believe it's the roach motel. Right.
-- Like you can get your data in but you can't get your data out.
-- I mean, that,
-- that's a lot of SASS vendors.
-- Right. Right.
And like, they want you to come in but if you want to leave, no way.
That's not hotel California.
Yeah. So
this has become,
it's sort of like spam, it's become so normal.
We don't really think of it as that much of a problem. But
what I'm noticing is now that I'm paying attention to,
where's the unsubscribe button? Where is the thing to kind of find out?
How much does this actually cost with shipping? And well, simple question.
When I buy something online, I want to know two things. Really.
How much in total, not how much is it, but how much with tax and shipping
and
when's it going to get here? Right. And I don't need like, minutes or hours.
But I mean, like, I need a rough estimate or days or at least weeks
because,
like, I've ordered stuff that will take 2 to 3 months to get here and that's ok.
-- Sometimes
-- as long as you understand it and you're expecting it, I think that's fine.
Well, and they're upfront about it. Right.
Because I get some things have a long lead time.
I had this with, I ordered some appliances and there was a certain,
there was a certain, I don't know what you call, like the coating on the outside.
It was like the
the it's not the color whatever, but like my wife wanted a certain look to the,
the appliances and it was basically we have to build these for you.
-- So it's going to take a month. We're like,
-- ok,
the first ever couch I bought went to sofa land or sofa world or something like that
sat like late I sat on this, you know,
found this really nice couch and it was just long enough for me to lie down and nap on,
right.
So like, I'm like, I love this couch.
I'm like, ok, how much to get one of these, you know, the price is reasonable.
I'm like, cool.
Like how does it order when you know how, how do you guys drop it off at my house?
She's like, well, you know,
first we have to order it from the factory in Italy and I'm like, whoa stop time out.
I'm like, how long is this gonna take?
And she's like 4 to 6 months and I'm like,
is this floor model for sale right now about the floor model?
Because I'm like, I'm not,
I am not waiting 4 to 6 months for a couch.
-- I mean, that does it, it would like
-- I needed something to sit on now.
Exactly. Exactly.
Ok. Ok.
We're, we're out of time, I guess here's, here's the, the bit I would end this on.
It's just,
I'm glad the conversation is starting.
Go to the show notes. Look at this stuff, leave comments,
get educated.
And I think this is,
I it makes me sad that I hadn't
-- realized any of this before now.
-- It's insidious.
It is like seeing the thing Facebook is doing with the new privacy controls on I OS,
right?
How Facebook is like this will kill freedom so you should accept it.
Yeah.
No, it's, this is the new normal and it's I,
I think part of it is people have to be aware so that,
you know,
it just reminds me of all the people the first
time they see the internet running without ads and like,
what the heck is that?
And I'm like, this is the adblock. You want it on your browser.
They're like, yes, I do. Exactly.
Hey, browser plug in authors, you know,
if you could maybe write a browser plug in that
warns people of dark patterns on a web page.
That would be pretty awesome.
It, it would be, it sounds hard. So good luck.
I'm ending it. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening. Go to open
source security podcast.com. Hit up all those show notes, use the Pound
Os S podcast. Hashtag Do hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
Thanks everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.