Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast.
I'm Kurt Siefried and with me is Josh Bresser.
Hey, Kurt, how are you doing?
I am doing good.
All right, man.
The topic on everyone's mind this week. Open SSL. Let's do it.
-- Yeah. So do you want to lead us off?
-- All right. Yeah,
this is,
this is such a crazy story.
So let's start here. What is open SSL? How, how, how do we define that in,
in say what's, what's the tweet we could use to explain what open SSL is to people.
-- Open
-- SSL is the thing that does the magic crypto
-- and
-- uh
stressing the
world
-- nobody understands crypto. There's like 10 people on the planet
-- if we're lucky.
Yeah. And they probably all work for the NSA.
So yeah,
open SSL is a cryptographic library which is a fancy
way of saying it's a big pile of building blocks
that you can use to build something that, you know,
given like a secure web session will as a server,
be able to talk to the client or as a client will be able to talk to the server.
Uh And so,
yeah,
it's basically this pile of building blocks that
will do pretty much whatever you want.
And then the challenge is, you know,
making it behave and do things correctly can be a bit of fun.
Well, and I, I think there's two really important things that
maybe not everybody knows about.
This is number one open S SS L is about 100 years old now.
It's a
very old piece of software. I bet it's, man, it's got to be at least 20. I mean, really,
it's II, I can't think of how when it came to be.
But anyway, so open SSL is very old but also
it powers a nontrivial amount of the internet
which makes it a very,
we'll say high profile piece of software that,
that many others don't necessarily have.
Right.
Yeah.
Well, I mean, just by virtue, it's, it's like a lot of libraries. It was the first
decent one with, you know, a good license in this case,
-- the Apache license decent
-- very loosely here.
-- Well,
-- you know,
it's like a lot of like there's a lot of these libraries that honestly, you know,
somebody wrote them to scratch,
uh somebody wrote this library to scratch their own itch and then, you know,
a couple of people piled on because it helped them.
And then unfortunately at some point
everybody was using it and, you know, and of course, being open source,
it's not like we know that until it happens,
-- you know,
-- it sort of sneaks
up also
in the case of open SSL. This is a great example of 20 years of adding
and very little removing.
All right. So anyway,
I,
I guess here's where we stand now and here's what makes
it so interesting is last week on the 22nd of September,
there is a security update to open SSL
and the security update fixed a couple of issues. Nothing was very exciting.
One of them did have a logo.
It was not super exciting issue once again
proving that having a logo does not mean anything
as to the quality of your issue.
But the,
the point is they released an update and it was done in the typical embargoed manner,
which will we get to embargoes in a minute
and then they, they released their update and then not
four days later,
they released another update
because it turned out that the patch the first time around
actually added a new security flaw and a much worse security flaw
than the one they had just fixed,
which that also happens from time to time when you're fixing security issues.
But let's let's back it up and start at
embargo doesn't mean anything to everybody.
So why don't you tell us what is an embargo? Kurt?
Well, so generally speaking,
an embargo is the idea where you keep a security vulnerability private
until you are ready to fully release a fix.
Uh And actually what an embargo is means different things to different people. But
fundamentally, the idea is you want to reduce
the gap between bad guys knowing about the flaw
and the good guys having access to an update that
they can use to prevent exploitation of the flaw.
And to be honest, it's,
it's something that's become a bit of a bad habit in the security industry.
Um,
I think part of it is because back in the day we used
to not have as many flaws as we do now to deal with.
And we, we generally tended to embargo everything.
You know,
I remember those days man,
-- even
-- trivial things like cross site scripting vulnerabilities, you know,
only one or two of those now.
Yeah.
And so, so the challenge with an embargo is that well, by definition,
you're trying to restrict who knows about the vulnerability.
Uh And this can also vary like sometimes the embargo will be
any mention of the issue at all. Sometimes the embargo will be
just the specific technical details. Uh
Sometimes the embargo will be,
you know, just the exploit code, right?
So and
-- so,
-- but hang on, hang on
open SSL is an open source project.
How can an open source project possibly keep anything secret?
Well, see, and there's the problem is generally speaking,
open source projects are not
built for secrecy and privacy of the code.
I mean, the whole point is to be open source and
you know, let people collaborate.
So the problem with an embargo becomes,
how do you do your job building open source software
without doing it the open source way. And so essentially, what usually happens
is people have to
abandon all the workflow and all the tool chain
that they currently use.
And essentially nine times out of 10, they end up emailing patches around,
but developers then build on their local workstation to see if it works or
not and then maybe try and test it locally on their workstation and,
you know, if it doesn't catch fire, then it's probably ok to ship.
So it sounds like you're telling me that because of an embargo, a
project might not get quite the testing. It would normally have
as a regular update and could maybe introduce a much, much,
much worse security flaw with their security update.
Yeah.
And I think part of the challenge too is,
is when you are dealing with a security vulnerability.
Uh people, you know, people, when they're dealing with problems,
they tend to tunnel vision,
right?
And this seems to happen sometimes where people, you know,
tunnel vision on the vulnerability they're trying to fix
and, you know, they,
they end up doing something that actually makes things worse or just as bad.
Uh Like if you look at the CV database,
there's over 200 vulnerabilities that essentially have the text,
uh you know, an incomplete fix for,
you know, where they've tried to patch something and then a day or a week later,
come back to it.
-- And whoops,
-- I'm skeptical
that it's only 200.
However,
I, I think there's, there's kind of two things that number one,
not fixing something
correctly.
Incomplete fix. Right? Is not what happened in this instance with open SSL.
Well, it's a generic text they use.
Would they, I wonder if they're gonna use it in this case, if it's,
I don't know.
That's a good question.
Um But anyway, regardless, this is not an incomplete fix,
this was a brand new problem that got found and funny enough, it got found because
they released their update.
And then some researchers started doing testing that I imagine
they would do in any normal situation and had they had access to this software
beforehand, they, they could have done it then.
So
I think if we look at this one singular instance, it sounds like embargoes are bad
and we don't want them.
Well, embargoes definitely, you,
you're basically trading a variety of risks uh off against each other.
You know,
there is definitely a risk that bad guys, you know,
find out about a vulnerability and use it to exploit users.
On the other hand, there's also a risk that, you know,
you write a software patch that introduces
an even worse vulnerability, you know, and
the challenge is we don't really have any
data to make good decisions about these risks.
So we tend to go with our gut
which, in our case, nine times out of 10 means we go with, you know,
historical trends, which is embargo everything.
Sure. Sure. So when you said
we trade risk, I had a vision of the uh risk trading market,
which sounds hilarious to me in all the wrong ways. But,
ok, so, so that's a really good point I think is
it is easy for us to want to embargo everything. And additionally,
I don't think there's a researcher out there
who doesn't want to think whatever they found,
whatever they're doing isn't the most important security issue in the
history of security issues, right? And so
I'm sure these researchers love embargo their stuff and let's face it.
When you're a researcher,
you can also request an embargo and say here's something I found,
I want it embargoed.
And so that, I mean, what's the challenger? How do we, what do we do here?
How do we step back and look at
something like an embargo, especially in the open source universe,
kind of with the, the, the we'll say
the, the glasses of sensibility on.
Yeah.
Well, to me, it's one of the fundamental questions is why are we embargo this issue?
Are we embargo this issue because it actually presents a high degree of risk to,
you know, end users and maybe the internet as a whole
or are we embargo this issue because we want it to be kind of cool
uh or in some cases, you know, uh, especially with some commercial vendors,
they want embargoed issues because it
lets them take a long time to fix things without, you know,
kind of being caught out as doing that.
What if I give my issue a logo,
-- then it should totally get an embargo.
-- Right.
Well, exactly, because you need time to get the designer to do the logo.
You need time to think of the,
yeah,
exactly. That's right. That's right.
You know, that, that, that's a good point actually is,
I wonder
if you're getting AAA logo for your security issue?
How much information do you want to give your designer so they
can design you an appropriate logo for an embargoed security issue.
That's,
it will be hilarious.
When
did that, that happened though?
-- Wasn't there a logo issue that, that some, like third party pr firm ended up
-- leaking
the, yeah, the company had hired APR firm to handle the,
the disclosure of this issue on their end.
And, yeah,
the pr firm leaked it. I think it was like half an hour, an hour early,
you know,
and it would just sort of prove the whole thing is largely a bit of a farcical,
uh just sort of proves the whole thing is a bit of a farcical circus
sometimes.
Yeah. So, so back to embargoes,
the, the real problem is, you know, open source projects,
spend a lot of time building process and infrastructure and, you know,
getting the right people involved
so that they can build good software and build good patches and test them and,
you know, and then release stuff that works really well,
you know, and, and 99 times out of 100 that's what happens and it works great.
So, yeah, I mean, obviously if you,
if you force them to essentially give up all
that stuff that they've worked so hard to create,
you know, by embargo the issue and you know,
them having them email patches around and build it locally.
Well, it's hard to do the, the quality work that they're used to doing.
Yeah, I mean, that, that's a really good point. And I think it's also worth noting
embargo. I mean, regardless of open source or not embargoes are
very expensive
in terms of sanity
because it's a lot of work to get all this stuff, right?
And just in terms of resources because now instead of shooting
a quick email or picking up the phone and again,
a quick call,
you might need to GP G encrypt something or make
sure you're talking about something using certain words or make
sure that only this developer can see this patch or
only this Q A person can see this bug.
And so it's, it's very difficult dealing with this though.
I mean, I remember when I used to do them all the time, it was,
oh, it was such a nightmare. But at the same time back in the day,
I never thought twice about embargo something. It's just kind of what we did
and, and in hindsight,
I won't say they, they should never happen, but they should be very sparing, like,
less than 10 a year.
Right.
Yeah,
I think also one of the, it's, you know, it's like the goalkeeper's dilemma. Right.
When a goalkeeper in soccer takes a penalty shot,
they have to be seen to be doing something, right.
So they dive to the side even though statistically they're,
they're way better off standing in the middle,
you know, and
instead of picking one side and diving, but the problem is, you know,
if you're not seen to be doing something and, you know, you know,
you're not taking it seriously, we didn't keep it secret, we didn't embargo it.
You know, people may complain
and 11 annoyance I have is on the flip side by embargo everything.
You're also reducing customers ability to protect themselves.
Uh, because let's face it.
A lot of these embargoed issues are not as secret as we would like. Quite often.
They were known,
you know, uh by some bad guys, you know, it turns out
or,
uh, the reality is for a lot of these places,
they're gonna take so long to patch anyways.
I mean, very few places are gonna,
you know, open SSL ships, an update and, you know,
five minutes later people have deployed the update,
right, which I suspect is what makes in this case, this issue,
even though it was very critical
in the kind of grand scheme of things in reality,
it's probably not a big deal because I would
be surprised if hardly anyone has deployed that code
in production yet.
Yeah.
I mean, it's gonna take at least a few hours or days for even an agile organization.
Well, no, you know, even like some sort of mythical agile organization
and the reality is especially something like openness ell. Right? If you,
if you update
Open SSL and there's a problem, like, you have a big problem,
it's on your network
and, and I would say that any reasonable,
I guess, even if you say bleeding edge DEV
ops agile, pick whatever word you want to use,
I would hope that Open SSL isn't one of those things.
You're, you're constantly upgrading
to stay current. Right?
Once you have a version that basically works, you're never going to touch it.
Yeah.
I mean, the reality is Open SSL by and large is a very nice, boring,
stable piece of software that works,
you know?
And, and, I mean, yeah, they do introduce new features which we definitely do need,
like, you know, when they, uh, like, say TLS 1.3
you know, we're gonna definitely wanna upgrade
Open SSL to get TLS 1.3 or, or TLS 2.0 or whatever comes down the road,
1.3 should be out very soon.
It's,
it's, I, I feel like
the, the draft is nearly complete but don't, don't quote me on that.
It's been a while since I've looked at it.
Yeah.
So, I mean, that, that is a good case for people to upgrade.
But even then, you know, it's gonna take a minimum of a few days or weeks because,
you know,
uh,
not all your clients are also running open SSL. Right.
We've also got good new tlsnss and then of course, there's a whole host of, you know,
closed source libraries which God only knows what they're doing with TLS 1.3.
Right. Right.
Well, and I think another interesting thing that people don't always realize is
in the case of open SSL, they recently broke the API.
So if you're using an old version,
you can't just like dump the new one in place when TLS 13 comes out,
you have to actually rearchitect your software
to be able to use the newer version, which I mean, that's,
that's not a small feat for most people.
I mean, especially given this is an extremely difficult API,
well, you're also assuming they still have the source code and,
or they still have the developers with the expertise to, you know, to fix this thing,
right?
Like
I've, I've seen more than a few places where,
you know, they have like one or two,
uh where they have one or two devs who
originally wrote it and everybody else is new and,
you know, works on the front end because the back end is boring and stable.
And, uh, yeah, so, yeah, definitely an A B I or API change in open SSL is,
is a very big deal and,
and quite frankly, personally, I kind of,
I kind of like it in a way because hopefully it kills off some of this old software.
Right, because the reality is if software is old enough
that you can't,
like, use a newer version of open SSL,
you know, it might be time for that software to die.
I totally agree with that.
That I, I never really thought of that angle before, but that makes a ton of sense
because,
yeah, there's, oh, man, there's some garbage out there.
Oh, well.
And, and,
but what's worse though is by definition pretty
much anything using the openness of celebrity.
It's probably talking to the network either as a server or a client.
That is the sad truth, isn't it?
Now, I, I wanna bring up one other thing is there is a
news article I saw
the other day about all of this kind of crazy going on
and they said that
the reason this happened to open SSL was sloppy programming.
What do you think of that?
I,
well, it's, it's easy to accuse people of sloppy programming, you know,
like an off by one,
you know? Oh, you should have, you know, paid more attention.
I, the reality is crypto.
Well, the reality is software in general is hard,
especially with a low level language like C or C++, right?
Like you have to do all kinds of crazy memory management.
Whatever, man, I love that.
Yeah, this is,
this is why I generally won't use anything less high level
than Python or Bash because I'm not smart enough to do.
Don't use Bash. Bash is never the solution no matter what your problem is.
It's not a high level language. It's crazy.
Don't use bash.
Kids don't use Bash.
You probably
don't let friends use Bash Curt. That's, that's the way we got to look at that.
Yeah.
But I mean, the reality is I've been in this industry for 20 years,
I've assigned 5000 CV S and I know for a
fact I am not smart enough to do memory management like
almost nobody is. And so,
you know, these tools like C and C++,
even if you're paying attention and even if you know what you're doing,
it's still easy to make a mistake.
And then especially with crypto
code. I mean, crypto
code,
you know, that's, you're taking some pretty complicated mathematical concepts
and
you have to break them down completely for the computer to understand.
I mean, in this case, you can put that problem aside
it, it wasn't crypto
code. That was the issue,
let's face it, it was, it was a memory management mistake. And see,
I mean, and
as you pointed out that that's more common than anyone would ever like to admit,
especially with
kind of some of the best in the world. And this is
so I kind of have two things to say about.
This is number one, it wasn't sloppy, it was just bugs happen, right? It is like
the real issue was the embargo prevented proper testing,
right?
And that's easy enough to understand. But then secondly, is the fact that
open SSL has some of the better developers in the world working on it.
If these guys can't get it right? Every time, which let's face it, they can't.
And that's no secret.
Is there any hope for a normal programmer to not make security mistakes?
I would say as an absolutely not. I mean, and my perfect, my favorite example
is CV 2016 0 triple seven, which is,
I don't know if you remember it's the open SSH bug with the uh key disclosure stuff.
And that was
in code that was not only not active and not used,
it wasn't documented, it was in the config like it was in the dot C dot H config files,
but it wasn't even in the man page, right?
And so, you know, by any notion of normal software hygiene, right?
You remove dead code or unused code, right? You just don't keep stuff around,
you know, you, you, you delete it, you get rid of it
because it's probably gonna cause a problem at some point which, well as it,
we found out it did
and I remember when that flaw came out, it was so funny. Right?
Because I,
I remember gripping the source code for
whatever the configuration directive was and OK,
I see it in the dots here.
The dot H file. I forget which,
but it's not the man page. Oh, ok. That's weird.
So then I was like, well, I wonder if there's anything else.
So I took, I pulled up the man page
in one terminal and I pulled up the, you know, the, the source code and
that defines all the options. And I, I went through,
uh, and like,
made sure every single one matched up that there wasn't something in
the man page that wasn't in the source code and vice versa.
And luckily, you know,
and then I also emailed, you know, the devs to say, did, did we have,
we made absolutely certain there's no more hidden
surprises in here and they were like,
yeah, we've done that.
So that was good.
But,
you know, how many other software programs haven't done that little, you know,
these kind of spring cleaning tasks.
I would be surprised if more than 10%
have done it.
And I think that is optimistic.
Yeah, I would agree
because when you look at, you know, some of these like, uh, I mean,
something like send mail or Apache, you know,
the number of configuration directives and bits of code it supports
versus what's actually in the code base.
I mean, matching that all up would take dozens if not hundreds of hours.
All right. So number one,
I think it is safe to say send mail is mostly dead at this point,
which pleases me because as an ex recovering
send mail
cis
man,
it is not the most pleasant thing in the world. But the real problem Send Mill had is
you had to write all of the configuration in something called M four,
which was a macro language and M four I believe is turn complete.
So
you have a mail system whose configuration files are essentially, you know,
self aware.
And that's terrifying.
I mean, how do you, how do you possibly not screw that up?
Well, you know, I remember because I,
I actually at one point had to write a custom send mail to facts, Gateway and,
you know, I, I had to go out and buy the bat book,
which if anybody remembers was the 900 page send mail book.
You could kill a person with that book. It was
a weapon.
-- I
-- remember, I think it was the thickest o'reilly book.
-- Like for pretty much ever, I can't think
-- of any other
wide, right?
Yeah.
And, and I remember, you know, just,
and I got the thing working and that was it.
And I, I literally told the client that like if you touch this mail system in any way,
shape or form
the warranty is void. I will not.
Yeah, it's like, and, you know, and then luckily at some point they went to, like,
a phone based, you know, phone company based fax solution.
Thank God.
But, um, yeah, no, like, and that's the thing, right. These, these are
large, complicated, capable, powerful pieces of software, you know,
openness sl is, it's not the Swiss army knife of encryption software.
It's like the, you know, it's the nuclear warhead of encryption software.
Right.
No, no, that's not accurate either. It's the Swiss army nuclear warhead.
It
can explode but it also has a spoon.
Yeah.
You know, you need to encrypt a disc.
It'll do it, you need to talk to an encrypted network.
It'll do it, you need to handle certificates, it'll do it, you know, it'll,
it'll do literally
every crypt operation
you can think of
including, uh, nearly ruined the internet.
Right. With her.
Yeah. So,
yeah. No, it's tough. I mean, I, I think
the reality is, I think what would help a lot is if we only, honestly,
if we only used embargoes when we needed to use embargoes, right.
The majority of the sort of low and moderate stuff, you know.
Yeah, it poses a risk to people, but
quite often too, a lot of these issues you can put in compensating controls,
you know, you can firewall for them or you can,
you know, you use rate limiting or, you know, whatever there's,
there's usually things you can do to minimize the risk.
Uh, and in general these are things you should probably be doing because regardless
of what you do there's, there's always gonna be flaws in your software.
It's true. It's true. Yeah. I mean, that's fair.
That funny enough I keep seeing with microservices and containers and dev
ops and just kind of
the way the universe is starting to look,
we're going back to that old UNIX model of do one thing and do it well.
Yeah.
Oh, yeah. No, I, I actually really like it
but the challenge is, you know, instead of piping
one output from one program to another over a command line,
we're now doing it over networks that are software to find networks that are
running. God knows where.
Yeah.
And
on the flip side,
that's actually really cool because it gives us
really well defined boundaries between pieces of software,
you know,
and if your interface is a
json,
you know, rest api
it's really,
you can actually filter what's going through that,
you know, to a relatively,
you know, there, there's a,
actually a pretty restricted character set and to
test whether or not the input is well formed
is actually doable, you know, versus something like a binary protocol where,
yeah, good luck with that.
No, I really,
I like this idea because it gives us well defined boundaries and you can,
-- there are you know, web based firewalls that can handle this stuff already
-- today.
Well, I mean, regardless of that is,
I wonder if there are any Jason firewalls that exist today.
I, I've never looked for this.
The latest mod security which runs on Apache is and
X
uh can call in, I forget which
JSON library, but you can,
you can filter
json and you can filter it.
Like you can say things like only allow an array called customer or do
not allow an array called customer or do not allow a data name of SSN
-- or
-- don't allow 64 gigabytes of
JSON data to pass
through this
firewall.
So it's actually, it, it can parse the
JSON data
and you know, filter on content, filter on
types and all that.
Um So in theory,
you could write like a white list for what your application should be accepting and
in theory that would prevent a lot of problems long term.
And heck you're probably going to find a ton of bugs because you know,
somebody's gonna do something dumb at some point.
Wow, that's fantastic. All right. So let's sum it up open
SSL good or bad.
-- It's a great piece of software.
-- In my
opinion, I would say it's great, but it's good.
It's,
it
runs the
-- what
-- choice do we have?
We have no choice.
It's,
it's,
it's the encryption library we deserve not the one
-- we need right
-- much like everything we have.
Oh, my goodness. That's so true.
All right.
So, and I guess at the same time for those of you out there don't give these guys too,
too much flack for this because
it, it, it's an honest mistake. Anyone can make it. It's hard to do software.
And if you've never released, you know, in an internet,
driving gigantic piece of C code,
I suggest you start such a project and see how it works out at the end.
I would challenge most people to even read the Man page.
Ah
No,
no.
Well, open us.
It has about 100 man pages because every one of those
esoteric commands it chips with has its own man page.
It's oh man. Just my head starting to hurt thinking about it. I
I'm done.
But no. Anyway.
All right, Kurt. Well, this has been a treat as always
until next time, folks. Thank you.
01 other thing though,
one other thing before we go is we have a proper website
set up now where you can go for the show notes and,
and whatnot.
There's uh open source security podcast.com
and this episode will obviously be there along with all of our other episodes
and any of the links we might mention any of the interesting tidbits.
If you're wondering where to find it, we'll post a link there.
So I guess, hey, thanks for listening, everybody. Until next time.
-- All
-- right. Thank you. Stay shiny.
-- Stay
-- shiny. I like curry.