Hello and welcome to episode 26 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime, Josh Pressers.
Kurt.
This is the greatest week of the, well, maybe the first or second,
greatest week of the year.
Are you familiar what's going on right now as we speak?
Uh
You mean the snow outside?
No, it's actually raining here. It snowed.
So funny, it snowed last night and then I went and shoveled and now it's raining.
So I'm actually glad I shoveled before it rained because
I'm sure uh rain soaked snow is no doubt,
very, very light.
But no,
right now there's a thing called awesome games done Quick Happening,
which is a speed running marathon for video games.
And these guys are like video game ninjas when you watch them play.
But the relevance to us being a security podcast
is the fact that most of these speed runs
these guys hack the games.
And the reason they can get these insane times is they
find out what the exploits are in these video games.
They, they exercise them
and then they end up being able to beat a game and, you know,
maybe five minutes instead of the four hours, it would take a normal human being to do
and it is amazing to watch. But I thought it would be really cool to talk about it today
just because this is an example where people can actually
see hacking in action versus something we just talk about.
So to clarify, I'm assuming, uh, because I've seen speed runs before and,
uh, so these are speed runs where they're allowed to essentially
uh manipulate the game in any way that they can use sort of the normal controls.
Like I'm assuming they're not allowed to like, use a hex editor
by the binary or something.
So they don't modify the game and generally speaking, they,
they play the games on the original system, however.
Right. Right. So the original system changes things quite a lot, obviously.
Yes, that's, I was assuming this was an emulator thing.
Emulators
are legally questionable
and so
they use real systems and, and they quite often play them on C RT S as well.
They don't use,
you know, L CDT vs,
you
have to otherwise the games look wrong.
Uh
Yeah, sure. We'll say that.
And in fact, there was one of the guys when I,
when I was watching was complaining about that the C RT is different than his L CDT vs.
So he was struggling with one of the game. But, but anyway,
so there, there's various rules and some runs are what they call glitch
less
where obviously you're dealing with.
I won't say
100% skilled because they still,
some games have like randomness and they've learned how
to manipulate the random number generator inside of it.
Or
they might have found,
you know, some bizarre way to play the game and like, like some insane ninja
but
-- essentially
-- some combination of power up items.
Right?
But, but when you say glitch list, that's kind of like, like no hacking,
we'll say is what glitch
really means.
-- And those are
-- like the pac Man thing where you can't like,
-- I think you what you get to the end and then the buffer overflows and you
-- can write
like level 255 right?
And then you, and that, I mean,
that's a great example of kind of one of the things that happens here.
And so,
II, I guess the, the reason I wanted to bring this up is, is again, like I said,
this is something you watch these guys play.
And apart from the awe of amazing video game players,
this is an example where you can see
real hacking, right?
Is these guys do something and they will manipulate the game in a strange way.
And it's actually really funny to listen to
them sometimes because coming from a security background is
they'll talk about doing something where they'll get like so many of an item
and it's like, that's an integer overflow. Right.
That's what I'm thinking and, you know, they have their own lingo for it all or,
or they'll do something that's clearly a buffer overflow.
Or they're, you know, they're, they're relying on an out of bounds reader,
right to do something.
And it's,
it's hilarious because
they're doing the things we talk about and
we understand and we defend against except it's,
it's a video game and, and a lot of them don't really understand what's happening.
They just learned if they do this particular sequence of actions,
you know, they can jump over that wall or go through that building or something.
And it's, it's hilarious man. It's crazy.
Well, I remember when I was younger playing uh oh boy,
this goes back what are called door games on B BS S for those
of you that don't remember this B BS S were bulletin board systems.
So the idea was you would dial into a computer
and then you could like download files or upload files or
play games on the computer, right? And some of these games were multiplayer.
And I remember this one, it was like a space Empire game.
It
was,
there was some weird logic in essentially the items
pricing.
And so basically the deal was as you,
it wasn't linear pricing,
it was like algorithm like logarithmic pricing or something stupid.
So essentially if you could pick an item and essentially get a monopoly on the item
um by just creating like
millions of these things.
You could like essentially corner the market on
it even if it wasn't a very important item
and then you could sell it back, like to the game, not to other players,
but like to the game,
you could sell it back and just, and get huge amounts of money, right.
So I would basically pick some random item that nobody cares about
and, and like turn my whole economy into producing that one item. Right?
And then I would be super weak, super weak, super weak for like,
you know, the 1st 90% of the game, which would take weeks
and then all of a sudden I would sell all these items overnight and like,
15 minutes later by like the biggest army possible and then
just go on a rampage and people actually got basically banned,
right? Because it's not fun the way I play it, right.
Because I would just do nothing for a couple of
weeks and then just rampage and win the game,
you know.
So, yeah, there's a lot of these things where you can just, uh,
exploit game logic or whatever.
It, it's completely crazy
and it's awesome.
Yeah, I know. Well, if you want to win, it's awesome.
If you, if you're looking for game play ability, it's like, you know,
it always reminds me of people when, when you play risk with friends
and if you're playing for fun, it's fun.
But if you're playing for fun, but one person is playing to win.
It just, it's a horrible game,
-- dude.
-- You never play risk for fun, right? You play to win
and because you hate your friends, those are the only two reasons.
Well, not only that, I mean, there are even examples of board games.
I'm, I'm trying to think of one off the top of my head
where
the rules can be broken
and if you, if you play it correctly,
you can essentially cause the game to kind of self destruct on itself.
Well, and that's one thing I like is, you know,
the better games like these sort of newer Cooper
games where essentially everybody wins or everybody loses type deal.
You know,
I
do to kind of avoid that,
-- that you can still hate your friends though. Trust me.
-- Well,
-- you
-- can still
throw
monkey
wrench
-- for this
-- but uh no back to the video games. Yeah, I mean, so that's interesting.
So you're saying that these people are essentially,
there's the glitching speed runs where it's what
I think of as a traditional speed run.
Like you just
like Super Mario being a great example, right?
You learn the pathing of the work pipes and which are the easy levels
for an expert player to like get through as quick as possible.
So if these speed runners man, if, if they can do the but you know,
even so you say this but even on the Super Mario Brothers speed run.
They've found a glitch. They use
to essentially get themselves to the end faster.
And, and what it is is it comes in handy on,
I, I think 41 is probably the biggest level, but they also use it in the last castle is
essentially what happens is the way Super Mario Brothers works is
you have like various,
I think they call them zones
where essentially like when there's a, there's gonna be uh like,
let's say on level 4-2
there's the little bean stalk that'll bring you up
to the warp zone to go to level eight.
Well,
if you can get to the pipe after the beanstalk and jump
in it before it loads whatever the zone is for the pipe,
you can go in,
you actually end up where the beal
brings you instead because
they've essentially,
you know, abused the mechanics of the game to get themselves to do something faster.
And in fact, this is how
there's something called the minus world in Super Mario Brothers.
And this is how you get to the minus world essentially is
you go into the warp zone area before it loads the warp zone
zone if that makes sense, which it doesn't.
And then by going down the pipe, the game like has no freaking clue what to do.
And so the world minus one
is essentially just like random memory that it turns into a world.
And that's why there's no end because you go in the
pipe and the games like I don't know what to do.
Go back to the beginning
which yeah, it's crazy. In fact, there is a youtube video I found that goes into
great detail explaining exactly why this happens
in Super Mario Brothers, which is that,
that is a weird way of loading the levels like it doesn't pause or something.
It just,
-- that's weird.
-- But you got to remember too, man. This is what like 1982?
It's
amazing
when you look at Super Mario, right?
Uh The original Super Mario, bros if memory serves was
like seven people,
like seven programs,
artists and developers.
-- I mean,
-- it's crazy to think about.
Yeah, like it, it and, and now a AAA title is like
a
gazillion people.
Seriously, it's completely crazy how many people it takes to make a video game now.
But well, not only that these game, the Super Mario Brothers is what? Like like
-- 10-K of code. I mean, it's
-- crazy.
Yeah, they did all sorts of tricks to like the, the, the what is it?
The clouds and the blocks are the same bit map, just
-- the
-- clouds and the bushes are the same.
And well, not only that the,
the sound of getting the,
I think it's the one up mushroom
is the same sound as when you get the end goal posts just sped up like 200 times.
So they, they obviously abuse reuse significantly.
In fact, there's, there's an Atari 2600 game.
It's uh yars' revenge. I think it is
where all the sound effects in the game is just they,
they found random areas in memory that made cool sounds.
And so that's what they played because they right,
they didn't have room for sound effects.
So they just played random memory locations that happened to sound like something.
It's a solution.
It's crazy, man. I mean, it's amazing.
But, but I guess this is part of it too is you look at
the way the world of computing used to work,
the whole Y2K thing. Well, it was a simpler time, right. They shortcuts were taken.
You didn't always do things because it was the right way. You do
something because it got the job done.
Well, this is one thing people often forget. Right. If you,
if you take a risk and ship now, but take some sort of risk that might hurt you later,
it doesn't, you know, at least you ship.
Whereas if you don't take that risk and you don't ship, you're,
you're definitely up the creek.
Right.
Yes. You know, that's the reality of it
that, I mean, yeah, that's, that's exactly right. And obviously
that's how a lot of these games end up in this situation that they're in where
there are problems found, they know there's bugs
and they don't care. And in so in the old games,
no one no one gives a r, right.
Because look, you can make Mario jump through a wall and nobody really cares.
No one gets hurt. And now you have an awesome bug
that the speed runners are going to do crazy things with.
But games today are becoming a huge industry
and there's some, there's certain parallels with the,
the whole just world of it and, and computer security here I think is
you, look, now there's games where you use real money to buy things inside the game.
Right.
And so
-- Facebook game industry.
-- Right.
-- Right. Right.
-- Let's face it. Right. I
mean, and if you can cheat at those games
now there's real money at stake.
It's not just doing something cool with the character in the game.
It's the fact that the company that made the game doesn't get all of
their money because players can get something for free that they aren't supposed to
-- or rip other characters
-- off. But, yeah, that, I mean, that,
-- what was
-- it? Oh, yeah. The world of war thing, uh, arm tr,
I don't know what armor trimming is.
So, the idea was the armor things look stupid.
And so people would offer to trim armor and
the idea was that you would drop your armor,
they would pick it up, they would trim the armor and they would give it back to you.
Guess what happens?
Like
it's like, it's like my wallet cleaning service. Right.
-- You give me your wallet and I'll, I'll clean your wallet.
-- How do you fall for this?
This is obviously a scam.
I often wonder that. How do people fall for these things?
And, well, you know, like, what is it? The PT Barnum? You know, there's one born,
maybe, maybe, man.
Oh my. That's,
that's completely crazy.
But, uh, so, and then, so you mentioned, so these glitching speed runs. So they,
I'm assuming that there's like, uh, some website or something where they trade or,
you know, kind of like a Wikipedia for these glitch.
There's these crazy communities actually where
these people work together to try to
understand what does a glitch mean and what can you do with it?
And
it's, it's surreal to read about some of this stuff and what they do.
I mean, like, so one of my favorite actually is
if you've ever played the original Legend of Zelda,
there is the, the graveyard
where there's these ghosts
that wander around, right?
And
now as you can imagine on these old games,
they had a static number of sprites that could be on the screen.
And obviously, they basically had a set array of sprites.
And
every time you touch a tombstone, another ghost appears, right?
Well,
basically you touch the tombstone enough times you get enough ghost on the screen
and now you filled up the number of available sprites that can be displayed
and the game is smart enough to not let you generate any more ghosts, right?
But you can play the whistle which makes a little uh tornado appear
and the game isn't smart enough to not show
the tornado or delete one of the other characters.
And so you end up essentially having an out of bounds, right?
A buffer overflow in this case,
and then you can cause execution to jump anywhere you want.
And so these guys have figured out how to essentially, you know,
set up the game prior to doing this.
So when the override happens,
you overwrite the right bit of memory that then jumps the game to the end credits,
which is considered
beating the game by the speed running rules, right?
So essentially, you know,
these guys have turned a buffer overflow into a game winning strategy.
So now it takes, you know, like seven minutes instead of two hours to beat the game,
which is, which is crazy.
Yeah, I remember the graveyard level. I really did not like that level.
It's not even the,
even the level you just have to walk around
screen or whatever you want to call it.
That was man, I
love that game
actually.
So funny enough,
the Zelda games are some of the most breakable games that they play probably because
they are, they're very complex games.
I mean, there's a lot of interlocking items and abilities and you know, they,
they were for their time like I remember
I got Nintendo thumb playing that damn thing.
-- Um You know, I had the dimple on my left thumb.
-- There you go. Awesome.
That
metro,
the
metro. So, actually funny enough you say Metroid
and at the end of the event, at
the end of a GDQ, which is the winter one, there's also a summer one called SGDQ.
Summer games done quick versus awesome games, done quick. Right.
They're all awesome though. I assure you.
So at the end
they play Metroid, Super Metroid
and
it's quite often a race where they'll have in, in this instance there's,
I think that today this week on, I think it's Sunday, maybe.
I think it's Sunday night or Saturday night. I forget which
there's gonna be four people
essentially racing through Super Metroid and in this case they're doing what's
called 100% where they're going to collect every single item and it,
it takes a while.
It's gonna take like, I, I think an hour or two
to complete
power up and every,
yeah, but they still do all these like crazy glitches and stuff where they,
they make jumps, you shouldn't be able to make and they,
they go around things and they, they do,
they, they,
there's all these bugs with Super Metroid for whatever
reason in the way the input works off the controller
and so they can like, you know how,
I don't know if you ever played Super Metroid but you can like,
build up speed and you get your super run boost thing.
I forget what it's even called.
But
so these guys have found a way you can tap
the run button in a certain frames on the screen
and
they can start running in like a third of the distance that you, right?
So you can obviously like,
it's amazing how broken these games can become when you like throw all the rules away
and this, but again, I'm gonna bring this back to security now is like,
this is how security works, right?
When the bad guys throw all the rules away,
the good guys,
what do you do?
Cause you, you couldn't even imagine a world where someone could do this.
And this is kind of like
when you can make Samus run in a third of the distance, normally,
the programmers and game designers never assumed that was possible.
And so the game becomes incredibly broken
when you uncover this, which is again, just like kind of hacking in the real world.
Well, yeah,
I remember when you know the first cross site
scripting vulnerabilities came out and everybody was like,
oh that's, you know,
that's not so bad.
But oh wait, you know, online banking is a thing now that is kind of bad.
And you know,
now we have this endemic problem of cross site
scripting vulnerabilities in all software all the time everywhere.
You
know, you know, the other thing I'm always reminded of is
uh double free,
which
I if you're a AC programmer, you obviously have to male
your memory and make sure you check those returns.
And then
when you're done with it, you free it.
And there's a common security issue called double
free where you free the memory once and you
still have the pointer to the memory that is now freed and you free it again.
And GC uh GGCCG LIB C these days has some protections built in that.
Basically, if you try to double free, it figures out, hey, I've already freed. This
don't do that. Bad. Things can happen.
And I mean, I remember when double free was found, everyone was like, yeah.
Wow, what a silly bug don't do that.
And then solar designer one day figured out, you know, hey,
if I do some trickery here, I can essentially set up a fake memory structure.
So when it gets freed the wrong time now
we're overwriting whatever we want wherever we want in memory
and all of a sudden it's like, oh, crap, double free is a really big deal.
Yeah.
Well, it's like a lot of these things, you know, initially when these bugs come out,
it's like, oh, that's bad.
You can trigger a crash for sure, which, you know, it is not good.
But yeah, and then somebody figures out how to weaponize it easily.
Um, like my favorite was, um,
I forget which Microsoft vulnerability it was, but it was a one bite,
overflow,
one bite
and that was enough. Somebody weaponized it.
Oh, man, there have been so many instances.
I mean, I, I think Tavis just did this, what,
maybe a year or two ago where there was a one bite overflow in something and no one,
everyone's like, hey, it's only one bite.
What can you do with that?
It's like, well, you can do a lot guys and I think it was a null bite even so it was, it
didn't even look that bad.
But,
and that's the thing, right is if you give a smart person enough time,
they're gonna figure something out.
It, it's like even the,
the Chris Evans issues that were just found in which
in fact are video game related because it's those video game
uh sound file players. Right. Right.
And so, well, here's the really crazy thing about this and, and this is, you know,
since we're talking about video games, I'm quite happy to go,
go into this because I love it.
So these sound files are, they're not like audio files that contain audio, right?
They are essentially instruction code for the sound processor in this hardware.
And so
you, you basically,
it sets up an emulated chip and then it runs the instructions
through and makes the noise that is expected to be made.
And
I mean, essentially what Chris did
is he figured out that, hey, this emulator sucks.
And if I basically write a sound file that,
that it will let me write memory to anywhere I want in the address space.
Of course,
that's the easy part because then he had to figure out where to write certain things.
And he ended up overwriting the free call, you know, back to free
to, instead of freeing memory running the system cis call, which then lets you run,
you know, executables.
And it's like this is the craziest exploit ever.
But again, you know, you let a smart person do crazy things and,
and they're gonna surprise you
and
it's, it's amazing and, and well,
what always gets me is just how complicated these systems have become, you know,
like you take something
air quote simple like,
yeah, like playing a sound file or opening an email,
I mean opening an email nowadays, you know,
you can have multimedia attachments,
you have it going out to the internet to download images, you have,
you know, you have any number of stuff going on
and you know, it's, it's gotten
so complex.
It, it boggles my mind, you know, like especially when I look at web browsers now,
like the fact that
for example, Chrome,
they have an extension so it can talk to USB
so it can do UTF authentication using USB hardware tokens.
And when I first heard like, you know, web browser talking to USB,
I immediately was just like, no, no that bad idea, really bad idea.
And then
when I heard the use case, it's like
is you and I
are broken
because we are security people and security people are always broken and
I love
taking a walk or something with my wife and I'll point out things and she's like, why,
why would you even think that
where it's about, you know, doors or signs or,
or things that they have in certain places that just aren't right or, you know,
you could, someone could, you know, take advantage of this thing over here,
this window, whatever.
And
when a normal person thinks of USB in a web browser,
they think that sounds neat because now I can
do all this cool stuff with my USB devices.
You and I see that we think how can we abuse USB to make the browser do terrible things.
Yeah, exactly.
You know, I'm thinking ransomware on removable USB storage, like the time machine,
hard drive and my Mac.
Uh, you don't,
you shouldn't you be using like some remote Wi Fi Deo
for time machine? Don't you have one of those? Do they still make that weird
-- thing?
-- The capsule thing?
No, I don't, I don't like those because they're,
they're just not fast enough because the problem I
have is all the V MS on my machine change
and then it like, wants to back up a 40 gig file.
I
can, you
know,
this crap up,
but I want it back.
Well, that's fair.
-- That's the whole
-- point of
this
time.
I want a backup of my complete system
because, you know, then if, well, for example,
I actually did break my laptop once during an up, uh, a Mac Os update.
So, all I had to do was hold down. What was it? Command control?
Uh, what is it,
whatever the button is to do a R for recovery with the hard drive plugged in.
It's like, do you want to recover your hard drive and you click? Yes.
And then you go away for an hour and then come back and your computer's working.
That's pretty cool.
Yeah.
Um but yeah, no, so I'm, you know, yeah, like, yeah, you and I,
when we look at something like that, it's like
not, oh, what a cool feat. And, and in fairness, the use case of having
native
like UTF authentication
through in your web browser is
really good because like let's face it, right?
One of the biggest problems with web
browser security is people typing their passwords in
when it's not the site that it should be, right?
Like a great example being the John
Podesta Democratic National Convention email hack,
right? That's these,
this is a real problem that is massively
exploited through phishing emails and spear phishing emails and
all that other stuff. So,
you know, having UTF authentic, for example, you know,
if every Gmail user had one of these and used it
in theory, basically, you know, bam, no more gmail hacks,
right?
-- You know, via
-- password
it would, it would definitely make a difference.
Yeah.
And so
in this case, I think that the benefit will definitely outweigh the cost
until somebody finds like a ransomware hack and like every single chrome,
you know, running on a machine with a connected USB hard drive all of a sudden,
you know,
encrypts that hard drive and we all got to go pay
like 50 bucks or 100 bucks to get our data back.
Maybe,
maybe
I
hope it never happens. I really do because I use Chrome and I mean,
it looks like other browsers are going to be doing this.
So we don't really have a choice in the matter.
-- I
-- know Firefox and Chrome both support U two F and
I mean, I have one because at one point github
was selling them for like five bucks.
And so I bought a couple of them
and this was before
the UBK four came out which does
like regular UB key stuff plus U two F on one.
at five, I don't even know what they call them but, but the little devices
and,
but now at the same time,
there have been
phone based authentication options for gmail for a really long time.
-- And
-- yeah, but they're a pain to use.
You have to type stuff in, you have to know how to use it.
This is a little thing and you just touch it.
Yeah,
but if people can't be troubled to take out their
phone and type in a number like once a month.
Why are they going to
do?
There's a lot of people who use public computers, for example,
which
you shouldn't do.
Listeners, do not use public computers.
All right, you are a bad person if you're checking your email. But people
who don't have the money for their own computer,
you know, there's ii,
I know some people that work for the government and work with lower
income people and literally these people don't have a computer or a smartphone
and they, they, they use the, you know,
there's computers at these government offices
for public use for checking your email and stuff and they have to because, you know,
they want to get jobs and
in the modern world, how do you get a job?
-- You get it by email in that
-- instance is somebody giving them
U two F keys because if you're not giving them away,
they're not going to buy one.
No.
Um,
but I'm just pointing out that there are a lot
of people that use public computers still and have to.
Ok, that's fair. I think if you have to use one,
you can do that.
But there's nothing that makes me sadder than when I'm in the lobby of the Marriott.
And I see a guy in a suit using that computer and I just wanna like,
run up to him and grab him and shake him and be like, why are you doing this to yourself?
Don't you know what that thing is going to do?
Yeah. And, uh,
you know, in fact, I remember one time I walked past the, the computer in the lobby
and there was a USB drive sticking out of it and I'm like,
someone's gonna take that and they're gonna plug it into their computer and,
like, oh, my goodness. I should take it and throw it away.
I didn't, because I didn't want to touch it. But you get the idea.
Yeah. Could be Coton Strick name.
Right.
Well, no, I'll be accused of stealing trade secrets from some company or something,
you know.
-- So,
-- yeah.
-- Anyway.
-- Yeah. No, it's, um, so, you know, and that's the thing, right?
There's always these tradeoffs when we make the, uh, security decisions and,
you know, realistically, you know,
like I said, you know, password stealing attacks, that's a big,
big current problem that's, you know, it's endemic, right?
Like it's,
and the only way to make it go away is to sort of,
you know, have two factor authentication.
Really. That's, that's the only way to solve it.
But now at the same time though, like the attack that was
leveraged against Podesta,
you could still do that sort of attack
with two factor authentication. Maybe not. You two f could be trickier.
-- But,
-- I mean, well, you could still do a man in the middle attack and have,
but you wouldn't have continued access to their,
not even just man in the, you don't need continued access depending upon your goals,
but it's, it's not really man in the, it sort of,
it sort of isn't right where you bring someone to a fake site,
they type in authentication credentials.
And then you essentially take all that data
log into the real site and then ferry information back
to them to make it look like everything is fine.
But
and then obviously, you have some access for a limited amount of time.
You're right, you couldn't log in a second time,
but it would give you certain advantages. This is actually where
and this is one area, for example,
where I really like what Apple has done with their two factor authentication.
You told me about this,
like I love this because um
it not only like,
so basically the way Apple does their two factor authentication is you,
you can register a phone or whatever,
but essentially it sends a request to another one of your devices.
So for example, like when I was setting this up,
I set it up on my phone and then I started setting it up on my laptop
and you know, so my Apple is like, oh, you know,
somebody's trying to like log into your account.
Um
So they send an alert to my phone. And
the best part is it showed a little map saying
somebody's trying to log into your account from you know,
Edmonton Alberta with a little picture of it.
Now,
Edmonton Alberta is where I live. So, like, obviously. Cool. That's awesome.
That's me.
But, you know,
if I get one of these alerts in future and it's
like some dude's trying to log into your account from China,
I'm going to be like, oh, like time to panic.
That would be a great time to panic.
And it made it so much.
Yeah. Exactly. And so it made it just so obvious, you know, it's, it's just
because the reality is if somebody hacks me statistically,
they're probably not in Edmonton.
Right. They're probably in like Russia or China Lord knows where or they're,
you know,
and having said that now they're going to be smart enough to buy, you know,
-- to buy VPN access through a provider in Edmonton or
-- just find an IOT device with an
IP address
and then,
but, you know,
at least it's a really good start because it's a very simple
piece of information for me to consume and it's very intuitive.
Right. Like I, people tend to know where they are usually,
you know, they've been drinking heavily,
um,
you know,
or they're so jet lagged like me once I was in Ireland
and I thought I was in an Irish bar at home.
That's impressive.
They all look the same.
You.
Jet lag
is
a
combination
of jet lag and Guinness.
But the bathroom in the hall to the bathroom looked exactly like one at home.
But anyways,
um, you know, and then I have to type in a six digit code. Right.
It shows me a six digit code on my laptop or my
ipad or whatever that I then have to type into my phone.
See that.
So that makes it the bar
there, I guess the barriers to entry there is really high. Which is fantastic.
Well, and it's very easy to use.
And again, like I said, it's, it's really intuitive because I, I,
you know, it makes life, it, it adds a significant step for the attacker.
You know, they now have to
kind of figure out where you are and then log in from a machine at that location,
you know,
-- do they enable this functionality by default or is this something
-- you
had when I turned on two fa that's what I got.
I was like, because I was at first, I'm like,
why is this thing showing me a map of where I am followed by?
Oh, that's cool.
You know, like
as far as I can tell, there are no settings I can change. It's just on or off,
you know. Well, and Google does a similar thing, right?
When you are not able two factor authentication on your Google account
and you enable, you know, device specific passwords,
which I love because then I can, you know, have my Thunderbird or whatever, you know,
log in all the time.
Um
But for example, if I go to a significantly different network,
like I log in from China or something, it'll be like, oh, you know,
I kind of know who you are but you're logging in from China.
So could you please enter your password again?
Like your, your master password? You know what I mean?
And it's like, you know, great. Yeah,
let's do that.
Um, and so I think these systems because, you know, let's face it.
The majority of people don't
travel a ton,
you know, they tend to use one or two compute devices in whatever city they live.
Uh,
and quite honestly for the people that travel.
Well, I'm sorry,
-- you're just gonna have to remember your password and type it in on your devices
-- that
you
get a password safe
and you use it to store the 10 bazillion passwords you need
and you keep it somewhere safe
and hopefully you have a really good password for your password safe.
Yeah, it's ok. We'll say it's,
I guess the way I look at it is if you steal my password safe,
you have a level of access to me that is so substantial.
My primary concern isn't going to be that safe.
Uh, see, I use, uh, last pass which, uh, luckily it's a zero knowledge one.
So they basically, you know, it's,
they store it but it's encrypted on their end using my pass phrase.
Yeah, I don't, I don't trust those people and So, I, well,
-- not only that I
-- actually too convenient.
I, it's so like between my, all my mobile devices and my laptops and everything,
it's just all, everything magically works.
I enjoy the lack of convenience.
Uh,
well, not only
-- that, the thing that
-- you, the true security
person. I know. I'm crazy.
Whatever,
whatever. It's true.
But the thing I really like is I use something called PW safe,
which is a password safe. No, no. There's a reason for it though. And there's one,
there's one aspect of it that I've yet to find in any other password safe.
And it is so important to me
that I'm unwilling to change, even though it is of questionable quality, we'll say.
So. Here's the deal is I've got my password safe and it's full of crap.
And when I type in, say my, I want the password for, let's say, you know, yahoo.com.
Yes, they've been in the news. So,
so I, I, you know, I basically say, you know PW safe dash up which means user name,
password.
And then yahoo.com.
And what it does
is I type in the password,
I unlock things and then
it waits for something to request the password out of the X clipboard.
And then when it does be it, you know, I basically go to the website, I, I middle,
click over the user name, field it paste the user name
and in the terminal where I ran this command
it tells me which window received the paste
and then it switches to the password.
I, you know, click on the password field,
middle click and it tells me which window received the password and then
it clears the copy and paste buffer of all of my data.
So that password can only be pasted one time.
And
that is it.
Whereas a lot of password managers just stick the password into the paste buffer
and then literally anything that can access it,
they've got it.
Yeah, that's a good feature. I'm wondering how
some of these other ones handle it.
-- Like, do they clear the clipboard after
-- most of them have a time out where?
Well, no, they, they don't pay attention to it at all.
They basically dump it into the clipboard
and then
they'll say after 10 seconds or 30 seconds or 50 se whatever you,
whatever you said they will then wipe it.
But no, I mean, because last pass uses, for example, they have a browser extension.
-- Uh,
-- I would imagine if there's a browser extension,
they're probably just doing some magic on the back end where it's not involving the,
the clipboard in any way, which
in most instances I would say is safer than using a clipboard based option.
Well, yeah,
because there's all sorts of javascript shenanigans to yank the clipboard out and,
you know?
Right.
Exactly. Well, and this is,
this is one of the problems I had actually is there was,
I was running a AVNC viewer.
VNC is like a remote desktop type virtual network computer. Yeah. Yeah.
And
the VNC viewer I was running basically was just waiting for things
to go into the clipboard and then it would steal them.
And so I'm like, crap, you know, every time I do anything with password safe,
like the VNC viewer is just stealing it all.
And it was driving
the
clipboard functionality. Does that? I think it does that on virtual box as well?
-- I think that's kind of how it was.
-- I have no idea.
But anyway, I, so obviously I, I don't use that
and it was,
it was half funny and, and half made me sad.
Well, and then the, the,
the thing that really ticked me off too is
the way they were reading the clipboard was clearly broken
because password safe.
Also, you have the ability to say, like,
never let this application access the data
in the clipboard because apparently the way
the X clipboard works is you can tell who is asking for the data
that is there, right?
And well, I, I don't know if this was a bug in VNC or a bug in X.
I never really investigated it enough to figure it out.
But essentially
I, I would try to tell password tape,
like never let VNC touch the clipboard and it didn't matter.
It still got it every freaking time. And I'm like, oh, crap. This, this blows.
Well, the thing,
you know,
I've noticed about all things like VNC and
virtual boxing and everything is always the,
the guest tools or whatever, always run with like a ridiculous amount of privilege
and they,
and they quote
unquote, just work because they do.
-- This
-- isn't even
inside of the thing, right? This is on the outside
where, right, where,
where the VNC viewer application is just like listening to my host clipboard
and waiting to steal whatever is placed in it.
And then of course, when you're in the gas,
things are even crazier when you try to do any
of this stuff because you're right with the tools and,
and just all that.
So
needless to say
I do not use a password safe inside of any of my virtual machines,
which is also a good thing because let's face it.
They, they don't need to be there.
So moving on to another topic that's uh kind of
related but not really is uh that whole bad review situation
-- of that Ham radio song.
-- Oh, man, I heard about this. What is, what a crazy story?
Yeah. So I read,
-- I read the whole Reddit
-- Post.
So why don't explain this for anyone who doesn't know what this is?
Ok. So there are ham radio enthusiasts
now.
Am radio. Is that like, like tasty smoked hams
amateur?
It's, it's a shortened version of AM amateur radio. Yeah. Yeah, I know.
I know.
I know. When I was a little kid I was like, this bothered me in ways you can't imagine.
I'm like, that doesn't make sense like we eat ham. Like, that's not amateur.
Yeah.
So there's, um,
in most of the world there's a bunch of spectrum licensed
to amateur radio operators and so people can do things like,
you know, use their CB radios or,
you know, um, more powerful systems
and, um, obviously a lot of modern radio equipment is uh you know,
computer controlled or computer managed.
Uh And one of the cool things you can do with ham radio
is, you know, packet radio.
So rather than like say actual voice or, you know, like the old timey Morse code,
you can actually send data packets over,
you know, AM and FM and long range transmitters. So you can actually
send data to like, you know, completely random parts of the world
and, and basically not have to pay for it, which is pretty sweet.
Also things like in disaster relief and whatnot.
When you know, all the cell tower batteries have died or, you know,
gotten clobbered by hurricanes,
you can now, you know, get maps and stuff uh from remote places that, you know,
have the satellite imagery.
Uh So anyways,
there's a whole bunch of software obviously to, you know,
interface with all these different devices.
Um And not surprisingly, a lot of it is uh open source and
there was a really famous uh open source package that,
uh, essentially the maintainer was like, I,
I just don't have the time to deal with this.
And he basically handed it over to this other group that, uh,
formed a company around it
and took it commercial
and started selling it, you know, nothing too strange there.
But what's interesting?
So they had, you know,
their standard sort of terms of use and user license agreement and one of the clauses
was basically we can end your access to the software for any time for any reason.
We want blah, blah, blah, no recourse,
which I hate to say is actually a reasonably
normal clause to have in a lot of software.
Um, and user license agreements in terms of service,
like if you've ever looked at terms of service for a website or anything, you know,
that, that clause is almost always there.
So what happened is this guy gave a negative review of the software, uh due to some,
there was a software bug that, you know, um wasn't being fixed
and the uh tech support people were a bit snarky
with him and he was a bit snarky in return.
And anyways, they ended up blowing up a bit.
So they
licensing server for this thing.
So basically the software you run it, it connects to a licensing server and then it,
you know, the licensing server says basically you're allowed to use this or not.
And the software, you know, works or doesn't work based on that
and they blacklisted him, they basically disabled his software.
Um,
and so,
well, and here's where things get really messy.
So, like if this isn't bad enough, it gets way worse.
So he posted about this and essentially the company kind
of got even more riled up and more rude.
And what's interesting though is other people came forward saying? Yeah, me too.
I've been, you know, my version of this software got bricked as well.
And now what's really fascinating is the original guy, if you read the email thread
or the ticket thread or whatever the support request,
he says I bought this software. I own this software.
You have done me wrong, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah. And it's like, oh,
I see where the problem is because this guy thought he actually owned the software,
not that
he had a license to use it that was limited to, you know, whatever,
essentially the company decided.
And so the company basically pointed out, no,
the software is licensed
to, uh, your ham radio call sign, which I find kind of weird but whatever
those guys love their call signs. In fact,
I remember when I worked tech support a million years ago,
there was a, a ham guy who would call up to the ISP I worked for and this guy, like,
I hope his radio skills are better than his computer skills.
We just say that.
But he insisted I call him by his ham ID.
I couldn't use his, his name was Bob,
which is obviously a fairly easy name to remember and pronounce.
But no, no, I couldn't do that. I had to call him the string of letters and numbers.
That was his ham ID.
Yeah, it was great.
Yeah.
So anyways, um, and this is, this is what gets me is fundamentally,
I hate to say this, but, you know, this software company is not wrong.
They did license the software and this guy should have
read the terms of the license when he purchased it.
Does it
say
negative
-- reviews will get you bricked or?
-- No, it says any reason we feel can get you bricked.
-- Any reason we
-- feel any reason we feel
and, you know, and that's the reality.
Like,
uh web servers or web services are a great example of this because not only are you,
you know, it's somebody else's software, it's,
they're running it for you and making it avail,
you know, the service available to
them.
But that's so true. That's actually one of the things I'm terrified of is
with using things like Google for picture, like storing,
picture backups and stuff is it can go south if they decide,
like you've done something wrong, all your data is gone and it's never coming back.
Yep. Yep. Totally gone.
Yeah.
It's, um, this is the modern world, you know, Richard Stallman,
for those of you who don't know, the,
the open source proponent from way back in the day, you know, turns out he was right.
Stallman has always been right.
I mean, let's face it. This is not the first time this has happened.
It certainly won't be the last.
Yeah.
And so what's really fascinating to me is that, you know,
although I must point out you, you say Stallman was right,
as we record on a Mac, right. Right.
now
it's, you know, tradeoffs, worst case scenario though,
I could get myself boots strapped into a Linux environment without, well,
it would take me about 20 minutes
and then I'd have to learn how to use uh you know,
-- whatever audio program
-- I I'm telling you, man, I use pulse caster in my end.
It's fantastic. It's awesome for recording.
Yeah.
But uh anyway, so
it really raises some questions, you know, especially for say, security software.
You know, what happens if we enter a realm where, you know,
security vendors start bricking people's antivirus or, you know, firewall
-- or
-- I'm sure that happens now.
I mean,
you got to think how many of those
antivirus applications that come pre installed on someone's computer
where they work for what,
like three months and then they start begging you for money.
-- Well, that's a little
-- different because that's more of a passive thing.
It's like this thing
will stop working at this date automatically
unless you do something.
It's a little bit different when the company takes an active
step and says you have the software, it was licensed,
it was working correctly and we've now decided to remotely disable it
and see one thing that's interesting to me is in the past easy, just firewall it.
So can't talk to the licensing server,
you know.
And of course, the solution there was that they made the software, you know,
it has to check the licensing server X every X number of days or whatever,
you know.
So then you entered into the thing where people
would like roll back their system clock and stuff.
Right.
However, now part of the problem is a lot of these apps
really do need to talk to the,
to the internet, you know, to these end servers to, to do useful things,
-- you know, to download updates or to download, you know, whatever,
-- not even that,
what if it's like software as a service
where you're literally using someone else's computer?
I mean, they have total control over what's happening.
And I mean, the reality is this has always been true of many, many,
many services and products we consume.
It's just generally speaking, these companies would never turn it off,
you know, like the power company, you can be,
I,
I can't even imagine how abusive you'd have to
-- be towards your power company for them
-- to cut,
there's regulations that govern things like power.
I mean, they can't just, I mean, if you don't pay your bill. They can turn.
But, although even then, you know, you and I live in cold climates,
they can't turn your power
in the winter.
Uh,
actually what they do here is they install a special meter that only allows
a very small amount of electricity through which is enough to run a furnace.
Interesting. Ok. So we'll use gas then maybe as, as the excuse of,
I know if you don't pay your gas bill, at least where I live.
Yeah. Yeah. Right. Natural gas.
They, they cannot turn off your natural gas service in the winter.
Like, that's just, you could not pay your bill, of course. Now come spring,
they will turn it off
and they don't have to turn it back on when it gets cold.
Like it's assumed like you're on your own now. But,
I mean, this is, this is an example of regulation, right? Because
I'm sure these,
these companies would love to do nothing more than to show up at your door, you know,
on December 24th and turn your gas off because you haven't made them in two months.
But the government said
I don't do that because people freezing to death is bad press. Right.
So,
it's also expensive.
Right.
I, I kind of get that and maybe I, you know, I,
I hate claiming regulation is the solution to anything.
But as we enter into a world where there's more and more as a service going on,
we're gonna need some sort of consumer protections here because today,
in virtually every instance,
the supplier of the service holds all of the cards.
See, and I think part of the challenge there is though,
if you make the regulations too onerous, let's face it,
the companies are going to gain them and move
offshore.
Um I mean, Russia actually has done this,
remember with the linkedin thing where Russia passed a law and, you know,
I actually don't totally disagree with this law, but the law basically states that
if you're going to hold data on Russian citizens,
the data has to be held on servers in Russia.
Now on the face of it, that's not actually a terrible law because you know,
this data about your citizens now
is residing in your legal jurisdiction.
-- So you can then do things about it
-- and it's out of the jurisdiction of your enemies.
Exactly.
Now, obviously being Russia and the,
the challenge being that this law is a two edged sword too because obviously that
leads to all sorts of things like it makes it easier to do warrants,
it makes it easier to do censorship and all that other stuff because again,
it's in your legal jurisdiction,
you know, the guys with guns can show up at the data center and say
do this or else.
Um And of course, you know, linkedin is afraid that I'm guessing, you know,
a this is going to be abused and B it's going to be kind of a pain because
one of the challenges being is if you let people set that precedent,
you don't have to have data centers in every single,
well, in every
single country you want to operate in
and potentially in every single legal jurisdiction,
you know,
-- and there's hundreds of
-- those Amazon is basically starting to do this though where
they're opening AWS data centers all over the place for this exact reason.
Yeah. True.
Um, and there it becomes, you know, a marketing thing where, you know,
your data is beholden to say European Union
law because the data center is in Frankfurt.
That was their most, or I think they did, what was it?
Frankfurt and London were their two most recent announcements.
Um,
you know,
and yeah, and so it really, it's, it's a new world we're entering into because I know,
for example, like I will,
uh,
I would be very hesitant to be rude towards Google because, yeah, they host my email.
-- I'm
-- like
-- a
-- lot
-- of
-- my and a whole bunch of other stuff. I'm
-- terrified of the day.
They decide I've broken their ya
and, and what then?
And yeah, like they're gonna really miss that 50 bucks a year. I'm giving them.
Right. I mean,
-- let's
-- face it.
And what's even more scary to me is even if we say, let's say, for example,
they pass a law saying, you know,
if you essentially turn off somebody's blank service.
You have to like, ship them a DVD or a CD of their software or of their data,
you know,
well, without the
whatever software to process that data, I mean, what use is this right? Like,
I don't know what format Google keeps my email.
So
Google has a service called take out
that lets you download all your stuff and they give you a gigantor
inbox of all of your mail.
It's huge but you can get it and it's a standardized format, which is awesome.
I give them,
for
example,
what about my Google documents?
They
come as word docs,
-- they just exported
-- as
they did this, right?
I mean, I give them loads of credit for this because they could have just been like,
yeah, screw you guys.
We don't care but they, they, they did it right. They did
-- happen,
-- for example, when it's stuff like sales force and tickets
and
that's, you
know, that's fair.
And even if there was, I'd still have to, you know, find some sales force competitor.
And I mean, as far as I know sales force, you know,
especially if like what happens when you're using
tie ins and other applications that are,
you know,
tied in, right? Like
um you know, same thing with like, well, any of these online, you know, software,
the service guys, right?
There's part of their value is that you can tie everything together, you know,
slack can talk to Jenkins can talk to signal, you know, can talk to a
whole pile of stuff
and great, you know. So if they did give me an export of this data, it would be like
an Irc chat log.
Great. Now, what,
so
the reality is, I mean,
these companies are gonna end up holding a lot of power
over their, you know, customers with this sort of unintended lock in. Well, not,
you know,
it's pretty intentional lock in.
And um, yeah, I kind of wonder, you know, how, how are we going to do this?
Are, are we gonna end up with laws passed that saying, you know,
email providers have to
give you a grace period or have to host you at a certain size. You know,
-- I
-- don't know, man, it's,
it's crazy to think about
it. It, it's a tough problem to say the least and I, I have no idea
because one thing that really gets me is similar to this is the whole, you know,
self driving cars as a service problem
because right now, for example, Uber, because they're not a taxi, you know,
taxis have to be accessible to disabled people or if they're not accessible,
they have to help the disabled people in and out
and they have to allow their service animals in,
right?
You can't refuse a fare with the service animal. You know, it's a protective thing.
You can't refuse fares based on like what is it like race age, you know,
things like that.
But, you know, Uber has in past, been found
to, you know,
been doing these type things where they made, like,
service animals ride in the trunk, for example,
or not pick them up at all.
And, you know, I say this and now I, I hope that my Uber app still works.
Right. Exactly.
You know,
but, you know, especially once these things are automated, you know, uh,
there's sort of, uh, some implicit biases, like, you know,
people without credit cards.
How does that work?
Yeah, we've talked about this one before.
-- Yeah.
-- So
anyways moving away back to it.
But as far as Stallman goes, I,
you know, these other service and these cloud providers are just so,
you know, economically I can't, I just can't, not use them. Right.
I can't do my own email for 50 bucks a year.
You know, with my own servers
you can't
and spam filtering and calendaring and documents and everything else.
Unless your time is worthless,
you cannot do it. But if your time has no value
-- which there
-- and even then, I mean, the minimum would be like, what,
five bucks a month for a VP,
a virtual private server.
So it would be $60 a year.
Yeah.
But, you know, I wouldn't, you know,
one of the problems with modern email is if it's not coming from a major provider,
you tend to get scored as spam.
Well, you can make sure you set up the various anti spam things on your domain and
whatever other ii, I forget, I don't even call it anymore
and
all that stuff
and that works well enough. So,
yeah. Anyway.
All right, man, I think the, the moral of the story is, uh,
tell your sister Stallman was right.
I wonder what else he was right about that.
-- We're going to find out in the next five,
-- 10 years. Everything, everything.
That's why Richard Stallman looks like he does.
You know, when you see the pictures of the old prophets from the days of your Yeah,
there's a reason they all look like Stallman,
-- right? Because they're so stressed
-- out
because no one listens to them and they know they're right.
All right, folks. So
thank you so much for listening.
If you wanna comment on the podcast on
the episode or have anything interesting to say,
feel free to use the Hashtag Pound
Os S podcast,
you can check on the show notes which will have links to
all the crazy things we talk about on open source security podcast.com.
And
if there's nothing else, you all have a fantastic day.
-- And until next time, Kurt take
-- care.
You too, everybody stay warm.
Yeah, most people don't live in the middle of nowhere. Pal.
We're the lucky ones.