Hello and welcome to the open source security
podcast with my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
You hesitated there for a minute.
I don't think I have the energy to do real crime right now.
That's ok. I understand my two levels.
My sat levels are, they're definitely better.
They're like 9695 when I'm sitting and not moving and not talking.
So they're probably going to dip to about 92.
-- No
-- one knows what that means.
Oh, I had bacterial pneumonia over Christmas.
Which seems funny because we've actually had,
we pre recorded a whole bunch of content prior to Christmas.
-- Good thing
-- we
did.
And then Kurt got, like,
-- deathly ill to the point I was seriously concerned about him. Uh,
-- not deathly ill.
Like, if I let it go another week then, yeah, I would have been deathly anyway.
Yeah, that's, it's the, I've had pneumonia before but typically I, you know,
go in very early and say, like, I'm sick and they go, here's antibiotics,
get better and I do.
But this time, obviously I didn't want to go to the hospital for obvious reasons.
And so I got, yeah, pretty sick. Before I went into the hospital.
And then, I mean, good news is bacterial, pneumonia is easy.
They just crank you full of about a liter
of IV antibiotics a day plus a bunch of steroids
and, you know, +34 days later they kick you out. You're fine.
Well, I'm ecstatic to be talking to Kurt again.
It's been a very long time and usually we talk on a regular
basis and this is like the longest we've gone in years not talking.
So,
yeah, it's been like 34 weeks.
I wanted to open this episode with kind of a,
I don't know if I'd even call it a correction necessarily.
So
we get feedback every now and then from, from listeners, we love feedback.
-- By the way, I
-- would say clarification. Sure, that's,
that's fair.
So anyway, one of the, one of the email threads that we got kind of was discussing,
one of the comments we made, I might have been one of the advent episodes.
I don't even remember anymore. It's been so long.
But basically, we made the comment about if,
if all the security people stopped doing their jobs,
like nothing would really happen.
And for about six months
maybe.
But anyway, the,
the listener assumed we were saying we don't need security in organizations at all.
And obviously, our intent
was we're saying most of the security in an
organization is so ineffective if they did nothing,
it wouldn't matter.
Arguably in probably about 50% of organizations,
if the security team did nothing that would be better than what they're doing,
it
might be.
I mean,
I won't disagree with that statement, but the point is security is hugely important
questionably, but I think a lot of the security we do today is ineffective.
And that's kind of the point of that statement is that's the question
you should ask is if you stop doing your job for a week,
would anyone notice?
And if the answer is no one would notice,
it's probably time to revisit some assumptions
and make sure you're doing the things that matter.
Well, see, and here's the flip side. If I stopped doing my security job at the CS A,
yeah, nobody would notice for weeks or months. But that's because
I've set it up so that we're in a bunch of providers with single sign on two fa
and there's basically nothing for me to do.
Literally, the, the,
the biggest thing I'm working on right now is improving our email deliverability,
which will actually have the side effect
of giving us slightly better email security,
you know, through D
mark and D
and all that crap. But fundamentally, I'm not doing it for security.
I'm doing it to improve our email deliverability.
-- And
-- now I would, I would say in your context,
what you have done is outsource security for the most part.
Yeah, dude, I'm one person I need to sleep. I have to outsource it
and you have to get sick sometimes for a month. Like,
yeah, like I was not terribly effective or useful for about a week and a half.
I can imagine.
I understand that. Absolutely. No, not every organization is like that. Remember?
Well, and
-- I can't spend time reading log files and stuff.
-- No one should read log
files.
Numerically, most organizations are tens of people.
When I say there's a lot of fortune. One hundreds, there's actually
100. Fortune one hundreds.
There's 1000,
1000.
But do you know how many small and medium businesses there are? There?
There's a lot, I, I know there's a lot millions. None of them have security people.
Number one. Where are they going to hire them? They don't exist. Number two.
No, you just outsource that like we don't make our own power.
We don't make our own roads.
You just, you pay for infrastructure. Absolutely and compute.
And it
is
infrastructure.
Any small medium business that says we want to hire a security person.
You know what my response would be? No. Spend that money on a social media marketer
-- and
-- roll your
bank.
II, I agree.
I think if you, if you're small and you have security people you've probably done,
screwed something up
unless you're some super weird niche corner case
-- which
-- I, no, you don't get to talk about corner cases.
You do this every time I'm cutting you.
But that's exactly my point. It's so like we can't even think of an example.
That's how rare it is. So it's ridiculous and stupid.
Anyway.
So the point of this is,
and I guess the lesson for everyone listening is as Kurt and I discuss
things and if you ever don't understand it or you think we're idiots,
I mean, by all means,
let us know because we will happily clarify what's happening or, I mean,
in most cases, we just, we literally are idiots.
Part of it too is sometimes we actually end up clarifying thoughts.
Like look at the whole S MS phishing thing.
Like we're both in violent agreement of, we think it's probably
a problem,
right?
And as far as the solution,
I got nothing,
-- it's
-- whatever, whatever anyway. Anyway.
So, so, but now at the same time,
here's what I will always say is when
you are communicating something and someone misunderstands you,
it is never their fault for misunderstanding you.
It is your fault for not commuting
it appropriately. Absolutely. In this instance,
100% Kurt and I didn't communicate our thoughts well enough.
And I mean, this is always, it's, it's a lesson, right?
Because now we know we need to do a better job of this
in the future and make sure we clarify some of what we're saying
because it makes sense in my head, but it probably doesn't make sense to anyone else.
And part of it too is we often don't give some of the context for the background
that we just take for granted.
-- Yeah,
-- because we've been talking about this topic, you know, on,
on slacker or signal or whatever for weeks.
And then all of a sudden no one has any of that backstory.
-- And, and so it's like,
-- oh, yes, you know what,
actually link this in the show notes where Richard
Femen explains why manhole covers around and,
and that is a perfect example of how to correct.
I answer the question in a way that essentially
I don't think you're stupid,
but I'm going to go through some background information to
make sure that we're both on the same page.
Feynman was lovely at that and he always did it in a way
that didn't make me feel like I was being talked down to.
And my absolute favorite is when
it's someone I think on the BBC asked him how meg
autism works
and he spends like 15 minutes explaining why he can't explain how magnetism works.
And it's like
I learned more from your not explanation
-- than I think I learned from any physicist
-- ever.
Well, and part of that is survivor bias too.
And that there's let me put it this way, how many of us had teachers
who are terrible at teaching,
but they like they know the material cold,
like you ask them to solve that physics problem or that
chemistry problem and they could bang it out in a second.
But as far as actually then teaching and imparting that knowledge to the class,
a bit of a train wreck,
knowing something and knowing how to teach
something are two very different skills.
And I think this is one of the problems security
sees a lot is we know a lot about security.
We don't know a lot about teaching people about security.
This is actually something I've been, uh, recently,
I've been looking for some classes on how to
things, right. Because I do this a lot with my Children.
Obviously, you know, my,
my one son asks some pretty deep questions
and will go through some pretty deep answers,
you know, with, with respect, adults are different than Children.
And also I'm not the boss of you.
-- Whereas I am the boss of my Children,
-- we need to move on.
But I want to clarify one important thing.
I don't think adults are different than Children in the
context that one learns maybe better than the other.
I think Children are willing to say, I don't know what you're talking about.
Please clarify that where adults want to nod along
and pretend they know it's happening because they don't,
I want to look dumb.
-- I
-- have
-- been consciously teaching my sons to say,
I don't know because that is the beginning of what we can find out.
-- Oh, I agree
-- completely. I think adults forget how to do that and kids don't.
Well, and also the embarrassment factor and even with vocabulary, I'll ask my son,
you know, I'll use the word and I'll be like,
and I'll see the look on his face and I'll be like, pause, Felix.
Do you know what word X means? And he's like, no, not really.
And,
and then you know what I will do is I will actually look it
up online before I tell him what it means to make sure I am
getting it right because there's been a few times where I'm like,
oh yeah, it's a little right. I've been using this not 100% correctly.
So actually, you know, what's more powerful than that though,
I think is the act of looking it up.
I think also shows the, the people you're talking to,
-- it's ok to stop and learn something new, then continue
-- well, or,
or make sure your facts are correct.
-- You know, the population of Canada is 17 trillion. Is it?
-- No, probably not.
-- No, it's a bit lower.
-- I don't even know
a couple of tens of million maybe
or
no.
-- Sorry. Sorry, I, I think 38.
-- Ok. Whatever. Tens of million.
-- Yeah, basically
-- it's about uh yes,
it's a rough estimate usually is about 1/10 of the US.
-- That makes sense.
-- And right now it's about 37.6 million anyway.
Anyway.
Ok, let's move on.
I want to talk about today. So this is sort of related to the whole solar winds fiasco.
That's happening right now.
-- But I keep seeing people say I
-- would say it's beyond a fiasco.
We're not talking about that right now.
I would, we, we will discuss it someday once we know more.
But I feel like there's still too much
hearsay and conjecture to have a reasonable conversation.
-- It's,
-- it's not even hearsay and conjecture. It's no,
no, we're not talking about it.
What we're going to talk about is people keep saying, oh,
Attackers only need to get in once or there only has
-- to be one tiny failure and then everything
-- is no,
no, they only have to be right once.
Whereas the defenders have to be right all the time.
And,
and I, I, this drives me crazy
because
nearly every successful attack in the history of humanity
is like hundreds of ridiculous mistakes compiled together.
-- It's never one thing.
-- It's airline disasters.
-- Yes. Exactly. Right.
-- It's just like banks, it's multiple failures
and the system eventually, once you find enough of these
small failures and chain them together, you know, the,
the whole oo the kill chain and all that.
Yeah, you get in and you, you own the place the reality is, well,
there's a couple of things at reality here.
Number one,
the Attackers actually have to be right more than once because quite
often it's not like they just log into your database server directly.
No, they have to like,
pop a web server and then they have to pop an app server and then they have
to bypass your laugh and then they have to explore your network a bit and blah,
blah,
blah, blah.
So, you know, the Attackers have to get more than one thing right, correctly.
You know, they have to exfiltrate the data. Like back in the day
I had, you know, our Amazon VPC S set up to
not allow essentially any outgoing connections, which made updates a bit of a pain.
That's what DNS smuggling is for, right?
-- No, outgoing DNS was allowed.
-- Oh, wow, that's hard core man.
-- But dude,
-- the web servers don't need DNS. They just talk to the load balancers.
-- I,
-- yeah, I mean, that's
fair.
Like unless you're processing log files, what do you need to do with
us? Look up on a web server for
unless that web server is making a call out to an external entity. Now.
-- I mean,
-- I think lots of web servers today do lots of things.
Well, yeah, yeah.
-- Nowadays they do but I, this is like 10
-- years ago, I hear you. I agree.
The other thing too is, is there are ways for defenders to flip the relationship.
The obvious extreme example being ll Airlines
and their security protocols where essentially you
get on an LL flight or well before you get on the LL flight.
A depending on how things are going for you,
they might stick you and your partner in an essentially an interrogation room.
And interrogate you and make sure your stories match up to people,
making sure their stories line up is a non trivial exercise.
It's completely impossible if it's not true.
-- Heck, even if it is true you're going to have differences.
-- Yeah, exactly.
-- All
-- right, you should, you should clarify this a little bit. What's allow airlines?
So, Ll Airlines is Israel's flag carrier,
right?
And they have some pretty stringent security protocols because, well, Israel,
let's just leave it at that.
And,
and I would like to clarify as well that their solution isn't by
a bunch of magic X ray machines and everything will be fine.
-- It's
-- things like training
all of their staff on reading body language.
It's there, there's a really nice,
it's probably, I forget if it's an article or a blog post or an interview or what I,
I will try to dig it up.
That explains a lot of this.
But the things Israel has done to secure their airports is absolutely amazing
and it's effective.
Right.
Well,
that's a good point actually because you could say the things
the United States has done to secure airports is amazing.
-- How
-- much
-- money is the TS A spent.
How often do they fail the FAA security test where they smuggle?
Well, like the infamous case of, you know,
somebody stole a sweater from a security checkpoint
and then later when they're putting that stolen sweater in the overhead bin,
a fake grenade rolls out
Oops.
Yeah.
You know, or even within, well, not
the last year, so much but you know,
where people literally get on a plane and they're like to the steward, like,
I'm so sorry, but I accidentally brought my gun on board in my briefcase.
I'm not a bad guy.
Please. Please don't tase me, but I don't know what the process is here.
So like you take the case,
you're getting tased. That's how, that's how that ends.
The other reality is,
is we can build systems so that they degrade and don't fail immediately.
Like my favorite example being
-- roads have potholes, I think we're all in agreement on that one. Holy
-- count.
No, I'm not going to let you talk about potholes. You talk about potholes too much.
A simple example being we have this thing called the high level bridge and it is a
high and level bridge because it's a rail. It's an old rail bridge
that goes across the North Saskatchewan from,
and it's, it's quite long because it goes from the,
the flat part to the other flat part.
Right? There's no grade and it was built just over 100 years ago. It's just a big old
I beams basically,
like it is just rusted, so nasty and you know,
they repainted it once about 1015 years ago, which was um,
like a year long project because
of course, it's covered in lead paint. Why
wouldn't it be?
Well, the lead paint actually is a, it's a, it's a bio,
it, it kills all the biological stuff that tries to destroy steel. It does.
That's why marine paint.
Like, it's great. It works great. Just not so good for the environment.
But, you know, that's ok because number one,
it's a rail bridge.
So the loads it was designed to carry versus what it carries now with just, you know,
car traffic like that thing was designed to carry mile long coal trains versus,
you know, 100 cars and maybe a city bus.
The reality is that bridge until it's probably 50% rust is probably fine.
No, seriously,
like because it's, it's over engineered for what the load it carries now.
So we don't actually have to maintain it that well.
And in probably 100 years it'll hopefully not fail violently, but, you know,
get rusty and nasty and we'll replace it.
And so that's the thing d we want degradation, not just outright failure.
And what's funny is if you look at these systems, like,
remember the home depot hack where
the,
the Home Depot they had that external security company
or something that like literally kept telling them,
look, there's like bad guys in your credit card system do something about it
and home people ignored this.
I feel like so many stories of breaches contain that,
-- that person warning willful
-- ignorance,
right? The person saying, oh, something's wrong, they're like everything is fine.
Go away. And
it's,
it's so funny you listen to these stories about disasters or you watch like
disaster movies and there's always like the
one guy warning everyone and you're like,
oh, that would never happen.
And it's like, that's literally what always happens in every single one,
every single bloody movie about a pandemic where you're like, no, that's stupid.
Everybody would just isolate and behave.
Nope.
The movies leave out the part where the
people run towards the zombies demanding to be bitten
-- my right
-- to.
-- It's
-- right.
-- Anyway,
-- almighty.
And I, I think part of that willful ignorance though is alarm fatigue.
Like a great example being Josh, I have an automated scan report of your software
and it has some really bad serious issues and of course your
immediate response is yeah to groan and think bad thoughts about me.
No.
Well, one day in theory, maybe somebody actually has a scan report with like
a
really bad flaw in it.
I would bet you once a month I get a scan report
that has an actual legitimate finding in it that it's like,
oh, I mean, they're never anything super critical but it's usually like, oh yeah,
we should probably fix that
and
yeah, great. Like that's fine.
Now, granted, at the same time,
the things I'm doing would have probably picked it up in a day or two.
So I
happen to accidentally find out about it early,
but it can happen and I acknowledge that.
But at the same time, so what I've done here
is people send me scan reports and I have written a bunch of
automated tooling that I basically never have to look at them anymore.
I run my tool 99.9% of the time my tool
spits out a report that's like here are all the answers
and that's it. Right. And that's the right way to do this.
And now my, my goal long term is to just be like here is an API
don't talk to me.
-- Well, unless you have something new. No,
-- because my plan there
is you're going to submit something to the API if there's something new,
the API is going to shoot
it,
email to me and be like, go look at this
and then the customer will get back. Hey, oh, thank you for submitting this.
We found something we don't know about.
We're looking at it right now and we'll deal with it appropriately.
-- And
-- here's the funny thing.
So what you're saying is you have a job in it and you've used your knowledge of it,
automate some work
and have the computer do all the boring less value stuff.
-- That's basically the, the point.
-- Right. Well, but
my point is you're a freaking unicorn. How many people are doing that? Not enough.
That's what blows my mind is how many people are actually
like,
I have a simple rule in that I won't do any security
for the CS A unless it basically adds nothing to my workload.
I mean, that seems fair.
There's, there's an XK CD comic where they break down, like,
how often you work on something, how long it would be worth spending to automate it.
Essentially.
I've looked at some security stuff and it's like, oh, cool.
Except that will now take an hour of care and feeding every week.
Yeah, you don't want that,
like literally the, again, back to my email diatribe.
The only thing I've done recently,
like in the last six months that has added to my workload
is setting up D mark reporting and getting, you know,
I get a daily report and I look at the data
and again,
that's far less about security than it is about improving email deliverability,
which is, you know, critical nowadays if you want to talk to your customers, right?
Because uh last I checked,
I don't think there's going to be any conferences this year.
I would be
there.
There will probably be some,
I keep getting invited to this one in person conference in May in DC.
And it's like,
buddy
like, no,
yeah, don't, don't do that.
Yeah. This whole the Attackers only have to be right once.
I think if you have like really poor immature security,
can the Attackers punch through in seconds? Yeah.
Yeah,
because you're running out of date software and they
literally just fire up a copy of metas,
metas
it's like yum num num num num num num.
Right. Doesn't even have to try. It's, you know, we just use a bunch of known
exploits to punch through your six month old systems.
Easy. Peasy, rum and squeezy.
Right.
And, and, well, and the brutal truth is unless somebody
has an internal team maintaining their systems or like a managed service provider,
maintaining their systems,
well, that's how that works.
You know,
like hands up on the show who here has updated their bias in the last 12 months.
Let's say,
I doubt most people update their biases ever.
So I I will say actually something really neat is the
I I imagine this works similarly on Windows but in Fedora now on a thinkpad,
because the thinkpad X one Carbon I use is, is well supported.
There is in the software update tool thing.
It has a bios update button. I can click to install the new bios.
It's super awesome and it's convenient.
-- So I keep installing it
-- the way it works in the Windows world is
your motherboard manufacturer.
Probably had like if they're a major one,
like M SI or gigabyte and I use those two
brands because those are the two brands of Motherboard.
I have, they essentially have a Windows app,
either specific to just update the bios from within
Windows or like M SI has this horrific monster.
It's like 500 megabytes called Dragon Center
that does like R GB like control and bios
and a bunch of God knows what else. And you essentially fire that up.
And I love how it, it just like,
it literally shows you a screen with the auto updater thing running
and two giant signs,
one showing like a uh a red circle with a slash of unplugging
your computer and a red circle with a slash of taking the USB K
out that has the uh
the bios update on it.
And it's literally like, and so I,
yeah, because I just updated both my bios
because I'm hoping this year to be able to buy
one of the new uh Ryzen 5 5600 XCP US.
If
you can find one,
I'm guessing around
June
or maybe October, I'll be able to get one.
So like, ok, I mean, it as exciting as it is listening to your recount,
the thrilling tale of a bias update
and how would most people even know this is a thing,
you know,
I
-- mean, you're,
-- you're a freak look
and autos
are getting better,
but the problem is auto updates.
Even if you only have a one in a million failure rate,
that's still a bunch of people affected.
Yeah.
And now at the same time, at the same time, if you don't update your bios,
does it really matter?
-- Well,
-- to quote every motherboard manufacturer on the planet,
if your system is working,
don't update your bios because updating your bios might break your system.
-- Let's be
-- straight. It, it doesn't matter,
not unless you want to, you know, upgrade your CPU at some point.
I mean, and there's,
every now and then you'll get some weird security issues where you've got
some, what was the Intel management thing came up or? There's,
yeah, Intel Management Engine and the lights out stuff. I
PM.
-- The C
-- PU side channel attacks. That it feels like there's a new one every week.
You know, some of those are bios.
-- Like
-- I'm pretty sure my bios updates aren't fixing anything security related.
I don't know.
I mean, actually, so when I, when I get my,
when I read the release notes of the thinkpad bios updates
every now and then it says it's a security fix.
-- So
-- stupid question. They are actually
there's somebody making an R PM package
and they're like downloading the bios update.
No, it's, it's not an R PM. It's like some service that I guess Lenovo
somehow works with. They basically,
I don't know if the service is downloading from Lenovo. Lenovo is pushing them out
and then
the, so
there's like a FW up D it's called in Fedora.
Yeah.
And it like magically downloads,
firmware and updates them and so far nothing is bricked
every time I run it, I keep thinking like this is the time,
-- this is the time it's
-- gonna
break
that old where I updated my bio
and it broke the delete key to get back into the bio.
-- Yeah. Right.
-- It's like,
right.
Anyway, anyway, it's,
we are off
on such a crazy tangent right now.
But the point is the point is I want to
bring us back because we're running ourselves out of time.
But like
the point of all this, of all this crazy discussion is the fact that
any time there's a failure, it's never one thing. Right?
It's the result of many poor decisions
when taken together create failure.
One thing I've learned in the last few months
and I don't remember when exactly I learned it.
Root cause analysis is wrong.
What you actually need to be doing is
root causes plural analysis because as you said,
it's never one thing.
Yeah.
Right. I mean,
-- yes.
-- And that has significantly changed my mind on how.
So I would say between that is there's always multiple root causes.
And number two,
we really want to look at
number one building systems that are survivable and
essentially ideally in a perfect world don't fail,
they degrade.
So actually Netflix has a great example of this
where Netflix is just a giant mess of microservices
and essentially they will degrade nicely. So it's like,
oh, you know, recommendation engine crapped out.
Well,
that still doesn't mean we can't just show you
like what's popular and what you watched previously,
you know, I've seen places where, well, a perfect example, Slack, right.
Yesterday,
-- Slack had a massive outage
-- except yesterday has
no meaning in the context of this podcast.
Uh The first Monday of 2021 of course,
I
had
a meter outage
the day. We all went back to work. It was a Christmas miracle cart. That's what it was.
No, what it was is Aws had outages
that affected a bunch of third party services. That slack was reliant upon.
-- No,
-- Kurt.
-- It was Santa Claus giving me a gift
-- because we also had overnight like Hiroko
was bouncing up and down like a kid on a trampoline.
There is actually a bunch of other stuff that I noticed was broken.
And so my assumption was
a
US
because like I used to do it to track a bunch of my personal
to do items and like to do it wasn't working and Slack wasn't working.
I was like Aws is messed up.
And of course, I looked at the Aws status page and they were like, everything is fine.
Everybody. I'm like, yeah, you're lying.
You know,
I've been thinking about that a lot because and this kind of feeds into security.
So let's say for example,
Gmail has a global outage where nobody can access your email for 50 milliseconds.
Does that count as an outage?
-- I mean, technically, yes, but I mean, realistically
-- no.
Ok. What about one millisecond?
Technically, yes,
an outage is an outage.
And what about if there's an outage for, let's say 1% globally for 50 milliseconds
outage?
I mean, look man, there's technical outages and there's realistic outages.
Well, what I'm saying is there's, there's a continuum of,
from 0 to 1 of where clearly we're not going to call this an outage.
Like one person was affected for 50 milliseconds
because of cosmic ray, hit a server versus, you know,
everybody on the planet can't access their gmail for six days.
-- Ok. That's an
-- outage. That would be lovely.
-- Yeah,
-- actually it wouldn't be that bad at all, would it?
But you know, and then somewhere in between where does it count as an outage?
You know?
Does it,
does it affect the same 1% of people for a day or
is it like a rotating pool of people affected for five minutes?
I mean, this is, what is it, the ship of, who's the, who's gonna
ship in these,
the ship? These,
right?
Like that's what this is, is at what point does if you start replacing parts on a ship,
does it stop being the first ship and turn to the next ship?
I mean, it's the same problem.
-- Well, same thing with Star Trek transporters,
-- right?
No, no, that's been C GP Gray has a video about that. Like it's not you,
it's a clone of you.
Yeah, exactly. Well, as we,
because we got the double riker issue
that one too,
man. I hate that.
Oh,
it was terrible.
But, um, same thing with security is
for example,
oh, my favorite is all these fishing emails,
we sent you a fishing email and you click the link.
Yeah, because that's what you do with links and email.
That that's a whole another story. We're not going to talk about fishing today.
But the point is is that a security failure.
-- And I would say not really,
-- that's human nature.
Like the security failure is the fact that clicking a link can p your organization.
That's the security failure.
You know, or a great example is
you have a fleet of 100,000 desktops,
is at least one of them going to be infected with something at some point in the next.
Like, there's probably more than 100 of them infected right now.
If you have a 100,000 desktops,
we can all agree that it's going to be
more than one and hopefully less than like 50,000.
This is what I keep coming back to with security is,
you know, ok, it's going to be more like,
is there a remotely exploitable code execution flaw in windows?
10,
at
least one lurking in there somewhere.
Well, of course, there,
there's a remotely exploitable code execution flaw and like everything.
Exactly. Is it less than 10 million? Oh, God, I hope so.
But more than one, you know, and,
and part of it is figuring out these ranges so that
we can figure out kind of how much risk we have.
And then,
you know, what can we actually do for defense because part of it is too is
we don't have to have perfect defense.
You know, the bad guys,
-- we will never have perfect defense and
-- we don't need perfect defense.
A great example is bank robberies, right?
Bank robberies now are essentially a non-issue because
the cash drawer has like $7 in it.
Like all the banks I go to now if you withdraw more than about 100 bucks,
they go, they, they do the transaction and then they go to that armored
box thing with a computer on it,
you know, swipe their card punch in their thing and then it like,
spits out a bunch of cash and it won't unless there's
a valid transaction attached to that for just auditing purposes,
let alone also making it harder to rob the bank.
And
I mean, so robbing banks is probably a great example and we can kind of end on this is
there's different kinds of robbing banks right.
There's going in and telling a teller to give you all the money.
Well, they don't have a lot of money, right. You know why?
Because people would go in and tell them to give them all the money like
they fix the problem.
But then there's also like, so you've got a vault,
the vault is full of valuable stuff,
but breaking into a vault takes like two days.
So
-- it depends
-- how you break into the vault because I
actually just opened a safe deposit box and she's like,
do you need the room?
And I'm like, no, I just need to fire some documents into this.
And so she actually turned her back to me like face the corner and I
put my documents in my safe deposit box and then, you know, put it
back
in
it. That's not the good stuff though.
-- Like banks have gold, they're not letting you in that one.
-- You know,
funny story.
My safe deposit box agreement says that I'm actually
not allowed to store stuff like that in my
safe deposit box unless it's like a collectible like a coin or something.
-- Well, they don't, they don't really know either.
-- Well, no, they don't.
But, but technically for example,
I am not allowed to keep cash in my safe deposit box.
I mean that I would be in violation of my agreement with the bank,
-- didn't
-- you watch breaking bad?
Like,
-- you know, yeah,
-- the guy with the cake pops in the suitcase full of cash.
Right.
Well, and that's how they were, that's how they were laundering the money around.
Right? Is they were, they had safe deposit boxes?
No, that's how they were paying people.
That's it. That right.
Yeah, they were putting cash in safe deposit boxes anyway. Anyway,
the point is, yes,
I I get that. It, it totally makes sense. So I guess
here is
my parting statement on this episode is that defenders only need to be right once
Well, they, yeah,
they only need to interrupt the kill chain once to kill that attack.
Yep. Attackers have to get it right. Every time defenders only have to be right once.
And that is,
I think the fundamental misconception we have about attacking versus defending.
I would say it's even more subtle than that.
Defenders can then choose to fix that and potentially in
a way that's very permanent or a perfect example,
being early on with the CS A I made the
decision that we're not going to be PC compliant.
We're not going to handle credit cards. We're just
gonna
use
paypal. Uh What is it?
Paypal's IP N instant payment notification api
we don't have your credit card number.
-- That's my security solution to credit card numbers at the
-- CS A.
And that's the right answer always.
I will say though,
the one other thing is that saying defenders only have to be right once Attackers
have to be right every time that's not going to sell a lot of products.
So
I don't expect many marketing companies to, to latch on to that one.
-- I think
-- that whole interrupting the kill chain thing.
-- I, I'm, I'm seeing more of that.
-- II, I do think it's getting better. I agree.
I feel like we're making progress
-- in many places
-- and as we've learned from the solar winds hack,
having a strong offense is cute and all
but essentially having a strong offense means a bunch of
people can come into your house and rob you blind,
like literally, that's what happened.
And so you need to get much better at defense.
Uh Yeah, and, and luckily you only got to get right once. So I'm going to call it.
Thank you, Kurt.
I'm so pleased to talk to you. You have no idea.
And thank you everyone for listening.
I
-- feel much better.
-- Excellent.
Go to open
source security podcast.com hit at the shut
out to
Pound
Os S podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media.
And as we mentioned at the beginning, we absolutely love feedback by all means,
get in touch if you, if you like.
-- We are very nice people. And yeah, Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day. You
-- too.
-- Thanks
-- everybody. Thanks
everybody. Bye bye
the.