Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt
Siefried
and my physically isolated. I hope partner
Josh Brass.
That's right. So I, I have COVID.
It's, I'm doing quite well, but I'm testing positive. I have
extremely mild symptoms and I told Kurt, let's, let's cut a podcast now before,
in case I get worse.
Oh, please don't do the audio editing. If you're like all COVID fog brained up,
no one will edit this podcast except me because they will do it wrong.
No, what I'm saying is you shouldn't do it until you're better.
Oh, well, I've already got one in the, in the Hopper. So we're fine.
I got like two weeks for this. Good.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, it's great
because
that's honestly my biggest fear of getting COVID
is because I'm fully vaxxed and everything.
It's just that long COVID stupidity
that like people talk about and
Charles Strauss, you know, author
and he's like, you know, it took me like three days to write a page of text.
So
the
thing I keep thinking of is I feel like I'm quite lucid and with it,
but am I, is my brain is my brain telling me this is just how I am.
Well, this is the same problem with drunk people.
Right.
-- Yeah.
-- How do you feel? I feel fine.
I'm fine. I could, I could drive,
you can't, you can't find your pocket to get your keys out.
He's gonna drive your car. Yep. Yep. I know. I know. So, we'll see. Anyway.
Anyway, I'm actually really excited for today.
There's a tweet from Kelsey Hightower that I want to read
and I'm just gonna read it verbatim. I'll put a link in the show notes of course, but
it, it says
less people are using OS package managers in some language.
Ecosystems have moved towards source based dependency management.
How do we deal with vulnerabilities when a
get update isn't an option?
The Go security team offers a solution for Go
Lang and then it links to a blog from, from the Golan
folks. And basically
what's happening
is go
will now tell you if the dependencies
you're using have security vulnerabilities in them,
-- which
-- is cool.
I mean, we've been doing this at the CS A for years
with N PM N PM has had this for a long time. Yeah,
exactly. Like we, we were there are Ruby on rails shop with N PM and whatnot. It's like
what is it bundler
audit or yarn audit or something? And like
they use ecosystem
specific tools that have an ecosystem specific database.
My devs have Macs but I think vagrant set up. So it's a Linux
thing
running on top of
Hoku, which is Linux.
Well, it doesn't matter. And that's exactly. And that's the point
if you use the system package manager, for example,
we're going to pick on Red Hat because you and
I used to work there and we know that's right.
We know all about this.
We know a thing or two and this is generally
true for all Linux distributions and P sds as well,
even though ports is totally different than packages.
But it's basically the same thing. But the point is
ok. So Red Hat wants to get all of the pie pie packages into R PM.
You can't, there's just too many damn pi pie packages. Even if you automated it,
half of them would still be broken in some weird way.
-- Well, pipe pie is nothing. Pi pie is what? 30,000, maybe
-- 350,000,
350,000.
Yeah, it's about a third of a million. So like,
-- yeah, like
-- which now a typical Linux distribution has a couple of 1000 packages.
Generally
-- uh
-- Red hats running around 10 to 15,000 in total across all their ecosystems.
But Red Hat's the outlier.
There's Red Hat and souza, there's Debian Ubuntu
and again, about 10 to 15, maybe 20,000 packages in total.
But if you start looking at packages,
a lot of them are out of date and dead.
Like, and I should know,
because I'm in charge of two of them for Fedora that I abandoned like a decade ago.
Ok. I just looked up Debian has 59,000 packages
but how many of them have been updated in the last two years?
Oh, man. I bet, I bet the number is, is bananas for sure.
It's about 20%. It's
most distro seem to average. Yeah, it's, it's a magic number.
-- It's like 10 grand to 15,000.
-- I assume it's long tail, right? Where the
the core things like kernel X Windows, web browser, all that stuff gets a lot of
updates and then you've got crap way on the end,
there's about 1 to 2000 core packages for each
Os that are like if you look at the security updates page, they're all there.
So that's the first thing is,
is quite literally even if Red Hat or Debian or Ubuntu wanted to
put every single pie pie package and N PM package and everything into
their package ecosystem.
They can't like it's just
there's too many.
Secondly,
what would be the benefit those ecosystems have good package managers?
-- There
-- would be a negative benefit actually because one
of the selling points of the current Linux distributions,
they they say like we this is a curated garden, right?
Come to us and you know, the things we give you will be cared for you.
Now, that's a debatable point, obviously, but generally speaking,
the core packages in
an operating system are well cared for.
Well, I mean, that's in general the whole point of open source based distributions.
Be it an operating system, be it something like,
you know what the Apache software foundation does with Java stuff or whatever.
It's like, yes,
you could absolutely go on the internet and download a bunch of
source code and make it work yourself and glue it together.
Or you could just grab Debbie and man, like we have a nice bootloader.
We have a package manager,
you know,
everything works
-- well
-- and, and so I think that's part of this story, right?
Is if we look historically, I remember in the early days of Red Hat,
there was a very concerted effort to say like
you should only be using the things we're shipping,
right?
Don't use this other stuff like installing random binaries off the internet,
installing random Python packages,
man.
Yeah, don't do that stuff because we're taking care of what we have and,
and back in the day.
Well, we did as well because it was a very small number of packages.
So we, we literally, it was, it was, you know, heavy lifting,
but we did it
well and more to the point you've got
commercial vendors and other vendors who just drop their
stuff into opt and kind of hope it works because what else are they gonna do?
That's, that's a kind of a different story.
Well,
but it's the same thing as these packagers taking
it instead of if I'm a pipe pie maintainer,
do I want to go build packages for Red Hat Debbie and Ubuntu
alpine blah, blah or do I just want to build my pipe pye package? And
it's funny,
I actually just got a um an automated thing asking me about
my interactions with pipe and their management like pip and install,
easy install and all those like, do you contribute?
Why don't you contribute? What stops you from contributing?
And honestly, I was just like, because this stuff works, like,
why would I get default if it just works
because I'll just make it worse. Let's be clear.
And, and then I just, I actually ended up giving up on the survey about six pages and
it was too long
as a developer. It's like,
well,
you could make all these
packages or push people to make all these packages
for all because there's over 100 Linux distro.
And again, what would the benefit be?
You're from like a from just a simple economics perspective,
-- you build pip and boom, everything in pipe P works right
-- now.
Let's ignore that, that particular issue because I think it's,
it's talking about building every Python or node
package for an operating system is bananas.
What, what Kelsey Hightower said,
I think is kind of more interesting when you look at how the world has changed
because back in the early days, you took your install CD
and you installed an operating system and then you installed software,
you need to be at web browsers or whatever, right?
And now we exist in this world where, you know, to kind of just steal the term DEV
ops
where the developers are often building the thing that gets deployed, right?
As a container image. And from their perspective,
they don't give two craps.
If they're using operating system packages,
-- they want to make something
-- work like snap
or, or just,
I mean, that's, that's the thing I love about Mac Os. Where's my, where's my thing?
Oh, it's just this file,
right?
And
well, but
oh, I want to remove this program,
-- drag and drop it to the trash bin and it's gone until
-- you install home.
Brew.
-- Well, yeah, I know about home brew. I use that
-- Homebrew craps all over your desk.
There's something to be said for also just having stuff kind of work
and maybe it's not like the, and I'm making her
here like the old correct way because a perfect example of this, right.
Red hat was a big believer in the packages because for example,
everything should use the system G zip, not its internal G zip because that way when,
when not, if, but when there's
G zip, we just update one system package and you like,
restart your server and you're done, you're good.
You don't have to go play archaeological Splunk looking for G zip and all your stuff
or
log for J because for example,
almost every open source package that does compression includes
gzip. So it'll compile on Windows.
It's just
exactly. And same thing with XML, right? Same thing with XML.
They like, I remember when XML hash for do SS came out and I'm like, oh my God,
why does everything have its own XML cut and paste in here?
Oh, because Windows OK. Fine. Yeah, we don't use that cool, great.
But the world has also changed in the
sense of Linux distributions are way more stable.
Like the rate of change in Linux
-- has slowed down significantly. Like,
-- oh man,
-- it's so boring now, which
-- is great.
You know, it's like cars, cars are really boring right now.
Like they just work mostly not compared to 50 years ago.
People have these platforms that are stable enough and similar enough like the uh
the LSB you and I lived in a world pre Lsbihlsb so much I
do.
But the point is like politics, even though it's terrible,
it's more terrible without it.
And so the Linux standard base is this idea of
like we will at a minimum have something that's like
-- Glib C
-- like, let me explain this in a way.
That isn't,
that is an old man because that explanation is old
man and probably no one knows what LSB is,
which is great because don't, don't even look it up.
It
don't, don't look it up. I'm not putting in the show
notes. So if I have a container that has Debian
and I'm installing
pip inside of it and then I do my pip, install whatever.
And I've got my Python application and I package it up and then I hand it over to the ops
and say, here's a container, run it.
If I switch out Debian for alpine, there is an extremely high probability,
no one would even notice anything changed,
-- right? Which is
-- cool
and, and an alpine doesn't even have g lipsy. It uses mule,
like,
but it's compatible and that's the thing, right?
I remember downloading stuff like bind and having to hand
patch and tweak it to make it work on my flavor of Linux because the ISC people clearly
they made it work on like slurs
and stuff, but not on my flavor of Linux.
And now I can't even imagine downloading something and having to do that.
Like if I did it was, it would be clearly broken.
I can't remember the last time I compiled source code into a binary that wasn't go
-- on my system.
-- Well, even more. When's the last time you compiled source into binary?
That wasn't like a
like not the classic
do
slash make, make, install whatever,
but like like R PM build like R PM build already is
-- stuff away.
-- Wait, I, I just remembered
I wrote C code and compile it while I was at cipher con in maybe May
because in their program, they had some C code and had a buffer overflow in it.
So I typed it in to make sure I was right. And then I mocked them.
-- Couldn't
-- they just give you a QR code where you could download the file?
They made you type it in, like in 19 eighties
it wasn't a file meant to be typed in. It was, it was like a background image
and they were,
they didn't their buffer, their string buffer wasn't null terminated,
right?
Anyway,
and that's the thing, the world changed like stuff.
Here's the thing 20 some years ago.
Like remember when Pearl CP Pan came out the Comprehensive Pearl Archive Network,
which was essentially the
like I think it was kind of the first one to really do this and succeed at it.
It's the first I knew of
and it,
it totally worked and succeeded at this.
Like all that's one of the reasons Pearl took off is because,
oh you have Solaris, I have Linux. Well,
yeah, you just
C
A this stuff in and, but a boop
and that's the thing is that it gives you this beautiful layer of abstraction
where if your pip or your CPA or your whatever tool works,
then everything else will work,
right?
You basically have to port the interpreter to
the platform which you have to do anyways
and you have to port the install
thing of a jigger to the platform,
which you're probably gonna want to do anyways versus having it
done at that operating system level, way of doing it. And there's hundreds of these.
Ok. Now, I want to take the conversation up to the next level
and that is, if I'm running a Linux distribution,
I can subscribe to their vulnerability feed and I get
a note whenever they release a terrible security update.
Right in the,
in theory. But if, historically, if I was using some
like Python or node or go,
it was kind of yellowing it where I didn't really know what was in there.
I mean, in many instances, if you had to go binary
before it was 1.16 maybe they like you couldn't even tell what, like what was in it.
And now they add information about the dependencies directly into the binary,
which is great.
Well, on a practical level, Javis had this problem forever because part of it is Java
is so huge,
you have like 16 million packages
and one of them is like Http dot Jar and the other one is also Http dot Jar, but they,
you know, one is
six kilobytes and the other one is six megabytes.
So
like,
where did they come from?
-- And it's like, literally
-- Maven has fixed a lot of this because now Maven includes,
well, Maven exists now, didn't when we were around.
I mean, you're right, you're right. I remember,
I remember pulling apart an R PM
and you know, what the Build Toast was.
Workstation dash something.
Not a domain name but like just a single.
I, I know, you know, and I'm like, where did this come from? And we can't ship it?
Oh, no, I, I know, I remember that.
I remember when a nontrivial amount of the fedora infrastructure
was like running under someone's desk and it's like,
this is probably bad
-- an R PM that had an iso image in it. And I'm like, uh what
-- now?
That's probably fine. That was probably, was it KVM?
-- Uh It was a satellite thing, I think.
-- Satellite. Ok. Same thing. That's fine.
That's fine. The point is I'm kind of like, what is this file? And why is it so big
followed by, oh, there's an entire
whole other operating system in here. I hope it's ours.
No, that was my first thought.
It's like I really do hope it's ours because I don't know, I'm sure it's signed.
I mounted
it was,
it was.
But um,
but that's the thing, right? Like it's, it's a, it's a scale and efficiency thing of
you port the interpreter to the platform.
That's the sunk cost you port the, the installer.
And then,
and here's the clever bit,
like I told my CS A devs don't bother tracking security bones.
Just keep that thing up to date. You update it twice a week and ship it out twice a week.
Sure that I can't ask for much more than that. Now you always say this.
Now, granted that works for like we have a website that we control everything.
We're not shipping a piece of
for that has to run on 16 Kaji different platforms.
-- We
-- have like Anchor Enterprise is a
nontrivial piece of software that has to connect to various databases
and various scanners and various endpoints. And so when we upgrade
most of those libraries, it is a significant amount of testing that happens.
That's the beauty, right is there's,
there's a huge amount of risk that we
can't even begin to quantify because nobody keeps records
and it really boils down to like nine times out of 10.
It works 100% of the time where you just update everything
and like literally nothing breaks and then once in a while
you like tweak some minor version
and like kaboom, it just breaks.
Yeah.
Yeah. Or it happens all the time.
Or my favorite is when like something, you know, you get a 1.2 0.17 and the devs like,
yep, that's fine.
But we're, we're, we're going to 2.0 now and you're just like, oh,
you know, there's my weekend gone.
Its
this speaks again to mature software practices of having like end to end testing.
Like not just smoke test.
Like, like if I hit password reset,
do I actually does an email pop out at the other end?
You know, if I
like
we connected to the database, the connection was established. Cool.
But like when you actually send the query, does it
the
correct
thing back.
And that's hard. That is a ton of work. It is good. Tests are very hard.
But the thing is if you build all that testing
yet now you can really start to YOLO it because
if it does break, you'll find out right away.
Sure. Oh, absolutely. And, and I mean, that's literally what we do.
We have an enormous amount of testing and we obviously, you know, what's,
what's wild now is there are test suites that track the amount of coverage you have.
So we can be like, we're only hitting 80% of the code. How do we get to 85 90 95?
And that's really cool. You know, that kind of stuff just didn't exist.
Well, you know, I'm always reminded of, remember when Google built the whole letter
test PDF
and they're like, you know, what we really need is like a corpus of PDF,
all the PDF S and they're like, oh yeah, we have that.
We're Google.
And so what was it like? 10 terabytes of PDF S or something crazy?
And it's like, yeah,
it's every code path gets exercised through this corpus
that they boil down into this monstrous data set.
But it's like,
and
what's really cool is,
so there's a project Google does called OS S Fuzz
and there is uh a measuring aspect to it.
I forget the name of it off the top of my head.
I'll try to look it up later and put in the show notes maybe. But
basically Os S fuzz now is designed in a way that it watches the binary as it runs.
And it can say, all right, we've taken this code path 66 times.
How do we get onto this code path over here?
Oh, we just twiddle this bit and now we can explore down there.
And that's really cool. And so anyway, anyway,
so we are going to get this to
happy at
scale because having a human being twiddle your
test cases to exercise every code path.
You're going to need 1000 people.
Well, that's it. Like you're gonna need 1000 people,
which is not happening
so
bad.
So anyway, here is, I think
the, the, the, the moral of the whole story, right?
The operating system used to be special.
And now, well,
actually the hardware used to be special and now it's a commodity
and the operating system was special and now it's a commodity,
the development environment used to be
special and they're turning into commodities
like let's face it.
I mean,
-- we're reaching a point
-- where text editors that
do syntax highlighting used to be magic.
And now I think they all do it. I mean,
oh, you know, I just noticed in VS code, I love this,
I was writing some Python code and it underlined re like I
had an re match and it underlined it with a red squiggle.
And I'm like, that's not spelt wrong.
And then I realized I didn't have an import re statement.
So
I added that corrected it. I'm like, oh, that's nice.
Did you click it? Because you can also click on the little light bulb and it will often
give you like, say, oh, I can fix this for you. And I bet that one could be fixed
because like
anytime you call an object in Python, it has to exist somewhere.
And so if you use like a new variable name, like if you assign it, it's happy.
But if you use it without assigning it, it's like uh I don't like that.
And I'm like, thank you because whoops. But um and that thing is that stuff used to
not be the default, but now it is.
And that's the thing like developers basically only care about their one
or two language runtime because what else would they care about?
Right.
That's their job.
Their job is to crank out Ruby on rails code or N PM coder or a website.
Well, and that's the dream, right? I mean, I remember my first job out of college,
I was in a server room with other admins. I was the UNIX admin.
We had like five Windows admins because Windows admins could
only take care of like two computers back then.
And like
that's all we did,
there were developers developing and we just gave the care and
feeding to the hardware and the software and think like,
does anyone do that anymore?
I mean, it's, it's become a commodity,
old school still does and it's incredibly inefficient.
And that's one of the reasons cloud one is like,
I don't want to manage software or hardware, especially hardware. And also I can't
like Amazon is doing, it's like supermarkets, right.
It's like 3 to 4% kind of margins.
If I run it, it's going to be way more expensive than that
and you'll get sick and die if I eat your,
I
just keep coming back to the fact that like developers just want to develop,
they want to get their code done. They,
the less things the developer has to care about or that just work or are just stable.
Like a great example is
in my experience now, the majority of web devs
cannot explain even simple networking concepts and you know what?
That's OK because every wi fi router or piece of network here you buy now you plug it in
and it
just works.
Now. Now I want to make a very important clarifying statement to all of this.
The importance of having people creating good usable container
images and good usable runtime for us is critical.
Like if everyone said I'm done working on containers,
the world would collapse in a week.
Well, so here's the thing you and I are ok, woodworkers.
But mostly because we have
access to amazing tools. Like, I just bought a new cordless planar from DeWalt.
It was like 300 bucks
and I fixed a bunch of doors.
Like there's a door in my parents' basement that now opens,
that never in my life has fully opened because there's like a hump in the floor.
Yeah. Yeah.
And so, but, like
I looked at buying a, like a shoulder plane, like a proper nice shoulder plane,
Japanese one or something
again, it's like 300 bucks. So I'm like, well, might as well get the,
and it's got a nice knob to adjust it from 1 64th of an inch to 1/16 of an inch.
It is fantastic and basically an idiot like me can use it with, you know,
I watched like two youtube videos.
I'm like, ok, it works exactly kind of the way I thought it would
and that's it.
But the thing is so my level of expertise can be vastly lower with
a vastly better outcome because I now have access to this magic tool.
The trick being
the people that built that tool are truly
experts.
And I don't mean just in the sense of like technical experts,
but like value engineering.
Like we built an amazing tool that retails at 300 bucks.
I could build a great planer that cost $10,000.
Right? And that's the thing. Like back to engineering like
you and I can build a bridge. Sure. Just give me all the concrete in North America,
you know,
but can I build a bridge that's actually affordable and will last like, say
-- 100 years?
-- What's the saying?
It's anyone can build a bridge but only an
engineer can build a bridge that barely stands up.
My favorite is when the sewer line failed at my old house.
And it's this stuff called cardboard Darow,
literally a cardboard tube covered in tar. And I'm like, what the,
he's like, Korean War man, there was no steel and nickel.
And I'm like, oh, ok. Fair.
And he's like, yeah, the lifespan on these things is 50 years. What's your house?
He's, I'm like, oh, my house is 51 years old, I guess I can't complain,
you know, and then they replaced it with PV C that will last 100 years.
And, but that's the thing, right is you get the knowledge
kind of concentrated more and more into the small group of people
who then ideally take that knowledge and shoved into a tool.
Be it? Software, hardware,
business process.
Like how many books are there now? On business or on accounting or bookkeeping?
And that stuff was like black magic 100 years ago.
Oh, yeah. Yeah. Yeah, totally.
Look at, look at the services you can use, you've got things like expensify and
I ad P does payroll now. I mean, all of that needed an army of people before
even simpler man filing,
keeping like finding your finding data in a file.
There were people who were professional filers
both putting data into a filing cabinet and pulling it up.
They were essentially like a meat powered SQL system.
No. Seriously, right? Like
the whole premise of the film, you know, being John
-- Malkovich.
-- That's true. Actually,
that's not the whole premise
-- of those
-- pictures of like secretaries typing out letters.
No, now you just write an email
dictated but not read. Nobody in our audience under 50 is gonna know what that means.
But that was a common thing back in the day.
Exactly. Exactly. It's so different. But at the same time, like this is cool
because I think this is
the kind of progress we all want, right?
Like if you look at human, just progress over time.
Like we started, everyone had to farm now, 3% of us farm, right.
-- The rest of us can do other things.
-- Now.
Uh It's actually lower than 2% in the Western world. It's
no like you look at the size of those farms and farm machinery like, and
yeah,
that's,
yeah, but I mean, think about you've got operating systems, right?
It used to be, you had teams of people taking care of operating systems.
Now we have containers.
Well,
-- the
-- rule of
thumb used to be one admin per 10 windows
machines and one admin per 50 UNIX machines on the high end,
like, those were the good super competent admins.
And now it's like,
I don't think we technically have a server admin at the CS A because we don't, I guess.
No, that's not true. We still have three DEV systems running in Aws.
But, like, we literally,
our production systems don't have a system in because they're a container.
You don't need it. Exactly. We're, we're seeing that now
with, with languages. right? These languages are becoming
the operating system from our perspective
where it's tracking its security vulnerabilities.
I'm installing the packages.
It's kind of doing some of the heavy lifting, but I still have to care and feed it
and I'm excited to see how we get rid of it because they will go away at some point.
It's so, for example, it's like networking gear,
what networking gear
is underlying
anything nowadays. Nobody knows or cares.
It
doesn't
matter. IP works, you know, data comes in, data comes out.
Same thing with the operating system now, essentially, even within a container,
right?
Like as long as it's Linux
-- ish, I don't care.
-- Yeah.
-- No one, no one cares.
-- It works.
It'll work unless it's some really horrendously niche
version of Linux that's broken by definition.
F
yo,
the FIP stuff you have to care but everything else. Yeah, no one cares.
And so then with languages we're, we're already getting there like, well for the,
for the global Security Database, we have that thing running in Digital Ocean
where it literally just asks you for like, what's your github
Repo? What's the subdirectory you want me to point out?
And then like three minutes later, a bunch of tech scrolls by and it's like,
there's a website running with the thing doing its thing.
And I'm like,
it was funny because the other Josh was like,
I wonder how hard this would be to port to Heroku.
And I'm like, I scroll through the text. I'm like,
oh, it says like the container name is Hiroko something he's like, oh,
it's the Hiroko container. I'm like, yeah, it appears to be that I'm like,
I guess porting will be easy because we don't do anything.
But that's the beauty. Right is Digital Ocean. Can use a best of breed tool.
I like,
I don't want Digital Ocean inventing or
building their own containers for their paths.
Go use a good one.
Yeah. Oh, absolutely. It would be foolish for them to do that.
Well, it's like a home builder. They don't make their own lumber.
They go to Home Depot. Like the rest of.
That's
right. Yep. Yep. That's a good, that's a good example.
Or nails or tools or any of that.
-- You know,
-- the, the only, literally,
the only thing would be like snap on where it's just like as a mechanic.
I need my tool to work now.
So they have trucks full of tools that will like, show up an hour later and
-- hand you a new wrench.
-- That's part of their value add.
That's why those tools cost a fricking fortune, man.
Like the thing is that is actually still available to you and me,
it's just very expensive because of that kind of
they fixed delivery
and, and I don't care. I, I usually don't need a wrench right now.
I can usually drive to the store and get one.
And I think
it's similar when we look at things like this,
these go vulnerabilities that are being tracked as some people don't need to care.
Some people do need to care.
I'm writing a bunch of code for GSD and it's like, oh I need to, oh perfect example.
I need to
uh
CP strings
and obviously I could do it myself. But I'm like
I go to pp.org, I type in C pe.
There's a bunch of libraries and I'm like, oh crap, they're all really out of date.
But then I'm like, oh pause CP was set as a standard in 2011.
So this library that stopped development in 2016 is actually fine.
And I'm like, OK,
I will go get the library literally called C pe and I
will literally import C pe and it will fail because oh yeah,
you got to run pip three space,
install C pe. Wait about, I don't know, 20 seconds.
This is what you need virtual environments for now. Virtual environments
and that's the thing, right. Like, is it for me to get,
for me to number one? Discover and find a package that will do what I want?
That's a hard problem.
And that's solved now,
number two
to then install and get it working.
Yeah.
P I three, install C pe, or, like you said,
I should actually be using virtual in for something a bit more sophisticated.
But I can't be bothered.
That's fair. That's fair. And if it's in a container it doesn't really matter.
It's just running on my Mac.
Well, that's
like, I just know because it's so easy. I just don't care.
-- Well, until you, you have stuff crapping Python libraries. Yeah,
-- I don't care.
It works.
Ok. I mean, well, it works now,
-- like,
-- when it breaks here I'll go fix it with virtual Inver something.
But for now I'm like, don't care.
I've had that bite me though because I
called one library and then there's another library with a very similar name
and they both imported the same
and things
didn't go real good.
But anyway, anyway.
-- But, yeah,
-- like it's, but the thing is I can,
that's the other thing is these tools are so good and high quality
that you can use them incorrectly and still get a good result.
That's true. Actually, I
-- mean, that's a good point.
-- Like, all I know is what the planar is.
Keep my hand away from that 10,000 R PM spinning blade
as long as I do that
everything's fine,
-- that
-- seems
-- fair and we're safety protection because man,
that sends little wood chips everywhere.
Yeah. Oh yeah. Yeah they do, they do and I mean I guess that's not unlike go, right?
Like you got, what's your safety gear?
Which at the moment it's things like you know,
maybe pinning dependencies and installing updates,
but once you've got that stuff in place
and you've got your your safety goggles on like
you're,
you know,
that's really cool.
That's really cool. Alright man, I think I'm going to call this one.
I'll give you the last word
I think.
Well,
I mean this is this not the whole point of
it is to automate stuff by taking people's knowledge and expertise
and a perfect example like something like curl where it's like, you know,
what I would love to see is like
see him give like a one hour on the most rare corner cases occurred more than once
and I'm sure he would come up with stuff that would just blow
him around because I actually literally just tweeted at him a thing.
I had an idea.
I want to grab a whole bunch of web pages.
I just want the headers, I don't want the body.
And so of course, the thing to do is to send the body to DEV Null and I'm like,
that's very wasteful.
I'm still downloading it and ignoring it
and I sent him a tweet saying
can curl get an option
to grab the headers and then send a TCP fin packet to close the connection.
So I don't waste the data
bandwidth and electricity serving the body.
And what kills me is at his scale
that would probably save a couple of megawatts per day globally
because there are so many people that are just wanting to grab the
headers and ignore the body like it's all over stack overflow and everything.
And it's something like that is a great example
of a ridiculously small sophisticated change because like again,
I know enough about networking to be like, well with a web connection.
Yeah,
you could just close it with the TCP FIN packet and just not get the body boom done
and
write it in
Python,
you know,
and then we could have this option that literally
will save megawatts of electricity potentially over a year.
Yeah. Yeah. But again, it's, it's, that's so specialized
-- but
-- well, uh
ignoring the body is a very common question,
stack overflow and a bunch of other things.
-- But
-- it's not common.
I bet in the grand scheme of things, but in the case of curl,
they can address corner case.
Exactly. And that's the thing like that's what these tools can do is they
at scale. And with this degree of specialization, it's like
we made your lettuce 0.1% less wilted.
OK. That doesn't help me.
But it really like it helps society as
a whole because now we're wasting less lettuce.
That's right. That's right. I agree. I like it. I like it. Go l
lettuce. All right, I'm calling it. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. Go to open source security podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes, Suzie Pound Os S Podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media.
-- Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day. You too.
-- Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks,
-- everyone. Bye bye.