Hello and welcome to the open
source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
and my partner in Thought Crime. Josh Pressers.
So, what's new?
Uh, it's spring, which is nice.
-- I think we had our last snow last week.
-- And
is it not where I live?
-- Like, freaking still winter here?
-- What do you consider?
Like, I consider there's not gonna be any more snow
-- that spring?
-- It literally snowed yesterday here.
-- Oh, that's not too
-- bad.
Whatever.
Sick of winter, it didn't stay, it melted right away, but still
snow should no longer be falling from the sky in the month of April.
-- It's
-- better than rain in January
because
in January freezes
that well, or,
or it's the impending doom approaching due to environmental catastrophe.
Well, we have that but we have like a like this year was a brutal freeze thaw cycle.
Like the potholes on my are just
really bad this year.
So I was in Chicago
over the weekend, my, my kids had their spring break.
So we spent a long weekend in, in Chicago now,
for anyone who doesn't live in the Midwest or has ever kind of been to Chicago.
Chicago is legendary. For potholes. They,
it is just,
they have a lot of roads and a lot of potholes
and not nearly enough time or money to fix them all.
But I felt like this year the number of potholes
I had to deal with driving around Chicago was ridiculous.
And that's all it was just, I, I've never seen it so bad. And
now I will also say though, I finally went to a Microcenter since I was there.
What's a micro,
oh, the store that sells electronics?
-- Yeah,
-- that like that, that, like epic computer store.
It was nice. I liked it. But I, I think though I was a little spoiled because I
also spent a great deal of time at fries. Electronics back in the day.
And micro center is like,
if you just kind of chop fries in half and only had
the computer stuff and didn't have all the other cool stuff,
fries used to have.
So it's like this is cool. But,
you know,
there's no oscilloscopes and there's no telescopes and there's no keyboards and
like music, keyboards and all that jazz. But
it was cool.
Like, I'm old enough to remember when Radioshack had radio components.
Like those, those kind of walls of little packets of little components,
you know, like straight up, like all the little things because, well,
part of it too is there's no internet to order that stuff on.
No, no,
just destroyed that market.
Yeah. I mean, I did the same thing.
I would go to radio shack with my parts list
for whatever the thing is I was going to build
and I would acquire things.
But now, like, my basement is like a radio shack because when I'm on digi
key or something and I'm like, oh,
I could buy 10 resistors or I could buy a 7000 pack of resistors for only $2 more.
So
I'll just buy that. Oh, and now I need this storage for all my resistors.
But yeah, I have so many electronic components. No, it's, it's lovely.
Yeah.
Anyway,
what are we talking about today?
That leads the story segue into uh emergency data requests, which
I love this like was actually not only was it done on the TV show Mr robot
but like the way it was done on the TV show Mr robot
is he literally Googles like how to do an emergency data request?
And then does that
hold on
-- back
-- up to the beginning and explain what this story is?
OK.
So the idea is typically when you request information from a company,
you need some sort of like
legal document that says you can do that otherwise it's, you know, it's basically,
hey, Josh, can you tell me your PIN number?
And you're like, no,
and especially for law enforcement, there's typically, you know,
some checks and balances because the power of the state is,
well, it's, it's all powerful basically compared to an individual.
And so the idea is you're supposed to have a warrant or something.
But having said that of course, there are,
um, well, in legal terms, one of them would be, you know, exigent circumstances,
you know, like you're in hot pursuit or something.
And so
there's this idea that you can have an emergency data across like, oh, you know,
we don't have time to get a warrant because for example, you know, Bob just phoned sue
and now sue phoned 911 saying Bob wants to hurt himself planning to, you know,
self harm.
And so sue is like, worried for 911 and of course, 911 is like,
we don't know where the hell Bob is, but Bob's cell phone company knows where Bob is.
So we can ask the cell phone company and be like, where the heck is Bob?
We need to know right away. We don't have time for a warrant.
It's a blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
And of course, that completely lends itself to,
well, social engineering.
Right. Right. Exactly.
Especially because there's, there's no framework for this.
I've always wondered that, you know, when the police say, you know,
if a policeman pulls you over and you don't feel safe, you know,
you can check their warrant card or their, their badge and I'm like,
I don't know what that looks like.
That's right. You know,
and now in fairness what you can do is call 911 or whatever,
your local emergency number is like 110 or
999.
And that works because obviously, you know,
that dispatcher should be able to tell pretty quickly that, oh, yeah,
you're actually being pulled over by a cop.
So, like, do what they say or, yeah, we have no record of this going on.
We're sending a real cop,
you know.
Well, that's happened locally.
There's been a couple cases of people were being pulled over on
the freeway by somebody who turned out not to be a cop.
Right. Right. Right.
-- So hackers are
-- so it's a great way to social engineering
using social engineering
to abuse this system.
Well, and not even good social enduring,
like they're just sending an email saying I
want this information and they're getting it.
-- Right.
-- Right. Well, because
most companies
are set up to efficiently respond to law enforcement requests and not
ask too many questions because that usually just gets you into trouble.
Well, somebody also pointed out if you kind of stall on each of these requests,
eventually, a real one's going to come in,
somebody's gonna get hurt and there's going to be a lot of bad press about it.
That's probably true
versus you just kind of give away people's information. Yeah.
Some of them will complain. But
does the, does the press really care about privacy stories anymore?
-- Yeah, that like that shit burnt down with Facebook about 10 years ago. So,
-- anyway.
Ok, so we understand this.
And now you said Mr Robot did this now, kind of an fy I, for anyone listening,
I've never seen an episode of Mr Robot and
everyone keeps saying you need to watch a show,
you'd absolutely love it.
And I feel like at this point I would
doing a disservice to the universe by actually watching it.
Like,
well, so like what I love is
and I hadn't really thought about this because I'm a Canadian.
But in the US, there's something like 18,000 policing agencies because you have,
um, you know, you know, federal and, and the thing is the US, of course,
-- never has one federal police force you have,
-- of course,
and then there's
state level
and there's so many states
50.
-- Yeah.
-- Plus
Puerto Rico and Guam and a bunch of other protectorates or whatever.
That's a good
point.
And I,
I would hope that they have police probably, then there's
the next level down is my understanding would be county.
That's correct,
followed by municipal.
Uh and you can probably go even deeper than that because like, for example,
when I was at university,
the university was in a city and the city had their own police department.
And then the university also had a police
department and the campus police were actually like,
deputized by the city.
So they can like, legally arrest people and stuff like that.
Well, and we're also going to ignore things like, you know,
the Department of Treasury or the Department of
Education having their own quasi police forces or,
-- you know, the postal inspector,
-- actually I found out the other day on Reddit,
the United States Postal Service has a police force.
Yeah,
of course it is.
Dude.
-- Have you looked at their powers?
-- The Postal Service police.
I was actually a long time involved in somebody did some mail fraud,
Uh retrospect to an organization I worked for.
And
that was a mistake because
mail fraud in the US is like, oh,
like it's worse than
it's a worse basically.
Anything you do with the US. Postal Service is an automatic federal crime,
right?
You rob a post office, bam. It's a federal crime
like you done screwed up, son.
And so anything with mail fraud is almost always also across state lines.
Uh That's probably true.
Yeah, you just,
you just made a big whoopsy and they came down on this guy like
a sack of hammers and he went to jail for a long time.
But I digress.
So,
but so part of the challenge like I live in Canada
and we have a federal police force basically the RC MP.
And then
we have a couple of provinces with provincial police forces, you know,
like the OPP or the Sirte
to Quebec. But like Alberta doesn't have one. BC doesn't have one.
And then we have municipal police forces like
Edmonton Police service or Calgary Police Service.
Right.
Well, that's it.
I, I've stopped because that's it because for example, like a smaller town like
Luc or, you know, the province of BC or, well, the province of Alberta
essentially outsources their policing at that level to the RC MP.
I mean, that feels app for,
to me
it is. Right. And so,
you know, if you get pulled over, like, in the Duke or whatever,
it's going to be an RCMP and,
yeah. Oh, and well, ok.
Also that technically now we have Alberta Sheriffs as well as a
new thing in Alberta and they kind of do freeways and whatever,
blah, blah, blah.
But the point is like the, the number of police forces we have in Alberta,
I think I could count on two hands
roughly like we basically have over four or
five municipal police forces in the RS MP.
But in Dunk, that's it. And the Alberta Sheriffs.
So it's,
and, you know, it's easy to kind of track them down.
There's not a lot of weird domain names.
For example, you know, the city of Edmonton,
Edmonton dot C A links to the EPS website very clearly.
And for example,
I was looking at where you live trying to find the official website
for the police force of where you live and I can't find it.
I found their Facebook page,
like their Facebook page comes up right away, but there's not a link to their
like they, they literally say email us at what? At mail.de
pair.org, what the heck is de pair.org? That's not even your government website.
It might not be. I have no idea. Anyway. So I, I, for the people listening,
you're, you're pronouncing it wrong
because this is America. So we don't pronounce French things correctly.
So, while the city was named by the French in the 16 hundreds
and it is spelled de space P er E and a
French person would call it de Pair because it's the father,
obviously,
how else did you say it?
We call it deep here, deeper,
-- deep here,
-- deep here. Like,
like
it's
a
all right, there's,
there's a tweet I saw the other day that basically said
anything with a French name in the Midwest of the United
States is pronounced in the most unf French way possible.
And that sums it up.
I won't even get into some of the other French named things around me
because it is as atrocious as you can imagine. Now, to answer your question though,
I live in what is functionally a suburb of Green Bay, Wisconsin Green Bay being a
reasonably sized city. My city is very small.
We technically have a police force but we lean on Green Bay
in the county to do most of the heavy lifting for us.
And so that's why like we don't really have a website because the
county and the city of Green Bay are doing all of the work.
-- Anyway. Well, there is a sub
-- page on the De
Pair
W
i.gov. You're still pronouncing it wrong,
which is actually where de pair.org redirects to. So that's nice.
But
anyway,
so that
the thing,
right? Like how,
like if I'm in Canada and I get a request from, like, you know, the RC MP,
it's going to come from the RC MP domain, which is pretty clear.
Sure.
You know, same thing for any municipal police force. There's not a ton of them.
And of course,
well,
there's not a lot of provincial police forces in Canada, it's again, single digits,
you know, so it's not hard to kind of put that in a spreadsheet and, you know,
collect it as time goes on.
Right.
But the US having, what is it? 18,000
state
county and sheriffs and,
and of course, there's no like actual sort of national accreditation type deal.
Like there's no central authority
and, and even in the United States
municipalities make up their own domain names and use them.
So if I registered, you know, city name, police.org
and started sending email requests and put up a website that looked plausible.
I'm pretty sure most companies that received
these emergency requests would just be like,
yep, looks legit
or you just do an off by one or like a two eyes or something.
That's true too.
Like, like, because I've also lived in Germany and in Germany, you have the,
you know, you have the, um, well, you have the German police.
That's it. Like there's the German police,
whether they should surprise anybody, I guess.
What's the point of this conversation? Other than just,
there's no way to secure this?
No, there really isn't
right there. Like,
I know we need police department NFTS.
-- That would almost certainly solve this problem.
-- But how do you validate that?
Basically.
How do you do
KYC, How do you do know your customer?
-- How do you do know your customer with this thing?
-- Right?
You don't
it?
I mean, look, so this is one of those examples I think and,
and the intended purpose of this discussion which
we're now what like 15 minutes into with no conclusion
is anytime you hear
anybody, especially like the FBI talking about, oh,
the back door will be safe because only we will have access to it. Like
this is the reality of that statement.
Yes. Only law enforcement agencies will have access to it.
-- And law enforcement agencies include clever people with domain names
-- or
people who get elected sheriff in some little podunk place.
You get that too. Yes, that's another one in the United States.
We elect our sheriffs in certain locales.
So you could literally like, I have zero law enforcement experience.
I could run for sheriff and be elected.
Like what? Actually in my city we don't do that. But there are places that do.
One thing. I didn't realize is
like,
again,
we have standards around policing
and education requirements and training requirements
and
it,
I did not realize in the US that there are states and counties that
they don't have that. Like, you can be elected sheriff and, and you could hire me.
That's terrifying. I,
you know.
Yes,
it is.
And
it,
it works exactly the way you think it does in your mind right now.
Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. Exactly. That
anyway,
so,
and what's fascinating to me is that people think this can somehow be fixed.
Uh It, it probably can't be
because here's the thing, even if you had some sort of certificate authority,
central authority that vetted and did KYC on all of these and actually,
you know, kept up to date records and blah, blah, blah,
I mean,
18,000 departments, times how many people in each department need access to this is
that's a lot of people to bribe
potentially
like it just,
you know, I always love these companies are like we want to keep this data secure,
but we also need to give it to everybody in sales.
And I'm like, well,
um,
uh, I
got some bad news for you,
you know.
Yeah, pretty much.
Yeah.
Look, we all know what the answer is gonna be, right. Sales wins that every time
it, it, look, I think
this is a really good example of
we exist in this space
right now
of we're kind of teetering on the brink of the old way and the new way,
right where there is, everything's becoming digitized.
We need to find ways to work together. We need
-- things like authentication is a huge deal.
-- Everything was digitized.
-- Well,
-- no, no, it's becoming more so than it's ever been. It's too late. It is too late.
But I'm saying
there,
the solutions to these problems don't yet exist and it's nothing we have to do.
So anyone talking about like
NFTS or a single sign on or zero trust or certificates or P GP or whatever,
no,
none of that crap solves these problems. This is a new paradigm
in technology that we don't yet understand.
And obviously as these things tend to go,
the bad guys are years ahead of us.
Well, they don't have to play by the rules. That's literally kind of their stick.
Right. Right. You know, like you can set up rules. Well, a perfect example. Right.
Every time.
Like, how many people have you heard?
Oh, that's not supposed to happen.
I say that every day, all day.
-- Yeah.
-- No, it's not supposed to happen.
But you didn't build the, the system took physically, technically, whatever,
actually prevent that happening.
So it did.
That's what Attackers do.
You know, I, I love, well, the R Street Institute, you know, with the whole,
you can make actual good legislation.
But yeah, if you have a room full of, you know,
lawyers earning a couple of grand an hour, they're going to come up with something,
you know,
or these tax avoidance strategies. Right. It's,
yeah,
I mean,
and it's just way too
easy. Well, and here's the other thing that gets me is
if the attacker fails, there's no repercussion.
Right. There's not like, like, let me put it this way. If you rob a bank and fail,
you're probably going to jail for a while.
Right.
Whereas if you send an email from some similar domain
and try to get some information and they go like,
ha ha
you're a bad guy. We're not going to give you that information.
Well, yeah, they're also not gonna like chase you down.
Right. Right.
And track you down online and arrest you
assuming they could even find you,
assuming you're even in a jurisdiction that you know,
has an extradition treaty with the US.
So
yeah, I mean,
and that's what gets me with all this
online scamming and like text phishing and blah,
blah, blah is that
there's no downside like it's like trying doorknobs on cars and being like,
oh, you know, I was not doing anything officer
actually, you know what you just reminded me of, have you seen the uh like
the the browser in browser phishing
demo that, that people have given lately? Like that's brilliant.
So, I mean,
basically what it comes down to is normally like
you'd hit the log in with Google button,
right?
And then it pops up a little Google window and you click the Oh yes, please log me in
and then it goes back to the original site and you're logged in because the, the oo
magic happened behind the scenes.
And
what and of course, when you do that you can see in the browser window that Oh yes, the,
the location bar says google.com.
So I know it's like the bad guy.
Well, it's, I don't think it's bad guys even I think it's just the demo at this point.
But basically
they pop up a browser window that says log in with Google
except everything is being rendered in the browser window using CS
S. So you're not logging into Google,
you're still on the original website that just makes it look like you're
logging into Google and the location bar looks right and all the,
the little check boxes and lock symbols and all that
all check out.
So when you click log in with Google, it's going to say,
oh type your user name and password in which is not uncommon that happens
except now you're typing your user name and password in into the bad guys website.
What's fascinating to me is about is two things about
this number one is that this was predicted years ago.
And actually there was a, a test thing in windows where they would actually
like you would choose sort of a theme or like a wallpaper type deal
that it would
put around actual real system windows.
So you would know if it was a real system window or like or like a faked one like this.
And you could also,
I guess do this within a web browser kind of
-- maybe sort of anyways point is doesn't matter
-- well.
And this is why windows made you press control alt
delete to log in
because a
malicious application could not capture that keystroke,
like only the operating system could capture control alt delete.
This is one of the reasons we're getting UB keys deployed across the CS A because it
takes the meat bag out of the question of making this kind of mistake
to put it simply,
right? Because it's part of the authentication chain.
Yeah. Right. Right. Now, it should be noted that
UI
key is do the web
a authentication, which is where the URL
in the location bar is part of the
like magic token that's sent into the UI
key.
And obviously that can't be spoofed
in that regard
it,
part of that
initial set up when you actually assign a key for that site and everything.
So it's like locked to it.
And
this is why like having passwords at all is is becoming dumb.
Whereas just literally like having a UB key and maybe
sending an email is vastly superior to having someone type in
-- a,
-- it's actually worse than dumb because if you do passwords properly,
by definition, you have to have a unique, strong password for each site.
Yeah, we can't do that. We're humans
unless there's some sort of, you know, Savant with an identic memory.
You have to use a password manager.
And here's the thing, if you have to use a password manager, now,
you're at the point of,
well, why not just use like a software authentication token?
-- I mean,
-- I agree. And that's functionally what a password manager has become.
Right. That's what it is.
Now, on the downside, you do have the,
the issue of if someone steals your master password, you're pretty hosed.
Which
is
again, if you have a, a software authentication token, it's the same problem.
Well, but the beauty is that, that master password, for example, again,
we're rolling out UB keys.
Right. Right. Yeah, for this exact reason.
Right. Like,
and now granted I get that because it's managed, you know,
Bob can lose his key and that's ok as an individual.
It's tougher because,
well, how do you then do recovery securely?
And that becomes the whole can of worms that the Attackers exploit and blah, blah,
blah.
Right. Because, like, no offense.
But why would I break into your account when I can just do an account recovery
and
the account recovery reset the phone number to, you know,
because that's happened with banks where people like to reset their
phone number and do account recovery at the same time.
And I love how the banks are like, well, we're not supposed to do it that way,
but your money's gone too bad.
You know. You know, my favorite thing about the bank is always, is so
when I go in
to get into my safe deposit box, which I do like, once or twice a year,
I have to, they used to just check your ID and then let you in.
Now I have to type in my, my safe deposit box pin
-- except I have no idea what it is. I never, I never remember.
-- See
-- here
-- we just
all the banks that you just basically
put your debit card in pin number and they're like, hey Mr Siefried.
Yeah, but that's the thing. It's not my right. It's not my debit pin.
So I I try my pin like 10 times and it doesn't work.
I don't know what it does and they're like, well,
I have to reset that for you here type a new pin in
and I'm like, what is the point of even having me do this step? Like this is absurd.
This is why I ended up keying my parents' cab or no,
I was going to keep my parents' cabin to the same key as my O key.
So I just didn't have to bring
I didn't have to remember to bring a key
Ive,
Ive. Alright. Anyway, anyway. Ok,
I
I want, I want to, but before we run out of time
I want to move us over to this crazy Z
live issue
that just got a, it is 2022
and the CBE is CBE dash 2018-25 032,
which people are looking at and saying
what the F is going on
with this issue.
-- So we're gonna tell you
-- apparently the deal was that
this was
identified as a security fix back in 2018 and fixed in
zip back in
2018.
And because it did not get a CV identifier or, you know,
strongly identified as a security fix, everybody's like, cool.
-- Yeah, great.
-- Well, it, it wasn't strongly identified. It was called a crash
and
-- no one seemed to care.
-- Well, and that's the thing, right? Like there's a be jillion
security bugs that start as a crash and then somebody has to look a lot deeper.
In some cases.
You don't have to look that deep, but in some cases you have to look really deep.
Every crash in Z
lib is a security issue like
that is, that is all I'm, I'm going to stand behind that statement.
Well, I would say, yeah, things like Zed Lib or lip J peg,
things like that must eat any data.
Yeah. No, I agree.
Now, funny enough, this is a bug when you're encoding data, not decoding data,
which makes it extra hilarious because it's like, wait,
what I remember reading Tavis email and I was like, hold on a second
and I read it three times because I'm like, I can't be reading this correctly.
How do you trigger
this kind of bug encoding data? And then I thought about it for a while.
I'm like, OK, I kind of get it. But anyway,
why, let me, let me start at the beginning.
Why does this have a 2018 CV E ID when we are sitting in the year 2020 two?
So the theory behind CV, identifier, the year in it
is that you use the year
that that issue was
known as a security issue. So uh as a simplistic example,
if somebody
commits a fix to code that says this fixes a security bug in the year 2018
and
it gets CV
at
some point in the future, it gets a 2018.
Now, if you have like a very subtle flaw that's fixed
and then for whatever reason, somebody goes back and looks at old commands and goes,
oh, you know, this is actually turns out to be a security issue
that would be like
when the person did that research and found out later,
whatever year that is in the future would be the year that they use.
But more to the point,
it just doesn't really matter that much.
It, it shouldn't matter.
-- But
-- it's, it's basically, and the problem is people expect it to behave that way.
So, OK, we do it that way. But
in some cases, I mean,
I've seen long discussions and arguments about what year to use on a CV,
where it's like, does it really, like,
shouldn't we just get more of these out of the door quicker?
-- I mean,
-- well, ok, look, here's the problem. I see.
And in fact, there was a tweet where, uh, uh, Dan Lawrence,
who we had on the show a long time ago, he basically was like,
what the heck is going on here?
And he kind of, he,
he detangled it and he wrote a Twitter thread and he added us at one point.
But anyway, the point is
like, the security people don't even totally understand what's going on here.
And fundamentally,
we exist in a place now where when you look at the year in an security identifier,
you make the assumption rightly. So that, that is the year something was actually
assigned
and became a thing.
So when I see a 2018 CV ID, I assume the CV E was assigned in 2018, not in 2022.
Now, what's happening is people are seeing this assigned 2018 ID and they're like,
oh, my goodness,
it's been four years. Why didn't you fix this?
And it's like, because it's been out for four freaking days,
like I'm getting there and obviously updating Z
live is nontrivial
and you've got to jump through all the hoops.
And I would actually argue that there's an actual, much worse,
more subtle problem to this,
which is
CV goes by that everything must be completely 100%
basically proven to be a security flaw before we'll go to CV.
And that's not how the world works and,
and actually hasn't for 20 years and especially not now.
And what,
and this is one of the things global security database
is doing is we're looking at not so much,
just 100% provable vulnerabilities, but this is security
related.
This is security information and we're gonna
take stuff that is like a vulnerability
as a vulnerability so that you can ignore kind of all the maybes.
But the point is there's, well a perfect example of this like,
yeah, like you said, every time there's a crash in Zed
Lib, yeah,
probably somebody with a security background should take a peek at that,
but it should automatically get an identifier.
It should automatically get an identifier,
an investigation and further processing
because like it said, Lib, man, like here's the reality.
It's like the, it's,
it's basically like log for shell, it's everywhere and it's a pain to update.
So it's not going to get updated unless
there's a screaming good reason to do it.
That's right. That's right. Right. And that's the thing because
let's be real.
So if all this stuff was easy and fast to update
security would be trivial because it would just be run current,
which is impractical.
And even though we,
we, we constantly go back and forth on this topic but
it
-- is impractical.
-- Yeah. Like in my perfect spherical cow world
run current. Perfect. But, like,
my smoke alarm needs to function.
And it, well, and the other thing too is I don't want my smoke alarm getting like,
a software update every day because at some point it's probably gonna break
because even if the chance of breaking is one in a million.
Yeah.
Or those poor people who bought that stupid Wi Fi barbecue
and every time they try to barbecue something,
it has like 10 or 15 minutes of updates to run before they let them barbecue.
Oh, that's exciting. It was on Twitter, man. It is brutal.
But yeah, like, I don't want my software constantly being updated on my light bulbs.
I just want my light bulbs to turn off and on.
That's right. So, anyway, anyway, the point is this is why
this stupid issue has a 2018
CV E ID
because
it is a relic of the past that is still being clung to.
So if you care, come and help us at Global Security database.org,
I think that's right.
I'll put a link on
it.
Uh
The Cloud Security Alliance is trying to fix this and Kurt and I are helping.
So it's very cool.
Yeah. Or two. That's right.
All right, I'm going to call this one skin late.
So thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to open security podcast.com. Head up. The show,
not Su Podos
S podcast. Hashtag hit us up on social media. Kurt have a lovely rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye.