Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast
where we take your privacy and security seriously.
Episode 148.
-- What?
-- No, we don't take anyone's privacy and security seriously. That is a lie.
-- Yeah.
-- Well, yeah.
Yeah, actually that is, that is true and not just for us,
but for most people that say that
that's right. I will sell all of your data for any amount of money.
That's actually not true. That
and I guess in full disclosure, we,
we've been approached by various organizations asking to fund us and we're like,
-- no, we like being a hoes to everybody so you don't own
-- us.
It's not going to be worth the hassle
and then people are going to burn us on Twitter and rightly so,
so I guess the reason Kurt opened with that, which was unbeknownst to me is
we decided to do a show talking about
disclosure, disclosure of breaches and security incidents.
The thing that kicked this all off is there's a friend of
the show named Dave Hall who sent me some Twitter messages showing off
some breach notifications he got from a company called Canva
and I'll put some links in the show notes to the replies. But it's like, holy crap.
Don't let your marketing department write your, your,
your release about the security incident you just had.
So, ok, well, why don't you tell us what happened at Canva? All right.
-- So,
-- from what I understand and I did some, a bit of research,
probably not as much as I could have,
but obviously there's just not a lot out there at this point either.
They had some sort of incident. They don't seem to exactly know what happened.
There were email addresses and passwords that were probably stolen.
And the first email they sent to people was basically like a nice
paragraph of marketing material before they told them what was going on.
And it's like what, I guess they, they did send a follow up email.
I give them points where they sent another
one that didn't have the marketing material,
-- but it's still a bit
-- fluffy.
It does seem a bit like, you know,
those companies that have their negative release on
Friday a minute after the stock market closes.
That's R A
stick.
Right. Right. And, and so anyway, but the point is I read this, I was like, holy cow.
This is crazy.
And then Kurt and I started talking and we were like,
we should talk about this because actually disclosing,
I guess terrible news really is what, what a security incident is,
-- is, is
-- hard and there's a second piece too.
It's not just disclosing this,
the breach of the incident and informing your customers and giving them, you know,
hopefully actionable advice,
but there's also steps and things that the provider should be doing.
Yeah.
And so I think, and, and I'm just going to read.
So they, they actually updated their website here.
Uh, update May 28th.
Our teams have been working around the clock to
investigate the attack and communicate with our customers.
Ok. That's good. I I'm ok with that.
Do that.
We are continuing to investigate and are being thorough and methodical with
our examination in order to understand all aspects of the incident.
Ok, so far the sentence is good. I like it
and provide the best advice to our customers.
We have also engaged forensic experts to investigate the incident. So
that falls down because the problem is they
in their original email,
they basically say people should change their password at the site.
Right?
No, no, that's wrong. That is so very wrong.
No, you, you send out a password reset email to everybody
and you force them to change the passwords.
Like I just went through this,
I was trying to download a statement of my uh my retirement account,
whatever you know, from the company it's at and try to log in and it won't let me so.
Ok, it's like you haven't logged in for a long time, like reset your password.
Ok. It's been a while.
Can't reset my password because I forget my secret question answer.
So I phoned them up,
go through that whole song and dance, you know, blah, blah, blah.
And that's the correct thing to do
is, you know, you force people to change their passwords,
especially when you think they've, well, when you think when,
you know they've been breached, right?
And not only because here's the thing forcing them to change the
password number one is the right thing to do because like they're,
even if their password is salted and hashed and all of that stuff,
they may have used a weak password and more to the point, it's the right thing to do.
And their mail says they had
salted passwords that were hash with decrypt, which is, that's great. Do that
the correct way.
Right. But no, I, I agree if your hash gets out, even if you have a scary good password,
you should definitely change it just because it is one of those,
it's better to be safe than to be sorry, sort of incidents.
Well, more to the point.
Why not?
No, no, seriously, why not force users to change their password?
What possible reason is there
to not force users to change their password?
I, I can think of two reasons that they wouldn't do this.
Number one is it's going to be technically difficult for them
to add that feature to their system because it doesn't exist,
which if I had to guess, might be
-- reason
-- they must have a password reset feature.
They might have a password reset feature.
But do they have a password reset feature for all of the users?
Dude,
I don't care if you have to hire interns to
hit the website and manually do it or script it.
No, that's your responsibility as a provider.
I will not disagree with you, but I'm, this is just a potential excuse.
I'm not saying it's right.
Well,
more to the point you can script this up and add this as
a feature and write this as a feature in less than a day.
Well, those are famous last words.
But I think the second potential reason
is you have a user base that is potentially non technical
and you are concerned at their ability to change passwords.
Um I don't buy that. I'm sorry.
But if your users are so technically
incompetent that they can't change their password,
then how did they get on the internet?
I won't disagree with you.
I'm just saying those are two very weak excuses I can think of
and I can't think of any other good ones and those aren't good,
but they're at least something.
No, it's um
yeah,
so, so I guess here's what we should do.
Let's stop picking on these guys because having an
incident is really hard and it sucks and,
you know, good luck everybody involved.
We, we feel for you.
Well, and in fairness the good news is at least it was salted hashed passwords. And
one thing that drives me nuts is whenever people are, like,
email addresses were exposed.
I'm sorry, I can't get excited about that because it's an email address.
I agree.
-- I'm in the same boat
-- if it was your
birthday or your social security number or something.
Sure.
Yeah, then you can get annoyed and excited your email address,
something that by definition you're typically handing out and
giving. I, I mean, I get that. Ok. I get that.
In principle,
people should have control over their email address and who has access to it.
I agree with that in principle, but in reality,
that's not how the internet and the world works and
we need to stop pretending that it is that way.
I, I tend to agree. I'm not saying we shouldn't,
you know,
do things like GDPR and give users control and the right to forget realistically,
we, we need to build systems that take this into account,
right? This is like
I would compare it to having your phone number or address listed in the phone book.
Back when we had phone books.
It is, you could get it delisted.
But even if you delisted it,
it's really not a secret and it's probably not that hard to find.
And so
I, I agree with you.
I think pretending it's a secret when it's not,
is more dangerous than just admitting.
This thing is everywhere. It's like a bad rash deal with it.
Well, the reality is, you know,
something stops being a secret,
-- it stops being a secret.
-- Well, and you can never put it back. Right.
It's that old, like, I still love the old hacker saying information wants to be free
and it's so true. Once it's out, it's out, you can't undo it ever no matter what.
Right.
And then if you try, you usually end up with the Streisand effect,
which is even funnier than any other possible option.
But anyway, anyway,
I want us to take a step
back
and let's just talk about some of the kind of fundamental
I'll say best practices or reasonable steps one could take if
you find yourself in the middle of an incident because I know
I have been through more of these than I want to remember.
And
it's always hard because I guess the thing that always happens is
you learn about something has happened and then the question always becomes,
well, what do we do now? Like the first thing I, I, we always think of it.
How do we, how do we cover it up?
-- Well,
-- or for the, you know, one of the first arguments would be ok.
Something has happened.
Do we have anything actionable to tell people or is it just the buildings on fire?
Sure.
-- Yeah. Yeah, that, that's part of it.
-- Right.
And that's the first thing because,
and I see it both ways because part of me is part of me wants to say
full transparency, tell people sooner rather than later.
But the problem is if you're telling people
something and you don't give them actionable information,
you're just stressing them out and adding to their alarm fatigue.
-- So
-- you say that's your first step. But
you and I have been through this,
so we have a different view.
But if you take someone who maybe hasn't been through many incidents or any at all,
-- their first reaction isn't going to
-- be, it's going to be. Can we cover it up? Right.
How do, how do we hide it?
It's kind of like,
I remember when I took forklift training a million years ago
when I worked at the factory and they were like,
what's the first thing you do when you get in
with your forklift?
You know, you hit something and everyone's like, oh,
you call someone or you do this and he's like, no,
you look around to see if anyone noticed and they didn't, you drive away, right.
And we all laughed hysterically. But reality, that's what happens.
And this is the same thing here. Our, our first reaction is, do we have to tell anyone?
Is it that bad? Can we pretend it didn't happen?
And I, I will tell you now,
that is an easy question to ask and it can be very
easy to convince yourself it is the right thing to do.
But in almost 100% of situations it is going to end badly.
Well, more to the point,
not so much whether it's the right thing or the wrong thing to do,
but people think they can cover it up and get away with it.
Yeah, you're not going to get away with it.
You can't get away with it. It's someday
something is going to come out.
And if it's a, if you're a big enough popular enough company,
you, you cannot hide it.
If you're, if you're a little tiny no name company,
you might be able to get away with it for a while.
But even then I guarantee someday
someone's going to figure it out.
So assuming the company kind of wants to do the right thing,
it is a very challenging problem that sort of race between,
we know something bad happened, but we don't know exactly what, like
how much was exposed, what was exposed?
Was it a subset of the database or the whole database,
which databases and trying to figure that out
and balance that with telling people what happened?
Because you don't want to tell people every 15
minutes and give them an update every 15 minutes.
-- That's, that's kind of useless. It
-- is completely useless.
I would, I would say here's
my advice.
Always in a situation like this is like very
hitchhiker's guide to the Galaxy step one is,
don't panic.
Well, that'll only make it worse.
-- Uh, Right.
-- Right. You end up like, doing something dumb
and it's not that you meant to, it's just,
you weren't quite thinking because your head isn't in the right place
and you make mistakes and you can often make things worse.
-- You can always make things worse. Right.
-- Right.
You end up with like, oh, I'll shut that machine down.
But now the rest of your infrastructure is failing because, like,
it needs that machine or something
or the evidence you need, it is gone.
Yep. Yep. That happens a lot too. And we'll get to evidence that that'll come later.
But no, I, I think don't panic is really kind of step number one.
And it, it's, it's easy to say,
but it's hard to do because I've seen so many people make so many mistakes.
-- Well, that's human nature. Right. We make mistakes.
-- Right. Right. Yep. Exactly.
And then kind of my step two is always, let's assume the worst. Right.
Let's start at the worst and work, walk our way back.
Don't start at the best and walk your way forward because it is very easy to
protect and something isn't a problem or to miss a minor detail if you're saying.
All right, let's assume they don't have anything.
Let's try to figure out what they got versus, let's assume they have everything.
Let's try to figure out if they didn't get something.
And, well, and the reality too is most
providers and most, most infrastructure is not set up with
having an incident in mind.
Right. How many places get robbed? And then they're like, yeah, we have cameras.
Oh, wait,
we had to put tapes in the machine.
Ok. And this shows how old we are,
um, or, well, not tapes in the machine but, oh, you know, the system was broken, or
one thing I've really noticed is the difference between, like, modern,
like, I was at a gas station
a few months ago
and I happened to notice their security cameras covering like the gassing up area,
the resolution on them was insanely great.
Like you could read on the license plate, not just the number of the license plate
you could see the year of the expiry take
and that's like a, you know, that's like less,
that's about two centimeters or less high text.
Uh You could really see people's faces and it took like kind of that.
It didn't take continuous video.
It took like a kind of like an image every second or two.
But like, man, I, you know, this is not the station you want to gas and run up.
Their, their video quality was seriously great.
Conversely, you know,
I've seen a lot of other gas stations where the video quality is,
you know,
something that was like VHS recorded and coded and shoved on to youtube and
then somebody recorded it on their iphone in like landscape mode and then like,
you know, just it got mangled and most computer infrastructure,
most people barely have good logs, let alone,
-- what's the word I want to say? Like, forensically acceptable logs,
-- nobody has
forensically acceptable logs.
I think there are very few organizations that have that and,
and a lot of them probably don't need it
either. And I think
that this is one of those challenges I always see is you have to
draw a line somewhere between good enough and like getting your work done.
And I think
security people, what I see too often is they go into perfect mode
and then everyone else says this person is nuts and I'm
not going to listen to them and then they just do nothing
instead of kind of again, starting at eight. This is the minimum we need.
-- Let's at least try to do this.
-- These complex systems require a lot of care and feeding
-- unfortunately. Well,
-- a great example, Pixar, right?
They almost lost toy story, the original movie.
-- The second one, it was the second one. Was
-- it the second one? Ok. Sorry,
it was the second one.
They almost lost it because I forget what
somebody like deleted the file structure in production.
-- So
-- somebody was cleaning up temporary files
and they basically accidentally like RM dash RF
the disc.
And
by the time they realized what had happened
and they stopped it,
-- a nontrivial amount of the movie was gone
-- and
then they found their backup infrastructure wasn't working.
As expected.
And the only reason they saved it was
one of their animation directors or something was
pregnant and had a workstation at home with a recent copy of all the data,
which is
crazy. Lucky.
-- I
-- just, I can't imagine the amount of lost man hours and,
and women hours and time and effort
if you like nuke AC G I film like two thirds of the way through there.
Yeah, that's when you, there's a lot of people looking for a new job after that.
I mean, that, that's how that ends, end of story.
And again, I mean, this kind of comes back to some of the, the resiliency of backups.
Well, and,
and backups. We've been, we've known about backups for a good 5060 years
and we still suck at them.
You know, when the last time anybody here restored a backup to see if it worked.
I do it occasionally for fun because I'm
weirdo, but I don't do the whole thing, but I also use cloud backups because I,
I got rid of all my hard drives and tapes and stuff because they're very unreliable.
-- And if your os burns down, you're still up the creek.
-- That's right. Well,
I had a complicated system.
I wouldn't be,
but we'll say I'm happier with the cloud because
I don't have to think about it very often
and then every now and then I will
-- restore some files and
-- there's that maintenance piece.
-- Right. Yes,
-- exactly. You know, it, it's expensive and time consuming. Yeah.
Right.
So, so anyway, anyway, let's keep talking about in instance.
So let's assume
you've decided to do the right thing.
You kind of started at the beginning or, I guess at the worst possible place,
you've walked yourself back a little bit, you've collected a little bit,
little bit of evidence and now, you know, you have to tell.
Oh, no, no, I'm, I'm gonna have to disagree with you politely.
You used the term you've collected some evidence?
Yes, that's true. We did not collect evidence.
-- You have not collected evidence.
-- That's true.
-- If I put my, at best,
-- you have some random
files. If I put my
hand on evidence is a very specific thing. And
unless you are literally a forensic,
even ignoring the lawyer hat that the quality and the
content of stuff I've seen people do is so laughable.
Right. Right. And, and that's, we'll get to that. But basically,
unless your job is forensics,
you are almost certainly unqualified to collect evidence
and
some people don't understand that either, but we'll get to that a little bit.
So anyway, anyway, let's assume it's time to tell the world.
What do you tell them?
Well,
I would back up a step actually and say one of the first things
you need to do is are you going to bring in outside help?
Are you going to call the FBI? Are you going to call the police.
Are you going to call a private firm?
And the answer,
I think outside of there's a handful of organizations
that have the competency internally to do this.
But they're very rare.
Generally speaking, you're going to need to go hire somebody who, you know,
probably has some obscenely high consulting contracting rates.
And I'm sorry,
but that's how that is if you actually want to do this properly because
the reality is like you and me have been doing this for over 20 years
and if you said Kurt,
somebody has done something on your computer
and you need to image your computer
and figure it out, I would say, ok, right off the bat.
I know that I cannot safely image my computer because I don't have a right blocker.
Like I don't have a physical right blocker to take the disk out,
put it in the right blocker and image the disk and copy
it and read it only and not write anything to it.
Like I know enough about this to know that
I,
I can't even get step one which is making a copy of the data and also
smart enough to know that I need to make a copy of the data to work on
-- the original.
-- You don't know what you don't know. Added.
Yeah, exactly.
And, and so let's, let's pretend we're not worried about outside help just yet.
Right?
Or maybe at all because let's face it in many instances,
you're going to have an incident and you're not going to call on
the FBI or police or something to press charges,
you're just going to clean up the mess and move on.
Well, especially not with a breach.
So anyway, let's talk about communicating to the world,
right? How do you decide what to tell them?
What, what is an acceptable amount of information?
What do you, and don't you tell them that happened?
And I think that's one of the hardest decisions to make.
One thing I would say is you want to
tell them things
and not tell them about the absence of things. I'm, I'm going to go with one of my
favorite examples.
A non-financial database
right now. If anybody Googles that they'll know who I'm talking about.
But fundamentally
what's a non-financial database?
I've never heard, I've never heard that term before. I, I have no idea
by definition what a non-financial database is. If you think about set theory,
it's everything except for this tiny little circle of financial databases,
that's probably what it is.
And as it turns out it was, it was bad but not as bad as it if you're
of thinking about it, like, oh my God, what could this be like worst case scenario?
OK. It's not financial database but what could it be? That was really bad.
-- So
-- I would, I would argue that's a bad term to use because it creates ambiguity,
right?
Well, and that's what I say.
You tell people things, you don't tell them about the absence of things.
-- Yes,
-- that's fair. I agree with that.
Well, unless it's something like you can say, like for the sake of argument,
let's say you actually do have a database with really good
production logging to a remote system that can't be tampered with.
And you can say conclusively that for example,
the attacker got access to your email addresses
but not to your hashed passwords. Right?
Then you should say that, then you should say categorically, you know,
the attacker got access to your emails but not to your hashed passwords.
But we,
you know, and I would still in that case
because me being me, I would still be like,
and you're still going to have to reset that password, right?
You are,
you know, because,
um,
you know, when I go in public and I come home,
-- I still wash my hands even if I didn't touch anything weird,
-- I agree with that 100%.
And
I, I feel like
when you see a term like non financial database
that reeks of lawyers to me.
And my advice always for security people writing these sort of releases is
don't let marketing write it.
-- The security team needs to write it.
-- Don't let marketing initiate it.
-- Maybe marketing can, they, they
-- can review it.
Don't let the lawyers write it. The security team needs to write it
and then you let the lawyers and the marketing team and
whoever else might need to review and sign off on it,
you let them review it but you cannot let them write it because if you do,
you end up with terms that don't make sense.
-- Well,
-- and,
and it's really clear to anybody in the industry and
even to people who are not in the industry,
it just reeks of something that was written to write, shift blame and guilt
and, and that's part of it too. I mean, blame is important.
Sometimes you're done, screwed up and you need to eat that sandwich
and
you just do it right because here's the thing,
you're better off to be as open
and blame yourself as much as you can at the very beginning
because people are going to be far more forgiving at
that point than in six months when you're like,
oh, and by the way, actually, this is what happened,
we basically lied to you before.
That's when people get really mad.
-- I think
-- Leonard French, you know, he's the famous copyright attorney on youtube.
I think he said it best. And it's basically to,
it's,
if you have to eat crow, it's best to eat the crow while it's young and tender.
Not when it's old and tough.
That's a good comment. I like that,
you know, and I don't think he created that, but that's where I first heard it.
And I'm like, yeah, like if you have to
own up to something.
Yeah,
people are going to be much happier that you owned up to it sooner rather than later.
You know. It's like, well, think about kids. Right. Kids do something
and if they own up to it, ok.
Yeah, it's still gonna suck for you. But,
you know, if they hide it,
you know, then, then, then there's the, the,
the aspect of what did they intentionally lie about this, which,
you know, now you've committed two crimes,
so to
speak. Exactly.
You know,
I get why these places do end up with
marketing and lawyers writing these things because again,
they want to make sure, you know, they want to avoid liability
and I get that right. Like avoiding liability.
That's, that's a very fundamental human thing.
You know, we all want to avoid liability.
-- The,
-- the other thing,
here's a really important thing that happens in these incidents also is
lawyers are used to dealing with weird stuff
and so a lawyer can show up and seem like they
know what they're talking about and to a degree they do,
but they're still not the right people to write your public statements
because they're lawyers
-- unless you magically happen to have a technical lawyer on staff
-- and,
and they exist and they're awesome
and their hourly rate is even more obscene than the forensics.
-- 70
-- bazillion dollars.
Well, and one thing I would say too is you need to pick,
I would say two communication channels at a minimum.
And that would be ideally
some form of push communication,
be it email or text message or whatever way you have to push to these people.
And number two, you need, you want to have a web page, either
status sites or like if you have a security status site
-- and
-- that's exactly the right way to deal with it is you have one,
push you annoy people once and then you give them a place that if they care,
they can go and look to understand what's
happening as things unfold because things often unfold
and I would encourage you to update your status
at least once a day.
-- Just so, I mean, depending upon many things, just so
-- people know it's being updated,
right?
And they know you're doing something, right?
It's not like do they even care?
I would actually disagree slightly with the one push I would there,
there must be at least one push.
And I would say actually you can have more pushes if
something really actionable or really important kind of comes out like,
you know, for example,
oh,
they also accessed
X or Y or Z or oh,
we actually have a specific technical step you can take to protect yourself.
Oh And by the way, offering people the cheaper credit monitoring for a year or three,
right?
-- Man, that makes me angry. I
-- have never reclaimed that once and I've heard of so many,
these companies getting broken into themselves.
-- It's almost certainly not
-- good, famous fun story. You know, um,
Equifax, remember they
was it Equifax after their breach?
They were trying to Upsell people on the credit
monitoring when they were giving the quote unquote,
free credit monitoring away.
Right.
That's
right.
Good job.
You know, I don't know if you can hear my deep sigh there but there was a very deep sigh.
I, yeah, anyway,
this stuff is hard. It is never fun.
-- And
-- that leads to one really complicated thing is, should you, then
I guess, offer support and help to these people be on just a web page.
Like, should you actually have them be able to email you chat at you or, or
phone you
to get assistance in some way, for example, with changing their password?
I, I think for what it's worth if you do your job. Right.
The answer should be no,
because you should be able to
enable or disable whatever technical controls you need.
You should be able to communicate concisely what has happened.
And yeah, if they need to change your password, like it's like you said, if, if,
if you don't know how to change your password, you know,
how did you get on the internet?
And
II, I feel like if you need to follow up with people individually,
you probably have done something terribly wrong
along the way. And that should not be the outcome.
Well, there are breaches and incidents where, you know that.
Well, Mount Gox is a great example of a place where, you know, a
lot of people lost a lot of money and they just fold it up and walked away, you know,
technically, probably what should have happened.
Well, this assumes Mount Gox was one properly, so it wouldn't happen in the
first place.
Kind of a bad example.
So there are breaches and incidents that are sort of how do I put,
they're kind of high value, but there could be this level of hand holding.
Um, you know, and because when I heard Equifax was, you know,
setting up phone lines so people could call them and figure out what happened
that that's just going to be a disaster right there
because so many people were affected by the Equifax breach,
even if like 1/10 of 1% called them in the first week,
that would have still been
hundreds of thousands of phone calls.
I don't know anybody that can set up a call
center to handle that kind of volume anytime soon.
Right. Again, I go back to, I think
there can be situations where it makes sense to do some
sort of hand holding for a certain subset of your customers.
But I think in general
you need to make sure you don't have to do that because that's just going to
-- put you in a worse place than you were in when it all started
-- well,
and it's probably not going to work and customers are going to be on hold for 10 hours,
-- you know. So, it's just, it's going to make things worse.
-- Exactly.
And, and I guess you just hit on
the thing that is most important, I think is
when you have an incident of any sort,
I think the thing you need to always keep in mind is
don't make it worse for your customers. Right.
You can make it worse for yourself maybe along the way.
But your real goal is don't make it worse for them. Right.
Because something has already happened that is potentially your
fault and your intent is to clean up the mess
and make sure you don't make their lives
more terrible than you've already made them.
And I think that is where a lot of this falls
apart because I think a lot of organizations worry about protecting themselves
as opposed to protecting their customers if you work for a company
that's more worried about itself than it is about the customers.
I have a suspicion that company is not going to be around for a real long time.
Uh, well, I'll disagree with you there because there's lots of,
plenty of evil companies out there.
But I was gonna say, um,
the reality is for most of these security incidents and breaches that
the, the stress and the hassle and all that, that stuff that you're, you know,
you can dump on, you can dump it on to your customers and it's an externalized cost
and they can't do anything to recover it from you so
bad.
I mean, a great example is like this, oh, you know,
free credit monitoring for a year or two or three.
no. How about you mail me a check for 50 bucks
and let me decide what to do with it.
-- And of course, no company is going to do that if they have a breach.
-- Right.
Well, in, in the right answer is to freeze your credit because
the credit monitoring,
yeah, your, your data could be out for five years before someone uses it.
You don't know. I mean, and even then the, the credit monitoring is isn't very good.
Well, again, it requires the user to take additional active steps and do.
It's one more thing they got to do in life and not forget to do and blah, blah, blah,
dude, I don't check my credit report for weird stuff.
I've done it like twice in my life.
I hear you. I hear you.
So let's, let's wrap this one up. We've got what, what does our advice look like?
We've got uh don't panic, which is always great advice.
Be honest
and ideally be honest
in ways that are actionable,
you know, try, try to,
it's, it's better to help people than to just let them know that their house is on fire
-- and show up with a bucket of water.
-- I agree with that. I like that.
And, and I think the one thing we didn't really talk about
is if you need help from law enforcement or someone like that,
get them involved early and don't mess with the
-- evidence because you're going to screw it up
-- well,
or hire a firm that is certified in your jurisdiction to do this kind of work.
Right.
That's fair. That's fair
and important words,
certified in your jurisdiction because the laws and rules of evidence vary
-- significantly in some cases
-- and it's hard and even if you think,
you know what they are, you probably don't.
So there you go.
-- Well,
-- I don't even want to think about like all my stuff in Amazon, East Coast.
I don't even know what state it's in.
I think it's Virginia and some of it's in California.
-- So like, so I don't even know which jurisdictions apply at this point. Nobody
-- does.
Fine.
That's true. Right.
So, yeah,
but yeah, hire some outside help
because if nothing else,
like they're going to hopefully prevent you from making it worse.
Hopefully. All right. Anyway, man, I'm going to call this one. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you, everyone for listening. You can go to open source security podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes.
You can, you see Pound Os S Podcast hashtag to hit us up on Twitter and yeah,
Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks. Everyone. Bye bye.