Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself. Kurt Siefried
and my partner in trying to help make things a little bit less worse. Josh Bresser.
Do I make things less worse?
No, I said we try.
-- Ok, I'll accept
-- try. I didn't, I didn't say we're accomplishing it.
II, I try, I do try to
make things better wherever I can. I'll agree with that.
-- Oh, no, no, no,
-- I better would be. No, no, no, I'm not going to go that far.
I'm going to go less worse. Like, let's be achievable.
Sucks less. Let's set realistic goals.
Ok. Ok.
-- Whatever, whatever,
-- like my yard, I mowed my yard for the first time in a month.
So it's less worse. It's not better. It's just less worse
a month.
That seems like a long time.
It was really hot for a while and then it rained
a bunch and then it was hot and it was like,
never a good time to mow it because
it was too hot
or the grass was wet, you know?
-- And when the grass is wet, like
-- anyway, all right,
I'm not gonna ask you too hot is because you live in Alberta?
30 it was up to 3035.
We had,
we had five days, over 30
°C in September. Like that's never happened. Very
normal.
-- Oh,
-- totally. Totally.
All right. All right. We're gonna talk about
the, I'm gonna pull up the tab, so I get the actual title. Correct.
It's the 2024 tide list. State of the open source maintainer report.
-- That is its official title. We'll put a link in the show notes, of
-- course. Ok.
And so let's just clarify two terms.
One open source means exactly what you think it means here.
What does
-- maintainer mean? I because I forgot to
-- check to Ashley.
It's the people who took the survey.
You know what? That's actually a good, that's actually the correct answer.
I know it is because I've taken this survey in the past and it's like,
am I a maintainer kind of
here's what drives me nuts is, yeah,
they say in mid 2024 Tide Lift fielded its third
survey of open source maintainers plural over the phone.
See, that's what kind of always confuses me. They use the singular in the title.
And I'm like, there's like the one person like we're just,
it, it's like the guy. It's like that little stub in the XK CD comic. It's that guy.
-- It's
-- like the royal we herd. Ok. I want to start this
conversation by preface.
We have not reached out to Tide Lift nor did we invite them on the show.
And I thought about this.
Actually, I thought, oh, I should because I, I know a bunch of those guys.
I worked with them at Red Hat, but I don't, I don't want to talk to them yet about this.
Maybe in the future, like tide lift.
-- If you're listening, you know, get in touch with,
-- we will talk about it and then they,
they can correct us.
They, they will hopefully correct us.
But more importantly is just the fact that I want Kurt and I to have a
very raw and honest conversation about this report
versus Tide Lift is going to will say,
be a little more polite than, than I suspect we will be.
And so
Tide Lift, you are welcome to come and talk about this, but not yet.
No, we
uh
yeah, they're probably more polite than we are.
All right.
I want to start by just asking you, what was your very first kind of takeaway?
Like one sentence?
Take away when you saw this report,
-- you mean
-- like when I saw it come out or when
-- I actually kind of flipped through it
-- when you read it,
whatever?
-- Ok.
-- So
essentially one sentence,
car things are probably worse than this report leads us to believe.
Oh, that is an interesting
and I agree with that.
And my first thought was this all feels like for anyone
who's been kind of paying attention for the last year,
it's the no fuck
shit report. This is not new
and I feel like it's also not getting better.
Well, actually, I would say it's in many ways getting worse.
And, and, and what's nice though? Is this actually quantify?
Well, I'm going to say quantifies it even though technically,
well, there's 400 respondents. So that's statistically relevant, right? It is.
But I mean, obviously the numbers in this report are not perfect,
but with 400 respondents, they're probably close enough.
Yes.
But on a sort of anecdotal data slash qualitative data,
there are a lot of common themes that
match with what I know
to be true. So to quote Stephen Colbert, you know, the truth in us, it feels true.
I wanted to
true.
It reaffirms my biases and beliefs. So I like this report.
Now, I I want to here, here's one thing though I would say in terms of like bias
it, I, I just had, I define the number 19% of the respondents are paid by tide lift.
So that's a, I'm sure they reached out to all of the people they work with.
And we're like, hey, we're doing a survey. Can you please fill it out?
So, my suspicion
is
that kind of lifts some of these numbers up a bit and makes it look less dire
and maybe it, it really is.
Well, there's a, there's a couple of, in my mind, there's a bunch of key takeaways,
which is in some ways things are getting worse.
And a good example of this is the XZ
uh thing that happened.
-- Yeah,
-- they have like a huge section just on that. Yeah.
-- Well,
-- because it, it has led to people being less willing to just blindly like,
oh you want to come into the project and be an admin?
Sure. Cool. Or oh
yeah, this pr fixes a bunch of stuff that's important, you say? Sure, cool. Like
they
without mentioning current events,
there are threat actors that we know to be active in the open source space
and you can no longer like 2025 years ago.
If somebody came to you with a device driver for the links kernel, you'd be like,
yeah,
sure put it in or if somebody came and it's
like I want to rewrite this device driver entirely.
Sure, whatever man do it.
Like go ahead.
No really like oh Kurt,
you want to take over the PHP open ID plug in because you say you want it to work.
OK. Go for it.
Statistically, you can probably still blindly accept a lot of people
because the amount of like legitimate activity vastly outweighs the amount of,
you know,
naughty bad activity.
But the problem is,
you know, it's kind of like that goalkeepers dilemma.
If you don't like dive to save the ball, everybody's going to look at you and be like,
what are you doing?
Like why didn't you try.
Right.
And so you, if you are to be trusting and let people in
and something bad happens, you're going to get yelled at and conversely,
they're also stating the problem now is, is if I do be a little bit more suspicious,
I'm driving a lot of people away. So I, I like that. This report
really quantifies a lot of, oh, it's not just me,
there's other people worried about this,
there's other people that are having this problem.
And I think that for that reason,
this report is invaluable because it validates
a lot of what's people are dealing with
and they, at least now they know they're not on their own.
Like there's other people suffering the same problems.
So I want to start with what I think is the most dire statistic in this report.
And it was basically, I believe it was exactly the same last year.
Yeah.
60%
of maintainers have quit or have considered quitting
their maintenance work. 60%.
And in fact, on the report this year, I don't know what the number was last year.
Well, it says 58%
but anyway, it was 22%. Yes, I have quit. 38%. Yes, I have considered quitting.
Yeah, that is dire
and I, I don't want to, like, try to spin this in a positive way,
but like that is a scary number.
Yeah,
I mean, there's a lot of software I depend on that. If it goes stale, probably be ok.
But there's some stuff that it probably won't be ok and there will be problems.
And what gets me is economically like this system, it's like let's encrypt.
If you even charged a penny for it, it would
cripple usage because you'd have to have a credit card and payments and everything.
And so being that it's free and licensed appropriately,
open source has enabled the modern software industry full stop.
Like there's no more arguing.
Like 20 years ago, we were saying, oh, open source is doing well.
It's gonna help out it's gonna be good. Close source has a place but now like
like straight up WSL hyphen hyphen install on a windows
system and you get a choice of Linux distro,
like the world
is so much more efficient. It's,
it's kind of like the US in the colonial days of like basically
stealing all the patent data from Britain to jumpstart their economy and industry.
And that's what like open source has enabled,
not just the modern software industry,
but the software industry has enabled everything.
Everyone who listens to the show knows this.
Well, I I don't think a lot of people really think about it. Like
without this open source being this cheap and available,
we would be 10 or 15 years behind.
Sure. Sure.
Like the cloud revolution wouldn't have happened without open source.
That is correct. Right.
Or rather the cloud revolution would have happened and it
would look like what oracle and VM Ware are offering,
which would not be pretty.
-- So,
-- based on the, the graph
I just mentioned 60%. Right.
There is another kind of picture,
image graphic. I don't recall it,
but they've got paid versus hobbyist open source. Right.
And this where this has my, my, my brain wondering,
61% of unpaid hobbyists are solo open
source projects versus professional and semi professional.
Only 26%
are
single. Yeah.
And
two or more is 53% in that bucket. But in unpaid hobbyist, two or more is only 20%.
So, like 60% have considered quitting.
And I also feel like 60% are running their own projects. I have a strong suspicion
that Venn diagram has an enormous amount of overlap.
It's probably an oblate spheroid,
right?
-- With like a little
-- big
words.
I mean,
-- the thing that always gets me.
-- Well, hold on one more, one more. The graph above. Then
I'm, you'd think if I was smart,
I would have taken some screenshots of these prior to us con conversing.
But no, no, I'm not smart.
Then above that, 60% of open source maintainers are unpaid.
So I feel like that 60% keeps showing up over and over
-- in this report, they're
-- unpaid for that work. Right.
They probably have jobs, I hope.
Yes, they, they almost certainly have some other
sources
and not all of them
because there were some famous cases of people who are literally like I'm broke.
I don't have a job and I'm still maintaining this project.
Can somebody send some money?
Like we've seen that happen?
Right. Right.
But hopefully the vast majority of them do have
a day job,
so to speak.
Yeah, I don't know. I,
I just, I keep coming back to part of the impossibility of this is
the scale of it.
Like we're talking
hundreds of thousands of people, the developers
-- and no,
-- we're talking about 400. That's the thing.
Well, and, and what I was about to say though is
of that 420% work with Tide Lift and get paid.
So the real numbers are,
well,
-- it's probably more than 60%
-- Tide Lift is probably paying
less than 1% of open source developers is my guess,
definitely less because there's literally millions of open source developers
uh
depending like
there's a lot, I don't think it's millions, but it's well tens of thousands,
hundreds of thousands, probably.
-- No,
-- I've, I've kind of a pack of the envelope looking at things anyways.
It's the the thing to remember is there's
millions of open source projects and developers,
but how many of them are actually used by somebody else
as a dependency or like as a popular plug in?
And that very funnels quickly.
Yes,
a perfect example of this funnel is you look
at how many people are involved in this project
you have the data you've run where it's like one person or less, uh,
90 something percent.
And by the time you get to, like, what three people it's, you know, that the, it's,
-- it's vastly squished.
-- I
wouldn't call it a curve. It's just one giant spike at one
-- and then it falls off
-- very good. It goes like 23
to
not zero but close to zero.
Every, the, all of the other numbers are zero
because they're functionally rounding errors compared
to the single maintainer number,
which is in the millions.
Yeah.
Yeah. There's not many Linux kernel projects or Apache Maven projects or Curl.
No, no. And and it's OK. So tide lift draws many conclusions. But I want to
kind of this is something that I feel like comes up all the time
where a lot of people listening to the show are gonna know this, you and I know this
but like the Linux kernel is not normal, right?
Curl
is not normal.
They are well used and also well maintained.
There's so much else going on here.
And I feel like when most people think of open source, they think of the Linux kernel,
they don't think of the six
100 N PM packages maintained by 12 people that
they're using to basically prop up their entire business.
So like I'm on the STF board to and look at these projects
stf the Sovereign Tech Fund, right?
So they're the German entity that is, you know, funding open source work.
And a great example is one of the recent ones was, uh Express Js which,
uh, yeah, I think you would agree is widely used.
Yes. Yes, it is.
And part of, for example, they want to do some stuff, like,
have a scope on N PM and get all their projects under scope
so that people know they're actually getting the real Express.
Yeah, that makes sense. Right.
And I'm like,
oh, yeah, they haven't done that because I'm like, yeah, when you start, like,
I want to install Express, like, where the heck is it?
And
Express is a wildly successful project. Like it is.
I don't even want to guess how many
percent of websites and traffic go through Express.
Right. Well, into the double digits. It's a lot for sure. Yeah,
they have a ton of people working with them and for them
and even they are struggling or another good one is Apache.
They want to do some stuff.
And I was looking at, I'm like, well,
why can't the Apache Software Foundation fund this?
And then I looked at the Apache Software
Foundation's financial reports for the last three years.
And I'm like, oh, yeah. Yeah. No, they can't fund this at all. Not even a little bit.
-- Yeah. It's like a one or 2 million only
-- isn't just a hair over 2 million
of which about 1.3 million is spent on infrastructure. Right.
Which doesn't leave a whole lot of money for
like paying a pile of developers to do work.
-- Like it's, they're a very lenient, like they're very lean. Like
-- most of the open
source foundations are, the open
source foundations are not flush with cash
well, and they're not paying their top people millions of dollars.
With kind of the notable exception of Mozilla, if you look at their financials,
their people get quite a lot.
But the Mozilla Foundation and the Mozilla
Corporation are different things as well.
But again, I think this is another example where like people
at Mozilla,
they look at the Linux Foundation, they're like,
oh look at the tens or hundreds of millions of dollars here.
Open source foundations are doing great and it's like, no, no, just those two.
And I think part of the challenge is,
is that a lot of the stuff that people actually use and interact with
is
by definition wildly successful otherwise they would
not be using and interacting with it,
right?
Like the Linux kernel one
Firefox did well.
And there's, but there's all the kind of underpinnings and dependencies, you know,
like on master when I ask like, how big is Chrome or Chromium or whatever
guys? Like
one guy answered with, you know, it's this millions of lines of code or whatever,
but like that some of that is just headers and not the actual stuff I'm like, oh,
so it's bigger and I think that's part of the problem is that there's a
lot of bias here because people don't use those like little tiny foundational NP MS.
They pull in something that uses it, like
going back to this, those things need to be maintained and, and well and improved.
Yes,
because
like we talked about last week,
there's a whole bunch of who is libraries and probably a bunch of them could be
from some updates to assume that the who is server might be more.
Sure.
Sure. Ok. Ok.
I want to move on to another interesting data point that I have a,
I have a hunch about but, but I'm, we'll see.
So it's on page 17 of the report and it says maintainers are spending
three x more time on security than they did a few years ago.
And they go into, they talk about like the open SSF scorecard,
which I don't have a lot of nice things to say about.
-- Like there's old episodes.
-- I think the problem is
the OS the open SSF scorecard is not good,
-- but there's not even anything close to an alternative.
-- No,
there's not. But that doesn't mean we should just use the open SSF scorecard though.
-- But the problem is people again have to be seen to be doing so
-- anyway, I don't want,
I don't want to dwell on
openness of scorecard right now. So here's the thing. Here's my suspicion.
Developers are spending three times more
on security I have a suspicion.
The reason this is, is because so uh tide lift asked us in 2021
I think 20 yeah, 2021. And they haven't asked it again until this year.
And so the three X numbers from 2021 to 2024 not 2023 to 2024.
And in 2021 the world was very different.
You didn't have depend
aot
you didn't have all of the crazy free utilities,
github offers. We didn't have all of the security things N PM has been doing
like the Python, the PSF when you're using
PP,
they're doing a lot of like two factor off and things like that.
And so I think
the universe has moved on. And so the thing I wonder
is our developers doing three X more time on security because they
want to or are they doing three X more time and security?
Because they have to,
I think it's a combination of two things.
One, they're having to do things like two fa and M fa
either setting it up or using it that, that eats up your time,
right?
And number two,
they're
doing a lot of compliance driven security.
The old pan SSF scorecard being a prime example of it
because there's what else can they do?
-- Like they're gonna make their own security program that would be worse
-- probably.
Well, they don't have the manpower. So, so
one thing I have seen happen is if you're a project, people will say like, oh,
your scorecard score is bad or this is bad or this is bad or an auditor said this and
sometimes even though you don't like or want to do
whatever thing it is they're claiming you should do,
you just do it to make it go away.
I mean, I do this all the time when I'm dealing with security reports at work
where it's like, all right, I've just justified this finding, you know,
10 times to 10 different customers.
Like I'm sick of it. It's stupid. Like let's just deal like let's fix it
even though it's just paper mache
over the hole.
I don't care. I'm sick of justifying this.
A great example is Jackson data bind has, you know,
lots of remote code executions in its
deser
it used to,
they fixed it kind of.
But anyways,
um satellite version five or six shipped it but did not use that never has never will.
-- Elastic,
-- did the same thing in elastic search
and customers would complain. And I'd be like, we don't use that code.
We will not use that code. We,
there's like no way for us to use that code. Like it doesn't do anything
and
it got to the point where you like, yeah,
we just need to update this so that they stop bothering us.
Yeah, we did that at elastic all the time.
We didn't use the, it was the, the polymorphic deser
routine
and that's a mouthful.
But I, I like, I will be,
I'm gonna be like old and senile someday and just saying the word polymorphic
deer,
it'll be like the guy can't say any other words,
but he keeps saying this one for some reason, he's
having flashbacks
for
Jay.
But, but the point is like, yeah, that was, that's a great example.
We get reports constantly saying, oh, you're,
you're vulnerable to these critical CV ES.
And it's like we're not using the code and like, can you prove it?
I'm like, actually I can because you have to
use these functions to be vulnerable, which if you search the source code,
they're not there.
And so the problem is you like we at Red Hat then
waste time upgrading and doing stuff we don't need to do.
But on the flip side, if you have 100 customers all wasting a couple hours
dealing with this because you just don't fix it,
then the answer is you just fix it because that's what
customers are paying you for is to make problems go away.
And so like, I'm of the mind where
Red Hat is paid, they should make their customers' lives happy.
But an open
source project that you're using for free.
No, they can do whatever they want. They can ignore you.
They, they can't though, rather they can ignore you. But then there's,
they get like harassed.
-- Yes.
-- And that's let me, let me find the graph. Uh
I'm, I'm dumb Kurt.
Yeah, honestly, even if I took screenshots,
I just would end up taking screenshots of every graph and had a document,
I still couldn't find anything in.
So let's I know what it looks like. Here it is
uh P
page 38.
It says not being financially compensated, blah, blah, blah,
top things maintainers dislike about their work.
Obviously not being compensated is number one unsurprisingly.
But then you've got number two is feel
underappreciated or like the work is thankless.
Adds to my personal stress, asked to comply with requirements.
I don't have, I mean, this is literally all the things we just talked about, right?
Users are too demanding and expect too much of me. Like,
although I will say I find it amusing that um
coming in at what 33% is reviewing codes
submitted by others with a narrow self interest.
-- Which,
-- well, but what else the users like? Why?
What is my economic incentive to make to add to this project?
-- Well, it's to fix any problem. I
-- have something I care about. Exactly,
you know.
Yes.
OK. I'm just gonna say it again at the STF.
We had a project asking for money and one of the
things they want to do is long term support releases.
And it's clear that essentially it's
two or three big companies that are involved in this project that essentially want
the STF to pay for LTs versions because they don't want to fund it.
Of
course,
it's just, it's pretty obvious that that's what's going on here
because, like, these are some major, like,
top five it companies,
you know,
guess which three they are?
-- Well or two in this case,
-- it's, it's hilarious to me sometimes how, like,
utterly penny pinching and cheap.
These, like Mega
Corps are that use all this over
sometimes.
And like, they want
an LTs version of this product because they're clearly using
it in production and they want it to just work.
Cool. Well, they can pay for that. Why? No, like,
nobody outside of them legitimately would want this
because the people running this for like,
or
it's cheaper, it is to try to,
to bike, to bamboozle the stf into paying for it.
Right.
And so that one, like, went
to the second last one and I actually, that's when I'm gonna, like,
die on that hill of like,
this is not a project that should be funded
but back to this. Yeah. I mean, why,
why would I get involved in a project to make the world a better place?
Like, there's like all,
there's very few people that are like that
and they're already involved in open source.
I don't think you can make that assertion that there's very few people,
I think the vast majority of people do want to make the world
a better place and they do things in an attempt to do so.
Granted, there are some people who probably don't,
although maybe it's just because their idea of a better place will say is the end,
a
modern society and maybe that's what it is.
But I think virtually every person I know is happy to volunteer and is happy to help.
Well, but also, I mean, maybe to make it a bit more nuanced, for example,
if they are paid,
their boss is not going to pay them to work
on features that their business does not need or want.
And that
often happens,
-- you know.
-- Well, OK, I I want to take AAA little diversion here on that note. And I think
when a company does open source, right,
that act like what the company wants
and what the open source project does.
I think if done correctly are the same thing and I'm going to use Sift
and Gripe at Anchor of this is we have these two pretty widely used projects,
Sift and Gripe Sift is an S bomb generator.
Gripe is a vulnerability scanner and we have purposely erected a firewall between
the enterprise side of the house and the open source side of the
house and the open source side of the house is allowed to do
their thing the way they want to do it.
We are but a community member in their community where we can file bugs.
Granted we can talk to them a little easier than others. Can.
But the view is that whatever like this team does we say for the community
and put community in air quotes like that is what is best for us.
And that is generally held true.
Well, can I offer a subtle,
you're essentially cheating and letting the market speak?
And,
but I, I think Red Hat was really good at this.
Also, back in the day
is they would just hire open source developers
And generally speaking,
they were told to develop an open source.
And there was not like, oh, we need this one feature granted.
Sometimes it was like, we really need a thing like help us out here.
-- But a lot
-- of those features were actually
-- reasonably good ideas.
-- Yeah, I agree.
But corporations did actually need
or there were bug fixes where there would be large
scale users of the software at Red Hat that,
you know, they're like, oh, like once every 50,000
operations, this thing like does a weird thing,
you know, that normal people won't run into.
And one nice thing is when you, when you hunt down and fix those bugs,
you invariably find a whole bunch of easier bugs
as well while you're looking through the code and solve those and, you know,
generally improve the software for sure.
I think part of this is is letting markets speak.
But also a good example of this is one reason I love wordpress
is because there's like three bajillion wordpress.
Developers and administrators. It's true, right? Like
I can literally throw a stick out my
front door and probably hit a wordpress developer.
Yes.
You know,
whereas if I build a framework or I do something in house,
well,
there's like those three people that understand how it works.
Yeah, for sure. For sure.
A lot of companies I think go into open source with we want this,
this and this and it's like, no, actually you don't want that what you want
and the way to do it is this, this and this and it will have like a very long term payoff.
But a very
like wordpress is a great example of like, yeah, it's 30% of the world's websites.
Yes. Yes. That's
even if they lose like 90% of their customers,
they'll still be limping along in 200 years,
-- didn't
-- they? They're the ones who are selling the 100 year domains, right?
Yeah.
But I mean, that's the thing, right? Like,
even if Wordpress shrinks by 90% that's still 3% of
the world's websites that's enough to run a business on.
Yeah. Yeah. Well, I mean, a lot of free users but whatever, you know, whatever
I want to keep going, I wanna keep going.
So
we mentioned XZ A while back and they have some graphs about XZ actually,
which are on page 43.
So
I, I found the first graph they have,
it says I'm less trusting a poor request from non maintainer contributors or
feel the need to vet them more carefully and the agreement is 66%.
But here's what I find funny about that, the JIA
Tan character who infiltrated XZ spent years building up
of horror with the, the author.
And so I, I ironically, 66% again, sixtyish percent who keeps coming up Dell,
people are gonna be like, oh, we're gonna, we're gonna investigate this,
this pull request that came in out of the blue versus
I have someone who's been working with me for three years and I'm going to trust them.
That's a tough one, you know.
Well, that, and that goes back to like we can't like if a project is like, Kurt,
I'm gonna need to see government ID to validate who you are.
I'm gonna be like, no,
I'm not going to participate in this or
like when Google had their insane blog entry about having a real name policy for open
developers. Like
that's, they're literally, that will have secondary effects.
Like there will be people that get killed or die because of that. Quite possible.
That's assuming that policy is even legal.
Like I'm pretty sure GDPR is gonna have harsh words with Google.
I'm pretty sure they aren't friends already. So
there's a lot of stuff that people propose as a solution or as a way to deal with this,
but
it's not that it won't work. It's that it's not physically possible. Right.
Like, and it won't work as well. Like it won't do what you want to do.
Right. Because
standing up sock puppets and making fake people is easy.
Like I just did it again yesterday for a project.
I'm not going to ask any questions about this. And
we're gonna,
anyway,
standing up a sock puppet and putting a one or two or three year history on it.
Especially now with the help of A I, like you can do this so efficiently it
is easier.
Well, remember the t-shirt thing where, uh,
what company was it that gave away t-shirts if
you got an open source pull request accepted,
I think that was Digital Ocean for Hot
HTO.
Yes, that's what it was. I remember all these open
source people are like, I'm getting flooded with BS poll requests
and Digital Ocean is like, oh, well, we'll make it so you can opt out and it's like, no,
that's not how this.
No.
Right.
Well, now you have to opt into
Heber
fest.
But
yes, like when things like that cause problems,
you think you can
do something to keep a nation state out. Well, you can't like,
you just can't
for sure, for sure.
And so I think that's part of the challenge here is we need to look at what is
like, what can we actually physically do to make things better then?
Will it work or not? And will it have like worse secondary effects.
Like, yes, we could.
My favorite always is like, people like you can check ID and I'm like, cool.
How do I tell if your ID is real or fake? I don't know what a real US passport looks like.
I think it has an eagle on the front.
-- I have one and I couldn't tell you.
-- I don't even know what color it is. It's,
it's,
yeah.
Right.
Like, oh,
the new Canadian passports just came out and when I first saw
them I thought it was like a mock up like a,
like a meme because it was so hideous.
And I'm like, oh, I'm glad I have the old one because the new one just looks stupid.
-- Does it have a maple leaf on it? Please tell me it has a maple leaf on it.
-- Oh, it's just,
uh, it's beyond,
-- um, we'll put
-- a link in the show
notes.
There's R slash passport porn. Of course, there is.
All right. Anyway, we're going to keep going.
So I wanna, I wanna kind of close this out here because we,
we've gone on and on about this.
I don't feel like we've said anything particularly dicey.
Well, I want to say some things where I think things are going to get a lot worse.
Please do.
And this is a two parter. So hold your question until the end.
The first part.
Is that
A I is here and A I generated poll requests and
A I generated bug reports and A I generated blah,
blah, blah.
-- The thing at the bottom about that
-- there's a ton of noise
but there's a second problem which is
in using A I, there's a huge generational divide where
the older people and I've, I've experienced this, like I see this in like, you,
you are like
a I ra ra ra ra,
no, no, I'm not against A I, I use it all the time. I'm against you. Selling out to A I.
There's a difference.
I, well, I view A I as like the next spreadsheet.
It's just, it's a massive tool that's,
you know, you don't
anyways.
So the problem is is that I don't want to call them Attackers, but in this situation,
we'll call it Attackers and defenders.
So the people using A I to generate poll requests and
all this other stuff are going to vastly overwhelm the,
the humans.
And maybe if these humans refuse to kind of use technology to help them,
they're going to get clobbered by poll requests by just all sorts of stuff.
And I fear that a lot of older maintainers are going to
potentially leave sooner rather than later as this
kind of coming A I tsunami happens.
Are you done because I can answer this?
OK. So first of all,
there is a graph about the age of maintainers and there's an age graph,
it's towards the bottom.
I've got to be, this is a big report. It's 63 pages. Like, ok, the, the age 58
there's those, those bell curves that are,
yeah, there's, they show the three Belker and they keep going.
They're, they're,
they're shifting.
And so first of all, most open source is old people.
So you can see there's a generational divide,
but I would say the more concerning generational divide is just the fact that
open source developers continue to age while
new people aren't getting to open source.
It's a population pyramid.
It
-- is,
-- it, it's a population pyramid, right?
Like I don't think it is because
if you look
and this is my suspicion. I asked um tide lift about this actually a long time ago,
if you look at that, their graph is shifting to the right?
Because when you and I were young,
it felt like all the open source people were my age now that I'm old.
It feels like all the open source people are my age. Like
I don't think that's a population graph.
I think open source is more popular with our particular age
group because we grew up in a time when it was
exciting and new and fun.
-- And
-- we've talked about this too, but like a lot of the,
it's hard to join a lot of these
big projects because they're so technically complex.
It can be. We did a whole podcast episode in this, didn't we?
I actually have data for this?
This is a recurring theme in the STF applications where about a solid half
or more of the STF applications are like who's going to do the work.
And it's us the core developers because this thing is so like there was this one,
it was um particle flow modeling, computational fluid dynamics, right CFD.
And they're like,
yeah, there's like three of us, we all have phd S,
we're the ones that are going to do the work
because
there's three of us that have phd
and we wrote the software and like, we're the ones that can do the work. Like it's,
I want to go back to your statement though about A I, OK.
So, first of all, everyone's old,
we're getting older and yes old people generally have trouble
accepting new technology that is like a well known,
I mean, Douglas Adams has that quote, right? Like not new. We all know this.
Now,
here's the thing with open source though is if a project
starts getting flooded with pull requests or bugs or something from,
from A I or whatever, they're just gonna,
they're either gonna quit or they're gonna turn it off.
That's what's gonna happen. There's no, like, secret option
where it's like, oh, we're gonna, we're gonna hold hands and sing and adopt a, I like,
if they don't want to, they won't,
and it's either gonna kill their project or they'll just turn it off.
And there's actually, uh, there's a podcast. I just listened to, I don't remember
which podcast it was, but it was, it was titled
Open Source, Not Open Contribution. And it was with,
I can't remember the project even now the guy was talking about it. It's not bad.
I will find a link and I will put it in the show notes
because it was, it's worth listening to. But like
this is like we the SQL, well, the, the SQL light,
the episode we've not yet released which everyone will hear at some point.
And Kurt's looking at me like, yes, Kurt, that's right. It hasn't gone out yet. Uh
-- We recorded it a while back.
-- I don't, did we ever talk about SQL Light?
Oh, don't actually they have this exact conversation.
It was on the change log, I think is the name of the podcast. Anyway,
there are open source projects that like, I want to do this work.
I want it to be open source,
but I am completely unwilling to take pull request
from other people because I just don't want to,
I can't be bothered
and like there's nothing wrong with that.
-- That's still open source and you can do that
-- well,
and you can fork it and have your own version.
And a perfect example is,
is YT downloader didn't fix a bug or rather they sort of fix the bug and get,
I feel like we need a Bingo card and YT downloader because I every episode Kirk.
Well, but this is a good example of,
they've now gone something like two years with the software being broken.
And so youtube downloader is
the fork replacement of it that's very active and very
well maintained now and everybody moved on to it.
That's
great. That's how open
source work. You know,
it's not ideal, but
I am able to download entire youtube channel
easily for my son and also to back up the CS A stuff
anyway. Ok.
Ok.
But back to the, but the thing is I think it's more subtle than just poll request.
It's things like comments and issues or it's things like
it's essentially the problem is as a human developer,
you have at most 24 hours in a day.
I think people
feel tricked and feel cheated when they interact with an A I thinking it's a human,
right?
Like if somebody submits a poll request or submits an issue that was
like A I generated and is maybe not of the highest quality.
The reality is humans have a very finite amount of time and it's going to eat it up. And
the maintainers are already vastly saying that like, I don't have a ton of time,
I don't have a ton of energy.
I,
I'm struggling, I feel like quitting.
And a great example is I'm not going to say the name but the person
who submitted that bad pandas CV E request where pandas can read etc passwords.
And it's funny because I was having this discussion with other Josh
and I was like,
etc password is a CS V file except with full Collins instead of Commas.
And he's like, what I'm like, go look at it and he's like, oh,
yeah, it is. I'm like, and if I was going to open a big, etc, password in Python,
I would use Pandos
because
it's
the library to open big CS V files.
And so
I don't think this person was malicious.
I don't think they, I think they honestly,
I suspect what happened is they found that issue in a context
where it looked like a security issue and didn't realize that.
Well, in that context, it could be a problem. But
as Pandas is meant to be, it has to read files and if you can read the file,
you can read the file,
um, because they deleted the get repo with the,
the vulnerability and all that stuff.
-- I
-- think, II, I think I forked it just because I was like, this is going to get deleted.
-- Yeah.
-- Yeah. If you iii I would appreciate a copy of that.
Actually, I, I'll check, I'll check if I still have it.
But this is a good example of like,
what if people start using A I to generate a ton of CV E requests?
And that'll like, that'll crush the CV project and it's
all right. We're, we're, we're off in the weeds and
I want to end this on a hot take. Ok?
You brought up a really good point
and you're talking about overwhelming developers,
they're already overwhelmed.
And the reality is most people start open source projects because it's fun.
Right.
-- Well,
-- or they need to scratch an itch.
Right. It. Right.
Uh Well, it, and it's fun to solve problems, right? Like engineers solve problems.
That is what engineers do.
I'm going to say that a big reason this
has become so hard and people aren't having fun anymore
is because of github.
And the reason being
when open source was a CS V repository,
I was hosting off of some website at my university.
I had a Readme file and in the Readme file,
it said if you have a problem or a bug just send me an email.
No one sent emails because it was hard and annoying.
And I didn't want to opening an issue in github.
Very easy, sending a pull request, very easy. So that is my
hot take
on all of this.
I want to add a comment to that, I think because it's in github,
-- it looks every project looks much bigger and more professional than it is
-- also true.
Yes. And people have that expectation that this is kind of a corporate capable like,
well, and that's just it like random project in my github.
And I have like hundreds of github
repositories,
half of which are like started and not working open source projects in some way
versus,
you know, some sort of like Apache Foundation project or Python or something.
Linux, the Linux kernel
that is a real actual project with people running it.
They are not the same.
All right, I'll give you the last word on this one. Make it quick.
I think open source maintainers need to start putting their foot down
and actually, maybe not quitting, but you know what,
maybe quite quitting and just preach it.
Not, not be so nice and not be so accommodating
because quite bluntly, if a large company actually needs to use your software,
they can fork it and maintain their own fork.
And if that's too expensive and too much hassle for them,
then
that's too bad
for them.
-- That's not a you problem.
-- Agreed. All right. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to social security podcast.com of the show,
not TZ Pound do says podcast hashtag on Mastodon.
Kurt. Have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye.