Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
Now we're back to Thought Crime again.
-- Well, I mean, uh, we're not allowed to go outside anymore. So,
-- yeah,
kind of.
-- It's complicated anyway, actually,
-- it's not complicated.
There's actually two really simple solutions, but, well,
we all know what happened with those.
Anyways,
-- moving along on to happier topics.
-- Are there happier topics, uh,
puppies?
I, oh, man. So, ok. Ok. I'm gonna plug puppies for a minute because
I, I do have a dog who's big and stupid and, and awesome and, and we love him,
but there is a Twitter account called We rate Dogs.
And it is the best thing ever. I love, we rate dogs.
A, what about, I don't know, the Twitter account,
the raccoons that will cure your sadness.
-- I've never heard of this one. It
-- is, it's, it's, yeah, it is what it said it is.
And there's my favorite one so far is an older gentleman
sitting outside in the cold with a giant tub of hot dogs
and there's like 20 or 30 raccoons around him and they're
all enormously fat raccoons and he's just feeding them hot dogs.
I mean, that
-- sounds pretty awesome to me
-- except
-- for the rabies. But you know,
-- send me, send me,
send me that link. I'll put it in the show notes. I've never seen this before.
It's nice. This is what qualifies for a podcast now.
Yeah, pretty much.
We gotta do something, man.
All right. So we want to talk about GSD today, the Global Security Database. Yeah.
Which also in hindsight was a terrible hashtag to choose because German
Shepherd dogs beat out us 100% of the time on Twitter.
-- I don't know.
-- OK. Look. All right.
I'm putting my foot down right now.
You keep making a big deal about something that is
or isn't going to be a hashtag on social media.
And I think if you're planning anything about your project based upon Twitter,
hashtags
the, you're setting yourself up for just abject failure.
I would agree.
But also because Twitter is for old people,
I think all the new people are on what the tiktok and the Instagramming or
-- I
-- don't
-- mostly tiktok, I think.
No, I, I, no, no, I think from the concept of the, the infosec world, Twitter is
unfortunately the most important place you can be.
It shouldn't be, but it is, which I think Lord for J proved that.
Well, and this leads into the show, which is, well, what's the alternative?
We don't have one
and Well, that's where the global security database comes in.
-- The
-- alternative is thoughts and prayers today.
But we're gonna fix that. We're gonna make thoughts and prayers. Number three.
But I'm an
atheist
thoughts and prayers will be number three when we're done. That's the plan.
All right. So, anyway, all right.
-- Uh, send me that link because I'm still waiting for
-- it.
-- But
-- I
can't
find it.
-- What?
-- Oh,
my goodness.
Look,
your homework for the rest of the week is to find me that link.
I need it.
I'm
trying to
find
my mental health. Depends on it at this point.
Anyway,
Global Security Database.
I'm going to start telling the story while Kurt looks for this link
and then sends it to me
and we'll get, we'll, we'll get back to that later.
So, all right. So anyone who's been listening to the show for any period of time
knows that Kurt and I
were involved in this project long ago called Distributed Weakness and Filing.
We even did a whole episode on this when it was resurrected again.
I don't know, like a year or two ago, what happened is
Kirk created DWF long, long ago
DWF was
killed and it was meant to be,
-- uh,
-- killed. Is it, it just sort of died?
-- Yeah,
-- it's, it's complicated.
Well, the first one just sort of died.
The second one was killed.
The second one was not killed. The second one proved a point.
We'll get to that we'll get to that. All right. So first one happens, right.
Meant to be kind of community powered CV E for open source stops.
It's resurrected for a variety of reasons which we
actually have a whole podcast about we go into
and
I'll, I'll put a link to the old DWF podcast.
It's, I don't know, a year to go a year, two years, whatever, it doesn't matter.
Right.
So, basically,
what happens is the second reboot of DWF was
meant to be throwing down the gauntlet of attempting to
salvage what could be salvaged from CV E.
And we'll say
when the CV E board tried to get me fired from my job,
it became obvious that there was no way
to salvage what was there.
And this is when we moved on. And it's actually a good thing I think because we have
an immense amount of freedom now.
Well, and one thing for the timeline is I, I actually had resigned from the board
prior to us kind of really pushing the DWF two point. Oh,
-- yeah.
-- And that's, that's in the
podcast, which in hindsight, I'm s I'm so glad I did
because
the right, otherwise you would have had to sign that, that mean letter,
that threatening letter signed
by
my previous company. It was signed by the CV E board,
like talk to me on Twitter. I'll explain it anyway.
So then
the Cloud Security Alliance basically says we're interested in
this project and we knew we needed a name.
So we picked something called UV, I,
which was universal vulnerability identifier.
Ok.
That's,
that's
a,
I hated that name so much.
So he picked that knowing it was bad and it had to be changed.
There wasn't a lot of anything that happened for a while.
There's a lot of putting,
it's surprisingly difficult to stand up like these working groups and get all the,
the right pieces in place and get the right people involved.
Well, it's critical mass.
Yeah, it's, I don't even think it's no critical mass comes next.
Like that's what we're working on now.
Just getting the right pieces in place, getting mailing list, set up, getting
the, the, what is it circle group, whatever that thing is CS A uses
getting the right structure in place,
getting people from the CS A as part of the working group.
There's what the charter had to be written. There's, it's,
it's one of those things that like
when I want to create a new open
source project, I just created github
Revo and I'm like, oh, here it is open
source project
and this is nothing like that. And
it,
I forget sometimes how much work some of this stuff is. So anyway,
we spent almost a year just putting up getting everything in place,
doing the right thing,
figuring a whole bunch of stuff out.
And now
it is what the, the 19th of, of January 2022 yesterday,
we had like the inaugural kickoff public meeting for the
global Security Database with the CS A and I,
I must say
I am tickled pink by the fact that 44 people were on that meeting for an hour.
I, I literally expected like seven people plus
us.
Well,
and what was even better is some of them
actually cared and had good questions and concerns a
lot
of them
stuff.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah,
I was II I, I'm tickled pink, 44 people that's
exceeded all of my expectations. I, I feel like
we are in a place where everyone is starting
to recognize the importance of everything we need to do
and
we don't even have to explain the why, which is awesome.
-- So, but we will, I'll let you do that part because I just talked a lot. What is the
-- why?
It's really simple. We need a mapping of,
well, not just a mapping. We need a source of vulnerability data
for software and services and hardware and,
-- well, basically everything
-- just vulnerabilities
because for two reasons and this is the part for people,
forget they only usually think about the first reason which is, oh,
I need to know what I'm running and what's
what the vulnerabilities in the stuff I am running is
so that I can like go patch them and stuff
and that don't get me wrong. That that is important.
But the number two thing is so that developers can learn
and maybe
stop making the same mistakes or even better
build tools that don't make the mistake.
So a great example of this is, you know,
you had that presentation where you went through the
top 10
and you're like, it's actually three things and it was, what was it remind me?
It was use a framework.
It was like use a framework, use authentication from
like someone else that's good. A K A use a framework and use
crypto.
It was
no, I think that fell under. Don't roll your own off.
-- It was basically
-- the majority of it boiled down to pick a good framework and use
that.
-- Yeah, that's basically it, which
-- is like, that's exactly it.
Like the same thing with,
well, like the web servers. No, you pick one, don't write your own,
you know.
And so like,
because we're seeing this in the crypto world
where people are making all these horrific mistakes.
And it's kind of like,
oh, you mean this thing that has been a documented, like
software issue for 50 years?
Like, and what I love is even better yet,
like the Ethereum dow hack way back in the day.
There was like a specific article of concern about that re entr
the attack like two years in advance
and re entr
the attacks are, again, that's been something that's been known for decades,
industry
like, you know, but because it's not well documented and it's not well understood.
People don't think about this, like,
how many developers still don't understand SQL injection
-- in, in a web world? And the answer is like, there, there's
-- a bunch.
Exactly.
Why should they,
you know, that's my argument. They shouldn't have to
-- care.
-- Actually, I would argue. Exactly. They, it's like
they should just be using frameworks that are so safe
that they don't even have to think about it.
-- I
-- mean, let me, here's a great example
at what temperature do your brake pads stop functioning in your car.
You don't know, you don't care. It doesn't matter.
-- Well, it does if it hits minus 50 you slam on the brakes.
-- Well,
I was just thinking heat, I didn't even consider the fact that the cold affects them,
-- but
-- you're probably right.
My brakes were actually squealing a bit the other day because
I washed my car and so the disc rotors got wet,
froze.
So there's like a thin, it turns out when there's a thin layer of ice on your rotors,
-- it's probably fine. I'm sure it's fine.
-- It cooked off.
It would be
fine.
Unlike that Tesla was shipped without a brake pad
anyways. But so,
so the problem is because we don't have this kind of inventory.
We don't like,
there are often times where I'm like, oh, this is a big problem and they're like, no,
it's not.
And I'm like, yes it is. I'm like, cool, show me the data I'm like, uh
it's
a big
problem. So we're, we're kind of pontificating in a silly direction.
But I think fundamentally what this all comes down to is
in the world of vulnerability identifiers.
There's, the data is pretty bad.
-- A lot of it is very pros, it's, it often has a lot of
-- errors. It's self
-- selected it.
-- Yeah, it's very self
selective.
Like an easy example is if I find a vulnerability in, let's say,
Windows and Microsoft says we,
we claim that's not a vulnerability that's pretty much the end.
-- And that's not right.
-- Well, and it's 10 times worse with the bug bounty programs now.
Buying silence.
Oh yeah, totally. That's a different, that's a different problem.
And we, we won't worry about that at the moment.
But fundamentally what it comes down to is this data is hard to update.
It's hard to acquire, it's hard to parse and
it, it honestly, it shouldn't be this, this hard to fix it.
And so this is basically what the GSD is, is going to do.
Yeah, it's actually worse. It's not hard to update.
It's impossible to update because basically
there are private sources of data where
I don't think you can get those realistically updated.
And then there's only one public.
So like there's only one real public source of data which is CV E,
there are obviously certs and other things, but
their data sets are so fragmented
and, and it's, it's pros like this isn't, this isn't well formed machine data.
This is just like crap Humans wrote,
which is literally the worst possible kind of data.
OK. So I'm done with the why?
What are we doing about it now? And this is the story of GSD.
What GSD is doing is, is kind of simple in a way. It's, it's 2022
and we have some well-established technologies and processes for having
large projects
that have large data sets that get updated and that is get
and well github because it's free to post,
you know.
Um And then
JSON
data,
well, I would, I would even go
well. And then the process is very simple in that
it's in git.
So like no matter how bad, we kind of make a mess of things,
we can always roll it back or fix it
well.
And, and look,
I think more importantly is what we want to do is create a community driven project
that
exists under the Cloud Security Alliance umbrella.
So this isn't like 11 government, there's not a company,
this is a, a very
public and open space.
And the intent is to use all of the process and knowledge and techniques
that open source has taught the world over the last what like 30 plus years
and apply this to vulnerability data.
Because fundamentally at the moment,
all of the vulnerability data is walled garden
and that is not helping anyone.
It makes me sad that in the like security scanner space,
your ability to parse this data
and then make decisions of it is seen as a competitive advantage.
That's bananas, that should not be a competitive advantage. This is public data.
And that's actually a really good point that I often
don't think of because just consuming this data is a nightmare
like one quarter,
like there's just all the data sets conflict and
the data within the data sets conflicts.
There's not a lot of standards around how the data is provided.
There's errors in the data, you know.
And
luckily we are seeing some changes like you know, with like uh in the ruby world,
we have like what is it yarn?
Auditor yard
bundle, whatever and it automatically kind of scans.
No Ruby is gem yarn is N PM.
Yeah, Ruby gems and it automatically scans and will tell you like, hey,
you just build something with a bunch of security vols.
Do you want to do something about it or just forcibly ignore it? Cool.
But like now, you know, and knowing is half the battle, right?
Um
But you're right, like even just consuming the data is hard
and
yeah, traditionally,
there's been no way to update the data or
append or amend or improve or correct the data.
If, if you do spot up an obvious error,
you know something as simple as like I,
I literally managed to the colors dot Js thing.
I managed to
spell it wrong.
I used color dot Js instead of with the S which, well, that's not the name.
Like if you plug that into N PM, you, that's not what it is.
And so
a module named color because N PM has like
every English word has been taken at this point.
-- Yeah.
-- Well, there's like 3 million NP MS.
So what is color? It's something else
this actually
used to happen to me all the time when I would deal with vulnerability
reports where customers would run it against a product I was responsible for.
And for example, there would be a Java package and a node package with the same name.
And so there'd be a vulnerability in one of them,
but the scanners couldn't tell the difference and so
they would just treat them as the same.
Yeah.
I, it's funny when I saw that the OS V data format had the ecosystem and I'm like,
oh yeah, that's, yeah.
Well, yeah, like a wordpress package with the same name as an M PM package are two
totally different things.
-- Right.
-- And, and we were running on
-- and the fact that we're still figuring that out is like,
I'm just hitting my, you know, my head on the desk.
It's like, good God, this should not be this hard to fix.
Well. Ok. No, no, no. Look,
the problem is, I think we have kicked this can down the road for more than a decade.
Because what we had while everyone can acknowledge
at this point is lacking in many ways,
it was good enough and no one wanted to do the work to fix it because let's face it.
This is some crap work and it's hard to do and it's not exciting.
This isn't the kind of stuff that's going to get you on the front page of a magazine.
This is, but it's, it's foundational and important.
Yep. Like collecting weather data.
Yeah. Right. Exactly.
And, and look there, I know weather nerds that love this stuff and like,
God bless you all.
I'm not one of them.
Well,
what I mean is you actually have to collect all the data
for a very long time for it to be of any use.
-- Right? But
-- there's people who love this.
I mean, I, I have a neighbor with a weather station on the roof of his garage and it,
like, don't ask
that man about weather, you know,
but, and, and God bless them.
Like, at the same time, I would say we are vulnerability nerds. We love this data.
We love processing it. I mean,
I have a project in my spare time where I parse public CV E data
and look for patterns and, and lessons in it.
Who does that?
You know, weirdos. That's who.
But that's ok.
Now we want to give the vulnerability nerds
a place to go and there was nowhere to go before this.
No and well, and the few places there were to go had a really,
really sharp learning curve and steep on ramp.
Like there was no gentle way to get involved.
And that's something else the GST I want to fix is I wanna have like,
easy on ramps to get involved in this.
Like,
if you literally just want to correct a one word typo or like a one character typo.
Yeah. Here we'll make it as easy.
Like you don't even have to fix it, just submit an issue.
-- Yeah,
-- exactly.
-- This should be that easy.
-- And, and so this is, it's funny because
I remember back in the day
when I think it was Steve Ballmer made a comment about, oh, and open source.
Like anyone can just show up and contribute code
and like
he saw it as a negative, but everyone open source was like, yeah,
anyone can show up and contribute code.
And it was funny because you and I think the vulnerability world is very similar.
It's like, oh, how will we know the date is correct?
It's like, how do we know the data
now is correct? We know it's full of mistakes. We know it's hard to understand.
We know it's hard to parse. Don't pretend like this data is magic.
The data we have today is crap.
And honestly, I'm skeptical we can do worse.
Well,
one thing I'm wondering is virtually every security researcher
I've talked to has at least one story of,
I tried to push this vulnerability, you know,
nicely to this company and they denied it
and, you know what I give up
and I suspect,
I kind of wonder, does everybody have that story?
I suspect the answer is yes. It's absolutely yes.
You know, and it's kind of like that left handed bagpipe repairman thing.
It turns out the village is full of them.
You know, we just never had a message board to talk about on.
I don't, I don't know what that means.
So, like you think you're rare,
you think you're the only one that's had this experience
with this vendor and it turns out that no,
-- that's, this is
-- no.
Wait, how does it have to do with left handed bagpipes though?
I don't, I don't understand that reference.
Well,
like there's right-handed bag pipes and left-handed bag pipes
are there left handed bag pipes are more rare,
are they?
I don't know,
I don't know. It's a, it's at this hour is 22 minutes reference.
I don't know what that is either. It's a Canadian comedy show.
It's really good.
But yeah, so that's the thing.
It's like, like this log for J thing, you know, initially,
like it was kind of played up as being really terrible.
Uh turns out it was actually kind of worse,
you know, but it was, it was on Twitter of all things. And thank goodness that hashtag
-- like that hashtag did the coordinate and heavy lifting,
-- which is bananas.
I mean, you figure between the hashtag and
gassy, the dog
that was basically the log for J coordinate.
I mean, just what
I still don't even know.
I just keep thinking how much worse it could have been.
You know, it's, it's, well,
it's kind of like log for Jay is like one of those events
like freezing rain where it kind of just affects everybody a little bit.
It's just sort of a universal thing, you know, it's not like a car crash.
It's just like everybody has slippery slide walks now, go deal with it. Good luck.
It affected a lot of people a
-- lot.
-- Well, but you know what I'm saying? Right.
Like, it wasn't some singular incident. It was,
it was like, it was like a hurricane versus a tornado.
Yeah. Yeah. Right. Because tornadoes have a narrow path of destruction.
Whereas hurricanes are enormous.
It's like the state of Florida.
Right. Right. That is fair. I agree with that.
And,
and this is also the more normal thing because,
well,
it turns out
we deployed these web apps that, uh, well, it
pulls in some stuff. Who cares?
Well, the problem is that some stuff is now like 1000 dependencies deep.
Yeah, that's one of the things that, so I, I have another side project.
I'm gonna, I'm going to give some talks on this at some point, but I took the top, like,
130 containers in Docker hub.
And I, I yanked out all of the dependencies. I basically ran.
There's these two scanners called sift and Gripe that
anchor creates sift is an S bomb generator.
Gripe is a vulnerability scanner.
I pulled down the containers. I scanned them with sifting gripe.
I put the data into elastic search and then I started looking at it.
Guess how many dependencies the, the worst?
I, I guess, I don't know if I'd call it the largest container.
-- I don't w worst
-- defender. I'm gonna go with order of magnitude higher. 10,000,
-- 3000, you're pretty close. So
-- within 1000 and 10,000,
like
that's,
-- that's three zeros,
-- that's a lot of packages in one container.
-- Do I
-- dare ask which language? All of
them?
I,
I don't remember the name of it off the top of my
head and I'm not going to look it up right now,
but I mean, most of them are in the neighborhood of 200 ish give or take.
But you,
I mean,
that's a lot of stuff though.
-- I
-- mean, it depends on how often it gets updated and how we see this update.
Like, and again,
that's part of the problem is some of
the stuff updates pretty easy without breaking stuff.
Well, it also depends on what you're using.
Like, for example, the alpine container has almost nothing in it.
Whereas a Debbie and a redhead container is kind of big and there's a lot of stuff. So
it, it's this weird dance we're doing right now with all this container,
everything.
But anyway, it doesn't matter. OK.
So in the time we have left, I want to talk about kind of
how,
how a listener who's interested can get involved in working
with GSD because I think part like we want help
anyone, even if all you have are ideas or you,
you want to ask some questions or like literally
anything you can contribute is a positive. So how are we doing this?
And all these links will go on the show note.
So don't worry about trying to write anything down.
So if you really want to get involved, you know, join the mailing list,
join the circle group, you know,
follow or what is it star us or follow fork or whatever on
github
if you, if you want to be involved, but like not get involved involved,
like just throw issues at us in
github.
You know, like if, if you spot a flaw in the data,
just file an issue against that file
and run away, that's fine.
You know, like literally just say like there's,
there's a typo there or that thing is wrong or
you know, Zabi
is spelled Zabi,
not
Zabi,
literally, you know, it just something as small as that, you know,
but these errors do matter because that,
that CP data no longer works because there is no Zabi
that's right. That's right.
And so now I, I wanna part of this, I wanna kind of explain what we're doing.
So, what Kurt's talking about is
there was a AC pe added by the NVD project.
NVD adds C pe data to all of the CD ES which is complicated and weird,
but basically they, they misspelled something
now getting them to update it is difficult.
Not that I'm saying we shouldn't try and we want to get it done.
-- But
-- how do you actually get the NVD to update stuff? You have to
email them
and hope,
thoughts and prayers.
And so basically what we've done is we've taken,
we have a mirror of all this data in GSDGSD is
specifically designed to be able to be compatible with CV E.
So you can just literally change CV E to GSD in an ID
and you can find it.
And so now we can add a note basically to the, the, the data
from NVD that says
actually this is the right C pe name, not what's in the NVD data.
And that takes seconds to do which is great
and more to the point, it's transparent and open.
Like if you file an issue with us, you, you can know that we're ignoring you versus
like knowing if your email got there or not.
Right. Right. And, and who is working on it? Who did the update?
Where did it come from?
There is a lot going on
did somebody else already file this
too.
That's something that always drove me nuts is all
these places where I want to report an issue.
But it's like somebody must have reported this.
Right.
Well, maybe, I don't know. You know, should I, should I bother? Will they fix it?
I don't know. You know,
and then by the time I sort of try to figure out how to contact them, it's like,
you know what, I, I could go have a sandwich
and sandwiches usually when
I will agree with that.
But no, seriously, right.
This should be this like think about how much work it is to file a bug in open source.
And
it should be about actually less work than that because we don't need to
know what run time you are or what version of the software you're running.
It's just like
you spotted a problem, let us know
bing done,
right?
Or even better
-- submit a pull request with the change you want to see,
-- be the change you want to see,
right?
And now I, I will say
how we're going about doing a lot of this is still in flux because
we want to have community discussions around what the data format should look like,
how we want to structure the data, how we provide updates to things.
And so there's kind of a lot going on
and I mean, this is again where we, we want people to help us answer these questions,
you know, come and participate in the discussion and, and ask questions and,
and give your opinions because
there's no right or wrong way for any of this stuff.
I mean, this is, this is how open source works.
Open source works because of participation. Not because you have,
you know,
two hour meetings every week and then no
one makes decisions and everyone just complains about.
No, no, like just do the work meetings are not where work happens.
And that's the beauty too is you can very easily just fork the repo
and do your own experimentation. And then, you know, come back to us with
like, show us because like, I, I've invented, you know, a vulnerability
json format
and it's terrible because I invented it and
wasn't able to get much input from anybody. So I did what I needed and well,
it turns out what I needed was wrong for myself, let alone other people,
you know, that start though.
Exactly. And so that's the beauty is, you know, it's,
we also see,
and this is the other trick is there
have been open source vulnerability databases in the past
and they all fall into the monetization trap of,
-- well, trying to monetize
-- here's the difference.
And I want to uh we probably should have talked about this in the very beginning.
But fundamentally,
this is why the Cloud Security Alliance is involved because if a,
if a company is behind this data
what you end up with is like, you can be altruistic at the beginning,
but generally speaking,
you're gonna see a lack of involvement because let's face it.
If I'm a competitor or I'm,
you know, involved in some other way,
I'm gonna be hesitant to be working with you a
lot because you're gonna benefit from my hard work.
Right?
And so when you have something like the Cloud Security Alliance,
the Cloud Security Alliance
knows there's never going to be money made off this. They know that
the intent isn't to make money.
And I think that's the difference between foundations
and companies and to date every single vulnerability
data set that has existed that I'm aware of has been part of a company.
And I think that is why they have all failed
and let's face it. The only reason CV E works
is because the Federal Government of the United
States is literally throwing money onto the fire
like that's it.
Yeah. No, it's interesting to see and it's,
I also want to build this so that intentionally it's not that oh,
companies can use this if they want.
No, no, I want companies to strip mine this
and I want companies to use this and also maybe never give back because,
well, it's gonna happen whether I like it or not
-- and if we're even remotely successful
-- and, and look, here's the thing, this is,
this is just like open source, let's say 5% of the users give back and that's it.
But that's ok.
That's also where you can run into some scale where if you,
if you have four users and one gives back, yeah, that kind of sucks.
But if you have 10 million users
and 5% give back, like
that's a pretty big number of people, you know,
and I think that's the key and that's the thing, you need to understand that a lot of,
a lot of the vulnerability databases to date have not.
-- And they haven't made it easy to give back.
-- Well, that too. Exactly.
I double dog dare anybody to go and try and
update a vulnerability in any other vulnerability data set.
Uh That's not true. Some of the, like Ruby and,
and Python data sets
are very public and usable.
Ok. Well, I, I don't. Yeah. Ok. Yeah.
II,
I was talking more about the sort of general data
-- sets like the commercial vendors
-- or here's the thing to remember
is the only reason like Ruby and Python are doing their
own thing is because they gave up on everything else.
-- Well, there's no other option.
-- No, there isn't.
And so they were just like, screw it. I'll do it myself.
And that sucks too because now how much infrastructure
are they trying to take care of and maintain
-- to support this endeavor?
-- Right.
Well, and the duplication of effort too, that's what really drives me nuts. Is
all these companies with all these data sets that all sort of overlap and not really.
But man, I'd really rather just have one good data set.
I agree.
Yeah. So come join us. It's easy.
It's going to be easy. There's a lot of work to do.
I'm not going to pretend we have all the answers or all the hard work has been done.
There is an enormous amount of work and
obviously,
one of the advantages of getting in early is
you can have a dramatic effect on whatever's happening.
One of the disadvantages is
you have to do a lot of the work.
It's still
uh
-- it's, yeah, we're still in the pioneer phase.
-- So I, I mean, I don't know, I guess
this is,
we just spent what, half an hour advertising for our project,
which I guess is part of the fun of having a podcast.
But yeah, I mean, I mean, in all seriousness,
like we're completely serious if you're listening, tell your friends this is,
you know, we've, we've never, we don't ask much of the people who listen,
we don't ask for your likes or your subscribes, we're just happy to have you.
But like in all seriousness in this particular instance,
if you know anyone who you think could be, could benefit from
the global Security database or anything going on in this space, like by all means,
please, please, please point them in the direction of GSD
because I think this is one of those projects that we desperately need
and it cannot fail.
Well, I,
yeah,
yeah, because I mean, we, we've tried everything else and it's been, well,
-- here we
-- are.
I don't know if anyone's tried anything else. It's,
I
think
i, it's complicated.
But anyway, so anyway, there we have it. I'm gonna call this one.
Let us know what you think. Send us emails. Hit us up on Twitter.
Join the mailing list for GSD.
I'm gonna put a bunch of links in the show notes and I'm excited. I
again,
44 people in that call. I expected seven. So I'm still just like ecstatic.
I'm like it, it feels like it's happening, which is awesome.
All right. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you very much for listening.
Go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up our show, not it Sud
Pound Os S Podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You
-- too. Stay safe, everybody.
-- Yeah.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye bye.