Hello and welcome to the open source Security podcast episode 138 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
-- Josh Pressers.
-- I can feel the spring in the air. Kurt. It's, it's coming.
Yeah, it was actually above zero. It hit plus eight yesterday.
And I assume you're talking about
Celsius
-- and not the lovable Fahrenheit scale we use in the United States
-- 46
°F.
That's solid man.
Yeah, I think that's,
that, that's pretty good.
That's warmer than it's been where I live and you live way north of me.
So,
yeah. No, it was beautiful yesterday.
Nice. That's awesome, man.
-- Unlike the world of security, which is beautiful.
-- Right.
Well, and what I love is the world of security is bad enough.
But then when you get sort of, I, I guess I hate to, I hesitate to say normal people,
but when you get sort of normal people interfacing with it,
it, it tends to just go to excuse of expression, good,
tends to go to hell in a hand basket, you know, good intentions at all.
And I, I think this first story is a, is a really great example of that.
And what is the first story?
Apparently the Japanese police arrested some Japanese girl
for spreading
malicious code.
Said malicious code is a well known,
uh javascript snippet that basically loops a pop up
and won't let you close the pop up.
Yeah,
like,
and I get it, those are super annoying and I,
I,
yeah,
I have all sorts of things to prevent that crap on my computer, but
they actually arrested her.
I mean, but it's kind of one of those things like, where's that line between,
you know,
me hosting and spreading malicious code and it just being like an annoying ha ha.
You know,
so
I, you know what I love about this story. Do you remember
the inception of the Rick roll?
Yes,
it is. This right.
It was, there was a website called Internet is Serious business.com
and you'd go to it and it would start playing
the,
the Rick roll video in the background and then have
just constant pop ups that you couldn't get rid of.
And the web browsers actually didn't have a way
to make them go away and you could never close the tab.
The only the way out was to kill the whole web browser.
It was, do we even have tabs back then?
I don't even tabs might not have even been a thing. I don't remember.
No, I literally would have multiple browsers open,
-- right?
-- I remember those days, man, or remember the X 10 pop under ads. It's
so, anyway, anyway, I don't want to,
-- I want ads were
-- literally the
worst.
They were great.
I
remember, I close my browser and there'd be like, 45 X
or you
wondering,
-- like, I'm from,
-- well, I just remember, like,
why is my computer performance sucking?
Right. And you open up
whatever your command explorer and you're like, what, like,
I didn't open up 50 browser windows.
It was beautiful. It was beautiful. I loved it. I loved it.
Ah, the good old days, right? Like everything was better then.
Anyway, here is my thought on this is we talked in the last show about how
regulation and kind of government intervention is one of the
few ways people are going to actually start to care
and then
-- the government does this
-- well,
so I think there's an important distinction to be made between
the regulators that is the people making policy and then the people
enforcing policy because part of the problem is right now,
they don't have good policy to enforce.
It is very true.
You know. So they're kind of winging it. They're doing the best they can.
And it's like, well, let me put it this way.
Somebody goes outside your house at three in the morning every day and,
and starts screaming for an hour.
Is that illegal? Should it be illegal? I mean, it's
disturbing the peace.
There are noise ordinances, at least in my town
and yeah, you can't do that. Ok.
So what if they just stand outside your house and they play a kazoo
-- for an hour?
-- It would defend how loud it is.
The, the noise ordinance is quite specific about the decibel level and, and look
if, if a crazy person wants to stand at my house and play a kazoo,
I can call the police and it's conceivable, the police can't do anything about it.
But kind of, there's two ways I'd look at this
is
I, you can ignore them or like maybe spray them with your hose.
Well, then that's assault
-- or battery
-- rather. What if it's an accident? I accidentally sprayed them.
Well, see, and part of the thing though is the cops can issue a lawful order.
Like, please move along, sir.
And then if they don't do that, then boom, you're resisting.
That's
fair.
That's probably fair.
You know.
But anyway, we're talking about playing kazoos and the reality is that a young girl
pulled a prank, let's face it.
It's basically a prank and she got in trouble for it and I have
a feeling this is half the police not having a freaking clue what they're doing
and half she probably ticked off the wrong person by
doing this because that's usually how pranks go wrong.
Right.
Yeah.
Well,
it's like those what Nigerian call scammers that phoned the
former head of the CIA and he actually was like,
or was it the former head of the FBI or something right there.
It's in the news right now.
And so he actually called a bunch of his
buddies and they investigated and arrested these people,
which, ok, great. So if we can do that, why can't we do that to all of these scammers?
Uh because we're not like former heads of the FBI,
it's not cost effective, right? Like, you know, I hate to say it.
So, um this reminds me. So I was in San Francisco for Rs A
and I, I think I agree with a lot of people that,
you know, San Francisco is,
I, I don't know what's going on there.
But uh so Friday night, we were walking down um Folsom Street
and within the space of two blocks,
we saw three people smoking crack cocaine on the street
-- and
-- that does not surprise me
and the cops were out and around.
It's not like there were no cops around and, and I was thinking like, if I was a cop,
what would I do?
Arrest these people for possession or whatever?
-- And, and then
-- what you do almost nothing.
Yeah.
Well, and I was thinking like,
what could I do that would have any meaningful benefit or change?
And I don't think there is
anything really
-- that the police could do in this situation.
-- No, there's nothing the police can do.
And this is,
I think this is related to this particular story
about Japan as well as just security in general,
it's a fact that
any time there's any sort of anything going on,
there's always many layers, right?
There's like the fundamentals that cause the problem to begin with.
And then there's the stuff we see.
And obviously, in terms of like we'll pick on San Francisco.
San Francisco has a well known homeless problem
and the cost of everything there is ridiculous and is out of control.
And so obviously there are lots of people that for
whatever reason stay there and they have no way out.
And so they end up generally engaging in
some sort of illegal activities and of course,
you could arrest them all.
But what's going to happen? Right. They don't,
you're gonna arrest them and they're eventually going to get back out
and just do the same thing over and over and over again.
Right.
And it's one of those things where
San Francisco is a city.
I know they always talk about, oh, we need to fix this, we need to fix this.
But I mean, let's face it fundamentally. They've done Jack Swat.
-- Right. And I can't wait for the tweets about all the work they're doing.
-- Well.
It's, it's tough too because you have a lot of it looks like mental illness issues
then propagating as homelessness and illegal activity
and drug abuse at which point,
you know,
then
the thing that always gets me is when you look at that
type of problem
getting these people, not even getting them out of it,
but getting them just stabilized, getting them sheltered and fed
is incredibly difficult.
Right. And, and I'm going to compare this to security
is
fundamentally if the people in charge don't care, nothing changes.
And that's, it's the same problem in both directions.
This assumes the problem can actually be fixed for a reasonable amount
of effort and money and I'm not sure it can be.
And that's like some of these security problems. It's possible,
you know, like for example, this, that that latest have I been P
thing where it was like 790 million email addresses.
And it's like, but why are we pretending that email addresses are somehow private?
Uh
There was other personal data in that dump by thing.
But yeah, I hear you
but a lot of people are like,
I should have control over my email address and it should only go
to the people I want like I had to do a GDPR takedown of
somebody, you know, for the DWF who um accepted the CV terms of use,
which specifically state what the CV terms of use were and explicitly stated,
you will end up, you know,
I will put this email artifact into this get repo
publicly so that we have a record of it.
And this person two years later was like, oh, I want my email address to be public,
please remove this.
So I had to.
And it's,
you know,
it's just weird to me that we pretend that
something like your legal name is somehow generally private.
It's like, I'm sorry, but it really isn't. And I'm not saying that
we shouldn't treat this data carefully and, you know, treat it sensitively.
But the reality is your personal data is out there.
And I think we need to now look at ways like for example,
these companies that allow people to get a mortgage
by, you know, stealing your identity.
Well, the problem isn't that they stole your identity. The problem is that the bank
has such weak security controls that anybody with your name
and date of birth can go get a mortgage.
And I think that's where we come back to some regulation.
You know, if regulators were to say that, like look,
the bank has to fully eat the cost of this and has to make it right.
-- I'm guessing that the security controls would improve
-- quickly.
Well, they, they do though, I mean, there is, this is actually a problem.
Well, I shouldn't speak for obviously Canada, but in the United States,
we had this issue where people would have incorrect things on their credit scores,
for example and say this isn't me,
you need to take it off and the credit companies were like we don't
want to and eventually the government said you have to do this right?
That's not ok.
You can't be basically marking someone as having bad credit when
there's things they didn't do and they can prove it wasn't them
right. And it's like the same deal with getting a mortgage, man. Like that's fraud.
If somebody gets a mortgage
in your name,
you're not responsible for their mortgage because you didn't do it.
It's the bank's problem for.
You still need to deal with it and you still need to deal with the outfall of it.
You need to, you know, go to law enforcement,
that's just life current. I mean, that's true of anything.
You're, if somebody does something to you,
you're going to have to clean up the mess because you're responsible for you.
And I mean, that does suck. I'm not saying it's right.
It's just the way it is and it's always going to be.
Well, what I'm saying is, for example, imagine the bank had to pay you out of pocket,
say your working rate times the number of hours you spent on it.
Right. I'm just saying, right. Things like that.
I suspect would make the banks be a lot, take a lot more, you know,
interest in being secure.
I, I don't disagree with you at all and,
-- you
-- know, I don't think it's ever going to happen but
it,
I don't think it will because I think that's when you start getting
into those situations where your incentives get kind of spun around backwards.
It's, you know, the old story of the Cobras in India Yes.
Yeah. People started raising them.
-- You
-- could conceivably depending upon the kind of reward have people, you know,
purposely defrauding banks to get their, their compensation.
If you can game a system, people will game it.
Well, if you can game a system to gain value.
Absolutely. People will game it.
That's what people do.
That's fundamentally
how humans work.
-- God bless humans.
-- Right. And that's how we got to the top of the food chain.
-- Uh,
-- sure. Yeah, that's, that's probably fair. So, anyway, uh, poor girl in Japan
got in trouble.
Is it, is it ok to get in trouble for your pranks?
And I think
I, I would like to say no, because young people do a lot of dumb stuff.
But at the same time, like,
sometimes you'd uns screwed up and I think she's unscrewed up
and that sucks and I hope it works out for her.
But it's, I,
I don't know if there's ever going to be
a good answer to things like this just because,
-- well,
-- the good news is the justice system in general has the concept of men's rea,
you know, intent.
Right. And hopefully that's taken into account.
-- Uh,
-- yes, that is. Well, do they in Japan though?
I don't, I don't know how the Japanese legal system works.
Uh,
they have something like a 98% conviction rate because they really
only take stuff to trial if they know they're going to,
ah, gotcha.
And that's fair.
She could conceivably just get in some trouble with
the police and then get let go eventually.
Which is hopefully that's what happens because
it's,
you know, I, I was young, I got into trouble.
It's ok to get your wrist slapped every now and then.
But I don't like ruining someone's life for a trivial,
I guess. Silly thing. And this is definitely a trivial, silly thing.
Well, especially
how do I put this nicely. Young people are stupid because they don't,
they haven't fully experienced and understand the
world and the brain is still developing.
Dude, adults are stupid too.
That was actually my next point is that
just because your brain is done developing at the
age of like 20 whatever doesn't mean you still
have any idea of how the world works because
for, well,
let me put it this way who here has driven in traffic in the
last 24 hours and witnessed at least one moving violation from another person.
-- I have not driven in the last 24 hours. Ok.
-- So,
but you know what I'm saying? Right?
Like if you, if you drive your car to the store,
you're going to witness somebody else doing.
-- Lord knows what actually
-- you,
you say this and the police for whatever reason has started
pulling people over like crazy in front of my house,
which makes me really happy because I live in kind of a busy street.
And so it pleases me that they're fine.
You know, I'm always complaining about the speeding and,
and anytime I see a police officer, I'm like, people drive too fast on my street.
You got to deal with that.
And it's, it's glorious but it's like constant,
there's constant flashing lights in front of my house now and it amuses me to no end.
Yeah.
No, I remember this one cop used to, uh, just,
he would go around the block park facing the main road, pull somebody over,
drive around the block and do it again and he
would just do that for like eight hours every day.
Right? And it wasn't even like it was, yeah,
like, well,
because people are just so oblivious to cop cars that you could just park
there and wait for people to come down the street and do something stupid.
Pull them over. So
well, speaking of doing sort of stupid, oblivious things that,
that end up being very painful according to Twitter,
a bank, uh,
accidentally published a private N PM package to the public N PM registry, which,
you know, ok, I, I totally get how that could happen.
Um, but apparently it took him three years to notice
that they did this
and then they, uh here we go,
a major international bank accidentally published a private package
of their own to the public N PM registry.
Took three years to notice and then sent D MC
a takedown notices to Amazon and cloud Flare for hosting,
quote stolen code unquote.
Now, I have to pay a lawyer to explain this to them.
-- Yeah,
-- I like that. That was amusing to me.
Uh,
now I, I will say
I am hopeful
that
the N PM group will be able to recoup the legal fees from the bank.
-- I don't
-- think they went to the N PM group
because no offense if they're dumb enough to do this,
they're probably dumb enough to be like, oh,
it's hosted at Amazon and through cloud flare.
Let's go blame them.
I thought, I thought that that tweet was from someone who works at N PM.
Ah, ok. I wasn't.
-- Yeah. And N PM is like a company.
-- Yeah. Yeah, you're right.
Yes.
Yeah.
-- Ok. I stand corrected.
-- Sorry. I,
I guess so. Here is II,
-- I have sadly been involved in things similar to this in the past.
-- Oh, I've, I've seen
similar shenanigans. Yep.
-- It,
-- it, unfortunately, what happens is there's a lot of institutions that, like,
I'll pick on banks here because they're an easy one
where
there's something that went wrong and somehow somebody alerted them
of this source code and it wouldn't shock me if they
were getting some sort of like pen test done or some
sort of review of sensitive code or something they have internally
and somebody showed up and it was like, oh, your source code is here
and it
is quite likely not unlike the Japanese story.
We just had where the recipient misunderstood, what was going on,
assumed there was malicious intent
and, and basically called up the lawyers and was, like, go
-- and now you look like an
-- idiot.
These always remind me of like a large animal being stung by like a,
like some sort of large fly or insect.
Right.
And you see them get stung by it and then a few seconds later, like,
they process the pain signal
-- and just flip
-- out, right? Who's closest to me. Exactly.
Who did that?
You know? Yes.
Yeah. So I
see.
And this and I get it because this is frustrating because, you know,
when it comes to the A IC and I hate that I, I prefer the CIA try, you know,
confidentiality, integrity and availability.
You know, the classic three measures of sort of security,
you can always recover from availability,
you can stand it back up and get it working again
and you can always recover from integrity.
You know, you can restore from backups or otherwise un muck the data,
but you can't really like 100% confidently ever recover from confidentiality.
-- It's the old saying, man, information wants to be free.
-- Exactly.
And, and II I love using that whenever I can just because
it's so for, for you, you young. And
a
long time ago,
there was a very vibrant hacker culture will say.
And one of the I guess hip slogans was information wants to be free and of course,
it was what it really means at the end of the day, it's very profound actually is that
once information gets out, you can never bring it back. And this is,
you look at some of the data leaks that have happened for like, you know, CIA or,
or the NSA or who,
you know, the Snowden leaks, the Manning leaks, whatever.
Once they publish that stuff, it's, it's over, you can't, you can't take it back.
Right. And this has been true forever.
-- Well,
-- and it's,
it's more true now because the ability to store
and publish data is just so much easier.
Right. Right. And Google Man. Right. With Google, you can find anything.
And so, I mean, fundamentally, what,
what this bank is going to have to end up doing at the end of the day
is they could send takedown notices, they could get their stuff removed.
But it,
it's there and people are going to be able to find it if they want to.
And it's probably mirrored on 7 billion websites. Like it's you lost,
you know,
I've had fantasies if I had enough compute power of like downloading
all of github to look for credentials or to look for,
you know, pi I personally identifiable information to see who's accidentally,
you know, shoving that stuff out there.
Right. But part of the problem is then, then what would I do?
You know?
Right.
And, and the good news is there are some automated projects working on this,
like looking for pass.
Like there's one that actually looks for entropy and
based on the amount of entropy in that string,
you know, says, oh, we think you posted a password
to your G
repo,
you know, and they send you a warning email and they're like,
we're totally not scammers and this is legit and
like go click over here to read about us.
And you know,
they kept flagging on my one repo because I was publishing emails to it and emails
have the message ID header that looks like
a password because it's like a random string.
So, you know, good on them for actually detecting this crap, right?
And crawling github
and trying to do the right thing.
Um But again, it's, you know,
it's one of those classic like boiling the ocean problems of like,
I have to find all the problems that I have to inform everybody.
And then worst
in about what 99% of the cases I have to educate them
if you say to somebody, you know, hey,
it looks like you publish something you shouldn't have to, your,
to your github or whatever, they're not going to understand, right?
-- They're going to have to be educated what that means. Uh
-- So actually I'm gonna,
I'm gonna pull an audible on you here and talk
about something that I don't know if you heard about,
but there was a tweet, I'll dig it out.
But basically there was a study done where, where this, it was a university,
hired a bunch of freelance developers and basically
said we want you to write this login system
and like out of 50 or something like four
implemented password hashing. And then, right, like most of them didn't do it.
And of course, there's a bunch of outrage on Twitter and everyone's like, oh,
look how dumb these people are and everything.
But the reality is
why would a developer know this. And so what I did actually
was, I,
I did a search and I said, how do I hash a password into, into Google saying like,
if I was a developer and I didn't know this,
what would I do?
And the answer is nothing like everything I found was freaking terrible.
The, even, even when there was advice,
it was not good advice, it wasn't very actionable.
It would say things like, oh, you should hash your password.
Well, what the, you know, wtf man
and
I feel like
saying we have to educate people. Well, that's,
-- that doesn't work. Right.
-- I just googled, how do I safely store a password?
And it's all aimed at the client side, not the server side,
we store a password on a server
and how do I safely store a password on a server?
Oh, dear.
Yeah.
Right. It, seriously. Exactly. Exactly.
The searches are awful and, and everything is,
is horrible for advice here and this is
the, the, the obvious answer is don't use something like Google or
zero or pick a service that can manage user, you know,
-- authentication for
-- you not to plug my own thing.
But, so the Blockchain project I'm working on,
we looked at how do we securely do
accounts and account management and passwords and emails?
You can't
and no, no, no even better. So, so the answer is we don't,
you don't need a user name or password to
service,
you know, and it's
so, yeah, so if all of a sudden this, this whole huge attack surface and,
and big pile of technology and, and
everything is just the answer is simply we don't,
we business engineered our way out of it
and see, and that's part of which is exactly.
And that's part of what I'm,
I'm beginning to realize is there are so many technology problems
that
they, well, they can sort of be fixed or they, they can generally be dealt with.
But man, if you can change your business process slightly or majorly,
you, you can make certain technology problems just disappear.
Right. Right.
And,
and user names and passwords are such an easy example because it's super hard to do.
Right.
And if you look at places like Microsoft or Google or Facebook or linkedin or whoever
the reality is,
they have enormous teams that are
doing essentially constant monitoring on what's happening
-- to that data
-- even worse than that.
When you have accounts, you know, have to do account recovery.
So, how do you allow somebody to securely recover their account in a way?
That means I, because I know your name and birthday can't just go gank your account.
-- Right. Exactly. Exactly. It's, it's, it's a mess. It's a complete mess.
-- So,
no, it's good time to be alive as a security person. So, I guess,
which leads us to sort of, the last thing uh
is a notepad plus plus.
-- Yeah,
-- they're not signing their executables on windows.
-- So
-- those of you that don't know,
Notepad plus plus is it's a really awesome text editor, especially on Windows.
Like it's, it's literally about the third thing I install on a windows
back when I had windows.
You know, I've never run it before. I probably did
just a very nice text editor and it's free.
You know,
I
honestly, I can't remember the last time I used Windows like for fields, the I'll,
I'll play some games on it here and there, but generally speaking, I, I never use it.
It's,
it hurts, it hurts when I touch. It.
-- Probably
-- haven't used Windows in about five years.
And it's funny because I'm actually going to be building
a gaming PC for my son here come spring break.
And so I will actually need a copy of Notepad Plus plus so
that I have a decent text editor because Notepad dot Exe is not,
well, didn't actually Microsoft open or no, that was Calc dot Exe that they open
sourced.
Yeah, Cal
dot Exe, I love it. Now I can pop CAL
on
window on Linux.
But so yeah, so Notepad plus plus, apparently the deal is he wasn't signing his code,
which let's face it.
If you're an open source developer,
you're not going to go spend the money on a code signing certificate because
that, that stuff ain't cheap
and he was gifted a three, a free three year certificate.
So he started signing his releases like, cool, you know, thank you.
And now
the problem isn't so much the cost.
The problem is that Notepad plus plus isn't like a legal entity.
So he can't get a certificate
that says Notepad plus plus,
I, I guess he would have to get one that says his name or something.
-- Of course,
-- that is my understanding
and, and the certificates aren't that expensive.
It's what, like 300 bucks or something.
It's, yeah,
but still like asking somebody to not only donate their time and effort but like,
oh by the way, you know,
go drop 300 bucks on this thing that honestly
it doesn't really have much value.
Uh it, it does, I think today because if you
look at the ecosystems of, we'll say Mac and Windows,
it's not quite the same in the Linux
world just because of how the infrastructure works. But
in Mac and Linux, if you don't have a signed binary.
It's kind of a pain in the neck to install. Now.
It's not like the good old days where you
could just double click anything and it just ran,
-- which is good. Right. We don't want that to be the case.
-- Well, I agree.
So it's funny because again, for the project I'm working on, we,
I actually just got us the CS A set up with Google and Android
so that we can do code signing when we start releasing a binary.
Hopefully this summer
because quite,
and it's, and it's honestly the security aspect, I want to do security,
but it's more about the ease of use.
-- Right. Right. Well, and you can, you can be in the app store and stuff then.
-- Right.
Well, exactly.
And,
and that's the thing I think Notepad plus plus is it's one
of those classic situations where it's a good enough piece of software.
I will jump through a hoop to install it.
And by and large,
the people that use Notepad plus plus are a little bit technically savvy.
Right. They know enough.
Some
of them are, I mean,
the, the story I'll tell here is, and I, I,
I'm pretty sure I told this in the past on the show is
my dad bought, buys a printer,
a Canon printer and he types in Canon printer drivers
into Google and he ended up on a scam site that
and thank goodness, he calls me and I just said, just turn your computer off,
like literally pull the plug.
I'll come over later tonight
and fix it.
-- Burn it down.
-- Madagascar has closed its borders.
I mean, for real, man, that's exactly what happened. And
it's the same deal where there's going to be people who someone says, oh,
notepad plus, plus,
you should install it and they're going to type in notepad plus plus, you know,
who knows how they're going to spell it
and they're going to end up on a scam site. And they're now granted
there's no reason that couldn't happen
otherwise.
But now
if they say,
hey, uh, it's popping up this thing saying this, this is an unsigned executable.
What do I do? Friend who knows what's going on?
It's like, oh, yeah, they don't sign it. It's fine.
Right. Whereas previously that wouldn't have happened now, at the same time
I feel like
I'm sensitive to their plight
and I'm not going to knock notepad Plus plus because
this kind of stuff sucks and getting certificates sucks.
Well, and using them is not usually as
fun.
Yeah.
Well, and you got to store them securely and there's, there's so much wrong
with that ecosystem. I kind of get it.
But at the same time I don't,
I don't have an answer.
I, I think
it's too hard to do and it sucks.
They're not doing it, which is like, damned if you do, damned if you don't. Right.
That's pretty much what we have here.
No, it's, I mean, the reality is we need this end to end signing.
So we need like the packages to be signed.
But, yeah, asking somebody to do this on their own time, on their own dime
and if it was just a dime, sure. But it's like a couple 100 bucks,
you know, that's,
I mean, there's a lot of open source developers all over the world where, you know,
in some cases, 300 bucks is a lot of money for them.
So
totally
and unquestionably,
I don't know what the
answer
-- is.
-- Well, I'll pick on this podcast, man, like
we,
we pay for this podcast out of our pockets.
Like if you told me to spend $300 be like, no, I'm not spending $300.
I spend enough of my freaking money on this thing. Like, no,
you know,
to
-- every episode
-- and it's the same deal. And so I, I don't know if there is a good answer
to this problem.
I feel like this is some people will argue
this is where the Linux distributions got it right?
Because they kind of have their own build
infrastructure and they sign things on their own.
And while that's true,
the Windows ecosystem is probably several 1000
magnitudes larger than the Linux ecosystem.
So it's just not a practical expectation to have there.
And so I, I feel like if I was in notepad plus plus position,
I would do the same thing.
Well, here's more to the point if somebody,
if some company actually thinks Notepad Plus plus is worthwhile, they can easily
throw a couple 100 bucks and get the guy a signing certificate
or, you know, this company could read, gift him another certificate.
And the fact that
this hasn't happened
yet, you know, it's like, so
I, you know, we, we shut, I, well,
I shut down the, the distributed Weakness filing project last week.
You noticed because, well, you're sort of involved in it and we talk a lot.
But like, because you told me,
yeah, and like six people on Twitter kind of noticed.
And then
the Jenkins guy
because I told him, you know,
you're gonna have to do your get commit straight to might or not through me anymore.
And that's it. Nobody really seems to care my text or my tweet about that, um,
that printer
or the photocopier deposition thing got way more traction on Twitter than,
you know.
Oh,
man, that was,
that was hilarious. I must say,
well, we'll put a link in the show notes but it was basically
what it was is
no, I'm not gonna explain what happened. I'll just set up the premise.
So there's basically, there's obviously in court cases, they,
they log who says what?
Right
as part of the
process, I guess it was a deposition, right?
And anyway, there's these people who reenact it and this one is solid.
Freaking gold. That's all I'll say. So, go, go to the Sea
Notes, hit it up and you will not regret watching the video.
But, uh yeah, I mean, literally nobody seems to care that the DWF is being shut down.
So I guess there's my answer,
you know, and I feel like no pa
plus plus would be a lot of people would be sad if it got shut down and stop,
you know, developing
it. It, it's not going to get shut down.
It's like you said, it's, it's,
there's hoops to jump through and it's probably
compelling enough that people will jump through the hoops
and you could probably argue DWF was a similar situation where there were too
many hoops to jump through and people weren't willing to do it right.
For better or worse.
Well, part of the reason, well, to be fair, one of the reasons I,
I intentionally put some of those hoops in the play
so that I didn't have to spend an hour on each assignment.
Sure. Right. Totally, man. I totally get it.
I, I agree with you 100%.
And so
it is, I mean, this is a topic for another day, I think because we're,
we're basically out of time.
But fundamentally,
if you look at what is the market willing to pay for a
good or an item and we think about security in that context,
like,
as much as people don't want to hear this and
you're probably going to throw your shoe at your computer.
Uh, the market is basically spoken. We have the security the markets will pay for.
And that's
right. That's the way it is.
And so if we want something else, like,
it's not going to come from the market because
they clearly don't care in almost every situation.
Well, part of it is, the market also can't care because I, I can't really,
I'll pick on Amazon a little bit.
I can't,
I don't want to say Amazon has a monopoly but at the same time,
where am I going to go to buy stuff that is as painless as Amazon
because I, I've actually tried to go and buy stuff from, not on Amazon, like,
and I'm like, big people like Walmart.
Right. I was, I was trying to buy some T shirts for my kids from Walmart
and the process was so painful. I actually gave up and went to the store.
That's terrible. Yeah.
Actually, you know what?
I bought some, uh, I needed some I CS, I'm building a task spot where it's, you.
Basically,
I'm going to build a Raspberry pie that plugs
into a Nintendo and Nes like an actual console
and then can, like, play the games and it's fun to do it.
It's something to do with kids. Right. So, anyway,
-- for speed runs
-- or,
uh, well, yeah. Right.
That kind of stuff where you can download,
there's something called task videos and you can download like,
basically like the button presses and then
program the Raspberry Pi to press the button
and
obviously they're really cool. Again.
Look at the show notes.
So it basically, ok, so it plays the game for you kind of running a recorded loop.
It's like
super
-- human way because it
-- can, it's basically a player, you're building a player,
piano for your video.
-- Right.
-- Exactly. That's exactly correct.
And it can obviously do superhuman things where you can press buttons, you know,
like 60 times a second, which no human could possibly do.
But anyway, anyway,
I needed some, some I CS to do this
because like, there were some chips I needed and I was,
I was looking around and they're,
they're kind of obscure now because they're just an older
chip that used to be used with the Nintendo and I
wanted the exact same chip in the Nintendo just to know
it would work the way I want it to work.
And anyway, yeah, like I had to buy them off ebay
and I'm like, this sucks.
If it wasn't $5 for this stupid thing,
I would have totally not dealt with it because it was just, it was painful.
Anyway, anyway, I,
I think that is a great topic for another day that was just talking about like the,
how the market and security are integrated as well as something that I know
we talked about in the past it's just like the science of security where
it's, it's not just voodoo, like it's market driven voodoo.
Well, and the market is broken. Let's be real.
-- The market is broken.
-- Yes, it is.
Or is it? I don't know, maybe it's not whatever, it
doesn't matter if it's broke or not. It is what it is.
I'm calling this one because we could probably talk,
we could spend another hour talking and nobody wants that.
So,
thank you everyone for listening. You can go to open source security podcast.com.
Hit up all the show notes. You can use the Pound
Osis
podcast. Hashtag You hit us up on social media.
-- Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye
the