Hello and welcome to episode 69 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Pressers.
If I was a less mature person,
I would make up some silly jokes right now. But, but I will hesitate from doing that.
Right.
So I guess the, the big question for you, Kurt
is,
do you want to let Amazon break into your house to deliver packages someday?
-- Uh
-- Probably. Yeah,
which blows my mind. Like, why would you let them do that?
Um, well, it's the thing to remember and here's the best part.
It's not just Amazon having the ability to
come in and deliver packages inside your house,
but you can then use that to give other people access to your house, like,
say your cleaning service
or, you know, a repairman or whatever.
And honestly, for some people with certain lifestyles, that would make sense.
I mean, I work from home so it makes less sense for me
because I'm here and I can just let them in.
But for a lot of people, you know,
especially if you have like a one or two hour commute.
I mean, can you imagine? I mean, there's services.
What was that service in the US where you basically hire somebody to, like,
sit at your house and wait for packages to be delivered.
Is that a thing?
Yeah,
it's crazy.
Um, or they could, like, check your, on your pets or Task Rabbit.
That's the one and Task Rabbit got bought by IKEA. Not too long ago. Interesting.
But, uh, anyways, you know, Task Rabbit would literally be something like
you'd pay somebody to like,
sit at your house and wait for a package delivery or wait for a repairman or whatever.
I mean,
because how many times have you had, like,
how many people have had to take half a
working day off so they can get their cable installed
or get their phone fixed.
Those are the worst too where they, you know,
we'll be there between the hours of 8 a.m. and midnight and, and, you know,
the only time they come is for the five minutes you step away into the restroom.
It's, it's great.
I mean, the meme is those ups, you know, messages where it's like,
please knock loudly.
We're home,
-- dude.
-- They never do.
You know, I had
so many instances where a package was to be delivered and
I go look outside and there's a note on the door
and I have a doorbell. I'm at home. There's no noise, I can
hear them. I can even hear them knock on the door. And like,
you clearly did not knock or anything. You just stuck that sticker up and left.
I remember at my old house,
I was actually sitting on the couch and the couch backed onto a large window
and outside that window was the front steps and porch to the house.
And like, literally, I was watching TV, heard a strange noise,
didn't think much of it, then went outside and checked and yeah,
ups delivery notice.
You gotta love it, man. You know.
So, yeah, from this perspective,
I can totally see people wanting this because I've also had packages that say like,
uh, signature required and it's like it's been delivered and I'm like,
I don't remember receiving it or signing for it
and then, you know, I'm hunting around my porch and then the back porch for like
the box.
So no, I can totally see this.
I mean, the Amazon video shows essentially those,
those two main use cases of like somebody dropping off a package and,
you know, having a cleaning service come by to, to clean the apartment, you know,
and, and honestly, I mean, if somebody has a one or two hour commute,
-- this is going to save them half a day at a time every time they use
-- it,
I suppose it can depend where you live also because
-- we,
-- we
-- supported in some major urban centers in the US right now.
-- Right. Right.
But even ignoring that, I mean,
let's say major urban centers are a great example where there
are very nice places and there are much less nice places.
Right.
Where, where there are certain places you could live that you would never ever
want to, like, leave your door open, for example, or, or anything like that,
or trust the package laying on your stoop because it's going to get stolen.
Right.
And,
and I guess I'm slightly less sensitive to that because
I've had packages on my front porch for a week
and nobody took them
and I don't think anybody ever will.
Well, part of it too is, it's, it's, I mean,
I just,
over the weekend I was using Amazon to buy stuff with next day delivery because I just
literally,
it was cold outside and I didn't want to spend
the 10 minutes driving to a store to get the,
you know, a 3.5 millimeter male female audio cable that was 6 ft long, right.
Bought one on Amazon for 10 bucks and it shows up the next day, free shipping
versus spending, you know, going,
it was like minus 10 °C and blowing kind of miserable for the one day on the weekend.
And yeah, like literally
it's just, it's getting easier to buy stuff on Amazon than it is to
-- go to a nearby store.
-- It's not getting easier. It's significantly easier, man.
-- I
-- mean, well, I mean, more and more stuff has the free next day shipping and you know,
like, it's more and more products that I want are literally, if I buy it online,
it will be there
in, like, one business day or less.
It's almost like they have data on people's buying habits.
It's weird using that to their advantage. Right.
Yeah.
Well,
and I assume most of their logistics keep getting better
and better because Amazon just recently bought some planes.
Remember?
Yes.
Yes. That's,
that's awesome.
Good
for them.
Yeah.
And I mean, and when you think about the efficiency from an economic point of view,
right?
Like, ok, you know, 100 guys with shovels versus one guy with a bulldozer,
And this is a great example of
the, the economic cost of like,
somebody having to take a half a day off to
wait at home for the phone installer or whatever or
slightly better. They, they hire Task Rabbit who hires somebody, you know, who
obviously has.
I,
I assume they don't have a lot of other
options for work if they're working for Task rabbit,
you know, doing this sort of, um,
sort of piece work. And
so that's, you know, a bit less inefficient, right?
You have somebody who's maybe not a phd waiting at home for half a day.
But fundamentally, you know, you replace all that with a smart lock,
a camera and a little bit of software magic
and all of a sudden, you know, the, the repairman can let himself in
do the thing that needs to be done whenever and, and leave.
Right.
I
mean, yeah, it's,
I imagine if every single package being delivered had to be signed for.
It used to be like that
and it was horrendously expensive and
inefficient.
And it also reminds me of the, the days of checking baggage
where people would, like, make sure it was actually your bag
and,
you know, there's, there's a good security lesson there as well where
yes, people are going to steal bags. But the number is like so insignificantly low
-- that it's, it's just easier and better to replace stolen bags.
-- Well, the
overall cost is lower. Yeah.
Well, same thing with packages. Right.
How many packages actually get stolen versus how many more packages get delivered
because we just don't really care about the security of these packages.
And
there's, there's a lot, a lot of that which, which this reminds me of
you sent me the video of that guy who had packages stolen off of his,
his front porch and he, like, put a shotgun shell in it.
So when somebody grabbed the package, like it exploded, it didn't hurt them.
It just made a lot of noise.
-- I took the shot out. So it was just like a giant fire
-- crack
that
was
illegal
in most places
and it's got to be illegal everywhere for the most part. Right.
Well, I mean, the potential for shrapnel hit somebody is there and just that alone.
I mean, anyways.
But uh yeah, and I mean, I get that because if, if you live in a bad area and like,
you know,
like literally you,
you can't
get people to ship you stuff with like signature
required or like face to face delivery required,
even if you wanted to.
Because most of these places are like,
we're just not set up for that.
Like we, we do the lowest common denominator, which is like
some Rando basically throws the package at your front door.
You know,
like I've seen, that's one of my favorite.
I see those videos where like you see the UPS driver,
you know,
like literally pull up and like a package comes flying out the side
of the truck and like bounces a few times and you know,
honestly
I'm ok with that because again, you know, packages get delivered faster.
And have you ever seen the videos of
the sorting facilities where these packages get processed?
I've never seen a video but I've known people
who worked in them and I've heard stories.
Well,
you have these giant bumpers like whacking the package
onto the right conveyor belt or you know,
it falls like two or 3 ft onto another
-- conveyor belt
-- that like the people who handle them,
I guess often we say entertain themselves
by seeing like who can throw the package the farthest.
Oh, that's fragile. Let me
that on the ground.
I went to Home Depot,
the other day and they have a whole pile of fridges and freezers out in the front,
you know, for clearance or whatever.
And half of them are labeled do not drop.
Are we supposed to be dropping certain models of fridge and freezer?
I, I imagine like a lawyer made them put that on the side or something.
Well, did you ever see when they ship certain high
sensitive scientific equipment?
They have those, those little
G
shock and the tip sensors, basically,
it'll tell you how much it's tipped and how many G's it's encountered.
Which, which obviously,
like if you're shipping an electron microscope across the country,
that's
a huge deal. Right? Like your refrigerator. Probably less so.
But still, I'm sure you don't want it, like, dropped off the back of a truck, right.
Yeah, I remember looking into those and they're not cheap.
They're like a few bucks each and again,
just for the majority of packages that do arrive.
Ok.
You know,
I don't want the whole industry spending like
an extra five bucks on every single package
to save like 1% of them.
-- Unless it is like high value in your, you're gonna be insuring it.
-- Right.
I mean, I'm sure an electron microscope is what, a couple million dollars?
Probably not anymore.
I, I'm guessing you could probably, I mean,
that's what gets me about some of the scientific equipment, right?
Is like, or like CNC milling machines, right?
I was looking at them a while back and it's like,
they used to be a half a million bucks and now they're like,
five grand for a really nice one.
Not like an industrial one that'll run 24 7 for like, 10 years. But, you know,
something with like five access computer control. The whole shenanigan.
Just get, just get a 3D printer now right there.
I was looking at getting a 3D printer and a
milling machine so I could do additive and subtractive manufacturer.
There's nothing you couldn't build then.
Pretty much. No,
I just don't have the time to actually learn how to use this stuff properly.
I know the feeling.
I know exactly.
Although the beauty of 3D printing is there's the thing burse so you can go
to thing Burt and download plans for nearly anything you can imagine at this point,
which is awesome.
-- So, so,
-- yeah, just got to get feed stock.
Right. Right.
And, well, that's cheap. Right. Let's face it.
Yeah.
But back to the Amazon key.
I mean, the fundamental thing is they're not forcing this on people.
Um,
and yeah, for a certain group of people, this will make their life a lot easier.
And just from an efficiency point of view, I,
I mean, the reality is whoever is coming into your house is going to have to be like,
registered.
They have to like, you have to, ok, opening the door for them
and there's gonna be that video record of them.
Like you get a camera from Amazon that uploads straight to the cloud.
So there's like that entry and exit record.
And I mean,
the reality is if somebody wants to break into your house,
they're just going to boot your front door or use a pry bar
or a door jack to spread the frame and just open the door.
The thing I always think of in situations like this is,
it's kind of like the lock in general
of
it. It exists to keep the honest people honest and, and I think that's going to be
kind of the next great challenge is
and, and here's, here's my example, right?
Is because I, I've dealt with some of this kind of stuff before in the past is
so let's say you have a delivery person come to your house
and
you come home from work at night
and you notice that, you know, the some, some antique is missing from the captain or,
or whatever, pick something, right?
I, I have no idea.
Then you think the delivery person took my stuff,
right?
And, and the reality is no, the, uh, you know, your cleaning lady moved it,
you know, two days before and you didn't notice until this.
And so like,
that's one of the tricks and that's one of the things that
makes it really difficult when you have situations like this is,
is now what do you do?
Do you accuse the delivery person of taking it and they're of course going to be like,
nope, not me.
And then it,
it messes with your head. Right.
And this is like, uh,
I forget, I forget what it is. I, I, I've dealt with this,
I'm just going to point out at this point
this is first world person problems because like,
my cleaning service, like, uh,
must be nice.
Right.
And, and, well, that, that part of it and I'm not even saying this is bad.
This is just, this is the kind of stuff we need to always think about is the fact that
when you let someone into your house and then
you can notice something missing or whatnot and it becomes difficult to enter,
you know, how do I,
how do I put this together? Do I accuse this person of stealing?
Which they, let's say they didn't do,
you've probably now made them lose their job and they're gonna have a rough time,
right?
Because of something they maybe didn't do.
And, and how's Amazon gonna deal with this?
Are they going to say, ok, if someone reports a theft, just
screw this guy.
If you read the fine print on their thing,
they have a package delivery happy guarantee.
Like it's literally called the happy package guarantee or some stupid thing.
And it guarantees that if you're not satisfied with how the package is delivered,
blah, blah, blah.
But they, I, I looked through and you know,
hit control fa couple of times looking for.
Kind of, yeah, what happens if stuff gets stolen or broken?
Right?
Like what happens if the guy delivering your package kind of pops
it in the front door and knocks the vase off the table?
I'm sure
-- that will happen.
-- I mean,
and worse yet, what happens when something happens? That's off camera
and you don't have that
use of proof, right? Like if you have the proof of, like the guy,
you know, you see a hand reach a packing bumps, the table. Vaz
falls off, door closes.
It's like, ok, that was the Amazon delivery guy knocking that off the table,
right? And I imagine, you know, Amazon would pay you off just to make it go away. But
when it happens off camera or, you know, there's, there's like no solid proof,
you know, how do you know the cat didn't do it?
Right.
Yes.
Yes. That's,
there's lots of youtube videos of cats being jerks and shoving stuff off shells.
It's great. They are jerks.
Yes.
Although,
so I have a puppy now
and, and it is funny because like, cats are jerks but like, dogs are just dumb
and so
it's, it's two sides of the same coin, right?
They, they ruin everything just for very different reasons.
Yeah. No, I mean, it is a major change in
sort of houses used to be really private spaces
unless you specifically invited people over and like,
unlock the door and let them in.
You know, like you really had control over who kind of came and went from your house.
-- You still do today. I
-- mean,
it's not like, for example, I have repairman coming by and it's like, yeah,
he looks like,
I mean, because for example, like the local cable, you uh, shop, you know, they,
most of the guys don't have work fans,
they were a private vehicle with like a sticker on the side,
you know, they got rid of the big Shaw vans a long time ago.
And so these guys are wearing like a shaw ID, like,
I don't know what a Shaw ID is supposed to look like,
you know, like
the gas guy like, yeah, he's got an Atco
Gas ID lanyard. I'm like,
that's great. Like,
did you print that yourself? Like, I don't know.
Right.
And I'm just letting this complete stranger into my house
and he's poking around my furnace and it's like I,
did you
call, you know what you're doing? Did you call and ask them? See,
-- and that's different, right? If you ask someone to come and a guy shows
-- you
-- meter
-- readers
that is different and those
I don't think exist pretty much anywhere anymore.
They're phasing them out like they pretty much locally.
I know all the meters now have been replaced by the electronically readable ones.
Yes.
And you know, and that was a huge
because for example,
the electric commuters were being replaced by people who were not electricians.
It was actually outsourced to a company in North Carolina.
I actually, I just had my water meter replaced
and I was talking to the person who did it and she was not a plumber.
She was just a, a person who took some training courses, I guess.
And in fairness if everything goes, ok,
99% of the replacements are going to be
literally like unscrew this bolt unscrew that bolt,
pop the old one off, pop the new one on, tighten the bolts.
And like,
actually I was talking to her about this is because so,
so all of my water hookups are brand new because I had some work done down there.
And so like, it's funny because they gave me a water meter and no lie like a year later,
they replaced it,
which I was like, this is crazy. Why don't you just
like, and that's the first thing I said, I, like I said,
how long have you been installing these meters?
And she said, oh, for the last two years. So I'm thinking
they knew this would happen.
But instead, well, my,
my guess is they probably are replacing the whole neighborhood at
the same time and it just wasn't my turn yet.
So they were, you know, dealing anyway. Anyway,
I, I asked her, I'm like, ok,
so you come into someone's house and obviously I live in an old neighborhood.
And I said,
what happens if, if like, you know, everything's corroded and nothing works.
And she basically said, like I give it one twist with the wrench.
If it doesn't work, I tell people
you have to bring in a plumber, get this fixed, call me in a month.
And like that,
honestly,
they
just outsource the cost onto the
right. It's not their problem.
Like if it needs to be fixed, it's my problem. I would have to call the
in and the plumber would basically have to tear my internal plumbing apart to,
to take care of it
anyway. We, we're in the weeds.
-- We're talking about
-- water
fundamentally.
Well, I think the real concern that kind of is nagging in the back of our heads. Right?
Is like, what if this thing just fails catastrophically for everybody using it?
It isn't going to fail catastrophically.
Well, there was those bricked door locks, you know,
those smart locks that got bricked by an
update and nobody could get into their house,
but these, these locks appear to have keys on them.
Well, no, no, no.
The, the,
the deal is you can buy one of a several
set of approved smart locks or there's this one like
lock that kind of goes on to the back of your lock and uses the knob to turn it.
Um, so essentially you're,
you're given a choice of which smart lock you can buy and use with this system
and I don't know if you can, like, mechanically,
like if the lock decides to go bonkers or whatever,
if you can mechanically override it with a key.
Like
if there's like a
look though, man, at the same time, if you have a, a purely electric door lock
and you have no like backup means of entering your, your property,
-- you're an idiot.
-- Right? But if you're a condo or whatever, you wouldn't have that
you have a door to the hallway and what are you going to do?
Climb the building and go on your balcony?
You, you make sure it has a key hole on it
and you have a key somewhere,
right?
I, I don't know, I, I've not,
I've been avoiding electronic locks mostly because
they just don't solve a problem.
I have.
Um,
but I know looking at a lot of safes, like looking at all the electronic safes.
Uh, I was kind of wondering about that.
I'm like, what if the batteries in this thing die?
Like you pay a locksmith to cut it open? Like how does that work?
No, the answer is most of them.
You,
you like the keypad physically prize off and then you're presented with a keyhole.
-- Yes,
-- I've, I've seen those before and, and like,
that's the only right way to do this is you need,
you need an alternative means of entry,
right?
It just has to be that way because someday the battery is going to die,
the electronic lock is going to fail.
And we're just not at the point today
where we have enough resiliency built into the circuitry
that we can, we can call them
batteries die.
It doesn't matter how much resilience you build the thing of the batteries. I
mean, look, if, if the battery is replaceable or you have a way to like
something
from the outside of the door.
Right. And, and that's part of the trick. Right.
And, and it, it is conceivable that electronic locks
will just never be a thing on a residential scale that's reliable enough. Right?
To be, to exist without like a keyhole.
Yeah.
Well, you'd also have to have them feel safe in like a fire event or something as well.
Right. Like,
they are purely electronic and like,
the purely electronics tend to be centrally controlled.
I would hope they have at least like a knob on the inside.
So, if the battery does die, you can at least exit the building
code. You're required to have a tool as way of getting that door open
and, and
push bar or whatever.
Yeah. Yeah. I don't know.
I,
I honestly think the Amazon key thing is awesome because it
will save everybody involved a ton of time and pain.
And, I mean, it's, it reminds me of the self driving car thing in that
self driving cars are cool, but at the same time it's suddenly, you know,
things like self driving school buses.
Just your kid goes on the school bus
and you can have like micro buses that hold six kids.
So kids that are like in a small town can now go to AAA larger regional school,
for example,
with less hassle,
things like that. You know, it's, it,
it gives people options that just
like,
I think of all the blind and disabled people, right?
And just all of a sudden, boom, they're,
they're on the same equal playing field as the rest of us for transport.
You know.
Um, because my, like, I know people that, you know,
they volunteer and they basically want some of the things they do is like,
just go with a blind person to help them with their errands.
That's,
and,
you know, going to the bank. Right.
And so I, I think this is part of that inevitable march forwards of,
you know,
-- ease of use and convenience.
-- Yeah. Well, and I guess part of it too is
we love to complain about all the ways things can fail.
I mean, that's kind of what we do,
you know,
it's, but anyway, the point is it,
it's going to be good enough often enough that it won't matter.
Right.
Like, yeah, the, the locks will fail occasionally, but big deal,
it'll be good enough
and, and that's just kind of the right way to look at it.
It, it's never going to be perfect
but it will be good enough, I'm sure.
Yeah.
Well, and my other thought too was though the concerns for privacy because,
you know, have a company with, you know,
interior footage of your front door who's coming and going facial rec
can they,
are they allowed to use facial recognition to profile you and see what you're doing?
You know, what happens if the cops, uh, ask for that data under warrant?
Because that's already happened with, uh, what was it with the, um,
with the
Amazon?
The
Alexis
did?
Yeah. And I don't, I think they got it but they, well, no, I, I remember what it was.
The police wanted the recordings without a warrant and Amazon basically said no,
go away, you know, go get a warrant.
And I, I don't know if they did get the warrant or not. My suspicion is they did.
But I mean, I think that's pretty common is law enforcement is gonna, you know,
they're going to pick the easy way first
and,
well, I mean, it doesn't hurt to ask.
Certainly not. They might say yes.
Right.
Right. II, I kind of get it and,
yeah, and I don't know, man, I, I wonder the privacy is tricky. Uh, no GDPR
in the US to keep us safe.
Yeah. Interesting. In the Alexa
case, apparently the suspect okayed handing over of the logs.
Interesting.
Um, so anyways, yeah, but I mean,
the reality is eventually they will start getting warrants for the stuff because,
like, from a crime point of view, oh, somebody got murdered.
Oh, a company has video of their front door people coming in and out. Yeah.
No, I'm sorry. That's, we're definitely gonna want to see that.
Right.
And, and I would imagine in an instance like that you could easily justify a warrant.
But at the same time if, if, you know, some cop decided, like,
I don't like this curt guy.
He, he looked at me funny yesterday, I'm gonna see if I can't find something on him.
Right.
And, and that's an instance where, no,
you do not want that person to have access to your footage
and recordings and entry, exit data. And,
well, well, that, that's true too.
If you have an electronic lock,
they're gonna probably know whenever you go in and out of your house.
Right.
I don't know that most of those locks are smart enough to keep a log.
Like if we're talking to just the simple home ones that are like 100 200 bucks.
I doubt that they keep a long,
although they have the recording so the video will do.
Yeah.
But, uh, no, I mean, it's, it's part of this March forwards because, uh,
you know,
I, I just, I can see for a lot of people this being a very huge time saver. Right.
Every time you've ever had to wait at home for something that's suddenly gone.
Yeah.
No, I get it, man. I get it. All right. All right,
-- cool. So,
-- and just, and just to, maybe we'll put show notes.
But I, there's this guy called the lock picking lawyer and he shows how easy these,
like, high security locks are to defeat if you know what you're doing.
Like, he's picking things in under 30 seconds. It's crazy.
Every lock is terrible locks, locks don't keep people out. I mean, that's just
a
couple of decent ones.
There's, that are like, pretty crazy. Hard to pick. But now we're talking like 2 $300
you know,
locks
and here's the thing.
All right. So you have a lock that can't be picked.
My guess is, is a good swift kick to that door
is
gonna get you in.
Well,
unless you have like a security door with
a security door frame because that's the thing.
You can have a high security door.
And the classic thing is you just put a carjack
-- and push the frame open and, oh, pops the lash.
-- Yes.
Or,
or the other favorite I've seen is
most people don't know this,
but the vast majority of houses built in like the last probably 3040 years,
the walls, you can basically, like, just stab through them with a crow bar
-- and then stick your arm around and unlock the door.
-- Right.
Yeah.
Yeah, I actually saw the De Walt had a new,
it was a really cool blade for a
Sawzall that could cut through plywood without needing a pilot hole.
And the way they accomplished this is they just cut out one or two of the front teeth.
So there was like a little hook at the front and then a little blank space in the teeth.
And you could literally kind of basically you could stab a
hole into the plywood and then cut a hole through it.
And
yeah, like you said, most
North American construction is like half inch or what is it?
3/8 plywood on two by fours and
a
battery powered saws all with the right blade.
And you can just cut a man sized hole inside of the house
-- in five minutes.
-- I've seen houses built without plywood on the outside.
How, what,
how
-- does it not fall down because
-- they put a metal cross brace
on the frame?
Ok. So what, how? Ok. So by definition, a wall has to be
like not air. So you've got your two by four framing and some cross,
we've got like a foam insulation board on it,
which is not like you could kick through it with a foot and then you put the, the,
the siding on the outside of that
and the drive
drive
on the other side, insulation in the middle.
Yeah, for real, man.
It's crazy.
I I
I'm literally speechless because I'm just thinking
if your neighbor's house ever catches fire,
your house is going to go up in like seconds.
Most of these buildings I've seen are in the, we'll say, not high end neighborhoods
-- and, and my suspicion
-- is
it's like Grenfell Tower then it's ok to
poor people's buildings on fire.
Ok. Awesome.
Again, I mean, it's, it, that's incredibly efficient.
That saves a ton of wooden trees
as a traditional person who lives in a house that has walls that are
made out of thin plywood. Still. That
I, it would.
-- Oh, man. Yeah, that, I just, I don't know that I could get my head around that.
-- I would,
I would not live in one of those houses. We'll just say that.
Right.
Just, no, I mean, you think you could,
you could break into that house with a baseball bat, right?
Just like, hit, hit the wall.
Yeah, pretty much.
But I doubt that happens because most people, you know,
-- it
-- doesn't happen. That's just it. Right. It has nothing to do with security.
Let's face it. It, it's, we, we love talking about Doom and Gloom,
but
none of this stuff really happens very often.
-- I think
-- that's part of the problem is, you know, online to even just sort of do like a,
sort of
just a simple attack without really targeting somebody. You still have to
target them in the sense of it's not like you're walking by a house,
you see the door ajar, you pop in and swipe whatever you can grab,
you know, which just happened to me.
I left my garage door open and then we were moving and it's like, where's, you know,
where's one of the bicycles is missing?
And then we realized, like, ok, like, we used the bike last week and now it's gone so
great, it got stolen,
got
you,
you know,
and they just took whatever was, you know, easy to grab and,
-- and sell for 20 bucks. Right.
-- Well, you know, that's actually a really good point
is
if somebody wants to target you,
you're going to lose. Right.
If,
if somebody says I'm going to break into Kurt's house and I'm going to steal his TV.
And like, that's their goal,
they will find a way to do that.
But as opposed to people, you know, walking down the street being like,
that's a nice bike I see in that garage.
Right.
Like, like there's, there's, and this is true in cybersecurity,
there's kind of the targets and there's opportunistic
and you will never stop the targeted people,
but you can stop the opportunistic people by obviously doing certain clever
things like shutting your garage door and locking your front door.
Right.
Yeah. My new security system has a garage door sensor
and it's not to prevent people from breaking in.
It's to prevent me from forgetting to close it.
Right. You know, I don't have that and
I
II, I bought all this stuff and I keep meaning to, like, hook something up so,
so I can, I can figure something out because,
well, the real reason is I have a heated garage
and at least at least once a year, at least once a year,
we forget to shut the door for a couple of hours and
you know, when it happens, because all the snow on the roof has melted
in the front of the garage door.
So, yes,
and that's what gets me is,
is honestly the main reason I'm buying a security system is
for things like to prevent me from leaving my garage
door open and also to have like a log of,
or being able to see my front door so I can see if a package got delivered or not.
You're right. It's, I'm, it's like 20% for security, 80% for convenience.
Yeah, that's probably fair. Well, let's face it, man. I mean, again,
the,
something like that can help prevent opportunistic crime but targeted crime,
it doesn't matter how good your security system is, they're, they're gonna get in
like, you know, none of these security systems are that good
that they're going to stop even a, a mildly competent thief.
-- And granted, I'm sure eventually they'll get caught by the police. But it
-- doesn't
matter.
The problem with a lot of the online stuff too is that, you know,
these alarm systems won't stop somebody.
What they'll do is alert somebody who will
hopefully eventually alert somebody who comes by and,
you know, ultimately the cops come by and can enforce,
you know, the law,
uh, through physical force. And that's ii, I
see a lot of companies where it's like, oh, yeah, we, our, our,
our security system notified us that we were broken into, but we never, like,
dealt with it properly,
you know, and, and that's like the Equifax breach, the Home Depot breach,
like all these breaches where it turns out they
knew about this stuff for weeks or months and,
and just didn't properly deal with it.
Uh,
yeah. Yeah,
-- that, that is true.
-- I mean,
and that's the thing, right?
If you, if you have, you can have the world's best alarm system. But,
uh, well, like that giant diamond heist in, what was it? Amsterdam or something?
And they literally,
the guards apparently were like, yeah, stupid alarms going off. And literally
the one guy basically said that,
ok, so the vault alarm went off.
That means somebody is in the vault and I'm not paid enough to die.
So I'm not going to go deal with that.
That's
great. Like, you know, I'll have to find that.
Uh, but as I remember reading the interview with this guy,
that's basically what he said.
And it was like, honestly, you know,
yeah, you can't ask a human being making, like,
near minimum wage to put their life on the line for some random company.
Yeah, I would agree with that. I,
yeah, I, I totally wouldn't go into and, and my guess is because it's Europe,
they probably didn't have guns.
Right.
-- Like, just,
-- no,
they, it was like the, oh, here we go. The Antwerp Diamond. He,
that's the one.
And, yeah, apparently they screwed up because the classic thing, like the guy,
they left garbage or something somewhere, whatever, you know.
Well,
but I guess at the same time my assumption is the security guard called the police.
Right.
I
would hope so. And let's face it. Like that's kind of the point is
you're really not there, you're there to stop the opportunistic crime
or call the police if there's like a legitimate crime taking place. Right?
Like that's the job of a security guard job.
The security guard isn't to go into the vault and start a gunfight with,
with the thieves.
You know, contrary to what the movies tell us
that is not the way it works.
Not unless you have exceptionally well paid security guards
and those people exist
like
they're, they're real and, and they do stuff,
but, but in this case that probably wasn't them. And again, opportunistic, right?
Which actually let's use that to bring up.
The next thing I wanted to talk about, which is actionable advice,
which is something that came up for me.
Actually, last week I was at, uh, De Ops Day Madison last week
and I gave a talk to nonsecurity people about why
basically, like, let's treat security like a minimum viable product.
And I gave them three things to do.
And
uh I took the oas top 10 list and I broke it down into basically saying uh number one,
use a framework,
right? Because like that will take away a significant amount of the oas top 10.
Number two was, don't roll your own off just like let Google do it right.
You're gonna screw it up.
It's, you know, don't roll your own crypto people get that now, like,
don't roll your own off is the next one.
And then number three was
when you do your deployments, you know,
you don't use like answerable or containers or, or chef or,
or whatever, right? Like, don't, don't do artisan deployment.
That, that is just a bad idea.
And,
and so anyway, this really kind of,
it was funny because I showed this to some security people.
They're like, dude, you can't turn the Os top 10 into three and I said I just did,
right.
And they're like, no, it doesn't work like that.
And I said, well, what would you suggest? Right. And there,
of course they said, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, whatever, whatever, whatever.
And of course, I recognize this podcast is targeted towards security people.
So, you know,
-- but,
-- well, I, I think it's, it's hard because it's part of it is admitting
it's not that we're wrong so much as that we've been looking at this wrong because
I'm beginning. Ok?
No, man, I'm gonna stop you right there.
The oas
do
10, basically hasn't changed in the last 10 years.
Like we clearly are doing something wrong because if we were giving advice,
it would be a different list every couple of years.
Well,
the thing is you can give good advice but people
ignore it or people keep building their own stuff.
And I think this is one of the strengths of open sources. Ideally,
you can get a good framework, you can get good crypto libraries,
you can get good off libraries
and if you use them correctly, and that's the other challenge, right?
You can still use frameworks and use them wrong,
right?
I mean, it's getting some of them are making it harder and harder,
which I think is really good.
But a lot of frameworks unfortunately take the the idea of like, well,
we're just a framework, we're not going to enforce policy or security,
that's kind of up to the end user, right?
And so, for example,
they might, you know, make it a lot easier to say,
turn off session tokens than it should be,
right?
Um
But I think that's one of the benefits of this open source, you know,
world we live in is that we have access to these frameworks like say Ruby on rails,
right?
If you use Ruby on rails
even remotely correct,
it's like all of a sudden most of your like cross site
request forgery and like cross site
scripting vulnerabilities just magically go away
you know, things like authentication and session handling,
just magic, it happens, right? You, you can still mess it up
but it, it becomes,
you, you have to definitely make more of a mistake than like, oops, we made a typo,
you know,
and I think that's what I kind of find most frustrating about.
A lot of security flaws is a lot of them are not
like some giant chain of complicated events and, you know,
everything aligned just right.
Typically it's like a bunch of really simplistic mistakes,
you know, any one of which really probably should not have been made.
Yeah, but look man, I mean,
what you described is not wrong.
What kind of advice are we giving people that they can use?
Like my favorite example is
people will say, you know, don't, don't click on links, pay attention to links,
you click on it.
That's the dumbest
advice in
-- the world. And
-- how do you implement it?
Because for example, every single link on Twitter is t.co or whatever,
some some URL shortener.
So I don't know where it goes.
I can't until I,
-- you
-- know what
this is, this is just pushing responsibility onto someone else.
So you can say, oh no, I'm the security guy. I told them pay attention to the
link you click on, right? Not my fault.
And it's like
no like you failed in countless other ways.
And now you're blaming the user for, for not listening to your terrible advice.
Well, I mean, this goes back to the classic, you know, usability versus security
and I think where security got it wrong is that we sort of made
security is so hard in most cases that you had to give up usability and
the reality is you can have
-- no good security without having to give up usability.
-- We, we thought
that was an option
and the reality is
usability wins every time it's not security or usability, it's usability.
And that's what I mean is you have to
have security that does not impact the usability.
And as it turns out there is actually a lot of good
security stuff you can do that really doesn't impact usability that much.
You know, the problem is most of those things take
a lot more effort on the back end and a lot more cleverness,
you know, things like like a great example is Apple's Face ID, right?
That is not at all a simple thing to do,
right? That is a horrendously complex thing to build.
But once you've built it and it works,
all your users are like, yeah, I just,
well, basically I just hold my phone and then it magically says, yeah, that's you,
you can use me
and you know,
and there's been all these articles about people wearing hats and
scarves and makeup and trying to fool it and blah,
blah, blah,
you know, and it apparently works quite well.
And so I
think that's maybe part of the problem is traditionally, you know,
to build these like two factor authentication systems
used to be horrendously complicated to build,
right? So most people are like, well, you have user name and password. Good luck.
Yes. You know.
Um and, but now we have, you know, these frameworks, these, you know,
you can or you should be able to easily enable most things for single sign on
with whatever, you know, back end it is that you prefer active directory,
Kos LDA whatever, right?
But that basically means that your,
your ops team and your admin team and your security team are
gonna have to do some extra work to benefit the users,
right? And a lot of these people
uh well, I mean, I've, you know, not all it shops are good and caring about their use.
-- But again,
-- we're gonna, I mean, we, we,
so II I think we're proving the point here is we've already
devolved into talking about solutions when we started on actionable advice.
But like
talking about a is a great example where look at, look at password advice.
Oh, use it, use a strong password, change your password all the time.
And,
and we think we have all this stuff and the reality is
it didn't work and we weren't telling people anything useful and,
and there's people still telling this to him,
right?
-- It's,
-- well, I, one of the biggest problems I have is
all the people that want autocomplete equals off on password fields in web apps.
And I'm like, no, that's wrong now because
you need to let people use password managers
and they're like, oh, what about brute force attacks? And I'm like, yeah.
-- No, that doesn't.
-- What? Right. It's, no, I, yes, I agree completely. And again,
this is one of those places we're not giving out good advice. Right.
It's, it's very difficult for people to grasp what's going on. And I mean, like,
or, or I'm gonna pick on training.
I, I
hear people keep saying, oh, you know, train your staff.
Just, just if, if, if you have, if you have security training it'll,
-- it'll reduce your number of incidents and I
-- keep
the
training.
Yeah, like, like,
right. And I keep thinking,
where is the data
that shows this work?
And of course, people never show me data when I ask them for it because I,
I suspect it doesn't exist and I'm pretty sure this training doesn't work
-- and, and,
-- well, you'd have to do, like, a double blind study. You'd have to properly,
you know, you'd have to spend some good money on this and,
and more to the point, like,
you've always read those things where people send
out fishing links in emails and it's like
it, well, from every single article I've ever read about it,
it seems like the vast majority end up clicking on it.
Yeah. Even the security people do Right.
Well, not only that I remember
taking, like, the, the corporate ethics training every year
and,
and there were,
there were a bunch of people like the game was who could get through it the fastest.
Right.
Like,
we're not learning anything from that training and if
you have security training that's what's going to happen.
No one's actually going to learn anything from it and in some cases
it might make it worse because today they're probably giving out advice like,
oh, use a strong password, you know,
and change it every seven days and no, just don't, don't do any of that stuff.
Yeah, I mean,
a part of the problem is it's to design experiments to properly test this and
then execute those experiments would be extremely costly
and who's going to pay for that?
Uh Well, let's turn it on its head
and say,
prove the training works
versus proving it doesn't because proving a negative is,
is obviously like impossible.
True.
Part of the challenge there though is you,
you're going against what is considered the established.
Like, of course it works. We know this, these rocks keep tigers away
-- because there's no tigers around here.
-- That's exactly right.
And, and this is where we come back to our advice. Then of
we, you know, we'll just tell people, oh, don't click on links, you know, good job.
I, I did my work today
and it's, it's madness, man.
Well, like, you know,
the biggest thing I see is I want my web
browser just to be able to handle like there's no
content I loaded my web browser in a normal way.
That is to say clicking a link that should result in my computer being on,
I think
just flat out and same with email that should just not happen.
Those are reasonable requirements.
Yeah.
You know,
um
because there's no way I can control my web browser
encounters online because I have to go to websites,
I don't control,
you know, I go to cnn.com now and I'm noticing they have those sponsored content,
weird stuff at the bottom for like
really dodgy looking, fraudulent type stuff,
you know, like diet, like literally
like this diet you'll never believe. Right? And it's like this is cnn.com.
This is supposed to be a reputable news site.
I hear it's not fake news now, Kurt. Right? Like, yeah,
yeah, sad, fake news, very dying media.
But I mean, that's the thing, right? Is
all these websites that I'm, you know, are
supposed to be relatively trustworthy organizations.
They're like loading content from. Lord knows where.
Uh Yeah, because they want to sell their ads
and, and you know,
this is actually one of the places that I think the the sites that are now like Mining
Monaro
with my, with my web browser.
I would rather every website on the planet Mine
Monaro with, with my browser than showing me an ad like any day.
In fact, if you told me you were doing it, I would even hang out on your site for, like,
five minutes.
Well, we'll talk about that. We're going to be doing a Bitcoin episode.
But, and we'll talk about that. But, yeah, it's,
I, I don't know, it's,
I, I do know a lot of the traditional business models are definitely not working.
We know they're not working. We just don't have any idea what to replace.
It sounds like security, right? Like it's,
it's, it's not working. We don't know what to do and, and
yeah,
well, I think, you know, I, I see a lot of stuff where we could, we could and do,
do better.
So, for example,
making the assumption that people have smartphones all of a sudden, you know,
you can push
two factor authentication via applications or S MS or,
you know, like the, the new Google one where it, it, well,
same like the Apple one where it basically sends
you a message and the little app says,
you know, hey, somebody's trying to access your account from like
Uzbekistan. Is that cool?
Like, is it you,
and if you're ok with this, then, you know,
we're going to display a six digit number that we're going to force you to poke in,
um, to make sure that you really, you know,
hopefully don't hose this up and like Google, you know, I, they just opened that, uh,
program now for high security for, you know,
at risk accounts of like human rights organizers and whatnot,
where literally they do have state level actors trying to attack them.
And Google's like, yeah, you know, we're, we're gonna protect you.
It's gonna be kind of annoying because for example,
we will not let non Google apps access your Google account.
You're just gonna have to live without that. Right.
And I mean, I'm assuming that right there
cuts out so many attacks.
Yeah.
Yeah. No, I get it. I get it and, and I guess this is
going back to the beginning. We
we'll tie it all up with this
is there are certain people in certain situations
that necessitate added security,
but for the vast majority of people they don't need it,
right? Like, like let's face it, you and I
don't really worry about assassins breaking into our homes, right.
That's, that's not really on my list of things that keep me up at night
and, but there are people that it is on their list, right?
And, and
it's the same deal with like Google and Apt
style attacks is there are users that could necessitate the added protections
and it's awesome that they're doing that because again, this is like,
oh, you know, hey, Mr President, don't click on links on Twitter, you know.
No, that's, that's bad advice. Just don't, don't give that to them.
That's someone you just protect in an extra special way
and So,
yeah. II, I think it's all tied together is
there, there's always varying levels of security
and there's varying levels of advice.
And I think part of the trick is understanding, you know,
what is my actual threat model and where do I fit in?
Because especially security people, we love to put our tinfoil hats on and,
and make up things that are never going to happen,
which means we're not focusing on the things that could happen,
which is where we should be paying attention.
Right.
Sweet.
Yeah. No, I think, I think the
security industry is starting to mature a bit in that.
Like, I know my,
my sort of view of security now is more wrapped around
sort of quality of life rather than this sort of arbitrary,
you know, like the, the traditional risk slash
impact slash, you know, monetary value of such,
you know, there's, there's,
we need to start thinking about quality of life because for example,
if somebody breaks a whole pile of door locks,
you know, I'm less concerned about denial of service,
I'm more concerned about a whole bunch of
people standing outside in the cold in winter
and, and from the security perspective,
uh that's not how he would look at it traditionally.
So,
no, I agree. I agree, man. I, I think that might be the,
the happy thought to, to end this one is,
you know, making sure we keep things in context.
I, I think you go a long, long way
and, and we fail at that a lot. So
thank you folks for listening.
If you want the show notes, you can go to open source security podcast.com.
Hit us up on Twitter with the Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag
We have a Facebook group. You're welcome to join and, and chat along
and yeah, I guess if nothing else, Kurt,
you have a great rest of the day and
I guess any parting actionable advice for the audience,
uh, don't stare at the side.
That is,
that is very, very good advice.
The.