Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in totally not thought crime.
Josh Bresser,
what is totally not thought crime? Is that regular crime or is it not crime?
It's not, not thought crime,
-- not,
-- not thought crime.
Look, we can't say anything bad about Google. So we can't think about Google.
We can't say anything bad about Google because if you know,
both of us lose our Google accounts, we are screwed.
Uh
Yeah, that's true.
-- Why, why do we care about this?
-- Well, so in, in past
I actually moved to Google because they supported IMAP properly.
And so I moved my email there because I knew I could move it back out if I didn't like it.
And email is, you know, it's relatively portable, right?
Getting a copy of all your email and your email inboxes, you just, you, you know,
you use IMAP sync or something to get it all.
But the problem is now I use a lot of single sign on with my Google account.
-- Yep. That's right.
-- And that's not portable.
Uh No, no, it is not.
So today for those of you who haven't figured it out from Kurtz will say
awesome description.
We want to talk about single sign on
because it's been something that's been on the minds of
Kurt and I for a couple of weeks for,
for nothing particularly important or interesting.
It's just, it's a good topic and I think we should discuss it.
And more importantly, we want to focus on single sign on
as provided by major companies like Google or say Twitter, linkedin, Facebook.
We're not talking about like corporate enterprise, single sign on or for example,
the CS A where we run an authentication back in.
So that,
you know, when you access CS A stuff,
you have a single account with us to access multiple services.
I think the corporate example is good though because it, it's something, it's,
it's something you can understand and I would explain it as
how many of us have had services we signed up for with
our work emails and then you switch jobs and then it's like,
oh crap,
I can't access this anymore because I don't have access to that email.
Yes.
And that's one reason we're so
encouraging people to put that backup email
address and because of exactly this right,
people change,
we witness about it's about 1 to 2% a year
of the email addresses we have in our system just
die mostly due to people switching jobs or leaving that company,
right?
You know,
and then for them to get back into their account
is if they didn't set up that backup email address.
Oh,
it's a nightmare because, like, how do you prove you're, you
and you're the CS A?
If you try to do this somewhere, like Google,
there's, there's nothing you can do.
Unless you literally know someone who works at Google, you can ping and say, like,
please take pity on me.
Even if you know somebody who works with Google, you, you, it's no good
the, the, the latest hacker news threads.
Yeah, that could be.
Yeah.
-- No, it's that, that ship has sailed. So
-- there you have it. I mean,
ok, so let's,
let's set this all out that way before we go
off on whatever ridiculous tangent we end up on.
So fundamentally
when we, we, we love sso and obviously if you listen to the show,
Kurt and I have talked about the awesomeness of single sign on for, for many,
many years now.
But I think one of the, the hidden dangers in it
is let's say I log into a lot of services with Google, which I do.
And let's say my Google account gets shut down for
whatever reason. Right. There's millions of reasons this can happen.
Well,
and they won't even tell you the reason in some
cases as to why they shut it down because Right.
Right. And, and in fairness they,
this is one of those catch 20
where
Google deals with abuse at such a
volume that they actually can't tell people specifically
why or how they caught them because then
the abusers will just change their patterns,
do different spam, whatever, whatever, right.
But that means that those,
those innocent bystanders that get caught caught up in this,
you know, they're caught in a calf
casque nightmare of what did I do wrong? Well, we won't tell you what you did wrong.
So the point is
you can lose access to your account via Google or Amazon or Apple or whatever.
And now you can't log into any services that you
had tied to that account using their single sign on.
Like what does that mean? And what can we even do?
Well, the frustrating thing too is like,
I have the Google advanced account protection enabled.
So I have all sorts of, you know, all the two of a goodness and multi factor blah, blah,
blah.
I cannot replicate that myself,
right?
Or right.
In theory, I could replicate that myself,
but not at the reliability and cost that Google does it, which is 50 bucks a year.
There's no way I can build that for 50 bucks a year.
Well, and look, it doesn't matter because
if I use some random service,
they aren't going to be willing to tie into my single sign on environment.
Well, exactly.
Yes.
And that's something we have at the CS A where, you know, we support a bunch of, we,
we prefer people to use single sign on
because then the accounts under their control and
we don't have to deal with their passwords and stuff.
And we support a number of major single sign ons.
And while the one big thing though is we also
let you set a backup email address to do account
recovery. Right. And I think that's sort of the correct answer here because,
yeah, realistically,
so in the past, there were things like open
off or OO or open ID. And for example, at one point, kurt.c.org
was a wordpress.com hosted site which actually had an open ID endpoint,
which I could then use to log into any open ID enabled service.
And it was kind of funny because
some of those open ID services, like when you plug in curt.c.org,
they just flipped out
and would spit out all sorts of warnings,
but then it would work because it was a valid, you know,
end point for the authentication.
A lot of them refused to use it because it's like, oh, it's not one we recognize.
And so
ironically, all these protocols,
the single sign of protocols that were sort of help meant to help
in part decentralize all this login stuff,
ended up the reverse of it centralizing it
heavily because to put it bluntly running accounts
is hard
and expensive and a pain like if somebody gets a hold of your password and user name,
they can log into your account,
maybe, maybe not like if you have Google advanced account protection, you know,
it's going to look at your IP address.
It's gonna ask for two fa all those things. Not let you do anything nasty.
Even if somebody gets your user name and password,
that's really hard to replicate and build, it's extremely difficult. Yeah.
And so we, we're at this
point where on the one hand,
I want users to use single sign on and
have one account that they protect properly and well,
rather than have, you know, 100 accounts with their email address and,
and random passwords now.
And that would be fine if they all had a good password manager, but they don't.
That's right. That's right.
So there's another side of,
there's something you said way at the beginning
where you mentioned about a backup email.
And
I mean,
that's not a practical solution for most people
because the vast majority of people might have
a backup email and they're going to give
it a completely useless and worthless password,
which will probably be very easy for an attacker to get into.
And now the attacker can reset the password because
they have access to the backup email account.
Right.
Which is,
and that's something I spend a lot of time thinking about right
now is all these places that have really good front end security,
but their account recovery is weak.
You know, the classic one being,
especially for stuff you pay where as one of their validation questions.
What is the last four digits of the credit card number you used to pay for this?
Well, quite often that
that
numbers get included in like an email receipt sent to you. That's right.
It's funny to me that on the one hand,
I get all these receipts with those last four numbers printed on them.
But on the other hand,
they're also somehow treated as being like secret data that can be used
me to validate who I am.
That's probably just because the credit card companies
let you store the last four digits.
So it's like the only identifying information
they have on you
that the customer,
the customer service person can actually see.
Yeah, exactly.
So I've seen many places that have account recovery
that is far weaker than the front end security.
The classic case being,
oh, you got locked out, you need to reset your password, plug in your email address.
So, ok, if you control that email address now you control that account
or worse
your phone number and with the whole SIM swap thing like, and I didn't realize this.
I thought SIM swaps were always targeted.
I didn't realize what was happening for a while was they would break, you know,
they would break into a cell reseller at
a, at a mall
and just, and grab like say
100 or 1000
phone numbers sim swap them all out.
And then
the thing is you go to Google or Facebook
and they go, oh, you forgot your account. Like you,
you've forgotten, like you somehow forgot your email address. Cool.
Plug in your phone number
and then it sends you a text and I'm just like
who forgets their email address but ok, whatever. No, no, no, let's just,
let's ignore that.
So given just control of a phone number,
you can go hijack people's Facebook or Google accounts.
Ok.
I want to stop you right here because you just said, who forgets their email address?
And the answer is normal people. We're not normal people.
And my suspicion is most of the people listening to us aren't normal people.
And
we live in two extremely different worlds where the technical people
like forgetting my email address is a laughable
concept that would be like forgetting my name.
But
I know people that if I said what's your email address, they'd probably say,
I don't know.
And like while I can't understand that
they probably also can't understand the universe
where
someone's email address is like literally part of their identity because I,
I own a domain, you know, like that.
That's not something normal people can comprehend.
Yeah.
Well, and, and all the, all the, well, number one,
all the good names are taken and b there's a lot of people, you know, John Smith.
John Smith 23,
right? Like, well, no,
like what do you do if you're John Smith?
Like what do you pick, you have to pick random garbage?
I, I have, I have an example I can give is there is a gentleman
we used to work with at Redhead. His name was Matt Smith. I believe he's still there.
And there were,
there were two Matt Smiths at Redhead and they
would obviously get the emails for each other.
And it was always a good laugh because I,
I screwed this up all the time and I remember I was talking to him one day and he's like,
this is the first company I've worked for where there
weren't at least four Matt Smiths working in the company.
And I'm like,
that is a banana's problem to think about because I'm pretty sure I am
the only Josh Bresser on the planet Earth and I have a suspicion.
There are millions of people named Matt Smith.
There's actually a shockingly simple solution to this that I saw.
I think it was AT&T does it back in the day? I don't know if they still do it.
Ok.
First initial part of your last name and then it was three or four random digits.
So it was like J Smith, 2794.
-- But
-- that's
AT&T, I don't want to work at AT&T like
-- I got to pick my email address at work.
-- Well, and that's the thing, right?
Like a phone number isn't sort of, nobody wants like 1 800 Josh B
-- or whatever, right? Josh brass.
-- I wonder what that is.
I'm gonna, I'm gonna figure this out later
but, like, everybody wants
sort of their name at company.com and, and that's great.
If, like,
there are four Courtesy Foods in the world and the chances
of two of us working at the same company are low,
although all four of us work in it.
But, um,
yeah, if you're like John Smith, then that, that's a problem.
So that's the thing, right? People don't identify with a phone number.
Like I've never heard anybody complain about the phone number they were given,
but they do complain
like they want their email address to not be, you know, QX 47293 at company name.com.
-- Well, sure.
-- Which is reasonable.
-- I, I agree, but we're, we're also talking about a single sign on.
-- Now.
What gets me to is, is
one of the things I level with single sign on is
as the provider of a service using single sign on it.
Lets me just
on the one hand, I get to outsource a whole pile of pain and costs like, oh,
you lost access to your account. We literally can't do anything for you,
right? Like that's your Google account. Go deal with it
on the flip side,
especially if they paid for something.
Yeah,
you kind of do have to maybe even legally kind of let them back into their account.
What I find shocking though the number of places that do single sign on
and then allow you to register a backup email address is almost zero.
-- In my experience, it's pretty
-- bad. And even if they do, it's often not encouraged.
I mean, so one of my favorite examples here actually is
uh feed
because this is one of the first services that I, I realized this on.
And the only reason was just because I was trying to connect some
weird device that couldn't log into Google because Google didn't like it.
It was,
it's this hilarious
combination of problems.
And anyway, I was using Google to log into Feedle
and,
and then I through reading for
posts, I found out I could set a user name and password for my account,
but it was nontrivial and it was really hard to do.
And once I did that, oh, I remember now.
So I had a,
I had a device that it was, it was like an E reader or something. And I wanted to read,
I, I think I needed to log into Feed le to use their app or I forget what the,
what the details were.
But basically
Google wouldn't let me log in because Google was like this device is insecure
and it probably was because the web browser was probably like 10 years old
and, and like that's what set me off on this journey. But
no, nobody would have done this. And
now at the same time, this also made me realize
Ok. So
if I have a service
and it's only tied to Google and I can't log into Google for whatever reason,
I'm completely screwed.
So I put some effort into trying to register backups for whatever I could.
But it's definitely,
it is hard to do and most services don't encourage it in any way, which I understand.
I just want to call out Feeley here because I just like I,
I read feed through the website.
So feedle.com/whatever, click on your little profile, click on settings
and then you click on logins and click, add, log in and it's like
Google
Feed,
-- what normal person would do that. Right.
-- But I'm just saying it's actually easy to do
and it's possible and easy to do. Right.
-- Yeah. Yeah. Before who knows
-- it was back when I did it, it was not easy.
-- That's all I remember.
-- But I'm,
I'm gonna call them up for actually making this possible and easy
because I've dealt with other things whereas there is absolutely no way
to
set up a different one as far as I know.
And, and I know because we, you know,
we did this at the CS A and it's a very nontrivial amount of work.
Yeah. Like it's far easier just to have it hand off
and be done with it.
-- Not, not have a backup, not have an account recovery system, just whatever.
-- Right.
And well, and you think in, in certain instances, so, like feed is a great example. I
do not pay feed
money, do I? No, I, I don't think I do anymore anyway, I don't pay the money. Right.
So, if I lost access to my account,
why should they care? Right.
Whereas if I'm paying someone money
I'm in, in theoretically it would be different. Like an easy example. Here could be I
AT&T who is my internet provider has a single sign
on surface which I need to access HBO go,
which is a hilarious combination of weirdness.
But anyway, like in that instance, I can call a human,
I can say I can't access my account.
Like
let's let's fix this and they could almost definitely work through.
I'm sure they have some hilariously insecure account recovery process.
But you know what I mean? Versus a service
that has no phone number,
it has no contact info. It's almost certainly a black hole. If I try to email anybody.
What do you do then, you know,
also,
so I was just poking on github's interface trying to
see if I can add backup sort of logins.
One thing github
has that I,
I didn't even think about that I should have
is successor settings like next of kin type thing
because, and that's something that's interesting to me is because I,
there will be cases where you don't necessarily want your
next of kin to get something automatically because you're dead.
You know, it, it might be more of a corporate thing.
But you do want, for example,
if somebody shows up with a death certificate for that thing to
be handed off to somebody else so that it smoothly continues.
Yeah, I mean, so actually funny enough I maintain a package like this.
Well, it's not a package. It, there's, there's this old text based game called
Yarn,
which the original author of is, is deceased
and there's like three or four Forks. Of course, we all claim we're the real one.
But, like,
I through a series of weird events, it landed in my lap one day and I'm like, ok, I,
I'll own this
and, yeah, like the original author is gone.
What, like, obviously in our case, like github
didn't exist way back then. But,
-- you know, it's a real problem.
-- Yeah, I'm looking at this. I can change my password.
I can add two factor off.
I don't seem to be able to set like a backup email address or anything.
And maybe I'm just,
and if github
does support this,
they are not making it easy to find.
II, I don't know.
I've never, no, I know you can add different accounts because in fact,
my github
account is tied to my work single sign on and my, like,
you can join organizations or something.
I think I forget how it exactly works,
but it's definitely something weird like that or maybe it's tied to both.
I don't remember. It's so confusing.
-- Ah,
-- you can manage, it's under verified email settings,
you can add verified emails.
See like this is
I found it. So it's under emails, add email address, ah backup email address.
So yeah, I would have not thought to look under emails for, you know,
my account login type thing.
I mean,
this is one of the problems is there's zero standardization and so
it's just kind of let's click around until something looks right.
And in fairness though some places like Google are now when you register an account.
Really vigor like actually Microsoft is a better example, Microsoft 365. Now,
at
least on the corporate plan we're on when a user logs in Microsoft
is completely insistent about getting a backup email address or phone number.
Interesting and not letting you proceed until you do
because part of it is for account self recovery
that yeah, I mean, because how else are we going to do it? Right?
They have to add some secondary piece of information like a phone number or an email.
-- So
-- we've gone on and on about this problem. But II I want to talk about.
So how, how do we, how do we fix this? Right.
The first two things that I think are going to pop into everyone's mind is,
oh, let the government run an identity provider,
which ha ha good luck or let's regulate the giant identity providers.
And um let them like we'll, we'll say you have to let people reset their accounts.
Honestly.
I, I use login.gov
like, yeah, I'm a Canadian. I know I have a US government account.
It's because the Nexus pass.
-- I like login.gov. It works really well. I don't even
-- know what login.gov
is.
It's
a,
it's literally what it says. It is.
The public's one account for government,
use one account and password for secure
private access to participate in government agencies.
You should call them and try to regain access
to your account pretending you forgot your password.
Oh, absolutely. Because they have everything about me.
They have my passport, my driver's license, they have
my biometrics.
They
like I have us federal identification
in the form of a nexus pass, right? Because, and it's
purely like it's 80%
just to skip the lines at the border, especially the land border man that,
that land like, oh, wow.
Yeah, the tail back from going from Vancouver to Seattle versus the Nexus Line. Who
so worth it. So you, you joke about the US government running a single sign on
-- but they, they do and it works
-- well. Ok. Hold on, hold on.
I'm not saying they are incapable of running single sign on.
My suggestion is more along the lines of,
I don't think we could get the citizenry to use it
because it is clear that a nontrivial number of people, if the government said,
like, don't play with fire,
they're going to be like you can't stop me from playing with fire
and they're going to burn their house down just to prove them wrong.
Like that is the problem I see is if this existed,
there would be a group of people that would be
like I'm not using computers anymore to own the government,
but that's the world we live in.
And I think there's some good sort of niche alternatives.
So for example, in, in Canada, with the Canadian Revenue Agency,
you can have a AC R A my account for
looking at your tax statements, making payments, whatever.
And the way they do single sign on is via your bank account.
You,
they essentially support about a dozen or so financial institutions in Canada,
which is like
that covers pretty much the whole population.
And so you, you go to log in and you, you choose like TD or Scotia Bank or whatever C I BC,
click it
and then, you know, bump you over to their website,
you log into your website uh to the website like normal
and allow basically cr A to let you log in through your bank account.
And, and that's also nice because that
banks tend to do good, know your customer, right?
Like they, they tend to know who you are.
There's a lot of people without bank accounts who can't get bank accounts.
True. Absolutely true. But the problem is
then you're saying, oh, we,
you can't do this because it doesn't cover everybody Well, yeah,
that's always going to be the case.
-- No,
-- I'm saying
if you did that,
you have to make sure there's some alternative for the people who are unbanked and,
or make it easier for everyone to get bank accounts,
which is probably a whole another story.
But,
and this is going to one area where in that email I wrote where
I think this needs to be regulated because, uh, like,
I like banks are regulated and as terrible as they are, it's generally, you know,
the bank can't just take my money, lock me up and walk away and laugh
like it happens. But we'll ignore that,
you know, there are processes to deal with it.
There are legal processes to deal with it. Whereas if Google shuts down my account,
I'm screwed
too bad. Like,
yeah.
And so
I think where this is headed is
these single sign ons potentially end up as gatekeepers
well to everything. And I think as such, there maybe needs to be some regulation.
Like there needs to be some,
some way to do account recovery, you know, that they can't,
like, it blows my mind that they can just shut down accounts
and
I get that they can shut down accounts because it's private system. They own it.
They deal with the bruisers and spammers and all sorts of horrible stuff,
but they do catch innocent bystanders
and I've seen it happen,
you know,
and
the problem is, you know, somebody pointed out if you have like,
a 1% outage that sort of evenly affects everybody for one minute out of 100 minutes.
Sure. Whatever. No big deal.
But if you have a 1% outage that affects 1% of your users consistently all the time.
Yeah, that 1% of users is screwed.
Yeah.
Totally.
You know,
and that's like account lockout is,
yeah, it's kind of,
it's pretty severe potentially.
And so I, I don't know what the answer is but the reality is,
I think we need more single sign on
because user name and password, like, have I been ped
has how many records now?
-- All of them, it has all of
-- the record.
I think
the last time I looked it was like seven or 8 billion. Oh,
-- it's
-- more than that. It's got to be hundreds.
It might even be what, what's after billion, trillion,
trillion?
It's any normal.
Oh, I was way off. Yeah.
Uh, 11
-- billion, 11.4 billion.
-- That's it. I figured they'd have way more than that.
But you, you get the idea, I, I think talking about regulation is
easy
but the reality is, I don't know anyone on, like,
a national or global level that even considers this a topic.
You know what I mean? True.
And I,
I think it will be at some point but it's also one of those
problems of how do you explain this to a lawmaker or a voter or anyone
in a way they can even reasonably understand because let's face it.
Google, shuts down probably millions of accounts a day.
The vast majority are bots and a couple of people they,
and they catch in their net is such a small number that it, it,
no one's really gonna care.
And anyone truly important. Like, if they did this to a senator or someone,
the senator is going to be like, Google,
shut down my account and Google is going to be like, oh, sorry, Mr Senator,
we'll fix it right away.
Whereas if you're Kurt siefried, they're like, yeah, whatever, nerd,
we don't care.
Yeah.
Well, the thing is in the past we have had a similar thing, which is the post banks,
right? The idea being that people needed bank accounts to do
banking type stuff.
And there's most countries have a postal system which has the unique property of,
we know where everybody lives because we deliver their mail. Right.
And so,
and they also have the unique property quite commonly of, oh,
you want some sort of organization that can provide services to, like,
99% of your population within a two hours walking distance.
Yeah, it's the post office.
And so,
I mean, there were post banks in the past, you know, in Germany, Japan.
I know we had big ones. I'm just looking at the list here. China had one Iran
anyways.
So, the, the idea of having, like, a government,
either run or regulated entity that kind of provides
a basic service to everybody that involves authentication.
And,
you know, ideally, banks involve authentication because I want
not you to get my money.
Um,
-- we have done this successfully in the past.
-- I mean, it, it's possible.
Well, although again,
we come back to,
I think the political climate today would make it incredibly difficult.
Whereas even in the past, there was probably some of this but
-- it, it clearly worked to a degree well
-- and, and there are valid arguments to be made,
you know, there's people, for example that say I,
I'm not so much concerned about this activity,
but I'm concerned about the backend database then being used for other purposes,
right? And that has been a problem in past in various countries. You know, it is
true.
I, I don't know what the answer is but I, I
feel deeply uncomfortable giving Google Twitter, Facebook and linkedin
because those are the four big social sign ons,
you know, and Apple. So let's say those big five,
I do feel uncomfortable giving them so much
power with no oversight and no regulation and no
-- recourse.
-- I mean, I agree. I, I think though,
I, I don't,
I don't see how we get to a point where people care just because this is
such a non issue on the grand scale that unless you're like some weird identity nerd,
you don't even know this is a problem,
I think because every time I read about identity theft and
you read about how much time and effort people put into fixing
the problems they're experiencing with identity theft.
You know, calling vendors, calling banks.
It's
hundreds of hours. And so they're, they're,
yeah, but it's, it's hundreds of hours that don't affect the people in charge.
So, why do they
-- care?
-- Well, yeah.
Well,
and it's also kind of spread out like nobody
unless you actually know somebody that went through it.
Like you're not going to see somebody making hundreds of hours of phone
calls to their banks trying to sort this out like it happens in private
and, and,
and here's the other part of it is even if
you know someone that's been affected by identity theft,
it's, they,
they might complain a little bit but the vast majority
of people recognize like this isn't a conversation topic.
Don't
just sit there and complain about this because no one cares.
Like, granted we have a podcast so we could talk about it for hours.
But like normal people, they don't have an out
and, and, I mean, this is,
this is a weird and hard problem and I don't,
I,
I want it to get fixed.
I want to think it's easy to fix,
but I think it might be in the probably impossible bucket of problems.
Well, more I think worryingly is that
fixing it remotely correctly? Is
it's a lot of work. Like,
I know providing a single sign on and providing multiple,
single sign on and providing multiple sign,
single sign on with backup email addresses.
It's a lot of work.
Yeah. Yeah.
And like the CS A actually has
customer support that's actually customer focused because like,
we have things that cost money.
Yeah. And when somebody pays money for us and then isn't able to log in and get at it,
they get really annoyed. It's so strange.
Now, if you guys had a billion users who weren't paying you any money,
you'd probably be like, whatever.
I don't care.
And I get it and, and, yeah, on the flip side, yeah,
you can't have a billion users that pay you $0.
Uh, I mean, if there's some way to monetize them enough to provide good support,
I would love to know what it is.
And so with Google, I bet
and Facebook and
-- tiktok and all those guys. But
-- they, they seem to be doing pretty well.
I don't, I don't think this is on their list.
Yeah.
II, I suspect it's going to be one of those things where it's just, you know,
the people that get affected by this, it's gonna really suck for them.
That, that's it. That's the end of my thought
that it is. And
I don't have any good news.
No, I, I agree. And I think kind of anyone listening if you haven't done so already
figure out what kind of your,
your critical path services and accounts are and make sure you've got either
a secondary sign on enabled or a backup email or something important.
Because yeah, if, if you lose Google, what happens and it would be, I mean,
I guess that's one of the things actually,
I think about a lot is like I own breast.net, which is my email address.
And while I use it with Google services, if Google boots me,
I also made sure I didn't register the domain with Google.
So if they boot me, I can just pick up my domain and go elsewhere.
-- It would suck and it would take a long time to deal with, but I could at least do it
-- well.
And that gets into the whole, you know,
people having multiple domains like so you have
domain A which is primary but you have
Domain B which is kind of your admin domain and you use for your admin logins
and also to
protect stuff more blah, blah, blah, blah.
But
yeah,
that's like carrying a full set of winter tires in your
car all the time just in case it snows a bit.
Yeah, no one's going to do that. I mean, let's face it.
The vast majority of people have like a Gmail account.
Well, even people with their own domain,
they're not going to get a second domain to protect the first domain and then
you know, an anti anti anti
missile
actually in all seriousness. If you need a great backup email, a proton
mail is phenomenal and I'd highly suggest throwing them some cash anyway,
just because like they're doing, they're doing the Lord's work for sure.
Like, go look at what they're up to. It's great.
And then the challenge too is with, with things that are privacy, security minded,
like proton
mail.
Well, then the bad guys tend to use them and they tend to, you know, it,
it can be difficult to send email from them because
that's true. Actually,
it's, it's a catch 22 and in
that,
if you actually provide people with good security and privacy,
yeah, guess, guess what kind of people go there to use that service?
-- You, you get some of that, you
-- know, I've seen like with all the, uh, you know,
with all the stuff that has trial offers now and
everybody's trying to do crypto mining on them or whatever.
It's just
if you provide a good service, people are going to try and abuse it, that's just
a
-- universal thing.
-- I know I'm going to call this one. I feel like
I feel like we've beaten this to death.
I wish there was a better solution but there's not. So
here's hopefully at some point in the near future we could do another show of, oh,
how we were wrong.
It's easy to fix and this is it.
I don't, I don't think that's happening anyway. Thank you.
Kurt, thank you everyone for listening. Go to open
source security podcast.com, Hit
Bar
at Chez
Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media.
-- Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks
everybody. Thanks everyone.
Bye bye
the.