Hello and welcome to the Open source Security podcast episode 94 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
So I went to RS A and I came home with the con flu. So, that's pretty neat.
Yeah, I've, uh, I've heard from several people that something went around Rs A.
Yeah, I mean, from, I guess, from a risk management perspective,
putting lots of security people in the same place
is probably
-- this is what happened
-- and the fact that they all eat the same lunch, like,
or what is it?
You have like two choices for your lunch.
Uh,
there's like no choice for lunch because everything
is so busy you can't actually get lunch.
So you,
you eat nothing and you shake hands and goodness knows what everyone has touched.
And
because I've just been watching on Netflix, we watch the, uh,
the Wild Wild West documentary.
You know about the,
essentially that cult in Oregon that, you know,
we
tried to weaponize salmonella and
make everybody sick on election day so that they could
vote
themselves into power and just go watch it on Netflix folks. It's just, it's,
I mean, it's, it's,
they, they, they use the original, you know, footage.
It's not like there, this is absolutely not hyperbole or
like, literally everything that happened actually happened and they have like,
video footage of it.
Like, it's, it's just, it's too crazy to even begin to explain.
I, yeah, it's, it's on my list.
Well, we'll get to it someday. It's probably
right. I, I still haven't seen Ready Player One Man.
And that movie has been out for a while. I read the book though. The book was great.
Yeah.
So anyway,
speaking of sort of major incidents, uh,
it sounds like somebody pulled off some shenanigans on Amazon the other day.
This story is crazy for many reasons.
And I, I think that the thing that I, I find is just the cherry on top is
this was a really impressive attack on route 53 and B GP and DNS and everything.
The Steel Ethereum,
right? Like that was the goal. That's,
this is a super impressive attack.
You used it to steal Cryptocurrency.
Yeah. Well, I mean, that's money.
I get untraceable money.
It's like, what was that famous bank Robber when he was asked, why did he rob banks?
And he's like, well, that's where the money is.
Yes. I mean, I guess at the same time I,
I would imagine
there are, there are more lucrative opportunities with this sort of capability.
Here's a quick
question.
This is an organization.
Do they really have a lot of, um, for political clout to chase you down in,
-- in
-- this case. No.
And that is fair because if you're working with,
we'll say a questionable government or other organization,
uh, that's how you wake up dead.
It's like those attacks on the swift banking system. Right.
Those are actually real banks with, like,
people who have budgets to chase you down and
to convince the government to chase you down.
Yeah, that's true. Right. And whereas like I'm guessing my Ether
wallet.com doesn't have a whole lot of uh political influence or clout anywhere.
And this is assuming it's more than one guy much like, you know, mount gawk,
it probably nothing, nothing would surprise me
so well, why don't you give us a rundown of kind of what happened?
So, so this is my understanding and, and part of this as well is
that the news keeps changing as more and more details emerge.
And I have no doubt there's way more to this story than,
than we know today.
And I guess
I, I also don't want to speculate too much. We'll speculate a little bit
speculation,
right. So my understanding is
basically somebody had the ability to
send fake B GP routing information around the internet
to essentially divert all of the Amazon route 53 traffic
into a data center in Chicago
where they then basically, I,
I think using the word man in the
middle might be slightly incorrect in this instance,
-- but we'll just
-- say it.
No, technically it would be correct.
They, they redirected the traffic using
that's
hijack.
That's fair. But then basically they,
they served up fake DNS traffic. They intercepted
http S requests to an Ethereum wallet service
and I guess he didn't even get a valid certificate, which it's like, come on,
guys get with it.
Well, that's kind of, I find that kind of
odd, to be honest. Yeah, that they, they were able to technologically pull this off
and then not get a certificate.
But the reality is apparently they didn't need a certificate because here's right.
Well, here's, this is basically
two failures. Number one,
the my ether wallet
uh website should have been using HSTS headers saying to web clients, you know, hey,
you're visiting me, you really should be visiting me on HTTP S not http,
right?
And if they'd done that,
then they would have, the attacker would have needed a valid HTTP S certificate.
-- Uh
-- No,
my understanding is they didn't have a valid HTTP
S certificate and people still click through the warning
then in
that
case,
and again, this is how much of this is here saying conjecture as well.
Like I can't prove that that's just what I read somewhere.
And, and that
because
like,
um
I
mean, if I go to my online bank,
uh
well, yeah, if I went to my online bank on a web browser and it
gave me a certificate, error warning.
Uh, well, what I would do is I try the mobile client
and see what happens there. And if that failed then,
well, the difference being with my bank is there's an actual physical local branch,
you know, in my city. Right,
with my ether wallet. Um,
who knows? I guess I have to log in whether I like it or not if I want to get my money,
you know, or wait, which, you know, people are not good at waiting,
people are really not good at waiting.
But,
but I guess here's the more important part of this story I think is so this happens
and
watching Twitter for the last couple of days,
watching security people argue with each other has
been hilarious because there's lots of people saying,
oh, if they had DNS se this wouldn't be a problem or if we probably secured B GP,
this wouldn't be a problem or,
you know, quit using route 53 and this won't be a problem
and it's like
nothing you people are saying is, is helpful to.
-- It's one
-- of those,
you know,
we,
we
definitely have widespread support for htps at this point,
widespread mature support both on the client and on the server.
And yeah, we still get it wrong all the time.
Well, not only that, I mean, getting to where we are today has basically taken what,
-- 30 years of effort
-- and what, and there's an even bigger problem with DNS
E is with, with a web browser,
I'm interacting with a human being directly and I can be like, yo,
this certificate is wack yo,
like it's expired or it's not valid or it's the wrong name or it's
from some dude in Kazakhstan and you really want to trust them.
But with DNS Sec, it's like, you know, my, my web client is getting an error
then,
well, assuming
you going back to your experience where you had your web client set up to, um,
hard fail on certificate errors.
And, you know, it lasted for 15 minutes before you gave up.
That's the problem with DNS SE C, right. If you, if you
have your DNS EC resolver being very strict,
yeah, a bunch of stuff is going to break
and people hate that. Right. So, they'll, they'll turn it off in a heartbeat. Right.
There's people that still don't wear their seatbelts because they're like,
it rumples my shirt.
Um. Right. And I mean,
yeah,
so,
yeah, di in a sec,
if it was 100%
supported. Awesome. And
100% or close to it. Correct.
So, there weren't these false positive problems of like, oh,
the website is broken because of some weird wonky DNS error
then? Yeah, that would be awesome. But I mean, yeah, we're nowhere near that.
Well, not only that DNS Sec is really hard to get. Right.
I
mean, people can't get most things right. Expecting them to get DNS SEC. Right?
Is, is probably too high of a bar.
-- I think
-- we just need the same model that we've shown works
for HTTP S which is you outsource it to a larger competent organization
end of story. And
I, I do agree with that and that might be the answer that makes this happen.
I mean, like a great example here is
it is, it is conceivable. Amazon could make this work in route 53.
They don't,
my guess is because they probably don't see a valid
return on investment today because no one's probably asked.
No, no, no, they support.
I was under the impression of 53 does not do.
I'm pretty sure route 53. Yeah, they support it. They have for a long time.
Oh yeah,
they do DNS sec. So people just aren't using it then.
Yeah,
they uh blah blah blah Attackers sometimes hijack
traffic to internet and or sorry to internet endpoints
such as web servers by intercepting DNS queries
and returning their own IP addresses to DNS.
Resolves in place of the actual IP addresses for these endpoints.
Users are then routed to the IP addresses
provided by the Attackers in the spoofed response,
for example, to fake websites.
Uh Just to be clear,
this is the first result for route 53 DNS SE C which is the Amazon documentation
and then they tell you how to uh
to enable it.
Uh
blah blah blah sign into your Aws, go to registered domains, uh, at the DNS E
field. Choose manage keys, blah, blah, blah, click, click. And you're done.
No, no, no. I mean, they, they've supported this.
Well,
yeah, but the problem is you turn it on and then a bunch of clients stop working
and people complain.
Yeah, that's probably true.
You know, or you turn it on and like a lot of HTTP S stuff,
you do it slightly wrong or a bunch wrong.
Um, although I'm guessing knowing, you know,
having had experience of the Aws tools,
they generally don't let you poke yourself too hard in the face with a sharp spork.
Yeah. So, I mean, they could have totally turned on DNS EC but again, who does that?
And more to the point, how many clients have that enabled?
I mean, again, I tried DNS sec strict for a while.
Turned it off because, yeah, it was not super fun.
Well, in ironically as well, in
this particular instance,
if you can take over B GP,
you could just take the IP address of the web server. Well, potentially, right?
So even if it's returning IP addresses and you can attack B GP,
you can essentially move the IP routing to wherever you are
and DNS set can be valid and you could still mount a similar attack,
-- which
-- is
really
funny.
I hate to say it, but yeah,
DNS E would not have helped here because yeah, the,
apparently the attacker was able to hijack Amazon IP space.
Uh,
well,
in
this instance,
it sounds like they were specifically hijacking the route 53 traffic.
Right. Not, not the web traffic.
So, like in this particular attack DNS SEC would potentially have helped,
-- well,
-- or they just would have hijacked that space as well.
-- Maybe II, I have no idea
-- because apparently the hijack lasted for about a good solid
two hours.
That's what I heard was about two hours and, and not only that, my suspicion is
two hours isn't that long.
You figure an organization like Amazon has a lot of tooling.
I'll bet you, they knew something was up in a couple of minutes.
But then it's going to take probably at least
half an hour to figure out what just happened.
Right. And seeing something
being
messed up. B GP. RO monitoring is the thing.
But then the problem is you have to go thump
somebody with a hammer and get their
upstream ISP to, you know, block it off because,
I mean, the problem with B GP is
it's, it's essentially a trust based
protocol and that, like, I trust that, you know, these people are not gonna, like,
randomly hijack stuff because we've had that right.
Where, what was it in India or something?
Or Pakistan, they accidentally or otherwise hijacked,
you know, was it Google or Twitter or something? I mean, this happens quite often.
Um, there are,
uh, there are,
there is a security protocol to prevent that.
But the problem is like, everybody has to do that. And,
you know, even if like say 90% of North America does that, well,
then you'd still have 10% of North America, you know, having
listening to the hijacked route and honoring it. I mean,
a great example of this is cloud flare.
Uh set up a new public DNS resolver much like Google's.
So Google has two DNS resolver which are pretty nifty 8.8 0.8 0.8 and 8.8 0.4 0.4.
Uh Cloud flare got a hold of 1.1 0.1 0.1 super easy, you know,
and it turns out a whole bunch of people are using that IP address for stuff,
right?
And so cloud floor had like a blog entry and, and, you know,
they literally had to reach out to all these I SPS and be like,
you know, why, why are you actually routing 1.1 0.1 0.1 into your network?
What are you doing it with it? Like, please stop doing that. That's R IP.
Um There's a bunch of hardware manufacturers that like
bind 1.1 0.1 0.1 to a local interface for God knows what reason.
Um
You know, and just,
I mean, yeah, just all sorts of wackiness.
Um Hundreds of organizations have apparently chosen to, you know,
-- use this for God knows why So
-- I've got a funny story about that is,
I remember a long time ago I was working at this place.
I was, you know, young and
I, I was eager and ready to go
and
back then, you know, you've got your I PV four only there was,
I don't even think I PV six was deployed by anybody.
In any way. You obviously generally have your internal network, right?
And depending upon most organizations would just use
the 10.0 0.0 to zero slash eight.
Right? Because you've got like a gazillion IP. S you never run out. Nobody cares.
And there's the other one you'll see a lot, lot in use is 192.168
you know, slash 16.
And I remember I, I start my job and they're using 172.1 0.1 0.1 and I'm like,
whoa, this isn't a private IP. And the guy was like, oh, it is,
it is 172 is private. IP, I
think
-- 1 72.16. Right?
-- That's 16 to 31. It's what, like a slash slash 12 maybe.
I think, I think
12 anyway, it doesn't matter.
And I remember like this is, this is a real IP, you can't use that
and,
and I remember he started arguing with me and I had
to show him like the RFC defining all this stuff.
He's like, 00, well, it's never been a problem. Before. So, who cares? I'm thinking?
-- No, like this is not how
-- life
-- works.
-- Didn't this happen to you at your gym?
Your gym was using some
random block of IP
space.
-- They
-- were
-- also using, uh, the 172 space. In fact, that's what it was.
That's right. That's right. They fix that.
They've since moved to a 192.168 IP space.
Uh,
not because I told them I didn't tell them anything but that's right because in fact,
uh, uh there's some Google services hosted off of the 172 dot something space.
I believe
that that is where this is a problem and like
Google should have enough sense not to do that.
Right. Because
people screw things up,
you know, I guess this is like the moral of the story, right? Is
if the technology is too hard to use and I'm going to like, pick on I PV six here where
I PV six in theory is vastly superior to I PV four except it's harder to use.
And my I
SPS don't support it.
Well, then your ISP,
you have that like big fat data connection, you
have I PV six.
So the two local, big I SPS tell us and Shaw do not support I PV six yet.
The smaller I SPS like Tech Savvy do
because, well, simply because tech Savvy is, you know,
running on their infrastructure.
So they're having to do tunneling anyways
so boom, I PV Six. Right. Easy.
Whereas,
tell us and, or Shaw would actually
have to,
I'm guessing the main problem is they would
have to upgrade all their point of presence stuff
in the neighborhoods because I'm sure they bought
whatever the cheapest thing they could buy is.
Right.
That talks, I PV four, which, you know, five years ago or whatever years ago was fine,
still is fine.
Except, yeah, it would be kind of nice to have I PV six support.
Interesting. I
didn't
and I'm not going to do a tunnel because the
latency and everything is going to be a nightmare.
Interesting. But you get the point though, right? Like this is a great example
where
it's hard enough to use and there hasn't, like,
unless people are forced to do this stuff and I have a suspicion like HTTP S
was probably forced on people more so due to things like PC I compliance
than, than having an altruistic view of humanity and that too. Right.
I mean, that was obviously a huge, huge one there and chrome obviously and,
and I believe Firefox are going to start marking,
you know HEP sites is insecure and that's going to give things a huge push as well.
But you look at things like DNS sec and B GP and I PV six and this other stuff,
what is, what is pushing us towards using it? Right.
And you can say, oh, well, we're running out of I PV,
four addresses and like we've been running out of I
PV four addresses as long as I can remember.
Right. And so nobody takes that seriously anymore.
And, and, well, I understand we really are this time but it doesn't matter. Right.
It's
the
thing to remember is, is, is like all the mobile devices in most of
the world are I PV six space now.
So like all the new hardware and the new networks are I PV six only because,
well, yeah, I mean, you can't get I PV for addresses for Love or Money.
You know, they're the, like when companies go bankrupt now those,
like if they have a block of addresses that
that's an asset that's being sold to,
you know,
usually a company like Google or Amazon or Microsoft's buying it because
they need huge blocks of I PV four for their cloud services.
You know, because
all of the schmucks like you and me who want to run a
web server on I PV four because we don't know any better.
That's right. You know.
Right.
Yeah, I know.
But what really gets me is fundamentally these, these security protocols rely
on
the end user,
right?
And worse than that is that they have a quite a high number of like false positives,
right? If you actually turn it on and enforce it, it's like, oh,
you know, it's one thing to block email attachments like dot exe and dot Bat and.com.
Cool. Right. Those like very few false positives there nowadays.
Um, but for example, you know, I remember, uh,
dealing with some places that block dot zip down.
I'm kind of like,
uh huh. Well, that's a problem.
Yeah. Well, I, I guess
here's the way I look at this
is
and, and we can even tie this back to TLS and HTTP S is back when this stuff came out.
Like it did suck. And it failed a lot.
I remember going to lots of websites and getting certificate errors.
It was very, very common.
And then over the years we've cleaned up our messes
and we've learned and we've made the user experience better
-- and I think the fundamental,
-- I
wouldn't
say
we're not better
yet.
But, but here's the thing like DNS Sec hasn't had that.
And while you can talk about the security advantages all day long and I'm not gonna,
I'm not gonna disagree that there aren't enormous benefits to getting DNS SE C,
right?
They're just, if you look at the return on investment,
it's, it's zero for most organizations, right? Why would you do that?
There's literally no upside to them supporting it.
The only thing I can see is there's a few things
where you can leverage DNS as a distribution mechanism for say,
encryption keys or other bits of information that are useful
and they're having that be now a trustworthy platform is actually kind of valuable.
Uh but again, those use cases are on the rare side compared to the typical use case,
which is, you know, they're just using DNS to serve DNS,
you
get people to their website and email server and beyond that they could care less.
Right. And, and I,
sorry.
Exactly.
I would imagine
there are organizations that want to use DN
SS for key distribution or something like that.
And that's fine and they're, they're quite likely doing it.
But that also suggests they have a certain level of expertise
in house to even understand a lot of this stuff,
right? And, and that's the thing, man, this is,
this is one of the things I actually realized that at
RS A as well is you're talking to a lot of people
and
the, the industry is so wide now and there's so much going on that, that
everyone has their little niche,
but in general expecting anyone to really grasp a
lot of this stuff at scale is impossible.
And so you might be a DNS E expert in your
organization and you might go to your leadership and say,
like we should do this and like, I don't even know what you're talking about.
Go away. Right.
It's just the challenges are enormous and I, I don't know,
I, I don't know how we're going to solve them. Right.
Well, part of it is, it has to be really cheap and easy to,
that's number one, we have to reduce the cost of doing this.
Ideally, number two, we have to add some benefit.
That's, that might be number one,
I, I haven't seen any killer use cases for this yet.
You know what I mean?
Um I, I just checked my,
my two I SPS Shawn tell us also don't use DNS EC for their own domains,
not that it would really matter.
But
so like, you know,
everybody will set up an expensive ecommerce platform because then
you can sell stuff to people and make money.
Right.
That makes sense. Yes,
I, so, you know, that's the problem though, is DNS EC is plumbing,
DNS SEC is, is low level, like low
level plumbing,
you know,
and as long as it works and doesn't flood your house and mess up your floors,
who cares?
-- Right. And, and you should have a chief plumbing officer. Yeah. Exactly.
-- Exactly.
And so, I mean, I,
I don't see,
you know, I, I've heard a lot of people talk about, oh, security is an enabler.
Well, yeah, it does enable some things. But DNS ec, fundamentally,
DNS EC doesn't fundamentally enable something you can't do without it really, it,
it would be less trustworthy
and quite frankly, you know,
while we have people clicking through their HTTP S warning, so
that's
not that
the world has basically been surviving without DNS second at this point.
And so
claiming it's, it's extremely important
is probably at best a lie. I think it's it's certainly not
the honest truth.
Honestly,
the biggest use case I would see for DNS SEC is
the I SPS that are monkeying with DNS replies from clients
to either,
you know, replace the ads or inject ads or, you know, that kind of stuff.
Um,
and again, that's really, you know, oh, Wild google.com doesn't even do DNS SEC.
And again, it's probably because of an availability thing. Right.
They don't want to break it for everybody.
Um,
interesting.
Yeah, I totally thought they would have done it.
-- I mean, I'm sure those Android phones from 1995 are doing DNS E just fine.
-- Right.
So, I mean, yeah, that's the problem is
until it becomes essentially, basically free to implement.
We don't have that use case that makes it compelling enough.
Like, e-commerce, like, having a web server.
Everybody has a web server now because, well, partly you have to, otherwise I'm not,
you know, nobody's going to talk to you.
Um, and also because you can sell stuff to people or whatever.
Yeah. Right. Right.
And, and now I could see an instance where if something like PC,
I compliance or SOC two or something said you have to use DNS SEC
that, that now gives someone an economic incentive right to care.
But at the same time, like, trying to
incentive though, it's, you know,
it's like saying you have to spend $1000 every year on new windows on your house.
Yeah. The Glazers Association would love that
and the Rock Throwers Association would probably go out of business. But, you know,
um, again, does that really buy us a huge advantage? Because I, I,
like you said, I mean, it's,
yeah, I,
I haven't seen a very strong compelling use case where DNS
Sec lets me do something I could not do before.
Right. And, and that's what it really comes down to.
I mean, you could, you could honestly make a similar argument though
around TLS way back in the day
because I mean, there was a time when, when man, in the middling,
all of the internet was unheard of.
Right?
And so I remember there were lots of organizations that were like, oh, it's fine.
You can take your credit card.
Is now, is that my I SPS man in the middle in me because for example,
if I type a domain or something,
they show me a helpful search page rather than an error.
-- I don't think DNS E could help with that though. What it
-- uh
well,
I mean, it depend
on how they're doing garbage.
-- Yeah,
-- but I mean, no, I've had um
well, the
in theory, if we had DNS E at the full root level and everything,
then I would know for sure that there was an NX like no existing domain, right?
And again, that's again, but this isn't gonna happen anytime soon. So
fundamentally, as far as I can tell,
really the only thing that's going to drive people to like,
protect their man in the middle attacks is ad revenue
fundamentally. Uh,
because what other economic incentive is there to really
strongly avoid man in the middle of attacks?
You know, uh,
banks and stuff,
you know, that they're not going to eat the cost.
They're just going to pass it on to somebody or
like my ether wallet, you know, they're just going to claim, look,
it didn't have a valid certificate like Jesus.
-- What do you want us to do? You know,
-- they'll probably just go out of business. Right.
Like close up shop. Say it was fun. And then what do you do?
You know?
Yeah. So, uh, no, it's,
yeah, I don't know.
I mean, fundamentally the internet largely runs on trust,
especially with things like B GP.
Um,
and it's a boil the ocean problem.
You know,
even if you get 90% compliance that still leaves
10% of humanity being man in the middle,
which is enough to make it worthwhile.
Right. Exactly.
Well, that's fun
that
we should all just give up. Right. I think that,
I
don't know
about
mud hut.
Speaking of canned food. That was, uh, what was it? Why did that come up?
We were talking and you, the
Franklin expedition. That's right. Lead poisoning in the Franklin expedition.
-- And then, then I looked it up and it turns out it wasn't the canned,
-- I was
-- the wrong thing in school. It was
-- the
water.
Yeah.
Well, it was the water going through fresh lead pipes, hot water,
going through fresh lead pipes.
No scaling,
picking up a ton of lead.
And then they were baking bread and bis, you know, they were baking stuff,
feeding it to the officers.
So the officers got an unholy amount of lead in their system.
And so, like when they, the ship got stuck as happens back in the day,
when you try to do the northwest passage in a,
like wooden boat
and not like a nuclear powered icebreaker, which is the correct way of doing it.
Uh They basically hauled a life boat off with a bunch of stuff,
including the ship's table and some other random odds and ends.
I think they took all the silverware,
uh, you know, and, and tried to head south, which again,
that's not gonna go real well because it's several.
Well then, yeah,
it's over 1000 miles kind of to anything remotely approaching civilization,
especially back in that day.
Right. Right. So they all died.
-- Indeed.
-- A classic tale of adventure in the 18 hundreds.
Right. They were, they were pioneers just like people in DS
DNS. E
today are pioneers, right?
Pioneers get the arrows, man.
Yeah,
it's,
yeah, it's, it's just the way it is.
All right. So, I guess in summary
we're all doomed except we're not because everything still works
pretty much. Yeah.
And really don't avoid those ssl errors when you go to like your banking website or
your
ecommerce slash,
you know, Bitcoin website, like
your browser is trying to tell you something. It might be important.
You know,
I don't know if you've tried to click through certificate errors recently,
but it's a lot harder to do than it used to be.
Although I also see them much more rarely than I used to, which is great because
it, I remember, man, it used to be super common
to see
t the, the SSL warning strategy.
I mean,
Iran
websites with self signed certificates for ages because,
right, why not?
We all did? Right. Right.
Well, in, in certificates were hard to get and they were expensive
in other.
Yeah.
So anyway, anyway. All right. Right. I, I think that's enough of that.
Ok. Well, thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com to get the show notes.
We've got links to some social media groups and
you can use the Pound Os S podcast hashtag
to get a hold of us on social media.
And yeah, if nothing else, Kurt, you have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks.