Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast
episode 155 with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime,
Josh Bresser.
So, what's new man?
Uh, actually not much.
It's been a nice summer except with a lot of rain because of the jet stream.
It is true.
There has been an insane amount of rain
and unfortunately for the poor farmers,
they have had a struggle to plant anything in their fields
which I'm sure is going to get us come winter and spring
because all of the food will be expensive.
Yeah, my understanding is meat prices are going to go way up.
So, I guess now is the time to buy your half ac and stick it in your freezer. Right.
Me,
I like food.
Yes, it is true. It is true.
I,
I feel like every year during the summer it kind of quiets down
and I think honestly part of it is just maybe because people are,
you know, outside having fun instead of, you know,
on their computers trying to raise a ruckus,
whatever man, everything's on fire all the time.
But it's like, it's just an exciting fire. Yeah, it's, I, I, honestly there's,
well, we both struggled to find anything truly interesting for the show.
And, I mean, the best I could do was, you know, 75 Mercedes cars got stolen in one day,
which is
amusing and
quite well, I imagine that's a bit of money right there.
Yeah, probably because Mercedes are generally on the high end.
So I guess it was the Mercedes sl, a sedans and G A sport utility vehicles.
So those are who,
those are a bit pricey. Are they $100,000 each?
Oh, no, these are the cheap ones. Sorry, these are like a 53,000 us max.
That's still a lot of money.
Oh, yeah.
No, these are the, the ones that have the uh the, yeah, they're only,
I wanna say only like 50 grand but still 50 grand times 75 is that's uh three
$0.7 million at the top end.
But what's funny to me is, is how do you think they got stolen?
I will let you tell the story because you're way more excited about this than I am.
But it's a very interesting story to say the least
car to go is a car sharing service that
was actually introduced by the maker Daimler A G,
which is the parent company.
My understanding is a lot of these car companies are bidding to understand that
it's not so much that they make
cars but that they're transportation service companies.
So they're sort of trying to transition into instead of selling you a car,
selling you like a transportation solution, you know, basically like Uber.
Uh so when you kind of like, just let somebody grab your car and take off with it,
typically
you have sort of background checks or some degree of checking
to make sure that this person will care if you,
if they steal your car and you charge them with it. Right? Because uh
you don't want, you know, for example, some destitute,
like you're not going to let a homeless person rent a
Mercedes car because like you charge them with car theft,
they're not going to care.
Not, not just that, the other way I would look at it is if I give you my credit card
and I steal a $300 scooter,
you can probably charge $300 to my credit card and get it.
If I take a car
and you have my credit card,
you're not going to be charging $50,000 to my credit card.
Just a minor pre off.
Right.
So they, they apparently did background checks
and then apparently they loosened up the background checks
and so what could possibly go wrong? Exactly.
And, but what was really fascinating was not so much this because honestly, this is,
I'm not going to say it's expected, but it's not shocking.
But what's really fascinating to me is it's, it's expected.
Kurt it's totally expected.
There was a really interesting thread on hacker news with a bunch of people
chiming in about their experiences at various companies with this kind of thing.
And,
and one thing was, for example,
was what a lot of companies have tried to do because here's the thing,
companies don't want to do proper background checks because those cost money.
Right. You have to pay for them.
When I joined Scouts, Canada, I had to get a police background check
which
like costs money and you know, I'm not gonna, you know, if car to go is like,
you need to go get your police truck and mail it to us.
I'd be like, I'm no, like I'm not going to, that's just it, there's two sides to that.
It costs the company money from the perspective of doing
the background check and maybe you charge the customer whatever.
I don't care. Well, ultimately they always charge the customer.
The bar to entry is sky high at that point and you're right,
it becomes a matter of, oh, I'm not going to do that.
I'll just call an Uber. Right. Right. Seriously. And I will tie this back as well.
So in the U SI have my credit locked
where
you basically can't,
no one can, can do anything with my credit unless I unlock it and unlocking. It sucks.
And so that's actually had the side effect of
if the few times I've thought about maybe going to
get a loan for a car or something or whatever.
I'm like, ah, that's so much work I don't want to. So I just haven't,
it's like a friend of mine.
Uh,
she had a credit card for emergencies only and she found
herself using it for online shopping once in a while.
So she froze it in a block of ice in her freezer.
That's definitely an emergency. Whatever worked, man.
So, what a lot of companies have been doing is
you take a picture of your driver's license or?
Well, in this case,
it would have to be a driver's license
because you probably should have a driver's license.
If you're using a car share service, one would hope.
Um, but other places, you know, they'll use a passport or ID card or whatever
and
no offense. But that's, it's not hard to get a hold of a picture of somebody's ID
or
just to borrow their ID or steal it or whatever.
There's, I mean, there's entire, we've talked about this in the past where there's,
you know, with passport security, there's entire
communities where it's not really seen as such a big deal to
lend out your passport to people that kind of look like you
or they cut out your picture or whatever.
So what they'll do is, you know,
we need a picture of your driver's license and we need a picture of you,
right? Because what could go wrong?
Well, I think they wanted you with the driver's license. Right.
I think I read which in theory raises the bar slightly but probably not that much.
Yeah, except Photoshop.
So, anyways, this one person was talking about how they tried that
and they had a whole bunch of fraud and what
they found was when they did reverse image searches.
It was all pictures of like us senators and famous people.
And so what these people were doing
was simply taking the driver's license pictures,
they could like harvest or otherwise get a hold of
uh you know, take the picture of the person and then use like a reverse image search
to find images that were relatively close to that.
And let's face it. If you're not paying a human to validate these
and you're doing it with a machine learning A I type system,
it's gonna be super easy to fool whatever man. Even even if it's people,
how many have you looked at people's ID pictures? It
they never look like themselves. It's
Yeah, what do people know? I mean? Right.
As long as you basically have this bright color hair and skin tone,
they're going to pass it here in Alberta.
At least my driver's license photo was black and it's gray scale, right?
It's not my passport and my nexus card.
Uh actually my next yeah, my Nexus card is color if I remember, right?
My passport is definitely color but yeah, my driver's license is uh,
it's gray scale, which I always found odd because, yeah, I mean,
it would be much easier to fake that because now you are missing
tons of skin tone information or even hair color to a degree.
Well, I, and I love that the lady at the DMV
last time said she would let me keep my hair color as brown on
my license form and I didn't have to change it to gray yet.
Old man.
Pretty much. Yeah.
No, I hear you actually. That's a good point.
I have to go get a new driver's license soon
and
I need to, I haven't even thought about that.
I'll have to ask him like, what is my hair color now? I don't know.
It's brownish.
So, and it,
it got me thinking because realistically there's a lot of businesses
where I need to entrust you with something that's pretty expensive.
Like, um, you know, I've rented stuff from Home Depot where
that stuff is easily worth of a couple of grand. Sure. Yeah. Some of those tools.
Well, or you can rent those little baby back
from them. I rented a bobcat once. That was fine.
It's, it's really cool for an hour and then it gets really boring
and it was, it was better than going to the amusement park to say the least.
I, I rather enjoyed it. But, yeah, you're right. I mean, I bet that was Crepes.
I bet that thing was $100,000 at least.
And I don't remember giving them any,
anything other than a driver's license and maybe my credit card.
And then, and, yeah, a couple 100 bucks later I had a,
I had a bobcat in my backyard and I was moving dirt.
It, it really calls into question because another aspect of this is, I mean,
I've met very few
people outside of law enforcement who actually know how to validate an ID.
I would agree with that. I have no idea.
If you showed me your ID, I would have no idea how to prove it was or wasn't you?
Yeah.
Well, like my,
my partner got a new driver's license and it looks completely different from mine.
Like, it's got a dinosaur bones on it.
You know,
he's got new graphics and stuff. Yeah, it looks pretty nice
when you have dinosaur bones. What's the significance of dinosaur bones?
Alberta is famous for dinosaur bones.
The Toll
museum. Yeah,
Albertos
Arus.
There's a dinosaur called Albertos
Yeah, I think we were part of the precambrian basin.
So there's,
there was a lot of sedimentary rock laid down with a lot of dinosaur bones.
And if you go down to, um, Drum Heller Provincial Park, you know, they,
they have a giant, a really good dinosaur museum.
And you've got like, honestly,
it's funny for me because all our museums and
stuff are just full of dinosaurs and dinosaur bones.
And I was like, what's the big deal? Right. Doesn't everybody have that
well? And the answer is no.
That's right. That's right. Uh Yes, I found a picture of the Alberto Saurus.
So I will put that in the show notes for anyone who is interested.
But it is a, it is a real thing. Kurt did not make this up.
I almost never make things up.
You don't. But some of your stories are unbelievable. And so I always fact check them
and
this is one of those, one of those instances.
So anyway, anyway,
identifying people.
And so the reality is, I mean, the good news is, you know,
99 times out of 100 when you rent a car to somebody, they're not going to steal it.
The problem is if you have a weak process,
well, that's who the Attackers are going to go after
because it's just easier. Right? They'll be more successful.
This is, this is a fair point. I guess when I rent a car
I show up, I give them a credit card and an ID
and then they give me a car
and I feel like
there's not a lot of crazy process going on here. So what made this?
They don't take a picture of you.
They don't take your fingerprints. No, they don't.
No, they don't do any of that stuff. I've, I've never had a problem. So,
so why is this? Although I guess the one difference with this
particular services. It was all like online magic, wasn't it? Versus
having to talk to a human.
Yeah, I know this was,
you could you get the app and you give the app the right data and
you can use the app to unlock a car and drive off with it.
So why, why would people be different?
Well, I think part of it boils down to is, is the retribute of getting caught aspects.
So for example, you know, all those spam phone calls we get, you know,
with various scams,
there's basically zero risk to the scammer of number one getting caught.
And even if they somehow did get caught,
you know, uh, the CBC news here has done investigations and gone,
actually gone to India and
paid a person to go work in the call center to collect video.
Like, so what, you know,
and they even got one of these call centers shut down and it
was hilarious because they show they have this like truck full of like,
you know, old P CS and
the police are hurting like 200 people out
and, you know, and it's up and running the next week,
right? And by the end of the day it was back.
And so that's the thing, if, if I can go around,
commit a trying to commit a crime with no sort of downside for being caught.
You know, for example, those people who walk around testing car door handles
to see if they're locked or not and if they're not locked, you know, they,
they rummage around your car and try and steal stuff
if there was zero chance of getting caught.
Well,
somebody is more likely to do that than to do an
activity where they could get caught and could get punished.
That is potentially fair. And
if it's all digital, you also have the instance of,
you probably don't need a very believable ID, right?
You could either Photoshop it or potentially even just
print it out on a piece of paper.
Yeah.
Well, and I was also thinking kind of like that,
remember we talked about the Russian casino scam thing where it ran on your phone,
but that sent the data to rush to be interpreted and
then send it back to you telling you went to hit.
I think there's an element of that here where you can have somebody smart
who figures out how to scam the system
and then they can get, let's say mules
to actually go pick up the cars.
That's probably true too because if I was a mastermind behind this,
you wouldn't catch me dead with one of these stolen cars
because that's like you're going to jail if you have it.
And if you're smart, you're living in Russia doing this or somewhere,
you know where you just the, the chances of extradition and well,
the chances of getting caught and extradition are zero.
And so, and I think that's a big aspect of it because if I,
if somebody can commit crime across borders,
I mean, it's at the point where, you know, even in the US now, right? Aren't there?
I think it was the FBI was sort of off the record quoted as saying, ok, ransomware.
Yeah, go pay it. Like, what, what do you want us to do? That's an interesting topic.
Also. I was reading a story
either earlier today or yesterday where all of these cities
now are getting hit by ransomware it seems like.
And a bunch of them are obviously just paying the ransoms
and certain people are are losing their minds saying, oh,
how could you possibly do that?
You know, you're, you're creating a market for ransom. I
mean, it exists already but whatever,
but now I believe it was the city of Las Vegas just basically signed on to some
charter thing that says we will never pay ransom
if, if we're random. I'm like, yeah, that's easy to say.
Now wait till you're hit with it. A great example of that.
That's how the market for kidnapping was shut down in the
US was a combination of we will not pay the ransom.
And number two, we will chase you to the ends of the earth and make sure you get caught.
But that's different.
Well, I'm just saying, but it is essentially possible to eliminate
pretty much an entire class of crime which is kidnapping for money.
Right. You still get a lot of, you know, parental kidnapping type stuff.
But the actual kidnapping for money as a business is basically not a thing in the US.
Whereas in other countries it's doing well.
Sadly,
I, I have no doubt
but in the,
I don't think it's a fair comparison because
something like ransomware or stealing cars or whatever.
Oh, it's definitely a lot harder. Right. You can do it from a remote location.
Whereas if you're going to kidnap someone in the United States,
you have to be in the United States.
Well, and I think the,
the impact of the crime is a lot higher.
Like, I think the impact of the crime is a lot higher and it's a lot more newsworthy
because to put it bluntly, you know, somebody kidnaps a person for money.
Yeah, that's,
but somebody, what do you mean your computers are encrypted?
Why don't you just whatever restore from backups? Like, who cares?
And not only that if you're kidnapping someone for money,
you have to kidnap someone with a lot of money.
And chances are if they have a lot of money, people know who they are.
So you're talking about kind of celebrity level
incident here.
Whereas if the city of Baltimore has a ransomware event, people are like,
ok.
And I bet in the United States if I pulled out a map and said point to Baltimore for me,
less than half of the people could get it right within a circle.
That is 100 miles large. True.
I would point sort of at the east coast generic.
But in Canada we actually had a case of an armed kidnapping of,
I believe he's a Chinese national.
He's over here as a student
and apparently comes from a wealthy family.
And, yeah,
now the police have arrested the four sus suspect in the armed kidnapping.
So, you know, and,
and that made the national news here because literally the
number of armed kidnappings like for money in Canada is,
it's like in the single digits yearly.
I would hope so.
I I agree because what is, yeah, here it is saying the city of Baltimore,
uh they wanted a ransom payment of 13 Bitcoin.
So whatever that is now
probably a bigger number than when this
article was published apparently because they are
not paying is my understanding and trying to clean up and fix it.
Here we go in total young,
estimated the aftermath of the attack would cost the city $10 million in
addition to the $8 million lost while the city could not process payments,
the figure could rise as the city pays for
cybersecurity experts to bolster their systems in the future.
So that 18 million doesn't even include fixing it,
right. It'll, it'll go up, it'll go up a lot. I I think
when, when the city of Atlanta got nailed
the the ransomer wanted like $46,000 and I feel like it cost them
28 million or something. It was ridiculous.
$46,000 is, I mean, that's like single digits,
numbers of servers being purchased and maintained and run for a year.
But at the same time,
people don't want to pay ransoms because they feel it empowers the ransomers.
Well, it makes a market right.
There would be no market for ransomware if nobody paid. But I,
man, there's so much, there's so much here.
Oh, somebody starts throwing paint at my house and says I'll stop for $10.
Yeah, I might just pay the $10 right. You know,
so let me ask you this and this is,
this is a conversation topic that comes up on
a regular basis when I discuss this with people
is ransomware.
The tax you pay for being insecure effectively.
Yeah, it creates a market and you can call it a tax or, or it's,
it's an external and are we comfortable saying that?
Well, to me,
a tax implies taking money and then doing something good with
it or maybe not good or at least filling potholes or,
you know, trying to, trying to do something good with it.
Let's go with that. Right.
I think we can generally agree that
as annoying as taxes are, they're, we're,
we're generally trying to do something useful with them
like infrastructure or paying for firemen or whatever.
I'm, I'm sure this will go to infrastructure in
Russia or something.
Yeah.
So the, the challenge would be, I mean, the reality is if you're bad at it,
there's all sorts of costs.
Like you can't be agile, you can't upgrade systems and take advantage of new things.
You can't
do things that your competitors can do when it comes to security.
A simple example would be, you know, you get shut down for a week or two and your,
your competitors don't, you know, all the people that can,
well, how many people get d
dost
and die
versus how many people that get de
dost. And they're like, yeah, that's Tuesday. We get de
Dost on Tuesday. Now, let's ok.
So let's, let's take this and, and turn it on its head a little more
if you're bad at it.
And I'm assuming if you're bad at it, you're probably also bad at security.
If you're bad at it,
you're going to have more downtime than someone who isn't bad at it.
Right?
So, is a ransomware incident any different than your infrastructure just,
you know,
you know, committing suicide one day because it sucks.
I'm gonna say yes, because you, you actually, generally speaking,
have a guaranteed way to fix it for a guaranteed cost, which for most it problems,
that's not the case, right?
A lot of it problems boil down to.
Well, we, we think we can fix it and we think it will cost this much and then of course,
it goes way over budget.
And so ironically, ransomware,
it sounds like most of these ransomware attacks are reasonably
legit when it comes to you paying and getting your encryption keys.
Yeah. No, you can say like we will pay X and they will give us the keys and,
and it's done
and for a lot of businesses that kind of certainty, they love that
because how many it projects have you? And I seen
go over budget over time or just fail
all of them?
Well, you know, the stats I read are the,
the average seems to be at least 50% as high
as 90% depending on what sector and type it is.
I, I believe that
I believe that so perversely in a way paying the, the Attackers,
I suspect a lot of these people would trust
the Attackers more than their own it department.
And as evidenced by the fact that their it department
ran it so poorly that they got hit by ransomware.
That may be a reasonable description even
though I imagine it's not popular honestly.
I mean,
I've been doing it for over 20 years now and this
is the reason I have all my stuff in the cloud.
I am as good as I am. I am not competent enough.
There's no way I can defend against
DDOS.
No,
no. And I pay cloud flare
like 20 bucks a month.
I, what can I do for 20 bucks? A month, like, seriously, although
cloud flare went down the other day and everyone lost their minds.
Well, and at least what I like is they went down for a somewhat interesting reason,
which is, as it turns out, operations of global scale is still hard, who knew?
You know,
at least they're not going down like Verizon where it's
like if Verizon had implemented this well known security protocol,
so they didn't get fake B GP routes,
there wouldn't have been a problem as far as I know. Pretty much all the ransomware.
Very few of them use a zero day.
I think. Not. Petya used a zero day in that accounting software.
That wasn't ransomware. That was like a cyber attack.
That was war.
Yeah.
In general, the majority of ransomware use known flaws or if they do use a zero day,
then why is that ransomware still chugging along months or even years later?
Right. I mean, that's fair. And
I think an important point to that also is
when you have a zero day,
you can only use it a couple of times before it, it's gone. I'm going to disagree.
You can only use it a couple of times against competent defenders. That is true.
That is true.
But, like,
look at member Stuxnet that was a zero day and the people are
still getting hit by those flaws because they haven't patched their systems.
You know, they, they failed so poorly at basic hygiene.
I, I mean, come on, you and I both know
of people with systems that are a decade out of date running in production.
But that up time. Right.
It's so good. I haven't rebooted in two years.
You know, I, I'm guilty of this.
I ran Fedora in production for six or for three years and as
everybody who's run Fedora knows you actually only get 12 months of support.
I, I don't remember if I said this on the podcast,
but I actually migrated my breast.net machine to running in S3.
Amazon S3
because I logged in one day
and I realized that
I was two years behind
schedule.
And I thought, well, this isn't good.
And I thought I, for whatever reason in my brain,
I thought I was running Sent Os and I had
automatic updates on and I logged in,
I did have automatic updates on there. Just weren't any automatic updates.
So
the last year or two,
it's like, well,
this is a great reason to get rid of this.
Well,
and there's a perfect example of the cost and time of upgrading Fedora across what,
three or four versions,
it's actually not that bad, right.
You're looking at probably one or two hours, but it was less work to just dump it in S3.
And now I never have to think about it again for the rest of my life.
And, and I mean, that's the exact same thing I did with c.org Right.
It's been an S3 bucket for about
almost a decade now. And that's part of the challenge though, is a lot of companies
as bad as their, it is, it's kind of not bad enough to make those decisions.
Uh That could very well be, I, I don't doubt it.
How many places are still running their own email servers
with, and let's say running their own email servers with less than
20 users Even. That sounds like a sad, sad email server.
It's, I mean, small medium business, the whole thing. I, I think
fundamentally I think it boils down to that. That's the challenge with security.
Right. Is that
it's not that you
are dealing with computer bugs or weird behavior.
You're dealing with an intelligent human adversary
and the human adversary will wait.
You know, I, I'm sure there's people now keeping an eye on car services going.
Hey, that worked with car to go.
Ok, let's keep an eye on all these other car services and wait for them to, like,
decrease their requirements for renting cars and when they do that
king it, it wouldn't shock me at all.
Or now they're going, hey, how much does it cost to hire some patsy to do this? Oh.
Right. Right. Absolutely.
Yeah. I don't, I don't know.
I, I mean, I think about this and there, there's so many problems here. Right.
There's the fact that we don't have
a way to easily identify people
I mean, I think that's kind of problem number one.
Well, not just identify but validate that identity.
Right. Yeah. Sure. Exactly. I consider it the same thing, but. Right. Right.
Same, same thing.
You've got that issue
then you've got the problem of, so you've got this crazy expensive vehicle.
What now?
Right. How do you, how do you keep something like that safe?
Well, and I'm kind of surprised they don't have, like,
tracking systems installed in them because they would have had to fit it
out with stuff for the app to talk to and unlock the car and
whatever. Right.
Yeah, you, you'd think so al although, although at the same time, Kurt,
would you rent a car if the company is tracking exactly where you're going with it?
That's already a thing with some rental car companies. Is it?
I don't know, I don't, I don't feel like I'm aware of that
and I would think twice about it.
Uh, for example,
I know somebody that ordered a Mercedes ship
from Germany and they lost the damn thing
for a while
and, and my thought was like, I know that cars are kind of,
well, they're not big, but come on, like, really?
And my thought was they're pretty big.
Why do I have, like, real time delivery information
on
my small packages?
What you know, like,
can't you literally just glue an Android phone to the inside of the container
with the car in it poke a little hole in it for the antenna
and, you know, stick a car, like, stick a, a big, you know,
marine deep cycle battery in it to power the phone for
a month or however long it takes to ship the darn thing
and then you just know exactly where the car is pretty much in real time.
Um, you know, unless it's like on a container ship in the middle of the ocean,
in which case,
you can probably guess that it's on that container ship and just track that thing.
You know, assuming the container doesn't fall off the ship, you're fine.
And, I mean, it just kind of blows me away though.
I have, you know, better tracking on my pizza than on a car.
I'm ordering from Germany.
Yeah,
I mean, that's, that's fair.
That's interesting to think about.
So, I, I suspect as time goes on we'll see more of this tracking
and telemetry on
stuff. Right. Because internet of things, I will say
the one other thing to consider is
if we have a universe where people aren't driving their cars,
it kind of makes car theft go away
in a lot of ways. Right. Because now the car is just gonna drive itself. Yeah.
Well, exactly.
Like, if there's no controls to you, you'd have to what, I guess, get a tow truck and
physically, like, lift the car up and take off with it.
But then what are you going to do with it once you have it chop it up for parts, uh,
who's buying the parts,
people in other countries that ask less questions of what cheap parts.
And they could be,
I mean, those, those Tesla batteries they're worth, uh,
I forget what they're worth but it's, I think it was like, 10 grand or something.
I'm sure it's not zero.
Yeah, it's to say the least.
I guess the problem is we still have the same problems we had 1020 years ago.
And are they going to get better? No, that's it. That's, that's the
end of my thought
that, that, that's the thought. And I feel like
this is one of those instances where criminals are
very opportunistic and sometimes the technology and the,
the function functions of society have to catch up
to accommodate dealing with crime in that way.
And, and this is one of those instances I guess is how do we have online services
where you're trying to validate who a human is and
you can't.
So criminals abuse it.
Well, and a second problem is it's not just about identifying the user,
but intent is their intent to rent the car,
do their thing and return it or is there intent to steal the car?
I, I don't know what the answer is.
I feel like we will probably figure it out
because we've always figured it out in the past,
but I don't know.
Yeah, I don't know where we go, we will, we will see.
So. All right, man. Um I'm ending it. So, thank you everyone for listening.
Thank you, Kurt. You can go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up the show
notes, you can use the P
and OS podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media.
Yeah, Kurt, have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the