Hello and welcome to the open source Security podcast episode 77 with myself,
Kurt Siegfried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
What's New Kurt?
Uh, we're finally getting some snow.
Finally. You live in, like the north of the Arctic Circle and you haven't had snow.
We've had,
we had a little bit of snow early on in the year and then
we had a little bit of snow a few weeks ago and it,
it got warm
and so my front lawn was actually, I would say maybe only two thirds covered in snow.
And then there was that really terrible brown looking grass.
And you've told me all the skiing you've done though,
I assume your ski hills have the magic snow machines.
Yes.
Well, I mean, Snow Valley is literally inside the city. It's a 15 minute drive away.
And so
you can actually take a bus there if you want.
So if, if they're in the city and they make snow,
do they accidentally like it snow on someone's sidewalk if
they're in a valley,
I suppose,
hence
the
name?
Yeah,
exactly.
Yeah, I know. Hey,
um, yeah.
And, well, the trick with snow making those,
it has to be below a certain temperature and they
usually make snow at night because it's colder then.
Um, and so we were lucky because this year we had essentially,
we had very early snow for about a week
and then we had a cold snap of like, minus 1020 degrees for about 23 weeks.
I assume this is Celsius, the gentleman's temperature scale.
Ok.
-- The, the one that all of the world uses except for America,
-- except for that one place.
Yeah. Yeah.
Uh, but, uh, yeah, so they, they were able to make a ton of snow early in the season.
So we've been going skiing, like, 23 times a week
for a couple of months now.
Yeah, it's awesome.
But, uh, yeah.
No, it's, uh,
it's winter and it's funny though because we had a cold snap and everyone was like,
oh, my God, why is it so cold?
And I'm like,
it's the first week of January.
Like, that's,
that's normal.
That's
what
I don't understand the question.
Warming.
I know.
But, uh,
yeah, so, well, I mean, I guess this week's latest kerfuffle is the whole, no Js.
Yeah, this one's really good
actually.
Well, there's,
there's kind of two stories I really like on this one is there was the issue of I, it's,
what is it left pad this time or something?
Well, it was kick and then left pad.
-- Ok.
-- And that was,
that was a few months ago
when that
happened.
Ok.
Kick was this one.
No kick led to left pad
and it's just being brought up again because there was
ok. So yeah, there was, there
was the original kerfuffle.
Ok.
So the two main things are uh so no Js is uh well, no Js
and like many modern things,
it has a packaging system so that you can like go grab a package that, you know,
converts dates or
whatever, uh changes the font color of your log files, whatever.
And there was a developer who had a package called Kkik
and there was a company called Kick
and they exchanged some emails apparently and
essentially they couldn't come to an agreement.
So the company went to the uh N PM people and under their
sort of package name, dispute
resolution process,
they booted the developer with Kik off and let
the company take over the name of that package.
So essentially they
N PM controls the name space for
N PM.
And that's important because like when you, you know, node install
blank, you're getting whatever it is they send you right. Hopefully it's
what you expect.
Um
So basically this developer, I guess, didn't really appreciate that.
So they deleted
all of their packages off of N PM and they had one package called left pad,
which basically like literally,
oh
like straight up, just
left pads, text,
right, just like what was it was right shift was the last one.
Right.
It's like,
yeah.
And so it was used and depended on by,
by thousands or hundreds or thousands or whatever of,
of other N PM packages which then all failed.
Well,
and the other thing to remember too is
in any sort of packaging ecosystem.
It's turtles all the way down because everything depends on everything.
Eventually.
I wonder
-- if we've gotten to the point of circular dependencies.
-- I guarantee they exist.
I guarantee they exist. Well, I remember writing dependency
uh algorithms
along. I don't remember why I even did. Oh no, that's right.
I, I worked for a company called Progeny Linux systems like a million years ago.
And one of the things we were doing
was trying to build like customizable Linux distributions.
And so obviously a package dependencies. It was, it was crazy, man.
This was back in like 04, maybe 02. I mean, it was, it was a cool idea back then, right?
And the answer ended up being containers but
ignoring
the answer ended up being jam it all until
straight
up, just
keep adding.
And I, I remember writing
something that would kind of go through all
the dependencies and figure all this stuff out because
yeah, it was,
you'd end up with things like circular dependencies
and you'd have to make sure certain things
depended on certain other things in certain ways and,
and things got crazy out of hand doing this.
And I, I remember that, that was actually really fun work,
but it was ultimately unsuccessful.
Yeah. So anyways, it's
so that's the first kind of story about the N PM.
And this has also happened with lots of other, you know,
um
package systems like uh Ruby gems.org is a good example.
Ruby gems.org is sort of the Ruby Gems package or
that or site that won the Ruby Gems Wars.
Uh There were actually sort of three main ones to begin with.
And so you essentially had three separate name spaces.
And so for example,
there were packages that were like had the same name across three name spaces,
but were controlled by different people,
you know. So,
so yeah, exactly like and, and some of these were pretty clearly, you know,
not super good guys.
Um I think one of the names that was squatted on was like the B zip two package.
Um
because something to remember is, I mean,
let's, let's how do I put this nicely,
the majority of developer developers, especially in the DEV
ops Agile World,
they write a bunch of code with a bunch of, you know,
import or depends or whatever statements
and they don't audit that code
and they don't audit the code that that code pulls in and so on and so on and circular.
And I mean, quite literally,
it's quite common for something like a note Js
application to then pull in dependencies which
pull in dependencies which you end up with
easily over 100 megabytes of, you know, Min
javascript,
which is literally enough javascript to, like, you know,
build an airline reservation system,
like straight up.
-- That's a great comparison.
-- Right.
Basically,
it's so much code that nobody will ever be able to
audit it and actually determine what it does or doesn't do.
You know, and the system runs on trust and,
and, and it mostly works. It's, it's ok.
Right. You know, people find flaws, we squash the flaws and there's luckily
there don't seem to be many bad actors getting involved in this probably because,
uh,
-- well, I don't know why because it is quite,
-- I have
some thoughts actually. And, and this is, there was a
story someone wrote
and the title, let me, let me pull the title up here.
It's titled I'm Harvesting credit card numbers and passwords from your site.
Here's how,
and this guy kind of laid out
if he was going to say abuse
node
and have a malicious package that was
stealing information off of people's websites,
kind of what he would do.
And I started reading this
and I was thinking this is extremely plausible
and then
I think,
and, and no, no, here's, I, I don't think it is anymore.
I, I put a lot of thought into this and, and I think
this sounds like something that, that will work in a very short term.
But you have to remember. This is the long game we're talking about here. Right.
And,
and the thing is you only have to get caught once I
view this as kind of like the reverse blue team problem where
the blue team has to succeed. Every time the red team only has to succeed. Once
in a situation like this,
you have to stay undetected forever once you're detected, once
it's game over
ever. But
I mean, for example, let's say the guy,
So the premise of the article was this guy wrote
a uh N PM package that uh actually yeah,
changed the font color of your log files to make him pretty
and then also harvested credit card numbers, you know,
and they had some tricks like only harvesting credit
card numbers between like 7 p.m. and 7 a.m. and
um you know,
trying to do it intelligently so that if you were
using like square or things with like good security,
it wouldn't, you know, get in the way of that and kind of block it.
And here's the thing.
I mean, it takes a lot of work up front,
which probably is why a lot of Attackers aren't
doing it because Attackers are going for like,
I want to break into a website in half an hour,
harvest a pile of credit card numbers and sell them online, right?
Not,
I want to invest six months building up this long
con and then harvest a pile of credit card numbers.
Right? I, I think that's part of it. Yes.
And, and not only that though,
so here's
what I keep thinking about is
you do this
and you'll be successful for a little while.
But like all these mitigations, this guy talked about
those mitigations might work at 80% of organizations,
but they're not going to work at 100.
Right. And again, you only have to get caught once and the con is up.
True.
But the question is like,
does the con go on long enough to harvest a big pile of credit cards?
-- And, and
-- I,
yes, it certainly could.
I think if you actually started this,
you could probably get thousands or hundreds
of thousands of numbers before you're caught.
But kind of the point being and, and the thing I keep thinking of is
I would be surprised if you could get away with this for more than 3 to 6 months,
maybe a year if you're lucky.
And now,
granted, that's a super long time. I'm not saying it isn't,
but you're gonna get caught.
And that's what tells me the fact that we haven't heard about this
before suggests to me no one's done it because you're gonna get found.
You're not going to be able to do this 100%. Right.
Well,
there have been modules that were leaking
information or exposing information and then it's,
the question is, well,
is this a malicious piece of code or just really poor programming?
Right. And and
that, I
think we could debate for days.
You know, I, I'm totally willing to
go
with
Hanlon's
Razor on this one.
Yeah, I kind of agree. I think it's, it's often silly mistakes
but, but
like this story here is,
it is hugely complex and, and I think
this also makes me think of like movie, movie Theft
where
you, you look at movie plots and the bad guys have these insanely elaborate plans
and it's like in real life,
you could never do that
-- in real life. If your plan has more than two steps, you're going to fail.
-- Right?
Well, part of it too is this, this is one of those things where
you need a lot of domain specific knowledge
to even
interact with the systems, let alone interact with them in a malicious way,
right?
You know, he gives the example of, I mean, first of all,
you'd have to be able to write some useful, no Js code.
OK? That right there raises the bar of it, then you'd have to publish it to N PM. OK?
Then you'd have to convince other people to embed it.
Then you'd have to do, you know,
um or you'd have to make a lot of other fake projects that embedded,
to make it look real, you'd have to make a pile of github
accounts that look real.
You'd have to, you know,
you and granted, you know, if you wrote some tooling around this to automate it,
then you only have to do that once.
But again, even, you know, that is a level of sophistication and expertise that,
yeah, probably not a lot of Attackers have or if they do have it, you know,
they're going to use it for slightly more targeted and direct attacks.
Um,
this kind of reminds me of that whole, it's like spam in a way and that, you know,
rather than these targeted attacks
that we focus on a lot, these kind of spam level attacks where I'm just gonna like,
slam everybody and, yeah, like 99% of people will just block it out.
Right. But 1% might be stupid enough to fall for it and like,
you know, believe that the Nigerian Princes need your credit card number.
Um, and I kind of wonder if we're also approaching that
security era as it were because,
you know, these targeted attacks definitely work. Um,
but I mean,
they, you know, they take, they take a lot of personal effort
and if, you know,
if I, if you tell an attacker, hey, here's a tool.
It'll automatically attack 1000 websites and, you know,
one of them will be vulnerable and you'll get credit
card numbers and you just run it for an hour.
Yeah, they'll probably start doing that.
-- All
-- right. Yeah,
I, I think you might be right.
And, and not only that, speaking of Nigerian Princes,
I remember reading an interview with one of those scammers once
and someone asked, like, why, why is your spelling so bad?
And, and like, why are these stories so ridiculous? And he said,
you have to make it as over the top
as possible because that way you know anyone who replies
is you've got them right?
Because these aren't people who,
who probably have a firm grasp on what's going on around them necessarily.
It reminds me of three card Monty.
If you don't know that somebody on the street doing three card Monty is a scam,
then OK, you're the mark.
Yes, that's exactly right.
You know how, how anybody thinks they can win a three card Monte on the street.
Uh No, but the guy before me won. So,
but the guy before me just won. So I know I can because I'm smarter than him.
Oh, man, I know
you was funny about that is I was, I was at,
I was, there's this touristy trap in Wisconsin called Wisconsin Dells.
And right, it's all full of water parks and it is a nice place.
And we were, there was a street magician there and the guy was like, hey,
you guys got to come here and do this and I,
I literally kept my hand in my pocket on my
wallet the entire time he was doing his magic.
I'm like, this dude's gonna steal my wallet
and I'm not gonna know it.
-- And like I, the things he did
-- did you
check for your phone.
Uh, I did not. That was in my other pocket and
I admit I was slightly less concerned about. Oh, here's the thing though.
The street magicians never steal someone's cell phone, right?
They always steal the wallet,
right. Like that's the, that's the gimmick.
And so
I, in fact, now that you say it,
I think a street magician stealing your cell phone would be very cool.
But no, it's always the wallet, man. You should know that.
So, anyway, and, and,
and, yeah, the crap this guy did, it was like, I,
people are terrible at dealing with hucksters like this. Right.
And the guy was great. Right. He gave everyone all their stuff back.
He stole from him. But it's like, holy crap if this guy wanted to be.
Although I guess that's part of the story. Right.
That guy could become a pickpocket and he would probably do, ok.
But I get, he's, I,
I bet he makes way more money as a street magician than he would stealing from people.
Not counting the fact that he's probably going
to jail.
Right. Exactly. Exactly.
I mean, heck, I gave him like, 20 bucks because my kids were just, like,
enthralled by this show.
Right.
Whereas had he stole my wallet,
he would have made about 25 bucks. Right.
That's,
that's what it would have been. You never have cash.
Yeah.
Yeah. No, this, uh, going back to the N PM. Thing.
Uh, part of what really sort of scares me in a way is that
we have these systems where people own a name space
that is globally used
and, and all of a sudden becomes very important, uh,
like a great example of this is like, Yelp.
Yelp owns the kind of Yelp wants to own the name space of all businesses
and, you know, well, it'd be a shame if your business got a bad rating on Yelp.
But hey, you can pay us to get, you know,
those bad ratings suppressed or the good ratings on top or whatever, right.
You know, same thing like Google
to put it bluntly,
I don't go to restaurants that score below four on Google Maps.
I
just straight up, don't,
I totally get it.
And like, quite frankly, Google could,
you know, more and more people are going to be doing this, I assume because
I, I'm at a point in my life where it's like, wait a second,
there's like a ton of really good restaurants.
Why would I go to this one with like a 3.2 rating where
people are saying that like the staff is surly and the food is cold
like that. Why, why would I even, you know, bother
looking at the restaurant, let alone going there to eat right now. I
don't let me ask this in the context of Saint Node package managers.
Is there a way to rate
the packages
Well, see, and that's sort of, uh,
one of the things with a lot of these name spaces is
they don't really do that or it's sort of implied rating by,
you know, how many people use it
or, like on github,
you know, how many people are starred? This, how many people are watching it?
How many people have forked it?
Right. Yes, I do. And I use that kind of as a metric when I'm looking at code
to kind of see, you know, like,
oh, this code has like, you know, 2000 people watching it. Ok?
It's, yeah, it's probably somewhat legit versus like, oh,
this code has nobody starring it.
Nobody watching it, nobody has forked it.
Nobody cares about this code,
you know.
Um
And, but the thing is these,
these control of the name space is incredibly powerful because in most cases,
it's very opaque in the sense of like you can
do whatever you want and nobody has any recourse,
right?
Um
You know, like
uh some name spaces have very official policy and rules like for example,
DNS the domain name system, right?
You know, if I register something.com and there's a company with that, you know,
they can come after me and there's a bunch of laws
they can use to recover that domain name and it's,
you know, there's at least some laws and process that are documented, but
you look at things like say N PM and looking at the name space policy.
I'm not really clear why
the company Kik man, you know, got
was allowed to grab this package name away
from the developer who originally built it.
-- I mean, if there's a trademark, the
-- blog entry kind of reads like BS,
well, the blog entry might be and they're not lawyers, but I mean,
you can make legitimate trademark claims against things like that.
I mean, if you're a company named Kik the
software,
but the problem with trademarks is that trademarks are quite often just local.
So for example, what happens when you have three different K companies,
one in Canada, one in Uzbekistan and one in Australia,
it's going to fall to probably let's face it,
the American company because I assume that's where,
where much of this silliness often happens and where many of these people live
and, and look,
I'm not gonna piss off the local, whoever in my country, right?
They're the ones I care about like, yeah, Canada is great and all, but
I'm not worried about them. I don't know.
-- Yeah,
-- exactly.
And see, that's the thing about,
that's the problem with names spaces is up until recently, the world
didn't have global name spaces, right? You,
you generally didn't worry about Bob's Deli
in Australia having the same name as Bob. Bob's Deli down the road,
you know, but now that's a problem with these, especially with these, you know,
single name spaces like
N PM or CPA
or Ruby Jams, you know where it is global in nature.
And then there, you know, for example, you have nouns like Amazon.
Amazon is just a well known place name and it's also a large company.
It used to be a well known place name.
Now it's a company.
Yeah,
you know, and so like for example, Square,
right?
That's a big payment processor. But you know, it's also the word square.
And what if I write a package called square that like
measures the space?
I don't know, it does something with squares,
geographic or geometrically speaking, I don't know,
you know,
should square have the right to take that away
from me because they have the trademark on Square.
Well,
yeah, exactly. Whereas
the name space control and where's the lawyers and all that. But
-- I,
-- I think we should say the
other thing is the open
source legal podcast.
But, but the really ugly problem here is that
most people use these name spaces without thinking about it at all.
Right.
So
these people all pulling in left pad, for example, and
it disappears one day and all their apps all break, right?
And I mean, well, I used to work for Red Hat and I still do and this is why Red Hat,
for example,
we take software and we package it and we package it in a way so that there's no
um
like external dependencies, you know, when we install an R PM on your system.
It's not like, oh, I gotta go
off to some random website and grab a bunch of stuff.
Right.
And,
and I think that is still completely valid and I think if you're operating in
an environment where you don't keep copies of
the artifacts you're putting in your products,
you're going to have a bad day.
Well, yeah, for, and the other aspect too is if that,
you know, if it goes away, you're boned and or if it changes.
Yeah. Can you revert to a known good copy?
Like if somebody hacks a developer account and then puts malicious code,
not even hack a developer account, man.
I mean,
how many of these projects don't have breaking changes between versions where you,
you just
upgrade to a new version? I mean,
it's super common
and,
and now we've made it to a supply chain
argument which is totally where this was headed anyway.
And, and yeah, I mean,
this is one of the things I,
I deal with this constantly every day and I think
about it all the time is the fact that,
you know, there is an open source supply chain
and
we aren't doing a good job of,
of dealing with it.
Like there's some companies like Red Hat is,
is in honestly the poster child for doing it right.
And, and I look at a lot of places that are doing it horribly wrong
and I work at a place that I would say is doing it pretty good. Right?
I won't, I won't say we're perfect. Not that Red Hat was perfect either.
-- But,
-- but here's
in fairness, there is no
easy tooling or frameworks.
Like for example, there's no N PM as far as I know,
no CPA N PM or whatever framework where
you like tied into your C I system and it acts as a caching layer that also magically
actually, there are some
but
-- they're not
-- easy
-- to set up
-- more
expensive.
And
I mean, it's part of the problem I think
of
this is really hard to do
and it needs people because we don't have
any standardized anything today for dealing with this.
It's well,
I think part of the biggest problem is a lot of this problem exists
not at the developer layer but at like the build and continuous integration layer,
right?
If it was at the a developer layer, you would just check the code into your git boom,
done, right?
But that's not how these systems work. You have your code and get
and then when you build it or run it,
it automatically magically pulls in a whole pile of dependencies, right?
Like a deploy time, not a development time, right?
And so,
you know, uh well, for example,
like we the the the cloud security lines has several ruby
on rails, applications for like the CCS K and stars.
And you know, we have the code that we've written in.
Get
cool.
And then, you know, when we deploy it,
uh what is it called? Uh,
rail ties, whatever, whatever the thing that
magically pulls in all the dependencies is does that
on the server keeps them up to date?
And it's kind of like, well, you know,
yeah, how do we, how do we properly back that up in an easy way?
I mean, I can back up the entire server. Cool.
But how do I kind of have say like rail ties or whatever
kind of give me a cash copy of those in a, in a structured way that I can more easily use.
And the answer is there's not really a good, simple, easy answer for this,
you know,
um I know some major companies,
what they do is they basically they block access to things like Ruby gems.org
and they run their own internal version of it and you know, they, they,
oh developer wants this package.
OK. We're going to go download that package, audit it, put it into our local,
you know, instance
and you can now use that and it's so it's now, you know, internally
copied and run.
Uh
And like that's gonna happen with maybe a
couple dozen or 100 companies around the globe,
right? No developer is going to ever do that.
It's also hard because you need,
that's a very specialized skill set and you, you need to be of a certain size.
I mean, start ups aren't going to be able to do this because it's very difficult.
Right.
It's, it's, it's hard
and it gets even harder because
you might be pulling in one dependency and you think all right,
I'm gonna check out this dependency.
But then your dependency pulls in 20 dependencies and those
20 dependencies pull in 30 dependencies and it gets,
it gets really crazy.
And that's where I think a lot of this
kind of let, let's audit everything can start to fall apart because again,
it's turtles all the way down and it's, it's so hard.
It's so crazy man.
And, and this, although I mean, I'll, I'll point out
github is, is hopefully going to help deal with some of this
with their, their dependency checker they have.
But even that I know is going to take probably years before I'd say it's,
it's good enough,
right?
This stuff is hard.
Yeah.
Yeah, I mean, there are things that do this but again, it's,
they're not really
easy, automat, shareable. You know, there's no,
like as far as I know,
there's no like simple plug in that you can
basically like tie into your github and be like,
so every time you build this, the C I system will magically
do its thing.
But also this other system will get a copy of everything and keep it
and index it and catalog it and make sure it's the right one,
you know.
Well, you know, what else? I think part of the issue here also is
what's the incentive to do this?
There's a handful of.
-- But yeah, it's, it's
-- too hard until it breaks horribly and, and,
and well, the thing too to remember is so the left pad example is great.
You remove left pad from N PM and it breaks um a bajillion apps
but fixing and replacing left pad on,
on N PM took like one developer five minutes because he had a like a copy of it,
right? Like it's open source, right? So he just uploaded a new copy,
took the names. Uh N PM allows you to take the name space of abandoned projects.
So basically one guy fixed it quickly by you know, re uploading it. Basically
you compare that to the effort of like
these million projects running local cash stuff.
Yeah.
No,
it's clearly a lot less work to have one guy fix it on N PM than to have a million people,
you know, build a bunker of of cached files in case you know,
the the end times come for that file,
right? And that's part of the problem with a lot of these, you know,
uh solutions is that
kind of everybody has to do it to be safe, you know,
and that just
between expertise and scale and resources is just not going to happen.
So we end up with these centralized, you know, attempts at solutions.
Yes.
And
man,
I don't know. I, I think about this one a lot and I don't know what the answer is today.
Uh,
there is a project that's really cool actually. Uh,
some, some ex red hat guys.
What is Tide Lift I think is the name of their company and it's libraries dot IO.
And it's, it's starting to track some of this stuff.
They've got a long way to go, of course, but
it's,
it's the beginning I think.
And if I was gonna put money on anybody today,
it would probably be those guys because one of my complaints I have and,
and you and I discussed this often
is like we have a standard for tracking security flaws in software. It's called CV E
and how many of these private vulnerability database
type places actually use CV E consistently.
None of them. The answer is none of them.
And I have a suspicion
they don't have an incentive to use CV E because they want to
say my database has more stuff in it than their database does.
So I'm clearly better than you.
And it's like, no, you're just all a bunch of idiots that's not,
you're not better than anybody
work together.
Well, you know, it reminds me of antivirus companies, right? Like they, they all
the
amount of duplication of effort is
literally insane.
Well, it used to be much worse.
I mean, I, I, from what I gather, they actually work together now to a degree.
-- But back in the day
-- they do, there is a lot of,
there's
of code samples and that's been around for a long time.
But,
but before that even I remember hearing stories
back in the day where one antivirus company
would literally write viruses to attack another antivirus
company's product just so they can be like,
look, our product catches this virus.
There's a dozen. It's like, yeah, that's because you guys wrote it, man. Like
no kidding.
Yeah.
No, it's,
the reality is for people to do this correctly. It's kind of like backups.
It has to be
super easy
and super on by default
and require
literally no effort
or so little effort. It's like you type in one command
or something.
No, I agree with you 100%.
Right?
Because I've, I've looked at this, you know,
for the CS A projects where I'm kind of paranoid.
Like, yeah, like what if one of our dependencies goes away,
then our outbreaks and I get yelled at and it's going to be a bad, bad week.
But the solution is like, oh my,
it's literally a minimum of tens, if not hundreds of hours of engineering.
Right.
And, and the better question is
you've not spent hundreds of hours implementing a solution and
how many times has your site or project broken?
Exactly.
And more of the point, you know, again, this, this kind of thing doesn't scale.
Well, right.
Every single person writing a Ruby Gem app that uses like these common things.
They're going to spend tens or hundreds of hours of
engineering and ongoing maintenance and backing it up and blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah.
And the answer is no, clearly we're not.
Right.
You know, because that's what's happened. The market has spoken.
Uh and, and maybe it has, I, I feel like I wish we could fix this but you might be right.
Maybe,
-- maybe it just never will get bad enough.
-- I don't know that we need to fix this.
It's like houses burning down,
houses, burn down and apparently over Christmas that it's about twice as likely
for houses in North America to burn down. I
guess. I
assume,
I don't know.
Well,
you would think now with led lights it would
be very unlikely because they're so low voltage.
But I'm guessing it's more like people having fires and they
haven't seen their chimneys in forever or people having candles.
Right? Like those big red,
you know, Christmas candles that people seem to like, whatever the
point is, houses burn down and it really sucks when a house burns down,
especially when it's minus 40 outside.
But the reality is houses burn down so rarely now that it's kind of like, well,
you know what?
Ok,
like we, we, we're not going to build, like in North America,
we build the majority of our, you know, houses out of wood, right?
Two by four plywood construction
and, you know, once they get going, they burn
right. There's condos locally, four story condos, several 100 units
and they're just all plywood and two by four
with like, you know, cinder block, uh,
cinder block staircases for the fire escape.
And you are. Right.
But
we didn't get to the point where if your house is burned down by luck. Right.
Oh, true. No building codes and, and, you know, lots of operational changes.
Like people don't heat their houses by, uh, well,
I was gonna say people don't heat their houses with, you know, wood fires,
for example.
Although my neighbor right next to me does,
um, you know, the majority of us have like natural gas furnaces now, which again,
generally are quite safe and tend not to catch fire or burn the house down.
So, yeah. No, we definitely didn't get here by just magic.
You know, we got here through a lot. Well, it's like the whole airline
disaster thing last year.
There weren't any and we got there through like decades of continuous improvement.
Right. You know,
like decades of, of technology, of operational changes.
You know, things like, oh,
maybe we should not make pilots fly for 18 hours straight because when they do,
they tend to get sleep,
you know,
what is it controlled? Descent into terrain? Right. They, they fly into things is
if you look at like the N PM and Rube GMS and all these things,
the number of times we have really bad massive problems that result in massive,
you know,
uh pain for people.
It's really rare,
like it's so rare that when we look at the N PM thing,
there's essentially that one instant.
Well, there's two instances. The second instance being is that
N PM had some sort of weird technical glitch
and a bunch of packages weren't available for a while
and something went wrong. Some
people tried to register the packages. And
so basically, there's two examples for N PM in a span of like two or three years.
But there's an example every week we have a
podcast that we never run out of content for.
I mean,
the Intel bug N PM, there's a million things
going on. They're just
when you
consider how many
different technologies and hardware solutions and things we're talking about,
you know, it's just like the real world,
how
many
microwaves,
right? And, and let's think about airplanes.
There are thousands of ways an airplane can fail, right?
But the problem is the end result of an airplane crash is a catastrophic event.
People can relate to
the end result of a house burning down is a catastrophic event. People can relate to.
The problem with software is the Intel bug is
maybe catastrophic, maybe not, it depends how you want to talk about it.
But fundamentally,
the result of that problem is different than the result
of Equifax is different than the result of node.
And I think the fact that we have this lack of consistency as
kind of our outcomes is what makes it difficult for people to understand
that these are related problems, but they are not the same problem.
Part of it is, it reminds me of heart bleed.
Um So when the openness cell, heart bleed bug came out,
normally, these things don't make the national news, however it did in Canada,
because revenue Canada had to shut down
their website for taking tax returns, which
it was a week before the deadline for taxes.
And so the final week of tax filing
electronically
didn't work, like they turned it off.
And so obviously that made the national news and they
had to extend the filing deadline and it was a,
you know, like
I remember my mom asking me about this because she heard about it on the news, right?
Like the intel meltdown thing as far as I know, never made the news,
like the mainstream media,
like cnn.com,
it made the online news for sure. But like, was it on TV? I don't really think so.
I don't watch TV, but it was in the local newspaper for what it's worth?
It did get a little b
I think the business section for me.
Ok.
Yeah, normal people don't read that.
Uh,
probably not.
I, I did have one normal person. I know
when they, they, I, I talk to them and they're like, so how's it going.
I'm like, I've had better weeks. They said, oh, this is a chip thing, right?
I said, wow. You know what that is? I'm impressed.
Well, no, they don't know what it is, they've heard about
it.
And that's what I was going to say is the
next problem is for most of these technical failures.
Ok. Plane crashing and burning. Yeah, that's easy to understand.
House burning down, easy to understand,
uh, the specter and you know, um meltdown bug.
Not so easy to understand like true or false.
Do you have to patch the underlying hardware host?
True? You always have to patch the underlying host.
It doesn't matter what CPU you're running, you just,
yeah, if it's, if it's like an X 86 processor, you almost guaranteed have to patch.
Now,
here's a question,
virtual machines
running on top of a patch toast. Do you need to patch the virtual machine?
I know the answer to that because it's yes, but many people
-- don't.
-- Well, the answer is a little more subtle than that. It's
yes for virtual machine to other virtual machine attacks,
but no for virtual machine to host attacks
if the host is patched,
right? And so all of a sudden like
we've gone from simple to, oh, this is actually getting really messy, really fast.
And then what's the outcome of this book? Well, you can steal some data
in theory blah, blah, blah blah blah, right? It's not like
it catches fire or it just fails. It's like, no, it's loads.
Exactly. Not like the movies.
And, you know, that's the thing,
like most of the security flaws even trying to explain it,
you know, it becomes very complex, very rapidly.
And that was one thing I noticed about the meltdown.
Inspector coverage is everybody on Twitter
complaining incessantly about how the journalists were
technical de tells wrong. It's like, of course they are.
Right. Right.
Like,
ask somebody to explain how to change a wheel on
a car and nine times out of 10 myself included,
I get it wrong because I always forget that you crack the nuts first
and then put the thing on the jack and then loosen the nuts.
Right.
My thinking is always jack the car up, take the, take the nuts off, take the wheel off,
-- swap,
-- right.
Spin that wheel. Right.
I have done that so many times where I jack the car up that
I go to take the wheel off and the wheel just spins and like,
put the car back down.
Then I loosen the nuts, then I put the car back up. Yeah,
I've done it.
Yeah,
exactly.
And that's a relatively simple thing that you can explain to a four
-- year old.
-- You think so? Like,
like specter and meltdown
or, or heart bleed or poodle, like a downgrade attack.
That's not really a downgrade problem if
you know the server has like certificate ordering enabled blah, blah.
You know what I mean?
Like it just all of a sudden like people start and I'm talking about
like technical people that their eyes just glaze over and they give up.
Right. My, my take on the specter and meltdown is really easy
if your vendor has provided patches,
you install them.
And as far as microcode goes, uh you,
we're gonna have to wait for proper good microcode updates
and as soon as they come out, you install them and it
literally boils down to like my phone strategy,
which is uh about once or twice a week.
I just run the updater
and update everything.
Yeah.
You know what else this reminds me of is I
remember when stack clash came out that one was,
it's been,
it's been a while.
That was the one where the stack and the heap
you could get them to overlap and then you could essentially
like
three
months working on that one.
I
was,
I remember that one.
There were a lot of really smart people, I was talking to that, that they, they were,
they were confused.
And I remember one person was talking about how you can become
root with this and you could because of an attack against.
Was it pseudo I think?
But I said, explain to me how you can become route if we, if we,
if you don't have pseudo on the machine because
the one of the machines in question didn't have pseudo
and he's telling me about how you can use this to overwrite kernel memory.
And I'm like,
right,
that's not how this works. And then I spent like an hour explaining the problem.
But, but like, that's the thing, right? This stuff is so hard.
Well, that's the thing.
Like, I mean, the stack clash stuff was at least it wasn't hardware. Thank goodness.
And I remember, you know, Kace
found it did a ton of good research.
They were like, oh, we think we found a good solution one megabyte guard pages.
And then Florian was like, no,
if we're going to do the guard page route, we have to go with about 3.5 gigabytes.
And that's not really going to work on 32
bit systems because you can basically have three threats
and
memory systems anymore, right?
Not like billions of devices
connected
to.
Yeah,
exactly.
So, and then, you know, so the whole guard page thing was like, whoops,
that's really not going to work.
And, you know, and then it was like, OK, well,
and, and then it got worse because it was like, OK, well, now we have to fix the kernel.
OK? And we have to fix
GLIPS C
and we have to fix GCC.
So all of a sudden we've gone from like, oh,
let's just increase guard size to let's start monkeying
around with fundamental memory primitives and how code compiles.
-- Oh, and don't break anything while you're at it
-- and, and
right,
and nothing changed
and
don't impact performance if you can while you're at it.
That doesn't matter anyway.
I think actually I saw a really funny tweet yesterday that it was,
someone said you knew this was a security problem when someone posted a patch
that impacted performance and Linus didn't yell at them and called them an idiot.
Like
that's, that's true.
That's very true.
Yes.
So,
and you know, and, and,
and it's funny to hear people complaining about the embargo for the, for this
specter and meltdown thing because it's like, no, this was like
crazy amounts of engineering for like seven months
and
like, it's still not done, right? Like
there are, what is it?
There's specter patches in the upstream Linux kernel and I don't
know at the time of the release of this podcast,
whether or not the meltdown patches will have landed in the,
in the Linux kernel tree.
I don't think they're there quite yet.
Like they have some good ideas of what they're going to do,
-- but they haven't actually
-- done it.
Meltdown patches. I thought they already patched meltdown
-- in the upstream kernel or
-- was it?
Oh, no, no, no, sorry. I got it.
Yeah. Meltdown got patched. It's specter that didn't get patched.
Sorry. Yeah. See, I
like living and breathing this for two months in my brain is just, I
can't keep it straight anymore
anyways point being is like, like the Linux kernel upstream still hasn't
completely finished dealing with this.
We're still,
there's still going to be microcode updates
that are going to take
a while
uh conservatively to get it this fully, right?
Like we have microcode updates right now that
are causing problems, right?
If you Google it, there's like a lot of people that, you know,
install these microcode updates and they're really not happy about what happened
again because this is like a hideously complex thing to fix.
And so,
you know, we really needed the embargo on this one because
like you said, and I think the last podcast, you know, if,
if you're trying to do like really complicated
engineering with a whole pile of people screaming,
hurry up at you,
you're going to make decisions that are going to turn out to be not so, so great.
No, I, I totally agree.
And so all right, so, but let's stop ranting about the problems because I,
I totally get that.
But
so, so let's come back to the point.
Are things so bad
or rather will things ever get bad enough that we will actually ever fix anything?
Well, it's, we are fixing things in the sense of looking at this.
We've traded problems. So for example, we we now have developers can trivially
build an application that pulls in a bunch of dependencies and it
basically always works.
Like, I don't know if people remember 20 years ago,
but like what Java's solution was was
while you embed
style.
And so like, I've literally seen Java apps with 14 layers of embedded jars,
Wars and ears.
And it's great when you have the same jar in, in five other jars because they,
they all depend on it
at
multiple depths of the chain and everything,
you know.
So that, I mean, well and back then you got to remember,
we didn't have as much bandwidth or servers.
So like the solution was OK, you know,
essentially statically compile this pilot stuff,
you know, and things like ma
didn't exist for those of you thinking just
maven.
Right? Yeah, exactly.
And so on the one hand,
we've created a pile of security problems, but on the other hand,
we've actually solved a huge pile of real world problems where
you know, that we're preventing developers from getting their jobs done
and now developers can get their job done,
they can churn out code that works and does useful things
way faster.
And you know what I'll take that I will take risk,
you know, pretty much any business will take. OK?
You can give me a working product with risk or alternatively, no risk,
no working product for six months.
Well, clearly, you know, if we can ship today, we can start selling.
-- So that's what we're going to do.
-- I agree
with you
100%.
And here's the beauty too is, is on the one hand,
I hate this centralization of kind of, of power and failure.
But on the other hand, it means we only have to fix it in one spot.
That is a reasonable observation.
Like what if N PM changes the client so that it, locally,
it has a switch to locally cash stuff in a really intelligent way.
I know
it
will that fix anything.
I mean,
well, you'd at least have a local copy when N pm.org forgets to renew their DNS.
No, like, straight up, that'll happen someday.
If that happens, there's gonna be way bigger problems going on
than cashing files locally.
They've only paid for the registration out to 2018 July.
Like I, I have a bunch of important domains that are, like,
registered out 10 years that I renew yearly
with the idea being that if I forget to renew it for like five years, I, I have some,
you know,
-- some time to make sure I get it right.
-- I think I have a domain I need to renew.
Actually, I should look into that.
I,
well, it's a dot Name
and, and I want to move it, but it's,
it's really painful actually to deal with dot Names because
dot Name has such a bizarrely spotted history behind it.
Yeah. The, the intent being,
uh, like, for example, I, if I went Josh dot Bresser dot Name,
I would have bought Josh dot Bresser dot Name but,
but nobody could ever control like Bresser dot Name.
Right.
With the, that was the idea and then it failed and then they let you buy anything.
So I bought Bresser dot Name, which it doesn't even do anything.
I just own it because,
and, and it's, yeah, it sucks now because actually doing anything useful with the,
with that domain is painful.
Yeah.
-- So, anyway, but,
-- uh,
no, I think part of it is on the one hand, it, it reminds me of Github.
I am terrified that github will go evil one day. But on the flip side
by having it centralized and having it well done centrally,
it's made developers lives so
much.
Here's the thing.
Like, I look at the CV project and for,
for like Miter and CV E to run a proper
GIT server publicly with accounts and with all that other stuff
versus, oh, it's free at github.com.
Yeah.
No, I, I totally get that.
Well, here's so github
is going to go evil someday. I mean, remember Source Forge,
those, those were the good things for a long time.
And, oh man, every time I have to download the D band dot iso
and I love the fact that in Firefox it's like, no,
it like blocks the domain
so, or, or whatever the,
you know, because it's like, so
-- I know stupid
-- at this point.
Yeah. No, I know. I, in fact, I downloaded
Dan the other day and I was like, what is this? This is terrible
actually.
That's something I was thinking of somebody should put together like a mini
is
o you know,
build one of these small container type operating systems that just let's face it.
Dan doesn't do anything that exciting. Like I could probably do it in an hour.
But anyway,
github
is going to go evil someday
and,
and N PM is probably going to become evil someday
because I think it's just the nature of these things
and
-- when that happens, it's
-- not that they go evil.
It's that what their interests and my interests are no longer.
That's fair. That's fair. I don't.
Ok. OK. I, I like that better. That's, that's a nice way to put it.
But at the same time when that happens,
it generally happens because the world has moved on
github
will become source forge when we're using whatever comes after github.
Right?
And I have no idea what that will be
good. VR
Right? He has VR source control. That's it.
Right.
It'll be just like,
uh was it the movie hackers where you're flying around the building?
Exactly.
Yeah. So, I mean, as far as actionable, actionable advice goes to people,
there are like various things in N PM and CP and
whatnot that will help you cash local copies of it.
So, you know, you would at least have those if like I said, N pm.org
goes away or if
somebody, some developer decides to delete something that, you know,
is a dependency of a dependency of a dependency of something you, you know,
rely upon.
Um,
but fundamentally, I mean, it's,
it's up to the central organizations and I think
one of the biggest things that could help here
would be having,
you know, good transparency around.
What are the rules, what like what is the behavior we can expect?
Like under what circumstances might this package go away or get deleted or be,
you know, just otherwise something happened that I care about,
you know,
and I think that's one of the benefits like
of a lot of the open source projects like, you know, Debian, for example,
they have some really clearly stated policy documents about when
and how and why they'll move or remove packages,
right? Like license violations or you know, the code blah, blah blah, right?
-- And so you kind of know what to expect.
-- Well, yes
and I like that consistency, but at the same time,
I think because of that policy and consistency,
Debian also moves a lot slower than some of these other distributions do.
Oh, totally. And,
and,
and we exist in a universe now where where speed is
seen as kind of the the killer feature for many,
many
time to market has always been a thing and
especially with software now time to market is like super
critical, especially with services, right? Because
like a great example is Cloudflare,
Cloudflare could have built something totally amazing and beautiful
and engineered even more perfectly than what they built.
But, you know, if they'd waited a year,
somebody else would have come along and eat their lunch,
you know, same thing with github.
Right.
Github.
I
remember github at the beginning. It was, it was good.
I mean, it was hosting Git and that alone took away so much pain,
like, so, so much pain and then, you know,
they've continued to add and add and add features like this whole dependency,
security checker thing is like, wow, that, ok.
That's really cool.
Yes. You know, stuff like that will, you know,
and they're getting to a point now where they kind
of have that moat around them where it's like,
oh, I could totally move to some other G
style hosting thing. But I would lose, well, at a minimum, I would lose the github
community
right
at
this point. It's,
there's nowhere better. I mean, let's face it.
Yeah.
Well, there's nowhere as popular. It's like Facebook.
Are there other social networks?
I guess
I couldn't even name them
certain people like Snapchat,
which is not controlled by Facebook, the medium age people think Instagram is neat,
which Facebook owns and the old people like Facebook,
that is pretty much the way of the world today.
And, and I think that's actually a great example and I wonder
I should, I should look into this but, like, obviously I can understand, like,
if your grandparents are on Facebook, Facebook isn't cool.
Let's face it.
That's the reality of that.
And
if you look at development environments, is it generational?
I, I don't know actually because I mean, I remember back part
of it is
it is generational
because one thing I've really noticed
is the difference between cloud services being built by people
who grew up with cloud that is to put up long
people around the age of 20 to 25
and the cloud stuff being built by
the older generation, a great example being Amazon web services,
they wrote the whole thing in Java
and now they're like, would we use a different technology stack if we built this?
Oh God, yes, except uh we've kind of invested in this and, you know,
we're not stupid enough to try and rewrite from scratch and go bankrupt,
you know.
Right.
Like literally,
if you tried to convince somebody under the age of
25 right now to write a major thing in Java,
they'd be like, you mean javascript, right? Like no Js
like they, that would probably be their reaction.
Yes, I'm familiar with this problem.
It is
at the same time though,
I will say Java does solve some problems very nicely but speed
in Java.
Well, Java is, it's provably it gets things done. I mean, Aws,
right? That is a heck of a successful software stack.
But uh yeah, so I mean, I, I think part of, and part of it is the culture of like
you. And I, like, I literally remember back in um
oh Lord, 1999
I taught a full day Linux security course at Vanguard Security Expo,
which is mainframe security people back in the day
and about there were eight or nine people in the class
and I kind of had to at one point stop and explain client server computing
in the sense of clients that were intelligent and not dumb.
Like they got client server in the context of like, oh yeah, TN 3270 terminal, which
I'm guessing most people are going to have to Google or look up on Wikipedia.
If you're under the age of probably 40 you've probably never seen or heard of those.
Um And so I had to explain to them kind of like why clients server computing with Linux
and, you know, smart clients was a little bit different,
why there was a much different sort of security profile around that.
And it kind of, I think some of them were not super enchanted about, you know,
having their security go from like a single machine to like, oh all the machines.
Um And you know,
I I'm from that generational gap too where I look at a web app and I think about
so how do we optimize processing on the back end versus, you know,
young people now are smart and they're like,
just do it in javascript on the client,
right? Scale out 100% right. For every client that connects,
that's a new server.
But however, ironically
that is going to bring with it many of the same problems where you have,
have issues with having to trust the client because you,
and that
doesn't really
matter a lot of
-- apps.
-- Right. I mean, certain things, it certainly doesn't. I, I agree with that.
Yeah.
Well, like banking apps, like, oh, you wanted to withdraw $73 billion? Cool.
Yeah, you probably need to check those numbers on the back end. Right.
Um,
but fundamentally, I mean, especially with, like, games and stuff. Right. Like,
anyways, the point being is that there is definitely a cultural divide
between,
like, as I kind of put it, there's,
there's sort of the, the server client application mindset which, you know,
roamed the earth and, uh, was supreme from like, what about 95 until 2005, 2008.
And then we kind of entered that
transition where clients became,
like, even the worst client. Like, my cell phone is what?
Dual core with four gigs of ra M or something stupid.
Right. Like, I don't even know or care anymore. It'll run,
it'll do,
-- like, it'll do augmented reality games on my phone.
-- Right.
-- Actually, you know, if it's in my pocket
-- it probably has something crazy like six
cars or
it, it, that's a funny thing.
Now,
it's even crazier because they're actually these chips now have like two low
power cores and then they might have two or four high power cores.
So when the phone is asleep it uses way less juice,
which is awesome. Right.
Yeah.
And so,
you know, and then there's this whole sort of cloud native client
uh generation where like the client is essentially what we think of as
a server as far as power and compute capability and storage goes.
Yeah. No, II, I totally get it.
-- So, all right,
-- let's my kids', ipads have 100 and 28 gigs of storage.
I remember seeing servers with,
well, I remember owning servers with one gig of storage and I was like,
I'll never fill this disk up.
Yeah.
So, you know, there is definitely that generational divide with,
not just in language and, but in how they view the world,
it's like those kids that pick up a phone and they're like like a dumb phone,
like a cordless phone
and are like, what, where's the screen? Like why there's no touchscreen?
-- This is broken, what's going
-- on? Let's let's bring this one home.
But you've got me thinking something
is
maybe,
maybe we are solving yesterday's security
problems and we're trying to project those
problems onto the technology of today
instead of building today's security solutions,
-- right? Everything you said,
-- I think
-- you're right. It resonates with
-- me.
One example of this is, you know, if you do Dev
ops and our trial, who cares if you have a security flaw, we fixed it in five minutes
-- because you're definitely gonna have security flaws no matter what you, right
-- now,
on that note though, you have to know about them is part of the trick
and
that can be tricky, although I guess maybe just keep updating a
lot and, and then you don't care, continuous deployments.
-- Yeah. I, I feel
-- like
why, here's the thing,
why bother tracking security flaws in your dependencies
if you update your dependencies every day?
Yes, I,
but then,
but then we've gotten to the issue of ok, so I'm stating my dependencies every day.
Am I? Should I cash them locally? Should I care if they're cashed locally?
And, and I feel like
everything we've talked about up till now about the supply chain is very much
the security problems of yesterday, not the security problems of today,
but we're trying to project our solution onto today.
I need, I need to think about this. I think,
-- I think this might
-- have something,
one thing you and I fundamentally get wrong
is we look at software as something that ships.
The majority of software
is
not shipped.
It's either used internally or it's provided as a
-- service
-- as a service is totally the future.
Man.
I mean, if you look even like elastic as a new company and our,
our cloud offering obviously is it's becoming hugely popular, not that the other,
the other stuff is hugely popular also.
But
yeah, as a serviceman, it's where it's at.
Well, from the customer perspective, it's easier.
And from the company perspective,
there's no more piracy and there's no more people not
paying their bills because they don't pay their bills.
You turn it off.
-- Yes.
-- Well, and not only that,
the, the, the dealing with support on something as a service is much nicer because
you have basically access to everything. You can see the logs, right.
You can, you can figure out what's going on, you can say, oh, I see what, you know,
there's a mistake here.
I see you're trying to do this or
it's, it's huge, man. I mean, I think
there are few instances where IC N A service being inferior to on prem today and I
know that that's something that people complain about and
there's a whole bunch of articles popping up.
It feels like since the new year talking about,
oh, the public cloud is too expensive and insecure.
And I'm like, yeah, you're who's paying you, right? You,
you didn't make this up. Someone's paying you to say that and I don't know who it is.
But
-- anyway,
-- well, I think there are, well, I think it's like any technology that
things like
the public cloud will definitely take off and eat up a huge part
of the market and there will always be those like niche situations or
regulatory guidelines or whatever.
Um
But yeah, to say blanket statements like,
oh the the cloud like I look at the CS A
what we pay Amazon web services and the weird thing is
we've consistently paid them the same amount plus or minus $100
for four years.
And we use more and more resources every month and year
because Amazon keeps dropping their prices and they keep coming out with services.
So for example,
I no longer have to buy SSL certificates because
Amazon provides that for free. Right. Amazon certificate.
You, it's just free.
Yes. Right.
And, and like a wild card certificate for a domain is like a couple 100 bucks a year.
And so
two or three of those go
like, wow, it's like 1000 bucks a year.
No, I know, man. I know.
All right, let's call it, let's call it. It's uh,
so anyway, let's just say this,
uh parents stop projecting your problems and your Children.
Right.
That's, that's what this is us as parents are projecting our security problems on,
on the youth, the future and
to youth. It's up to you to keep giving us a finger and telling us to go away.
-- So there we go.
-- Problem
-- solved. Don't trust anybody over 40. I
-- don't,
don't just don't trust anybody. Right. It's much easier that way.
Don't, don't draw lines.
It's fine. Anyway.
All right,
sweet. Thanks, Kurt. Thanks everyone for listening. We appreciate it.
You can go to open source security podcast.com for the show notes.
You can hit us up on Twitter with the Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag
And, yeah, I guess if nothing else, Kurt, you have a fantastic rest of your day.
Yeah, you too. Thanks.