Hello and welcome to episode 52 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime, Josh Bresser.
You know, Kurt, when we started doing a podcast, I didn't expect
for the internet to be on fire for so many episodes.
It's,
it seems
like
I'm, I'm starting to suspect it is that,
that occasionally someone puts it out for a little while and then it flares back up.
Yeah. Yeah. No, I, I mean,
we've been doing this now for 20 years. Well, the internet's been around for about 25
sixties. I
-- mean,
-- no, no, no. But I mean, with like normal people, not just a bunch of like time
frame and like,
probably 30 years.
Yeah, I would say late nineties
really is when you, like your mom got on it
-- and I don't mean that
-- in a
-- derogatory sense, just normal people.
-- Let's give credit where it's due.
Wallace broke
the internet.
Well done. Qac.
Yeah,
they, yeah. No, they did some, I mean,
that was literally one of the top 10 security
advisories when they said it to us initially.
Like it just the level of detail and the quality of the research was amazing.
-- I mean,
-- this is an amazing invite.
So, all right, let's, let's first clarify something. Is
you work for Red Hat and were involved
in working on this
for, for several weeks. Is my understanding
so. Well, just a real dirty quick timeline. Basically Q
found a bunch of stuff.
I don't know exactly when they found it internally,
but they found it and they came to the distro list,
you know, pretty much right away. And we're like,
we basically found this huge problem.
We obviously need to coordinate with you guys to fix it, you know,
how do we want to handle this?
Um
And so initially, Red Hat and Sousa,
uh
the security teams got uh sort of a little bit of early access for a few days to the
report and essentially just to, you know, first of all, like call
comes to us and says, like, literally, we have this thing that like,
we'll burn your house down if you look at it funny
and we're like, uh can you be a little more specific, you know, because
this sadly happens a lot.
Um And it's kind of one of those things, you know,
is this a kook off the street or did they actually, like figure out who killed JFK?
-- Uh So anyways,
-- in
fact, these guys are the ones who did it. I think.
So, us
and
Zzo, you know, we, we looked at the report for a few days and kind of went.
Yeah. No, this is all correct.
And, um, actually it's worse than that because the solution you've proposed,
uh, won't work very well.
So it's actually much worse than you thought it was. And calls kind of went.
Oh, thanks. That's great.
Um, what are we going to do about this?
And so essentially we, you know, we coordinate, um,
with the community via the distro list,
um, with initially like a two week embargo.
Uh and then that got extended because quite frankly, um we,
we just couldn't fix this in two weeks, right?
It's just, it's, I mean, this is memory management within the Colonel Angie Lipsey
on Linux and then
the reciprocal on all the B sds, right? So this isn't even just a bad Linux problem.
This is a bad Linux
and BS D problem.
Um
So, you know, it's pretty complicated and to quote one of the
Gipsy developers, you know,
I don't want to push out a security update that's gonna break everything,
right? Because when you start fiddling with memory management,
you know, you have the potential to break everything. Uh So
initially, it was thought, hey, we'll just increase the size of the stack card page,
right?
From four kilobytes to say one megabyte,
right? That'll work. Uh And the answer is no, no, it, it won't work on its own.
It, it will definitely make things safer and harder to exploit,
but there's enough user space
uh programs like say pseudo and
exim
that can be manipulated to allow you to bypass even a one meg stack guard page.
Um And obviously we can't go any bigger than about a one megabyte snack card page.
Because if you think about like a threaded application, say with 1000 threads,
that's now a gigabyte of allocated memory,
which on a 64 gigabyte uh 64 bit system is no big deal, right?
You got lots of address space,
but on a 32 bit system,
that's a quarter of your address space.
Right. Right.
You know,
so we, we just, yeah, I mean, even on 32 bit systems,
this one megabyte guard page is pushing it, you know.
Um although realistically anybody now should be able to upgrade to a 64 bit.
Hey, I don't know if I'd go that far, but yeah, I get what you're saying
one could hope.
But uh so anyway, so what was found?
Um especially once we roped in some of the smart guys like Florian uh Vimar
who does uh g lipsy security
is that we also needed to make changes to g lipsy
to really, you know, as he put it belt and suspenders, you know,
fix this for pretty much all of it.
And, you know, you don't
patch and ship a fix and
Gypsy in a few days,
like especially when you're monkeying with the core memory management
because if you do that you will break the internet for real,
you know,
nothing will boot anymore.
If you have a broken g lipsy, you're going to have a bad time. So
we asked for and got about a 2.5 week extension to the embargo, which, you know,
so we're not talking about an embargo lasting months or years.
We're talking about an embargo that in total
-- was about 4.5, 5 weeks.
-- That's solid, man.
I mean, this is a lot of work for, for four weeks.
Well, and, and also considering that, you know, like I said, it was,
it's all the Linux,
it's all the B sds like,
which is kind of impressive too because I can't think of too
many exploits that are kind of at this fundamental level that affect Linux
-- and BS D
-- at
-- the same
-- time,
there has been some TCP stuff back in
the day because everybody made the same assumptions
and uh,
-- well, things like, you know, user based stuff like DNS where
-- everybody
is
different.
I mean, I get that.
But yeah, as far as this goes, yeah, I mean, it's
generally speaking, yeah,
the systems have slightly different assumptions or the code has been, you know,
around for 30 years and modified enough that they're,
they've diverged enough that, you know, we just don't have the same problem.
It's kind of
a flaw in the general architecture of X 86 as well just because of how they work.
Yeah, I mean, if you want to get,
I guess technical it would be what the Von Neumann architecture and I forget
if that's the one with the data and code separated or with the mixed,
-- you have a comp sci degree, you should know this.
-- I, I don't know, you know, I
anyways, yeah. So the
one of the classic ideas of computing was to split executable and
like data data, right?
And, and the stack and the heap and all of that sort of kind of does that.
But the problem is, you know,
well, you can write past your stack and jump over the guard pages effectively,
you know, and get into, well, you know,
the the into the bits of memory that you shouldn't be able to change.
And that,
you know,
we're running the program on the assumption that these parts of memory
are not going to change and that they're safe to just,
you know, execute as is well.
OK. So why don't we back this up for a little bit?
Is
a long time ago,
there was an attack called a stack smash,
right? Which is a
one and Frack was at 43 I think
is the one who
it does. And it was very clever
and essentially you could
do some things.
And because the stack grows down when you overflow, a buffer,
you're writing into stack metadata essentially which
is located above the the variables,
right?
Just because that's how it's growing.
And so we, we got rid of that using something called stack protector,
which essentially puts a canary on the stack checks, the canary make sure nothing
did weird things to
the metadata on the stack, right?
And then
that's all good.
And then we end up in a situation where people found out you
could just grow the stack in the heap which grow towards each other
and you could grow them in such a way that they, they basically
collide.
And so now you have the stack writing into
heap data and the heap writing into stack data,
right?
And that was bad.
And so the solution to that was we created what was called a guard page,
which is basically a page of memory.
A page of memory is four K
page of memory just sitting kind of somewhere
that says
the stack cannot cross this,
right?
And, and the heap is a little different because of the way the heap works.
It's a little less dicey as to because,
but anyway, stat can't cross this right?
-- Too long
-- didn't read memory management is quite tricky as it turns out.
Well,
look,
no,
no, I'm gonna say no.
The problem is the X 86 architecture is like 90 years of cobbled together nonsense.
That's the problem. Although funny enough, I I, after reading the Callis Advisory,
I then thought,
I wonder if this affects arm because I don't know off the top of my head.
How arm does stack management?
Yeah, it's basically the same. So, like, good job guys, you could have done it.
Right. But you didn't.
So, anyway, although even the arm
architecture is old. So, anyway, anyway, the idea is you have your stack guard
or page, right? Your guard page for the stack.
And now if
it's more of a, it's more of a trip wire than anything else. It's
only if something touches that
page
and that's the problem.
And you can,
right when the spy sees the trip wire,
he just steps over the trip wire and then everything's cool again.
And so, I mean, that's basically what this Q
thing does is it,
it jumps over the guard page.
But the beauty of it is that they
found so many ways to exploit this.
It's not even funny,
-- which is just crazy
-- and some of them are really fundamental like the Q
sort issue
like that
right? In
so many things on BS D oh man,
it's I give these guys so much credit because I have
not seen an advisory this thorough in a long time.
But the other thing that's really awesome and,
and this is something to touch on in a little bit is
they talk about probabilities a lot
because back in the day of like smashing the stack,
you knew where everything was, right?
Everything was always loaded in the same
memory address every time you executed a binary
and things don't work like that anymore.
We have all these randomization technologies built in
that are designed to make attacks like this harder.
But obviously Qis
has kind of, I
guess they cracked the lottery, right.
They, they kind of figured out how this all works and now they can tell you, you know,
one in 28 runs of this will gain your root,
which is
good for them. I mean,
that's fantastic.
So, yeah, so the the original idea was, yeah,
let's increase the size of the guard page and you know,
chances are people will hit it, right?
Make a bigger trip wire.
Um The, the problem we found was to make it truly effective,
the guard page would have to be something like 1.6 gigs
which, you know, would basically break everything horribly,
right?
Uh Especially on 32 bit systems where you'd run out
of memory space once you have about three threads,
a minor detail.
Yeah, so obviously that's not going to fly.
So the good news is there were some changes made to
Gipsy and, and what was really surprising to me is
they're actually not that big, like for the number of lines of code,
like I was kind of working on the assumption that, you know,
Florian and the related g lipsy guys would, you know, be submitting like, you know,
thousands of lines of changes, you know, to,
to rewrite this whole thing and they actually did it with like
it's like a couple 100 lines of code at most.
It's
Yeah. No. Well, these guys are pretty crazy smart.
It is true.
You know, I mean, this is
Gipsy, this is, this is Rocket science,
you know, based on like 30 year old show
and it works. So like, wow,
that's, that's good.
So, you know, the good news is with the kernel and the
Gypsy changes, you're mostly safe And then with some additional um
essentially removing attack vectors, for example, with pseudo and
exim
you know, these programs are set U id.
So if you get arbitrary code execution within this program, you, you know,
you're now root.
Um
And, and that's a problem.
So with some changes to pseudo
examine some other programs, um you know, like everything on BS TQ sort,
you're effectively closing off all the avenues of the Attackers.
And I'm making air quotes here easily manipulating the heap and stack memory
in order to exploit this flaw.
And uh so honestly, between those three sets of changes.
Yeah, I mean, that's the problem is pretty much uh dealt with
and what's even better, of course is, you know, the,
the G Lipsy guys looked into this a bit more and you know,
have made some additional changes.
Um So
Gipsy, for example, only had one CV assigned to this,
they sort of only had one actual flaw.
Um But they actually made a bunch of changes that hardened
Gipsy and Harden how memory is handled
and we make this kind of thing in the future. Uh Quite a bit more difficult.
Nice.
That's awesome.
I'm also working on the assumption too that, you know,
now that people know about this,
there's going to be renewed interest in research into this, right?
Because
the dirty secret is like, uh this is based on research from,
-- I want to say 2004 was some of the first stuff.
-- It's pretty old.
I remember some of the first attacks where you had the heap and the stack overlap
and,
and I remember the guard page was created and we even
talked about it at the time that this isn't 100%.
This is, I mean, yeah, it stops the current known attacks,
but we know this is a problem and of course,
we never revisited it.
So I give KAC
a lot of credit for, for actually going back to something that
we kind of knew was a problem but, but nobody really put the effort in to prove it.
Yeah. And I, I always wonder about that, right?
Because you hear about, you know, the NSA and all these guys with their, you know,
secret efforts to find flaws and stuff.
And I, I kind of wonder, you know, didn't,
did some attacker or group of Attackers discover this at
some point say in the last 10 years and,
and, you know,
were they silently using it?
You know, whenever they gained local access to a system to get root.
Um,
and I, the answer is obviously, we don't know.
I suspect the answer is no, actually because, you know, at some point,
somebody would have noticed on some forensics and been like, oh,
look at what I found.
So it is kind of crazy to think that, yeah,
Wallace essentially looked at some papers from, I think, yeah, 2004, 2006 and,
and literally asked the question of like, well, you know,
what happens when the heap and the stack meet?
And as it turns out, you know, really bad things happen, that's
really bad things happen.
So,
yeah, the good news is pretty much all the major Linuxes are shipping patches today,
uh mostly around the kernel and G Lipsy and then um
same for the B sds.
Uh It doesn't look like anybody else is really affected.
Uh I know that Microsoft was informed because they
now have a Linux compatibility layer and I,
I have no idea how it works or allocates memory or what it's doing.
Well,
fundamentally though, I mean,
Os X and well, Os X is based off the BS D. So we kind of know how that works.
But but windows, regardless of what they do, like the way the heap and the stack work,
this is part of the architecture.
This isn't like some decision the Linux guys made up one day.
So my suspicion is
Microsoft probably has a degree of this unless they
have a massive guard page in the middle,
which they might, I, I honestly don't know.
Yeah.
Well, and they also have a very different permissions model as well with, you know,
respect to set U ID and that kind of stuff.
So it's quite a bit different.
Um, I mean,
that, see that, that was one of the big challenges here, right? Is, it's
not only did qualify that basically there's a whole pile of set U ID
applications you can use to exploit this,
but like one of them is pseudo
and like pseudo is
as far as I know it's installed by default
everywhere
since
I don't think there's a distribution on the planet that doesn't come with pseudo.
Yeah,
maybe some IOT devices hopefully don't have it because they're never going to get
paid
-- for it.
-- All right.
You just, you just said IOT which we have to give the, we'll say token nod to IOT here.
Uh It should please everyone to know that basically
every IOT device on the planet now has a nice
way to get from a regular user to root
just in case it wasn't already running its route,
which most of them do.
But uh given the, we'll say history of IOT updates,
we know that, that these will be running forever with this
local to root exploit, right?
Yeah. No, it's um and it's a reliable one too.
You know, that's, that's the thing, right.
I've, I've seen some exploits where it's like it, they are crazy,
difficult to exploit, like race conditions in the kernel.
This is not that this is, you know, Qac
found.
Yeah,
they found this was a gold nugget, like a giant gold nugget.
Oh,
it's the hope diamond, isn't it?
Pretty much? Yeah, I mean,
but like I said,
the good news is hopefully people will do some more research into this and, you know,
between g lipsy hardening and more people doing research,
you know, we might actually squash a whole pile of bugs in the next year or so.
-- I
-- certainly
-- can generally make things better.
-- I certainly hope so. This is,
yeah, I, I don't have a lot to say.
-- I mean,
-- just
-- memory
-- management isn't something you can, like, abstract away. Like,
for example, with this law, if you
virtual machine, everything and containerized everything
and
managed to get rid of Moet
U I Ds, like you,
you'd still be affected,
you know, that's just the reality of it. Right.
Um,
it's just, it's,
it's not something that you can sort of like stick a firewall in front of.
It's just that fundamental to the system. Right.
And that's the other piece of good news here is, it's
from what we can tell there's nothing,
this is all local so far and it
doesn't look like there's anything really remotely exp
I would not say that I think this will
be the area that the researchers investigate is there,
there's no reason
this doesn't affect demons listening on the network. It's just Qac
didn't find any. And my suspicion
is
they might have some hints for things they think they could look at.
But when you're generally exploiting things like a network facing demon,
you can't exploit it as fast,
which means what might take four minutes on a
local system might take four days once you're,
you're dealing with network and, and tear up and shut down and, and, you know,
standing up network connections and all that kind of stuff.
Well, there's one bit of good news here is that in general,
any network Damon that will sort of
allocate that much memory
would already be experiencing a denial of service typically, right?
Like if you can basically get say Apache
to allocate one or two or four gigs of ra M,
that's true.
You know, generally speaking,
these network demons are going to get killed or run out of memory.
Um
So in general, like I said, you know,
there's a good chance that the avenue of attack for this
flaw
has been found enclosed in a lot of network programs as a denial of service, you know,
over the last decade or two, right?
Um The cases where, you know, you can send a small
uh the great example, always being FTP servers with, you know,
regular expression globbing on the command line, right?
You feed it like star slash star slash star slash star, like 50 of those and then,
like,
the poor little FTP server, you know,
allocates all the memory and tips over like
a, a
top heavy whatever
and
whatever.
I
couldn't think of anything politically correct to say.
Um, well, I'm sad because I found out cow tipping is an urban myth.
It's not a real thing.
I'm
-- so sad.
-- It is an urban myth. Cows don't tell.
Yeah, I was watching youtube videos of people trying to do cow tipping.
And those are actually really funny.
It's like when they, the Boston dynamics video and they kick that robot,
it,
-- it's basically that
-- right.
So, so anyways, the good news is it doesn't, I mean,
basically any network Damon that is vulnerable to this is already has
a lot of other problems anyways that need to be fixed regardless.
You're probably right.
And I guess that's a good point is because having read this advisory,
it's really, it's,
it's at start up when they just kind of poison
the environment to make the staff do crazy things is,
is where it's all at.
And obviously in a network demon,
if you can do things to the environment,
like you've got way bigger problems than me connecting to your demon, you know.
Well, yes and no, because there are now
other service providers that do run code
within sandbox or a constrained environment,
but do allow you the user to pass things to it, like, say,
user names and passwords for the database connections.
Yeah.
But look,
if you're running a service like that and I'm not in
my own little sandbox and you know what I mean?
You're doing it wrong
if I can escape in any way, even if I was route.
Yeah,
I agree. But the reality is, you know,
we've had a lot of people build a lot of technology using old stuff, you know,
containers really weren't available five years ago.
I mean, they kind of were, but not really.
That's true. And they've matured a lot since then.
So.
Yeah.
Um, but yeah, so, I mean, basically, yeah. No, Qac
hit a home run. Um,
and like I said, the good news is, you know, with about a 4.5, 5 week embargo,
we basically got everybody patched, you know, every
in the next few hours, pretty much all the vendors have got all their
Gipsy kernel updates out and
for everybody that does apply these patches and reboot.
Good, great.
You can go home tonight.
Yeah. II, I high fives. Right.
I mean, I guess it sounds like everything worked the way it should have worked.
And that's amazing.
And, and,
yeah, I love it.
I guess that's one of the other ironic things
is the named vulnerabilities that really get the attention
are when something goes horribly wrong. Right.
And in this instance it has a name but it's like
good job guys, you know, pat on the back. I
love it. Pretty
fantastic. Well done. Kurt, well done everybody involved.
And I have to say the community did a great job here.
All I did was CV S and they were pretty easy by and large.
Although in fairness,
writing CV descriptions was tricky for this one because trying to compress
some of these things down into one or two sentences was nontrivial.
Yeah, I can see that.
I can see that. Well, and it should also be said that DWF assigned all of the I DS,
which is super cool too.
Yeah.
So, yeah, if you haven't been using, uh,
or if you haven't gotten ready for those longer I DS.
Uh, well, sorry,
whatever, man.
If you're not ready, you live in like 1997. I'm sorry, you just,
whatever. I, I don't feel bad for those people.
So I guess, uh, do we want to move on to some, uh, some bad news?
Yes.
Yes, we shall, we shall talk about the,
the terrible tragedy in London of the Grenfell
Tower,
which, which will, I guess we'll do the PS A up front of, I'm sure we'll,
we'll make some silly jokes and, and have some bizarre comparisons, but
we recognize the, the terrible tragedy, such a thing is to,
to the world for that matter and, and what makes it even worse is that it
is the fault of people,
right? This wasn't an accident like people did this. Which, which is terrible.
Yeah. No, it's, it's much, I,
well, from everything I've been reading, it's
what frustrates me is, it's not just a criminal
action at a small level. It's, it's, anyways, it's,
it's much worse than even, you know,
we thought it was 24 hours ago with some of the stuff that's come out.
Now.
Why don't, why don't you give us the, I guess, brief description of what's going on.
And then
the,
the fundamental comparison we're going to end up with
is this is a failure of risk management,
right.
Yeah. Um So, uh Grenfell Tower is this apartment block
in London that's owned by a council
and uh it was refurbished uh the exterior,
uh and they use these panels, uh that as it turns out are quite flammable.
And so there was a fire in the tower, I think,
I believe they think it started on the fourth floor and the fire
um
went to the exterior of the tower.
And so the exterior of the tower caught fire and the whole thing,
fuck it. It's horrible.
Um
Yeah, anyways,
a lot of people died. I think they're talking about 58 or so. Now.
I, and that's the other thing is that the
death toll has been rising.
Um And yeah, just, I mean, at its simplest, the horrific
fact is that
they could have used uh flame retardant panels
and it would have cost about 5000 pounds,
sterling more.
-- That's about, what, 8000 $10,000 us more,
-- give or take.
-- And that would have prevented this.
-- That's free
-- when you're talking about a project like this.
-- Right.
Yeah.
And, and what's even worse? I mean,
what really gets me is,
oh, so many levels.
Uh, number one, you know,
who signed off on this because apparently these panels are illegal
to use in structures over a certain height. I think it's like 10 m.
So that's what about three stories.
Um, because quite frankly, this is a, this is an obvious failure mode.
You know, when you have a cladding
on something that is flammable and it catches fire and there's a lot of it,
you know, you're gonna have uh what's called chimney effect where the air draws in
and it gets worse, you know, the fire grows.
Uh And what's even worse is these are panels with, uh, so there's an aluminum skin.
Um,
there's a, uh polyethylene
like core
and then another panel.
So you can't get water onto the fire because it's burning between these panels,
right?
So you, you,
yeah,
so you've basically essentially made like
something super flammable and then glued it
to the side or bolted it to the side of a building,
you know. Ok.
So let's, let's try to, to lighten this up a bit and, and point out the fact that
a significant amount of it
works like this
where we are adding
what is essentially flammable material to products and services
because it,
-- let's face it, it
-- solves
problem. Right. Yeah,
seriously.
-- But it's
-- a
problem
and then people don't,
don't take it into account and you think the building industry
is heavily regulated and obviously it didn't work in this instance.
But you look at,
you know, information, security, cybersecurity, whatever you want to call it,
-- there's basically no regulation, there,
-- there's no meaningful regulation.
I mean, based on the fact that we keep having these huge data breaches
or, you know, people,
uh yeah, uh keep getting compromised.
Um
And what's, and what's worse is apparently there's
hundreds or even thousands of buildings in,
in the United Kingdom with this cladding on the exterior.
And that again goes back to that in.
It's kind of the classic problem of if you build something and you build it wrong,
it's going to cost, you know, 10 to 1000 times more to remediate it,
you know, and that's where we are with a lot of these technical systems
where, you know,
people have a mainframe that they've come to rely upon and to replace that thing.
Now,
um, you know, great example, being like the airline reservation industry,
you know, um
that whole thing is based on a piece of software called Saber from,
I want to say the seventies,
it's pretty,
I know that
and it's,
you know,
we're at the point where replacing it would cost I
would have to guess in the tens of billions of dollars
and, and it would most likely fail
-- because it's just too complex of a project.
-- They build it on. No Js.
Yeah.
You know, like that FBI case management system that they ran, what,
one or $2 billion and it just never worked.
Right.
Right. Learning experience.
But, I mean, so, so here's the thing and you,
and you bring up some of these other it systems is
so
they know buildings in the UK have this,
there,
there is going to be
kind of, this was a forcing function to get rid of it everywhere else, right?
They're gonna make a huge deal about this
going
get dealt with and you know,
there's probably going to be legislation that comes out of this.
The last big breach,
nothing happened,
right? And, and
this is something that terrifies me is
I think until computers start killing people,
we're never going to see anything change.
I mean,
because like this is an example of where people have
to literally die before anyone cares about a problem.
Like people knew this was a problem.
They just didn't care.
Yeah. Well, and, and the other thing that's, that's really sad.
I find about just, and this is just one of the fundamentals of human beings is
unless a whole bunch of people die at once, we generally don't care, right? Um Like
I was looking at traffic deaths
and you know,
traffic kills far more people than most anything else really.
And, you know,
-- we just live
-- with
-- it,
-- whatever. I know. I know. And
that's something I always think of that. Every time I get on an airplane,
the odds of me dying on the ride to the airport were
magnitudes higher than the odds of me dying on an airplane.
But nobody's afraid of the ride to the airport,
you know.
Yeah,
man.
every time and I think we've reached a point
now where more humans have died from automobiles.
I think malaria is the only thing that has killed more people. Right.
Obesity.
Yeah.
Has it?
I mean,
-- uh,
-- yeah, obesity is now the leading cause of death, I believe in
the leading
cause of death.
But has it killed more people than traffic
accidents has over the course of human history?
I would suspect.
Well, if it hasn't, it
has really only been a problem for the last, what, 2030 years, I mean,
yeah. So, anyway, anyway, whatever. Ok. So malaria, maybe obesity
and nothing else but yet because it's a slow burn,
we let it go.
Right.
Yeah, I mean, hands up who here has not
been almost run over in a crosswalk
every day, man, like every day.
So, yeah. No, it's so I'm hoping, I mean,
this is what gets me is, is from what I understand is this
Grenfell Tower,
the cladding should not have been used and yet it was you know, and so I'm wondering,
like,
you know, who signed off on this product, who signed off on the inspection? You know,
I,
I imagine all the engineers involved with that building ever at this point are like,
you know, phoning their lawyers and trying to find the paperwork.
Right. And somebody
probably made a malicious decision at some point. And now that, that is
-- one of the things,
-- I don't think it probably was malicious.
I, I would have to bet that it was just simply cost savings
which,
and that they
were,
they weren't supposed to do it. Right.
Let's just say that we won't, we won't go so far to say malicious.
But I guess that's one of the things is even with regulation,
you can't stop purposeful intent with regulation, right?
Regulation can maybe stop stupid mistakes.
But if somebody is bound and determined to save those 5000 pounds,
you can, you will not stop them. They will get around that.
Well, that's, that's one thing I got like, uh,
so I had to do some uh get some wiring done in my house
and I actually bought a copy of the uh Alberta electrical code and read it.
And it was really interesting from an information security point of view because
you could literally see where every regulation,
like there's a story behind that and why that regulation exists now.
And the other thing is they were, they were layering security, right?
You know,
you ground stuff and then you have like
ground fault interrupt circuit breakers and then you,
you know, you do,
you have hopefully multiple stages of failure so that, you know,
when some poor schmuck drives a nail into the wall, he doesn't get killed.
You know.
And, um, and that's what gets me about these kinds of regulations is, you know,
they're, they're typically,
there's a whole bunch of stuff that,
you know, was intended to
save lives or help people or whatever
part of the problem, I think sometimes, um,
is that some of this stuff kind of needs to be expired?
Right.
Like,
there's certain building materials we don't use anymore or
certain methods of construction we don't use anymore.
Yes, exactly. You know, hey, that stuff
and that stuff is fire retardant. So, you know,
super
awesome.
Yeah.
Um,
and, you know, part of the problem I've seen is too, is I've seen people who
they don't agree with or like the regulation. So they, like, ignore it.
Well, yeah, we knew Asbestos was bad for like, 30 years and we kept
in 19 thirties.
Germany people who worked with Asbestos were given a stipend from
the government because they knew statistically these people died earlier.
-- Did they know why though? Or did they?
-- Well, they
didn't,
but they knew they had the correlation, they had the statistics to back
it
up.
Right. Right.
So we, yeah, we've known for a
long time. Asbestos is not good for you.
I think they used asbestos into the eighties, at least in the United States.
We were the last country to outlaw it on the planet.
Uh,
funny story.
I
think
we stopped exporting it about five or 10 years ago
and I'm sure.
And Russia still has asbestos minds.
Oh, good.
Because we,
well, and here's the frustrating thing again. Asbestos isn't, I mean,
it's not, you know, if it gets powdered and you breathe it in.
Yeah, that's bad for you. But this is also true of like uranium or, you know,
flu.
Your house doesn't have any U
in
it.
Well, I got rid of it.
I actually got rid of an original smoke alarm that had a stick around it saying,
uh essentially to call atomic energy of Canada,
-- uh this number to dispose of this unit.
-- Did
you call him?
No, I mean, it, it was like
that in a podcast.
I mean, this was smoke alarm was actually made in Canada. That's how old it was.
So,
but see, this is the thing, right?
It's, it's not that like asbestos, asbestos is a dangerous
material.
But, you know, we regularly have trucks full of gasoline coming down, you know,
residential streets, going to gas stations.
The trick is, you know,
to use the thing appropriately and to take the safety precautions around it,
you know. So hopefully people don't get hurt and die.
I mean, uh, yeah, fuel tankers being a great example. Right. They generally,
it, uh, don't
cause problems, you know,
except for that one that caught fire and burned
down a bit of interstate a few months ago.
Um, it was Atlanta, I think.
Yeah, because it was just after they had that other one,
they fix their road yet.
I haven't looked into that.
I,
I haven't been to Atlanta in a long time and honestly
I'm afraid to go because they haven't fixed the road.
The traffic got to be terrible.
But so back to this, I mean, we, these panels are not inherently bad.
It's just, they can't,
you know, they're not appropriate or safe for use in, say,
applications of like higher than 10 m or,
you know, maybe in a large, uh, residential thing, you know, maybe in a commercial.
Well, and part of the problem too is this building had no fire sprinkler system.
It only had one.
Yeah. Oh, yeah. So dirty secret.
Uh, apparently fire sprinklers are not required by code in the UK because
they essentially didn't want to pass that because they
didn't want to discourage people from building housing.
And, and that goes, I mean, there's a great example of a trade off to make,
we need housing for people.
But the country is
obsessed with telling people how to live their
lives and they don't put freaking fire spring.
I mean, they have, they have cameras watching everything you do in the city
of
London
Well, it's one of those tradeoffs they decided to make and,
and then what made it apparently much worse is that the official
policy for this building for fire alarms was shelter in place.
Which no offense if you have a sprinkler system, sort of makes sense.
But if you don't have a sprinkler system,
-- but the problem is again, they only had the one stairwell.
-- Oh, man,
this is like every bad
it is.
It is literally like you want to build a building
that will ultimately kill a whole bunch of people.
Yeah, this is what you build
and what you tell them to do.
You know.
That's,
yeah.
And I mean, and the worst thing is though, this was, you know,
all done by experts who had the best interests of people in mind.
And, you know, unfortunately they came up with a plan that had a very
-- bad, you know, very catastrophic failure scenario. Oh my
-- goodness,
this is, this is madness.
Well, like I said, I mean, anybody who's ever been involved with this building,
I mean,
yeah,
you know,
this is literally terrible. Now, what I'm hoping is, you know, from this,
the problem is though,
like if you have a building like this retrofitting a sprinkler system costs,
you know, several $100,000
going to pay
for it to almost just build a new building in some instances
or things like adding an extra stairwell,
right?
You know, that's a very nontrivial Right. You know, thing,
um, at a minimum, I hope, you know,
I know by code in North America stairwells have to have
uh positive pressure so that smoke doesn't get into them
because there's no point going down the stairwell if it's full of smoke.
Right, you're going to die.
Here's what you just made me think of with, with this line of conversation is
this is what we do in it
almost all the time. And even this qual
thing
is, is comparable of,
we basically figured out how to fix it without really fixing it.
And so
it's still
a
really fix it without rewriting everything.
And, and sometimes you got to tear down the building because it's that bad.
And, and I'm not gonna say that with that, Linux is that bad.
But I think this is something that
we're reaching a point with a lot of this technology.
We've been kicking the can down the road for so long
that
it, it might be time to burn some of these buildings down.
-- I mean,
-- well, in a, in a way it's happened, um,
like a lot of newer languages like Python and go, well, Python's not new.
But anyways, there's a lot of languages now that essentially, you know,
take the tact of,
we're not going to let you me,
we're just not going to let you manage memory, we're going to do it for you.
I don't think that's far enough. I think
I
agree.
Yeah.
But I mean, we, we're getting to that point like so go for example,
I looked at the temporary file creation function and you,
you're not allowed to do it insecurely,
you're just not
end of story.
No, the way it does it is it, you know, it does the randomized name,
it does the o exclusion open,
it does all the things that you should be doing
to create a temporary file safely and that's the default.
And as far as I know there's, I don't think there's any overrides for it.
And that's a great example of like, well, that,
that class of vulnerability is now gone.
Although,
sadly,
I've seen one or two go programs that shelled out
to bash to create temporary files and have floss,
which
I don't know that
I know exactly.
Well, and this is a, you know, like the, like, like this
tower block that, you know, if they spent an extra,
like, what, eight or $10,000 us on, on the cladding.
Yeah, this wouldn't have been nearly as much of a problem.
Uh,
you know.
Yes. And, and so here's where I want to tie it back to though.
You mentioned automobile accidents
and we know they're terrible and we know it's a slow burn.
What's gonna be the solution to automobile accidents?
Is it gonna be adding safety features into cars?
Well, I think that's part of it.
Oh,
yeah. And
I'll get there in a second.
Well, and
yes, self driving cars, but also, um,
there's a lot of cars now that also have pedestrian safety features
so that when they hit a pedestrian, they don't, you know,
destroy the pedestrian.
Um, but for example, I know Jaguar, uh, to get the profile of the car for their look.
Right,
the hood is actually,
uh, basically it's too low.
Like if you hit a pedestrian, it's gonna just, you're gonna knock the person flying.
So the hood actually pops up
to give a crumple zone for the pedestrian.
Like it pops up, I think, four or five inches
because otherwise it's basically right on the engine. Right.
So if you hit the hood, you're basically hitting the engine.
I don't view that as a feature because you still hit the person
and
-- you know what, just don't hit him. That's the right answer.
-- Yes. Oh, I agree.
But the problem is until we take humans out of the equation.
Yeah. And, you know, machines won't be infallible.
But, uh, for example, yesterday, at a marked crosswalk with my kids,
the,
you know,
and we were having some trouble getting
everybody collected and organized across the street.
You know,
the car will wait and not just get impatient and
drive when my one son steps into the road,
right.
You know, with his arm out and he's wearing orange. So,
yeah, anyways,
no, the, the, the simple answer is to take humans out of the equation.
I mean, the number of people texting and driving now is responsible for, I think,
what was it?
Two thirds of all accidents or some ridiculous amount.
Oh, man, I have no doubt of that. II,
I see that so often
where, where the vast majority of people who almost hit me,
I ride my bike a lot so I almost get hit a lot.
And
I more often,
I bet in 80% of the instances I,
I can see they're on their cell phone or they're screwing around with it.
Right. And of course, then they yell at me because it was my fault.
But it's,
oh man, it's so, so here's the question though, is
can we take people out of writing software?
And I'm sure there are a bunch of people that just threw their shoe at their computer.
And y
no.
Well, and, and the answer is there sort of is um I think one of the things we,
we as an industry need to push is more use of frameworks.
You know, there's a lot of really good web frameworks, for example,
that just don't have like cross site request
forgery issues because the framework authenticates every request.
You know what? Yes, I agree with you.
And I used to think that way, but I've come to realize, I mean,
Google can't get rid of the cross site scripting
and I'm sure they are framework to death.
There is
that is a good start.
But again, I think that's the hood flipping up.
So now we decapitate the pedestrian instead of just flipping them over the car.
Right.
Yeah.
Well, I, I don't think we can fully take humans out of the equation.
Um, because part of it too is, you know, you've got like, things like logical bugs or
behaviors that we defined that we thought were safe and as it turns out whoops.
No, that was a bad assumption.
Like email.
Yeah. Actually, no, that's a great example because, um,
I deal with one organization and they constantly get
phishing attempts and they're not even very sophisticated.
They're like, you know, the CEO name at gmail.com, you know,
go pay this invoice to this Russian bank account right now.
I'm,
I'm unavailable for the next 12 hours. So, just do it
right. And,
you know,
the reality is if people
read email and then follow the instructions blindly. Well, yeah.
Yep. Yep.
That's all I got. I don't have a solution.
People, people that are the problem.
Kurt, in nearly everything we look at the fundamental problem comes down to people.
Right.
Well, and the worst thing is it's people who are well meaning and trying to help. I,
most people are well meaning
and, and that's what makes it even more sad
is these aren't bad or evil people.
Generally speaking, these are just people who make silly mistakes.
Oh, man.
Uh, yeah. Anyway,
you know, in, in, so here's something else to think about actually is, is
kind of tying together
Wallace's stack clash with this Grenfell Tower is
Wallace did all this research and nobody really got hurt. Right.
That, that we know of
-- not so far as we know.
-- Right.
Whereas in the vast majority of real world kind of tragedies it,
we find out about it because something terrible
happens and lots of people get hurt and
it's kind of crazy to think about is
more often than not. I don't think this is like nice quiet research.
It's usually something crazy, literally lit on fire or exploded. And now we know,
well, I mean,
recently the city removed something like 30 or 40
slides from playgrounds because they're made out of metal,
they're welded, the welds can crack.
Uh,
and these two pieces of metal are joined at 90 degrees and
you can get your fingers in there and get them amputated.
And that's apparently happened to two kids, not in this city, but in other places.
Uh So there's a nationwide recall on these slides.
These
two little kids lost their fingers.
Uh They've been around for a few years.
It's basically three pieces of metal welded at 90 degrees. So you've got
a
slide.
-- I
-- remember when I was a kid,
like all the slides were metal because like there weren't plastic slides.
And so, yeah, no, two kids ended up with, you know,
losing bits of their fingers before we had a nationwide recall on these slides and,
right. And
not like that.
If it's only a couple of kids, you're never even gonna hear about it because it,
it's just not, it's not big enough.
-- Right?
-- I mean, in this
case, it's how the
news is.
But, well, in this case, the system has worked, right,
because they identified the problem clearly, you know, one kid,
maybe it's a weird accent.
Two kids. Ok. Now it's a pattern
and, you know, I mean,
I've always wondered about these slides because they didn't weld the entire scene,
just spot welded the scene.
-- Basically,
-- it seems bonkers. I mean, come on, you've got to know that's a problem.
Well, yeah, with like kids jumping up and down on the slide,
I always kind of looked at them a little bit, you know.
Right.
So, anyway, so, you know, they, what's interesting is the city was like, yeah,
a whole bunch of people have called and been really angry until they find out why.
Right.
So, and I think that's one of the things with Infosec is,
you know, sometimes, well, like today, you know, it's like, yeah,
we had this embargo extended because otherwise we would have
gone public with something and not had a solution.
Well, no,
even more dangerous though is when you don't have a solution and
you don't have cool heads looking at something you can make foolish mistakes
and, and I'll point to shell shock is one of the greatest examples. There is
the shell shock story and,
and a lot of people don't know this story and
I do love telling it is so shell shock gets announced
and there was a very, I was, I don't even know if there was an embargo.
I think there was a very
embargo.
-- It was like a one week embargo.
-- And I remember
we were involved in a
Florian Verner who you mentioned earlier who works on GLC.
He helped with shell shock and basically, he said your fix isn't complete.
We should do it this way,
but it would have broken some backwards compatibility in bash.
And so the bash guy said, no, we're not gonna fix it the right way.
We're just gonna fix literally this one instance of the problem.
And everybody knew there were more of these
bugs right under the surface and we're like,
ok, I guess we'll do it your way.
Right. And then
it gets released and like, two hours later,
I think it was Tavis Ormandy finds more bugs.
Exactly the same problem for the most part. And we're like, oh, crap.
And that's when I know like Fedora and Friends and Red Hat said
we're just gonna do what Florian said we should do because that seems better
and, and they technically broke backwards compatibility
upstream. Fix the one bug Tavis found.
And then I think it was, uh, Matthew
Zalewski with his one, a FL American fuzzle
laps fuzz.
He
he started fuzzing it and he's like, I found more than 50 bugs exactly like this.
Right. What are we gonna do?
And then the bash guys were like, I guess we'll fix it the right way
and like,
and see part of me doesn't disagree because on the one hand,
you have this theoretical security, potentially terrible thing.
On the other hand, you definitely have breaking backwards compatibility,
which definitely will break.
I'm gonna say no. And I'm gonna, I'm gonna stand.
I'm not
agreeing
-- with them. I'm saying I just see their point of view.
-- We have committed too many sins
in the history of computing
in the name of backwards compatibility
and
a, a nontrivial number of problems have resulted due to that fact.
Instead of saying we need to throw this away and start over,
we've tried to keep this broken down, train on fire on the tracks and that,
that is not OK.
I, I have become a huge opponent of backwards compatibility.
What do we do with all the in-house corporate software that's been written,
look, but here's the thing. OK. So let's use IE six as an example. IE six is end of life.
You need IE six. Great. Get a virtual machine and run IE six.
You know what firewall to death,
you know, the risk you're taking
instead of limping this crap along forever.
And, and you're, I, I understand the argument you're making,
but I think the counter argument which is the only right
way to go is to say if you need this,
like, you need to take extraordinary measures to make it work,
not expect the world to support your poor decisions.
Well, yeah, no, no more. My point is that
I,
yeah, if it was up to me, I,
I am much happier with breaking backwards compatibility
because I live in the open source world.
So quite frankly, if something breaks,
we have the source code and generally enough smart people to
fix it and then we recompile it and life goes on.
But that's not true of most of the world, right?
They, they may not have the source code or they don't have the expertise to fix it.
So I can understand why these programmers.
For example, the bash guys would want to say, you know,
we want to make a minimally invasive change
so that we, you know, break as little stuff as possible.
And I think that's a laudable goal, but the problem is, as you pointed out
-- quite often, those changes are insufficient,
-- right?
Well, not only that, let's face it,
the people who actually need the backwards compatibility
probably are never going to upgrade and I'm sure they're running
a version of bash from 20 years ago as it is.
Well, and see, that's one of my concerns is,
and that's one of my fundamental concerns with this whole industry.
We have no data.
We literally like,
I don't know what what is the patching curve?
You know, for a given organization?
Like, do they patch 10% of systems within an hour, within 10 hours, within 10 days?
10 years?
You know, what's, what's the, you know,
it's like when I think Trump came out and said, oh my God.
You know, the, I forget which government department has, like,
this 40 year old it system.
And I'm like,
no, they don't, they have like, 50 of those. Are you kidding me? Like,
like, I, you know, every, like,
uh, I'm trying to think of what my oldest it system at home is,
but it's probably 10 or 20
years old if I had to guess,
just because I'm a pessimist and there's probably something I've forgotten about,
like, literally, you know.
Oh, yeah.
No, my wireless routers, they haven't had ad DW,
they're old enough that I can't get DDW RT updates for them in the last two,
three years.
My wireless routers cook themselves about every two years.
Yeah, it's, it's about time for an upgrade.
Plus I can, it doesn't seem to reach the basement very well anymore.
There you go.
Um,
but, yeah, so, I mean, you know, even myself, I, I've still got it.
Well, I have out of date it systems because I have to go spend 2,
300 bucks on new hardware that essentially only gets me up to date software.
Not really much
-- advantages or features that I don't already have
-- Right.
-- Right. You should probably check those things for, uh, CIA Malware.
-- Now,
that's
not the worst idea. I was
with the
idea of
-- using raspberry pies with external antennas.
-- I've thought about that before.
It's, I don't know, every now and then I get tempted and then I'm like, ah,
these things are 100 bucks.
They're so cheap now and they work really well.
Well, I've been looking at some of the higher end wireless routers
to get better coverage in. This
might be why yours is 20 years old.
And mine only last two years because I buy the, I buy the $90 router
at the same time. Like it works. Right. It basically works.
And the beauty though, too of replacing them every two years is every two years.
There's something new and exciting in the world of wireless I get.
So I do see an advantage to that
anyway.
I think, I think it's time to clean this one up. It's
thank, thank you, everybody.
It's been kind of a, a wild conversation to say the least, uh, good luck patching
for, for Stat Clash. And if you haven't read the qual, this advisory
do it, it's insanely long, but it is marvelous.
-- Was beautiful.
-- It is, it is a work of art.
Yeah. When they send it to me, I was like, oh,
yeah. Ok. I guess that answers all my questions.
Like, normally when somebody, you know,
find something bad and they send in an advisory.
You're like, OK, I need clarification on like these seven things.
-- But in this case, it was like, oh no, that's, it's like,
-- wow,
this thing deserves a literature award
for writing. It is, it is well done and it has uh quotes from Clash
the
the Band, the Clash in it. So
you got to love that. Right.
So I guess anyway, if anyone wants to see the,
the various links to the stories we've spoken of today,
you can go to open source security podcast.com.
We'll have links to the QIS
blog, which is very short and the Qis
advisory which is very long. I recommend you read them both.
And if you visit the website, you can have links to Twitter and Facebook,
you can reach us with the Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag
I guess if anyone has any questions or feedback by all means, you know, hit us up,
let us know.
And if nothing else, Kurt, you have a marvelous day and, and good luck and well done,
man.
Thanks.
And I guess for everybody out there, you know, if you see something, say something
and don't just, oh, and literally don't, you know,
sometimes people will try and fob you off and be like, oh, no, it's not a big deal.
No, it, it could be a big deal.
-- So make sure somebody knows, you know, tell an adult as it were.
-- Indeed. Indeed.
All right. Have a good one, everybody. Thanks. Bye bye.