Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 156 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Pressers.
-- What's
-- new man?
Not a lot? Just enjoying summer.
-- It,
-- it is summer. I'm so, so I guess full disclosure today.
I am in my garage recording this podcast.
It's I can tell there's a little more echo than usual, but I'll,
I'll do my best to keep it down.
My house is ridiculous. Today I have workmen cutting holes in walls.
I'm getting an air conditioner installed
and the police have been pulling people over in front of my house
all day long for speeding and not stopping for people crossing the street.
So it's just sirens and saws are, is my morning. It's been, it's been awesome.
Yeah,
I've got road construction behind my house now
for the next one until the end of October
forever. Kurt, it will never end.
That's how road construction always feels.
And, and then, you know what I love though,
it looks like it's a total train wreck and
then two days later they're gone and it's perfect.
It always amazes me how fast that just like, last step goes
-- when they're doing that sort of work.
-- Yeah. Well, it's like a lot of things.
It's, you know, that final bit of tidy up and then it's, it's nice.
So, sort of, speaking of which, so Kazakhstan, similar situation,
they've made a bit of a mess of things, but
they just don't care because, well, they don't have to.
All right,
why don't you explain what's going on in Kazakhstan and then we'll go from there.
So Kazakhstan is one of those former
Soviet satellite states.
Kazakhstan is sort of in the southern middle bit next to uh well,
sort of sandwiched between Russia and
China basically like it, it's just next door to Mongolia.
So if you play a lot of hearts of iron for, you'll know where it is
the part with no roads.
And so like a lot of these former Soviet Republics, they have, let's say,
not a strong set of democratic institutions.
I think it might be fair to say
that's a generous explanation from what I
so their most recent bit of shenanigans from the government is a, is an online safety
program system.
Let's not call it that because we all know it, it has nothing to do with safety.
-- It's not safety for the people.
-- No, no, no.
And um anyways, so they're, they're trying to man in the middle,
all of the HTTP S traffic in the country
by requiring people to install a new root certificate.
And, and actually this, this actually that alone,
I think shows a vast improvement in the last 10 years.
Is that to now man, in the middle of traffic, you actually have to touch the end point.
-- Whereas back in the day,
-- that is true,
there are all sorts of ways to get around this.
Now, let's let's start at the beginning though.
And
what does it mean
to install a man in the middle root certificate?
Because I, I have a suspicion,
this is something people soar to know about but not exactly.
So,
one of the fundamental ideas behind encryption is
that you encrypt your data so that other
people can't see it and that only the remote end you actually want to talk to can
crypt it and see it. Right?
So you have this magically secure tunnel between you and the remote ant
cool. Right.
And, and you know,
theoretically speaking, anybody can record the traffic that's always possible,
but they can't
see what it is. Right.
Right. Without the secret key and these keys are quite large,
you know, several like 2048 or 4096 bits, which means, you know,
brute forcing these things with current
computational reality is just not possible.
Like as like, I literally mean by the way we understand reality,
it's not that we don't have the technology for this.
It's the way we understand reality.
This is not really possible short of some absurd break in quantum computing.
And even then we have ways to deal with that back in the day,
man in the middle and traffic was actually pretty easy because you could just
go get a certificate authority that was installed in a browser by default,
that was willing to issue certificates for anything.
And so they were actually man in the middle, you know, hardware products,
-- uh sort of these in line machines uh
-- they still exist,
They do, they do
-- but you have to install like a corporate C
-- A Exactly. And that's,
yeah, because the, the browser is the cab form the certificate.
What does the cab forum stand for? Again?
I have
no
idea.
-- But we should also clarify the concept
-- of uh C A browser for.
There you go.
We should also clarify what a root certificate does.
Your browser has an insane number of root certificates in it
and
the
way it kind of works.
Yeah, I know that's,
-- that's another story
-- because there's root certificates
and there's intermediate certificates and we don't,
we actually don't know how many intermediate certificates
there are on the planet right now.
So
that is true.
And, but anyway, what basically happens is you'll have a certificate, you trust
that says I trust this certificate for everything.
And then that certificate will sign another certificate, let's say
open source security, podcast.com
and say
I verified this person is who they say they are using some means.
And then,
-- well this
-- domain name.
Well, yeah, I mean. Right. It's, it's not super
exciting,
but the point being
they do some level of verification.
And then you can essentially say, well,
this certificate authority I trust says I can trust this certificate over here.
Well, basically, certificates provide a mapping to
talk to a DNS end point.
And
to be clear, I'm talking about web browsers here.
So basically it allows you to talk to a DNS end point
and get a certificate for that DNS end point
that you can be reasonably certain that,
that DNS end point actually owns and controls that certificate.
Right. Exactly. And so for example, if I
try to man in the middle of you, when you go to google.com
and I don't have a valid google.com certificate,
the web browser will, you know, blink the flashing red lights and say, oh, no,
something's wrong, don't do this.
However,
if I have a certificate that pretends to
be google.com signed by a certificate authority,
your browser trusts,
I can do that.
And so in the past, this is a big problem because there was a bunch of certificate,
authorities that were just handing these things out to security companies
and allowing them, you know,
and this is what I'm talking about with these intermediate certificates.
So the root certificates typically sign an
intermediate certificate and the intermediate certificate is
actually what is used on sort of the daily basis to sign other certificates.
It's certificates, all the way down. Exactly.
And in theory, the root certificate is very heavily protected and blah, blah, blah,
but
they're not.
And so, yeah,
so these companies would be able to sign
a certificate for any domain that they wanted,
which meant the in line box would have one of these magical root certificates.
Uh,
well, one of these magical quasi
root certificates, you know, intermediate certificates installed on them.
And so when you went to google.com, you know, it would
intercept the
connection and create a certificate for google.com
and your browser would accept that.
And obviously, you know, this is kind of a big problem like because this is, well,
this is how man in the middle attacks work, especially with nation states,
right? Because they control the I SPS and they can put these machines in line.
They don't have to do like DNS hijacking shenanigans.
It's like we own all the internet connections to the country.
Like if you want to talk to anything outside the country, you got to go through us.
That's generally how I SPS work. So Kazakhstan created a certificate
and is trying to get people to install in their browser.
And like I said,
this is this is actually a vast improvement over how
things used to be because it used to be.
You didn't need to do that. Like you could just man in the middle people based on
at least one of the root certificates they trusted,
right? You didn't need any action by the end client
and the end client would typically have no idea
that they were being man in the middle.
Um So now we've got a bunch of new technologies like
certificate pinning.
And um what are those DNS records CAA records called,
where you basically declare which certificate authorities are
allowed to issue certificates for your domain.
And theoretically speaking, if any, you know, if you see a certificate
for that domain or,
or if somebody tries to issue a certificate for that domain using another
certificate, authority certificate, it should be blocked or, you know,
cause a ruckus.
So, yeah, I mean, at least I, I guess the good news here is,
is that users are going to be somewhat
aware that they're being manned in the middle because
their government is forcing them to install a new root certificate on the browser.
Right?
There's an interesting discussion in the Mozilla Foundation's bug tracker
and it looks like the ultimate decision was, well, they had a couple of options,
number one.
just it's not a problem, whatever who care.
Right. That, that's one way that, you know, and that's
honestly, that's probably what more than a few browsers will do outside of the big,
you know, three or four browsers.
There's,
there's actually what a couple of 100 browsers now,
I was looking on the mobile phone and there's, there's quite a few.
Yeah.
Oh yeah. Yeah, there's tons. Definitely.
So, yeah. Number one is just ignore it, whatever.
Let the government do what the government does.
Uh number two would be to actually block the certificate, right.
These certificates have a, you know, a serial number and, and identifiers
that you could just block, then, you know,
the users would be kind of making bigger codes here protected.
A
third option,
which I think is a bit more interesting and useful is
to accept like to allow the certificate not to block it,
but to present a warning
when it is
ultimately used.
So for example, when you go to google.com
and instead of getting the google.com signed with Google's certificate,
you get it signed with this, you know, government certificate
to put up a giant red bar at the top of the browser saying, you know,
you're at google.com cool. But
the connection is actually with, you know, the Kazakhstan government,
right? They're intercepting it actively like they are
and this isn't a fast thing like they are actively
intercepting and manipulating the data. They're basically,
you know, you're talking to the government, the government's talking to Google,
Google talks back to the government, the government talks back to you.
Exactly.
I don't know because on the one hand,
sovereignty and law,
there's lots of countries out there with laws I don't like
or agree with and conversely Canada where I live has laws
but other countries don't have and disagree with, you know, uh the drinking age,
for example, even in Canada, the drinking age varies from, uh, what is 18 and, uh,
in a couple of places it's 19
in other parts of the world. It's 1416, 1821. You know, who's to say what's right?
Like,
you know, I, if I were under 21 I can't legally go to most of the US and drink.
So do I just get to disagree with that and be like, well in my country.
So, on the one hand, you know, I, I think about the sovereignty of this
government and the, you know, they,
they get to make their own laws even if they're terrible.
But on the flip side, you know, there are certain laws that we've had in the past that
we got rid of because they were terrible laws.
This is a terrible law.
And so in this case, we, we enter into that area of, ok,
so it's the law it's been passed.
Is it moral and ethical?
I'm not going to get into if it's moral or ethical,
I'm going to say it's stupid.
Well, and that's the second set. Is it effective?
No, it won't be. Well, ok,
it might be for what they want it to be for because let's face it.
This is, this is a country with a regime in charge
that is not necessarily interested in the safety of its people.
It's almost certainly going to use this technology to quell dissent
and there are, there's a couple of things that are in my mind
that concerned me about all of this. Number one,
there are no doubt,
a nontrivial number of other countries on the bench waiting to see what happens.
And if they get away with this,
they're gonna, they're gonna stand up and they're going to say we want this too.
And the reality is that the technology must exist to some
degree to pull this off on a pretty wide scale level.
Now, at the same time, there's companies are working with that,
do this and shame on you companies for working with Kazakhstan to make this happen.
Because this is,
this is one of those things where history will judge you and you're doing it wrong
unquestionably. Now, secondly, there is the issue of
if you're installing this key on everyone's computer,
I guarantee they're not protecting it correctly and it's going to leak.
And now you are going to have an instance where
the government
and probably some will say less than admirable organizations,
probably organized crime to a degree
are going to also have access to this. And that's terrifying.
Well, I mean, one of the challenges is is in this type of country,
the difference between organized crime and the government is
fuzzy
sometimes.
And, and one of the challenges too though is that these,
these technologies do legitimately need to exist.
Because for example, in America, in the finance industry,
there's basically a requirement that these financial companies
need to know what's on their network.
Well, and they, by definition can't if it's all encrypted.
So these financial companies on their own
works with their own users and their own devices and hardware
are installing these men in the middle proxies,
installing the root certificates on the users, you know,
phone and laptop and whatever. How is that different than this? You know, and
I, I would say, well, you know, that's a private network,
it's not a public network and it's, you know, there's,
there's very much more the full disclosure of what's going on and,
and in many cases, even the actual hardware being used as being, you know,
it's owned by the company, it's not owned by the end user.
-- And, and
-- for the record, I think banks doing this is also stupid because
at
the end of the day it lowers security and I understand they have to, I,
I get that and I'm sure most of them don't want to, but it's not, it's not their choice.
I don't know it. To me it's a gray area. I, I actually
in some situations, especially like say banking or where you have other
very, very valuable and sensitive data.
I I'm ok with this because for preventing leak,
you know, data leaks and preventing exfiltration of data.
-- Yeah, I'm ok with this, whatever
-- man,
I guarantee this technology has never actually prevented any data leaks and if
anything it's probably caused them because now you have to protect this key,
protecting keys is hard to impossible.
Well, yes and no. If, if the technology is done right, where you have like
hardware security modules in each of the intercepting proxies and you,
you know,
use them to generate a certificate that then goes back to a master one to be signed it,
it can be done securely.
The problem is doing that is expensive.
So most places don't, they do it a little bit cheaper, let's say
right.
And, and that's, yeah, that's where you get your key leaks and whatnot.
Your optimism is inspiring.
Well, what I'm trying to point out is, is the technology can be done correctly.
The fact that it isn't, isn't the technology's fault.
That's just the economics of the situation. You know, people want to save the
two bucks.
This is like saying we could cure poverty. We just can't.
Well,
-- we choose not to,
-- we have the technology,
we just don't.
Well, like I tell my Children, we have this, you know,
we have the technology and the strength of will to watch something on Netflix.
But, you know, for other things, we don't have the strength.
Oh
my goodness. So back to this. So
I think the problem is,
and I I tweeted this out probably a year or two ago that basically if your
information security strategy depends on behaving like a nation state attacker,
but it's probably going to fail longer term
because people like Google and Mozilla are,
well, they're trying to protect users from this because
that's what you do, right?
You want, we want to build it that protects users from attacks.
A nation state attack is hard to tell apart from like
a
ba a quote unquote bad guy attack.
Uh, in, in, in some cases, you could argue it's the same thing,
right? If, if another country is attacking me in
the United States,
that's a bad guy, right?
If the United States is attacking someone in another country,
we're the bad guy in that instance from their perspective, right?
Of course, everyone thinks that's a good guy in their own personal narrative.
But that's another, that's a topic for another day.
So what's interesting to me is there, there were a number of efforts
to deal with essentially this exact scenario. Http public key pinning.
So HPKP, it was a Google based I ETF standard
as I understand it, Google and others have backed off from this because
it,
how do we put it nicely?
If you make a mistake when you do this, you break everything
horribly and permanently.
So
a great example.
It's like SPF Records for uh Sender Protective Framework records for your email,
which basically are a fancy way of saying in DNS who's allowed
to send email for my domain and you have soft fail,
which is what almost everybody uses because
your SPF records sometimes aren't always up to date and
you don't want to actually block all your outgoing email.
Right.
You know, and that's,
and that's actually on my to do list this year for the CS A for example,
is to actually make sure
that all of our outgoing email is,
is covered by SPF and flip that tilda all to negative all and just tell the clients,
you know, if the
email didn't come from these servers or sites or whatever, block it,
you know, but that's,
it makes me a little nervous because you know,
what if we forgot something or password resets or whatever, right.
So,
you know, that's,
that's the problem with a lot of these
technologies designed to defeat this class of attack.
The chance of having a false positive and breaking everything is,
it's basically 100% like it's going to happen at some point is what I'm saying,
-- it will eventually happen.
-- Yes. Yeah. And it, and it
may take more than a few minutes or even hours or days to correct,
depending on what you did.
-- And
-- broke man. I remember doing that where back in the day when I managed my own DNS
where you'd before you touched anything,
you'd like the day before,
you'd always set the TT L the time to live to like five minutes.
If you did break something, it was only broken for five minutes.
Whereas the default TT L was like 24 hours or something. I think
the first time I ever broke a domain.
It took a day
to be fixed. I'm like, oh my goodness, this is terrible.
So I once made the trade off between DNS reliability and, and DNS reliability.
In that
I realized rather cleverly when you register a domain
like c.org
you
get to then in the root servers specify two or more
DNS servers, right?
So most people have like DNS 01 dot blah, blah, blah, and DNS 02 dot blah blah blah.
And I was clever, I realized I could save time on DNS lookups
on my website by making my DNS server,
www.c.org and putting that IP address into my registrar record.
And then basically hoping that, you know, I never switch I SPS for hope
and, and it worked like it was stupid fast and if my DNS broke,
you could still get to my website.
But then when I had to swing change providers, it was like, oh man,
that was a nightmare,
right?
Well done.
-- Yeah.
-- So that, that's, that's essentially, you know,
in solving some of these problems.
Sometimes the solutions have failure scenarios that are actually
worse than the failure scenarios of like an attack.
As far as I know all of these technologies for
http key pinning and everything have fallen by the wayside,
right?
Because they're all really hard and the cost benefit
analysis has been super skewed where generally speaking,
our existing C A infrastructure is kind of a tire fire
but it basically works good enough.
So we deal with it
and, and like this is even, you know, I'll pick on DNS
Sec where it always comes up as, oh, DNS SE can fix this.
It's like, yeah, but it's really hard to implement and nobody wants to.
So it's never going to win.
I will politely disagree in that DNS SEC is a lot like http was 10 years ago.
Currently, it's very hard for you to implement.
But if you choose somebody like and not to name drop, but cloud flare in cloud flare,
you click a button.
Yeah, I mean, that's fair and to be real, that's kind of how HTTP S
you go with a provider that had a relationship with AC A or something or had the,
had used a platform like wordpress or something where
you could just plug in a certificate easily.
If you wanted to, for example,
build your own Apache server with your own certificate.
1520 years ago.
If you could do that, you could easily earn six figures a year.
-- I remember those days. It was
-- me too.
It was terrible.
And you had to buy,
you had to buy a
library
to, to do http.
I actually bought a copy of Red Hat
Stronghold server because it was the cheapest HTTP
server out there. It was a mere like four or 500 bucks.
And now I think literally every everything I have with a web server.
Has built an HTTP S because why not?
-- Like, I'm pretty sure my, my bathroom scale has an HTTP S web server.
-- I hope so.
But anyway, anyway, back to
the concept of a country
intercepting
all of the HTTP S traffic. The, the thing that keeps eating my brain about this
is
let's assume
they have
things deployed correctly where the key can't leak because it's all in
HS MS and ignoring the fact that most Hs MS are,
are hot garbage, it turns out.
So let, let's assume the technology is sound though.
Right
now,
we get into the issue of what does it mean for the people who have to use the internet.
And the thing that keeps coming to my mind is if I was a corporation
and I was looking to set a business somewhere,
I'd look at this and say no f and we are any of my computers sitting on this network,
I can't trust the data going in or out.
Nope. Just no.
And like from, from the perspective of trying to be, you know,
a functional country on the planet today,
that's
terrible.
Well, as far as I know, it's kind of weird is that Kazakhstan doesn't block VPN S.
Right. There are a lot of countries that try to block VPN S
for government sort of information control means or,
or my classic favorite is a bunch of Middle Eastern countries where they block VPN S
so that you have to pay for phone calls because, you know,
they have a state telco monopoly that wants to make money.
And let's face it. A great example. Right.
I
called you on the phone the other day because the internet
connections with Skype and Slack and everything were so terrible.
And then I realized I didn't have long distance
on my phone anymore because this is the first
phone call I'd made with my phone in the US in probably two or three years, you know.
And I was like, oh, yeah,
-- here's
-- the other side of this. So if they're allowing VPN S,
that means the, the bad guys will put that in quotes
are just going to VPN,
right?
They're,
they're not going to use regular HTTP S now we're at a
point where basically who are you even catching in this dragnet,
right?
You're like,
you're catching people that have no idea what's going on.
And, and at that point, I mean, really, what's,
what is the point of that then?
Well, and I think that's,
that is the point of that is that you're catching people who are maybe
thinking about dissent or thinking about saying
bad things about the government but aren't
technologically clued in enough to not,
or to understand what putting the certificate on their machine means.
You know, it's like, oh, online safety,
I better do that because the government said
so I don't trust my government entirely.
But, hey, online safety is good. Right.
And, you know, they're probably like, let's,
let's face it how many normal people VPN
less than a percent zero,
-- zero is the number.
-- Yeah, it's essentially a rounding error.
As soon as you start using a VPN, you're no longer a normal person.
That's pretty much how it works.
And the other thing this has then is the,
not only does it allow them to sort of quell dissent by seeing what people are saying,
but for,
for example, the people who don't play ball, for example,
you can make that against the law and then now you have something to go arrest them on
-- for
-- you mean say making VPN S illegal.
Well, or requiring that the certificate be installed or for example, in the US,
you have wiretapping legislation and laws that require you
as a provider of telecommunication services to
provide lawful intercept capabilities,
which is why my understanding is signal telegram.
A couple of these other things are actually not based in the US,
right? Well, it's, it's, it gets complicated.
But you know, if, if you're like Skype,
my understanding is originally Skype had most of
their data centers in Canada to provide services
for the US because this allowed them to sort of get around it a bit.
It wouldn't surprise me. And
I mean,
I I won't get into that either because I think
the wiretapping laws are silly for a variety of reasons.
But
at
the very least
you can't just show up and say we need to wiretap this guy's phone.
You know, you're supposed to show up with a warrant and to get a warrant.
You have to go through some process
that, that justifies your activities.
Whereas when you have the government blanket man in the meddling you,
you know, there's no due process, there's no checks and balances.
Well, and, and I would point out even, you know, the US,
the NSA got caught doing this yet again after they were ordered not to.
So
the reality is even even in countries with
pretty strong democratic institutions and reasonably
well behaved security services and agencies.
Yeah, they, they just,
I, I guess the temptation is too great. I don't know, man.
Or they think they won't get caught. I have no idea.
It's probably all of the above.
Yeah.
And also people going to be people and do goofy stuff at
work that they really shouldn't do like wiretap the Western world.
But I think fundamentally what it boils down to is generally speaking,
the major browser providers of which I
will say basically we're talking Firefox chrome,
uh safari and maybe opera, generally speaking, they,
they do a pretty good job of trying to protect their users.
-- Right. Right. Yeah. But user trust is huge in this space.
-- Exactly.
Yeah.
And so
I'm actually kind of glad Kazakhstan is doing this because it's, it's
to be blunt,
I think the browser vendors need a poke in the
eye once every year or two to remind them that
-- this isn't some hypothetical like this stuff does actually happen.
-- That's fair.
-- I mean, I'll agree with that because
-- we went through this about what, 5, 10 years ago,
with a whole bunch of this and then it sort of got quiet for a while and,
and for example,
one of the biggest things the browsers did was clean up the cab for him by,
you know, if basically we catch you
providing these certificates that can be used to sign
anything in these man in the middle proxies.
Yeah, we're going to bounce you out and a few were and you know,
several that were not very well behaved got bounced out and it, it actually,
yeah. No, it, it actually made things a bit better. And so hopefully with this,
I mean, and what I really love too is, I mean, TLS 1.3
specifically has a whole pile of protections
to make this kind of nation state
shenanigans much more difficult
as evidenced by the fact that they have to install us. Like
we need you to put the certificate on your client so we can look at your traffic.
-- That means this stuff is working.
-- Yeah. No, I, I agree. I agree
completely.
You know, it's basically this is rubber hose crypto at this point.
I'm going to beat you until you put the certificate on your machine.
There's no
easy technical attack for me to exploit.
That's great. That means the technology is working.
Yeah. No. And I agree with that. I, I do agree and I think that
that may be the silver lining
in the story,
even though I feel really bad for everyone in Kazakhstan because this is terrible.
I'm glad it's not some truly large government or,
you know, something essentially as bad as this is.
-- I hate to say it, it's not bad on a global scale.
-- Well, look, I mean,
the other thing I thought of here is
it can't be on a global scale. If you look at most of we'll say North America, right?
United States and Canada,
there is no way
you could capture all the internet traffic and do anything with it.
There is no way there's just like that amount of storage you would need to do that
probably only exists in one place today because they keep getting caught doing it,
right.
I mean, fundamentally speaking,
it's just, it's, it's not practical
and I think that's part of it also is Kazakhstan clearly
doesn't have a huge robust internet infrastructure because if they did,
they couldn't do this.
I'm guessing that they're targeting
a few specific services.
So II I don't think we've done a show on this yet, but I was reading about how
these human rights groups have started doing things like, OK,
we don't do email attachments because yeah, email attachments,
it turns out they're kind of a security problem,
like who knew 30 years and we finally figured it out.
And so they're doing things like, you know, using Google Drive to share documents
and there's been now phishing attempts where, you know,
somebody sends you a link to kind of what looks like a Google Drive.
And the Google Drive document has some nasty virus in it, blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah.
So
the reality is these human rights groups are
uh, well, the how do I put this nicely?
The smart ones follow a couple of simple and effective best practices
and again, not to pump, pump a vendor,
but if you need to do secure email and document sharing,
go get yourself a gmail
full stop.
That's it. That, that is, that's the answer. And so
by monitoring, you know, certain people and their Google activity,
you know, they, they, the government will potentially get what they want.
But like I said, I can't help but think that
this is one of those cases where you can make a law that essentially
either you follow the law and you're kind of screwed or
you don't follow the law and now they have something to
quote, unquote, legitimately charge you with.
Yeah, I mean, that's fair,
you know. So the government wins, they got what they wanted
-- anyway.
-- We, we need to call this one.
I think, I guess we will have to wait and see how this all turns. Turns out.
I'm I'm very curious to see where we end up in a couple of months.
Once kind of all the, the newness and details have, have worked themselves out.
So, Kurt, any parting thoughts,
uh I guess for those of you working on the design of TLS
1.4 please pay attention to this and if you could fix it,
that would be awesome.
Seriously. Awesome. Wonderful. Well, well, thanks so much.
Thank you for listening. You can go to open source security podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes. Y
Pound Os s podcast hashtag to hit us up on social
media and Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.