Hello and welcome to the Open source Security podcast
episode 25 also known as the silver anniversary with myself,
Kurt Siefried and Josh Pressers.
Hello, Kurt, how are you?
I am excellent. I'm over my kid's bug.
I'm not
so a for me.
Oh, man, I, uh, this time of year anyway.
Anyway, so I apologize in advance for sounding more silly than usual
as I have a, a terrible head cold right now.
But
I
guess they
go
back to
school on Monday.
-- I'm
-- assuming they do go back to school and no doubt they
will pick up new diseases to bring home and give to me.
I know. I know. Anyway. So, uh, ce S was last week.
Yeah. Yeah, I have to admit tv's got dinner.
That's an understatement. But
there were some pretty sweet ones.
Yeah. You know,
here's the deal, I guess is
that stuff is really cool. But I think we're at a point. It's just like,
yeah, it
took you so long. I mean,
that's kind of what I feel like.
-- I
-- feel like buying a TV. Now consists of
go spend 500 bucks.
-- Right.
-- That's it. That's all I got like,
-- and make sure it's like maybe four K, I don't know. Right.
-- Well, I got a four K TV.
Uh, I don't know, maybe six months ago. I, I didn't even plan on it. Is
I basically walked into Best Buy and I,
I went there because I wanted to look at things and make sure II, I was, I found the TV,
aesthetically pleasing
and various other things.
-- Honestly,
-- that would be a criteria. Now, does it match your furniture?
Right.
Well, and some of them are really freaking ugly. Like, I mean, let's just face it.
But, but anyway,
I ended up going and I looked at them all and I just
found the one that essentially had the most features I was interested in and
that's the one I bought and yeah, it was like 500 bucks. I mean, crazy.
-- Yeah,
-- I remember when TV. S like big TV. S used to actually be expensive
and they weighed 7000 pounds.
I, yeah. No, I, at one point had a 32 inch. Uh,
I,
I did
sorry, excuse my language but wow,
that thing was, yeah, it's huge.
Oh, man, I remember moving a 32 inch TV, with, with the C RT and I bet it weighed,
oh my goodness. It must have been like 300 pounds. It was so freaking heavy.
It took two people.
It was,
-- you better not like set it down sharply or?
-- Right.
-- It's just not gonna work
-- that too.
That too. Ah, the times they are changing.
So, so moving on from, from there is,
I feel like the single most interesting thing
that came out of CE S
is that everything is connected to the internet now.
Like everything they had a freaking hairbrush man that had Wi Fi on it.
Oh, the hairbrush that listens to the sound as you comb your hair
-- and then recommends like expensive beauty treatment stuff.
-- That's right.
That's right.
I saw that. It was,
yeah, I I'm kind of envious to be honest because I don't really have hair anymore. But
that that's a good point.
You don't have any hair so you clearly don't need this this device. But
I guess the way I look at this is
on one side,
I get that everything's going to get Wi Fi.
In fact, I,
I read a new story of LG basically said every appliance we make is going to have Wi Fi
and
I understand it's kind of the inevitable conclusion.
It's kind of like how every toy now it takes batteries,
whether it really needs it or not.
And
another part of me thinks like, why are we doing this? This is, this is madness.
I have an answer for you.
And it goes back again to extending monopolies and lock in,
right? If I sell you a hairbrush,
whatever, if I sell you a hairbrush that requires connectivity to my servers
to provide the value add,
I can now either charge you monthly for that value A or I can,
for example, essentially control,
you know what beauty products are being recommended to you.
You know,
that's a bad example because the airbrush will still work if I never turn on the wi
fi.
-- Well, so
-- will my nest smoke alarm, for example,
it'll still warn me my house is on fire but it won't tell my phone
which is a crime.
Well, you know, it's, it's kind of useful, right? Because I don't have to worry like
it's like all these security systems, right? Like I want a security system that,
you know,
ideally will do two things. One tell
people who will ultimately tell the people with guns like the police to like,
please go help this guy.
Number two, I would like it to tell my phone,
right? Because I mean, let's face it, right?
The phone is an extension of self nowadays, right?
Everybody carries a smartphone in their pocket
or they're just a ludite or
they live out in the woods
-- and don't have, you know, cell reception
-- or maybe all of those things.
Yeah. So
I, you know, that's the thing, right? How do you differentiate a hairbrush? Right.
We've had a hair brushes for if memory serves.
I remember seeing one in National Geographic,
you know,
they, they're
-- paleolithic or whatever time,
-- thousands of years,
at least probably tens of thousands and let's
face it like fingers were the first hairbrush,
right?
So, you know, and I'm making air quotes here. How do you like
add value to the product? How do you make it better? Right.
Like the wheel, you know, clearly rubber, rubber wheels are better because they,
-- they absorb shocks and you don't like lose your teeth
-- and you know,
what would make it even better is if we added Wi Fi to those rubber wheels,
we did that
kind of,
I know, I
know
the wireless, uh
the wireless
pressure
set
things
which, you
know,
kind of useful.
No, no, we should explain that though. For people who don't know
is in basically any wheel on a car today.
It has a little wireless sensor inside of it that
it basically measures the amount of air pressure in the,
in the tire.
In that way
when
the air pressure gets too low, it turns on that little light on your dash that says,
you know, hey fool go put some air in this tire
and you know, that saves lives.
Yes, it does. And I, I have no problem with that.
And in fact, for what it's worth,
I really don't have a problem with putting Wi Fi in a hairbrush.
I mean,
it's a bit comical in a lot of ways, but I think it's just kind of,
it's the nature of the universe today.
But the thing that scares me is I feel like we're rushing into this Wi Fi revolution
without the correct tools to actually make sure it doesn't turn into a Wi Fi mess.
Well, I think it's actually worse than that because I suspect a lot of these places
don't have a good idea or a business plan yet.
So, let's put in the infrastructure in the form of, like,
let's make this thing wi fi capable,
then we'll figure out what to do with it.
Like, really, that, that's probably fair.
And there, there's additionally, the, the thing that always keeps me up at night is
how are
nobody updates this stuff? And it's gonna be
exactly
updates
to it.
Yeah,
but are they gonna have enough storage space to
actually download an update and then swap it?
Storage is cheap?
It's not, yeah, but
it's not that cheap, man.
I, I don't know what these hairbrushes cost or, I mean, are they battery powered?
-- Like how does that even work?
-- I assume so, regardless it doesn't really,
could they be static electricity powered now, that would be awesome.
You know, they're not,
you know, they're not.
But here's the thing too is these devices are,
and this is part of kind of the Wi Fi revolution disaster.
That, that worries me is
let's face it. All of this stuff runs Linux,
right?
All of it is full of open source.
A
lot of it is probably all open source
where there's minimal stuff added by the manufacturer.
And as you and I both know very well open source. It has plenty of security flaws in it.
And if nobody's ever updating it,
what the heck is gonna happen in like 10 years when every device in your house has
more than 100 security flaws because nobody has ever
updated any of the firmware that's running it.
I mean, I guess the good news is,
is that you'd have to have two things take place
for like a worm or something to really work is
number one, the worm would have to have a way to get into your network because I mean,
the good news is,
but they all phone home, Kurt, all this crap is gonna phone home
assume for a moment that, that is quote unquote secure
-- P OS or SSL, right.
-- Get those air quotes back up. Yeah, exactly.
Yeah.
Like, let's ignore root certificate stores on a hairbrush. But,
well, in fairness we do root certificate stores now on cables,
like on, you know, those, um,
what you might call it the Apple cables, you know,
because they don't want you plugging
garbage cables
and, and you know, it turns out right, like go, uh, that,
that Google guy that does those USB C cable
reviews as it turns out.
Yeah, there are cables out there that will fry your devices.
So as much as I hate Apple for making me, like, spend
like three or four bucks on like
cables that are, you know, rated to whatever specification on the flip side, I,
I get it because, you know,
Apple doesn't want to have to deal with returns because
somebody bought a 50 cent cable because the reality too is
I don't think the Attackers are going to be doing man
in the middle between say a device and its mothership.
Now, what will happen though,
expired domains? Right? Uh There was actually uh
I want to say
-- that a
-- router
one of the
and it had like a it had a, a URL for set up,
still not clear on how you go to a random URL to set up your local router but whatever.
Um
And yeah, Benoy
lapsed. Oops.
Uh so if you know, a bad guy had registered it and like done a site,
scrape of the other site, I mean,
yeah, you know,
uh they could have harvested all these routers essentially taken control of them.
And, and so this is part of the problem and I think we,
we like to disregard
man in the middle attacks right now
just because let's face it man in the middle is really hard to do today.
But
as more and more of these devices start doing more and more things,
it it may become more plausible
because let's face it if you can take
over someone's wi fi hairbrush and start spamming,
you know, the internal network and pretending you're the router now and,
and all the other devices start going through.
Now, we have a plausible man in the middle scenario. So I think
today it's impractical, but I,
I suspect it could become a significant threat in the future
depending upon how this all evolves.
Well, we've already had a case where it happened with, um, of all things,
Heinz ketchup.
They had a QR code on their bottles going to some contest or recipe or, you know,
some site like that.
We'll have it in the show notes,
uh the domain laps.
So some porn spammer bought it and, you know, Voila,
you got little kids pointing their parents' phones at a bottle of ketchup.
And
yeah, anyways,
so I, I personally have actually, uh,
there's a, there's a project called CWE the Common Weakness Enumeration database,
I want to say.
And so the idea is to catalog all the vulnerability types that we have like buffer,
overflow, buffer, underflow, buffer,
overread all these things and how they're different and have examples and you know,
information about them
and I've, um, they're revamping it and looking at some new ones and,
and one of the ones I proposed actually was
the domain name expired lapsed or was otherwise
let go. Right. And that's a problem now, right?
Like these routers had like printed on them,
go to www.something.com to like configure your router.
You, you can't update that short of like sending stickers out to people,
you know, like a QR code on ketchup. You can't
update it like short of pulling the product off shelves or something.
And so this whole domain name thing drives me nuts because it's, you know,
it's not hard to, like, not let domain names lap.
-- No, no, no,
-- no, you,
it's very hard because the problem is in any moderately sized organization,
there's probably a group
that buys domain names and
they do it for a reason because they don't want every employee,
you know, yanking out the credit card and all of a sudden the company has, you know,
12,000 domains.
And so there's probably some process in place.
And the problem is that the the organization that printed the QR
codes didn't properly communicate with the
organization that purchased the domain,
right?
I totally see how this can happen.
I think, you know,
ideally they should be like using like a domain
shortener dot whatever their top level domain is,
you know, point to that because they'll always control that.
But yeah, like you have these yahoos go out and like go out and buy
whatever domain for whatever thing. But
anyway, so
I think man in the middle, here's the thing.
The thing to remember about man in the middle is
for a target attack, it makes sense, but for a mass attack,
it's a total pain in the butt
unless
you can redirect a whole bunch of people to you
right by, for example,
grabbing an expired domain or uh what's happened in the past is people have grabbed
um there were all those hacks taking place with people grabbing unused IP space,
remember?
And so essentially like, ok, so the way the internet works, uh, well,
one of the ways it works,
you have IP addresses, right?
And there's these big blocks and some of them belong to organizations that,
for example, have gone bankrupt and just ceased to exist.
And these people then impersonate these organizations and say, oh, I, I am old
company.com or whatever.
Uh We haven't talked to you in a long time, but we're totally fine.
And by the way, could you please,
you know, transfer ownership of these IP addresses over to
Bob at evil.com or whatever.
Um You know, and then they can potentially redirect a whole bunch of traffic that is,
you know, still pointing there or whatever.
Um So I think this domain name thing is going to become a big problem.
Just don't like the man in the middle thing works best.
I think this is why state level Attackers use it, right?
Is because they can do it up like the ISP level, right?
They can go to the local National ISP and be like
redirect www.facebook.com to like our site or else?
Sure.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
The thing I'm kind of wondering is what other
ways than say domain name expires and stuff?
Are people going to use to redirect these massive blocks of traffic? And
actually this leads to
another topic
uh related that was in the uh the show notes today.
So yeah, there's the, the showdown NTP abuse where they stole a bunch of,
I shouldn't say they stole. It's this one's complicated. Really, isn't it?
So there's this idea of these pools of servers, right?
So there's like a pool of NTP servers for
-- um
-- Well, there's np.org which is
kind of the special pool because some, I mean,
some organizations like Microsoft runs their own NTP POOL.
They don't trust the public NTP servers for the reasons we're going to get to in just
a
moment.
So yeah, there's these public pools, for example,
for various operating systems like Debian Linux or Fedora Linux or whatever.
Well, they all basically use the same pool. Now it's just NTP pool.ntp.org.
I mean, it used to be, there were separate pools for various like distributions and,
and operating systems, but these days it's pretty much all the same.
Yeah.
Um they, they still have that layer of abstraction in, in case one of them goes crazy.
But anyways
so long story short, there's NTP servers that people run
and these are nice people
and they can, if they're super nice, say, hey,
I would like to be part of this NTP pool and
provide my services for free online because I'm just so nice,
right? And you know, it's, it's a wonderful public service.
A lot of people do these things. Um
So Showen
which is a database of devices on the internet
essentially with I PV version four.
It's very simple. You have two to the 32 addresses. It's about 4 billion addresses
with a modern scanning engine like Z
map
or uh mass scan.
You can basically scan the entire internet for say port 80 or port 443 or
-- whatever in like 10 to 15 minutes.
-- It's ridiculous now.
Yeah, it's
because you can like rent an Amazon web server or something with
so much bandwidth that you can just do this in 1015 minutes.
And
I remember when those dudes in the nineties did this like for the first time and they,
they sold a map.
I
I bought the poster.
I had it hanging on my wall for a long time and it was like,
it was crazy to think about someone scanning the whole internet, right?
And
it took them like weeks
and yeah, now it's 10 to,
but with I PV version six, you have two to the 128th addresses, which is like,
what is that?
More particles than in the whole
everything. A lot of addresses.
I think someone once told me that you could
give every six inch square on the planet Earth
-- its own IP address with I PV six.
-- I think it was a lot more than that.
It might be.
But uh regardless. So with I PV version six, you just can't
scan everything
yet.
Yeah,
give it time. That's true.
So here's the question.
How do you get a list of I PV six addresses that you can then scan and tell people like,
hey there this router or there's this port open or whatever.
Well, if I was a smart guy,
I would think about maybe running some sort of
service that many of these devices would connect to periodically
and maybe query some sort of information such as accurate time.
Yeah,
and NDP is a perfect example of this because
it's automatic. It is the one service that most operating systems.
Well, most devices let's face it like, like anything that connects to the internet,
the vast majority of it will query pool.ntp.org, right?
Like routers, like hairbrushes, whatever toasters TV. S they're all gonna use it.
And so what happens is if you end up using the showdown NTP server,
you get scanned by them like a few seconds or a few minutes later,
right? And you know, just a port scan.
And so what's really fascinating to me is about
it was last year somebody pointed this out
and nothing happened as far as I know
what is going to happen. I mean,
are they
doing the
pool?
-- Did they? I don't know
-- they didn't. That's what I mean, nothing happened.
They
do, they know which ones are showdown servers.
So they were using a showdown dot IO like the
actual NTP server they were hosting had their showdown dot IO
-- domain name attached to it.
-- So they weren't really, I mean,
they weren't being sneaky. Right.
They were, they were basically not pretending they weren't themselves.
Yeah. And then you would get scanned by Rock dot Scan six dot Show
dot IO.
-- I,
-- well, let's face it as well is
you can't hide behind
I PV six and pretend that you're safe because
while it's not practical to scan it today,
it's gonna be practical to scan it someday.
The reality is if your, if your device is online,
it's somebody's going to poke it at some point
and then they're gonna scan it.
And, you know,
if you have like a remote administrative service open with
no password uh or like a password of 1234.
-- Yeah, you're probably gonna have a bad time,
-- right?
And that's kind of the lesson, right?
Is that I PV six doesn't give us any added security.
I mean,
it does make showdown's life harder as they try to catalog the entire internet.
But fundamentally, if you think you're more secure because of I PV six,
you are going to have a bad time.
In theory. Actually, I PV six makes she's
life a lot easier
because end points are connected directly to the internet.
One of the dirty little secrets is with I PV four network address translation
-- NT has become a fact of life
-- because
you should have a firewall man.
I mean, like my router firewalls, my I PV six gift stuff correctly,
which I was very certain to test
because I know it can go horribly wrong.
Stupid question. What happens when you have an I PV six device, like a light bulb that
can't be firewalled without breaking.
What do you mean it can't be fired with it?
For the sake of argument.
You can't firewall it, say for incoming connections because of some
stupid way they wrote the software,
don't use it.
Yeah.
Well,
and that's going to work for your normal people buying this stuff
-- from
-- Lowe's normal people can enable incoming traffic on their fire.
-- Well, they're not going to want it to,
-- right?
But that's, that's my point. Basically
a long term I PV 61 of the,
one of the goals of I PV six is to encourage end to end connectivity without, you know,
network address translation,
right?
And that ultimately will make sure everything is online,
including your hairbrush, your your blue.
You know,
that's what got me was these light bulbs
at Lowe's were Bluetooth enabled with mesh networking,
not Wi Fi.
-- So Bluetooth, which
-- Bluetooth mesh or one of the other
-- IOT style network
-- specifically said Bluetooth mesh.
I
wonder if that's a thing.
Well, stupid thing.
If I have to build Bluetooth into a light bulb anyways to talk to your phone,
why not just do the mesh networking over Bluetooth?
I don't
know
enough about this to say if it's a practical thing to do.
Well,
Bluetooth is a very device to device networking
protocol though it's not like a lot of
these mesh networking protocols are designed for more
of the kind of Wild West style,
just throw data into the air and something else will send it along.
I just checked uh Bluetooth,
Bluetooth
special interest group has a
technology road map for mesh networking, for
faster mesh networking. Sorry.
So they already have mesh networking now. They want it to be faster.
So yeah, that's the thing. Well, and it makes sense, right?
Like why would I want two communication protocols built into a device?
Well, it's two chips as well and two chips cost twice as much as one
and power consumption.
-- Yeah.
-- Yeah, that's true.
And Bluetooth, that's a pretty nice job of low power these days.
-- I'm pleased with
-- it.
Yeah. And it's, you know, 240 ft range.
Yep. Yeah.
Yeah. Nice and far. That's good. That light bulb can see the garage that way.
So,
until it starts arguing with your door knobs.
-- Give it time, man. Give it time. It's the,
-- I am seriously predicting.
Ok. I'm gonna make a prediction for not for 2017 for the next five years.
At
some point
we're going to see some form of therapy
counseling slash network fixing
for mesh networking when like your light
bulbs stop getting along with your doorknob.
-- So
-- like
one of your
depressed,
-- well, there just doesn't want to talk to them.
-- Maybe they called it a name.
Yeah, exactly.
Um, or oh,
or a vendor blacklisted it. Right. Remember. Uh,
-- so actually
-- a
vendor blacklist, a light bulb and we send in a therapist to talk to it about it.
I predict that this will happen and it will probably be
-- itself A I backed with maybe Amazon mechanical Turks to handle the
-- hard case
mechanical Turks. No way. This is, this is all Alexa,
right? Like Alexa,
please go tell the doorknob that everything's ok.
Right. And then, then it can buy a doll house on the way. Right.
Yeah.
But I mean, you know, like if,
if you think that all these like look at the current problems we have with networks,
right?
Like why do people think that's going to be
any different than with the IOT?
It will be
worse because you're gonna have a million devices.
Well, it's not even about the buttons. I mean, buttons are relevant.
It's more the idea of le let's face it.
Most houses or most residences will say probably have what,
10 to 20 devices talking to Wi Fi today.
And if you live in an area that isn't the middle of freaking nowhere,
the 2.4 gigahertz spectrum is unusable. Right?
-- Oh, yeah.
-- No, I had to II I
still have a 2.4 gigahertz network for older devices but
everything
gigahertz
because
I think one of my neighbors
must have a bad microwave or it's just the 2.4 gigahertz spectrum.
Is that saturated for like the surrounding two. No,
it's not. The
microwaves operate in the five gigahertz range. For what do
they,
yeah, they, they're pretty high,
but more importantly is
the 2.4 gigahertz range is just so filled with garbage. Now.
I mean, you got to think everything from Bluetooth
to the, the wireless phones, like, like the,
the non
wired telephone I have, right? Like my, my, yeah, deck. That's it.
Uh,
like all this stuff is sitting in the 2.4 gigahertz
range plus the fact that like I can see 20 networks
all around me.
It's crazy. So actually funny enough is there's a hotel
I find myself at more often than not
and
they w whatever setup they have in the hotel for Wi Fi literally every
channel in the 2.4 gigahertz range is in use by one of their networks.
And so, and it's not even like the 1611 type set up.
No, no, every freaking channel has some
things sitting on it and you like, I've got my little Hutu
device that I like to carry with me and, and set up my own little network.
It does not work because there is so much noise.
I
feel like somebody should explain how these wireless networks actually
overlap and work they're using.
Well,
I
have no
idea
if anybody's using anything but 16 and 11
outside of France.
-- But
-- the thing is most of this gear picks its own, uh, uh, network.
I've only ever seen stuff, pick 16 or 11.
I, I
-- bet stuff, picks
-- lots of
dumb stuff
out
there.
I guarantee there's,
I know there's, well, this isn't even that. Right.
This is clearly something was set up to literally pick every single network ID,
every one of them in the wireless channels. And so it's madness.
But, but so here's the point though, right, here's the point is
everything is getting Wi Fi
and the IOT is on fire,
but
it's, it's a madhouse as well, like
nobody's in charge. And so it's just crazy
when you look at everything going on and, and
anyone can basically do whatever they want.
The only ray of hope I can think of is directional antennas. However, having
-- said that that's
-- not a ray of hope,
it's literally a ray, we just can't see it.
But
no,
I was just gonna say that doesn't work with a lot of
the IOT because a lot of the IOT moves like a hairbrush.
Right. Right.
Like, like traditional network devices tend to be like physically static, right?
Like they sit on your desk or it's a Wi
Fi access point or it's, you know, whatever, right?
Your TV, your apple TV, that like is staple to the wall.
But like that's the thing, right?
A lot of the IOT is about, you know,
these are things that are moving around or like sitting in your pocket or like your,
uh, what you might call it, your Fitbit thing, you know, monitoring your
steps and your, how many, uh, what
call it, how many stairs you climb up and down.
Yeah.
And so, you know, here's like, yeah, I mean,
those things are just gonna spam all over the place and, and that even,
well,
that assumes that you even have space to put a proper antenna on that poor thing.
Right.
Um,
I kind of really want to take one of
those hairbrushes apart and see what's inside of it,
-- you know? No, seriously. Right. Like is it like a chip? Is it a board? Is
-- it,
it's not a board, it's probably a battery in, in a sock?
I mean,
that's what it's gonna be and I imagine it probably has minimal storage space.
Oh uh
sock for those of you that didn't capture it. Si think he meant system on a chip.
Not natural,
-- not an act battery in a sock.
-- Uh That would work too. You could hit someone with it.
That was actually my first mental image.
Uh Yeah, that, that was not mine.
I mean, five gigahertz is the future, I guess.
-- And then
-- followed by it doesn't matter because five gigahertz is
gonna get full of crap too in the near future.
I mean, that's just the reality of it doesn't matter where we put this stuff,
it's gonna, there's,
there's just gonna be so much junk using Wi Fi that Wi Fi is going to become unusable.
The good news is we're talking
about 60 gigahertz spectrum long term
-- and that will give us enough bandwidth and spectrum
-- to until we use it all.
-- Well,
-- yeah, fair enough like
um I've heard people talk about what's called like smart dust.
So the the idea being that you literally get a
computer and sensor package and battery package and solar panel package
so small that it fits into like a speck of uh uh like a speck of sand essentially.
And then you can do things like just like mix it into concrete and like
certain percentage of them will be on the top of the concrete and they can
report how worn down that piece of concrete is.
So like for a road or a sidewalk, right? Like
the idea being that these computers and sensors and wi fi networks
and solar panels and everything get so cheap that we basically,
you know, spend like, I don't know, like a buck a kilogram on them, right?
And just have millions of them
and put them in everything or whatever, you know,
like put them in your food and they take
pictures of your intestines as they roll through whatever
-- sounds fantastic.
-- It's already happened. You can buy
a
that's a camera and it will,
it takes pictures of your intestines every like 10 seconds of
I've
heard of these
in the medical community. But can I as a consumer acquire one of these.
What does Amazon say?
Amazon
-- says yes,
-- Alexa
buy me a pill to watch my poop.
-- It's called a
-- pill cam colon procedure.
-- A
-- pill
cam colon procedure.
You can go buy one.
I love it.
I love it. We live in the future, Kurt. This is why everything should have Wi Fi
right here.
It comes with a double camera. I just looked it up. That's great.
So you can see where it's going and where it's been.
-- Well, that makes sense.
-- Of course it does, does it have Wi Fi though?
If it doesn't have Wi
Fi, I'm not
interested,
you know why it doesn't have Wi
Fi power source, but as soon as it can consume.
That's
-- true.
-- And,
and here's the beauty,
there are medical devices that can consume glucose as their energy source already.
But then it's going to become self aware and it's going to control me. Right.
It's, I've seen enough
the difference.
I, it would probably be a better life.
I don't have to make decisions anymore. Everything would be great.
Well, you would just, it would be like that. Uh oh, what is that thing in, in cat
feces, the toxoplasmosis, whatever
that essentially makes us think that we're like happy and joyful.
It's just, we're like being
-- turned
-- you into a crazy cat person.
Well, basically, yeah, I mean,
to be
-- what you are right. You've got what, like four cats or something
-- I have, I have No,
no cats.
Yeah. No.
Um, no, my, uh,
one of my cats went to a friend's place and then my other
cat went to my parents where she hangs out with my sister's cat.
-- I see. I see. So you had a zero can household?
-- Yeah, I have no pets. No cats. No carpets.
-- Nothing. It's quite nice. It's very dust and hair
-- free.
Uh, yeah, that's the worst part of on animals is all the hair,
which I guess soon we'll just have IOT vacuum
cleaners that will take care of that for us,
which I guess you can kind of get, you've got the roombas or the I
robots or whatever the heck they're called.
-- There
-- are, I have seen a video of a cat being vacuumed and the cat did enjoy it.
I, the cat I used to own did not enjoy that.
-- So
-- you vacuumed your cat.
I tried to vacuum the cat. It didn't work. It was a very hairy cat
and, and my dog for the record also didn't wanna be vacuumed.
You've just reminded me of a very important
point and something we forget about a lot,
especially when we start talking about putting wifi on every device on the planet
is
even if this stuff has it. What is the actual threat? Like, what's the
threat surface or? I'm sorry, what is the attack surface
of this device and of the
environment it exists in
and for like a hairbrush,
it's probably pretty low and I doubt there's
really anything serious that can go wrong.
But
yeah, whatever I
still
maintain
vs
has no monetary value.
The people
they're gonna find something else to do with, with all this crap. But
ok, so let's,
and, and
Botnet
is,
is the thing, right?
Botnets are bad. Ok,
I get that. But most of this stuff is going to be behind a firewall. And so a Botnet is
a much lower problem on the scale of what could go wrong.
Right.
Largely it's,
it's for me, what my concern is, is somebody,
you know, if you told me about ransomware 10 years ago, I would have laughed,
but now it's like, oh
two years ago, we laughed
that
funny anymore.
Yeah.
And, and my concern is, you know, yeah, like you said in the last show,
somebody's going to figure out some new business model involving
my devices that I'm not going to be happy about.
Yes. Which I guess so. Here's where I'm going to also bring up that the FTC actually
just announced a prize for securing the consumer IOT.
And I think you get like 20 grand
if you submit an idea to them and they like it and they
decide it's the winner for securing all these devices in a home.
And
it, it's a really interesting
and I think correct way to think about this problem
because instead of telling the device makers, you have to do it right.
Which they never will.
They're saying,
how can we add a device to the network or how can we do something
on the network in the environment to make things better?
Which I think is completely the correct way to look at this.
It's interesting actually the, uh, I just checked it's
for automatic iot patching.
But what does that mean? Right. I mean, you are
patch devices, right? You aren't gonna patch them. That's,
that's no secret.
The prize plot is up to $25,000 with 3000 available for each honorable mention,
blah, blah, blah.
But
they just talk about
minimal.
Yeah, will help, quote,
help protect consumers from security vulnerabilities caused by out of date.
So
that doesn't,
that doesn't mean patching, right? That, that doesn't mean a patch.
See, here's my thought, here's my simplest thought
man in the middle device because people who don't patch
their software generally don't do uh SSL or TLS correctly.
Well,
haven't you read any of the news about the antivirus
man in the middle fiascos that have been going on?
Like anyone who man in the middle stuff,
he
doesn't do it correctly either.
Yeah. Well, ok, so for those of you maybe not familiar with
so many networks,
uh and uh especially on financial uh organizations generally speaking, they
want to look at all the network traffic, including encrypted network traffic.
Um So what they do is they have hardware devices running software
that will essentially act as a man in the middle attacker.
And the way they do this simply is they install their own custom root certificate
on the end points like your phone, your desktop, whatever.
So that, you know, when you go to say walmart.com,
the man in the middle device actually talks to walmart.com securely
and then talks to you and pretends to be walmart.com.
The problem being that's exactly what state level Attackers do
and that's exactly what a lot of places like Google,
Facebook and those guys are exactly trying to prevent,
right.
So they do things like certificate pinning and like a variety of other
mes methods to
prevent these attacks from working. Now,
the majority of browsers,
if you have a custom root certificate installed will
allow that to override things like certificate pinning.
I suspect that may change long term because
the reality is the state level Attackers,
you know, they're getting better, they're buying better gear,
they're buying better software.
My personal take on this is if your security posture relies on
behaving in the same way as like a state level attacker,
chances are that's not gonna work long term because it's
going to be something that people block or otherwise well,
essentially secure
so that you're,
it no longer works,
right? And so with these like TLS and SS SSL inspections,
yeah, with an out of date device obviously that will probably work because you know,
these things are not super super secure,
but anything that is reasonably up to date or, you know,
you buy in five years and rightly so probably
freak out when it sees the network doing that.
Now. You know, what exactly can an IOT device do to freak out?
Well, actually that's a good question. Right.
Unless you register an email address with it,
I would,
I would bet you that the vast majority of
these devices aren't going to do proper certificate checking.
And so you can probably man in the middle of them quite easily.
But I still think that fundamentally, I
if you're a man in the middling someone,
you're probably at best making a lateral moves for security,
you aren't making it better and you're probably making it worse,
right? I mean, that's just the reality of that situation.
You're ticking off a check box
that says, yeah, we can see all network traffic on our network
in some cases. That's exactly what it is.
And I'm also not going to say that compliant security is a bad thing. It has its place.
I, I wrote a blog post about this a while back where
if you think about security as no security, compliance,
security and real security,
real security is really expensive and hard to justify compliant security is
kind of in the middle where some of it makes sense.
Some of it doesn't.
But if you don't do it, you don't get to exist in the business world.
And so people are willing to do compliance security
is what we need to do is do a better job of making sure that the compliant
security that is mandated is meaningful and works as
opposed to check the box because we said so
I agree.
And I think part of the problem there though is,
is no matter what set of rules you come up for with compliance, security
people will,
there's always some group of people or companies that will think
it's cheaper to game the system than to do it properly.
But that's ok. That means they've made that risk decision
and if they want to game it, that's fine.
But it's on behalf of somebody else, potentially like me,
the poor schmuck buying their product.
Maybe. I mean,
well, that's the case with IOT. Right. That's the problem with IOT is
I'm buying stuff.
It's not like I can update this or,
-- you know,
-- we, we know the IOT gear is garbage. Right. We just know it is.
And so
right now I think that's kind of acceptable and in fact, I don't even know
anybody regardless of technical skill level who thinks
any of this IOT stuff is secure.
They're buying, they know it's crap but they think it's neat.
So they hook it up to their network.
Well, I, I'm actually gonna go in further and this might offend you,
but I'm ok with this stuff being garbage
because quite frankly, it, it's gonna last for five or 10 years max part of it is,
I might actually get a real benefit from it.
For example, like my nest smoke alarms or my, uh,
my, my bathroom scale that, like, essentially logs my weight and body fat.
And then I have like a nice,
like, jiggly. Exactly.
Yeah, it shows me this nice wiggly line that's trending up or down
and more to the point, like,
even if it does join Adidas
Botnet or something, it's such a low cost to me.
But quite frankly, I don't really care and that's horrible. And I hate that
we, well,
we discussed this a couple episodes ago where we
discussed the the kill switch in IOT devices,
right?
But so here's the deal is you're not wrong
in the things you say.
But there's also
we need incentives for people in manufacturers
to do the right thing because I'll use
le let's pick on public health, right? Where
you can't sell expired food,
you know, you can't sell known bad food
is a great example here where
there are certain public health rules that must be followed
and if you don't, you're going to get in trouble. And as a consumer,
you,
you care enough because let's face it, man.
Would you buy expired fish that looked rotten
personally? Right?
Nobody would. Let's face it. Right.
There's
there,
there's levels to this because one of one of my favorite pastimes actually is,
is my wife is horrified by this.
But
when I find something in the fridge that's like, well past its its use by date,
like I'm gonna eat some of that and see what
happens and I never get sick for what it's worth.
Uh I never do
the bread that we buy in North America.
-- At least that lasts like what, two weeks out on the shelf
-- more than that man.
So I actually,
some time back I wanted to teach my kids about mold.
And I said here,
let's just put a piece of bread in this plastic baggie and put it on the window sill
and after like a month, it was still a piece of bread.
And I'm like, sorry guys store bread. Let's eat this, you know.
Yeah, there's actually an Australian chain of bakeries here called Cobb's Bread.
And they have to put stickers on their thing and they, they tell you
like, you have to eat this bread within 2 to 3 days or it will go bad.
And I'm like, well, duh, of course it will. And she's like,
I'm like, wait, do you do people not know this?
And she's like, yeah, no, people don't. They come back and complain.
I, yeah, I didn't realize how long it would last. And, and for what it's worth.
I love making bread. It's one of my favorite things to do.
So I'm, I'm quite familiar with how real bread works and
how long it doesn't last,
which is also crazy when you think about it because, I mean, back in the day
that's why people made bread every day because you had to make it every day.
And also if you had food, you would eat it because,
like, what else would you do with food? Right.
I don't know. You let it go bad and throw it away.
That's what, that's what we're gonna do with it.
Yeah. Well, and that kind of leads us back to the IOT, right?
If we're at that stage of the IOT where let's make stuff
and throw it away.
-- Like, let's see if it works or doesn't work, but we
-- don't throw it away.
I mean,
think about how many tablets are out there that
are running versions of android that are so old.
It hurts to think about.
I remember this guy who put his son five workstation online
and
let it get attacked.
He actually advertised it and like,
nobody knew what to do with it because it was so old.
All
I don't know if OK, now this is going back a ways.
-- You're going to remember this root
-- shell.
Oh man, root
shell. I remember that.
How
long ago did that die?
-- Is
-- it dead? I don't
-- know,
-- dude, root shell went away. Like
uh because I used to use it like on a weekly basis.
Shell technologies.
No, it's, that's not them.
Uh It's also two R's.
Um But Roel
D
used to be.
-- Yeah,
-- don't click that you can
read.
I can't.
Yeah.
So, um rel.org, I think it was.org or maybe.net.
It was like, it was essentially this collection, a
curated collection. No less of exploits. Kind of like Packet Storm.
-- It was a
-- very nice
list. Oh, it was very well done and you know, it went away.
And so here's the reality, right? If you want to find an exploit for, say
they say, oh, hey, here's Windows 95 21 22 years old now.
Good luck finding that, right? Like Google hopefully can find it. But,
you know, fundamentally, I mean,
there used to be so many exploits running around for these things,
but they've all disappeared off the internet, you know,
-- due to Bit Rod or
-- whatever they might be on archive.org.
Uh
Well, well, but, ok, so here's the thing is
you are correct
about things like root shell from back in the day.
And in fact, the root shell website is in archive.org,
but I don't think the exploits are.
But whatever,
here's the thing though is
we didn't have git back then. We didn't have github
back then. We didn't have metas
back then.
Thanks to something like
metas, you're going to be able to exploit basically anything produced
in the last 10 years well into the
future because those exploits will never go anywhere.
And even if they take them out of the G
repo,
there's still the history.
So I guess the solution then is to use Windows 95 for all of our IOT devices.
-- With
-- that is totally the solution.
Yes.
-- Yes. That's right.
-- I
-- think we fixed it.
-- You heard it here, folks? Windows 95.
I want the 25 grand
or whatever the prize is.
Yeah, you tell that to the F I want you to submit this to the FTC.
And I want to see what happens.
I suspect they hit the uh the delete key.
I would hope so.
It's yes.
Anyway,
but I guess at the same time. All right.
So it,
this is just such a weird problem and we don't
have a very good analogy for any of this yet.
But
it, it almost reminds me as well of
if I look at Roku,
I'm gonna pick on these guys. Well, I'm not gonna pick on
Roku
is a company that makes like one of those little boxes you plug
into your TV and you can watch like Netflix or Amazon or whatever.
-- Really? That's a shame. I really like
-- my Roku.
-- I, now that I think about it, I've heard about them, but never.
-- So
here's the deal is the TV.
I have actually, I bought a TV with Roku in it because I like Roku so much.
That was actually one of the things I was looking for
and I have a Roku that is
freaking ancient.
I mean, I've had it for, I bet more than five years and it still gets software updates,
I mean.
Right. So
that,
yeah, seriously.
-- Are they just
-- backwards compatible? Hardware wise?
I have no idea what they do or something.
I'm not. Well, in part of it too though, like, let's, so let's face it, it, it plays
movies. Right. And TV, it doesn't need to be some crazy complex.
Let's keep it updated to the cutting edge. I mean, let's face it too.
Like my chromecast is, I bought one of the first generation chromecast.
I still get updates to that.
-- You know,
-- I thought
what about a device or a series of devices that get software updates.
But for example, the older devices get, you know,
limited updates with maybe only core functions.
Here's the,
here's the deal,
ignoring this, ignoring that idea because you're not wrong, but
there are always going to be companies that make good stuff and
take care of it and there's gonna be companies that it,
it's just garbage.
And that's not unlike today when you buy basically any product
because
literally any product on the market,
there are good ones and there are garbage ones and I know when I buy the garbage one,
that thing's gonna fall apart in like two months.
But I'm making the decision that I would rather spend $5 on this
piece of crap instead of $20 on something that I'm gonna die with.
You know.
-- Well,
-- and part of the challenge though, especially with the IOT is well, twofold,
number one, there's a lot of new players in the market that have no track record.
And for all we know they're the next Apple or
Google or they're out of business in two months.
And the second problem I have is that even assuming that exists,
where do I find that information?
Like consumer reports,
thankfully did, finally did a review of the Macbook and
won't endorse them.
Which? Ok. Good, good to know because apparently the battery,
but here's the most fascinating thing about that.
Nobody's set up to replicate the results.
Nobody's been able to authoritatively replicate the results and say
they're full of bunk and they're wrong or? Wow. No, they're completely correct.
This is crazy
because apparently the deal with the Macbook pros and the consumer reports test
is they, they essentially open the Macbook
and they have this like test suite that like loads web pages
and does a bunch of other stuff and they like measure when
the battery dies
and they were getting results of like eight hours and
two hours and then like six hours and yeah,
like no, read the, put it in the show notes because it's completely insane.
It literally makes no sense.
And like I said, the challenge is, and this is even a simple test of like,
go buy a Macbook and like stick some software on it and then let it
like, run,
you know, like and plug it in to recharge it and then let it run
and nobody can replicate this.
What do you
mean?
What do you mean? Nobody can replicate it like they just haven't been
able to
or
when people try this, what do they get?
-- Well,
-- they don't have the software to do it or whatever.
-- I don't
-- know, write your own damn software.
Um And, and for what it's worth, if anybody wants to send me a Macbook,
I will gladly replicate this test.
-- I have no doubt,
-- but essentially nobody's able to replicate these results
in a way that either says yes, this is confirmed true or
no,
they're like full of bunk because when we did it like battery life was like 15 hours,
14.9 15.1.
You know what I mean? Like or whatever, right?
My fear with IOT is like, how do I, you know, for example,
I find some combination of like my light bulbs won't talk
to my other light bulbs won't talk to my chair.
That's when you bring in your IOT counselor
and they sit down with the devices and they, they share,
I think the problem is over sharing.
-- Maybe,
-- maybe it is, maybe it is, maybe,
maybe we all have to share our feelings a little less.
Uh
IOT we keep talking about IOT.
We're going to have to rename this like the IOT Security podcast. At some point.
I think
here's the dirty truth by number of devices. IOT is the future
-- it is
-- the
insects
of the,
I think it's the present. Kurt. I mean,
look
for all the tablets and the phones and the routers and the TV.
S and just, it's craziness.
This is true. My kids have four devices currently.
If I think about my house,
I bet I've got 20 plus devices on my network
right now and maybe four of them are computers.
Maybe.
No, this is true. I have two
desktops. Air quotes, Mac minis and a, and a two laptops, three laptops. So, five
traditional computers and everything else is phone tablet
or like my bathroom scale or
-- Lord
-- knows what else. And
-- game consoles and TV.
-- S
even
thought
-- of
-- that.
Yeah. Right. You think about that? I mean,
like my house has three Nintendo Ds
s
they all,
yeah, they've
got like an app store and stuff. You can, you can buy stuff.
Yeah, it's quite nice actually.
-- You think about,
-- you know,
I, I've actually been meaning to buy a Nintendo because
I have fond memories of them as a child.
You know, the Nintendo entertainment system class.
You can buy the mini if you can find one
if you do buy two and send one to me because
I can't find one.
Yeah, I think part of the solution will be to have just simply put some, uh,
some people like consumer reports and,
well, no, I, no, let's not even pretend we know what the solution is.
Here's what I think, I think what the F DC is doing. This, this prize,
this is great.
This is what we need to do because it's gonna make people start
thinking about this stuff in strange new ways because these are strange,
new problems
that need strange new solutions.
The old ways don't work.
It's essentially the bug bounty and
the reality is, yeah, we, we were at the point where the experts have,
I don't want to say failed us, but certainly haven't made things awesome.
They, well look, let's face it, man. Is the people who are the experts today
aren't going to be the people who are the experts of tomorrow.
And
right,
we need a new crop of people who look at
this stuff in new and interesting ways because the people,
the, the things we learned and the things we went through,
-- most of that knowledge is becoming worthless and we will talk about
-- it.
They say it's not just worthless, it's actively dangerous. Like the fact that I,
you know, I, I run into people that still think you can have a network perimeter
when like people have, you know, phones, tablets,
-- bathroom scales and like the cloud all mashed together
-- or
the fact that most of your employees have telephones,
you know, VPN into the network that they walk out of the door with every day.
I mean, no, and that's,
that's a whole nother conversation. Obviously. It, it is what it is. Right.
-- The future is now that I think is the problem,
-- the future is
-- now
-- the future is now.
And
unfortunately, I don't think we're ready for it yet.
It will get there. Right.
And that's, you know, that's part of it too,
I guess is we complain and we lament and we,
hey, people weren't ready for the industrial revolution for the 1st 100 years.
Right.
And,
and people weren't ready for the internet for a
very long time and they still might not be.
But
the
point
is
this will get figured out.
I am confident
and, and if you want to
accuse me of making a prediction, this is it.
I am confident
in humanity's ability
to overcome the obstacles placed in front of it.
That is my eternal optimistic part of me that I never let out.
But I'm going to for this one second here.
-- I
-- would, I would agree and just say it, it, it's, it just may not be pretty,
but it often works
and, and you know that. Right. Exactly. Right.
It, how we get to where we go is messy and crazy and bizarre.
And you look at like
the birth of democracy across the planet, which is potentially in jeopardy now,
but we won't
get it.
That's just it. Right. It, it wasn't clean and nice. It's still not clean and nice.
It will never be clean and nice. And this is
the same thing with us solving these iot problems. It's gonna be messy.
It's gonna be weird. It's gonna be hard
and
anyone who tells you no, or it can't be done or just, you're wasting your time, like,
ignore those people because the world has always been
full of the naysayers and you know what,
so far they've basically all been wrong
and that's just the way it is.
It does remind me of all those end of the world predictions
one day they're gonna be right, you know,
of
the universe.
Absolutely right. Someday I'll be like, you're glad you listen to me. Right.
It, it is what it is. You know,
it,
I'm confident we will figure it out.
And in the meantime, you and I will complain at length
about all of the things wrong with Iot and putting Wi
Fi and everything as we eat our breakfast cereal with our
IOT spoons and the,
and the
anti
tremor spoons
I, I have and they're very cool. Actually. That
to me, I almost cried. That was so amazing. Yeah.
-- Yeah.
-- Well, I mean, so that's a great example of technology doing amazing things.
And
you know what if, if all of the crazy before now hadn't happened,
you couldn't build something like that.
And so
imagine what the future is going to build with.
What we think is crappy wifi hairbrushes today,
right? And, and that's just the way it is.
So, all right, let's, let's, let's take it home, man. I'd say
the,
the crazy list of things we've talked about will be in the
show notes which you can find on open source security podcast.com.
You can hit us up on Twitter. You can use the Hashtag Pound Os S podcast
to let us know what you think or, or leave a message or whatnot.
And if nothing else, I guess happy end of ce S Kurt,
I guess the moral story is go
on spoons,
go along on spoons. That's right. All right, folks. Until next time, take care.