Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in tractor crime.
-- Josh
-- Pressers, whatever, man. It is the 764th day of 2020 one.
Do not panic.
Do not go outside.
Yeah, just continue,
continue hiding under the bed, rocking back and forth and crying. It'll be fine.
Maybe build a fort out of furnace filters.
I, you know, I actually have a lot of furnace filters. Funny, I buy them by the case.
-- Yeah, Costco
-- man, I Costco does not sell the furnace filters.
I need,
I'm lucky they do because they're literally less than half the price at Home Depot.
Anyway. Anyways. Yeah.
So killer tractors and cars essentially the right to repair.
Why the right to repair is clearly going to lead to the 1986 film maximum overdrive.
I don't know what that film is, but we should,
let's before we delve into whatever crazy talking points we have.
We should clarify that.
2021 is actually exciting because in the eu right to repair is,
has been codified into law
and it's kicking in and now companies have to,
there's a handful of things. They did some, a little bit research on this.
Probably not as much as I wish I had. But basically they have to
sell parts
for the stuff they make,
they have to make it actually user serviceable where it says you have to, I,
I think they use a word common tools or I forget what they said, but basically, like,
you can't use some ridiculous screwdriver that only you sell.
And then they also have to have like
manuals available for people to download for the,
well, a choir, we'll say for the products.
Like this is part of me, really excited for this and part of me is mortified.
Well, but on the flip side,
the challenges are with value engineering where you take a product
and shave 10 cents off the manufacturing cost every year,
you end up making certain engineering and design choices
that can really impact
repairability, but conversely can really bring the price of the product down.
So a great example of this is if you want to make something waterproof, guess what?
You, you can't use a lot of screws,
you got to glue the thing together and make it seamless as much as possible.
And, and then you crack the screen when you try to open it.
Yeah,
these manufacturers aren't necessarily evil but to be clear, some of them are evil.
Oh, totally unquestionably. Yes.
And some of them are just dumb and some of them are just, well, meaning schmucks.
My favorite example, being this guy who had an
stroller and, I mean, you know, I had twins so I had the duetto.
That thing is 900 bucks.
Right? Twin strollers are hideously expensive if they're any good.
Yeah.
And the duetto it's like, not side by side,
side by side is garbage because they don't fit through doors.
I won't argue with you. But someday I'll explain to you.
-- there, there are some that do that but they are ridiculously expensive.
-- I know
there is this piece in his stroller that was made out of plastic
and it cracked and it was part of the wheel lock system.
And
when you know, for anybody that's ever had their kidney stroller, those,
those two locks on the back wheels, like
that's not an optional thing to have, right?
You're never going to park your kid on a perfectly flat surface, right?
This ain't Rick and Morty.
So he basically took the crack part out, tried gluing it together,
that's not gonna work.
So he glued it together. 3D, scanned it, printed out a
metal version of it, popped it in off you go.
And I believe he got hit by AD MC A
takedown or whatever because he also published the part.
Oh
Thing of a
jigger
online.
Interesting
in many of these cases. Number one.
How do you even contact the manufacturer to buy that part?
Number two,
unless you have a manual with like an exploded diagram showing all the parts.
How do you like? This is my favorite thing. My parents used to own a 19
75 diesel Mercedes 300 diesel.
And the thing I most loved about the car were two things.
One, the air conditioning and that thing, I mean,
it probably made a hole in the ozone later about a kilometer wide.
But man, you could have kept beef in that car in summer.
And number two,
the Mercedes manual had exploded diagrams of everything like every nut and bolt.
That's epic. And I remember fantasizing always as a kid of taking the car apart,
but I was smart enough to know I couldn't put it back together.
That's a grounding right there.
-- Yeah,
-- that's probably going to get yelled at.
So how do you even know what part to ask for?
Let's reframe this all in the context of security because
an open source for that matter. So
we could go on and on and on about parts.
And I think that's something easy to understand as humans.
-- This leads to the second thing. Software is now apart.
-- We're getting to that.
So that makes it easy for us to understand as humans because we like physical things,
we can touch physical things, we feel like we can fix physical things,
but physical things basically are all just computers now.
And so the thing I keep thinking of in my brain
with bright for repair is how does software fit into this?
Because I've yet to see anyone discussing software
in the context of right to repair.
But I feel like in many cases,
the software is probably just as or more important than the physical stuff.
Ok. So we're going to stick to right to repair and not right to modify.
So we're going to ignore the whole
like car ECU hacking where you want to get your car to go faster.
So you get like some dodgy ec firmware that
essentially drives your engine faster, like more fuel, more air, whatever.
So let's ignore all that. Let's just stick with right repair.
So perfect example. Yeah,
cars nowadays obviously have a ton of software that runs everything right,
the the entertainment system, the lane assist,
-- they're computers with wheels
-- basically.
And so for example,
what happens if you find some failure scenario
that somehow you're competent enough to actually fix?
I mean, there's like what three people on the planet maybe
that can do this, but let's assume you're one of them.
Well, do you have a right, for example, to get to that source code?
Do you have a right, for example, or what if they're signing keys required? Right.
I mean, I'm pretty sure
that the automakers are going to look at this and pretty soon
start locking down the boot process just like the console makers did
for if nothing else,
maybe for just reliability so that people aren't
breaking their cars and then being like,
oh,
I did nothing at all. Weird to my car and it doesn't start now. So please fix it.
What?
Right. What did you do to your computer? Dad?
Nothing
like? Oh, ok. Nothing. Right.
What happened when it broke? Nothing. I wasn't touching it.
-- I wasn't even in the room.
-- That's right. That's right. Oh, look.
Anyway, I mean, this is a really interesting topic because
I think there's many angles, right.
There's the right to repair aspect, which is if I have an item,
I should be able to fix it or someone else should be able to fix it today.
That's very difficult now now.
But then there's the open source aspect which says I want
to buy a device and I want to hack on it
as much as I feel like
-- that from the perspective of tinkering. Not so much. Let's circumvent.
-- Yeah.
So that would be the right to modify.
And that's a very different thing than the right to repair, right.
But it's similar, oh, there's huge Venn diagram overlap here. Absolutely.
But from a legal point of view, I feel like from a legal point of view,
the right to repair is much easier to argue than the right to modify.
Well, I agree completely and I think that's easier,
but then there's still the security aspect of so from right to repair,
you can have people modifying things in dangerous ways or just the fact that,
let's say you have a computer that's 10 years
old and security updates stopped three years ago.
-- I mean, that's
-- dangerous.
Or you have a computer that's 10 years old and the hardware's
starting to flake out and you want to replace it with something.
Well, I mean, that happens anyway,
the point is so talking about right to repair in the context of physical goods.
Like if it's a washing machine, that's great.
-- But if it's a washing machine that they all
-- have software and control circuit book,
I actually had a friend who uh he was a Y2K consultant slash security consultant.
So pretty technical guy and uh one of the buttons on
his stove stopped working and it was like an important button.
It was like the thing to turn the oven on or whatever, right?
So it's not a button you can live without like resetting the clock. And basically
they had to, it was like a $500 repair
because you can't fix the button. You have to replace
the entire circuit board under the front of the stove.
Yeah, I, I had that, I bought a washing machine years ago and the power button
was like, it was set back too far and when you pushed it,
it cracked the like the front panel,
that little membrane
and it was brand new. So I called the manufacturer.
I'm like, hey, this happened, you know,
why don't you send someone out to fix it and the guy came out and, yeah,
he basically just took off the front panel, completely removed the computer.
Put a, like the computer board, put a brand new computer board in
and I was like,
-- this is bananas for one freaking button
-- from a cost perspective of fixing it.
That's way cheaper than having him de
solder the button and solder a new button on it.
-- Well,
-- I just thought they'd like, reseat the board or something, but no,
like he just literally removed the whole thing and put a whole brand new one in.
-- But
-- if he tries to fix it, then it may or may not work.
Whereas if I just take the module out and put a new module in, right?
Like look at the military and tanks. Perfect example, tanks. Now
they don't have an engine,
they have a power module that typically attaches with about 2 to 4 bolts or more.
And you literally just undo a bunch of bolts
and lift the thing out with a crane,
throw it away and put in a new one if it
gets damaged because you don't have time to fix it,
you need that tank to work now.
And so this is part of that whole value.
Engineering isn't just about, you know, making the product cheap.
So we make more money.
But it's about, for example, how do we make, if,
if the product does fail and needs to
be repaired because people expect their white goods,
you know, they appliances to be repaired.
Not, oh, you know, my fridge made a funny noise.
So time to throw it out and get a new one, you know, $2000 later.
And so this idea of modularity of just take the whole module out,
don't even try to fix it and just swap in a new one.
It's faster and it's more effective in the field repair.
I mean, probably in the big picture for these companies,
but we're talking about right to repair, which isn't big companies.
This is people like you and me and spending $500
replacing a computer versus 52 cents on a switch.
-- It is a very different story too
-- bad.
For example, car manufacturers no longer make engine blocks out of like steel.
They use some pretty exotic alloys and those engine blocks are not cheap.
So your engine block cracks because you do. God knows what?
Well, I'm sorry, but that new engine block is not going to be cheap.
Well, neither is the control panel in your stove.
Here's where your discussion,
I think starts falling apart a little bit
is the idea of this is manufacturers will supply
manuals that explain
in what's going on. They'll have, obviously there will be certain parts.
They sell certain parts.
They don't like, I don't think they're going to sell like a switch.
For example, you'd s
onto a board, but they'd probably sell the board but at the same time,
if I had a manual with the parts,
I would know like this is the switch I need to replace on this board.
You know what I mean?
You could send it to Luis Rossman who would, you know,
remove the surface mount components and put on new ones.
Sure. This is, I think an interesting thing to think about because from the
concept of being a company,
what you need to do is very different from being
a person who's maybe trying to repair their stuff.
-- We're
-- back to the law of large numbers.
I as a company am going to,
I know statistically I'm going to have to repair 10,000
of these washing machines over the next 10 years.
And I'm going to have to have people doing it out
in the field who may or may not be competent.
No one in the field is going to de solder parts who works as a repair person.
It's just not a valuable use of time.
Well, if it's even possible,
that is also very true.
So I, I think this right to repair legislation is a good start.
And I think what fundamentally is going to
have to happen is manufacturers are going to have
to integrate the idea of right to repair
into their business process as to how they design
and build these products.
I mean, I hope so.
I feel like now, now I want to also clarify that this legislation is imperfect,
but it is the first step in a very long,
-- all legislation is imperfect
-- and it always starts terrible.
But I think this is an important change of direction because
I am weary
of just having to throw things away constantly.
So, here's a question,
I'm actually just holding my Swiss army knife and it's
the bottom of the one side is chipped off.
At what point does
the Swiss Army knife? People say, like that knife is more than 20 years old.
-- We don't carry those parts f
-- off.
They haven't, they been using the same parts for like 100 years in those things.
Well, it's, you know, it's not like the, I don't know
right
there. I mean, there are products that are virtually timeless
-- and I think the Swiss Army knives are one of them, for
-- example, you know,
-- are shoe manufacturers going to be expected to carry an inventory of
-- soles.
I don't know what the legislation says about how long they have to carry parts for.
-- I guarantee there is some limits on this, but I don't know what they are.
-- Yeah.
Like what if they only make 500 extras?
And they're like, well, we ran out and we're not making any more.
Does the law have some recourse for that? Where? Ok. You know, now you have to
-- refund them or something.
-- I don't know the answer to that.
But look, I guarantee it's,
if it isn't addressed it will be soon because that's like,
it's idiotic to expect a company to continue making parts for the end of time.
Right. That doesn't make any sense.
And at the same time there is something to be said about a company that's like, oh,
it's been three months, sorry, we're all out.
-- Like, that's obviously ridiculous. Also
-- fast fashion. Right.
There, there are many
glasses of products now
that are meant to only really exist for weeks or months.
Fast fashion being sort of a very extreme example of this.
I'm trying to think of from an electronics point of view.
Are there any electronics that kind of are meant to be very kind of ephemeral almost.
There's loads of electronics that are meant to be ephemeral.
I mean,
so one of my favorite examples and I hate these things are those
you can buy those greeting cards or like birthday cards at the store,
you open them up, they play a little song
and then you throw them away and it's like that is
the most ridiculous waste of resources anyone has ever created.
I think reading cards in general. But
that's a separate discussion.
But regardless that's why people with kids, you just give them a piece of paper,
like free greeting cards, you can't be there.
You know what I mean? There's plenty of products that fall kind of in that category
where it is clearly going to be thrown away almost immediately.
And so purchasing them and using them is an annoying waste of resources.
Yeah, I, like I said, I,
the legislation doesn't exist in a vacuum, right?
The manufacturers have to start thinking about this and taking this into account.
And I think the brutal truth is this will mostly happen and be effective at the
levels of more expensive products that actually have
sort of discrete components and modules and systems.
Like say a car or white goods.
I mean, to a degree my IOT light bulb,
how much would it cost to pay somebody to take IO light bulb apart de
solder, a component, fix it and put the thing back together again.
-- I mean,
-- it would cost way more than the light bulb for sure. Like if you paid someone.
Yeah, absolutely.
I mean, so now here's another thing to think about though is so this is where Europe,
I love Europe when you buy, like we'll say household appliances, Europe is the best.
They do some things really well. So one of my favorite examples is
I was in the market for, you know,
those little like hand mixer things where it's like you fold it in your hand.
It's got the two little spinny things on it.
-- The thing
-- that's called literally a hand mixer.
-- I don't, people don't
-- know.
I, I actually just bought a new one from.
-- Don't know what it's called.
-- You don't
mix.
Ok, great.
So
we are, we use it a lot usually to make,
we'll say difficult things like mashed potatoes is an easy example and,
and we burn them out pretty quick.
And I was looking into this and in Europe they are required to have a multi
year warranty on
-- items like this. And so
-- well, the whole fit for purpose.
Right. Right.
And so I was, I was researching these and basically if I bought like,
the quality of the European mixers versus
the United States mixers is drastically different.
My mom's brown
is older than me.
No, that's it. Like, that's all I have to say.
Like my mom has a hand mixer that was actually made in West Germany,
which doesn't exist anymore.
And that brown will probably be used by my great
-- grandchildren someday to make mashed potatoes
-- in all seriousness.
Part of me is like,
I should put a 220 volt plug in my kitchen so
I can buy European appliances because they will last forever.
It's just, but like this is frustrating to me that, that
this stuff.
And anyway, anyway, we're in a rattle.
And actually, no,
that's a perfect example of because back in
the day making stuff was hard and expensive.
So making it really good, didn't actually cost that much more.
But then we got value engineering and for example, you know,
the machinist out of BC that takes stuff apart and shows
you these motors and these roller skate bearings and stuff,
right.
They the innards of these system of these power drills and,
and I think he actually does do a hand mixer at some point are so cheap.
It's amazing.
-- Yeah, they're full of plastic gears and stuff.
-- It's,
or nylon gears or laser centered anyways.
But the point is you go and you can get a decent hand mixer for 20 bucks. Not 200
so part of what I,
I love and hate about this repairability thing too is we've
driven down the cost of manufacturing so much that we've literally
gotten to the point where Amazon is even doing this now
where they're saying on certain items that are like below,
I think it's like 10 or 15 bucks or are bulky
and expenses to ship when it comes to handling returns,
our response is going to be here's your money back,
you can throw the item away or donate it to charity or we don't care.
We're just, we're not dealing with it. It's just not worth our time.
And this has led to this whole situation
where you have all these disposable products that
it's not that they can't be repaired.
I mean, and actually a lot of them can't be repaired.
It's that they're not worth being repaired. It's just economically makes no sense.
It literally would be cheaper to buy a new one than to fix it.
This is a security podcast and we've gone off into the weeds horribly. I think so.
I want to, I want to reel this back in.
This sounds a lot like the security we have versus the security we want.
-- It kind
-- of is actually, I mean, that's,
that's one of the things I wanted to bring up is the
fact that if we think about this in the context of software,
right, how often in software is it not worth fixing a problem?
Or how often in software is it easier to rip something out and replace it?
And how often in software does something just age out? It's like too bad.
It's, it's old.
-- Well,
-- how often in software do people rather than maintaining the old junk,
write something new, lose some backwards compatibility but lose
a lot of technical debt.
Like, well, a perfect example is computer languages, right?
Pearl Pearl was amazing.
And now it's a dead end despite the fact that it keeps lurching along like a zombie,
you know, then Python came along.
Python's doing pretty good.
But now we've got even better stuff like,
well and better is a subjective word here clearly
because people are going to yell at me.
But things like no Js or Rust, you know,
like some of the stuff Microsoft is doing with.
-- Rust is kind of amazing.
-- Rust is really cool. I like rust a lot.
Part of it too is do we want to repair these old things and keep them chugging along?
Like a perfect example being cars,
you don't want to keep cars more than 2030 years
old on the road in general because they pollute so much
compared to a modern car and ignoring all safety systems
and anti lock brakes and airbags and maybe even seatbelts.
My argument as well is going to be from the security angle is old things,
which is old software.
In the case of even a device hooked up to the internet
is going to be dangerous because it isn't going to be,
even if you can update the software.
There are,
let's pretend you can.
But I mean,
like in the silicon there's changes that have made things more secure for
the last 20 plus years and you won't get any of that stuff.
-- It was funny
-- when I was at the hospital, I noticed on my IV pole, like,
because it had so it basically had a battery pack,
a sort of control unit and then a pump unit and they kind of click together,
sit on the pole, you know, so that they can say, you know,
dispense the 500 mL of this over the next 27 minutes at this flow rate, blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah.
Anyways, it had a couple of stickers on it, you know, inventory control and you know,
this, this thing is a battery.
So charge it once in a while
and one was mandatory software upgrade needed. September 2020. 0, interesting.
And I was like, huh, I wonder if that software upgrade happened or not,
-- I was
-- going to say, is that there because they didn't do it, or
now I would also say that anything that says mandatory software update,
I would probably not touch with a very long poll right
now just because of the current state of the medical system.
Oh, yeah. No,
I would be like, we're going to just wait a little while on this.
And II, I don't think it attaches to the internet.
Everything attaches to the internet now. Don't kid yourself.
Well, no, no, no, this, this thing looked old enough that I don't, maybe it didn't.
Yeah. No, I just,
well, and that's the second part of the right to repair is the right to repair.
Assumes that you're actually going to repair it and make it better,
not break it permanently.
-- I mean,
-- well, there's a lot of repairs that don't end very well, we'll say,
but that's on you for attempting it.
I have the number of things I have broken while trying to fix them is probably
larger than the number of things I've actually fixed if I was going to guess.
But I'm ok with that too.
Yeah, I would say, I mean, I actually have had some, like, for example,
my washer started making a horrendous noise and so I kind of opened it
up and there's just this giant concrete block bolted to the top of it.
So when it's spinning really fast, you know, the laundry flies upwards and
the concrete block dampens the
momentum
just tighten the bolts because somehow the bolts had gotten loose. And I,
well, I know how the bolts got loose, probably because I overfilled the darn thing,
repeatedly bolts loosen.
-- Like it's just what happens
-- to bolt.
Well,
-- now I don't overfill my washer and it's not been a problem
-- but
it's going to loosen up someday even if you don't overfill it.
-- And
-- the thing is now, I actually know how to fix it quickly. Right.
So I'll hear that noise,
Wanka, Wanka,
Wanka.
And I'll be like, oh, I gotta go get my socket set, you know, 10 mil,
because everything,
that's something I find so weird is like almost every bolt
is 10 mil except for all the ones that aren't.
Yeah, that's how it works.
-- Although you live in Canada, which is a civilized country, unlike everything
-- is,
-- I say e here,
-- there's, you know,
what's funny is most things are metric now and I get annoyed
when,
well, ok, ignoring building supplies. But
like when I, when I work on some sort of mechanical device,
it's virtually all metric. And I get annoyed when my,
because I always just get the metric sockets and the metric wrenches right away.
And then when they don't work, I'm like, oh, for crying out loud.
Now, I have to go get the stupid.
And the worst part about English units is like, ok, this is a 7/16 wrench.
I need the next highest wrench up. What is that?
I have no idea
-- in my brain. I
-- just keep trying wrenches to one fits. Like, I literally don't know.
32. Si, don't know, whatever.
But like, in metric though the 10 doesn't fit, I'll try the 11, the 11 doesn't fit,
-- I'll try the
-- 12 and eventually you get to like 31 and you're like, what the heck.
Yeah, exactly.
But
-- anyway, anyway,
-- I was just so annoyed to find out that Sae is not imperial.
-- What do you mean? It's not imperial
-- standard?
Automotive engineering is not imperial, half inch Sae is not half inch imperial.
It's slightly different.
Yeah.
Why
-- I don't get that. That's just
-- how it works.
Yeah,
because I just assumed Sae was like the standard for the tools,
not the standard for the sizes.
No standard. Automotive engineering.
Imperial is different than like imperial imperial,
like half inch Sae is basically half inch imperial but not exactly.
Anyway, whatever, whatever, I don't care. Imperial units are terrible
and
I hate them all anyway, whatever, whatever we're talking about two by four.
What are we talking about?
So, back to this, I think,
I think what we've decided upon is that
it's complicated and that essentially the consumers,
the regulators, the manufacturers, heck, even the companies sell
this stuff are going to have to figure a lot out and going
back to your example of buying something that's quality and fit for purpose.
Again,
this is why I'm trying to buy like all my tvs
and stuff from Costco because Costco does a one year.
We don't care. Here's your money. Get out of my face, go shop.
And so basically everything Costco sells, you know, bathtub failure rate.
It's going to fail in the 1st 3090 days or whatever.
-- And I think they even sell an extended warranty.
-- They do.
I buy their extended warranties because my TV S always fail in three years.
Which is that right after the manufacturer's warranty.
But now I have my Costco warranty.
So that's perfect because basically I can buy it
at Costco and one of two things will happen,
one, I will either get a quality product and be happy or two.
I will not get a quality product, but Costco will make me happy, problem solved.
I'm happy.
-- But
-- anyway, anyway,
the whole reason I wanted to talk about this and we really
have not talked about near as much as I'd like is just,
I love repairing things.
But as a security person,
I'm mortified by the thought of having something
connected to the internet for 30 years.
Yeah.
-- And right. I mean, yeah, it's the only answer to that.
-- No. Absolutely.
You know, and I, I just bought New
Globe
Iot light bulbs at Costco last year.
You know,
I bought actually an entire case of them because here's the other thing is I
realized at some 0.1 or two of these bulbs will probably fail and burn out.
What do I replace them with? I have to replace them with the exact same bulb.
-- So I can use the app
-- if you buy a bulb today and you buy a bulb in a year.
Are they going to look the same?
Because if you have a lamp with two light bulbs
in it and one of different than the other.
Well, yeah. Yeah, they might be using totally different set of LEDs
from some other manufacturer that are off by half a percent.
I'm banking on Phillips not having this problem.
And if they do,
I'm going to weep tears of having spent too much money on light bulbs for no reason.
Yeah. But I mean, like, and that's part of the right.
This is, there's just, this is such a crazy topic with all this stuff.
And then the security person in me,
I feel like I'm locked in a cage in my own head screaming, let me
because
I love right to repair and I hate old devices on the internet.
And it's like, I, I don't know what to say.
Even I think part of the problem is even OK, think about this.
An incandescent light bulb is literally about a simple and I don't mean simple,
simple.
I mean simple conceptually because actually making a vacuum in a
glass thing is, is super nontrivial. But conceptually, it's simple. You have a, a
wire
with a filament
that you run electrons through and it glows that. Right.
Like I just explained how ink and doesn't light bulbs work
basically. Now, how do my globe light bulbs work?
They have Wi Fi, they have multicolored Led S
the Magic
-- and an app and they have a software app
-- and they, they run,
they probably run Linux or something too.
I would hope so. The, the difference in complexity is not
one or two or 10 times complexity. The difference in complexity is
throwing a rock at somebody's head
and calling in an airstrike.
Yeah, that's probably fair.
It's literally the degree of difference in complexity.
I don't know that I comprehend it and I
think that's part of the problem is everything.
Got that complicated. Your washer and dryer.
-- Now,
-- my washer and dryer, I specifically bought the,
the Speed Queen washer and dryer,
which are like twice the price of normal washers and dryers.
But they have like, no, I don't think they even have a computer in them.
I think it's all just like analog circuits.
They basically,
the only you can sell them is if there's someone who can repair
them who lives within like a 30 mile radius of the store.
So, like,
I can 100% use this washer and dryer for the rest of my life and just keep repairing it,
which pleases me to death
anyway, here's,
here's a point I want to focus on for kind of the end of this is
you raise a good point that the complexity
has become infinitely greater on virtually all products.
And the reason for this is fundamentally software.
So from the security perspective, do we see the complexity
de we see
due to something like right to repair or do we think it's just going to be a well,
good luck everybody.
And we're going to ignore the software.
The software is also subject to the value engineering and the cutting costs.
And for example,
is it just cheaper to have the software talk to some mothership in the cloud
and have the app talk to a mothership in the cloud rather than trying to build
something that will work locally,
but also somehow magically work remotely without a gateway.
And the answer is, of course not, you just have the mothership in the cloud.
And so
essentially, I suspect the software is subject to market and economic forces that
essentially doom us to crap and things like,
you know,
globe shuts down their servers in the cloud
and my light bulbs don't do anything fancy
other than turn off and on if I turn the power to them off and on?
Right.
Because why would software not be subject to the
same forces of business that the physical stuff is?
Well, I think the right to repair is going to change that conversation though.
Well, for example, how does the right to repair affect servers in the cloud?
That are needed to run this stuff.
I mean, I don't know, to interact with it and use the more advanced functions.
I haven't seen anything in what
read in. Right. To repair that covers this.
I imagine we're going to have to, the legislation's going to have to change, to
accommodate it.
-- Is my guess
-- they have to run the servers or do they have to
give me a copy of the software so I can run the servers?
I mean, that's a really good question. I don't know the answer to that.
And more importantly,
what if there's encryption keys that the light bulb talks to the?
Like, what do you do now?
How do you, you know, it's, this is,
here's how I'm going to end this from the security perspective.
I think our historical response to hard,
like this is to throw our hands in the air
and declare
whatever
everything is terrible. There's nothing we can do.
But like these are good and legitimate questions to be asking
and it's ok that we don't have answers to it.
-- It's, it's,
-- I'm also pretty sure like light bulbs are not some corner case.
Well,
everyone buys light bulbs but not everyone
buys light bulbs with an operating system,
-- but
-- it's becoming quite common.
It is becoming more common anyway. Anyway. All right, we are
at a time. I will let you end this what I will best call a bizarre conversation
almost related to.
Right. Or
there.
I like the idea that they're trying something
new that has good intentions and I suspect
may actually have a good outcome.
Like, I don't,
I don't think there will be some horrible second order effect where we end up,
you know, dooming the world to zombie plague because of this right to repair bill.
I don't think so. I think it is the first step
in a place
that we should be.
I'm also going to point out not just Europe
benefits from this because I like in theory,
yeah,
you could go to Europe and buy some appliances
or whatever and bring them back with you.
Maybe I actually knew a guy whose mother had this shoebox sized
voltage converter because she had a proper like Asian rice cooker.
That
that's it.
You know what I want. I want, I miss the kettle
had when I stayed in London
-- that I will give the British
-- that 200 and 20 volt kettle.
That thing could boil water in a frighteningly short amount of time.
And I, my mom's German. So I'm used to this thing called an Insync
orator, not the grinder, but it's an actual
hot water boiling. Like it keeps about 2 to 4 L of almost boiling hot water.
You turn the tap and it runs it through a little heater. So you get
like I grew up as a kid if I wanted boiling water, I,
-- I literally turned the tap on
-- every now and then I
think about getting one of those,
-- but then I look at how much effort
-- they're not that expensive.
The problem is an expense.
-- It's like getting all the right stuff to hook it up correctly. Dude, it's
-- easy.
-- It's just you put a tap into the cold water line and
-- electrical,
but you need like 220 volts for them, don't you?
Maybe
I should insulated
-- and it just keeps the water hot.
-- Anyway. Anyway, it is time to go.
Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for putting up with us.
If you made it this far, I commend your fortitude.
Go to open
source security podcast.com. Hit up sh
not use the
Pound
Oss podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media. Kurt have a fabulous rest of your day.
-- You too. Stay safe, everybody.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye bye.