Hello and welcome to episode 100 and five
of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
So I don't think we'll ever stop asking this question or answering it
is open source software secure.
Hey,
that would be my answer.
The answer is no,
nothing secure is the right answer. But
we bring it up because in the span of what like three days, there were 22 events
in open source projects
where there was what our, our clinics had.
The Adobe Reader had a like back door installed by,
by some nefarious actor. And then we've got a no Js
problem
with the ES Lint package
that, that installs essentially a credential stealing
Trojan. I don't know.
That makes sense because I was kind of a glance and I was like,
but who cares about a virus on a Linux machine?
I don't get it.
And so that makes more sense. So it's serving the Linux
virus to web clients or
-- sorry, it's erving a virus
-- to
no, no
ES
Lint dash
scope is a tool you run against your projects to,
to give you information about them,
you know, like a lin. Exactly.
And so anyway,
this particular package had
a,
a basically like malicious code put into steal credentials and send them off to pay
-- from
-- your.
Right.
So.
Right. Right. And, and it's,
this is one of those things that
actually
it is, it's fairly clever
and, and here's the thing,
I hate Linus's law for a variety of reasons.
But man, every time this happens in open source, it gets caught in a couple of hours
and it's actually
there's a really simple solution to this
so related topic, DNS. Uh I did a DNS webinar the other day
and one of the guys uh pointed out from a security point of view.
There's almost never a truly legitimate reason that
a user needs access right away to a newly registered domain.
So like, you know, a newly registered domain blah, blah, blah.com comes online.
Nobody absolutely needs access to it for the first
few minutes or even hours typically or even days.
And so, uh what a lot of these DS security appliances are doing are simply,
you know, looking up the age of the domain and going. Oh, wow.
That's like really fresh. And, you know,
I'm going to block access to it for now for like a few hours or days
until
reputation services,
uh get to know it and, or, you know, that just kind of gives it
time for the bad guys if they do,
do something bad with it for them to get caught and hopefully booted.
Right. And so you're not affected.
And I mean, I think that's really because I'm trying to think,
I was trying to think of some legitimate corner case where I would register domain
and then masses of users would need to use it right away.
And the only thing I could really come up with is like um a telegram, right?
Because they've been bouncing through domain names
trying to avoid that Russian block.
That that's basically the only legitimate case for something like this.
Yeah. But even then all they have to do is pre
buy
domain,
just buy the domain, sit on it for a week and then use it.
Yeah, exactly.
So there, there literally is no legitimate
need for this and
in the context of, of using these open source software libraries.
I, I think this is also true in that
99% of the time,
there's actually really very few reasons to upgrade
to the latest version of a library.
No, I'm not saying you shouldn't upgrade. OK. Let's be clear.
I hate it when people pin versions
and then I end up, you know,
getting some piece of software that has like some six year old library
which I now can't update because the new version of the
library is so fundamentally different that it like breaks everything.
But here's a thought
maybe, you know, unless that software update has a specific, you know,
security fix or like a bug fix that you really need.
Like, your system is crashing every five minutes,
you know, don't
run the absolute latest, greatest, like, give it a few hours or a few days.
And I was thinking,
are there any dependency managers that allow you to say something?
Like, get me the latest version minus one?
I don't think there are
any,
-- but
-- that'd be kind of a cool feature.
It's not a terrible idea. And, and you're kind of right where,
I mean, there,
there are some updates that fix critical security issues
or critical bugs that you want right away,
but I can count on one hand probably the
number of times that's happened pretty much ever,
not, not per year
ever.
And generally speaking,
hopefully, you know, when an issue is that bad, whoever's
distributing that software should kind of make a big deal out of it, you know,
put it in a change log.
And also ideally
that that should be like the only change for that version, right?
Like, ideally they're, you know, just like, ok, we like,
absolutely need to fix this bug as soon as possible.
So we're only fixing that bug, pushing it out. Boom. Done.
Well, I think the, the things you really need to care about,
you, you generally find out about them outside of
the normal communication channels,
right? It's because it's like on Reddit and Twitter and CNN
-- see
-- the downside is like,
looking at these dependency managers, there's no easy way to automate this. So,
uh what I encourage and have been encouraging most people to do is, you know, what,
just grab the latest and like if it breaks, then deal with it, either downgrade or,
you know, file a bug and get it fixed or what whatever.
But now in light of this, I'm kind of thinking, you know,
wouldn't it be awesome to be able to say like give me the latest but one, you know,
and let these other crazy bleeding edge people or, you know,
use the absolute latest in your dev environment, you know,
but not in production maybe.
Yeah, I mean that's fair. Yeah.
-- So
-- for, for those of you, you know, building systems like glider
or rake or whatever, all those dependency managers.
Uh Yeah,
please add this as a future because I would love to see if it
is useful or not and I suspect it might be kind of useful.
I think, I think it could be, although you could argue if more people
or rather if the number of people looking at things decreases substantially,
then the the likelihood someone will notice something bad
probably decreases as well. My guess is there's a certain,
I, I have no doubt there's a correlation between the number of people using a thing
and the, the speed at which
will say problems are found.
-- Well,
-- the other thing to remember is just because a problem is found,
doesn't mean it's properly reported,
right?
Like, I've,
I've had people tell me stories about them finding a bug in software and I'm like,
cool.
Did you report it? And they're like, uh, no. And I'm like,
you know,
it's like people who complain about potholes but don't phone the city or actually,
in my case,
we have an application
for our phone where you, like, take a picture of the pothole.
It asks you, do you want to include the, like your current location?
And you say yes.
And then you hit like,
send and then a few days later the little pothole filling truck comes out,
you know, so like,
or it's like the people who complain about politics but never know.
You know,
that's the only reason I felt so I can't complain.
But that, that's my one thought is that, yeah, I mean,
I suspect you're right in that the people mature enough and wise
enough to maybe use this are also the people that are,
you know, also hopefully mature enough and wise enough to realize if you find a bug,
the best way to get it fixed is to report it so that it gets fixed, you know,
upstream. So you don't have to carry your own patch,
right?
Because like, that's one thing I've, you know, when I deal with devs, I'm like,
you don't want it.
Like, you do not want a monkey with the software unless you absolutely have to.
Right. Unless upstream is refusing to do something that you absolutely need, like
grin and bear it.
Oh, I
have a funny story. I'll tell you many, many years ago.
This was back in the day when people were unsure
if this open source thing was going to catch on.
Right. That's, we're talking like more than 10 years.
I was at this conference and it was just a security show,
like a symposium type thing real small, maybe, maybe 100 people, maybe.
And
I was talking about open source security and just kind of how it works, what it means,
who's looking after this stuff.
You know, all, all the usual sort of questions that, that people had back in the day
and there was
a, a developer from a very large organization.
OK?
And
I, I remember the topic of contributing patches back came up
and he says,
why would I just contribute patches back?
And
I
looked at
him for a second, I thought
because otherwise you have to take care of it yourself forever.
And he said,
but no, you don't understand. I'm not,
I don't want other people to get this.
I'm not, it's like paying them that I'm not, I'm not paying these people.
And I'm thinking
you're taking their like literally millions of dollars worth of software,
you're using it for free and you're complaining about paying them with patches.
And it was,
it was one of those instances where I just shook
my head and moved on because there was no way
I was going to have a productive conversation with that person
and
man,
-- but anyway, yes, report, report
-- issues.
And the thing to remember folks is
you don't have to fix it.
I mean, it would be nice if you did, that would be super awesome.
But more fundamentally like, please report these issues because,
you know, I've seen so many cases where,
you know, some user has a slightly different setup or,
or maybe they have a really big setup that, you know,
the developers can't replicate and you know,
so they'll run into stuff that quote unquote normal people don't, you know,
so yeah, please do contribute bug reports and,
and I hate to say this because I hate bad bug reports,
but even a somewhat bad bug report is still better than nothing,
right? Because with nothing, it's like completely, why are you all complaining?
Right. There's, we got nothing in the bug tracker about this, like, go away.
But, but anyway, anyway, that's not the topic today though.
I think, I think it's important to note
that
people are noticing the security problem because there have been a handful of
attempted back doors
on what didn't even say attempted, there have been some attempted,
some have succeeded.
But I feel like I can't think of any instance
where it lasted for any significant amount of time.
And when we look at like the gen two incident
and the GEN two incident was literally half an hour before they,
they did something about it.
And then
this, this uh es Lint thing
was a couple of hours.
I don't know what the ARC ARC
lineage
a problem was, how long that took. But regardless, like
this stuff is being noticed.
Well,
I think part of it is the reporting channels now are so efficient and effective and
most importantly, most of them are public, right?
Like when you file an issue in github,
not only can the project see it, but like everybody in the world can see it.
That's true. Actually, that's really true.
Right? And if you file a juicy bug report, like, hey,
this thing has like a credential stealing Trojan,
I think technically is the correct term, not a virus but whatever,
you know, not only are other users and developers going to see that,
but then like somebody from the register is going
to see it and write an article about it.
That's true. That's actually really true. And in fact,
how did I find out about this? Oh, the, the snake guys,
uh they, they put a thing on Twitter and that's how I saw this.
They had like an emergency update sort of, of notice and like,
that's really cool, you know.
Well, the beauty is, I mean, these things are rare enough that they still get press,
right?
It's,
it's the things that happen like 10 times a day that don't get press,
you know.
And so,
to me that's actually a good sign that people are
still reporting on this because it's rare enough that,
like,
yeah, it's literally like, once or twice a month.
Maybe that it happens.
Yeah.
Well, although, although
it used to be once or twice a year. Right. And I feel like it's speeding up.
Well, it's, I think it's part of it is, it's not so much speeding up,
there's just more software and there's more community involvement and
the communities are much bigger and much less trusted than they used to be. Right?
Like,
I literally remember the day when like,
like when Linus knew all the developers personally
because there was like 50 of them,
you know, I remember like the open BS D camp was like
20 guys
still
is.
Yeah. You know, I mean,
yeah, I mean,
these communities used to be really small and really high trust and now,
you know, we're letting almost anybody in,
which is awesome because we've got so many more developers and so many
more people and so many more viewpoints and different things going on,
which is, you know,
ultimately a lot better than just having a bunch of grumpy old people.
But at the same time,
no one's hosting their source code out of an FTP site anymore either.
Right.
And
that's, that's where I think without github,
-- we couldn't exist the way we do today in open source,
-- the ability to clone a project.
It's one command line that takes like five seconds now. And everybody has a machine
and more of the,
everybody has a machine fast enough to check out
a couple of 100 megabytes of source code.
No problem.
I do remember the days when that was not true.
Those were,
-- those were dark
-- days
when unpacking the Linux Tar ball took, you know,
the better part of 1015 minutes on my machine, let alone,
-- I
-- remember I had a machine once that took three days to build the Linux kernel
three days
anyway. Anyway.
But, but here's the thing,
I guess I feel like security is kind of hitching a riot in a lot of these places,
which is really cool though because
I think that the, the security of open source is a really important topic and,
and my fear now is we're going to see more and more fear
mongering from some of the closed source people which ironically not Microsoft,
but there, there are some groups I see that,
that talk about this and it's like
you guys, well, not only that, their stuff is full of open source,
they're just pretending it's not.
Well, the beauty is it doesn't matter because the economics of it are ok.
You can either write
your own library and
maintain it and carry the cost of that
or you can go download curl or Apache or
no Js Library F
and
-- have it up and running in like, 10 minutes.
-- I think it's more esoteric than that.
The, the thing I'm seeing is
there are companies that will, I don't want to name any names because, like,
if they're doing this, they're also probably the sue
type.
Right. I don't need to be sued.
But there's companies basically saying, you know, this,
this alternative product is either open source or uses open source.
Like our product doesn't, even though, um,
in one instance I did do some research and yeah,
they have an open source page and it's full anyway.
They say like our,
the product is an open source and it's much more secure because of these reasons.
And it's like,
-- well, you're full of crap and everything you just said is,
-- well,
the beauty is that they'll probably be proven wrong.
And economically they're, you know, like,
remember when IBM had their own web server and
then they gave up and started shipping Apache,
right?
Everyone had their own web server, man.
Well, not only that, I guess you're, you're probably right because I mean,
Microsoft couldn't get away with this.
They lost at the end of the day. And they, they luckily saw the light,
-- oh
-- I on,
on the CV board called the Microsoft person flat out said because I was
asking obviously about open source and Microsoft
and how that's going to get handled,
you know,
and, um, like she flat out said that you know, it's, it's not from on high,
it's from the CEO, like,
use open source,
you know, the Reddit A MA they talked about having 60,000 developers at Microsoft
doing stuff related to open source. Like,
no. Yeah, that's just how it is now. Like everything is TCP/IP networking,
everything will be encrypted,
everything's open source, everything runs on electricity. Like that's just,
that's, you know.
Right. We don't drink toilet water, we drink from the tap.
It's the same water but, you know,
like it's just held with the same water.
But yeah, I mean, that's just,
-- that's just how it is. Right?
-- Ok. Ok. So you, you've got me thinking now,
let's assume
the, let's say you've got a dirt
company talking about open source is insecure and they're,
they're probably only going to trick a couple of people, but let's face it.
I, I have a suspicion at this point.
-- Well, they'll
-- be able to find specific instances where it is
a
problem.
But statistically on the average,
I would put a large amount of money that it's
as good if not better than most
qualifying that most closed source,
there are a handful of close source things that I know
that are actually quite secure,
but these tend to be very small things that do a very specific job
-- and are not widely different.
-- That's different.
Ok. So, so let's, let's think about this. Now,
everyone has accepted the fact that open source is basically
the same as everything else.
I'm not going to say more secure because it's not, and I don't think it is.
Everyone's basically using it and there's no way you're gonna stop it now.
So, even when there are security problems, like we're looking at right now,
it, it doesn't matter
-- really. It's, people are still going to
-- use
what, what
in theory might matter is. Ok. How fast does open source patch this stuff?
They patch it pretty quick in general? Cool. So that results in sort of
software churn where you have to like get on this upgrade train and it,
that costs money, right? Like,
you know, I remember the olden days where apps were updated like once a year
on CD, right? No, like you
and,
and here's the thing like that software churn has become
part of the process for anybody building decent software because,
you know, customers are like, I want this feature.
If you don't get me this feature in two weeks, I'm going to, you know,
cancel this test and go with your competitor,
right? So,
so that,
that cost of software churn is kind of built into building software now because
well,
customers expect bugs and stuff to be fixed
quickly and new features to be added quickly,
you know, especially if your competitors have that feature, you,
you better get that feature out quickly.
And so I think one of the main downsides to this, which is that software turn
is, is essentially ok now because it's a cost you have to carry anyways,
you know.
Yes, I do think you might be correct
thinking about this.
It's, it's just the way it is now, isn't it?
But ok, so, so let's take all this together. Then. We've got the, the churn aspect.
We expect a lot of updates. Where,
how does
is there? I guess, I guess let's answer his question then.
Is there a way to stop things like people
checking in malicious code either because they're a dev gone
rogue or they've stolen credentials from the DEV, I mean,
in theory we would have code reviews but I mean, I,
you know,
by the 4/100 code review that week your eyes are going to start to glaze over.
Um,
yeah, that one, I don't, I don't think humans, well,
not only that you've seen the underhand,
right? I mean, there's people that,
that some cool
off by ones are always my favorite because like in hindsight. Oh, yeah. Whoops.
Wow, that's like really obvious.
But, you know, obviously it wasn't at the time where they wouldn't have done it.
And so I, I think fundamentally,
I mean, and, and in a way, code,
like when somebody spots this after the fact and says, well,
that's a bad chunk of code, you better remove it.
I mean, that is a code review.
It's just, well after the fact before it got formally accepted
and it's this also kind of speaks to the economics of it, of,
you know,
code reviewing and properly vetting every single submission.
That's actually quite expensive. Right.
If you think about a human being's time,
if it's going to take a human being half an hour of time,
that means if you had a human being doing this full time, they could do.
Like, what is that? Like, 16 code reviews per day.
Right. A
lot of these projects, we're talking like 16 commits an hour
or more.
Yeah, there's no way. Well, not only that, it's,
there was a study done about, like,
auditing software and basically after one hour of looking for bugs,
you're done for the day.
-- So really people can review two code commits per day, not six.
-- And then
the thing too is, is that, you know, kind of once I'm using this code,
I actually do have more incentive
to review that commit because I'm now using it. Right.
Whereas if I'm a user of the software, I, why would I do code commits?
Because that software is not like that commit isn't in the software yet.
It doesn't, it's not my problem yet.
So, unless it's like a bug I really care about,
you know, unless it's a bug or a feature, I'm really like, damn it,
I need this fixed because like, production crashes every 27 minutes.
Um, you know, I, I'm not going to care about somebody else's commits.
Right. And that's just fundamentally, you know, why am I going to expend
time and effort on something I don't really care about. And so,
you know, once it makes it in
and so, I mean, a lot of projects do this, right?
They'll have like the stable version and the DEV version, you know,
um or the LTs long term support version and then the more
kind of quickly moving version, right?
You know, like Jenkins is a great example of it, right?
Like they have their current version which gets like,
holy heck, you read those release announcements, like they're,
they're doing a lot of work all the time
and then you've got your boring LTs version, which is kind of frozen
ish in time and gets like
really critical updates and stuff, but it is kind of boring and stable. And then
the thing is you use that LTs version for one
or two years and chances are you're gonna be like,
well, this thing is terrible because it's missing all these features now and you,
you know, upgrade to the next one
and, you know, for some people that's fine, right? They can like, you know, they can,
they're fine with that one or two year kind of upgrade cycle and then,
you know, you've got all these start ups where they're like, yeah, we're,
we're going fast and, you know, hard
and I, I think that's kind of the best of both worlds, right?
Because there's a lot of enterprise type software where you
don't really need to be on the bleeding edge.
Like if it's, you know,
an accounting system or controlling the plumbing of a large building.
Yeah, you, you can be a few days or months out of date.
-- Generally speaking. That's ok.
-- Right.
Right. Right.
Interesting.
-- But, yeah, as to this,
-- I think you,
I suspect part of it too is you gotta remember there's a lot
of people working on automation tools to find this kind of stuff,
you know, I mean, my, my favorite example is the guy that wrote that
piece of code that
uh it
looked for passwords in source code.
But the way it looked for passwords was by looking at the entropy of the strings,
right?
Because in theory, good passwords will have a high degree of entropy, right?
They'll be very random.
So, well, it's, it's so that's called Truffle
Hog.
-- Yeah. Truffle Hog. That's the one
-- and I,
I've, I've,
I've run it more than once and it does a lot more than just entropy now.
They have certain regular expression. So the problem being
looking for just entropy, in fact,
I know this because I did some research when I
was looking to see if uh backdoors have more entropy
than, than regular code.
And, and anyway, uh
so the, the problem being that
looking at just entropy has a very, very, very high false positive rate.
And so, in fact,
I think they turn off entropy by default
-- now and they only use a regular expressions
-- and
that's
a
good point is that they made it better,
they made it less false positive and more
correct.
And,
and that's how software works.
Right. That's the beauty of software is
generally speaking outside of a few terrible projects. Software gets better.
It almost never gets worse. Right?
Because by definition, if you start making your software worse,
nobody's going to use it.
Right?
And like, no sane rational developer actually wants to do that, right.
Most of these people actually want to make stuff that's good and useful.
You know, that's a very fundamental human desire.
So that's the beauty to me of software. Like when I look at, you know, like I'm using,
I've been using some software packages now for over 20 years,
like emacs Apache http D you know,
wait, you're an emacs user,
you seem so
uh I do know V I because it's on every system but who cares anymore?
Emacs is on every system,
not mine.
But uh
no, I mean, the the thing is basically, you know, when I look at all this software,
the stuff that's died is the stuff that didn't
get better or didn't get better fast enough,
right?
And all the stuff that has survived by definition is
like pretty awesome. Like, you know, you look at the capability of
like this.
I Yeah.
No,
when I think about the default software stack
and operating system typically gives you now,
plus what you can get for free.
It's like
that stuff used to cost millions of dollars.
So, you know, you know what I'm, I'm thinking about here now is
maybe
we're never going to fix the problem
because if you look at it
right, that's exactly it. It's, well, no, it's not good enough. It's getting better
but it's getting better in a boil of frog sort of way
where we're just not noticing it getting better.
But it is. And, and I feel like
things like
malicious code inserted into open source projects now that open source is kind of
come into its place in the world and it won.
I have a suspicion that's one of the next hills we need to climb because I mean,
by definition, security always lags reality
because it just has to, that's the way it works.
And this is our next challenge and I have a suspicion it's going to get solved,
but it's not going to get solved in the ways we think it is where I have a feeling,
things like
the scanning tools are what are going to solve the problem,
not reviewing everything
into a project. There's already
like there's already a huge market for these companies,
but, you know, look at the source code you're generating and,
or pulling in from other places and basically say, you know, like, ok,
this has known flaws or this has suspicious
flaws or this has really suspicious code,
you know, and you can wrap business rules around it, like,
deploy it or don't deploy it.
And so those companies have a huge incentive to,
you know, squash their competition by coming out with like,
something, a major thing in magic, like an A I
security flaw finder. I don't know. Right.
I'm sure they're working on it.
And so to me the beauty is there's economic
incentives here to solve the problem to solve it.
Well,
so I'm becoming sort of a market proponent in this way and that I'm,
I'm kind of not really worried about it anymore because
to put it bluntly, there's like gold in them, there,
hills and people are going to go find it.
Well, some of them will, I mean, this is
what I think we were arguing about this just the other day and flak or something
or, or signal
where there are,
there, sometimes market incentives will exist.
And I think for like an enterprise, it's going to be there.
But if we, if we talk about our iot light bulbs,
I don't think there's ever going to be a
market incentive for security of iot light bulbs.
And it is conceivable. It will never.
So, so in that case, if there's no market incentive,
it's, it's all about regulation
and it is conceivable that no one will ever care enough to regulate them either.
And so we're just going to live in a
world where like IOT light bulbs are completely terrible
and that's just the way it is.
-- No,
-- I suspect for the cheap stuff, regulation will have to be part of it.
Like, every time I buy screws and nails at Home Depot, I'm like, man, I, I, like,
I hope these are made out of the right metal and not like plaster.
Like, I don't know. Right.
-- I have never once thought that, you know, like,
-- when I'm buying construction
shoes
and up
-- to 50
-- pounds, I'm like,
I hope so.
Right.
Do you know, I never even look at that.
I couldn't tell you what any of the screws I have in the garage are rated for,
like,
I
don't know.
So then it kind of matters.
You just put in a lot of,
yeah, true.
But, um,
but yeah, so, I mean, you know, and on the flip side too there's been a lot, like,
cars were horrifically insanely dangerous until,
you know, public perception changed.
And now there's even car companies like Volvo, that market based on safety.
So,
and now they're only most. Exactly.
And so I, I suspect with IOT light bulbs that, yeah, it's going to take a long
time comparatively to the life cycle of these iot
bulbs and companies for it to catch up.
But again, um,
the flip side
is, I
don't know
if it
will.
And that's, that's my next comment is
I'm, I'm not sure it's going to be really a problem.
Right.
Maybe my light bulbs, mine Bitcoin
and maybe
they don't. Who
knows?
But, uh,
yeah. No, I, I think open source obviously has one. It's here to stay.
You know, even, I remember like 20 years ago Microsoft trying to, you know,
it's a cancer.
It's the Halloween memos and all that.
And even Microsoft
-- is rational enough to realize that. Ok. No, that, that war
-- is over, it's over.
I know, man, I used to argue with them so much. It was,
I guess you're right. That's,
that's the right way to look at this is,
it's not even argument anymore. And if anyone, it's like
people
-- to even
-- say it's straight up like flat earth people, it's like, no,
that's just not how reality is.
That's exactly what it is. Right. You, you're either, you're either trolling me
or you probably have some sort of disconnection from reality that that needs
help. I can't give you right. And that's basically the same sort of thing here with
is open source security. You're either trolling me and you know it
or you probably need like professional help.
-- Those are, those are my guess the two options we're looking at
-- pretty much.
I like that. That's,
and more to the point I would say the
question itself is even wrong because like is any software
secure? Is any hardware
business
process secure? The answer is
no, but most of them are good enough,
right?
In fact,
it's funny you say that because my kids for
some reason were talking about bank robberies the other day
and I explained to them why bank robberies today
aren't possible because of course they were talking about,
you know, wild west cowboy style bank robberies
and I explained to them like, just, just the security things I know about banks.
And I said there's plenty more they have that
I don't know about because they don't do people
and my kids were like, this is crazy.
And I said, see this is, but at the same time,
banks have money like they have real tangible loss if, if they get robbed.
-- So they have incentive to
-- fix.
They're insured
to a degree. If you get robbed every day for two years, no one's going to insure you.
Oh,
your insurer is going to drop you. Yeah.
But I mean, recently we had, uh, what was this like two weeks ago?
Alberta RC MP is, ah, jeez, this is terribly written.
Are asking for the public's help to identify two
armed men who robbed the Saint Albert bank.
Saturday morning.
Uh, police were called to the C I BC, blah, blah, blah.
But here's the fun thing. Ok.
One of the men held a black handgun and
demanded the staff hand over money from the tills.
The two men fled the area with an undisclosed
amount of cash and here's the funny part,
one of them fled on foot and the other one and rode away on a bicycle
and they still haven't caught these
and they got away though. I mean,
good for them.
But more fundamentally, like,
I know how much money they keep in the tills at these banks now.
And it's like,
not a lot. It's not a of
money.
It's,
yeah, it's not, it's not worth robbing banks. Like, go get a job, jobs are better
and you don't go to jail
anyway. Anyway. All right, man, I think we should call it.
So I guess we're going to end it with open source is totally
not insecure. We'll say I'm not going to call it Secure.
It, it's not insecure at
the
same time. Anyone who asked that question
large and varied like
that's true.
It's the same deal. So there we have it. We, we, we figured it out.
The problem isn't people asking is open source secure. The problem is people
again.
So, all right, sweet. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open
source security podcast.com to hit up the show notes,
use the Pound Os S podcast hashtag
to hit us up on social media and nothing else. Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.