Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself.
Kurt Siefried and my partner in taking pain over the counter pain medication. Josh
-- Reser,
-- I didn't take any over the counter.
So Kurt is laughing because I don't, maybe I'll leave it in. I don't know.
But right before we started recording, Kurt's like, oh,
I should go take some ibuprofen quick and then he like left to go take medicine,
which is just,
I guess that's being old.
-- Well,
-- I just, I have to train myself now that like if I'm in pain, like sore body pain,
I, I need to take Ibuprofen or Aspirin or something because
I hear you.
I'm, I'm older now and I'm out of shape and it's just,
I'll feel better if I take Ibuprofen.
It is true.
You know, that's one of the funny things I recognize now that I'm a bit,
we'll say older when I was young, I was obsessed with not taking medicine and
not wearing coats when it's cold. And
you know what I mean?
Like, just being a general moron and now if it's cold,
I turn the heat on and I wear sweatshirts
and coats I don't wear shorts outside and when I
or I take medicine and I rest and sleep and
it's nothing at all like it used to be.
I, I generally, yeah, like, it's funny because I was brought up to layer.
So I never had that thing with like
not wearing clothes outside when it's cold because also
Canada.
And, but what I do notice now is I see younger people walking around
and I literally want to open my car window and shout at them like zip up your jacket,
it's cold out
or like, you know, hand them some gloves or something.
-- I think that's as old person as you can get like literally,
-- yeah,
like I just want them to be warm.
So,
yeah, well, that kind of leads to today's topic, right?
Which is,
so you and I have been back and forth kind
of discussing this idea of open source specifically as,
as
how it relates to natural resources and,
and essentially how do you manage natural resources?
So you don't like strip mind the planet and you know,
destroy it, right?
Well, I mean, so there's a little bit of background to this actually. And
I mean, we've talked over the last probably couple of years.
I mean,
at this point about kind of how open
source works from a larger community perspective and
kind of in the last few, I'd say the last six months,
there have been a lot of banter amongst open source developers
basically pushing back a little bit uh along this like whole supply chain.
I am not a supplier
like I don't want to use multi factor authentication to use your ecosystem.
Like I just want to develop stuff and not worry about any of this other crap. And
there was I I forget I'll try to find the post. It was
what was the latest one titled? Like I am not your supplier or something like that.
That,
yeah, I'm not your supplier.
Like I don't have a contractual like,
and that's what always gets me is not only am I not your player?
Like I don't have a contractual relationship with you.
My license explicitly disclaims any warranty and,
or responsibility I have for the software because
otherwise I would be sued into oblivion and be broke because at some point,
everybody's software has had a bug that cost the company several $1000 to fix.
And if the company decided to, you know,
sue that person for several $1000 they would probably lose.
But that developer's life or project would be wrecked for several months.
I mean, probably
you want to deal with that stress.
No,
no, I do not.
And so conveniently enough,
it's covered by the license which what and what really offends
me too is that all the commercial licenses also do this,
you know,
where they explicitly say like you can't use
this for nuclear software control because there's,
there's regulations in that space on the software.
So
you can't use Java.
But I was,
so I've been thinking about this and I think I have two sort
of a thought A and a thought B which might help frame this.
So
the first thing is if we're going to compare this to natural resources,
then there's that whole thing of managing natural resources
and sort of the fact that some natural resources are
finite, like very finite
and some are basically infinite. So a good example of this would be
if you want to look at a mountain
that's essentially an infinite
resource. And I caveat that I'm making air quotes here.
So for example,
you can take a picture of that mountain and distribute it infinitely.
No, no problem, right?
And that's sort of what software is like in
that making that first copy is kind of tricky.
But once you made that first copy,
distributing it and you know, you just stick it on github
and everybody can download it however much like the natural world.
If 10,000 people decide to go see that mountain in person, now we have a problem,
right?
I mean,
and so I think part of this leads to the second thought of,
part of the problem is that we have this
infinite supply of like software say which yeah,
I can distribute the software millions,
like open SSL everybody on the planet uses it.
Basically if you own a TV.
But what that leads to at some point is TV, man, manufacturers, TV, users,
whatever people going to the open SSL people and wanting them to do stuff.
And that is a very finite resource. And I think this is,
but we have this infinite resource but it leads to usage of these finite resources.
Yes,
because to put it bluntly,
if people just used open SSL and didn't complain and didn't
demand bug fixes and left the open SSL developers alone.
Cool. I think that's the dream. A lot of open source developers have.
Well, it's simple, just don't put your email address in there.
I don't disagree
with everything you said.
And I don't know if mountain is
the right way to think of this even it's,
there's like so many pieces
and the thing I keep thinking of is when we think of open source,
it's often thought of in a very supplier context, right?
Not as a I am going to a place and acquiring resources. And I think that's
the thing I keep thinking of here is
when people talk about like the secure supply chain,
open source is a huge part of it versus
I am acquiring a resource
outside of my organization that I then have to shape into the thing I'm going to build
if that makes sense.
Well, I think the more the point of my observation is that we can't
separate
the finite and infinite.
They are tightly linked like a simple example is, well, Mastodon is a great example.
They have over 3000 issues in their github
and it's just out of control. It's a giant
of fire to the point where basically your choices are either, you know,
kill it with fire or
get 1000 volunteers to handle three issues. Each. Good luck with that. And so
I think the problem is, is that a lot of people focus on the infinite side of like, oh,
you just download the software.
What's the big deal? Well, yeah, there is no big deal until
one in 1000 people ask for the developers five minutes of time
and all of a sudden the developer runs out of time.
Right. Well, and they're doing it like for free,
you know,
-- you don't,
-- the majority of them are. Yeah, or actually at a
cost to themselves.
Right. Right. Yes. Absolutely.
And I think that's the thing I keep trying to untangle in
my brain and this is where I don't have a good,
a good way to look at this. I, I, so it, it's funny too.
I put a thing on Masted on a couple of days ago basically saying I am
interested in information about how companies at the
start of the industrial revolution before we had
many of the rules we have governing like clean air
and clean water and pollution and things like that.
Like how these companies basically ravage the resources around them for
their benefit with just blatant disregard for everything around them.
Well, and worse what they did to their workforce.
Well, ok. So here's the thing and that's what everyone keeps coming back to.
Everyone keeps coming back to the workforce.
And I think workers' rights while very important are not.
Well,
I don't think that's a valid comparison and
in this context and I think it distracts from
what open source should be. It's not about treating
the workers correctly. It's about thinking about this as a resource.
You are just like destroying along the way.
But workers are a resource and, and I guess one comment there is that
workers are a resource that can stand up for themselves and mountains can't
unless somebody champions the mountain.
That's exactly it. Right. That's exactly it is
like there's no open source union,
there's really no way for all of the open source developers to come together.
I really and truly think this is much closer to like a forest of trees
where it's a,
a bunch of independent things that don't
even necessarily want to interact with each other
that we are treating as a singular entity.
-- And, and we're cutting them all down
-- well.
And the other kind of vibe I'm getting from a lot of these arguments is it kind of
reminds me of the whole arguments around famous people
and how famous people sort of have this duty to
like, let you take a photo with them or sign, you know, if you go up in front of them,
like can you sign this and they have to sign it because they're famous and they,
if they want to continue being famous, they kind of have to pander to their fan base,
right?
But that is not the case with most open source developers,
most open source developers do not want to be famous. They don't, you know,
they just, I needed a library to do acts.
So I, I wrote one and I just, I released it because, you know,
that's a decent thing to do.
You know, like the person who wrote Lib JP,
it was part of his thesis defense. As far as I can tell
the guy, I don't think he was planning for it to be here 25 years, 30 years later,
you know, embedded in everything,
you know. Right.
And,
and that's the thing I keep coming back to with a lot of these arguments online of,
well, the developer should act otherwise
like people won't use their software and it's kind of like, well, OK,
I know for myself if you don't like my software and don't want to use it. Oh
OK.
Like I, I'm not bothered and if you want to fork it and do it yourself, uh cool again,
we can't treat everybody with the same
or paint everybody with the same brush I think is the expression.
But fundamentally, I,
I feel like I just keep coming back to the
fact that these open source developers don't owe anybody anything.
And again, the licenses explicitly disclaim this kind of responsibility.
They, they do remember XML has
a uh has hash dos,
right? It happened a few months after I started at Red Hat, right?
And I remember tracking down that one developer and
straight up, he's like, yeah, I can fix this,
but I don't have like a free weekend for two months.
And so we're like, OK, well, we'll, you know,
we'll do it because we need this sooner than two months.
This is I think a really important point that you just brought up
and this is something I've been also thinking about. So
if you look at the
kind of the history of open source, you see organizations like Red Hat and Google,
I'll pick on those two just because I'm very familiar with them.
You see these organizations like Red Hat and Google
that
used open source in amazing ways,
but they also were not taking from open
-- source, they were involved in open source,
-- right?
Well, they understand sustainability that, I mean, that was a big mantra at Red Hat.
And that's one of the actual useful things I took away from my uh tenure at Red Hat was
the sustainability aspect of everything,
especially open
-- source projects.
-- That's the thing is
when you're a Red Hat or a Google and you are sending
developers into the world to help it is vastly different than when
you are a consumer of a piece of open source and you're
sending bug reports back and now there is nothing wrong with that.
I'm not trying to say like using something and sending bug reports is bad.
But I think
there's definitely an aspect of
how do we balance that?
Because if,
if every let's say you pick on something like curl that has literally millions,
probably billions of users.
If, if a million people each file a bug in curl,
like it's probably what do you, you know what I mean? What do you even do with that?
And I think that's, that's the thing.
I keep wrap trying to wrap my head around is there's nothing wrong with using curl.
And I'm glad millions of people use curl.
But if a million people filed a bug all of
-- a sudden now it becomes a disaster
-- and that leads to
another thing I was thinking about. So I was thinking about offensive speech,
just bear with me for a minute.
So if I say something to one person,
I can probably tailor the message to not offend them.
And we've talked about this in the past where
if you say something to 10 million people,
like I had ice cream for breakfast,
some of them are going to be offended like, hey,
I'm lactose intolerant or that goes whatever.
And again, I think that's part of the challenge with open sources.
If I write some software and release it and 10 people use it.
Cool. That's probably ok.
But the problem is when a million people use it, it's gonna number one,
they're gonna find a whole bunch of edge cases and corner cases.
And curl is a great example because Curl talks to everything.
And so, you know, all these people are like, I could rewrite curl in a weekend.
You know, I would love for Daniel to do like a probably a 17 hour talk on.
Like here's the top seven, you know, top 17 edge cases we found
-- and curl
-- 17, there's,
well, the top 17,
-- right?
-- I mean, there's, there's millions, that's literally the whole code base
is, is a catalog of exceptions, right?
And so I think that's part of the challenge too,
is as a software becomes more popular, it interacts with more other software.
You get more bugs, more feature requests more, hey, you know,
the the standard now implements this, can we also have G
compression or can we have
whatever, whatever, whatever, right? And, and curl implements like,
well, everything like literally like you,
it's a scary man page,
right?
And that's, I mean,
it's a perfect example of a successful open source project in that.
How many options does it have? Well, all of them, that's the answer, right?
And if it's missing one, they'll add it.
And again, this goes to sustainability
of OK.
So if I file a bug report am I making more work for them or am I kind of a net benefit?
Well, the answer is you're making more work for them.
Whereas if you come to them with a,
like a bug report and maybe like a patch, maybe the patch isn't great,
but it's maybe less work for them.
So
I guess it goes back to sustainability of like,
it's like having a little kid help make breakfast,
right? It's not usually actually that helpful.
But if you also want that little kid to grow
up and learn how to make breakfast on their own,
you got to deal with this.
So again,
this whole sustainability long term thing kind of like is this a net benefit?
Well, in the next month, no, in the next 10 years,
maybe this company does grow up and do better.
Maybe they don't, maybe they just keep causing those problems, right?
And I think that's part of the,
the thing is right now we're at a stage where all these companies are like,
I want breakfast and some of them are like, I will help make breakfast.
Look, I put the eggs in the toaster,
it's cooking, I'm helping, you know, and it's like, OK, no, we,
we don't cook eggs in the toaster,
you know,
and so I think the next few years are going to be very painful for open source because,
well, OK, OK, you can't say that though.
-- Everybody's
-- using it
like everyone is using it.
But,
but it, it's like saying the next few years are going to be painful for the trees,
you just cut them down, they're gone. They're,
well, and that's the question is how many open source developers
go? II I quit or I give up or I don't need to deal with it.
That's right. That's right. Exactly. That it isn't going to be zero.
And that's the thing I keep thinking of is
we are ravaging open source in an unsustainable manner today, I think,
and
it's only going to get worse. The thing I keep thinking of
is
if you pull in a bunch of open source into your product today
in five years,
it's gonna be a lot harder to
upgrade assuming you haven't been upgrading constantly.
You know what I mean?
And I think then
you're going to see like, like in five or 10 years,
I think you're going to see a lot of technical debt is gonna come due.
And
if we don't do anything,
it's going to create
a nightmare scenario for a lot of developers.
And I think they will quit because they're gonna be like, I'm sick of these bugs.
I'm sick of talking to these people like I, I don't want to do this anymore.
-- It's not fun.
-- Well and worse. That kind of what you're describing is LTs, right?
Long term support.
And that is a thing, for example, with ubuntu and Red Hat, you know,
my favorite example being Red Hat, where when I explain to people,
Red Hat's life cycles and what it really means.
So very simply put Red Hat will release a version of Linux
that they will support for 13 years.
And when I say they will support it,
they guarantee that your accounting app that they have never seen
and will never see will run on it for 13 years.
And, and that's amazing when you think about it.
And the thing is that is not sustainable for the vast majority of projects.
Like I I, I'm not going to have an LTs version and a feature,
full version of my software.
I'm not going to maintain that slow fork because
to put it bluntly, the people that want that
I don't,
they're the kind of people I don't want to
deal with because they're not upgrading their software.
-- They're, you know, they're making crazy corporate demands
-- and,
and they pay for it in many instances.
I mean, Red Hat, it's not cheap to get proper LTs support from the likes of redhead
Ur
Muntu
as it shouldn't be.
And
I think that's one of the places we've become kind of spoiled in the world of it
is
the likes of Microsoft and, and Red Hat and ubuntu
have made a lot of this very long term functionality.
I think it's ruined some of our expectations.
Whereas when you get something from open source, it is, it is completely plausible,
you will import a dependency and
tomorrow
it will have a breaking change. You know what I mean?
That's just how it works sometimes. And that's great.
Or that version ceases to be supported because they went to 4.0
-- well,
-- and I think in, in the vast majority of open source,
there's no concept of support.
It's always amusing to me when you look at like open SSL
where they usually have like the current version and they support the prior version
where the vast majority of open source projects, like they,
they don't really even support the current version.
They support whatever is running out of G
and like, you know,
much less old versions.
And this goes back to, you know, again, we can't paint them all with one brush.
But if you,
it's just so bizarre to me, it's like you're, I guess, fundamentally
maybe part of the pro two is survivor bias in that the I, what do I call them?
The sort of the sustainable,
responsible users of open source are not the ones making
problems and causing grief. So
never hear from them and see them.
And it's only sort of the demanding people who stick out because
they're the ones filing bugs saying like I want long term support,
I want you to fix this bug.
I want a so like I want a SOC two report on your development process,
-- I want salsa signing, I demand two fa
-- I mean, I don't,
I think there's some of those cases and they, of course,
get brought up and we all laugh at them and be like, ha, ha.
What a silly person. I don't think that's, is that common.
-- I think we just, it's, it's very survivor bias.
-- No. No.
What I'm saying is the survivor bias aspect of.
Yeah. Yeah. But, but hang on.
But I think the important part is that
nearly every open source project that has a reasonable amount of use.
It's just death by 1000 cuts.
It might not be someone saying, fill up my sock to report for me.
It's just
this constant flow
of bugs and complaints
because let's face it. Every piece of software has bugs.
It's gonna do something, someone, it doesn't do something,
someone wants whatever.
Well, or it needs enhancements. Like,
like the fact that master on you can't undead people, you know, and the guy,
it's in the bug report, his cat killed the user by stepping on the wrong key,
which is really funny. But,
and, and the solution is we'll fix it in the database
-- which look, it's open source
-- technically is a solution. But that's,
that's like saying, you know, my car's broken, we'll go fix it like,
-- yeah, but
-- that's a really good analogy.
You say your car is broken.
-- I say, go get it fixed and you say I want you to fix it for free.
-- Well, no, no.
But what if that part keeps breaking.
-- Maybe that part needs to be re-engineered and
-- I mean, potentially.
-- But ok, so that's another example.
-- If the cars keep catching fire, then maybe
-- you as the manufacturer,
-- this is what I was hoping.
I was hoping to talk to Kurt and refine my thinking on this topic because
nothing
refines my thinking
like Kurt's stories. Now that that's an excellent example.
So let's say you have a product
and a piece of it keeps breaking,
right?
You're going to go to the, the whoever made the product and say you need to fix this.
Like there's warranties,
there's consumer protection laws like you can't do this now yet.
Don't you dare interrupt.
Now, if the reason it's breaking
is because I went to the forest and I'm using the wrong kind
of wood or I mined the wrong mineral or something like that.
No one's gonna say, hey,
you screwed this up. You should be doing a better job.
They're gonna say, no, you're the manufacturer.
You got the thing,
freaking get the right thing like this is your responsibility to fix it.
And I think that is the disconnect in some of
these instances is we have end users using a thing
and then
the,
the company making the thing
is going through the forest and demanding or asking for
a different solution. And I think that is the crux of what we see today.
Well, and also the user going directly to the forest and you know, you, you see those
bug reports of like
literally like uh he's got that statement on curl like, no, I didn't hack you.
It's called open source.
And that's like, no,
because literally this is why my name isn't the thing that you're using.
It's I didn't hack your car.
I remember the Apache Software foundation used to get tons of emails like that where
when you stood up Apache, you had the default page and people would,
they'd stand up a site and when something would go wrong with like DNS,
it would show the default Apache page instead.
And they're like, oh, you hacked us and it's like, no,
you screwed up DNS don't use DNS.
But
anyway, anyway.
But, and I think that's part of it is, there's this,
it's this weird and wonderful ecosystem
and there are not really official relationships
and I guess maybe that's part of the problem is companies
and commercial entities really
aren't used to dealing with that.
You know,
because like most companies don't kind of get a bunch of volunteers
in on the manufacturing floor to help them build cars like that.
That's just not a thing, I hope.
Right.
And
whereas in the software world that is completely normal and how
you do it because how else would you do it?
Right. I'm not writing my own web server. I know how complicated that is.
But like I said, I think the problem is,
is it's coming to a head where people realize now that open source is everywhere.
The bill, essentially the bill is coming due.
Kind of like with environmentalism, it's like, uh you know,
uh like a perfect example is forestry companies
finally realized it was cheaper to actually replant
the trees because then they have more trees to harvest sooner than to just clear,
cut it and like
leave it to
erode and be destroyed.
I wonder sometimes how much
of the company doing the right thing sometimes,
like in the terms of forestry management or,
or water management or whatever is because they have to,
or because it's, it's more economical. I have a suspicion.
-- It's because they have to,
-- uh, it's, it's a bit of both.
Like, so, for example,
locally there's a lot of talk of now using drones to plant seeds
to regrow the forest because
part of the beauty is like when you plant a seedling, like a small, you know,
little baby tree, like you got in great school, I'm guessing, you know,
that costs a couple bucks to plant and only a few percent make it.
Whereas you, you fire seeds out of a drone and yeah,
if only even 1/100 of a percent make it.
It's so ridiculously efficient.
It works.
I think part of the other problem too is,
is a lot of companies are sort of hoping or
expecting other companies to pick up the slack and,
you know, we have this free rider problem.
Like you can only harvest a tree once,
right?
You can only cut down the tree once,
but you can make an infinite number of demands to some poor
open source developer or project.
Well, you can't because they will quit,
-- but until they do,
-- right, they,
they kind of hold all the cards in that regard is they
can make the ultimate decision of like I'm out and that's it.
A lot of them though seem to be putting up like a lot of them.
It's, it's kind of like reading on Reddit, you know, am I the asshole? And it's like
some of these people are in clearly abusive relationships and it's just like, wow,
you need to get out and I'm, I'm not just talking about Reddit, all
the asshole I'm talking about some of these open source projects where
like I look at some of these projects and what they deal with.
Why do you keep doing this? You know, why, like the time zone guy,
literally one person holding together the world's time zone files.
Like, thank you.
But also
I would have maybe gone on strike for a month and like let everybody kind of
figure out that I'm important and they should all send me a dollar in the mail.
Uh Maybe, maybe, I mean, so here's another good example.
There's a, a new story SJVN wrote about it. Um
It was, it was shortly before Christmas. I think.
And there's a, a go project called Gorilla
and Gorilla basically said
they, they do, it's like a web, I think it's a web uh handling framework like HTP,
request, things like that.
And anyway, they basically said
we, we don't have time to do this anymore. I need help. No one helped.
And then they were finally like, we're, we're done, we're gonna basically,
this project is end of life.
They put a message on their
github.
And of course, there have been
some people,
I mean, some people basically were like, oh, I wanna help.
But at the same time, you can't just like hand the project over to
any random person,
right? Especially a well used project because like, where is that person from?
What are their intentions?
Are they actually going to help or are they going to help for a week and then give up
or install a crypto miner in it?
-- Right.
-- Exactly. And that literally happened somewhere else.
But anyway, and so there's this piece about, oh, what are,
what are we going to do about projects like this?
And of course, there's the usual, oh, just go get involved and like,
it's not generally that easy.
And additionally, the other thing I keep thinking of is
if there are a million
users of your library and each of them send one person like Mythical Man Month,
right?
You don't suddenly have a million times of the productivity. Now you have a mess
and you can't plausibly deal with that much stuff. And additionally,
if your project has 5000 dependencies,
you're not going to hire 5000 developers and send each one to a project.
-- Like that's just not a realistic thing to do.
-- Well, I think it's worse than that.
And by definition, any successful project has solved all the simple problems.
So only the complicated problems are left,
which means anybody that's going to get involved needs a level of expertise, right?
I'm always reminded of. Well, again, like environmental remediation is now a
per like it's a four year degree at university now,
you know, like when you look at a stream and you're like,
let's make this stream healthier.
What can we do?
And it's not like just a simple matter of like, let's pull out all the trash.
No, it's like let's spend several million dollars,
you know,
doing stuff to it.
Research, you know, maybe we need to put in a weir,
maybe we need to take out the weir whatever, right?
Put more rocks and
rocks in, you know,
all sorts of crazy things.
And I think that's a big challenge with a lot of these projects because that
everything is complicated now, like all the
there's no simple stuff. For example, I was looking
for some simple Red Xs to validate uh social media account names like Twitter, uh
reddit, whatever.
And what's fascinating is most of them don't actually properly document it unless
you actually go to the page to create one and then it'll like,
you intentionally create a mangled one and it's like, no, no, no, you,
you can only have 2 to 39 letters and blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
And what's fun fact. So, Twitter says it has to be like 4 to 20 letters,
but there are one letter you, uh I DS on Twitter, like there's twitter.com/,
that's what the grandfather did, I guess.
Right? Because they're
like, go to twitter.com/a letter
and, you know, the account's more than 10 years old for sure.
Or every,
every account with up to four letters is already taken.
So they just
-- ignored that because that saves you a database. Look up now.
-- Yeah, exactly.
Yeah. It's, it's something even quote unquote simple like that.
I could not find a good resource for it and then I started building it and I'm like,
wow,
this is actually kind of complicated because there's rules like it can
have hyphens but it can't start with or end with a hyphen.
And then,
so just collecting
the actual, where is the rule posted about this social media network
that took me about half an hour each to actually find like an authoritative source,
right? And then I realized I just had to go through the workflow of them and
actually, you know,
but like, with Twitter, I had to also make sure I'm like,
I'm pretty sure I've seen shorter than four.
So then I had to, you know, this is a nontrivial.
So,
so something that is quote unquote simple is a very nontrivial amount of work to get.
Right.
And you have to know what to look for in corner cases and, and I'm still left to wonder,
like, is there a twitter.com/ampersand,
do you remember in the Pearl book back in the day in the camel book?
They had the regular expression for validating email addresses in the
back and it was like 2.5 pages of regular expression.
Yeah, I know.
I mean, and I have one of those and I, I have a simplified one and it's just,
you know, for example,
I don't allow symbols in my email address names even though that's legal.
I'm like, I'm not dealing like
your email address better be less than 100 and 28 characters.
I think that's a reasonable max.
And like I've, you know, kind of filtered out some of the, uh,
the fancy characters that are allowed.
I'm like, no, that's
-- get a real email address. You know what
-- my favorite was, was back in the day.
I had an email alias of Star underscore Star, which looks like a little
face.
It broke so much stuff.
It was so good. It's totally valid. Like that's fine.
But
that's the thing when you learn what is actually a valid email address,
it's horrifying.
It's horrific. But ok,
but,
but
that,
that's part of the
resources.
That's part of the challenge is even if people want to help.
Yeah, it's great that you want to help.
But again, it's like my son, my son wants to help but like to fix the file server.
So, like, can you just be quiet while I do this?
I just,
I just had that over the weekend where I was fixing some computer stuff
and they're basically like, what can I do? I'm like, don't bother me. I
-- know.
-- Right. I feel
terrible.
But, you know, this isn't like we're not tailors and it's like you can just,
you can sweep the floor
and, you know, that would be helpful.
Yep. Yep. Like, no, it's just
like, ok, daddy's got to go fix the Z pools,
you know?
But what I, ok, this is,
yeah.
You know what, this reminds me of.
There's, I'll try to find this, there was a speed run of,
um, what, whats the
guesser? I think it's called the game where you have to figure out where you are
and,
and there was, they were doing like a demo of this at a, at a games done quick,
which actually this podcast comes out on the first day of games.
Done quick. Awesome games done quick. I'll put a link in the show notes.
You should totally spend your week watching. Awesome games done quick.
But anyway, they're, they're doing this like,
demo of this and one of the guys is like, this is Japan.
There's too many reasons to explain.
I'm like, that's so good.
And it was funny because to me it, it just looked like a random road somewhere but,
like, to that guy, like, he knew exactly what was going on.
-- What's
-- funny
-- to me is when I watch those and they sort of like,
especially sort of eastern Europe slash a bit of western Europe.
I, there are cues for me, like the way buildings are built, the way the
gates, the fences, the just, there's, there's cues and hints.
Ok. So I, I guess, I don't, I don't think I have a clear picture.
I'm still not clear enough in my mind that I'm willing to write any of this down yet,
but I am comfortable
with
kind of some of the conclusions we have. Right. Like, obviously I, I still think
it's more correct to view open source as a natural resource, like
water or forest or air whatever.
And I think
it's difficult maybe to
maybe apply pollution directly to it necessarily, or just, uh,
I think that's an aspect of it.
Yeah, I, I don't, I need to figure that one out.
I would say it's actually, it's not so much a natural resources,
it's part of an ecosystem of different natural resources
and it's all to quote the, it crowd, it's all interrelated, you know, you, you chop
down one tree in the rain forest and,
yeah. Yeah. To, I mean, to a degree, regardless. I think we all agree that
the way open source is being consumed today is on a path of unsustainability.
I
I think for me,
the biggest takeaway here is that the sort of the infinite use piece of this,
like looking at the picture of the mountain
is linked to the finite piece, right?
Because if a million people look at a picture of a mountain, at
least a few 100 of them are gonna want to go see the mountain in person.
And
I think a lot of people forget
that a successful open source project
is
1 to 5 people or less than a person dealing with the law of large numbers
like curl is a great example of that.
It's
right or Mastodon, right? You got a couple of core people dealing with
literally millions of new users now.
Good luck.
Yeah.
Yeah, it's,
it's tough, man. I, I'm gonna keep thinking about this one because
I feel like if, if nothing is done, I do think you're right.
I don't think open source will like collapse and die.
But I'm also not comfortable being like, yeah,
it's ok if some of these people like their lives get ruined and they're,
they're mentally crushed like that's fine.
That's just open source like that's not ok either.
-- So
-- I think part of it is we need to help them and enable them.
But at the same time, fundamentally, these are adults
who get to make adult decisions.
They have agency, they get to choose how they live their life.
And I think a lot of these people need to put their foot down a bit and say no
and, or otherwise I don't want to say meaner, but be a bit firmer.
I mean,
that's maybe a fair point also because I do think
a lot of open source projects are way too nice
where they,
they listen too much maybe.
And I, I guess this is part of, this is part of how it all works.
Like,
do we want our future open source to be a forest overrun with weeds
and gargoyles or do we want a nice place people want to go?
I,
we're gonna find out, I guess I, I'm, I don't know, I don't know.
All right, I'm gonna, I'm gonna call this one. I need to think about it more.
Well,
I'm sure we'll be back here again in
the near future talking about this particular topic.
But
thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening. Go to on our
security podcast.com. Head up the
Pound
Os S podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media. Kurt.
Have a marvelous, rest of your day.
-- You
-- too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.