I installed the Twitch app on the fire stick and watched a few minutes
of Twitch streaming just to show Mel because she didn't quite believe me.
And the top one was this guy unboxing yu
gi oh Cards.
That's it. And Mel's like, but what else does he do? And I'm like, that's it.
There's a guy on youtube who goes to the bank and gets coins and then he opens the coins
and I've watched hours of this guy and it is like, honestly, it's super boring,
but it's like, what's next?
What's next? It's, it's the perfect.
I am a stupid monkey
drug. It's lovely.
Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself.
Kurt Siefried and my partner in thought crime, Josh Bresser.
So I bought a track ball the other day because my,
my wrist was feeling the repetitive stress of using my mouse way too much.
-- Did you get like a thumb, track ball or like a palm track ball? No,
-- a thumb.
Actually, I didn't even think of the palm ones.
I just picked up a thumb one and it's not like super duper nice.
It's just, I figured I'd get a reasonably priced track ball and see if I like
it and go from there.
Yeah.
But you're, you're basically just transferring the problem from your,
from your wrist to your thumb.
-- So,
-- actually,
you know what I found is my forearm muscles are what are suffering at the moment,
but muscles I can deal with.
-- Whereas wrist joint pain is not enjoyable.
-- Well, yeah.
So my sister actually forced herself many,
many years ago to learn to mouse with her left hand.
-- I can
-- mouse with either hand.
Oh,
yeah, because you're a lefty
left handed. So I had to learn to use both.
-- Well, why not just have two mice and like, break it up.
-- I switch it every now and then.
I basically just decided, like,
I'm because the thing is I'd switch a mouse and then that,
-- that hand would start hurting in a couple of days and last
-- week.
-- So why not switch faster than a couple of days? Like, I don't know,
-- switch, I'm lazy
-- or
-- it starts hurting, like,
stop using logic against me. Won't that work?
It's like that time I exercise too much and then my body hurts.
-- So I never did that again.
-- Just exercises. What up with that?
Uh
No, no. And this is something I've wanted to do for a while anyway.
So I'm like, you know what, it's time and I've been doing
an unusually large amount of mouse work due to a project.
I wrote a Python script to read and edit Excel spreadsheets, which to let you know,
that's where I've ended up because I've grown
so sick of looking at these spreadsheet.
I'm like, I'm just building a robot to do my job because I hate it.
-- Which seems like a win to me.
-- Isn't that the whole point of it?
Is building a robot to do your job? I like. Isn't that the fundamental premise of it?
Yeah, pretty much so. Anyway.
All right, we're going to talk about old devices today. So set us up.
I have a theory actually that says there's basically, I think two,
maybe three kinds of compute devices.
So the first kind is the kind of compute device that is not necessarily locked down,
like, even like from a bootloader perspective,
but it's just something that has computer software in it.
And, oh, also we're only talking about stuff connected to the internet.
If it's not connected to the internet, it doesn't count. That's fair. Right?
Like, because to be blunt, like I'm pretty sure,
yeah, I have like this desk clock that has temperature and
humidity and stuff and there's,
there's got to be a micro controller in
there but there's like there's no network connectivity.
So,
yeah, no, it doesn't count. So I'm talking about stuff that is
actively connected to the internet, not stuff that can connect to the internet,
but stuff that is typically commonly connected to the internet, right?
So, like you know that guy that, like, hacked his game boy to go on the internet,
game boys don't count.
So the first set is those devices that kind of do a thing.
And, you know, even if you have like AJ TE port or whatever, you're not going to like,
monkey around with it and reprogram it or ever change the software on it.
You're basically going to get it from the manufacturer,
you're going to get the software updates,
maybe if ever from the manufacturer and install them and it's, you know,
I'm talking like IOT light bulbs, I'm talking like,
you know, just all that kind of small stuff.
And then the second category is stuff where it's like locked down,
but you can load software on it to do stuff of
used to you. So this is basically be like your smartphones and tablets,
right? Like I can't really jail, like I could jailbreak it in theory, but it's
-- a lot of hassle,
-- let's assume from the perspective of normal people.
But the biggest difference being for example, if one app stops working,
like say Google sheets stops working.
I can go to Excel or if you know what I mean, like the things I want this device to do,
I have some choice in the software to do that in theory,
right?
So like there's more than one drawing program, there's more than one web browser,
there's, you know what I mean?
And then the third one is what we all think of as classical computers, right? Where
you have a relatively open and, and I mean,
even Mac Os and Windows are relatively open by
the standards of like a mobile phone currently.
You know, you can, although Mac Os is going a different way, but, you know, like,
for example, with Windows, I can pretty much load whatever I want on it,
especially now at this point where it runs all the Linux software too.
And so
in case number one, what I want that device to do is very specific
and it's accomplished by the software on that device. And
quite commonly, that software also has like a mothership.
It connects to, to like log data or,
you know, provide control over the internet, whatever.
And so to put it bluntly, even if I can hack it or even if I can update it economically,
it's just not worth it.
It would take so much time and effort
to like hack my light bulbs and like build my own
firmware and load it on them that it's not gonna happen.
Contrast that to a use case like you where you're like, yeah,
I have to read all these stupid spreadsheets that are all mangled up.
I'm going to write a Python script to go through them, right?
You could write that in Python, you
write in VB script, you could write it in bash
whatever you, you have a lot of options because
kind of the problem that you want to solve is kind
of high level enough that there's a lot of options,
you know, and it's not tied to the hardware. Right.
Like you don't buy a laptop that comes with, like Excel preloaded.
And that's the only spreadsheet it'll ever be able to run. Now.
Microsoft sort of tried to do that with surface at one point.
-- But
-- for example, I could still go to the website on, for Google Sheets
and the,
the people revolted.
Yeah. Exactly.
So, with these three classes of connected to the internet, because quite honestly,
if it's not connected to the internet, I don't care.
I don't have to worry about protecting it. Yeah. Right. Right.
Realistically, unless it's like some military installation or something crazy.
Let's
explain the story that is the inception
to this
conversation.
So, as, you know, I love Android phones because I think they're awesome because,
you know, you're, you're locked into carrier updates
and they never get software updates past six months.
So I think they're just the bee's knees and
this is all coming home to roost finally.
Well, no, traditionally this doesn't matter.
They, they're insecure and they're easy to hack.
They're, they're dirt freaking cheap. I mean, that's what it really comes down to.
Exactly. They're dirt cheap. They're accessible, they work, but now
they actually kind of might stop working a lot. Sort of, some of them.
The reason is the, lets encrypt is getting their own root certificate.
Right in past,
they had a certificate that is signed by another root authority
that then allows them to operate as a certificate authority.
And now they're getting up on their own 2 ft, which is awesome.
-- Well,
-- they've been up on their own 2 ft for a while.
It's just, what's happening is the original cross signed certificate is now
going away because obviously when
another C signs anything,
there's a lifespan on that.
-- Also,
-- more importantly, when the C A cross signed something that C is now
responsible for everything signed with that cross sign certificate,
-- which that's, it's a bit of liability
-- right there.
I mean, sure.
And now let's encrypt has become big enough that their route is included everywhere
except for old things because you can't go back in time.
Well, and also it's the way it's included because the old thing,
the way it used to work is you had this,
essentially Firefox had a root certificate store and everybody else was like,
yeah, they did a good enough job vetting these people.
Sure, let's use that.
And I mean, the, the,
the process back in the day was hilariously terrible and that it was fail open.
It was if you went with a root certificate to Firefox and said,
I want to be in the certificate store,
essentially, somebody had to prove that you shouldn't be in that store
otherwise you were let in.
And I mean, there were some people that were terrible enough that they were like,
yeah, we, we can't let you in.
But if you, if you actually look at your root certificate store,
there's hundreds of cas in there and I tried to
track them all down at one point and I couldn't.
Oh, yeah,
there's a sort of a hidden spreadsheet the Firefox
people have with the data on these CS.
And even that is, like,
awfully vague in some cases like who these CS are or what
they do is like some of these cas don't really have websites.
And I'm like, um, how, what, how does that work anyways?
So these older Android devices are, you know,
these old devices that cannot get software updates because, well,
the carriers just don't support it.
-- I
-- want to also clarify, we're talking about devices from 20 16 and before.
So it's more than three years, which is three years.
Is that magic number, especially in Android land that infuriated me so much.
I switched to an Apple device because I think three years
-- because we get 5 to 6 years.
-- Exactly.
Well, and that three years too isn't like three years from when you buy the device.
It's three years from when that device is released.
So if you buy that device like a year after it's released,
you're getting two years of support, right?
Which is insane.
You know, same thing with chromebooks, chromebooks get, what is it?
I want to say six years of support from like a certain date that they're released.
Yeah.
And I bought a chromebook like a year and a half after it was released,
only to realize I'm going to get like 4, 4.5 years tops out of this thing.
And then it's, and then what do I throw it away? Also? Frustrating.
-- Well, it's annoying because it works fine.
-- Yeah, I know. I know, man. I know.
-- You
-- know, but it's garbage because Google said so,
and that kind of ties into that classes of devices where with these phones,
in theory somebody could jailbreak the phone side, load a new Os blah, blah, blah,
bring it up to date, but like nobody's going to do that.
Like the economics of doing that are horrid.
This and the skill and the technology needed may not be available.
-- You live in a small town. It
-- doesn't matter where you live. I think about
like helping my parents with their computer and it's just
I told them to buy a chromebook because they can't screw it.
And since they've had it, they've never called me once
and it's basically like it's got training wheels on it and
they're taped into the seat and they can't mess it up.
-- It's lovely.
-- Yeah.
No, if I had to get a device for somebody, I would start,
I would say you're in order of preference, it would be tablet chromebook.
-- And God forbid if they need a quote unquote computer then get them a Mac.
-- Exactly.
-- Although the windows stuff is pretty good these days,
-- Windows is getting better,
but you kind of have to set it up.
Right.
Yeah, that's probably fair. That's probably ok.
So, anyway, anyway, I don't want us to rat hole on these specific details.
The thing with this is
normally again, here's the thing with security bugs,
security bugs don't matter until somebody exploits them.
Right. You can a perfect example. I have accidentally left my
door unlocked on my house.
I
actually one time left my garage door wide open until like,
uh, uh, in the evening, my neighbors like, um, your garage door is open.
Did you mean to do that?
-- And I'm like, uh, nope, kind of hope everything's still there.
-- I have a fun story.
I have a heated garage
and it's a detached from my house
and I left the door open. We'll say I, I'll blame myself.
We don't know exactly who it was, but it probably wasn't me.
Somebody left the door open all night long.
-- Oh, God, what was that heating bill?
-- It was an unpleasant bill to pay, we'll say
because the heater in the garage literally ran for eight hours,
but I had no snow left on the roof, um, outside the garage door.
So what you're saying is you're admitting that global warming is your,
it is almost definitely my fault. I am a significant contributor to that problem.
Yes.
So normally with these security flaws and what not, it doesn't matter,
but this is different in that websites will stop working and,
and not just a few websites, but like,
let's encrypt is now a significant portion of the internet
and, and honestly also a kind of, of what matters. And now,
and this is funny because everybody's always like,
why do companies pay so much money for these certificates?
Blah, blah, blah. Well, now, you know why? Because they want to get
a certificate that's signed by a route that's
like in these devices for like the next,
like some of these root cas don't expire.
I remember some of them had like 38 year life spans or something absurd.
It's completely ridiculous.
And this is why that, you know,
your bank and Facebook and those guys will pay horrendous amounts
of money to whoever has like the longest lasting lifetime cert
in the browser store because they don't even
want to drop of like 0.00001% of traffic.
Right?
Ok. I've been thinking about this a lot, a lot more than is probably healthy.
And
I think here's where the conversation is going to start, where,
where we're going to say,
it's easy to say old devices should die.
And that's the, the cop out I think,
especially when you have the privilege that we have, which is, oh,
my device stopped working.
-- I'm just going to go to the Apple store.
-- Exactly. Now, there's the argument of
so there are,
we'll say low income or disadvantaged people who can't necessarily upgrade.
There's people living on $2 a day that have
managed to get a smartphone and God bless it.
These things are helping them, you know, they're opening up markets and economies
-- that are helping gank people out of poverty.
-- Now, I agree with that.
And, but here's my thinking in that regard is
just because you are
disadvantaged in some way.
And I wouldn't even say it's only economics because like,
I know people that have ancient phones because they don't
see a reason to upgrade and they just don't understand.
-- And it's like, whatever I've given up in
-- general though,
-- for their use case that might be ok for them
-- and, and it might be, but,
but here's the point is if you are disadvantaged in some way,
these companies are selling you unsafe products.
And unfortunately, the way the laws are written today,
old broken phone doesn't qualify as unsafe in the same way as let's
say I buy a product that kills me or burns down my house.
The liability is well defined there. And I think this is one of the big problems.
Two thoughts on this number one, how do you deal with secondary markets?
Like use stuff? And secondly, we have seen regulation around this.
So for example, where I live here in Canada
and I think it's Canada wide, it could be just provincial.
I cannot sell you or give you my used car seat.
It's just not allowed because it might have been in a crash, it might not be safe,
it might, you know, think of the Children.
And so even if I can guarantee, like, look, my car has no dents. This car seat's fine.
I can't legally sell it and I have to throw it out. And on the one hand
I get it and I like that because people should get new car seats that are like,
not all beat to crap and like art for their kids.
But on the second hand, this results in a huge amount of waste.
And there's a lot of people who can't afford a good car seat.
Here's my argument that is saying just because you can't afford
a good car seat doesn't mean you don't deserve one and
saying that disadvantaged people should be happy with the junk they
get is I think a twisted and demented view of society.
No, no, I'm saying the opposite of that. Well, yeah, society is saying that.
No, I understand you are. I'm not, I'm not. Society is saying it. Exactly.
I'm not, I'm not blaming you. Now, here's
kind of one of the ways I would look at this is if you have a small child,
a car seat is like legally required.
You can argue. It's kind of one of those like basic needs
and I don't know about Canada.
But I know like in the United States there are ways
to acquire high quality car seats if you are economically disadvantaged.
-- And
-- that's great for us.
But I feel like we're not going to see a, you know,
a mass cell phone subsidy program in poor
countries because they just can't afford it.
Well, we should though.
I mean, so in all seriousness, I mean, this is a society problem.
This is not a security problem because the reality
is if you to exist in the world today,
it doesn't matter where you live, it doesn't matter what you do,
you need access to the internet and the vast majority of people,
their access to the internet equals a cell phone.
Well, a smartphone smartphones took over cell phones.
-- Thank God finally from
-- this point forward for the rest of our
working relationship. Anytime I say cell phone, I mean, smartphone. Ok.
Fair enough
-- that goes for you too.
-- Listeners.
I'm just, I'm old enough to have owned a couple of flip phones.
I think I might still have one in a box somewhere. But
anyway, anyway, you, you get the idea. So this is a basic human right at this point.
And I don't think we're, we're recognizing that.
And so basically these companies that are making
low quality smartphones and never updating them.
It is the same thing as being like, oh,
whatever those poor kids can play with my broken glass, it's fine
just because you don't have the money to buy the good one, doesn't mean
that you should be sold an unsafe one.
-- So,
-- the question is ultimately who pays for this?
Because if the people could pay for this,
they probably would get a slightly better phone or, you know,
upgrade their phone once every couple of years to get better camera,
better features, better screen, whatever.
Right. So, it's a product safety issue.
I mean, look, if, if Ford makes a car that blows up,
no one's going to say, oh who has to pay to fix the Ford cars?
-- Well, Ford freaking pays to fix it because they built a car that
-- blows up.
We have different standards of vehicle safety across the world.
Like if you look at the crash test of some of those people in
China,
-- if you look at the crash test of some of those Chinese cars, they're horrifying
-- and,
and in that context,
it is up to the Chinese government to set those standards.
I don't want to dwell too much on China.
This is what really grinds me with this issue is, you know,
what one solution here would be, is to have somebody like a public group fund,
a really good operating system for phones that was open sourced
and freely given out so that it would be cheaper and easier to do updates.
You know, something may be based on Linux anyway.
And that
happened and here's where we ended up
Yeah, it did because it turns out that rather than
treating it as something we can upgrade.
Everyone just tried to lock them down and sell garbage.
What's like the smart TV thing where smart TV,
manufacturers make most of their profit by putting adware junk on your TV.
Like the problem is the cost of TV. S is driven down
but
I, I cannot make money selling you a TV.
Like if I charge you enough money to make money selling
a TV, it's going to cost like 50% more than my competitors.
So, what I have to do is the same thing with the old laptops and crap Warre issue.
Right. I'm going to, like, load crap Warre on the TV.
And, you know,
some antivirus company is going to pay me 10 cents and install because, you know,
on average one in 1000 people are stupid enough to accidentally hit.
Yes, and plug in their credit card number to get antivirus on their TV or whatever.
-- But
-- here's, I think the big,
the big point we talk about all of these problems in the context of security
and it's not really a security problem.
Like the fact that a certificate is going to stop
working on older android devices isn't a security problem.
Right.
It's the fact is that these companies made garbage devices,
we're letting them make garbage devices and
there is essentially zero regulation or liability
-- in any of this.
-- I think one of the challenges is, is that we have to accept that there.
The, it's, the product is a product as a whole.
Whereas it used to be, you know, products didn't used to have software.
Like for the first, well, basically majority of my life, anything I bought,
there was no software on it.
With the exception of like my game boy, literally,
-- which still
-- works.
-- Yeah, it actually,
-- yeah.
So fun fact, I have an original Game Boy in a box in my basement.
Mint.
It's in acceptable shape. We'll say it's clearly been used but it's not like beat up.
00, ok. I thought you meant like you were one of those crazy people like, don't do
-- that.
-- No, man. If only I was that smart.
Oh, yeah, I could retire.
But the thing is people don't sort of see products in their entirety.
I, what I see with a lot of people is they see the hardware of the phone.
They're like, well that still works.
That's acceptable and I'm like great,
but that hardware doesn't do squat without good software.
Like the camera on my phone,
the camera on my phone is useless without a good camera app.
It is. It is completely true.
Now, now, maybe, maybe a different way to think about this
is,
let's say I buy medicine at the drugstore, right?
That medicine has a use by date on it.
And if I use old medicine and I get sick and die.
People are going to say you shouldn't have done that.
That's a terrible example because somebody did a study into those use by
dates and found out that essentially if it's a pill and it's,
it's stored in a cool dry place, it's probably good for a few decades.
It wouldn't surprise me.
There are some medicines that do degrade and obviously medical isotopes.
Vast majority of medicines, especially in pill form are stupidly shelf stable.
I mean, it could, I
mean,
that's like even I enjoy eating expired condiments in
my fridge just to see if I get sick.
Everybody in Antarctica is eating expired food because they get
one shipment of food on a boat every year,
plus a few flights.
I would just watch a documentary on it
and the head of like, food services in Antarctica.
He's like, yeah, we don't really go by expiry dates.
He's like, look, see this stuff, this stuff was expired when it got here
because it came on a boat. That's hilarious. You know, like
there's just, I mean, there's like, I do buy canned beans and canned beans have,
you know, like a two year life expiry.
I'm pretty sure I can eat them in five or 10 years. And I mean, you know,
we'll put some show notes to Steve. What is it, MRE Info, Steve 1986 or whatever.
Yeah, that's awesome. And, um, watch him eat some 160 year old hard
p
or my favorite is like, he's like, oh, it smells rancid and he's like, oh,
and it tastes worse.
-- He's like, and then he tries it again and it's just like, oh, my
-- God.
Well, if you want a youtube channel you got to act like that.
No one wants to see the boring guy. He's like, well, I'm not eating
and it smells terrible. No, you eat it and you feel yourself eating it.
Dance, monkey dance.
That's how it works.
-- So,
-- back to our topic, I think the economics of it are, you know,
if I sell you a phone for 50 bucks and the hardware costs 48 bucks.
That gives me $2 a profit and that's not profit, profit.
Like, I still have to pay the rent and stuff.
So I'm going to maybe put some crap around there to make a few more bucks,
but I am sure as heck not going to spend any money maintaining that software.
-- Yeah,
-- exactly.
I can't afford to.
And that's assuming the company is still in business.
Well, and this actually is an interesting thing.
I was thinking about this in the context of like,
computers because you think about so you buy a Mac
and obviously Apple is in control and they win.
But you buy a windows computer and
the vendor put windows on it generally.
But then Microsoft is where all your updates are coming from.
You rarely get any updates from the manufacturer.
My understanding is that was sort of the vision of
the Android O si would be comfortable with that.
See, and that would be a good thing. But the
problem is these carriers want to have their, like,
flavored version of Android Os with their own crap
warre and they want to lock you into stuff.
Like I bought a $99 unlocked Android phone, you know,
as a starter phone for one of my kids.
So it was a Verizon phone from the US and it
had like an NFL app on it that I cannot remove.
-- Yeah.
-- Unless you root it. It's, you're stuck with it.
Yeah.
And I'm not going to, I mean, I'm not even going to bother.
So I literally,
my son tried to use it for a month or two and
then I apologized to him and gave him an old iphone.
Yeah, I mean, this is why I only ever bought the Google
phones because they didn't come with garbage and the garbage is terrible.
Yeah. Well, it would be nice. But those aren't really available in Canada.
Seriously. That's embarrassing. Yeah, we've had this conversation, right.
This sounds
proper Google phones are really hard to find in Canada.
And if they break, I got to send them back to the US to be.
That's terrible. See, and that's the other thing, right?
Like if you get a phone and you can't get it fixed locally, normal people can't, like,
it's not even the cost of sending it away.
It's,
I can't, like, I can't live without my phone for two weeks or three weeks. It's true.
You know, and most people
aren't privileged enough to be like, oh, crap, my phone breaks.
I'm gonna just go buy an extra iphone to have as a spare. Right.
Or even an Android phone, I'll just drop 100 bucks on it, you know, and be done with it.
That's just not how this works.
I mean, something a question is,
is there any existing product space that's even remotely comparable to this?
I can't really think of anything good.
No, it's,
it's new and weird in the Microsoft and Apple have broken the update trap and like red
too.
For example, Red Hat broke the update trap by becoming not selling you a device,
but like Apple sells you a lifestyle.
Microsoft generally sells you a platform that you then spend more money on,
especially with Microsoft and like office uh
Red Hat. Straight up, you get a subscription, you pay
-- and you get all your updates for as long as you pay.
-- This is interesting.
I mean,
maybe this is the right answer is if you thinking of this
-- more as a subscription than as a I've acquired a device
-- challenges,
people are given a choice between a phone that
is a subscription and costs a little bit more
than a phone that is not a subscription and
appears to be exactly the same and it will be
the same
for the first six or 12 months and then it
will diverge and you will have that worst experience and that
worst experience won't necessarily be a problem because you may
never get a security issue that is exploited against you.
Well, and you probably won't. The reality is, I think from
the security update perspective, the vast majority of people are going to be ok.
The certificate
thing is different because everyone's going to be affected by that.
Who has an old device full stop? There's no, maybe, maybe not like, yes, definitely.
Yes.
So I don't know what the answer is because I want
there to be manufacturers and providers of like literally $10 smartphones.
Like I think that is the most bloody amazing thing we as mankind have come up with.
-- I agree it would be lovely if it existed. Oh, no,
-- $10 smartphones do exist.
And that's the problem is that at a $10 smartphone price point,
-- you can't maintain it.
-- Right.
Walmart is selling a $10 smartphone.
I need to look at this. I wonder if they're,
they're worth owning.
I'd be curious.
They're probably flaming garbage and terrible. But you know what?
They are a smartphone, generally running Android.
Os generally they can browse the web and they have a couple of apps, you know,
I say go for it.
I mean, if, if you don't have internet, any internet is better than no internet.
Right.
Even on an old device,
-- a
-- hammer is better than a rock and a rock is
better than trying to drive a nail with your hand.
No,
-- I mean, yes, that is an accurate statement
-- and I think part of this will be,
is part of it would be driving down the cost.
Now, we tried that with Android Os and, you know, chrome and stuff
and clearly that's not going to work.
There's just all these weird market factors that make people
make phones that they then can't or don't support.
That's the other thing too is you got,
these people may not be able to technologically support these phones.
Like some of these phone manufacturers farm out their software dev.
-- And so they get like a software blob, drop it on the phone, ship it and that's
-- it.
That's not an acceptable argument if,
if a car manufacturer makes a car with faulty tires and this
literally happened and then the faulty tires fail and someone gets killed.
It is a car manufacturer's responsibility to deal with that.
-- Again, product laws don't force us to deal with this. Not
-- right now.
And they should though, they totally need to,
you're going to get the situation where if you have a country that enforces that
people are still going to the cheap phones from China and get them shipped,
that is a different problem.
I mean, we have that today where people will import unsafe products.
You know what,
this reminds me of people who don't have smoke alarms in their house
or co monitors in their house or my all time favorite people who rent
and don't have renters insurance because like apartments almost never burn down.
You know, except when they do,
-- which
-- is why renters' insurance is incredibly inexpensive.
But I know numerous people that have not had renters insurance,
their apartment burned down.
-- And
-- how do we deal with these people that
just fundamentally don't see the value in this.
-- But
-- there's a difference here. So if I don't get renters' insurance,
that is a conscious decision I made.
If I buy a product that I expect to function, there is a certain level of expected,
not harm.
I don't, I'm sure there's some legal term for that. But you know what I mean?
Well, not even not harm, but just that it still functions like that,
it still browses the web.
So I would say it's
no function function is different because like for example, I can buy a toaster
and in a year, my toaster might break.
And if I call the manufacturer to be like, it was a 30 day warranty stuff,
it you're out of luck.
But I I would say now if my toaster burns down my house,
that is a different situation, right?
And now these smartphones,
I think you could argue that the certificates not
working is closer to the phone just breaking.
However I think there's still some liability questions about this because let's
say there was a terrible security incident that happened against old phones.
-- Well, but
-- where do you draw the line? Right.
Like, I don't know,
what do you define as a commonly accepted root certificate store?
Because what if a vendor decides to,
because I've actually done this where I gutted my root certificate C A
to get rid of all the weird stuff from Turkey in China and Denmark.
And then nothing worked
well.
No, actually nothing, everything was fine because those,
there were like these government c
you know,
I actually got rid of like 70 or 80%
of them before I started to notice things breaking.
But the point is like, who defines, how do you define this?
It's, it's incredibly difficult.
You know, what about things like time zone updates?
What if your phone doesn't get time zone updates? Right.
We've talked about this before with the whole
time zone file that poor guy was maintaining.
-- It got sued by an astronomy company,
-- not an astronomy company.
-- It was a astrology company. Sorry,
-- I apologize. Yes, it wasn't a real thing. It was as
science.
-- Yeah.
-- Sorry,
because there's a million failure scenarios for where
the phone degrades because of a software issue.
And I guess here's where we,
we're basically out of time and here's the thing to think about at
the very end is that this whole digital universe we exist in now
has
terrible liability and, and prior art in terms of what's going on.
So like an example is GDPR, GDPR is an incredibly flawed law,
but it is where we start law never starts out.
Correct law always has to evolve and change
with,
with how it's applied, with intent with the world we exist in.
And I think from the perspective of product liability against devices,
it kind of doesn't exist because basically, unless the thing somehow kills you,
our legal system isn't set up in a way to deal with those problems.
And so I think as a society like this is kind of,
we are on the precipice of the next great thing.
And if we do nothing, we fall to our death.
-- That's it. Like
-- that's
-- it.
-- My one thought is faster churn and I hate to say e waste.
But,
you know, if you can make phones that are 10 bucks or a dollar, yeah,
people will replace them every year or two and
they just become a disposable item like socks,
your socks get holes, you don't fix them, you buy new socks.
Not anymore. People used to. I haven't,
I don't, I throw them away. I mean, maybe that, that, that might be the solution.
We don't know today, I guess here's the thing is, let's say the phones are dirt cheap.
It's going to be imperative that they just brick themselves then.
So people can't continue using what
-- essentially an unsafe device.
-- But is it actually unsafe?
That is a great question.
And is it like, for example,
is it actually unusable to be cut off from the lets and crypt world?
-- Well,
-- maybe, I mean, I don't know.
-- It is
-- because if they're just using the phone to do Facebook,
it's still going to work it.
Maybe, I don't know, I don't know who signed Facebook certificates, but it might,
in fact,
the Facebook app probably uses its own pin
certificate internally or something instead of the as,
as
would if I, if I built that. But I, I don't know, I don't know the answer to any of this.
I think it's a super interesting thought experiment,
but I will say as a human society,
we are currently unprepared for the world as it exists today.
From a legal and a regulatory perspective,
I would say part of the challenge is this is an economic problem and also
a technology problem that like we can figure out an economic solution to this,
but the technology
may not exist to support that economic solution.
Maybe I'm,
I'm skeptical it's as much of a technology problem as it is a society problem.
Well, I mean, it's ok from an economic perspective.
What if we can drive the cost of updating down to almost zero?
Well,
doesn't matter if we can't accomplish
that technologically speaking and that's fair.
I suspect part of this is just it's going to be ugly and messy. And much like cars.
It's never going to be perfect, but it's hopefully going to get
a lot better.
And that's, that's kind of the goal and I guess
like we're at the end of the first batch of
smartphones and now we're seeing it's all aging like milk.
So
anyway. All right, I'm calling it. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. Go to open
source security podcast.com. Head up our show, not its UZ
Poland Os S podcast. Hashtag You hit us up on social media.
-- Kurt, have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.