Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in wearing glasses, Josh Pressers.
That's true in the pre
roll, which I probably won't include because it was very boring.
Kurt is wearing glasses.
He usually doesn't because his eyesight isn't completely terrible.
And he was complaining about how annoying wearing headphones is with glasses. And
it's like,
please tell me more. Kurt about wearing glasses for anyone who's never seen me.
I wear glasses and I've worn glasses for a long time because my eyesight is very bad.
Well, see,
and I wore glasses from the age of like five until I
had LASIK eye surgery in my early twenties because I was 2400.
Like I could not see,
I could barely see my monitor if I put my face up against it.
And so now my eyes are degrading because it's been over 20 years.
And I got to wear glasses again
and I got a low grade headache because my,
when I take them off, my right eye is worse than my left eye or sorry,
my left eye is worse than my right eye, but my left eye is dominant.
So I take it off my brain. Literally, I can feel like a little shake inside.
You know, it's just
getting old man.
-- It's hard to get used to a new view of the world.
-- Literally.
It's funny you say that because every time I get new glasses, my,
obviously you get a different shape of lens, I usually try to,
I've had similar looking glasses for many years, but
even though my
prescription hasn't really changed in the last probably 5 to 10 years,
the shape of the glasses changes a little bit. And when you get new glasses,
the world looks warped until my brain adjusts.
And now what's really funny is I take my glasses off to like read at night and the world
has like a concave view to me when I
don't have glasses on because obviously my brain has adjusted
the probably
concave or convex, whatever the heck it is coming off my glasses.
And when I take them off,
then I see the whole world as like this messed up squishy space, which is funny to me,
there's been those experiments where they make people wear
prism glasses that flip all the images upside down
and apparently the brain will adapt to it.
Although I haven't found an actual proper scholarly reference.
I wish I had the time to do that. I would love to experience it,
but it takes like two days
and
I don't have two days of
I don't think you should be driving.
Well, that's the thing. Like, the whole world's upside down.
What can you legitimately do? Nothing,
right. Like, maybe use the toilet if you're lucky.
All right. Anyway, that, that got weird fast.
Well, it's kind of like this actually speaks to our topic today, which is like stom
Mery and like, analysis of how people write the phrases they use, you know, the,
the cadences, the expressions,
-- Let's
-- set this up. So
a
couple of days ago,
KT sends me a link to a tool that I'm going to look up now because I don't, it's,
it's called stallo.net.
And what it is is you type in the name
or a user name for,
for someone from hacker news and it basically looks at their writings
and compares, it looks for other similar writings and the obvious intent of this
is lots of people have sock puppet accounts and things like that.
And
you should be able to look at like
is how similar is the writing of this account to this other account.
And this is something I'm really interested in and I'm really excited
to talk about because a lot of people don't realize it.
But the way you write is like a fingerprint,
you leave all over everything you might think
you're trying to write like in another voice,
but you're totally not.
And this is something that's been used by
researchers and like the FBI and all kinds of organizations
to better understand, like, who are they looking at?
-- Well,
-- and to be clear, there's, there's sort of two elements of stom
ary.
There's the, like the statistical analysis where you compare A to B and say,
kind of how close are they?
And then there's,
and I don't think it's really how the word is meant to work,
but people conflate it with like,
oh, you know, this passage was written by an angry white male in his forties, blah,
blah, blah,
right? Which is kind of the, that's,
it's,
you can definitely tell things like education about a person from their writing,
even where they're from.
Oh, yeah, absolutely.
But one interesting thing is you can also tell
like if they're highly educated trying to write down
or yeah, where they're from, like what phrases they use.
Because like, for example, is my mom,
my mom's German and she'll say expressions and I'm like,
and then I translated it word for word back into German. And I'm like, oh, yeah. Yeah.
-- Yeah. Yeah. OK. That made sense.
-- Sure. Right. Right.
So my, my favorite example of this is
there was a character
named Ted Kaczynski who also goes by the Unabomber
to
many.
So anyone in the United States who's about my age is gonna
remember this was a like domestic terrorist who mailed bombs to people
and
had this manifesto that was kind of famous and it was like this just enormously long,
semi
unhinged
rant against society,
uh,
semi
unhinged.
But, yeah.
Well,
and, and so anyway,
they eventually caught him and they caught him because
of his writings and it was his style.
But when you read about what they did,
they actually caught him because I think it was someone who knew him,
it was his brother. OK.
Like, recognize some of the phrases used and we're like, wait a minute,
I think I know who that is but
just using the writing, like the FBI was able to ask or turn like general regions,
the person is from,
you know, how, where they were educated, things like that because like
where you live will dictate how you write because certain areas of a country,
for example,
will use certain phrases or they will use certain words more than other places.
I, I have an article I'll put in the show notes. I talked about this.
Well, a soda and pop, right?
There's the map of who, what do you call soda and pop?
Or if you want to be a jerk at soda pop,
you know,
or is it fizzy water? Right? Or whatever?
There's a bunch of linguistic maps out there
that are just fascinating because it's just,
it would have never occurred to me that people
would use that stupid word to call something.
My favorite
is I live in Wisconsin, right?
What would you think we call a water drinking fountain?
A
water fountain?
-- No, we call them bubblers here.
-- Bubblers
bubbler.
Do they bubble?
No, maybe, I don't know. Apparently
according to legend,
the creator of the drinking fountain is from Wisconsin and called it a bubbler.
But for some reason, the rest of the country
-- that sounds like one of those sour grape stories.
-- It's very possible.
And there's also like a very small part
of Massachusetts that also calls it bubblers,
which I don't know why but whatever it doesn't matter,
it's one of those hilarious things where people who aren't from here will be like,
oh, someone will say like, oh where's the bubbler?
And they're like, what
also it was, it was invented in uh looks like it was invented in the UK,
whatever that makes more sense,
-- it seems like a pretty
-- obvious
thing.
The inventors of it,
Taylor's father had died of typhoid fever
caused by contaminated public drinking water.
And so they literally wanted to
find a way to serve water in public safely.
Makes sense
anyway. Anyway.
All right.
But, but regardless, I want to tie all of this into the world of security,
which is the reason we're here.
Sorry. One thing that's just fascinating to me about salam
tree, is it?
So the Ted Kaczynski thing is a great example where they
basically got like a lead and I'll just read it.
Most importantly, David provided letters and documents written by his brother.
Our linguistic analysis determined that the
author of those papers in the Manifesto
were almost certainly the same when combined with facts gleaned from the bombings.
And Kaczynski's life that announce
has provided the basis for a search warrant.
So that was a very like classic, you know, super big FBI effort
focus, you know, investigation, blah, blah, blah.
But now the difference is, oh, yeah. Yeah.
No, I just downloaded all of hacker news and I can just cross
reference all the sock puppets like
this is,
this is what makes it so interesting, right?
Obviously,
I spent time at Elastic where I learned a
great deal about dealing with large Corporates of data.
And like this is something that these systems can do now
where you have the ability to take in literally like gigabytes of
text and do analysis on it in a couple of minutes or
seconds in many cases and you can gleam very interesting things.
And
like one of my favorites was when the Mueller report came out in the United States,
which was that Department of Justice, you know,
special investigation into like Ru Russia
ties with the administration and whatever
one of the employees basically took it,
dumped it into Elastic search and did all this
analysis on it where you can say things like these two words are often
connected or this word and this word are usually separated by three words.
And there were all these weird relationships you
could identify doing this kind of work.
And I'm like, wow, this is really fascinating without reading the report at all,
you could glean
the, like, intent
-- and message in the report
-- and that goes to what's called sentiment analysis, right?
Where people have done a sentiment analysis of sec filings and they're like, oh,
this company is on the ropes, you know, they're like,
it's like every time a company is like, everything is fine
is something wrong. No, everything is fine.
I, I wouldn't say it's fine if it wasn't.
-- Yeah,
-- like, like at Twitter, everything is fine.
We're, we're gonna make Twitter two point. Oh, it's gonna be awesome.
So anyway, Twitter is the reason I'm excited to talk about this right now
because
there is this, this whole concept, right? Of stom
Mery of looking at the writings of people to, to unravel who it is or what's going on.
And then we think about
in the Twitter universe right now like there was
just the spat of fake accounts like Eli Lilly saying
insulin is now free everyone and their stock price crashes
20%. Yeah.
The guy who did that actually put a video up on youtube about it and it's fascinating.
-- We'll link to it in the show
-- notes. Wait, what do you mean the guy who did it?
Like the they know who did that?
Did they arrest them?
-- And
-- that's,
and that's a big part of his video where he's kind
of like uh so I'm doing this video and I,
I
uh
did you just like,
what is it?
Oh,
man. Is it a, uh, what,
uh,
uh, I'm not prepared for this information right now. Like,
is this person in jail or are they going to jail? Is that illegal?
-- Like, no, no, no,
-- it's, it's a, it's a guy who, it's Sean Morrow and he writes for the,
um, he does, like, he, this is the kind of stuff he does but he's like,
I didn't plan to do.
It's, it's one of those classic, like I,
I do this for a living but I didn't plan to do this one incident of it.
So I did this stupid little thing that of course is now what I'm famous for,
you know, like you and I have done that where
we
in quotes.
But um
ok, put a link to that
in the notes and I will put them in the show notes because I, I need to,
I can't comment on that right now because it's hurting my brain too much.
Well, basically it's just like I kind of did this dumb throwaway thing and like,
you know, what's the most like inflammatory kind of thing?
I could say
insulin is
ok.
But look at the same time just because you were trying to do
a stupid joke and you accidentally burnt down the theater full of people.
They're not gonna be like, oh, it's fine. It was just a joke. You know what I mean?
Uh I, I'm on his side for this one. Like, it's uh Twitter,
I mean,
Twitter, I would say Twitter holds just as much blame for
legitimizing his message as
-- he, you know,
-- I agree with that. But we're also not going to talk about that today.
It's so hard not to talk about Twitter.
-- And because it, but at the same time it's like every two hours it's different.
-- Yeah.
Like that L tt link I sent you where, you know,
they're talking about Twitter for the last, like,
it's like just the last four days of Twitter and it's like, so on Friday and then like,
by the time they get to Monday it's just like what?
I know that's the thing. Like I, I,
but between the time we record a show, I edit it and release it
like it wouldn't, I guarantee whatever we talked about would be outdated and wrong.
And it's just like, I don't,
well, or just horribly surpassed by whatever fresh
hell,
you know, was visited people
up
anyway. Anyway. Anyway
where
-- like
-- that poor lady that took three days to
quit because she couldn't find anybody to quit from
like, because her entire chain of command was gone.
Like,
-- I know the
-- people in Europe who aren't getting paid on time or the one guy's like,
well, the money came into my account and then got clawed back from a different bank.
So clearly everything is not working as normal.
We're talking about
stry.
So, ok, but anyway to, to bring this back to the world of security.
And the reason I really found this interesting is there's a couple of instances that
I, I really enjoyed
this whole concept of
Silom
Mery. I'll say the first is Satoshi Nakamoto, right?
Which for anyone who doesn't know Satoshi Nakamoto is the
-- alias of the person who created Bitcoin
-- or persons plural.
-- Well,
-- that and yes, yes, we'll get to that
right where we don't know who made Bitcoin
and
the persona
who claims credit is Satoshi Nakamoto.
And
they have done analysis on the writings and they have almost certainly determined.
It's more than one person.
Well, more to the point
they, they claim to have his birth date fifth of April 1975.
Well, I, I'm sorry, it's kind of, again, it's an FBI level style of pain,
but you just go through all the birth records for that day in Japan.
It's gonna be a bit of
-- a work.
-- It's not guaranteed to be Japan, right?
Uh No, that claimed he was born in Japan.
Uh
-- oh, the, the analysis. OK.
-- No, no, not the announce.
But anyways, this is on the Wikipedia page.
Is it? I didn't read the Wikipedia page. I heard some other things
-- on
-- his P to P foundation.
-- Anyways,
-- we're not gonna, we're not gonna do it.
Yeah.
No, it's, it's,
that's, that's one thing that, yeah,
when you can tell if it's a single coherent voice or
25, 10, 100 whatever
number of people.
That's right.
And now the tie back to this, that really, I guess tickled my fancy back in the day
was when people were using this sort of technology to do analysis of hacking groups
and
like ransomware groups and,
and all of these nefarious groups and basically ask
them questions like who is actually behind this.
And this is where they could identify, like the author of this
English paragraph
is
Russian or they're Eastern European or they're probably from this country.
And that kind of stuff just fascinated me.
Person speaking. Russian is actually Romanian or Polish or whatever.
That's right. Exactly. Exactly. That stuff. And there's something I can't find
and, and I've been trying, I've been, I've spent like,
three days trying to figure this out.
But if I, I vaguely recall
an instance of
there was a hacking group back in the, it wasn't a hacker group but like a,
a security research group
-- that was doing.
-- Oh, was it eight little Green Men? Was it?
I don't know.
-- I don't remember, but it was basically,
-- remember they,
they took a hard run at HP and they just churned stuff out
and I remember talking about them and I was like this, if this is one,
like in hindsight, it always smelled like a group.
Right. Right. And that, that's, that's exactly it. I don't know if it was that group.
I can't remember anymore.
It was basically someone did the analysis and was like, this is not,
not a researcher, this is a group of people that are specifically targeting this.
And then there of course, were rumors about, oh, well, it's,
it's his country or it's his company doing the work or whatever.
And
it's just fascinating that
we as humans like to believe that we can hide behind aliases,
that we can write things with pseudonyms.
And the reality is if you have a presence on the internet in any meaningful way,
which many of us do now, thanks to blogs and social media
and whatever,
there's almost no way to hide who you are from.
-- A we'll say reasonably competent adversary,
-- you don't know,
like there's youtube videos on like os
courses basically that are half an hour long and it shows you how to
like dig up everybody's public profiles and then find their less public ones like,
you know, linkedin is a great example.
It's, it takes a little bit of digging, but you can find people on linkedin like the,
the, you know, obviously starting with their name and then there's like 10 billion,
you know,
John Smith.
OK?
Like if you got a city or a company or anything,
you can narrow it down real quick and get to their linkedin, get to their, you know,
previous, like I said, there's youtube videos that talk about how to do this,
you know, it's,
you don't even have to be that confident, you just need
a little bit of time and basic knowledge.
-- You
-- need some resources and because
not everyone has time to actually do all this.
And like, here's an example, let's say someone starts publishing something
as a pseudonym.
And you're like, I wonder who that really is. Right
now, you have to collect a huge corpus of information process,
that information process,
the writings of the anonymous individual and then try to figure out who it is like,
that needs some skill. It's different of saying
I'm going to track down Kurt
and figure out where he lives.
That's one thing because you're a specific target.
-- But if you're just trying to do like a, a casting a wide net, then you need
-- resources.
Well, I think this is the difference between I know who I'm looking for versus,
ok, like, uh a middle aged, a middle aged white male of average height and weight,
right? And if you know the name, you can
like easily, Kurt is very tall if you've ever met him, I'm not very tall,
I'm 6 ft one and a bunch.
You're taller than me. I'm, I'm average height, literally average height.
But that's, and that's the thing though, right?
Is, again, it's like all these police investigations where it's like, ok, well,
it was a red pickup truck.
Ok.
We're just gonna have to go visit every single one of them
in the city and work for damage to the front vendor.
And that's the thing with Stom
Mery is it changes it from, like I have to
cast, you know, I have to figure out it's, oh, you know, here's the top 10 matches.
0, 10. I can do 10. Right. But I can't do a million.
Yeah.
And I'll, I'll put another link in the show notes. I, I have one other point.
I want to bring up before we, we kind of miss it is
there, there's a video I found from Ted Ted Ed.
I think it is where they talk about William Shakespeare.
And obviously you can imagine
William Shakespeare has had
stom Mery applied to the writings at length.
You know, what's wild to me is they're applying stom
to the translated writings. And I'm like, uh
wouldn't you have to apply it to the originals?
And, and that is a very reasonable,
reasonable complaint. And, and, but, but so here's in the Ted Ed video.
They basically said that
when you create like the what I forget what they call it.
It's like the fancy graph they use when they're doing stom
Mery to, to decide like, what,
how,
how are we gonna categorize the writings like the words
used and how often they're used and things like that.
And basically Shakespeare is Shakespeare. And when they've tried to
compare some of the
proposed like pseudonyms where like real people
using William Shakespeare as their name,
like their writings didn't fit and it's like this is really cool actually because
there have been
countless examples of people making, you know, claims about.
Oh, so and so was really Shakespeare.
This person did a lot of the writing or whatever,
like it's not holding up to this sort of analysis,
-- which I find really cool
-- because my understanding
is Tom Clancy wrote his original books,
but then he got like a stable of writers to
Cranko's books and he would basically provide an outline and
the stable of writers.
Have you seen how many books he's written?
I mean, I know it's a lot,
I don't really pay that close of attention to what he's doing well.
Well, and in fairness though, like Isaac
Asimov cranked out like 500 books.
-- It's a big list, but he was a prolific writer. Give it
-- Asimov
-- wrote for 50 years. Like, yeah,
-- well, still 10 books a year. That's a lot of books.
Well, novels, short stories, whatever. There's a lot of writing them are short.
Yeah, still,
I just remember when I was a kid,
the section at the library of Isaac Asimov was like multiple linear feet.
I know it's awesome, you know.
But like, for example, Tom Clancy,
I would wonder like also kind of how abstract can it be?
Like, I know that they have code style
Lawry. But I wonder especially now with like the tools perfect example.
Like I'm writing a bunch of javascript and I tend to use Python style naming like,
like
square bracket, full quote name, full quote,
square back instead of like bla dot blah.
Right.
Yeah.
And,
and that's just because I'm a Python person and I
need to become more of a Java script person.
So, I mean, that would be an easy way to identify that.
-- This code, this terrible, terrible code was written by me.
-- Well, and that's just it.
Right.
So everything you do leaves a fingerprint,
it doesn't matter if it's Twitter messages.
If it's a code you write, if it's
blog posts, you write,
it's, it's what humans do, right?
And now we have these means to uncover who people are.
Well, and at scale like it's not just a 1 to 1,
but it's like
again back to, yeah, I just downloaded all of hacker news,
put it on an M two drive and fit it into my video card, right?
Why is this so hard?
Exactly.
And now you have to think
there's also other data that can be brought into this.
And this is where when you start talking about
an organization like the NSA or the FBI,
where they have like infinite compute at their disposal.
Essentially,
when you can take something like the writings of Satoshi Nakamura,
and you combine that
with all the data we have from the IP space, we've been sniffing for decades.
And you combine that with,
you know, who's posting at what time and how,
and like I have no doubt they could untangle that web if they wanted to.
-- They, they, they might have and they just won't tell us
-- also narrow.
Like, it's always all
about,
uh, well, for law enforcement,
it's oftentimes about that parallel construction of like,
either we know the person who did it but we
can't through some way that we can't use in court.
So we have to parallel discovery or
like, yeah, we just like, who's the Unabomber? We have no damn clue. Ok.
What do we do now?
And then we narrow it down and get a search warrant and it turns out because, you know,
that's the thing, like, pretty,
uh,
criminals by and large are not these criminal masterminds.
No. Right.
Like real criminal masterminds do white collar crime.
Like they do what I'm making air quotes here. White collar crime.
They do things that aren't even illegal yet.
Like some, like the early crypto scams or Kickstarter scams where it's like,
-- but it's FT
-- X.
-- Yeah.
-- Like it's not a crime. It's just,
it's sharp business or it's, uh, didn't you read the fine print about no guarantees?
Right. No, absolutely.
And that's one of the, I,
I have that conversation with my kids every now and then be like, oh, you know,
this criminal or whatever, I'm like, look,
the best criminals are running enterprise sales
organizations because they're making a fortune,
like, overcharging people for crap. They don't need
it.
I just,
I just bought a 23 battery for my garage door opener. It's literally
a AAA battery cut in half and it costs $12 at the store.
Actually, they
are not AAA batteries cut in half. Take it apart.
It has like four batteries inside of it or something.
-- It's the
-- same coin cells as a AAA. Basically,
it's just half
of them.
Right.
You gotta love it. Whatever. It's 12 blocks to live with it.
It's the modern conveniences of life we have to deal with.
Ok.
So anyway, we're,
we're running ourselves out of time and we haven't got
to any of the things I wanted to talk about,
which is normal.
But I think here is the overall point of
this conversation and why I was excited about it
is
when we put on our security hats,
we love to think we have this like ability to hide
or kind of anonymize ourselves on the internet
and we don't.
And I think that's what makes this terrifying and exciting at the same time is
the fact that if I create a sock puppet account on Reddit or something,
if someone wanted to, they could figure out it was me.
Well, I mean, just,
you'd have to either use GP T three or
run it through Google translate twice or something to mangle
it
enough to make it
different than you.
I wonder if that works.
Uh I suspect it would,
to some degree
in that you would
essentially your traces would get overwritten by Google's traces.
Like a bird example is I write and I use grammarly.
And so obviously, like, I, I literally will open up a piece of work
and it is clear and grammarly and I'm like, oh,
the other party obviously is grammarly because it stands clear, right?
And then what's funny is
like, my,
one of my editors will go through and make
a bunch more changes and it's not totally clear,
clear and grammarly, but it is better.
So I'm like, OK, the human is still sometimes a bit better than grammarly. Sure.
But I suspect like by running it through,
translate or like grammar check kind of things you would,
it would mask the traces
but it, like there would, there'd be less traces, they'd be harder to find,
but I suspect they would still be there.
And if you haven't enough data and enough elastic search instances, you know,
and enough patients to collect it all.
And that's the thing people forget. Right?
Is these, these government agencies, they just storage is cheap.
Oh, it's very cheap. Yes,
it might not be useful now.
But 30 years from now we got to figure out who's writing this crazy Manifesto,
you know, and that's the thing, the
offset of this. It's not just enough to do the
offset of this going forward, but you have to have ideally done it before.
Like, apparently this is one of the reasons the NSA loves Mormons
because they have no social media profiles. Oh, I suppose.
Right.
And, and that's what I was thinking about that the other day.
I'm like, how are you going to have like, spies
when I can, like, take their picture, run it against?
Uh oh, what was that American company, for example, that, you know,
mined Facebook for photos and was clear light or something.
Anyways,
you know, how are you going to have a spy when I can take a picture of the spy,
run it through like all the Facebook photos and be like, oh, here he is at 16.
Right. Right.
Yeah.
Yeah, I mean,
these are really good points and I think this is really interesting from, I mean,
I'm not qualified to comment on the way that's being done because I'm,
I bet they've got some plans.
Right. Like
-- the intelligence agencies aren't morons.
-- No, no. But it, it, how do you
have, well, or another example is with biometrics,
how do you have people have multiple,
you know, fake identities?
Well,
you can issue fake identities using like the US government can
issue all the fake passports they want by fake passports.
I don't mean like fake passwords, I mean, real passports but like,
that's not their date of birth and name
-- really.
-- Right.
But I think you're too, I think you're too deep.
What I'm trying to say is like sock puppet accounts on Reddit
and that's what I'm saying though. Is like, you,
you definitely have writings online before you try to mask them.
And so
again, that's the other thing is it doesn't have to match 100%.
Like when you use this stom
Mery tool with hacker news, it's like, well, here's the person and here's like the,
the closest 20 matches,
then
you could look at them, look at time zones, look at,
you know, blah, blah, blah, like sentiment analysis or, you know,
are they pro or against emacs or V I, you know,
whatever
and get those other clues. But the thing is
now you're looking at a list of 20 people instead of everyone on hacker news.
And again,
I can do 20 people. I can't do
an analysis of, you know, V I versus E A
sentiment for everybody.
Well, actually you could, it's really easy because they're all wrong.
They'll tell you.
-- Exactly. Yeah,
-- they're not gonna hide it there.
But, I mean, and that's the thing, right? It's all about this.
It's like industrial fishing, right? It's,
yeah, we just put a really big net out there and sure we killed, you know,
a couple dozen dolphins.
But, eh, what are you gonna do? Right.
I
-- guess that's one way to look at it,
-- you know, and again, I'm, I'm not, I'm,
I'm pro dolphin, but the point is like,
normally we didn't have this ability to do this industrial data mining on our own.
And now, like on a Mac M two.
You can like the, the CP US are crazy fast for this kind of work.
Right. Well, and so here's part of the interesting aspect of this
story, Stylo is not new, it's from the 18 hundreds,
right? It was when they say an Irishman, I forget who it it's in the TED video,
but
they talk about where this came from
and
back in those days they had to do this by hand,
right?
Like they didn't have computers and I think
computers have now created this environment that,
that unmasks anyone who you might want to unmask, which is terrifying and,
and maybe a little exciting.
I don't know. But
in anyway,
it, it reminds me of,
I love those examples people show on Twitter where someone
thought they were using their alt account and they were
and stuff like that and it's like, oh, that's so good. It's so good. And it's so funny.
-- Uh uh like
-- a perfect example of this is a
lot of jurisdictions now use biometrics on their identification,
not so much to identify who you are, but to essentially have one per customer.
Like we issued a driver's license to this fingerprint and now this
fingerprints trying to get a different driver's license and a different name.
Nope.
Nah, naughty.
And
you know
that
I would,
I, I wish Twitter had done that because you could have like, consoled.
Like how awesome would Twitter have been if they'd been like, oh,
this account is also related to these other 15 accounts
that also seem to use a VPN through Russia just saying, you know,
I kind of labeled that on the thing because
like, there's so much,
it's like spam, I get spammed to my inbox and I'm like, Google,
how did you not spam this?
There's like, come on,
you know,
something's going wrong and somehow the Attackers are getting this stuff through
and I wish Twitter had
made a bit more effort here because
like, Twitter could have been
amazing and it was amazing. But
like, yeah, the Russian troll
farms and stuff, like when you,
when you look at some of the people that post and the responses and just the, you know,
the vitriol and everything, it's just like, it's brutal
and
I, I can't help but think stom Mery on Mastodon might lead to some really interesting
uh
consequences.
Maybe. I don't know. I don't know.
I mean,
you could probably get
access to a lot more data on Mastodon if you wanted to.
Yeah, it's very, I mean, Twitter sort of was the Twitter api could would,
would be finicky at times.
Well, with Mastodon, you could,
you could run 100 instances and set up 100 sock puppets and
just follow huge piles of people and get all their stuff.
Yeah, you could, I mean, that, that's still a lot of work though. But I, I bet you can.
Well, that's fair. That's fair. And, and they probably know this stuff.
But, but anyway,
I guess it's time to go
and I don't really have a great takeaway for this show other
than I think Silom Mery is super exciting and interesting and I,
I love the, the work people have done.
I can't wait to see kind of what comes next.
So, a part of me is terrified because anonymity is already such a valuable thing.
And it's difficult
to even pretend
you can be anonymous if you want to be because someone can,
can tie this back to you in some way.
But
at the, at the same time it's,
it's very cool research and it's very interesting.
I think like a lot of things,
it'll lead to some totally unpredictable consequences that are probably
not as bad as we'd hoped in some ways,
maybe worse, like unmasking the true author of, you know,
whoever is leading a protest in some country with an authoritarian government.
I'm sure they do that, which is
bad.
Well,
we think it's bad because we don't live in the authoritarian government.
Well, the thing is we, we,
we went through this growth pain 100 and 5200 years ago in the western world.
-- I mean,
-- well, we're still going through it.
I mean, we don't have all this solved and I think this is one of those places.
I know, I, I say this a lot but like our
regular, our privacy regulations have not kept pace with reality even a little bit.
And,
and this is going to be one of the challenges
I think going into the future is we literally,
we have to solve some of these problems because
it's like a freaking free for all out there.
You know,
like there's a reason
that police can't just come in your house and search
your stuff whenever they want because they used to do that
and people were like, this is bad. Let's not do this anymore.
You know, and, and this is like,
this is the internet now is anyone can search your stuff anytime they want and,
and you can make the argument. Oh, just don't use the internet.
But that's obviously absurd.
So,
yeah, it's, I don't know, man, it, it's wild times for sure.
Clearview, clearview, face recognition. That's the one. Sorry.
It was bugging.
Glad we sorted that out.
But it's, well, but it's a perfect example of like, well,
these people published all this data publicly.
Why can't clear view, just grab it and use it, you know,
and the answer is because there's some really,
really potentially bad consequences.
Right. Right. Yes.
You know.
Well, and it's like anything, right?
It can be used for good or it can be used for bad or both.
Usually both.
It reminds me of open source coding in that
something that was basically
rocket science impossible. Like in 1940 is now like,
yeah, just download this library and run it on your,
like GP U enabled computer with at least 64 gigs of ra M.
That's
true. Actually, that does make it,
-- it's exciting for me as a nerd.
-- It goes back to that security tool podcast episode.
We did,
like, it's just all of a sudden,
like when you think about the security tools
we have nowadays compared to 20 years ago.
Good, sweet Jiminy.
No, I, I know, I think about that all the time. Like I can do things on my laptop now
that I couldn't imagine a
-- decade ago even I
-- processed 100 and eight videos using FFM peg on
my laptop in 25 minutes while I was writing code on it.
Right. It's, it's
like
-- magic.
-- Welcome to the future.
Everything's terrible.
But the internet is fast.
That's true. I have Gigabit Internet, whatever.
I'm
cutting this off. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you
for listening. Go
over our security podcast.com. Hit up the show now. It's Suzy Pound
Os, that's podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks
everybody.
I'm just trying to break up the
so you can analyze me
whatever, whatever. Alright. I'm hitting stop now for real.
The