Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 70 with myself,
Kurt Siegfried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
So, did you hear that Minix is now the most deployed operating system in the world?
Uh, yeah. Yeah.
Although I'm wondering if, what's that real time thing from Japan called Tron?
-- I thought that was on more embedded systems.
-- It might be, I don't know. This is,
but no, definitely mics. I mean, the fact that it's on,
um, well, I guess every piece of Intel hardware in the last,
-- the
-- last couple of years it sounds like.
-- Uh, no, because Intel me came out in 2008. Yeah. But
-- I don't, didn't run
mics at first. I don't know.
-- Did
-- they rewrite it to run?
I would assume they just pick something and went with that. Maybe
-- it's, who knows?
-- Regardless.
Or maybe they wrote something themselves and went, wow, that was terrible.
And then they went to mic
-- that,
-- that could be. It's,
that's crazy. I mean, where do we even start with this?
Like, what is Minix, what is in until me? How does this work? Why do we care?
There's just,
oh, man.
So for some context, I mean, Minnix
came before Linux,
right?
So, Minnix is like your great, great, great grandfather basically in UNIX terms,
you know, it's not the origin but it's very close to the origin.
Yeah. Yeah.
And, and Linux,
-- I think, could trace a dotted line. It's a
-- direct descendant. Uh,
and, and sort of,
um, well, it was a direct response to Linux.
Yeah. His first email.
I'm working on a Minix clone. That's true.
That's true. Like it's straight up like
it's, it's, I don't know, the mutant offshoot of
MX, basically
offshoot.
Uh
Yes,
I would agree with that 100%.
So.
Yeah. No. So, I mean, the beauty of mini is, it's, it's a very
old,
well understood,
you know, very well architected, very well built, little like,
and with emphasis on little operating system.
Um And apparently Intel, uh actually even got the memory footprint much,
much lower,
which, you know,
matters if you're making like a billion devices and you
can save like a couple megs of memory that,
-- that
-- does happen, even saving a couple megs of memory.
I mean, this is essentially like a hidden secret operating system.
You need to keep it small and you need to keep it out of the way.
Um And then of course,
like all pieces of software turns out it's a flaming pile of garbage.
That's,
we'll get to that.
I, I know. Anyway. Anyway. So,
so I guess to add to this pile,
it became clear
in, in recent weeks, we'll say, because this has kind of been building
that
Intel has taken minutes.
They've made it very tiny and they're running it inside of
every one of their CP US as what we call the,
the Intel Management engine.
And the idea is
people want the ability to
conduct certain management operations on systems.
And
if the system is powered off or sometimes even
you could have a system that's doing something,
I,
I don't know that that the operating system is incompatible or
you just don't want to muck with the operating system,
-- you
-- can use.
Great example being um
I had some as
I motherboards and if you wanted to update the bio,
you had to run a Windows utility.
There is a story that
although I, I think it was a think pad, I had at one time, they distributed a
like a flash drive image.
You could just dump onto a flash drive and then boot off
-- of it and it updated the firmware which is
-- really the free do
based one. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
There were some that did a free dos based one which was nice because yeah,
you just dumped.
Yeah, you
boot
-- image boop. Done.
-- Right. Right. It was cool.
But obviously that doesn't scale when you have 10,000 workstations and
it does not.
And, and so I guess this is the intent of the management engine.
But the, the downfall being
you now have what is essentially a,
a super amazing back door into every system running at
what we call ring minus three. That seems to be what the term I read.
But basically if you think of ring zero as super user ring minus one is like the bios
ring minus three is the, yeah, nobody knows I'm here
and I can, you know, it's, it's like existing in the fourth dimension, right?
-- You can manipulate the third dimension.
-- Yeah.
Well, and it has like wake on L A capability and stuff so that it can like, you know,
you can talk to it over, you can basically talk to a dead computer
over the network and tell it to update its bios, which is pretty freaking amazing.
And,
and the
point that is a feature people need,
right?
Like you think about like a university with 10,000 machines,
you want to do bios updates,
right?
You can just put them all out at 3 a.m.
And this is the fundamental problem with all
these orchestration products like in the cloud,
for example, you know,
you need to be able to control and manage this stuff at scale.
But that means that your control and management system is now a huge,
-- huge
-- risk. Well, and what really is annoying. A lot of people is
you can't turn off intel me
it's just,
well, it's complicated but we'll say fundamentally you can't
normal people can't turn it off
even you. And I would probably struggle with it. I did,
I probably brick the machine.
Yeah, probably
something like apparently Google is seriously looking at
uh getting like replacing.
Well, and here's the thing,
even if you want to replace the intel me stuff with say Linux,
which is something that Google and some other people are working on.
We'll put a link to this really great slide deck in the show notes
even then you can't sort of completely get rid of intel. I
because it also handles some of the hardware initialization
stuff that you kind of can't live without.
You know.
So
yeah,
it's just one of those little, well, I, I think what it boils down to now is
almost everything with software now has a web server
and the tell me is like no exception, right? It has remote management. You can log in.
Apparently the default credentials are admin, admin. So
that's, that's good.
Well, and what else would they be?
Would they, you know, I mean, they could have in theory made each one different. Um
you know, like for example, my cable or not my cable modem.
Uh Well, actually both my cable modem and my DS L modem both come
with a unique
uh Wi Fi password and a unique like admin login.
So, you know, at some point,
either my ISP or the original manufacturer, I assume it's my ISP
like flash these things to get them, you know, ready to go.
And I was part of that process, you know, gave each one a unique password and whatnot.
Um, but again that, you know, when you're making CP US in the terms of millions,
you know,
are you going to put a sticker on CPU saying the password for the Me on this thing is X,
well, if,
yes, I get what you're saying,
it's a huge
scale
of
it.
Yeah.
And this has always been the issue is management and scale. And
anyway, I guess it's interesting
that it's open source.
It's
interesting
that it's running on everything and, you know, it's not going to be secure.
-- Well, it's, it's BS D so it's a BS D license. So it is an open source.
-- It's
Apache two, isn't it?
Uh Well,
regardless the point is Intel doesn't have to
release the changes that they made in house,
right?
Like they would have, for example, the GP L you'd be able to, you know,
write to them and demand a CD with the source code for this thing
uh or whatever, right?
Where, whereas with the minix license, they can make in-house changes,
distribute those binaries and be like, yep, that secret sauce go away.
So, um although apparently they did push back um some changes and they did, you know,
they actually did help Minix improve, you know, with,
like I said,
minimizing the memory footprint and some other changes to make it more modular.
But, yeah, fundamentally, I mean, here's the reality. Right.
It's software so it's flawed.
-- Of course, it's flawed
-- regardless of things like admin,
admin for the password user name.
Right.
I, I just looked, it's BS D license which not that it matters.
They're all basically the same.
Which,
yeah,
send your, send your licensing complaints to Kurt.
I
know. But
I just said they're all the same and they're totally
anyway.
Right.
And I guess the other beauty of this is now that people know it's there and
they, they, they know what it is. They're going to dump it. It,
it is going to happen. Uh,
did they dump the O si don't,
I know that they've connected to the J tag essentially of it.
But
they, they did dump the OS.
Somebody claimed to have dumped it.
-- I thought
-- I,
I've only heard rumors and we've seen a demo of
using a USB device to connect to the management engine,
which is,
that's kind of also crazy in its own. Right? Because
basically
you have this thing wired up.
So anything that plugs into a USB port has the ability
to talk to the secret operating system running in your processor.
Ok. That's neat.
Yeah.
No, my understanding was that while they claim to have dumped the Emmy a few days ago.
Eighth of November.
Um, II, I mean, I don't know that it's been completely confirmed but
it's a matter of time.
It's, if they haven't done it. It will happen at some point.
Oh, yeah, it's totally going to happen and then they're going to look at it
and I'm sure people are going to find problems.
Right. It's, it's inevitable
and, well, and here's, here's kind of the other part of this.
I wonder is, I wonder how difficult it's going to be to update that thing
to make sure
it's not.
Well, yes, but micro
code is applied at boot time.
So if you have this thing off listening for wake on land,
you conceivably have an exploit vector that you can't stop.
So I would hope they have a way to actually flash what's inside the chip, right?
My understanding is the Intel management engine can be updated.
Uh Yeah, it says here.
Uh Yeah, because Intel ships updates for the Me.
-- Now, do you have to install them or do they magically
-- update? Oh, it's like a bio
update basically is my understanding.
I inspect that. Yes.
So this would also
because there was a, there was a thing a few a month or two ago, there was a CV E
for a security flaw in the Intel me stuff that we didn't quite understand.
Um And basically it was to prevent rollback attacks.
So once once essentially once you update the Intel Amy,
you're not supposed to be able to roll it back to an earlier version,
which would really make sense in the context. Now, of what we know about the intel, ay
and having said this, they'll probably never,
ever hire me and put me on some blacklist along with you.
-- Uh, that's
-- ok.
Yeah,
we're not knocking them necessarily. We're just pointing out the irony of all this.
Well, I mean, the problem is we need management at scale and
-- doing truly secure management at scale
-- is impossible.
-- It's not hard, it's impossible, let's say, well,
-- it's,
it's
-- doing, it cost effectively. It's
-- impossible
and securely is impossible. I mean,
no cost,
they had nothing to do with it.
If I gave you all of the money in the world and said,
build a completely secure management engine
at best, you could embezzle the money and run off to a foreign country,
-- for
-- example, some high value items kind of have these like satellites, for example,
you know, satellites are a high value item,
but the thing is there,
we're talking something that costs a couple 100 million bucks.
So yeah, spending, you know, a million dollars on a secure update
system for it totally worth it.
Um, now obviously for Intel, you know, at scale it would,
it would
average
like a penny per unit or whatever, but still
it, it would just be so much overhead and customers would hate it. Right? Because,
you know,
imagine you buy like you buy 1000 systems from Dell and it's kind of like great.
Now, Dell, what's like we need the me passwords for these things and Dell's like, oh,
right.
Uh, we, whatever
that's, you know, extra or,
you know, here's a, here's a printout. Good luck with that. You know,
like, it's just, they're so, like doing,
you know, it always reminds me of things like the, we've just,
we've built a world where, for example, like, there's
hundreds of millions of people running the same web plugins, like ad blockers.
And God forbid those ad blockers ever turn malicious.
It wasn't there an issue where one of them was,
their
system got compromised and they, they distributed a compromised uh
uh
thing for uh it was like four or five days and then Google,
I think blocked it or they updated it or whatever.
Um,
but I mean, that's, you know, that's part of the thing, right? Is like, I mean,
you know, 10 years ago when smart, well, 11 years ago when smartphones came out
right now we're at what I think is 3 billion smartphones globally.
There's a lot,
you know, so that's like 3 billion computers sitting in people's pockets
which are not getting updates for.
There was actually a new story I saw today that said
1 billion Android phones are like hopelessly out of date.
A billion.
I totally believe that it's terrible.
Well, again, the reality is the economics of it.
You know, somebody sold that phone, why would they support it?
You already gave them your money. What are you going to do? Return it?
Well, this is even true.
I mean, this is part of the story of kind of this Intel Management engine. Right. So
they take open source
and they put it in their product and there's nothing wrong with it.
But now the question kind of becomes, are they paying attention to it?
Are they updating it? Do we know what's in it? Are they building it securely?
They've been shipping Intel
-- em, me, updates on a pretty regular basis for the last few years.
-- And that is good.
And I'm glad they are.
So, they definitely have engineering resources behind this thing.
It's not being ignored.
And, and I mean, in Intel's case,
I know a lot of Intel people and I'm confident they're going to do this the right way.
But for every Intel,
there are probably 1000 other companies that don't really care.
Well, all of the IOT
space.
Right. Right. And that was outside
-- of a
-- few players.
There was, there was another story I read, I forget who even wrote this.
It might have been Schneer
Krebs.
But they basically point out the fact that like
the IOT is never going to be secure because
let's face it if you walk into the store
and there's a $400 toothbrush and there's a $4 toothbrush
and,
and the $400.01 has security and that's the only
difference you're going to buy the $4 toothbrush.
Right.
I mean, just end of story and, and it's even the same deal with these chips and stuff is
so Intel makes a chip and let's say they decide like, screw it. We don't care anymore.
We're just never gonna update Intel. I me.
Well, what do you do now? Right.
Nothing. You're gonna stop buying Intel chips.
No, you're gonna keep buying them and,
and actually that's another interesting story is
what happened. I mean, not that, not that I hope it happens very often.
But what happens if people have like 10 year old CP US? Are those gonna get updates?
-- Um, who knows?
-- I mean, I,
I,
I, I generally,
the good news is,
uh, here's one of the best pieces of news ever for this security thing
is that
most modern hardware is so much more
like energy efficient person basically work unit,
right?
Because either the,
it's a lot faster or, you know, it can do more instructions per cycle or for example,
like SSD store,
you know, um,
they store data at an energy cost.
Like, what is it like 0.05 watts compared to a spinning hard drive at like five watts,
right?
That
essentially there's a huge incentive
for most large scale operators to upgrade their
hardware every couple of years because it just,
it, like my understanding is like S sds in the data center
basically pay for themselves in like 6 to 12 months because of the
cost
or that's like, actually I remember when flat screen TV, S came out
and the power use was substantially less than AC RT. And I did the math once
and realized that by even if you only watch your
TV for something like two or three hours a day,
it basically a flat panel paid for itself in something like a year.
Well, I remember mentioning
to you, my parents' cabin has like a 70 AMP feed and you're like, oh,
you should upgrade that.
And I'm like, why? Well, literally
the only thing we have that uses power there is like the coffee maker in the microwave
and then like we plug in some tablets that draw,
I don't know, 20 watts.
Yeah, but you probably can't run the microwave and coffee maker at the same time,
which could be dangerous.
Yeah. Well, it's, we just got to get up early.
But, um,
I mean, fundamentally like, II, I look in my house now and I was uh
thinking, you know, do I need to upgrade the wiring here?
And the answer is no, because we
apart from like the stove in the microwave,
we don't have anything that draws a lot of power anymore.
I've actually, I don't have desktops anymore.
Well, I have two Mac minis and that's it.
But I guess the Mac minis are, you know, my quote
unquote biggest computer,
-- everything else is laptop,
-- a
giant computer.
It is when I record this podcast on even and it consumes an enormous amount of power
because it's got like four hard drives in it and a huge CPU and tons of ra M
-- and a giant
-- video even compared to the old time stuff.
It's still only drawing like 3, 400 watts.
Probably.
Here's the thing that's crazy to think about when you and I were kids.
-- How many 60 watt light bulbs did your house have?
-- Oh man. Hundreds.
Like everything had a 60 watt light bulb in it.
We just finished buying, like,
we've replaced every single light fixture and light
bulb in this house with one exception.
And, you know, the, the new led light bulbs are like,
quite a bit more expensive than the old timey filament bulbs.
But the thing is I'm going to buy them once and then maybe 2030 years from now
we'll move and then I'll buy a new set of light bulbs for the new place.
You need to unless someone hasn't already replaced them all.
Yeah.
You know, like these things have lifetimes of like, what, $22,000 or something.
And that's the other concern
with IOT stuff. Right. People buy a TV, with, you know,
they expect to, to, for five or 10 years.
You know, when I, now, when I buy a light bulb with like a 22,000 hour lifespan,
I'm expecting that thing to run for 10 or 20 years,
you know, and
I was tempted to buy some IKEA light bulbs that have, um,
uh, their iot light bulbs basically, they either have a remote,
I think it's Bluetooth
or you can control them from a phone app.
And, you know, I've held off on that because I kind of want to see, you know,
security wise.
Well, I've heard the IKEA ones are pretty good. I think it's, uh,
let's see, Matthew Garrett has been tearing up iot light bulbs
and at some point doing, you know,
security analysis and you can imagine they're almost all terrible,
but I'm pretty sure the IKEA ones
he didn't say are completely terrible. Right. I'm sure they're not
right.
Less bad. That's,
that's as good as they
-- get.
-- There's not completely terrible.
Right. Right.
And I, I have a feeling that IKEA cares
-- because,
-- well, they definitely have a brand to protect. Right.
They're not like some fly by night company.
I mean, repainting all those stores,
stores alone would cost several million dollars.
Yes.
That's right.
And the meatballs. Right. Don't forget those
delicious,
-- you know, I've never
-- had those.
And at this point I don't think I ever will just to prove a point.
Right. It's, it's like
I've never seen an episode of Silicon Valley
and I feel like if I did,
I would be ruining something because I can be like the
guy in the room that says I've never seen that show.
I don't know what you're talking about.
And then people look at me like there's something wrong with me.
Well, speaking of not knowing what we're talking about.
Have you heard about the other thing Equifax does
they know my salary even though I didn't tell them that. And
yeah,
and how they sell that data for, apparently it's 20 bucks.
-- I'm not even a
-- little surprised, man. I mean, look, here's the thing,
all of these big data organizations and in this, I'll tie back to the Facebook.
Listens to your microphone thing where
there was, there was an obviously the news story talking about,
oh Facebook listens to the microphone in your
phone and then someone replied eventually and said
they don't have to like they know this stuff about you and and I mean,
the Equifax thing is the same deal, right?
Even if they don't know exactly what my salary is,
I guarantee they can look at all the data they have
and probably get it within like 10 or $20,000 right?
Like this is just, this is the reality of of big data
is
I I remember when
uh what was it? Was it prism where the NSA was caught recording a bunch of con
or no, they weren't recording conversations, they were capturing metadata,
right?
That was a big excuse of,
oh it's just metadata and it's I I think
people have come to realize now that thanks to all
of these algorithms and all of these storage facilities and
and applications we have now metadata is enormously powerful,
you can take metadata and infer
things with incredible accuracy about people. I
mean, it's crazy and
you know what I love about it all too is,
is I look at all this and I think about everything going on and it's like
everything we see
all of the thing, all this crazy has been built on the back of open source,
right? Like this is never what anyone intended or hoped it would turn into.
And it's like
I feel like this is one of the wishes from
a genie I wish open source is used everywhere.
It's like poof,
you got your wish.
Well, and part of it too is this is the stuff we currently know about.
-- I'm sure there's even more.
-- Oh, right.
Because a place like Equifax is never going to tell you all the data they collect.
I mean, that's part of their power, right?
Is, is knowing secret things about people that,
that people don't even know about themselves
because one thing that just happened in the last week,
that's interesting is so in Canada,
we have what's called cr A Canada Revenue Agency and it it's the tax people,
they just got a federal warrant
for paypal
for every
business account holder
of Canadian origin on paypal
data from 2014 to 2017.
And it is the full name of every individual or
corporation holding a business account that has a Canadian address,
the date of birth of each individual holding a business account, the business name,
if applicable,
the telephone numbers on the or of the
corporation or individuals holding the business account,
the full addresses,
the email address is the social insurance number.
And here's the best part,
the total number and value of received transactions for each
calendar year between January 1 2014 and November 10th,
and
the total number and
uh the total number and value of sent transactions
uh for the same period. So,
because I'm guessing there's a lot of people that thought ha ha I'll use paypal,
-- they're an American firm and I'm not going to declare this
-- income.
Well, ok, I see two things. I see hiding income as part of it. But I,
if they're, if they're looking for revenue in and out,
they're probably also going to find money laundering as part of that.
Yes. Well, and it's curious though, it's just the business accounts right now.
It's not personal accounts, right? So when you open up a, a Compal
account, essentially, almost everybody opens up a personal account
and you can upgrade it to a business account,
you have to jump through a couple of hoops, right?
You have to prove that you are that business and blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, right?
Are the higher limits. I don't even know what the difference is.
Yeah, there's higher limits and you, well, back in the day you got a bit more.
Um they had some capabilities for businesses
that weren't available on personal accounts.
Um, you know, it was, it was, it was really like, it was really aimed at the, the,
the volume sellers on ebay.
-- Right.
-- Right. And, and in fact, that's all I've ever used paypal for was paying.
Oh
man, I've got a great story. So, so for Halloween,
I was a rabbit, a white rabbit
and
I needed ears.
So
I ordered bunny ears off of ebay for $5. Right?
And uh they showed up like a week ago because the seller
demanded a signature and I kept missing the postman every time.
Yeah. Right. For a $5 item. I'm like, what,
-- what is wrong with
-- you? I
refuse that because quite frankly, it's more hassle than it's worth,
you know, I should have
a
$5
who cares?
Well,
-- and
-- part of me was thinking there's no way you're
going to request a signature on a $5 item.
I bet this is something else I ordered
and, and they just never sent the bunny ears.
No bunny ears.
That's one reason I like Amazon. They just throw my packages.
I know. Seriously.
I mean, yes, if I'm buying a eight super expensive TV or something,
great request a signature.
I'm fine with that.
I know they don't,
I've had stuff left behind my snow shovel with the door mat on the back porch.
Honestly,
I, I was having this discussion, but basically
when you think about, like, yeah, package stuff happens,
like we discussed this last time and I think the,
the rate is low enough that quite honestly it doesn't really matter.
I guarantee it doesn't.
-- Right.
-- You know.
So, but anyways, it's curious to see that the revenue Canada, you know,
is
what I'm more shocked about is that revenue Canada did not do this sooner.
Yeah,
I can, I can agree with that. I wonder,
I'm,
I'm guessing it might be part of one of those Panama papers or what's the other,
those leaks that they're discovering
that, you know, maybe some, because for example,
I used to have a contract but I got paid through paypal.
-- So it was quite a bit of money on a yearly basis, right? And I declared
-- it all
personal account.
Uh,
it was personal or business.
I forget I flipped to business at some point so long ago I don't even remember. Right.
But, you know, I
like most tax places you declare every penny because if
they find you not declaring every penny then they,
you know, come down on you like a sack.
Seriously, man.
Like, yeah, just don't, I, I never mess with taxes and II, I know people that,
you know, they'll, they'll always be like, oh, what about this?
And you can do this and that and this,
and it's like I'm gonna make maybe $100 if I do those things and
if I get audited I'm going to be probably paying $4000 to attorneys.
It's just, it is not the return on investment. There is not worth it.
But, uh, no, I'm really curious because I was thinking about what, there's a lot of,
sort of paypal like entities now online,
like there's a lot of these sort of online banks.
Um,
you know, ing, being a great example. Right. It's, it's an online bank.
-- They, as far as I know, have zero branches,
-- they were bought by capital one
because I used to use ING
and now
now I'm a capital one customer and I'm too lazy to move.
There are online only banks, there are
with respect to the Equifax salary thing. I mean
the frustrating part here is, is that
again, apparently you can opt out of this um
but you have to phone or mail them or email them and of course, you know,
the process is not going to be simple.
And here's the problem.
A lot of places use a salary check for actually legitimate good reasons.
Like for example, uh if you want to rent a property,
you know,
it kind of makes sense that they might want to check
your salary that you actually can afford to pay for this because
um something that's recently come up in the news this
week in Canada is like all these sort of landlord
tenant horror stories where the tenants, you know,
totally mess with the landlords and they know the law enough that they
can prolong the process for six months and then finally get booted out,
you know,
and there was this article on the CBC about
this guy who like rented out three apartments,
used a, like, he basically
provided a credit report but he like had cut and paste, you know,
change the info to show a good credit score,
you know.
So now they're saying like, landlords shouldn't take credit reports from people,
they should like run it themselves.
I mean, I think that's a given and, and even in the context of
your, your pay, I know anytime I've rented things in the past
they demanded for, for long periods of time,
they demanded like two or three paychecks, you know,
the last two or three paychecks or whatever
steps to prove that I actually have income.
The problem is those can easily be forged.
Yeah, they can be forged, but that's fraud, right? I mean,
so
I'm going to tie this back to security because I'm
actually dealing with some similar problems as this is,
those are two different problems, fraud
and it is a a that is a crime on its own, right?
And so
you do need a certain amount of due diligence,
but you can't expect every single person in every process to,
to handle every possible scenario.
I mean, let's face it.
-- There's always what they're
-- suggesting here, for example,
is rather than the person providing the Equifax printout is that, you know,
you go to Equifax and run there and like you basically get their name,
social insurance number and you go to Equifax,
pay the 20 bucks and get the information directly from Equifax.
-- Ok. You know, so that, you know, it's quote unquote,
-- correct.
If, if that's your prerogative,
I don't see a problem with that. Right.
But, but even if you do that, you aren't going to stop fraud.
-- Right?
-- Well, no, no, no.
What, what I'm trying to point out basically is that we're moving from.
So traditionally, whenever I've rented,
they've always been happy with a printout of
the credit report whenever they ask for that.
But we're moving now to a system where they'll want enough personal
information about you to call up Equifax and get your data.
But do you trust some random landlord to protect your personal information?
Because by definition,
they're going to have to ask enough
about you to essentially perform identity theft,
right? So we're basically trading one problem for a new set of problems.
And that's my biggest concern around this thing is that,
you know, the landlords by and large, uh depending on the market, you know,
some markets, the landlords have less power because there's, you know,
low uh high vacancy rates, right?
And then other markets like,
um
you know, there's like a very, very low vacancy rate.
So, you know,
I'm gonna make you jump through hoops that
might expose your personal information to the world.
Well,
somebody's gonna have to be willing to do that because they need to live somewhere,
you know,
and that's my concern is we end up with this sort of,
you know, diffuse personal information floating around everywhere and it kind of,
you know, goes back to this.
Well,
I think we're sort of already there
a
long time ago, man.
Um,
again,
I've definitely rented from companies now that in hindsight,
I really wouldn't trust with, you know,
much of my personal information.
Um I remember there's this one local computer store that wanted a
copy of my driver's license for me to buy stuff there.
And I'm talking about stuff like a mouse and using a debit card. And I was like, no
absolute like II, I
walked out of the store and drove, you know,
another 10 minutes to the apple store where they'll
just take my money and let me leave.
Um But, you know, this is my concern is that on the one hand,
I get that landlords want to and need to protect themselves from,
you know, these sort of nightmare tenants.
But now, you know, we have every single tenant on the planet, you know,
having to give up their personal information to rent
a place and exposing themselves to identity fraud.
Because um the,
the real problem is uh talking about this Equifax salary thing
is they use what's called knowledge based authentication where
they ask you information about yourself to authenticate you.
Right. Because you don't have an account with Equifax,
right? They just have a copy of all your data.
Well, how do you prove that? You're Josh,
you have an account with Equifax. Funny you say that
when you, when you freeze your credit,
you are given essentially a login,
but that's for the credit stuff though. Not for the salary.
Yeah. I don't know. Maybe it doesn't matter.
Right.
I know what you mean though because I've,
I've answered questions like this in the past where they ask, you know,
what are your last three addresses or?
You know what, who, whose name is on your pay stub or?
Yeah, crazy stuff like that. And
yeah.
Yeah, you got to love it.
And thanks to big data, none of it's a secret.
Well, and also thanks to the way these companies operate,
I can now use that information to assume your identity.
Uh
Maybe
you can't unlock my credit yet
but
you talking
about. So the
problem is if you, for example, do freeze your salary reports,
you may not be able to rent an apartment or something that, you know,
for somebody that wants to do a salary check on you.
You know, how do you deal with that now? Right. And so it's,
they're,
they're sort of letting people take a secure option but that secure
option in the modern world is such a giant pain in the.
-- But
-- yeah, but no man, I mean, that, that's not a valid argument.
I mean, this would be like going to the bank and getting a loan and saying
I can't check my credit, they're going to say great, then we're not giving you a loan.
Right?
That's what I mean. Right. Is
you want to take these security measures and you
won't be able to participate in the modern world.
Uh Yes. And that is becoming the new challenge, isn't it? Is?
How do we, how do we balance
all of these things together?
And, and I don't, I don't know what the answer is. I mean, I,
there's always like that,
that open source, freedom, loving side of me that says, you know,
everything should be free and we shouldn't give
any information to anybody and we should,
you know, do it all ourselves.
Then there's a part of me that's like I'm too lazy and old to care.
Just take some money and, and make this go away.
Right.
Well, I'm not going to give up my cell phone,
right?
Like I, I can't, I my calendar, my email, my to do list my, you know, my army focus
like my life literally would fall apart without army focus.
-- I would be outside in the cold, naked,
-- dying. I, I think this is a challenge
that we should figure out how to test.
But no, II, I totally understand what you're saying.
And you know, that's something I think about too every now and again is,
how long have we had smartphones?
10 years
and, and my life is unlivable at this point without one. I mean,
-- I mean,
-- think about it, but the same is true of running water.
Yeah. But we've, we've had that longer than 10 years.
-- Right.
-- There was a, many years ago in Canada there were some, uh,
issues with, uh, water supplies in towns
and I,
I think it was in ML A ended up writing a brilliant letter on how to kill a community.
And one of the top ways to kill a community, no fresh water, like no drinkable water,
water supply
because it makes life impossible. I mean,
it does,
you know, I remember once, um when I was living with my parents, the,
the water made out in the street broke
because, you know, it was like 60 years old cast iron, whatever.
So, you know, we were without water for like, it was like
12 or 18 hours, it was under a day
and like the water truck was actually literally
parked in front of my parents' house.
So we, you know, we could go outside, get a bucket of water, go back in
and it was just complete
pain. Like, I don't know how people lived without running water,
-- but
-- they all had cholera
like because they,
they, they,
they did their business in a bucket and then
they threw it into the street and this is why
if you are rich you lived on the top floor
because then nobody was throwing their bucket past your window.
You know, like I would like to flush the toilet.
No, you can't do that without going outside for a bucket of water.
I'd like to,
you
mean
in, in that
-- there were no buckets of water back in the day? Yeah,
-- exactly.
So, I mean, you know, and so things like, can I live without running water?
-- Well, technically, yes, because
-- you know, you cannot,
you cannot
do
without running water
people.
Yes.
Yeah.
Well,
I think part of it is you definitely can't
have density of people without infrastructure like roads,
electricity power,
you just can't have density of people without it being miserable.
You know,
and that's kind of, for example, like the modern world with smartphones,
I can't have as much going on in my life without having, you know,
a system that lives in my pocket that helps me.
-- So
-- you're actually saying that these smartphones are
making us busier in reducing our quality of life
well,
or you could flip it on its head and
they're making us more efficient because for example,
when I'm standing in the checkout line at the superstore now, I can like be
browsing the internet checking, email, buying stuff on Amazon.
Uh you know, I do a lot of price checking now when I'm buying stuff,
you know, because for example, I,
I was at a store the other day and the board game,
one board game at the store was actually $3 cheaper than on Amazon quite shockingly.
And then another board game was uh $30 less on Amazon.
So for example, just, you know,
I can't do smart checking with a dumb phone or a
-- price checking with a dumb phone
-- and I don't price check.
Right. Anyway,
it's, I don't know, man, it's crazy stuff.
Well, and I think this really goes back to what Bruce Schneier
has been talking a lot is about like what we thought of as privacy is dead
and it's never coming back,
right? Like
nobody is going to rent like
to anybody without doing a proper credit check
soon because you know, you can either
not do it and you have this huge risk of like fraud and this person screwing
you over and like tens of thousands of dollars in legal fees and fixing the house
or you can spend 20 bucks and require enough personal information to
do a credit check or a salary check on the person.
Right.
Any, well, you know, the major landlords, like the companies are,
are obviously going to start doing this if they are not already
and it's going to trickle down to the small landlords, you know,
because once they get bitten or know somebody that got bitten, they're not,
they're not going to take that risk.
I mean, it would be insane to.
Yep. Oh, I get it. I, I totally get it.
Right. A
great example is I know the local ski hill now,
starting this year requires all the ski instructors
to go get a criminal background check.
And I believe also a child welfare check, you know, which costs about 70 bucks to get.
It takes a couple of hours because you got to go
down to this office on the west side and like,
fill out a bunch of paperwork and, like,
submit it and then wait like a couple of weeks.
Um, and they're basically passing that cost on to the ski instructors.
You know,
you have to, the $70 cost if you want to be a ski instructor at the ski.
I don't see that kind of stuff annoys me.
Don't do that at least pay for the thing if you're going to make them get it.
That seems unfair.
I would agree. But
there's a lot more people that want to be ski instructors than,
you know,
they need so they can do this. Right. There's a lot of people.
Yeah. Well, it's supply and demand. Right.
Yeah, I suppose, I suppose
so.
You know, it's just, it's, I see a lot like, well,
think about all the companies that are passing like the whole identity theft thing.
Right? Like
that cost the hassle of that is born
primarily by the consumer now. Right.
You read all these stories, these people spent
hundreds of hours trying to un
you know, mess their lives.
But even then it's not enough people to create any real change. Yet,
we're going to need a whole lot more people to have
their identity stolen before anyone cares enough to fix it.
Yeah.
Well, the problem is, is that, um,
even if a whole pile of people get their identity stolen, well,
what's going to happen?
I mean, unless we get legislation that forces companies,
that's what
is, is I compare it to things like auto safety and pollution and things like that is
basically things had to get so bad
that the people demanded the government fix it.
And we're, I mean, this is where security. I, I feel like a crazy person a lot is
we talk about this stuff and we say things like, oh,
we should fix that or we should do this or we should do that.
And the reality is most of the things we think are important
topics aren't even on a person's top 100 list of problems.
Right?
And, and
there's no hope any of this is going to get fixed.
I mean, Iot security is a great example, right? Where
these IOT devices are just terrible and they're super insecure
and, and you've got people like us complaining about it
a
bit.
I don't know if you saw but arm the CPU arm people are doing
a security framework for updates and software
and everything for IOT and they're releasing it
-- publicly is my understanding,
-- I heard about that and
I, I guess we'll wait and see if it works. I hope it does.
Well, the good news is that gets like the low level sort of operating system,
stuff taken care of.
But the problem is you're still going to have, like,
people writing absent PHP on top of it that are garbage like
that you can't change or whatever.
I
-- know.
-- But, you know, it's a start,
right. It is, it's the beginning. But
here's the thing
they are,
they're, they're giving people some of the tools they need to do something, right?
But that doesn't mean people are going to do it right or care
and the only reason they're going to care or do it right is
if using this thing from arm costs less money than doing it themselves.
Right.
Well, that's my hope is, you know, like the frameworks, right?
That people will hopefully start using these frameworks more and more because,
you know, like going back to your slides with the OAP top 10 and how,
yeah, basically it's actually three issues,
all of which are basically solved by use a framework.
-- That's good.
-- Uh
That's, that, that solves most of them.
Actually the, the new OAP list uh just came out
and I think it is a draft now,
I don't think it's been officially announced,
but we should talk about it at some point
because I actually looked back at all the historic O
AP lists
and they are
painfully similar.
Yes.
Well, we still have the same problem. So they're not wrong.
-- I
-- don't even think it's at the end of
the
o
was
goal I think is to make a list not to fix problems.
So
good
job
guys
there actually
any,
like, there's sort of,
they have that generic advice of what the problem is and how to solve it, which is not
completely useless, but more to the point,
like, has somebody like Ola
done an actual review of, say the top 20 or 50 web frameworks
-- and what we should be using.
-- They've done certain things.
They're pretty good about a lot of that stuff actually.
But part of my complaint is 10 is too many
and
they're, they're probably not getting,
they're, they're not reaching the people they need to reach.
And that, that's part of the challenge is how do you,
how do you get some of this messaging to the right people?
And I, I don't know
if I did, I, obviously
we have fixed a lot.
I mean, a lot of people would go back to that whole education piece, which
in principle. Yes, but in practice, obviously, no,
you can't educate our way out of this one.
Well, it's, I don't know, I mean, we don't have the,
some industries have like engineering is a great example.
Engineering has largely educated themselves out of like bridges.
The government throws people in jail if the bridge collapses. No one educates
themselves.
They don't want to go to jail.
And as a result of that,
you know, you have very good education for engineers.
And then, for example, to be a professional engineer in Canada,
you have to effectively apprentice, you have to work under another PN for a while.
I think it's four years now or something before you can become one
that's part of that education piece.
And yeah, there's totally the stick of, like,
you sign off on something and it falls down and kill somebody.
-- Things happen
-- to go to
jail.
Uh,
actually I remember when I graduated from college,
many of the people I went to school with were getting,
they were taking the pe test and I knew I was going to go into it.
So I'm like, I don't need that
and
it was so much work and they studied so hard and I was like, at the bar drinking beer.
It was, it was great.
Uh,
but so the thing is I, the,
the, well, I guess what I'm trying to say is education is not necessarily
the answer in the sense of there needs to be something driving
that education both providing it and people wanting to take it.
Let's, let's look at pollution.
Do you think if we just educated everyone about pollution that would have solved it?
No.
No, it wouldn't have solved anything.
-- Uh, people still smoke cigarettes. Yes.
-- And that one is,
I don't know if education solved that or did that, the high prices?
Maybe because I know that these things are taxed to death in a lot of places.
Uh, well then partly it's, you, you can't smoke as easily.
Like, for example, smoking
you can't smoke in public places in
most of Canada, I think, you know,
uh, well, when I say public places, I mean, indoors outdoors, obviously, you know,
uh, there's signs always saying you have to be 20 ft from the door or whatever.
-- So there's like this
-- little, like,
huddle of smokers.
Yeah.
You know, and there's been,
I know some places have banned smoking in cars with Children,
um, things like that.
So, you know, I, I still see people smoking in their cars, which I find just bizarre.
But, um,
no, I, I think education only works if essentially people,
well, first of all this presupposes that there is good education.
Right.
Because, you know, if you have bad education that's not gonna happen,
-- it is
-- worse than nothing insecure.
And number two people actually have to want to take this education and use it.
Ok. I'm going to, I'm going to say no one wants to take it. You have to make them
pretty much. Yeah,
I
think either require certification or,
yeah,
you have to make the penalties high enough that they
want to make sure they're doing the right thing.
Right. But then, but then
to make it mandatory
you need an incentive for some organization.
Be it like an insurance company or the government or something
to care.
And today
you can make the most terrible insecure software on the planet
and it doesn't really make a difference, does it?
Well, I think we've pretty firmly established with the user, end user license.
What's you
stand for? Again, end user license agreement.
That's what the,
I was thinking association for some reason anyways. Um,
we, we've largely established that, yeah,
even if your software does something terrible
suing and recovering that is nontrivial in almost all jurisdictions.
So, yeah, just, uh, well, there's that happy bit of news. I
know.
I
And on the flip side,
it's good though because it's allowed innovation in the it industry there,
you know,
quite often people do build garbage things that sort of slowly get better.
I mean, look at a PHP is a great example. PHP.
I think people would widely agree
from a design and engineering point of view is, is a train wreck, huge train wreck,
-- but it's enabled so many awesome things like wordpress and Facebook
-- like, ok,
so let, let me ask this though,
is PP the problem or is it the people using PP that are the problem?
Well, judging by the number of security flaws actually in the language PHP,
let alone the PHP applications.
I mean PHP is, it wasn't designed, it was, it was evolved. I mean, it's got
you see
those
slide decks where it's like,
you know, zero equals equals zero false or whatever.
Like you get these crazy results because of the way PHP does typing and
stuff, right? Like it's, it's obviously a bit of a train wreck
but who cares?
People have built things of amazing value on top of them,
like wordpress or Facebook or
like the number of PHP apps out there
is
stupid
and
you know, are they all insecure? Yeah, generally, yeah, they are all insecure.
But do they also provide a ton of value
and let people get things done and sell stuff online? Yeah, totally.
And that generally outweighs,
you know, it's like the crew.
It's like, oh,
everybody's discovering container ships or running it
systems that were designed to be stand
alone except now they have like satellite internet hooked up on all of these.
Right.
And the good news is generally speaking, well,
outside of one or two spots in the world,
people generally aren't hijacking container ships or robbing them
now that
they've learned from us, they can,
well, I think
there would be some real physical challenges and like
getting the container off the ship or getting into
the container depending where it is in the stacks,
things like that.
But
regardless the point is,
you know, the container industry has enabled
the global economy that we have today,
like straight up, you know, the, the economy that we have
flat out would not exist without containers.
This is true. It's true. It's similar to the internet or smartphones. Right.
Like, it is part of life and we can't get rid of it.
-- Yeah.
-- I mean, it's just, it's enabled so much. I mean,
you know, when these, when these, uh, legislature, uh,
when these legislators talk about
limiting the internet, I mean, for example, you know,
there's court cases where somebody is banned from using the
internet or banned from using phones And it's like,
uh, I, I believe there's a challenge in Canada whether or not that's constitutional
because like,
how would you live in the modern world without access to the phone and internet?
Right.
I, I don't know.
It's, I agree with you though. It's certainly something you can't live without
-- anymore. You can't,
-- unless you're like a crazy dude living in the woods,
-- random animals. It's the dream
-- right there. It's living the dream.
Kurt live in the dream. All right. We should,
we should call it any, any parting thoughts
we need to start thinking about
what actually does matter with privacy because I've,
-- that's something I've not really heard people talk about
-- because we don't know,
we have no idea
what the answer to that is.
We know privacy sounds like a neat idea,
but we don't know what it means and we don't know how to get there.
So, there you go.
All right.
All right, man. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you, everyone for listening.
You can hit us up on Twitter with the Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag
You can go to open source security podcast.com,
get the show notes and get a link to our Facebook group,
which you're welcome to join and harass us.
Be sure to send Kurt all of your complaints about his views on open source licenses.
And yeah, if nothing else, Kurt, you have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks.