Hello and welcome to the open
source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in reading security advisories
that are May or may not be true.
Josh Presser.
That is the dumbest intro
you have ever done.
I'm ok with it.
That's fine. I mean, yeah, the bar is pretty low here, so it's fine.
Uh
-- So I've
-- got, I'm actually more shocked that seven zip still exists.
We'll get to that. We'll get, I'll tell you my story first that that's how we do this.
You see you do the intro.
I have some
enlightening insight
and then we talk about our topic.
So I, I've got a laptop that runs Linux.
It's where I do all of the like podcast recording the show editing.
I do all the podcast stuff on. It's like my personal laptop, right? Dual
boots Windows, by the way, which I basically boot windows,
like once every couple of months,
let it run for like six days to install all the updates.
But,
and sometimes I play games on it occasionally.
However, now, now Steam support because of the Steam deck and it runs Linux.
Actually, Steam has surprisingly good support to run all the games on Linux now.
So, so anyway,
that's not the reason I'm bringing this up.
So it amuses me that this laptop it's a, a Lenovo, uh,
idea pad is the brand and things always go wrong.
We like sometimes the sound quits working with the new kernel update. Sometimes
the, the brightness on the screen doesn't work, whatever,
pick a thing and this time the, it,
it wouldn't go to sleep or rather it would go to sleep but would never wake up.
Right. Which is obviously the most amusing way.
It's,
it's
so,
here's,
well, it went to sleep.
I actually found out I could wake it up if I would plug in an external
keyboard and push buttons on the keyboard that would wake it up for some reason.
But the, like nothing else on the laptop would work when you run Linux.
This is, this is normal.
Yeah. As a Linux user, this is perfectly fine
and
I
gave up on Linux,
whatever.
I want to close my laptop lid and then open my laptop lid and
-- have my computer work in a quick amount of time. Not,
-- it works again.
The newest kernel 5.17 dot uh, let me look, uh,
uh,
5.17 0.5 fixed it. So,
but it's funny because my, my, my kids
are old enough now that they like play games and
they care about computers and they know enough about them
and
they'll ask me questions like, why, why does your computer always break?
And it's like, because I run Linux, like,
this is just clearly punishment for some sins from the past or something.
And I just,
I absolutely love the fact that you never know what
is going to happen every time you update your kernel.
And it amused because this morning I update the computer.
I was booting an older kernel that sleep worked on
and then
I update my kernel. I get a new one.
I'm like, oh, I should see if they fixed the bug and they did. So now I'm happy today.
So there's that,
-- that's all, that's my
-- story.
That is, I have to say Linux has gotten to be less of an adventure and more of a,
it works.
But, yeah, it's still,
-- yeah,
-- it's pretty boring. Now. I mean,
I remember back in the day I would usually dedicate about a week to get
my computer working correctly when I installed a new version of whatever on it.
Sounds about right.
And now like, yeah, it, it basically just works. It's,
it's boring.
Part of me is glad it's boring. And part of me is like, man, those were fun days.
And my guess is they weren't, it's just,
I remember as a youth when I had a lot of free time and I thought it was fun.
Well, this came up actually, I was talking with somebody yesterday about
having, like, I don't basically I pointed out,
I am paying this person at a professional rate to teach me something because
I could learn it on my own.
Or I could spend some money. That's not even my money
for this person to help teach me and get it done faster and get his expertise
because I just don't have that spare time.
He's like, yeah, you know, like back in the, I'm like, yeah, when I was like,
when I was a teenager I wrote a 50,000 word document for fun
because I had spare time to do that. Like nowadays.
-- No,
-- I, I hear you. I hear you completely. It's,
yeah. Yeah,
I, I, as I age
it has become more and more obvious that time and money are
two parts of the same equation and when you're young you don't have any money.
But now that I'm older and I have a little bit of money, it's like
that time is looking pretty good these days. You know,
I think there's a third thing too is that you, you,
you can actually assign a value to time more than when you're younger. Like there.
I now know what is and is not important to me.
Yeah.
Yeah, I agree. Right.
There are activities I will not do, like,
I will not spend a lot of time playing video
games anymore because to me that's a waste of time.
Whereas when I was a kid that was fun and now there's things I would much rather do.
Right. It's not to say that video games are bad.
I think video games are actually pretty damn awesome.
But there are even more awesome things for me to do now.
I mean, sometimes I still, there's a handful of games.
I'm happy to sit down and play every now and then.
-- Oh,
-- I still crank out some time on Factorio.
Uh,
that one and
Peoria scares me.
I started playing it for a little bit and I'm like, I can see,
I can see the hole I am digging for myself with this game.
I need to, I need to stop.
No, the ones I like,
I love like Super Mario games because I can play them for
like 20 minutes and then not play them again for a year.
And it doesn't matter.
That's definitely something I want is casual.
I'm a filthy cash.
I
anyway, anyway,
-- we have a lovely topic today. Speaking
-- of casuals, this weird seven zip.
-- It,
-- you can't just say casuals, you have to say filthy casuals.
-- I did say filthy casuals, didn't
-- I I only hear casuals.
I meant well, when I say casuals, it's implied that it's a filthy casual. You have
to do
any other kind.
Ok. So this filthy casual.
So apparently there is
possibly a vulnerability in seven zip,
but there was a fake exploit code for it published that is not real.
So there is a CV E for this vulnerability that isn't a vulnerability,
but there is actually a vulnerability in seven zip
that doesn't have a CV E.
That's how I'm reading this after looking through all this source material.
Ok. I want to back up because you just confused me.
I didnt, I didn't think there was a vulnerable
there
anyway. Ok. I want to back this all the way up.
So there's a gentleman on Twitter Kurt and I both know a name Will Dorman
and Will is on my list of people. If Will says something is true, I will believe will.
And there's not a lot of people on that list. He is like, Tavis is one of them.
-- I
-- don't think I'm on that list.
No, I'm not on this list.
I won't lie to you. You're not on it,
but I, I'm not on it either and it's my list.
But
so
will Dorman put a thing on Twitter about this fake seven zip
advisory that was assigned to CV E
and you actually mentioned it to me like, oh, look at,
look at this from Will because II I missed it.
I have like, I have too much crap on Twitter. So I miss lots of stuff and that's ok.
I don't mind missing things but
you tell me about it, I go read it
and the more I read the weirder it keeps getting
and
from what I gather at this point, I haven't hit the point of a second issue.
Yet, but whatever it could be in there and I misread,
but
basically this person puts
a bunch of stuff on Twitter, they publish a bunch of information in a github
repository.
They put a video on youtube
that shows a privilege escalation vulnerability on windows with seven zip.
And it's one of those things like a human has to interact with a computer.
So it's where a normal person sitting at the computer becomes an admin
by dragging a certain
what seven zip file into the help window or something. I forget exactly what it was.
Yeah.
But anyway, get to CV E all the usual stuff.
A bunch of articles get written about it because that's what the press does
and then
-- it looks like it's fake.
-- Well, and here's something that I like.
I, I hate it when people try to throw the press under the bus because
normally the press can go to sources and confirm things and that
is really difficult to do here because there's like only one person
that can confirm it and they can easily lie to you.
Well, but also secondly,
the press,
especially the tech press is on horrifically short
deadlines like we're talking 15 minutes max.
-- No,
-- II, I agree. I don't wanna in, in no way.
Should anyone construe my statement as bashing the press?
I have a ton of respect for them. I know they're under intense pressure
and fundamentally, if the security researcher comes to you and says,
look at this thing I've done.
Here's a video, here's a github
repository
and they don't mention there's no proof of concept code. But I don't think most,
most people wouldn't recognize that as a red flag.
You have to be in a very weird group of security researchers, I think to say,
-- where's the proof of concept
-- to know what signals to look for?
Right? Like you and I have done this for 20 years
and, and this looks plausible.
Well,
and I have a list of like public signals to look
at a company to see how their security posture is.
And when I show it to people, they're like,
they'd never thought of like, it's about 20 or 30 things.
And they're like, oh, I never thought of that,
you know,
like that story of this major vendor who doesn't have any way to contact
them about a security vulnerability and there's
other major financial institutions like what?
And I'm like, yeah, there, this vendor that you're planning to use has
no public way to tell them about a security vulnerability.
I don't know if they even have a security program.
Like, they don't mention it anywhere. And she's like,
yeah, that's really interesting.
And then I could hear her scribbling notes and I'm like,
you know,
I gave her something helpful, but
literally
this,
they never thought to look for that.
Right. And why would they? Right.
It's just because they just, I guess they just assumed it well,
because everybody that size should have a security program.
Right. Like
we know that.
Well, no, but we know that these companies quite often don't,
it doesn't matter, it doesn't matter.
So, the point of it all though, right is,
it appears it's not real.
And
this is something that
I, I don't know what to think of this even because the researcher
made a lot of, to do about it.
Mhm And then
there hasn't really been anything since it's basically been outed as fake.
There's
what are we gonna do?
-- II I don't know,
-- like, see what, what annoys me very much is
the lack of feedback loops in the CV process, right?
They put Star, star, space disputed space, star
star
-- and, and it should be noted. It got a CV
-- E. No, it's more than disputed. It,
-- yeah, it's
-- disputed and I'm fine with it getting a CV.
Like because let's be clear, like, remember a red hat, like I,
I assigned CV S so
quickly at Red hat basically that like, I remember
we had one in openshift where it was like,
that's not a vulnerability, that's just how this product works.
And that is a,
there's like a privilege issue but it has to
be there for like the container builds to work.
And I'm like, oh OK. And so we retracted the CV and you know, got rid of it.
That, that, that's the thing is I would much rather have somebody say, oh, holy.
You know, I think there's a really bad problem here and let people know about it
and then retract it versus
the, you know, no,
you have to prove it's completely legitimately correct
before we'll even consider talking to you.
And, and that's
-- what CV E does now. And that's wrong. I think.
-- I agree.
-- Well, no, they don't do that now because they don't.
-- No CV E says if it's, if it's real,
you get one, if it's not real, you don't. Right.
Exactly. But they don't actually do the work to confirm it one way or the other.
And it's so people think that they do like people,
I assigned 6000 CV ES
and people were like,
what do you mean you didn't test them all? And I'm like, what's 6000 times?
One minute?
-- Like, no, I'm not
-- one minute, hour, an hour or more.
Exactly.
-- Right. Assuming I can even stand the product
-- up.
That was so it's funny you say that I was talking to some people about
vulnerability scanning
and determining false positives where if you vulnerability scan something
and security issues appear and then you have to look
at them and figure out like is this real,
is it fake?
And when it's a false positive,
I used to, when I would do this a lot,
I would spend an hour or more on each false positive is my estimation.
Like,
yeah, it takes a long time to unp prove something. It's very, very difficult.
-- And
-- anyway, well, you're trying to prove a negative. Yeah,
exactly.
So, anyway, here's,
here's my take on this.
I'm very happy. This has a CV E ID because now we have a name for it.
So if I say, oh, that seven zip issue that was fake,
you don't have to say which one or what are you talking about?
You can say, oh, do you mean CV E 2022 29 072.
And I can say yes,
that's the one or let's say another one of these comes out in a couple months now.
-- There's two. Which one are we talking about? What's going on?
-- Because the
github repo says I haven't posted any proof
of concept code anywhere for privilege escalation attack.
The POC codes found have nothing to do with privilege escalation for your fix your,
for your information.
So in theory,
there should be a real CV at some point for this actual privilege escalation
or this existing CV needs to be fixed or something and more to the point like,
yeah, it's at least now it's cataloged, it's public.
But the problem is we can't really interact with it.
Like see if it was in the GSD system.
You could just add some data to your name space and
say like here's what I have to say about it.
But with the CV E entry, we have to tweet about it,
put the CV number in it and hope people find it.
Ok. Look,
the, the GSD is compatible with CV E. You can go. So this is CV E 2022 29 072.
You can literally go to the GSD database and this is GSD 2022 29 072.
So anyone could update this today.
But I also don't want to turn this episode
into us complaining CV E sucks and GSD is awesome
because
that's already true. So anyway,
-- anyway, well,
-- it's more the, the,
the modern world is messier and more complex than ever before and we
need to fail gracefully. We can't
like like those 2000 plus vulnerable.
Like maybe it's a vulnerability,
maybe it's not a vulnerability from the Linux kernel, but at least now people know
instead of looking at the flood of Linux kernel mailing list,
which is like how many thousands of messages per day or a week versus
like here's 2000 specific things to go look at in whatever interests you,
you know, by the device driver or a network thing or whatever file system.
Well, and, and look, I think one of the views I keep
thinking about
in the concept of, of especially vulnerabilities is
there's really two buckets,
there's the stuff you can individually name and worry about.
This is like comparing thunderstorms to hurricanes.
Hurricanes get names for a reason
because it matters.
There's literally thunderstorms probably hundreds of them a day across
the planet and no one cares because generally speaking,
they're not that big of a deal.
And I think most most vulnerabilities are thunderstorms where it's one of those
things like you should be able to look at something and say,
ok, this has four vulnerabilities.
This has
hundreds of vulnerabilities,
this has thousands of vulnerabilities and you obviously
need to decide like four is probably fine.
Hundreds uh well, think about that thousands.
Like I need to find a new library, you know,
versus saying I'm going to individually nit pick every one of these things.
But anyway, anyway, I think the thing I want to talk about with our remaining time
is
this intrigues me because someone put a lot of effort into fooling us all.
Why, why did they do this?
See, and this is one of the frustrations I have is who actually requested the CV.
It came through the CV form.
I'm pretty sure because it has, you know, miter as the assigner,
but we don't know who actually asked for this.
I mean, was it a third party? Was it the original person?
You know, I have had people basically come begging to me
to try and get CV S because they want to pad their resume.
That that's simply it
and, and to be fair,
if you find a legitimate vulnerability,
I will happily assign it an identifier because like if you want to
gain the system of identifying vulnerabilities
by finding vulnerabilities and identifying them.
I'm ok with that.
That's
kind of the whole point.
But they actually have to be real vulnerabilities.
Steve Christie used to call that PHP Golf
where you could basically pick any PHP application
-- and find one or more security vulnerabilities in a couple of minutes.
-- Well, like
the year, you know, Larry blew up the CV stats.
I mean, that was a good year.
He did good work like, and, and now Jonathan Light shoes doing the same thing.
Yeah, so to be clear,
I'm ok with people getting identifiers
for like even wonky little vulnerabilities.
That's great.
Please do that.
But like, yeah, this kind of fake thing that causes, you know,
people having to investigate stuff and deal with it like at
least seven zip isn't like a widely used open source library.
So you have all these vendors having to deal with it, you know,
and see if it's vulnerable or not.
And because this is something I often thought about when I worked at Red Hat was
if I wanted to like asynchronously attack a security V uh
vendor team, how would I do it?
And the answer is like lots of fake vulnerabilities
because each one of them takes half an hour, an hour, a couple hours to, you know,
prove
negative.
And the problem is like you and I can speak from experience,
you can't ignore these strange reports that come in
in broken English saying I found something weird,
blah, blah, blah
because once in a while, yeah, they did find something
-- like, really bad. I, I,
-- I don't think anything should ever be ignored.
I think if someone makes a claim,
even when it's preposterous and you don't think it's real,
giving it an identifier makes it easier to deal with in the future.
You know what I mean?
Just because you can start recording links, you can tell a story here.
I mean,
the only details we have now is a Google Doc will
Dorman created like that's kind of nuts if you think about
-- it
-- and you know, that should be put in the GSD and that can be put in the GSD.
Yeah, we should probably do that.
There's then that central place for discovery
because that's like that's one thing I did with the log for
J injury is I added tons of Twitter links and added timeline data
which then allowed me to actually build a timeline because
for example, oh yeah, you know,
I found the actual message thread on the
forum discussing this like a week in advance.
And then,
you know, like that's really useful data, you know,
-- understanding this
-- like, so so for people listening, I, I can,
I can contextualize this because literally
I spent
a probably an hour this morning before work reading all about this
following links trying to put this story together in my head.
And then Kurt did the same thing.
And then we even discussed before we hit record, like, oh, what about this?
And this and this and this link here and that thing there.
I,
-- I just keep thinking so we did this
-- work and all that data is going to die in our heads.
Yeah, it's in our brains.
Which is, I mean, those are terribly worthless places for the most part.
And, and if we write it down, that's great.
And if you don't write it down,
no one but us benefits.
Well, the problem is if you write it down, that's, that's better.
But how do people discover it?
Well, yeah. Right. Because obviously like Will's Google Doc.
The only reason we know it's there is because we
follow Will on Twitter and we followed his link.
Like there's no other way you'd find it.
That's not a sustainable strategy for data management is like, oh,
I find it on Twitter
and then follow the link
right now. Now, right now where we sit today, Twitter is
the fundamental information source for security events and vulnerabilities.
And that is a horrifying thing to think about.
I mean,
I,
I mean, I if this is in my slide deck, I talk about this explicitly
that like they like literally we had spontaneous
organization on Twitter of hashtag log for J and hashtag log
for
shell.
And without that, that whole thing would have been so much
go
the dog is the reason log for shell was even semi organized.
One person decided to do a bunch of work
for free on Twitter and they basically saved us all
to a degree. I mean, and that's, yeah, that's not sustainable or sane.
No, it's ridiculous. Like it's just not efficient.
All right.
And that's,
I think that's what offends me the most is this can be done so much more efficiently.
And, you know,
there are literally thousands of people that are gonna have to read the
CV E and chew through it and do what we did and,
and arrive at the whole.
Yeah, I can ignore this moving along
and that's a half hour or hour of useful
work they could have been doing on something else.
That's right. That's right.
And now if they do the work and they find a
problem with the CV E getting it updated is terrible.
And, and like that's obviously a whole another problem.
-- It's
-- basically impossible
when you learn something.
It's very difficult in the world of security
today to distribute your knowledge other than Twitter.
Yeah.
It's
once you have like a good hashtag or something, it's nobody can discover it.
Yep. Yep. No, II, I get it. It's, it's hard, man.
And one of the things I, I think we,
we like to bash everything because it's kind of what we do.
But I, I also want to be mindful of the fact that none of this is easy to do.
And it requires a
certain amount of knowledge and leadership.
And this is where I give the cloud security lines a ton of
credit for being willing to pick this up because it's a very,
very, very hard problem.
And I think historically speaking,
we've been able to ignore most of this because the right people
knew how to get in touch with,
with each other and it was mailing lists before Twitter.
But I think now
everyone has dispersed
to a degree that it's very difficult
to have these conversations anywhere but Twitter,
there's actually a more subtle aspect to Twitter, which is
anybody. Ok. Well, no, I'm gonna say this and this is incorrect.
Anybody can reply to your tweet.
Now, I know that that's incorrect now because you can actually lock down who can
reply to your tweets. You can either have people you follow or people you mention,
but generally speaking prior to them implementing that feature whenever they
did a few months or a year ago or whatever.
But if I say something on Twitter, people can respond and reply
sure, whether I like it or not. And that's something that
doesn't
happen with mailing lists in the sense of
you have to be on that mailing list to a know that it exists and to b then reply,
right?
And there's a ton of mailing lists and Twitter sort of
is that many to many connective tissue
that then allows the for the discovery aspect
I
mean,
in theory, if their algorithm, you know the algorithm, as we all know,
the one that showed up on, you know github,
if the algorithm works, you know, it'll show me things that I'm interested in,
which would be like, yeah, these kind of security things.
Well, and you know,
you know what I'm going to take the off ramp here because you just
made me realize something that I think
is hugely important to this whole discussion is
historically, when we would talk about a lot of this,
it was all the open source security nerds
and we had vendor,
we had OS S security.
You know, we had some of these places we would go
and now
if you're a security person,
you're also an open source security person, you don't have a choice anymore.
And so I think that the circle has gone from a pretty big circle to
like all the security people.
And I think that's one of the differences now is just the,
the ability for these older mailing lists to service everyone is completely out
of the question because a lot of people don't even know they exist.
And so, yeah, Twitter is kind of where we go.
-- Well,
-- and there's also the eternal September aspect.
Sure. Right. Yes.
If you have the entire security community show up on OS S security,
it's going to break.
Oh, man, it would be, it'd be a train wreck for sure.
-- Whereas
-- Twitter gives me some reasonable filtering tools by, you know,
like I pay attention to Tavis Oram
and to Will Dorman and to these other people.
I think we overestimate the importance of Twitter on a regular basis.
I think Twitter is fun and interesting and it has lots of good stuff on it.
But I bet you the number of actual security people who actually use Twitter
is probably like 10 to 15% of the industry is my guess,
not even less than a percent.
Maybe it's a very small number though.
So I think what we look at Twit Twitter and
I think we assume it has an oversized influence.
Well, like everybody in corporate America doing security, they're not on Twitter
like tweeting actively
and, and so what you end up with is the only thing they have today is CV E I DS.
And I think that's why there's such an overemphasis on those
I DS sometimes because it's literally all most people have.
And unfortunately
when, when all your only tool is a hammer, everything is a nail.
Well, I mean, I talk about this in my slide deck but yeah,
like we don't have any alternatives.
So it's the only game in town. It's,
there are no other public databases, there's just this one and well, now GSD,
there's private databases but they're incomplete and expensive.
-- So that's not a solution like to talk about at
-- scale and generally not amazing. No.
And so, well, Yeah, we only have one data set to play with.
Yeah, I mean, I can't blame people for overly focusing on it.
Part of my concern is, is, you know,
the world has changed so much in the last five years, let alone the last 20.
And that's kind of where I really work like,
and that's one of the fundamental tenants of the GSD is again,
we think we know what some of the answers we want are,
but we're willing to admit we're very wrong.
Like a perfect example. I used to think S bombs were something we need
and I no longer think that because it's a little more subtle.
You don't want an S bomb,
you want to vex, you want the S bomb plus the vulnerability data.
Like
if I, if you give me an S bomb, great.
Now I have to do all this work and research to match it up against vulnerabilities.
Well, no, what I want is
that data
to begin with? Like I want you to send me the SS bomb with the vulnerability data.
-- That's what's valuable that integration piece.
-- OK?
So you're on the right track
but you don't know you're going in the wrong direction, I think.
So the S bomb is an an unchanging document which
is just the ingredients list fundamentally in the software,
right?
The
that the va
is a vulnerability exchange.
And what that allows me to do is let's say I take an S bomb,
I can scan the S bomb, right?
This this is kind of a new concept because
generally when we think about scanning things for vulnerabilities,
we like send in
the the client or something
and it goes and looks at what's happening on the
desk and then it comes back with the report.
The idea behind the S bomb is you, you have an S bomb
and instead of sending in an agent to look at what's going on, you just scan the S bomb.
You say I know everything in the S bomb
compare this to my vulnerability database and tell me what the matches are right
now. Some of those matches are going to have problems for a variety of reasons.
It could be things like it's a false positive.
I'm not using this library, I'm not using this code.
And so for example, a vex is a way to convey that information of saying, OK,
I have an SM I have a vulnerability scan
and these findings in the vulnerability scan
are either lower priority or not affected or whatever.
And, and that's functionally what the purpose of the vex is.
Now.
The S bomb never changes. Vulnerability scans can change multiple times a day.
And so what you actually need, you do want an the
bomb by itself is basically worthless. It, it, you need to do things with it.
Well, that's what I'm saying is I don't want just the S
bomb. I want, I want somebody else ideally to also do the work.
Like ideally,
the vendor provides that level because they have the maturity
-- to say we scan our stuff for security issues
-- and
you can't trust a scan from a vendor because when did they scan it?
Did they scan it last week? Did they scan it yesterday? Did they scan it an hour ago?
And even if they scanned it an hour ago, log for J just happened 25 minutes ago.
So
the vulnerability scan is something that what you want is you want a vendor s
bomb that is accurate and good. And then you want to have the ability to scan
that S
bomb constantly. And then the vendor can also provide vex details as you scan.
So it's this like weird dance
and we don't like none of this really exists yet. I should say
-- II I, we get
-- at
it like to be clear.
S bombs are better than nothing but S bombs are not what I actually want.
What I want is the actual intersection of S bomb and vulnerability data
that's what's used. And the point
is if a vendor hands out S bombs,
then all these people have to do the scanning and all that.
Whereas if the vendor can
at
least maybe get 80 or 90% of it,
that's a whole lot less work. A lot of people can do.
And more point in theory people can share the the intersection of
SB bomb and vulnerability data in the form of a vex.
You know, they could publish it somewhere.
-- You are in the GSD, for example, you are
-- incorrect in your thinking.
You're thinking
you're, you're, you're bending the old way into the new,
what's going to happen
is,
yeah,
this is weird and hard stuff like
by no means do I expect anyone to?
And,
and even the things I'm talking about are going
to change as we develop the technology and the concepts
what you want to do is you're going to get
multiple S bombs because every time something is updated,
you get a new S bomb, right?
And so really all you want from your vendors is S
bombs.
You don't want vulnerability details from them because it's going to change.
-- You want the data. No,
-- I want that as a feed is what I'm saying.
I I'm assuming it's not static.
I'm assuming it's like a live feed like software updates.
Well, every version is, is
frozen in time though
S bombs don't change,
right? New versions change,
-- new libraries change
-- like the vulnerability scanning.
S bombs can potentially change in the sense of you
get a better s bomb scanner and you just determine
-- something that is present, but
-- that's a different problem and yet you are correct.
Ignore that problem for now because it, it,
it makes it very hard and this is spherical cows, right?
-- Spherical cows, ok?
-- We'll assume the S bomb is correct spherical
cows and,
but then you,
you need to manage them as well because you're
going to have this historical archive of data.
You're gonna, I if you have a system with say 10,000,
you know N PM packages in it,
which for a modern giant enterprise deployment is not unreasonable.
You think basically every one of those packages has an S bomb,
the system as a whole has another S bomb,
that's all that stuff put together plus some other things.
And so you end up with these like layers and
layers of S bombs and everything is changing over time.
So you need the ability to gain insight into the data.
And like part of the insight is going to be vulnerability
in the data. Part of the insight is going to be like open source licenses in the data.
Part of it is going to be like what things are, what, which packages are old,
which packages are fresh,
what's going on.
I guess what I'm trying to get at is why can't the third party do this and publish it?
-- And that's what I want. I don't want to do the work myself. I just want the data
-- maybe.
But the problem becomes, here's the thing.
If I'm a vendor, I create an SBO
and I scan it
and I say here you go, Kurt, here's my scan and my S bomb,
-- you can choose to believe me
-- and we're already
light years ahead of where we are today.
Well, I, I won't disagree with that.
See, and that's the thing like I'm not asking for. Perfect. I'm just saying
I don't want to redo all this work and have
everybody redo all this work that is insanely inefficient.
And maybe
you get it, you get uh in SB
for me,
you get a vulnerability scan from me and the vulnerability
scan can contain vex or whatever it doesn't matter.
Now, you have to keep asking me for vulnerability scan details constantly. Right?
Well, yeah,
I assume it's like a feed because you're a mature vendor who does this on the regular,
just like you
regularly do updates and find vulnerabilities.
-- You're
-- almost there, you're almost there.
If you're already constantly pulling in vulnerability details from a vendor,
you have to do this on a completely regular basis
and then you're gonna need a tool to manage the results
of the vulnerability details you're pulling in from a vendor.
Like
if you already have this tool
and you're already trying to manage this information
and you're already trying to wrangle it.
Like
why are you pulling it from the vendor? You just freaking run it yourself.
You already have to have a tool to do this work.
I don't understand why you would want to
trust their vulnerability scan necessarily or you could take
it from them and you could do one yourself and then you could compare them as well,
-- to see if they're making crap up one
-- comment.
So you would trust,
you would trust the vendor to download and run their software,
but you wouldn't trust the vendor to provide a security statement about it.
Like, do you see there's a, a bit of a disconnect there.
Have you ever dealt with vendors and security statements?
They are
-- often hilariously wrong.
-- Why do you think I moved everything to the cloud?
But the problem is you just moved your risk to someone else and
that someone else could be a complete idiot and you have no idea.
So that while, while effective is,
well as it turns out, GH
and Hiroko,
-- that is an excuse.
-- But see, that's the thing.
Yeah, that's exactly what I did and it worked,
it did work. I'm not gonna say it doesn't work.
I'm just saying, you know, if you're fundamentally all of this,
everything we're talking about
is about managing risk
and if, if your risk appetite says I'm just gonna tell
her to the cloud. I don't care.
There's absolutely nothing wrong with that.
And that's a decision you can make,
-- but not everyone will make that decision
-- challenges for us to insource
the risk management would require a level of effort and expertise.
-- We need 5 to 10 full time people.
-- I, I understand that, but this isn't for you either.
You keep, you always conflate these hard problems into, well at the CS A.
We don't worry about that because, but
-- that's not valid. No,
-- no, it's not that we don't worry about it. It's not.
No, no, no, I'm saying,
I'm saying I can't worry about
it.
Why not? That's fine. This is like me trying to solve global warming.
I
let me, let me, let me rephrase this.
Would you be comfortable
having
one of your cloud providers? Github
saying? Oh, we just outsourced our risk to
Amazon because that's where we run our cloud.
Yeah.
-- Right. That's ridiculous.
-- Because what's my alternative?
-- No, they scan their freaking software. But
-- what's my alternative?
No, you're, you're, you're being purposely
confusing.
The reality is when you have a cloud provider, you better hope
they're paying attention to what's in their stuff.
You better hope they're keeping up on what the vulnerability Du Jour
is. You better hope they're keeping up on the code they're writing
-- because if they're not, they're going to get hacked 100%.
-- Essentially. Hiroko
and github
are quite competent and large
and even they had a, a hack that was so invasive and large that they're,
they're forcing a global password
set for all their customers.
They've invalidated all the tokens and not allowed
us to use tokens for like three weeks
and
-- they insourced all that risk and here we are.
-- No, they didn't insource all the risk.
They're providing a service and they have a
competent security team that identified a problem and
the competent security team took the necessary actions
to remediate that problem for the customers.
In this particular case, it was a very,
they definitely took the sledge hammer to the wall for this one.
But the point is you can't just keep harping about outsourcing risk when the fact
is you did outsource a risk and the competent security team dealt with it.
And this is true of dealing with like s
bombs and vulnerabilities and vexes and things is,
it has to, you have to do this work at some point.
No, you don't. A lot of people don't have the budget or resources to do this.
-- Ok?
-- You're thinking about this from the opposite end.
I am, I'm thinking about this from the standpoint of I am
a
providing a service to someone else because those are the people I interact with.
I think we exist on two different ends of the spectrum.
You're talking about
the companies looking for services.
I'm talking about the companies providing services if I'm
working with a company providing services and they're like,
we don't care
too
about SBO
or vulnerabilities or any of that, none of it matters.
I'm gonna be like you have a great day, sir. And I'm gonna go find a company that does
and I,
I have actually had that experience where we're
dealing with third party plugins for airable.com.
And this one seems to be one person, you know,
running the thing off of a firebase without even a custom domain name.
And um they wanted a super admin access to our Google account to do the integration.
-- And I'm like, nope, we can't do that. It,
-- the point is all of this.
I'm ending this show because we're dragging on
the point is all of this stuff is just data.
And we've reached a point where you have two choices in the industry.
You can incorporate data into your process
and use it to make intelligent decisions,
which is fundamentally
epo
and vulnerability and vex are just all part of that data or
you can say I don't have the resources to deal with this.
I'm going to outsource my
work and trust and risk and all of that to
some other organization and there's nothing wrong with that.
But I think we have to recognize that there's a place for all of it,
given X number of S bombs and X number of interactions at some point,
this stuff has to be outsourced to companies that specialize in this because the,
the expertise and resourcing needed to do this properly
is going to grow exponentially.
Yes, I, I, I agree.
-- I work for a company that provides services and products to do literally
-- this.
Yeah, exactly.
I don't think anyone is arguing at that. That point is fair.
I hope what's going to happen is
rather than me run it that well,
you run it as a service or you enable an ecosystem that allows
people to run it as service and do it properly because I don't want
10 million companies having to set up C I CD pipelines to do security scanning.
-- I,
-- I want all of my vendors to do it though.
That's the difference.
We're talking about two different problems. You're talking about the consumers.
I'm talking about the producers. I'm not going to use a service provider
that doesn't do this kind of stuff internally.
Well,
ok, I can agree with that.
I would point out 11 point that there is the in house stuff that they build,
that they need to scan themselves because who else is gonna do that?
Right. Like
that's the point of being a service provider. You're providing a service.
Well, but,
but like that code that you write is 1% of your overall code base,
-- right? The rest
-- is
the
file
-- open source that you pulled in,
-- correct.
-- And I better know what that is.
-- Let me ask you this.
What would you prefer a vendor that does it themselves or a vendor that
outsources it to a massive company that is known to do it really?
Well, that's an idiot question.
I want a vendor who knows what's in their stuff, how they get that list, be it.
They're running a code scanner themselves, be it.
They're working with some other company that built the code scanner is irrelevant.
If you're my vendor and you don't know what's in your stuff,
you're not going to be my vendor.
Ok.
So I think that's what I'm not saying that they shouldn't know what's in their stuff.
I'm saying that generally speaking, this stuff will end up being outsourced.
It has to be
because the level of complexity and resources needed to do this correctly
is like apart from Amazon Microsoft and Google,
nobody else is going to be able to do it correctly.
-- All right,
-- I'm not gonna argue with you anymore and you're not wrong,
you're not wrong anyway, I'm ending it.
Thank you, Kurt.
What I'm saying
it
over.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you ever for listening. Go to open
source
security podcast.com. Hit up the show notes, UZ
PO
Os Podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media. Kurt have a lovely rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks
-- everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the