Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
Today we have a guest. I'm super excited. We've got Chris Weisel,
the founder and CTO at Verrico. Chris, welcome to the show.
Hi, Josh. Hi, Kurt. Thanks for having me on.
-- We
-- are ecstatic. I'll guess so. This is going to be a show about security education.
So if you're here for old stories, go, go find another podcast. But
I, I think why do
you give us kind of the, the 12th? Who are you? And how did we get here?
Because given education is a topic, there are going to be people who listen,
who don't know who you are.
Sure. So, um, you know, I've been doing computer security stuff for over 20 years.
I started in the mid nineties
doing vulnerability research before we even called it vulnerability research.
We called it hacking software.
And that was confusing when you said I hacked a micro
soft product.
But then I, you know, switched into a more professional role at,
at stake as a security consultant and consulted for a lot of security vendors
and then in 2006, I,
I founded a
uh application security company.
That's a SAS company that does security testing for people building software.
Awesome. Awesome, cool.
So you're here to talk about security
education and this is Security Awareness Month,
which is convenient.
So I guess
let's, let's set the stage, tell us your thoughts and what you think
-- we should know about this topic.
-- Well,
you know, my focus is, is developers because I think, you know,
developers have a huge role to play
in making the world secure security people
and end users certainly need to understand
uh how to make the world secure and have secure practices and behaviors.
But for me, developers are the most important because
they're building the technology itself and the decisions they make,
whether it's the way they code something or their design or their user interface,
those things make a big difference in how secure the, the the world is.
So I,
I think security awareness and security training needs
to be done to basically to everybody.
You know, I talked to my mother about this like on a weekly basis, right?
But I talked to developers about it constantly too.
It's something that everyone needs it and it should be focused on, you know,
-- sort of the way that you interact with technology,
-- not to be a devil's advocate.
But my one thought is we've been trying to teach developers to code more better,
you know, since ever. And
I, I'm not sure that it's working
and I can't help but wonder if, like,
automation and tooling is maybe a better answer than education.
Well, I think we need both. Right.
I, I think, you know, we, we talk about, you know, shifting left,
right when we talk about securing software.
So don't like,
put, put wrappers around it.
You know, we did the old way we did, it was, we tried to wrap the vulnerable software
when it was in production like, right, network security
WFS and,
and that type of thing to try to protect the vulnerable software.
And, you know, over time, we've realized that,
you know, there's big limitations to that so that the next best thing was like,
all right, well, let's at least get rid of the egregious vulnerabilities and,
you know, do manual pen testing or do a security scan
and, and get rid of the worst of the worst right before we go into production
and, you know, that doesn't work anymore
because, you know, software just moves too fast, you know,
going into production means every day.
So, you know,
the the whole thing about shifting left
is find the vulnerabilities earlier and earlier.
And one of the benefits of that is if you get to
um the actual, you know,
interaction with the developer as they're building the application,
you can start to get that learning experience to be part of their part of their job. I
think we've all become better spellers because
of spell checkers and to some degree,
better writers because of grammar checkers.
No one likes to give someone's uh a document full of squiggly lines.
It's like you just feel like I need to fix some things.
I'm old enough to remember when you spell, check the document at the end
before you sent it out.
And then you're like, oh my God,
I got to go through all these things and fix all this stuff.
I'm just, you know, it's not that important
but if you see that as you're typing, you actually, that, that quick feedback loop
actually gets you to, uh, actually learn how to spell something and, and of course,
when it fix, fixes the wrong spelling of their, you know, I, er,
to eir that's even better like auto fixing.
That's the best way.
But
I
think that those quick feedback loops is
something that's new for developer education,
like showing them
they're writing vulnerable code as they're writing it.
So I, I don't think we're done trying to
educate developers. I'm not ready, I'm not ready to give up yet.
That, that's very fair because
I don't think, I mean, spell check.
I've never thought of it in this context and you've got my brain
moving at about a million miles an hour now. But, but you're absolutely right.
We have spell check.
We're never gonna not teach people how to spell and write and do English
and
all this tooling we have in development, I think is similar
in that vein. I mean, this is,
I like this, this makes a lot of sense to me.
So I think basically every, every study I've seen around, you know,
criminality or training, you know,
getting Children to behave or getting dogs to behave, boils down to
the, the feedback needs to be as soon as possible. Right.
Like you, you can't have somebody or a dog do something bad and then
like, and then punish them a month later for it,
right? Because they're not going to have any idea what you're talking about.
And I can't help but wonder if that's maybe part of the problem is, you know,
developer writes a bunch of code
and then a week or a month later,
you know, the sort of the security issue pops up and I mean,
do they even remember what they wrote?
Like, I, I certainly don't remember code I wrote a week or a month ago.
No, there's no learning experience there and it's even worse than that because
uh a lot of times when you find something, a month later,
you have some other developer fix the problem.
Uh So there's not even an opportunity for the person who originally wrote the code
to, to, to learn from that um situation. So,
you know, getting the feedback uh as, as close to the create code creation process
is, is important and you know this, this isn't just the way that, you know,
security is done.
Like you don't want to find out that you have a syntax error,
you know, when you're compiling the code, right?
Like if it can give you that squiggly line as you're typing the code,
that's even better, right?
So like even things like syntax error
and other basic code quality issues, we've built into the ID E,
we've built into the developer experience
and
and and and security really kind of needs to be
the the same way and also like test driven development,
right?
It's like you write some code, you run the unit test,
if it passes you ship to production.
Well, that unit test should have a security test in it too
because you can't always find everything,
you know, it's, it's not always available in one line of code.
Maybe it's the way it interacts with some code
that you wrote last week that's in another module.
You still want to find out about that as soon as possible.
So to me, it's just finding out about that as soon as possible, we'll get these
official, you know, feedback loops uh ha happening.
-- So
-- now I want to bring this conversation kind of back to the
whole education piece because we're talking
about tooling and feedback while developing,
but you have to learn before you can develop. So where do we kind of
think about drawing that line between
what is a kind of a fundamental, you need to know about, you know,
developing in security and, and pick a topic versus
what is the,
you just, you're good enough,
the tool will help you fix it. You know what I mean?
Yeah.
I mean, I, I think that you need to go back further, right,
during the education process.
I mean, we all get trained around certain things
before we're actually doing the,
doing the thing and while you're doing the thing you want, that
you want that good feedback. Um
but you want, you also, you, you, you need to be trained in something first, right?
Just to have the basic foundational. So you just even understand
what's happened.
Like we, we, we,
we kind of understand basic spelling rules and basic
English before we're presented with the spell checker,
right?
So I think there needs to be a big push to move education of security in, into the,
you know, the college or the, you know,
the code camps or wherever people are learning how to code
that, that they need to get the basics there. They need to basically understand
the basics of, you know, how an application can be at risk to something like,
you know, SQL injection or,
or command injection or things like that because those concepts just,
you know, they, they're pretty specific, right? Like you,
you, you,
you need to have a basic understanding of how input flows through the system
and how an attacker can manipulate and control the system.
So I think training modules around secure coding and application security
principles need to be part of the standard curriculum for,
for, for developers.
And the, and the crazy thing is
we talk a lot about cybersecurity and education, you know,
colleges have cybersecurity programs,
but all that's doing is training cybersecurity professionals to to,
to try to protect from all the problems that the developers are creating.
So, so that's all,
that's all well and good because there's a lot of legacy code out there.
But as soon as that new developer comes fresh out of boot
camp or fresh out of college and starts writing new code,
um you're, you're exacerbating the problem. It isn't happening in many places.
I, I know a professor at Tufts University who offers a course on this and it's, it,
it's still an elective, right?
It's still an elective.
Like if you're in a computer science program, you can elect to learn about
security. Most colleges don't even,
don't even offer that in their computer science program.
So to, to me that, that, that's a huge missing piece of the puzzle.
I wanna grab on that for a second because I never explicitly thought of that before.
Like I,
I know some engineers like physical engineers with
their Iron Pinky Ring here in Canada,
a big part of what they do is try and build stuff that doesn't kill people,
right?
It's that simple that's,
that's like literally what the iron pinky ring represents is they built this bridge
and the bridge fell down a bit and killed a bunch of people.
And so they're like, let's not do that.
You're right. Like, in software, essentially building software fast. Good. Yes.
But building software secure is, is literally, like you said, it's an elective.
It's a, it's a,
it's not even a nice to have in some cases. It's like here's an option
that you could choose to take.
We're not even going to encourage it that heavily.
Yeah, I, I mean, I went to,
I went to an engineering school and I took computer systems engineering.
So I
certainly learned a lot about how computers work,
but I also had to take sort of those foundational
classes in mechanical engineering
and things like that.
Um As you do when you get an engineering degree and,
and in one of the mechanical engineering classes,
um I think it was called lumped parameter systems or something
of that where you learn about springs and things that bend.
And one of the video they showed a video
in the class of the Tacoma Narrow bridge incident.
And the Tacoma
narrows bridge is a famous uh bridge that basically
wind from a particular direction at a particular velocity.
Made the made the bridge go into this oscillation mode where it started
going up and down and up and down and eventually the bridge fell down
just from the wind
and, you know,
basically that's learning from a failure and now everyone who basically designs,
you know, mechanical structures
knows about that because they learned about it in college and, and,
and understands about oscillations and things like that
and, and plans for it.
Right. And it's like, what's the equivalent for, for, for computer science?
Like mechanical engineers are learning about this,
the failure modes of what they do.
But we don't do that in computer science.
It's like we're all just have happy, you know, happy ears on and everything's rosy.
This is, I've had this discussion more times than I can count now.
And I've gone in circles and circles and circles and I think that
the thing I always come back to when we talk about this is
the vast majority of regulation
in,
we'll say mechanical engineering and
civil engineering and electrical engineering.
Those regulations were written in blood. It's just the sad reality of it.
And I think in the world of computing,
I feel like we are standing on this precipice saying if we don't do something,
we're going to have regulations written in blood
yet it is a struggle
to get anyone to listen to us.
-- Sometimes I feel like it's
-- a good point because blood is, is very, is very visceral.
Um But where, where computers uh control things that,
that, that could cause
um
you know, people to die.
Um like the computers that are running in a you know, a 787 for instance, or,
um, I'm not sure what the, the, the, the, the plane that crashed, the, the 737 max.
Yep. Yep.
You know, there's, there's a lot of testing that, that happens
to make sure that the software controls are doing the right right thing.
Like there's a completely different level of
testing that happens in aeronautics systems.
Right,
as there should be. Right. And so,
but that also means that there's a long certification process
and you know, look, look at all the 737 maxes that are grounded,
we got billions of dollars of aircraft that,
that can't go anywhere until something is, is, is fixed.
So
that's,
you know, that's the, that's, that's one extreme, right?
And, and we actually have that now, but the solution is this, you know,
sort of extreme regulatory and testing testing process
and there's just no way that is going to
work for your sort of general purpose software.
But the problem is general purpose software is being,
is getting pretty close to being used in
those same situations where people could die.
Right. Yeah.
Yeah, people are using like browsers and cloud technology to, you know,
to administer,
you know, sensitive equipment that has like life changing decisions behind it.
So that's, that's the problem is like the,
the solution we have now for aeronautics isn't going to work,
but we're getting very close to using general purpose
computing and cloud computing and regular operating systems in
critical places. So,
um, we,
we need a different solution and, you know, part of that is gonna be education,
but I don't, I don't think, I don't have the answer for that.
-- It's a little scary.
-- I was just gonna ask you for the answer. So
that's unfortunate.
Well, you know, I certainly education in, in, you know, in,
in school schools and education on the job is,
is something that every engineer that is touching things that,
that, uh, is, is gonna go into,
you know, a system that, you know, where life or limb is, is, is a problem.
And, you know, I think that probably the closest place we have that right now
is, is, is, is cars, right? Because cars are
not as regulated from this standpoint
as an airplane, like the FAA pretty quickly realized like, oh, wow,
there's software controlling an airplane.
We got to do that.
But that same scrutiny isn't,
isn't, isn't on cars.
And, you know, I, I have a Tesla and, you know,
I get an over the air update like every few weeks.
So I know
that the same scrutiny isn't happening to that code that's happening to, you know,
the 787 Dreamliner.
Every time, you know,
every time they do a self flying airplane there's a big news
article about it because it's such a special and rare thing.
And then in the self-driving car world, you know, we find out that, uh, what is it,
Waymo, for example, has a bunch of cars getting lost in a,
in a dead end in San Francisco.
And,
you know,
they're talking about testing self driving cars where I live
in Edmonton because we have like really long snowy winters,
you know, reliably every year for six months of the year.
And I don't remember consenting to, you know,
being part of a self driving car test.
-- I
-- mean, that, that, that's an obviously a very, a
very challenging engineering engineering problem which
I think will eventually be solved,
but it's gonna take a really a
really a really long time.
Um And so sometimes it does scare me a little bit to,
to think about how much software is running in the car, I'm driving.
Um
And so far, you know, Tesla has done a de
has done a decent job
so far, but, you know, this is, this is gonna be everywhere,
it's gonna be in every car.
Um It's going, it's going to be in, you know, every, every factory,
every critical infrastructure
um is, is,
is going to have more general purpose software
in it because it allows improvements to,
to happen at a, at a, at a quicker pace.
So then is maybe one possibility that we'll see sort of,
especially from the open source world, that sort of best of breed software
that everybody just sort of agrees to use.
Well, you know, I think over the,
over the long period of time standardizing on certain open source is,
is beneficial, then, then a lot of, you know, focus
in of the community can go into securing,
you know, a few, a few pieces of software
that everyone kind of agrees are, you know, important pieces of software.
I mean, there's a lot of efforts go going, going into that right now.
Um
And, you know, things are getting more components.
So there is the, there is the opportunity
to, to, to, to do that, to have more, you know, sort of more reliable parts
that, that people are,
people are putting together and open source seems the way the way to
go there because of the visibility and the idea that anyone can,
can do the security testing on it,
right?
I feel like we've covered a lot of ground here and
there's two pieces to this. I think
that we keep coming back to is there is
the education aspect of we'll say new developers,
be it schooling or self taught or however, because I mean,
let's face it like we're all pretty old here.
None of us went to school to learn how to write code, right?
Like it's something we did on our own and, and that's not always the case anymore,
but then there's also the I think continued
learning aspect of once you exit university,
now you're in
the real world will say. And I mean, this is something like VIC
code obviously does where you have your tooling and you work with organizations to
help them write better software. And
I'm curious what your thoughts are on.
So,
should we have more expectation on?
I, I guess more stringent
education from, say,
like the university or online classes or
whatever versus should we have more stringent expectations
once you enter the workforce, let's say, as a developer
or maybe both?
Yeah. So I, I think it should be both but I, I, you know,
you, you're gonna have to educate people who didn't get educated in school no,
no matter what.
Um And there's always gonna be people who,
you know, are sort of self taught.
Um So they didn't, they didn't get that education in school.
So I, I do, I do think you need, you need both.
Um I, I would love it if the, you know,
the academic community would make this a requirement
of becoming AAA computer science graduate just like,
you know,
learning data structures is a requirement of being a computer science
graduate or learning how operating systems work.
So
I, I think, I think you really, you really need both.
And so, you know, the corporate environment
um you can have these feedback loops during, during the development process.
But I think the best way to, to educate, you know, take a break from, you know,
coding and take a class in something which, you know, developers do do that you know,
they,
they, they learn about, you know, Kubernetes or they, they, they learn about,
you know, server list, they, they do this
all the time. You know, it developers are constantly learning new technology.
They're just not learning how to secure that new technology, right?
So like every new technology is another opportunity
for, for, you know,
uh design and implementation weaknesses that then Attackers will exploit.
So, you know, it'd be nice if every time you learned a new technology,
you learned about the issues associated with that.
Like, so a class on, you know,
containers would talk about how you really kind of wanna know what's in
that container you're pulling from the repo that you're adding code to?
Like, is there
an old vulnerable library in there?
Like that's something you should know about, you know, I,
I think it can go hand in hand with,
with how the developers learn about new technology
because you don't learn about that in school,
right?
You don't, you, you typically don't learn about, you know,
Kubernetes or anyone who went to,
you know, comp I class more than five years ago didn't,
certainly didn't learn about it.
So, I it's got to be part of that continuous education process
again.
I, I think that's actually just sort of easier to take,
like instead of taking time out and saying, all right.
Well, we're gonna take like several days to learn about how to build secure,
you know, cloud native software,
it's as you learn about each new capability that,
that cloud native environment gives you,
you
also,
you know, learn about the risks um as that's happening.
The one thing I, I keep thinking about,
especially with continuous education is like,
everything I know is basically out of date by Monday.
Right.
Like I love that every time I log into Amazon web services, I'm like,
what is this new button or where's the button?
I want gone off to? Right.
No, totally.
And
but part of the challenge is, you know, where,
how do you get people to,
to, to resource and give that time to the developers?
That's a huge challenge, right? That's, that's where management has to come in
and work on this, you know, risk versus reward trade off
and realize that educating, educating the developers that are, that are building,
you know, your systems
is actually a very cost effective way of, you know, not having a, you know,
impact from a, from a data breach
rather than, you know,
having a huge security team and buying all these security products
that you're just layering on
hoping that, you know, the vulnerabilities can never get, you know,
never get exploited and you can,
it's cost effective to actually educate your, your developers.
And this is something that just management, you know, has to,
you know, has to understand,
maybe maybe we're not doing a good enough job of, of explaining that
because we have no data and we have no metrics and you know, this is, it, it, it, it's,
it's a hard problem, right?
It's a hard problem. And so
uh I think that people in sort of the, the,
the software security builder world have to
have to get better at, at, at, at demonstrating
that it is actually worth
spending some developer time there rather than having them keep, you know,
pushing faster and faster vulnerable code.
This rings,
I think with everyone, everyone understands this.
But the thing I just realized is you mentioned about
management needs to have a buy in here. But
let's say
you had leadership come to you tomorrow and
say here's $10 million educate the developers.
What now?
So that's,
that's a good question because um I don't know the Kubernetes
course that they can take that has the built in security.
They have to take a separate course in, in, in that, right?
They have to take like a separate cloud computing. So
the the the ideal world certainly doesn't exist.
Um One of the things that uh we found um at, at, at VIC
code is giving developers more interesting and interactive. Um and labs
based training
is something that engages them more, right?
It's not like if you if you give them
an elearning class where they're just sort of click,
click, click through and
you know, it's a video and it's a question, it almost becomes a game,
like how quickly can I get through this with as little attention as possible
and, and, and, and, you know, can I just, like,
skip fast forward and try to take the questions and see if I can answer it.
You know, we, we've all done this with compliance videos before
you do that.
I don't.
Um,
uh,
so,
so yeah, so,
uh, you know, I think a lot of, a lot of
that, that's not the best model, like it has some benefit,
but it's not the best but a lab based
model where you actually put someone in a virtual environment
and they can actually
attack an application,
you, you show them how to attack it and then they actually do,
like you give them tooling
to actually
try that SQL injection payload and see what happens and learn
actually how to attack.
That's kind of cool, right? Like that's interesting.
Like everyone, everyone would love to understand like, hey, you know,
I see a form field here, let me see if it, if it's vulnerable and if it is,
let me see what data I can access, right?
That engages like the black hat brain, which is pretty, pretty,
pretty interesting, right?
And that, that's the fun side of computer security, right?
Um And, and so
getting developer that can help engage developers like and, and,
and light bulbs can go on.
It's like, oh my God, I didn't realize this was so easy,
like one coding error makes it so I can just do this
so that engages the awareness of how serious these things are.
Like,
I, I maybe I should actually listen to those security guys.
Maybe they actually do know something. They're not just annoying.
Um
-- Yeah, they're
-- still annoying,
-- annoying and know things.
-- So hopefully that
type of lab can engage that,
that part. But then of course you want to say like, well, now let's look at the code
and let's look what was wrong in the code in sort of uh you know,
an editor where you can, you can actually, you know,
use real developer tools to look at the code
and then let's try to fix that code and then let's attack
it and see what happens in that sort of developer loop of,
you know, try to run the unit test, look in the debugger at your breakpoint,
understand what's happening.
And I, I think that's the thing that's been really missing
with developer education is to make it so that it, it just comes to life as, you know,
part of the way they do their job.
So, and I feel stupid for us on this. But
I'm thinking to all these companies that complain, we can't hire developers,
hiring developers is hard, they're not available.
But thinking about this, I've never seen a company advertise as part of their
sort of hiring practices that, you know, here's the salary band
and
we commit, say five or 10 hours a week to your furthering education. Which,
like, that's where I'd want to work. Right. Is a place where we're gonna help you keep
training and getting better at this. And I've,
now that I think about this, I've never seen that advertised.
-- Yeah.
-- I don't know if that's advertised. Certainly.
Developers ask for it once they're in the job.
They're, they're like, well, I, I want training, like, can I have training?
And of course, if you don't give them any training, they'll,
they'll eventually leave.
Um So I don't know if it, if it, if it needs to be
in, in, in the application, but
they don't want training around security though. That's the thing.
They don't want, they, until they get it, they,
they don't really understand the value of it
and then after they understand the value,
then they, then they get it.
So that, that's part of the, you know, the chicken and the egg egg problem.
Like I, I've talked to developers that have had
the, you know, they've gone through a lab, they've gone through a lab training,
something that's gamified where they were pitted against the, you know,
their teammates and they won because they, they solve the most challenges.
Uh They fix the most code or they attack the most code
and um they, they feel good about themselves and they,
they have a totally different perspective on this.
So they're like, yeah, the training was great.
Um, but they don't know that until enough of their peers
have done it.
I mean, we have, it's almost like it's a bootstrapping problem we have now, right?
Like there's just not enough critical mass
that there's awareness yet.
Yeah,
man, that's a lot. That's a lot to think about. All right, Chris. So we're,
we're nearing the end
and
I have a very unique opportunity for you here
during cybersecurity awareness month and talking about education,
there is a class
whose professor tortures the students by making them listen
to this podcast every week and then discuss it
and I'm not going to dox anyone so like, you know who you are,
but
you have an opportunity to literally address a
class of students taking various cybersecurity like networking programming
or kind of the the whole gamut here.
What do you want to say to them?
And what do you think is a useful piece of
advice they can walk away with from this conversation?
Well, I I think that having the uh an understanding of, of software security and,
and how vulnerabilities are exploited and how you can fix them.
It's just gonna make you a more valuable developer. You know, you're gonna,
in your career, you're gonna have more opportunities like, you know,
security architects that understand like cloud native computing and
architecture and security is a super high paying job.
Um And they're really,
if you think being a developer is hard to find that's really hard to find
and it's more, it's more fun, right? You're not like grinding
now, like basic U I code, right?
And in node I, I think it just, it enhances your career.
It'll enhance your perspective on, on the world of the future where
I know security is going to be more important because computers
are going to be doing more and more important things.
You might be coding a robot or something that has a gun, who knows?
Um,
so, so it's gonna make your career more valuable.
And I think it's really interesting when, you know,
II I learned development first and then I learned hacking
and I'm very happy I did.
So it just, it will, it'll, it'll,
it'll make dealing with technology much more interesting to, to learn this stuff.
I agree 100%.
And I guess I will end on one last note, which
you just open source Loft Crack. So, congratulations.
That is awesome that you, you did that.
Well, well, thank you.
Uh It's been a, it's been a long, a long journey with, with Loft Crack
and, you know, it, it's, it's kind of fun to, you know, have an open source project.
Now, I'm one, I'm one of the maintainers of it. There's a lot of cool code in there.
You know, Christian ryu
Dildo
is basically like a windows hacking genius and his code is in there.
So,
look at how he is dumping the hashes over the network from from a domain controller.
Look, look at how you know, there's some a lot of optimizations in there for,
for for cracking.
So
it's a fun, it's some fun code to look at and I think it's pretty,
it's a pretty capable framework to build upon. Yeah, so check it out for sure.
Definitely. Right patch is welcome, as we like to say in the open source world.
Awesome.
Well, Chris, it has been
-- absolute treat having you here. Thank you so very
-- much. Well, thank you, Josh.
-- Thank you, Kurt. It's been, it's been fun for
-- sure.
Cool. So anyone who wants the show notes you can go to opens
sources, security podcast.com, I'll put links to all the stuff we talked about.
You can use the Pound
Os Podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media.
-- Kurt and Chris have a marvelous rest of your days.
-- Ok. You
too. You too.
-- Thanks everybody. Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye.