Hi, all Josh here,
today's Remaster is going to go back in time for a blast from the past.
And we're going to talk about the left pad
security incident when Curt and I discussed this,
we didn't understand
exactly what we were dealing with yet, which is fascinating
to look back at all of the opinions and discussions.
We had, some of them were a bit dated.
I won't lie and I think we've changed some of our thinking sometimes drastically,
but I think the conversation is worth a listen because
an amazing amount of what we discussed is still valid today
and some many things have gotten better.
I'm not trying to doom and gloom the universe, but
it's a really cool discussion and it surprised me a great deal
and I think you'll really like it and I highly encourage you to give it a listen.
Kind of keep that thinking cap on and think about how
things are today and what they were like five years ago,
which is an eternity in this industry.
Thanks for listening.
Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 77
with myself Kurt Siefried and my part of the thought crime.
Josh Bresser,
what's New Kurt?
-- Uh, we're finally getting some snow.
-- Finally.
You live in like the up north of the Arctic Circle and you haven't had snow.
We've had,
we had a little bit of snow early on in the year and then
we had a little bit of snow a few weeks ago and it,
it got warm
and so my front lawn was actually, I would say maybe only two thirds covered in snow.
And then there was that really terrible brown looking grass.
You, you've told me all the skiing you've done though,
I assume your ski hills have the magic snow machines.
Yes.
Well, I mean, snow valley is literally inside the city.
It's a 15 minute drive away and so you can actually take a bus there if you want.
So, if, if they're in the city and they make snow,
do they accidentally like it snow on someone's sidewalk.
-- Uh, no, they're in a
-- valley. The ice was
the
name.
Yeah, exactly.
Yeah, I know.
Yeah.
And, well,
the trick with snow making though is it has to be below a
certain temperature and they usually make snow at night because it's colder then.
And so we were lucky because this year we had essentially,
we had very early snow for about a week
and then we had a cold snap of like, minus 1020 degrees for about 23 weeks.
I assume this is Celsius. The gentle no temperature scale.
-- The one that all of the world uses except for America,
-- except for that one place.
Uh, yeah. So
they were able to make a ton of snow early in the season.
So, we've been going skiing, like, 23 times a week for a couple of months now.
Very fun.
Yeah, it's awesome. It's winter.
And, uh, it's funny though because we had a cold snap and was like, oh, my God,
why is it so cold?
And I'm like, it's the first week of January and
like, that's,
that's normal
global warming.
I know.
Yeah.
So, well, I mean, I guess this week's latest kerfuffle is the whole no Js thing again.
-- Yeah.
-- Yeah. This one's really good actually.
Well, there's,
there's kind of two stories I really like on this one is there was the issue of
I, it's, what is it left pad this time or something?
-- Well, it was kick and then left pad.
-- Ok.
And that was no, but that was a few months ago when that happened.
Ok. Ok.
Kick was this one?
No kick led to left pad
kick
and it's just being brought up again because there was just tell this story. Ok.
So the two main things are so no Js is, well, no Js
and like many modern things.
It has a packaging system so that you can, like, go grab a package that, you know,
converts dates or changes the font color of your, uh, log files.
And there was a developer who had a package called KK Kik and
there was a company called Kick and they exchanged some emails apparently and
essentially they couldn't come to an agreement.
So the company went to the uh N PM people and under their
sort of package name, dispute
resolution process,
they booted the developer with Kik off and let
the company take over the name of that package.
So essentially they
N PM controls the name space for well N PM.
And that's important because like when you, you know, node install
blank, you're getting whatever it is they send you, right. Hopefully it's
what you expect. So basically this developer, I guess,
didn't really appreciate that. So they deleted
all of their packages off of N PM and they had one package called left pad,
which basically like straight up, just
left pads, text.
And so it was used and depended on by,
by thousands or hundreds or thousands or whatever of,
of other N PM packages which then all failed
in the
another thing to remember too is
in any sort of packaging ecosystem.
It's turtles all the way down because everything depends on everything.
-- Eventually.
-- I wonder if we've gotten to the point of circular dependencies.
-- I suspect we
-- have, I guarantee they exist.
Well, I remember writing dependency algorithms.
I
don't remember why I even did. Oh no, that's right.
I worked for a company called Progeny Linux systems like a million years ago.
And one of the things we were doing
was trying to build like customizable Linux distributions.
And so obviously a package dependencies. It was, it was crazy, man.
This was back in like 04, maybe 02. I mean, it was, it was a cool idea back then. Right.
And the answer ended up being containers, but, well,
the answer ended up being jam it all until it works.
And I, I remember writing
something that would kind of go through all
the dependencies and figure all this stuff out because
yeah, it was,
you'd end up with things like circular dependencies and you'd have to make
sure certain things depended on certain other things in certain ways and,
and things got crazy out of hand doing this.
And I remember that that was actually
really fun work,
-- but it was ultimately unsuccessful.
-- Yeah. So anyways, it's
so that's the first kind of story about the N PM.
And, and this has also happened with lots of other, you know,
package systems like uh Ruby gems.org is a good example.
Ruby gems.org is sort of the Ruby gems package or
that or site that won the Ruby Gems Wars.
There were actually sort of three main ones to begin with.
And so you essentially had three separate name spaces.
And so for example,
there were packages that were like have the same name across three name spaces,
but were controlled by different people.
Oh, good.
So Yeah, exactly.
Like, and, and some of these were pretty clearly, you know, not super good guys.
I think one of the names that was squatted on was like the B zip two. What package?
Because something to remember is, I mean,
the majority of developers, especially in the de develops agile world,
they write a bunch of code
with a bunch of, you know, import or depends or whatever statements
and they don't audit that code
and they don't audit the code that, that code pulls in and so on and so on and circular.
And I mean, quite literally,
it's quite common for something like a note,
Js application to then pull in dependencies which pull in dependencies,
which you end up with
easily over 100 megabytes of, you know, Min
javascript,
which is literally enough javascript to like, you know,
build an airline reservation system,
-- like straight up.
-- That's a great comparison.
Right.
Basically,
it's so much code that nobody will ever be able to
audit it and actually determine what it does or doesn't do,
you know, and the system runs on trust and,
and, and it mostly works. It's, it's ok.
Right. You know, people find flaws, we squash the flaws and there's luckily
there don't seem to be many bad actors getting involved in this probably because,
well, I don't know why because it is quite a rich target, rich environment.
I have some thoughts actually. And, and this is, there was a story someone wrote.
And the title, let me, let me pull the title up here.
It's titled, I'm Harvesting credit card numbers and passwords from your site.
Here's how,
and this guy kind of laid out
if he was going to say abuse
node
and have a malicious package that was
stealing information off of people's websites,
kind of what he would do.
And I started reading this
and I was thinking this is extremely plausible. Oh, it's totally doable.
And no, no, here's I, I don't think it is anymore.
I, I put a lot of thought into this and, and I think
this sounds like something that, that will work in a very short term.
But you have to remember this is the long game we're talking about here, right?
And,
and the thing is you only have to get caught once I
view this as kind of like the reverse blue team problem where
the blue team has to succeed every time the red team only has to succeed. Once
in a situation like this,
you have to stay undetected forever
-- once you're detected, once it's game over,
-- well,
you don't have to stay detected forever.
But I mean, for example, let's say the guy.
So the the premise of the article is this guy wrote a N PM package
that actually, yeah,
changed the phone color of your log files to
make pretty and then also harvested credit card numbers.
And they had some tricks like only harvesting credit
card numbers between like 7 p.m. and 7 a.m. and
trying to do it intelligently so that if you were
using like square or things with like good security,
it wouldn't, you know, get in the way of that and kind of block it.
And here's the thing.
I mean, it takes a lot of work up front,
which probably is why a lot of Attackers aren't doing it because it
are going for, like, I want to break into a website in half an hour,
harvest a pile of credit card numbers and sell them online.
Not, I want to invest six months building up this long call and,
and then harvest a pile of credit card numbers.
Right.
I, I think that's part of it. Yes. And, and not only that though,
you do this
and you'll be successful for a little while, but like all these mitigations,
this guy talked about
those mitigations might work at 80% of organizations,
but they're not going to work at 100.
Right. And again, you only have to get caught once and the con is up. True.
But the question is like,
-- does the con go on long enough to harvest a big pile of credit
-- card?
And, and I, yes, it certainly could.
I think if you actually started this,
you could probably get thousands or hundreds
of thousands of numbers before you're caught.
The kind of the point being. And, and the thing I keep thinking of is
I would be surprised if you could get away with this for more than 3 to 6 months,
maybe a year if you're lucky.
And now, granted that's a super long time. I'm not saying it isn't.
Yeah, I was gonna say, but you're gonna get caught.
And that's what tells me the fact that we haven't heard about this
before suggests to me no one's done it because you're gonna get found,
you're not going to be able to do this 100%.
Right.
Well,
there have been modules that were leaking information or exposing information.
And then it's the question is, well,
is this a malicious piece of code or just really poor programming?
And, and that I
think we could debate for days.
-- I always go with all uh Hamlin's Razor on this one.
-- Yeah. II I kind of agree.
I think it's, it's often silly mistakes.
Like this story here is,
it is hugely complex and, and I think this also makes me think of like movie,
movie theft
where
you, you look at movie plots
and the bad guys have these insanely elaborate plans.
And it's like in real life, you could never do that
-- in real life. If your plan has more than two steps, you're going to fail.
-- Right.
Part of it too is this, this is one of those things where
you need a lot of domain specific knowledge
to even
interact with the systems, let alone interact with them in a malicious way. Right.
Yeah, definitely.
You know, he gives the example of, well, I mean, first of all,
you'd have to be able to write some useful, no Js code.
Ok. That right there raises the bar of it.
Then you'd have to publish it to N PM. OK.
Then you'd have to convince other people to embed it.
Then you'd have to, you know,
or you'd have to make a lot of other fake projects that embedded to make it look real.
You'd have to make a pile of
github accounts that look real. You'd have to, you know,
you and granted, you know, if you wrote some tooling around this to automate it,
then you only have to do that once.
But again, even, you know, that is a level of sophistication and expertise that,
yeah, probably not a lot of Attackers have or if they do have it, you know,
they're going to use it for slightly more targeted and direct attacks.
This kind of reminds me of that whole, it's like spam in a way in that, you know,
rather than these targeted attacks
that we focus on a lot,
these kind of spam level attacks where I'm just gonna like slam everybody and yeah,
like 99% of people will just block it out, right.
But 1% might be stupid enough to fall for it and like, you know,
believe that the Nigerian Prince needs your credit card number.
And I kind of wonder if we're also approaching that security era as it were because,
you know, these targeted attacks definitely work. But, I mean,
they, you know, they take, they take a lot of personal effort
and if, you know,
if I, if you tell an attacker, hey, here's a tool,
it'll automatically attack 1000 websites and, you know,
one of them will be vulnerable and you'll get credit
card numbers and you just run it for an hour.
Yeah, they'll probably start doing that.
I, I think you might be right.
And, and not only that, speaking of Nigerian Princes, I remember reading a,
an interview with one of those scammers once
and someone asked like, why, why is your spelling so bad?
And, and like, why are these stories so ridiculous? And he said
you have to make it as over the top as possible because that way, you know,
anyone who replies
is you've got them right?
Because these aren't people who,
who probably have a firm grasp on what's going on around them necessarily.
It
reminds me of three card Monty.
If you don't know that somebody on the street doing three card Monte is a scam,
-- then, ok, you're the mark.
-- Yes, that's exactly right.
You know how, how anybody thinks they can win a three card Monte on the street?
-- I mean, that, that game is literally 100 years old,
-- but the guy before me just won.
So I know I can because I'm sorry for him.
Yeah, that's true.
That's true.
Oh, man. I know.
And you know what's funny about that is I was, I was
at,
oh, I was, there's this touristy trap in Wisconsin called Wisconsin Dells.
And, right, it's all full of water parks and it is a nice place.
And we were, there was a street magician there and the guy was like, hey,
you guys got to come here and do this.
And I,
I literally kept my hand in my pocket on my wallet
the entire time he was doing his magic because I'm like,
this dude's gonna steal my wallet
and I'm not gonna know it.
-- And like I the things he did, it's, it's,
-- did you, did you check for your phone?
I did not. That was in my pocket. And
I admit I was slightly less concerned about, oh, here's the thing though.
The street magicians never steal someone's cell phone, right?
They always steal the wall,
right? Like that's the, that's the gimmick.
And so
in fact, now that you say it,
I think a street magician stealing your cell phone would be very cool.
But no, it's always the wallet, man. You should know that.
So anyway, and, and,
and yeah, the crab, this guy did, it was like, I
people are terrible at dealing with hucksters like this, right?
And the guy was great, right? He gave everyone all their stuff back.
He stole from him. But
it's like,
holy crap if this guy wanted to be. Although I guess that's part of the story. Right.
That guy could become a pickpocket and he would probably do ok.
But I get, he's, I,
I bet he makes way more money as a street magician than he
-- would stealing from people
-- and he doesn't have to worry about getting caught.
-- Right.
-- Exactly. Exactly.
I mean, heck, I gave him like, 20 bucks because my kids were just, like,
enthralled by this show.
Right.
Whereas he, he stole my wallet,
he would have made about 25 bucks. Right.
That's what it would have been because I never have cash
going back to the N PM thing.
Part of what really sort of scares me in a way
is that we have these systems where people own a name space
but is globally used
and, and all of a sudden becomes very important, like a great example of this is like,
Yelp.
Yelp owns the kind of Yelp wants to own the name space of all businesses
and, you know, well, it'd be a shame if your business got a bad rating on Yelp.
But hey, you can pay us to get, you know,
those bad ratings suppressed or the good ratings on top or whatever.
Right.
You know, same thing like Google
to put it bluntly,
-- I don't go to restaurants that score below four on Google Maps. I, I agree
-- with you.
Right. I just straight up. Don't,
-- no,
-- I, I totally
get it.
And, like, quite frankly Google could,
you know, uh, uh, more and more people are going to be doing this, I assume, because
I, I'm at a point in my life where it's like, wait a second,
there's like a ton of really good restaurants.
Why would I go to this one with like a 3.2 rating where people are saying that, like,
the staff is surly and the food is cold like that.
Why, why would I even, you know, bother looking at the restaurant,
let alone going there to eat?
Now, let me ask this in, in the context of saying no
package managers. Is there a way to rate
the packages?
Well, see,
and that's sort of one of the things with a lot of these name
spaces is they don't really do that or it's sort of implied rating by,
you know, how many people use it
or like on github,
you know, how many people are star this, how many people are watching it?
How many people have forked it?
Right.
And I use that kind of as a metric when I'm looking at code
to kind of see, you know, like, oh,
this code has like, you know, 2000 people watching it. Ok.
It's, yeah, it's probably somewhat legit versus like, oh,
this code has nobody starring it.
Nobody watching it, nobody has forked it.
Nobody cares about this code.
And, but the thing is these,
these control of the name space is incredibly powerful because in most cases,
it's very opaque in the sense of like you can
do whatever you want and nobody has any recourse.
Yes.
Uh some name spaces have very official policy and rules like for example,
DNS the domain name system, right?
You know, if I register something.com and there's a company with that, you know,
they can come after me and there's a bunch of
laws they can use to recover that domain name.
And it's,
you know, there's at least some laws and process that are documented, but
you look at things like say N PM and looking at the name space policy,
I'm not really clear why
the company Kik man, you know, got
was allowed to grab this package name away
from the developer who originally built it.
-- I
-- mean, if there's a trademark,
-- the blog entry kind of reads like BS,
-- well,
the blog entry might be and they're not lawyers, but I mean,
you can make legitimate trademark
claims against things like that.
I mean, if you're a company named Kik and you're distributing software,
but the problem with trademarks is that trademarks are quite often just local.
So for example, what happens when you have three different kick companies,
one in Canada, one in Uzbekistan, and one in Australia,
it's going to fall to probably let's face it,
the American company because I assume that's where,
where much of this silliness often happens and where many of these people live
and, and
I'm not gonna piss off the local, whoever in my country.
Right. They're the ones I care about. Like, yeah, Canada's great and all, but
-- I'm not worried about them. I don't live there.
-- Yeah, exactly.
And see, that's the thing about,
that's the problem with name spaces is up until recently the world
didn't have global name spaces. Right. You,
you generally didn't worry about Bob's Deli
in Australia having the same name as Bob. Bob Deli down the road,
you know, but now that's a problem with these, especially with these, you know,
single name spaces like
N PM or C Pan or Ruby Jams, you know, where it is global in nature.
And then there, you know, for example, you have nouns like Amazon.
Amazon is just a well known place name and it's also a large company.
-- It
-- used to be a well known place name na
company.
Yeah.
You know, and so like for example, Square, right?
That's a big payment processor. But you know, it's also the word square.
And what if I write package called square that like
measures the space.
I don't know, it does something with squares,
geographic or uh geometrically speaking, I don't know,
you know,
should Square have the right to take that away
from you because they have the trademark on square.
Well,
yeah, exactly. Whereas
the name space control and where's the lawyers and all that. But
-- I,
-- I think we should save that one for the open source legal podcast. Right?
Yeah.
But,
but the really ugly problem here is that most people
use these name spaces without thinking about it at all.
Right. So
these people all pulling in left pad, for example, and
it disappears one day and all their apps all break, right?
And I mean, well, I used to work for Red Hat and I still do and this is why Red App,
for example,
we take software and we package it and we package it in a way so that there's no
like external dependencies, you know, when we install an R PM on your system,
it's not like, oh, I gotta go off to some random web
-- and grab a bunch of stuff,
-- right?
And,
and I think that is still completely valid and I think if you're operating in
an environment where you don't keep copies of
the artifacts you're putting in your products,
you're going to have a bad day.
Well, yeah, for, and the other aspect too is if that,
you know, if it goes away, you're boned and or if it changes.
Yeah. Can you revert to a known good copy?
Like if somebody hacks a developer account and then puts malicious code,
not even hack a developer account, man.
I mean,
how many of these projects don't have breaking changes between versions where you,
you just literally can't upgrade to a new version, I mean,
it's super common
and, and now we've made it to a supply chain argument,
which is totally where this was headed anyway.
And, and yeah, I mean,
this is one of the things I, I deal with this constantly,
every day and I think about it all the time is the fact that,
you know, there is an open source supply chain
and
we aren't doing a good job of,
of dealing with it.
Like there's some companies like Red Hat is,
is in honestly the poster child for doing it, right.
And, and I look at a lot of places that are doing it horribly wrong
and I work at a place that I would say is doing it pretty good, right?
I won't, I won't say we're perfect.
-- Not that Red Hat was perfect either, but,
-- but here's the one in fairness. There is no
easy tooling or frameworks.
Like for example, there's no N PM as far as I know,
no CPA N PM or whatever framework where
you like tied into your C I system and it acts as
a caching layer that also magically keeps a copy of everything.
Uh There, there are some actually, there, there are some,
none of them are free and they're really expensive.
And I mean, it, it's part of the problem I think
of
this is really hard to do
and it needs people because we don't have any standardized,
anything today for dealing with this
Well,
I think part of the biggest problem is a lot of this problem exists
not at the developer layer but at like the build and continuous integration layer,
right.
If it was at the a developer layer,
you would just check the code into your git boom done, right?
But that's not how these systems work. You have your code and get
and then when you build it or run it,
it automatically magically pulls in a whole pile of dependencies, right?
Like a deploy time, not at development time, right?
You know, uh well, for example,
like we the the the cloud security lines has several ruby on rails,
applications for like the CCS K and stars.
And you know, we have the code that we've written in,
get
cool.
And then, you know, when we deploy it, what is it called rail ties, whatever,
whatever the thing that
magically pulls in all the dependencies is does that
on the server keeps them up to date?
And it's kind of like, well, you know,
yeah, how do we, how do we properly back that up in an easy way?
I mean, I can back up the entire server. Cool.
But how do I kind of have say like rail ties or whatever
kind of give me a cash copy of those in a, in a structured way that I can more easily use.
And the answer is there's not really a good, simple, easy answer for this.
I know some major companies,
what they do is they basically they block access to things like Ruby gems.org
and they run their own internal version of it and you know, they, they, oh,
developer wants this package.
Ok. We're gonna go download that package, audit it, put it into our local,
you know, instance
and you can now use that and it's so it's now, you know, internally
copied and run
and like that's gonna happen with maybe a
couple dozen or 100 companies around the globe,
right? No developer is gonna ever do that.
It's also hard because you need, that's a very specialized skill set and you,
you need to be of a certain size.
I mean, start ups aren't gonna be able to do this because it's very difficult, right?
It's, it's, it's hard
and it gets even harder because
you might be pulling in one dependency and you think all right,
I'm gonna check out this dependency,
but then your dependency pulls in 20 dependencies and those
20 dependencies pull in 30 dependencies and it gets,
it gets really crazy.
And that's where I think a lot of this
kind of let, let's audit, everything can start to fall apart because again,
it's turtles all the way down and it's, it's so hard.
It's so crazy man.
And, and this, although I mean, I'll, I'll point out
github is, is hopefully going to help deal with some of this,
with their, their dependency checker.
They have, but even that I know is going to take probably years before I'd say it's,
it's good enough,
right.
-- This stuff is
-- hard.
I mean, there are things that do this, but again, it's,
they're not really
easy, automat, shareable. You know, there's no,
like,
as far as I know, there's no like,
simple plug in that you can basically like tie into your github
and be like, so every time you build this, the C I system will magically
do its thing.
But also this other system will get a copy of everything and keep it
and index it and catalog it and make sure it's the right one,
you know.
Well, you know what else? I think part of the issue here also is
what's the incentive to do this?
There's a handful of companies that do it.
-- Yeah, it's, it's too hard, I think
-- until it breaks horribly and, and, and, well,
the thing too it's
remembers. So uh the, the left pad example is great.
You remove left pad from N PM and it breaks on
a a jillion apps fixing and replacing left pad on, on N PM.
Took like one developer five minutes because he had a like a copy of it,
right? Like it's open source, right? So he just uploaded a new copy, took the names.
Uh N PM allows you to take the name space of abandoned projects.
So basically one guy fixed it quickly by you know,
re uploading it basically
you compare that to the effort of like
these million projects running local cash stuff.
Yeah.
No,
it's clearly a lot less work to have one guy fix it on N PM than to have a million people,
you know, build a bunker of, of cached files in case, you know, the,
the end times come for that file.
Right?
And that's part of the problem with a lot of these, you know,
solutions is that everybody has to do it to be safe, you know,
and that just between expertise and scale and resources is just not gonna happen.
So we end up with these centralized, you know, attempts at solutions.
Yes,
I don't know. I, I think about this one a lot and I don't know what the answer is today.
Uh
There is a project that's really cool actually, some, some ex red hat guys,
what is Tide Lift I think is the name of their company and it's libraries dot IO
and it's, it's starting to track some of this stuff.
They've got a long way to go, of course, but
it's,
it's the beginning I think and if I was gonna put money on anybody today,
it would probably be those guys because one of my complaints I have and,
and you and I discussed this often,
like we have a standard for tracking security flaws in software.
It's called CD E
and how many of these private vulnerability database
type places actually use CV E consistently.
None of them. The answer is none of them.
And I have a suspicion
they don't have an incentive to use CV E because they want to
say my database has more stuff in it than their database does.
So I'm clearly better than you.
And it's like, no, you're just all a bunch of idiots.
That's not, you're not better than anybody
work together.
Well, you know, it reminds you of antivirus companies, right?
Like they, they all essentially the amount of duplication of effort is
literally insane.
Well, it used to be much worse.
-- I mean, I, I, from what I gather, they actually work together now to a
-- degree they do.
There is a lot of,
there's sharing of coat samples and that's been around for a long time.
But before that even I remember hearing stories
back in the day where one antivirus company
would literally write viruses to attack another antivirus
company's product just so they could be like,
look, our product catches this virus.
There's doesn't, it's like, yeah, that's because you guys wrote it, man. Like
no kidding.
The reality is for people to do this correctly. It's kind of like backups.
It has to be
super easy
and super on by default
and require
literally no effort.
Yes or so little effort is like you type in one command
-- or something.
-- No, I I agree with you 100%
right?
Because I've, I've looked at this, you know,
for the CS A projects where I'm kind of paranoid, like, yeah,
like what if one of our dependencies goes away,
then our outbreaks and I get yelled at and it's going to be a bad, bad week.
But the solution is like, oh my,
it's literally a minimum of tens, if not hundreds of hours of engineering.
And, and the better question is
you have not spent hundreds of hours implementing a solution.
-- And how many times has your site or project broken?
-- Exactly.
Well, and more of the point, you know, again, this, this kind of thing doesn't scale.
Well, right.
Every single person writing a Ruby Gem app that uses like these common things.
They're going to spend tens or hundreds of hours of
engineering and ongoing maintenance and backing it up and blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah.
And the answer is no, clearly we're not,
you know, because that's what's happened. The market has spoken.
I'm gonna cut it off here and then
we will continue the story next week and next week we focus on
the market and the forces that it creates or doesn't create in some cases.
And it's a, it's a fun wrap up to the discussion for sure.
So I will see you all next week.