Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 83 with myself Kurt
Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
So, did you see that? Marvelous XK CD, Comic Kurt.
Yes, I did. And
I checked and I don't believe I actually have anything actionable to do with it.
-- And,
-- and what sort of actionable things do you expect to take away from that?
Uh Well, no, some of these could if they are true, be CV worthy.
It's a comic man. None of these are true.
Um Da da da da, da,
da,
da, da
da
da.
Technically speaking, for example,
the one in the middle critical under Linux 3.14
0.8 on system 390 UTC plus 14 times zone,
a local user could
potentially use a buffer overflow to change another user,
default system clock from 12 hour to 24 hour time.
Technically speaking, that violates the trust boundary
is that my assumption is that's not, well, I don't think any of these are real bugs,
right?
That's why I was looking at them and I was like, damn it like,
ok, start over with, what are we talking about,
-- ok, let's start there and then we'll, we'll go on.
-- Ok.
So XK CD is a, an online comic and if you don't know what it is,
why are you listening to this podcast would be my first question.
Yes, it's marvelous.
Yeah. Uh, so they, they, they do a lot of very, uh topical
uh comics about, you know, very technical topics like black holes or, you know,
what happens if you pitch a baseball at the speed of light.
And the answer is it basically it's bad, don't do that.
And so in this case, they uh they kind of do
spoofed,
leaked list of major 2018 security vulnerabilities in the
form of CV E hyphen 2018 hyphen question marks
and then with a description after it
and um some of them are quite humorous and some of them are,
-- well, like I said, if they were, if they were true, they would technically need a CV
-- E.
Yes.
Well, ok, look, they're, they're purposely comical, right?
This stuff isn't,
it's not.
II I looked at this and you were saying you were,
you were looking at it to see if there's any actionable items.
And I looked at this and thought
this is cleverly funny. It never even
occurred to me that any of this was real and I, I don't think it was supposed to be real,
right?
No, I'm pretty sure it's not.
But I mean, for example,
if Apple products did actually catch fire
when displaying emoji with diacritics again.
I mean,
there were those sun servers that I believe
the phrase they used was unanticipated thermal event,
uh, which was code speak for the power supplies caught fire,
right?
Uh You know, so like this potentially, I mean, well, the old comical error message,
you know, uh what is it?
LPT one on fire
which apparently was put in there because that was a
potential thing with some old tiny high speed lines.
Which actually, you know, what's funny is, is
long ago
there was a, a fire in a data center
and I remember someone shared around the, the logs of the Cisco router
and you could see the temperature on the router continuing to raise and the router,
of course, you know, screaming in the log, the temperature is too high,
the temperature is too high.
And it's like, yes, that's because like there's literally a fire.
That is why the temperature is too high.
Yeah, I remember that that was the uh the University of
uh what is it
in,
in the Netherlands, was
it?
Yeah, that fire actually knocked out a big chunk of internet for Europe at the time.
How exciting.
Yeah. Generally you're not supposed to keep firing your data center, you probably
outside
the data center.
That's what that fancy halon
systems for. Right.
Yeah.
Well,
and technically you're not supposed to use those anymore because they kill people.
So you're supposed to use water,
which is super good for computers anyway. Anyway. So, back to XK CD here is,
so, you know what the first thing is when I looked at this, my thoughts were, is
he's pretty harsh on Apple
when you, when you read this list, like it's not kind to Apple.
Uh,
yeah.
No, I mean, well, I think Apple, like a lot of vendors plays up the, we're secure,
we're secure.
By the way, here's a big list of security updates. Just please install it quickly.
Well, not only that there was the recent, uh, was it an Emoji or Unico?
It was a Unico character, right?
That could like crash any Apple device, minor bug.
Yeah,
it's, I'm always shocked at how some of these things escape.
Like I get that it's not easy to test some of these. But
yeah, when,
when it's like typing a character crashes the system or hangs it or whatever
or like that thing where they kind of messed up the route pass,
you know, uh, and anybody could basically just, you know,
try and do some administrative function and if they hit,
cancel enough times they were let out.
-- I remember
-- that one that was hilarious.
And, you know, and some of these are
not so much, well, they're not CV E worthy because they're like, you know,
they're operational issues like, uh
uh but
like, here's a good one and oversight and the rules allows a dog to join a baseball,
uh, basketball team.
Right. You know, I, I assume that's a reference to everybody.
Um,
and that's actually something I've been looking at is, you know,
should we be looking at expanding the scope of CVS
beyond software into services and maybe even business process?
Because a great example of this is
how many companies implement really good
two factor authentication and security. And the answer is actually quite a few now.
-- And how many of them have really good strong account recovery
-- setups.
Uh None of them.
Yeah, pretty much
so.
The reality is like, yeah,
I absolutely cannot break into your account and password,
but I can totally hijack your account and password by claiming to be you.
-- And, oh, I lost my wallet and forgot my password and got a bump on the head.
-- Right.
Right. Right. And you always hear about stories where
the bad guy calls up somebody. Right, and says I, I'm, I'm so, and so,
and here's how I can prove it.
And I seem to recall there, there was a story one time about somebody who lost,
I think it was their website
and they ended up like calling Amazon or paypal or someone.
And they gave them the last four digits of the credit card
that they then used to call the hosting provider and say,
oh, I'm so and so, and here's the last four digits of my credit card.
And they were like, oh, Ok. That must be you.
And it's like, wow, that was
good job guys.
Well, it's, that's the problem is it's not like these companies coordinate.
So like some companies have decided that, you know,
the last four digits of your credit card used to pay some bill are
well, oh,
that must be you then because you know that credit card number
and that's a super secret thing that nobody else would know.
Right. And then other companies are like, oh, the last four digits of credit card.
Yeah, here they are.
You know, they hand that stuff out like candy
or I remember one time hearing about the US asking
for the first three digits of your social security number
which are based upon where you're born.
So, like if you knew where someone was born,
you basically know the first three digits of their social security number.
Uh
Yeah. Well, sort of, it's,
it's where you were born as well as the date which of course,
like the age of somebody is not difficult, but basically the first three digits
are usually state and year kind of focused.
And so if you know, like someone's age within about 10 years,
you can almost certainly figure that out.
And I don't know if they fix that.
In other words, if you look at their Facebook profile,
you can probably get their
right. Exactly.
Well, just look at a picture of somebody. Right.
I mean,
the vast majority of people you can look at and guess their age within 10 years,
probably.
Well,
I know one clever thing I saw is I
know somebody that had to try and recover their Instagram
password because apparently some Russian dude yanked it.
And one of the clever things is, of course,
Instagram typically has a bunch of pictures of you.
So they asked this person to basically take a picture of themselves holding
-- up a sign with a random set of numbers and characters on
-- it.
I've heard of that before. I, well, Reddit does that for the A MA s, right?
Where you've got, you know, I'm, I'm so and so famous person.
Well, because obviously how else are you going to prove?
It's actually an A MA with that guy.
I always wondered what that OK, never occurred to me.
Right. Right.
Right. The mods would be like,
and this is
how do we know it's Vern
Schreyer
for real?
-- So question what's going to happen now with the deep fakes?
-- Right.
I was, I was actually thinking about this the other day and,
and the reason I was actually thinking about it is
one of the things people used to do is hold up like a newspaper to prove
it was a certain date or something happened. And it's like, you know what, it's
really hard to fake that now, I mean,
even my terrible Photoshop skills can essentially make up a newspaper.
I just have to hold something up and then I can fill in the blanks. Right. So,
yeah, it's
-- these days,
-- well, here's a great example. Letterhead,
like, letterhead used to be enough to authenticate something. Right. Because,
you know, prior to laser printers,
-- it's not like you can actually very easily fake letterhead
-- or not even that.
It was expensive. Right.
Like most people weren't willing to spend the money to fake it.
And no, I know exactly what you mean. You can totally fake letterhead.
Well, it's like fishing, right? Phishing is basically fake letterhead, right?
Just with email.
Yeah.
Yeah. Phishing attacks. Yeah,
just to be clear because for a moment
there I thought you're talking about actual fishing.
Yes.
Alright.
So anyway, anyway,
let's get back to this list here just because I think it's hilarious and awesome
and,
and I must say my favorite one though here is
uh CV E 2018 dash question question question question,
which is all of them and you know,
ok, I'll get to this in a second.
It says a flaw in some X 86 CP us could
allow a root user to deescalated to normal account privileges.
And what's great is I love this because I read that and I'm like, wait,
that's not a bug and then I'm like, it's a comic, right?
Don't be like that.
But anyway, here's the other thing is when he put all the question marks in.
Thank goodness he put in question marks because if he would have made up numbers,
do you know what kind of, like, insane chaos would have resulted from that?
-- We would have had to very quickly publish a list of rejects and
-- probably
would have been duplicates
and, right, it would have been,
it would have been hilarious as someone who didn't have to fix it.
But if I was involved in any way and who knows? Right.
If you would have, like, for example, use some of my I DS,
then it would have made work for me.
So that would have made me happy. But
yeah,
now, now here's what I will say about this
is I have a feeling this comic will do more to raise CV
E awareness than anything miter has done for the last five years.
-- Well,
-- the problem is marketing security stuff is not easy.
It's, it's boring and nobody cares until it's in a web comic. Right?
-- Yeah,
-- pretty much, pretty much,
you know,
and some of these two are kind of borderline like X 86 has way
too many instructions that that in and of itself is not a flaw,
but it kind of points to the whole,
like the X 86 thing is getting so complex that we're getting those, you know,
unanticipated side effects.
You know,
I read that one and thought this one might actually be a
bug like for real because X the X 86 instruction said is enormous
and it is out of control and
it's not going to get any better.
-- Yeah.
-- Well, I like, I like the last one because it's a flaw and miter CV, database law,
arbitrary code insertion.
And that's actually something we're, we're working on because
it's not a problem yet because we basically, we don't really,
if somebody were to pass in like html formatted stuff, we kind of be like, well,
first of all, why, second of all they do escape stuff,
but there was the case of a CV E and in the description, they included sort of a,
the the rejects example,
triggered it
and it actually
broke somebody's, you know, CV, data department stuff, right?
Because it, it encountered that and it didn't handle it safely and,
and just for our viewers, they may not be aware.
Uh we decided some time ago that
uh CV E descriptions are, are not just ask you text anymore, folks,
they can also be unicode and emojis and stuff like that.
Um Because I asked because there was that security flaw that was labeled by a,
an emoji.
Well, look at this apple one that just happened. I mean,
you could put that unicode character in the description,
which would essentially mean anyone viewing the CBE
data is going to crash their Mac.
I wonder you guys should totally do that. That would be awesome.
Well, see.
And then so the second part is right now,
we don't really support line breaks in the descriptions which
drives me nuts because I would love to enclose,
especially on the open source side
if I could include code snippets, man. Oh, man, that would be nice as
the
art.
Yeah. Well, and you know, things like that have come up.
So I've been like, well, do we have a list of banned words?
-- Uh Is there a naughty list
-- because there are words?
Well, uh not officially, but the thing is there,
there are words that if they were put in the CV
database would of course offend various groups of people or people.
So, you know,
in general it's not been a problem
because it's mostly just boring technical descriptions.
But at the same time, I mean, what if somebody, I mean,
if you search for example, well, the open source world
there are projects with, you know,
-- rather shall we say rude names?
-- Oh, totally, man. Totally.
I mean, that's one of the things I always think about that would be hilarious.
Well, I know it was
a,
some years ago there was a security group called themselves.
I think the bearded warriors and they got people to like,
give them credit and advisories and I thought this is hilarious, right?
Like so and so would like to thank the bearded warriors for reporting this issue.
And I'm like, what if you named yourself, like something super inappropriate,
right?
You know, I want to thank, you know,
-- would they, I don't
-- know, I I like that.
You and I are both just quietly dancing around, not saying anything like that. This
is
the
word that are identified by their first
letter
is a family
show. And
if we say such things, I can't click the clean button
when I submit the podcast.
So anyway, and,
and the beauty of it is I have the power of the edit so I can fix it no matter what.
That's right. Maybe Kurt's been spewing obscenity at me for the last 10 minutes.
Nobody will ever know.
So,
uh
yeah.
Well, I do enjoy this list too because there's a couple in here that are, you know,
sort of e strays like the numpy.
So numpy is a uh numerical Python library. Well, for Python
uh so numpy 1.8 0.0 can factor primes in o log in
-- time and there and must be quietly deprecated before anyone notices
-- that
man, that one hits close to home for more reasons than I'm ever going to talk about.
But like
that, that's one of the things actually
that's funny about security is there are security issues that can happen
that are so bad. You, you have to keep them.
I mean, like, like, like meltdown was kind of like this, right?
Where it's like everyone shut up for a little while, right? Like, let's face it, man.
Could you imagine if a researcher showed up one day and said I can factor primes?
Well, like I,
it would be mass chaos
-- in a realistic amount of time. Right.
-- Right. Exactly. Right.
Anyone can factor primes, let's,
let's say that.
But it's, it would be
in a realistic amount of time without costing,
it would be, it would be insane what would result?
-- Because essentially we've broken, even
-- if it was just purely theoretical,
you know, even if it was something like with today's hardware,
it'll take 10 million years.
Well, the problem with that is 10 years from now. How long is it going to take?
You know, like, like, remember des
des encryption used to be like who with today's hardware, it'll take up
to
AI
years. And then the eff built, built deep crack with, you know, was it
Asics or something?
And it was like, yeah, well, with Asa,
it's
now what days or weeks
and then a few years later, it's like your laptop,
there have been security papers written that were very theoretical in nature
that
I won't say we treated them like, oh my goodness, like do this now,
but there's definitely been
various mitigations put into place, let's say in like TLS, for example, or open SSL
that were based on purely theoretical research.
And in fact, funny enough a meltdown had theoretical research behind it.
It's just we were like, uh that sounds too hard. Let's not worry about it right now,
right. And then someone did it.
I think there's definitely a better understanding that
a lot of this theoretical stuff can be,
can become real a lot sooner and a lot more practically
than we planned. Like a great example.
Oh, you would need 10 million cor to do that in a realistic amount of time.
Oh, Amazon sells that now for a buck an hour.
Right. Right.
Right.
Um,
you know what, what kind of terrifies me is you look at the whole,
like Bitcoin thing and there's basically a global
shortage of GP US for all the various cryptocurrencies
or rather due to all the cryptocurrencies and the people mining them on these GP US.
And imagine if all these people with all these GP US decided to
turn it to like prime factoring of say some root certificates or something.
I, I don't know what the numbers are but
like what if the entire Bitcoin network decided we're going to factor this
prime number that is a root certificate for some important certificate authority.
I'm, I'm, I'm gonna get
over overly technical on you.
Uh Bitcoin uses a six because they are well past the point of using GP US.
And in fact, the Bitcoin algorithm
is more suited to A six because it is a relatively low memory, high CPU
algorithm. Whereas there are other coins
that are high memory
and well in high CPU obviously, but that's where you need the, the GP US to do that.
And now
I haven't kept up on all the different ones.
-- Yeah,
-- you're not, you're not missing much
to answer your question about if all the computing power in the world
was dedicated to cracking,
say a prime number that we know is in use for something important.
Today, I have a feeling we're, we'd still be OK
where you're,
you're still talking about probably thousands to
millions of years in many instances.
But, but at the same time,
I, I don't think
this line of reasoning is impractical
because
as the world continues to change and the way everything works,
the amount of computing power available is going up at,
at an alarming rate and it's becoming very cheap.
And so you got to figure like the total compute power of all GP
US today is probably going to be purchasable in Amazon in like 10 years.
That's crazy.
-- Well,
-- it's like uh what's this latest one? The um yeah, Samsung just,
it's not that they announced it, it's that they begin,
they began production of their new 30 terabyte SSD.
I saw that. That's insane. And it's like a normal size too.
It's not like a suitcase or something.
It's a 2.5 inch,
it's kind of a fat drive for a 2.5 inch drive.
Yeah, but still like to put that in perspective. That's like saying,
well, yeah. No, it's, it's tiny comparatively to like what? Let me put it this way.
What 30 terabytes of storage would have looked like 10 years ago.
Well, was it even possible 20 years ago?
No, like, actually possible.
-- I don't think it
-- was, it was like all the storage on the planet Earth. Right.
Pretty much. Yeah.
And now it's a single chubby, like, it's about what point, I think it's 0.75.
So it's the maximum height for a 2.5 inch hard drive.
But, like, that's basically a pack of cigarettes if,
for those of you old enough to know what cigarettes look like.
Everyone knows what a pack of, at
-- least in the
-- USA, you know, like,
yeah, I mean, this is 30 terabytes in a 2.5 inch form factor that draws it. It's crazy.
Probably only a single digit number of watts.
And apparently it's got 40 gigs of memory on it
for buffer because, yeah, I mean,
if you've got 30 terabytes even at SSD speeds you still need a big pile
-- of.
-- Oh,
yeah.
So, yeah, and, and it's, it's not cheap. It's like 20 grand. But
s
for 20 grand is,
that's
amazing.
Yeah.
And, and, you know,
in five years it's going to cost like, $4.99. Right? Because that's just how this
I've decided.
Like, so every,
every about 2 to 3 years I sort of re evaluate what
my baseline for a computer or any device I buy is.
So, and my current baseline now is minimum 1, 28 gigs of storage
built in.
Is that, that's
that's too small.
Lower. That, that's because you want a Mac only Apple provides such paltry amounts.
-- I'm talking also about phones, tablets,
-- everything. Ok. That's fair for a phone.
But even a phone I don't worry about because it's all in the cloud now.
Like, who cares?
Uh, I find it's annoying because when my,
my kids like to browse my photos on my phone and then it sucks up my data plan.
Right. Because if it can't keep it all,
see, that's why you get an unlimited data plan, Kurt and then you don't have to worry
about.
I live in
Canada.
Right.
Right. Right.
I know.
So, anyway, anyway, ok, we, we're in a hole we should talk about. You have a story.
You're saying antivirus maybe isn't bad.
-- Yeah.
-- So, well, well, antivirus, here's the problem with antivirus, right?
Is by definition it's not going to stop a lot of zero days.
So a lot and, and, you know, it used to be zero days, like w zero days,
but now it's like, no,
somebody gets a zero day shoves it into a
web based ad network and like goes and infects,
you know, a million computers.
Um, so anyways, what happened is these, these guy,
this company that makes this flight simulator, um,
they, uh well, like many companies got miffed with piracy.
So they included this component
that basically records,
uh, chrome user names and passwords that you enter into websites.
And uh
yeah, if you entered a fake serial key or mistyped your real serial key or whatever,
it would run this component and suck up all your passwords and user names.
And the company claims now that they've been caught doing this,
they claim that they never sent this data back to themselves, blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah.
But what's interesting is,
is the component they used is well known and it was caught by antivirus,
right? So
to quote, uh what this person said, just installed with a warning from zone alarm.
It thinks so this
program actually included a copy of this.
I don't know,
I guess you'd call it malware or hostile where
it's called test A exe which right away,
no offense if I see something called test
ad xe in something I'm downloading right away.
I'm like
I,
I like
it
has no place.
Yeah, exactly. So just installed with a warning from zone alarm.
It thinks that test dot Exen slash
T
slash something,
something is not a virus heuristic PSW tool when 32 security exploded Gen virus.
This apparently causes a wrist information on your system.
And the reply from the
flight simulator company is David. This is why we recommend you disable your A V when
any A V engines here are installer as a virus
which they are not also known as a false positive.
Now, granted A V does have false positives
that I've uh cli A V for a while.
For example, had a signature where if a file was double zip compressed,
it would flake as a virus,
which is just kind of ridiculous because there's a lot of
stuff that legitimately has zip files inside of zip files.
Um
But uh no, in this case, it's clearly not a false positive.
Uh And so I, I think basically
A V is kind of like that washing your hands thing where,
you know, if the attack can't get by a V then you know,
that that's a basic level of hygiene that maybe you should do because
you should be able to catch that kind of behavior in those attacks.
We should pick this one apart and let's start with A V.
I will, I will congratulate a V for catching this.
And I guess my view on A V is still that A V kind of sucks.
If you're on windows, you should definitely have it.
And I'm happy enough with the Windows defender because it's,
it's certainly good enough is
whatever. All right, if you have windows, you probably need it.
If you have other things, I figure it out. All right. Uh I,
I also feel like there are certain people that seem to
have a much higher regard for antivirus applications than they should.
And if you're one of them,
I would suggest you figure out who a guy named Tavis Ormandy is
and,
and read what he has done with antivirus applications.
It is it is one of those instances where
it could be worse than not having any, but I'll, I'll let the reader decide for that.
But now more importantly is
why the heck would, could a company even imagine? This is a good idea. I just, I, I,
like there are certain lines, I would say where you can have some gray area of.
Maybe this is a good idea. Maybe it's not like a great example is
various applications will phone home and just like
secretly tell the mothership what you're doing,
right?
That's totally gray area that I'd lean towards. Don't do that.
But this is like this is so far from gray is not even funny.
Well, this is literally
the Sony, OK. The Sony BMG copy
root
kit
B
because the root kit thing was only affecting one machine.
It's
bad,
you know,
I should say one machine, but like your machine, right?
So I mean, well, but it's basically similar to that and that, oh,
we want to do DRM and protect our product.
And
so to do that, we at
this is just like depth of personal information, right?
There's man, there's just,
I can't even imagine in my brain what the
meeting must have gone like to justify this behavior.
And, and not only that like, who's the dirt bag developer who turned this on?
I mean, come on, you knew what you were doing.
No, I suspect it was, I mean, it's, it sounds like it's a small company.
So it sounds like it, you know, probably wasn't
well thought out as a decision.
So, I mean,
legally they are in some potentially hot water depending on the jurisdiction.
Uh, because, yeah, taking,
well, uh, great example, good thing. It's not past me or, uh, GDPR would be in effect.
And so, yeah, if it was past May then basically everybody in Europe could have, uh,
well, yeah, that, that could potentially get very ugly for this company.
Maybe. I mean, heck, let's face it.
This company quite conceivably just destroyed itself.
I mean, this is the sort of thing that's going to be really hard to come back from,
-- maybe,
-- maybe I will
pay
you money to get away with it.
Probably.
You're probably right.
This is a company that sells a flight simulator and like apparently a model,
like a single, like data file for a model of a plane.
So that gives you all the characteristics of the plane
so you can fly it and play with it and stuff
is 100 bucks for flying one
airplane. Well, no, you can fly multiple airplanes, right?
But so it's the, the module is the A 320 X.
So like, I guess it's a very popular airplane to flight sim, I don't,
I don't play Fight Flight Sims.
I don't know.
Um, but apparently these modules cost like 100 bucks. So I, I mean,
not super shocked that people are p
files.
Yeah, 100 bucks is pretty stiff. But ok.
So anyway, let's ignore the, the ethical decisions. Here is,
well, more of the point it would also happen if you mistyped your serial number.
So wait, if you just typed in the wrong serial number,
it decided you were a thief and stole your, your.
So, here's the other part of this, I guess is
I feel like
the operating system should have a way for Chrome to say
-- like, don't let anyone else touch these files,
-- right?
Well, no, no, it wasn't touching files.
It was kind of pulling like a last pass style thing where it's intercepting
your user name and password when you type them into fields and stuff.
Oh wait. So it was but even so like, why,
why,
why are you letting an application do this?
I feel like if an application is able to to secretly backdoor your web browser,
-- there's something terrible happening, right? That's
-- not
really explicitly allowed it. Like me having my last past
module
on Chrome and very explicitly like,
I really hope nothing else is looking at
my user names and passwords in my browser because
when you install
lastpass, when you install lastpass, you have to click a couple of OKS,
right? It's not secret.
It's not like you go to a website and suddenly you have last pass. I mean,
oh man, this this feels like
an opportunity
for especially Chrome
to improve some security here because just keep people, like,
unless I explicitly grant permission,
nothing needs to mess with user name and password fields ever.
Right. Like
full stop?
Oh,
man, this is so messed up. This is,
it's, I mean, well, the problem is that
I think a lot of people, when they make security related decisions
quite often,
it's not that they don't think them through, it's that they're not,
you know, on the dunning Kruger curve of wisdom, they're not
qualified to think them through.
And so they, they do think them through to the best of their ability,
but their ability is not
sufficient to fully understand that.
Like for it, like example, if this had happened after
uh
after May
to understand that, you know,
the European, I think, is it the European data privacy commissioner or whatever,
what is it called
again
for
it?
Anyway,
the people in Europe that are enforcing this, I mean,
I believe my understanding of the fines for this are, it's
20 million or 4% of your
uh income,
whichever number is higher.
But there's also some weird rules if you're a really small company.
And my, my guess is this place is really small.
But again, this is like this is like willful,
just badness
versus
let me this way
if you put. So if you ship software that includes a third party component that
a V vendors are concerned about, chances are you're doing something very bad
I know,
I agree. If, if. Right, I guess.
Ok, let's,
let's say that and maybe this is the best way to end it is if you are a software company
and your software is setting off antivirus applications,
you probably need to take a good hard look at what's going on
because
just saying it's a false positive, like, make sure
it's not.
Right.
Well, every single program I've ever seen that says, you know,
disable your antivirus or firewall so you can get the scene,
don't do
that.
You just know that
regardless of that, the thing is not well written
-- by definition cannot be.
-- Well,
you're absolutely right.
And I guess this kind of comes back to basic hygiene, right? This is
if, if you need to ask people to do this,
you have bigger problems than the antivirus and the firewall.
Oh man,
just
my brain. It can't handle this. This is
I'm just gonna,
so the one, the one useful piece of advice I would thus say to people is so,
for example, whenever I download an installer,
even if you know something reasonably trustworthy,
I try to run it through Virus total.com,
I wonder.
And 99 times out of 100 it's fine.
And every once in a while though I've had stuff where,
yeah,
it has wires or it has something very questionable in it.
-- And I'm like, no,
-- what virus total said about, about this thing,
we'll have to, we'll have to look,
I'd be amazed if it's not already there. So, all right, man, I'm going to call it.
This is
like I can't handle this.
My brain doesn't know what to do. So, I guess. Thanks, Kurt.
Thanks everyone for listening. You can go to open source security podcast.com to
find the show notes. You can use the Pound Os S podcast hashtag to get our attention.
And if nothing else, Kurt, you have a fabulous rest of your day.
You too, Josh, thanks.