Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 128.
And no, we have not been compromised by the Australians at this time
that we can prove.
Well, I'm just wondering, for example, like, because if we were in Australia,
we could be compelled to put malware in the, uh, in the MP3, for example.
Uh I, I don't know, maybe it's this.
So if dear listener, if you haven't figured it out yet,
our topic is going to be,
we'll say the questionable law Australia passed very recently
around government. It, it, yeah, it's, it's super complicated. It's even worse.
It's, it's madness
anyway,
the, the, we'll say questionable bill that made it through
the Australian. I don't know what they call their government,
whatever. Uh, the, the Australian government,
I'll call it the government. It is all right. Like what?
I don't need to know these things, right? Like whatever doesn't matter. No big deal.
Not, not, not America.
They have a parliamentary system just like our, well, not just like mine,
but very similar to mine.
So.
Ok. Right. It's some sort of
uh elected government
that is full of obviously old white men who don't understand technology and,
and that's
-- true of most of the world yay for us
-- or worse,
some of them do understand technology and, and are ok with this,
it could be
it.
So anyway, let's, let's just start at the beginning and,
and the best part of today is I made a,
a flow chart of how I think this might work out and,
and
it's on paper which amused me greatly as I drew the picture
and, and I, I scanned it. I'll put it in the show notes for those of you.
-- I do
-- appreciate the PDF. You sent me of it,
right? The madness and the scribbly lines and like the mistakes I made.
-- And it's, it's beautiful
-- dude. This is the, this is how Ethernet got built
it probably I'm gonna, I can
I have.
Uh so anyway,
this next to the pictures my Children drew after we're done talking
and
I was just trying to load a copy of access
the assistance and access bill 2018 Department of Home Affairs.
-- It
-- doesn't exist. It's
404,
the web page
actually, right? I know the link you clicked because I found that link also.
But I'm going to,
I tell you now you can't load it and I'll explain why
after I set down my piece of paper out of arm's reach.
So basically, here's what this comes down to is I,
I did a bunch of research because I thought if we're going to talk about this,
I want to read it.
Right. Because obviously
everything I've read up to this point is like reporters or someone
else kind of regurgitating what it is and what it is.
And I'm thinking
I want to see it.
You, you can't, it doesn't exist.
And, and so what happened,
what they passed is Australia has a multitude of what
are essentially like telecommunications interception laws that date back.
I think the earliest one was 1901. If my mind is, is remembering correctly
and there's, there's like three or four of these
and they didn't pass a new bill.
What they did is they passed a bunch of amendments to all the old ones.
So we now need to wait for someone to basically take the old ones
and, you know,
conduct surgery on them saying here what the amendments make it look like now.
So, basically
this thing was passed and I guarantee nobody actually read the text.
They almost certainly were like, yeah, whatever passed, don't care.
Yeah,
I actually managed by using the search on their thing to finally
find a working link, that sort of.
-- But
-- it
-- doesn't,
it's massive and it's just
right.
It just talks about all the amendments to all the previous laws and it's,
it's not something that is helpful to anyone who probably isn't a lawyer
-- and getting paid a lot of money to actually go through
-- it.
You would need a team of lawyers for this.
Yeah. Oh, yeah. Yeah, definitely. One human couldn't do it. It's, it's huge.
So, anyway, why don't we sum up what we,
we have been told this thing is by many other people.
I think the premise of this is, is this is the reaction of, oh,
we can't legislate against encryption or we can't
legislate encryption to have a back door because
that's like literally all the encryption technologies we're working on.
Essentially we're at the point now where we've
kind of solved all the easy problems like,
oh whoops, you know, key lengths of six.
Yeah, they probably need to be longer than six.
you know,
or, you know, just all the simple problems have been solved.
And now we're looking at the problems where it's like, OK, well,
let's say now I have a state level actor with a quantum computer
and this is a real threat, right?
There's D wave out of Vancouver with their quantum computers there, you know,
these things are becoming real.
How do I, you know, encrypt something so that for example,
it can't be read for at least 100 years or maybe 1000 years or maybe forever, right?
So now we're addressing problems in crypto that are quite hard
and people are making progress. So
nobody's going to deploy a crypto system like the Clipper chip where it's like,
oh yeah, no, there's a government back door, but you can trust the government,
right? Ok. That's not going to work. But what can we do? Huh.
Well,
what if we mandate
much like wiretapping laws that people
put some sort of backdoor or assistance access
into their software or service so that, you know,
we can read Bob's telegrams or in this case his uh signal messages
or his whatsapp or whatever it is the kids are using nowadays.
Um So the premise being that, you know,
this way, we, for example, we know a bunch of bad guys are using, I'm,
I'm just going to pick on signal because I,
I love signal and I use it and I think everybody at this point
in the infosec industry uses signal and
likes it except it keeps getting terrible you
whatever.
Um
So, you know, we know a bunch of bad guys are using signal.
Well, we can't monitor what they're doing. But
what if you could compel signal to
create an update
that allows you, for example,
to geolocation target everybody in for the sake of argument,
Afghanistan and Pakistan
and read all their traffic or,
you know, everybody whose nickname falls into this list of shall we say, you know,
Middle Eastern style names, right?
And you could totally do that in software, right? This would actually not
be that difficult to do with
if everybody involved in that piece of software was on board with this, which
I can pretty much guarantee you with a piece of software like signal,
at least one of them is going to throw a tantrum and speak up.
-- So,
-- Signal would never go along with this, you
know, software isn't a S a
single developer anymore, right?
-- You got teams, you got Q A but, but
-- let's pick on someone like, like Facebook or,
or even Google.
Oh,
Facebook is a great example because they've done stuff
like this and explicitly made sure that their CSO
I forget what his position was that the Chief security officer, I think it was,
didn't know about this, you know, so he ended up leaving Facebook.
But yeah, so for example, Australia could use this to compel Facebook to say, look,
you know, everybody that's part of this Facebook group.
You know, we hate America death to infidels.
Uh You know, we'd like to see all the traffic, please.
Can you put that into your app or on the back end?
Can you start sending us those messages
on the back end?
It's probably not difficult for them, but Facebook's Messenger,
they own whatsapp, right?
And whatsapp does do end to end encryption.
And my understanding is they do it pretty well.
There is the danger.
Yeah.
Well, see, and the challenge is a lot of these apps do very good end to end encryption.
But I mean, I'm talking about a binary signal on my phone. How do I validate that?
You can't?
Exactly. So I really have to trust the app
maker
and the software
and from what it sounds like the, from what I've read
the,
the way this law works is they, there's a couple of things they could do,
they could compel a company to put in some sort of monitoring feature.
Well, or an individual that's where it gets really gross.
-- Yeah.
-- And that's really weird.
And let's kind of set that aside for a minute just because it adds a lot of,
-- I think
-- that's a really big part of the problem.
It, it is. And we'll get to it though.
So
there's
the compelling an organization to kind of put in essentially like a way to monitor,
but there's also compelling an organization to kind of magically update
an app, someone might have.
And there seems to be a lot of focus on phones and mobile devices in this context
being
we're gonna, we're gonna compel Facebook to only send Kurt
a special update that is going to essentially redirect all of his traffic through,
say these servers over here.
And that's kind of a, that's super doable technically speaking.
But it's, it's also really, really questionable
right? From just a, a sanity standpoint.
-- Well, I mean,
-- this, this technology already exists in the form of,
I forget the name of it.
But, you know, it, it,
it would intercept your downloads in real time and inject malware into them,
right.
So this technology, yeah, it was a few years ago, remember,
I think we talked about it on the show once.
Maybe not
anyway.
Um, but, you know,
essentially it's not hard if you can intercept a binary
in flight and add a bunch of code to it
like that. This is a well known problem in solution space
and, yeah, so they can't do that anymore because, you know,
pretty much everybody gets their updates,
hopefully at a minimum over HTTP S that's
hard to intercept and mangle and more ideally,
you know,
through some sort of app store that has a
bunch of other controls and protections to prevent,
well, this exact kind of shenanigan,
you know.
Ok, so, so let's, let's say we're just, we're getting angry and we should, but
let's move the conversation because I think let's face it
anyone. Like if you don't understand why the the technical
kind of aspect of this is bad,
just Google around for it and there's people way smarter than
us who have commented on like the silliness of this.
So,
but what I, what I really want to talk to is kind of the second order.
What happens next and this is where my,
my little flow chart comes in.
So I, I have
at the top I have what I've, I've the box,
I've titled Assistant Assistance and Access,
which is essentially this bill that was passed and,
and I have two possible routes that come from.
This number one
-- is nobody cares. Right.
-- That's a real possibility.
Oh, I, I have. Yes and yes, I need to fix it anyway. So nobody cares.
I, I'll, I'll leave it for the sake of posterity because it's amusing.
So, let's say nobody cares. This gets passed. Nobody gives two craps.
-- And that's just the way it is. Well,
-- it's, it's worse than that.
Nobody with the power to alter this cares and, and based on the fact that
that
there has been no, like
generally speaking,
everybody who's been consulted and asked about this
bill in technology said that's a terrible idea.
And they went ahead with it anyway.
But here's the point, right?
Let's say nobody cares, let's say nobody who,
who is in a position to do anything about it cares, right?
Uh What happens next? I have everyone else does this by everyone else.
I mean, like most of the other governments on the planet
because here's the thing
Australia is only 24 million people.
They would be the, the 22 million. Ok.
But they're like, they're, they're big but they're not enormous, right?
We have us states bigger than Australia by population.
-- Canada is bigger than Australia
-- 24.6 million. You are correct.
Ok. That's what I thought.
So anyway,
like the point is a company could exit this market and it would hurt a little bit,
but it's not going to end them.
Right? And so
so anyway, here, here's a point though,
is this is everyone else does this if nobody cares and I have, uh, if nobody cares, no,
like somebody cares.
And then I, I wrote people revolt and I don't mean,
like armed revolts in the street but rather, hopefully,
maybe people would stop voting for these clowns.
But the reality is,
I don't think that's going to happen because I don't think
enough people know enough or care enough to make that happen.
So, I'm, I'm pretty happy to say that's almost certainly not an option here.
Yeah,
it's,
yeah, I mean, it's one of those things where
-- there's
-- way bigger problems people don't care about, right.
Climate change is a way bigger problem and nobody cares.
-- Well,
-- climate change is an actual existential threat to our species and
this is, you know, kind of a major inconvenience and it's one of those like, well,
privacy is good.
We should
allow privacy and this messes it up. So,
yeah, we're not, we're not, we're not fixing this anyway. Anyway.
Let's move to the other side of my, my flow
chat now and I have a fight back. I mean, the company's fight back, right?
Like you've got your Googles and your Facebooks and Apples and whoever says like,
-- no way, yo,
-- let's be clear.
Are we talking about fighting back against the bill itself
or fighting back against being ordered to do this?
Because those are two very different things.
-- Uh being
-- fighting back against being ordered to do this, right?
The bill is passed like too late it's there. Right. So what now? OK.
So let's say a company, let's say
the, the government shows up and tells Apple you got to do this. And Apple's like,
OK.
Right.
If that happens now, we're back to,
nobody cares and we're back to everyone else does this, right?
No questions asked.
Now, let's say Apple says,
no way we won't do this.
And,
and the first thing that's going to happen is the government's going to sue them,
right?
And there's going to be some sort of court
case and somebody's probably gonna get in trouble and,
and but here's the thing, Apple might say, no,
the government could do nothing in
which case or business as usual.
Well, the thing is if this is all in secret, the government says to Apple, Apple says,
no, the government quietly goes on the way tries it with Google or with Facebook,
right?
They can keep trying it because an inherent part of this is that this, this is secret,
This isn't like
a warrant in a public court filing saying, you know,
we we want to go kick down this guy's door and like look for drugs,
you know, this is something that's done in secret because by definition it,
you know, you can't have like,
they don't want to have some sort of piece of paper that says, hey,
we want Apple to do this to target this specific group of people,
right? Obviously, that kind of tips.
Yes. And that's the thing. Right? Is because of the secrecy.
I think there is a, a less than 0% chance that if Apple tells the,
the Australian government we won't do this, they just go away
because the problem is if there is a court case, court cases are public
and so the Australian government is going to have to give away.
That's fair.
-- I don't know how this intelligence stuff works
-- Well, in the US,
you have the secret courts, you know, for fisa warrants and stuff
and there have, you know,
the EFS has been embroiled in a bunch of court
cases where they can't really talk about what they're doing,
you know. Um, so no, there is a framework for essentially
court cases, you know, under,
under the guise of national security, which like, obviously,
the government would push for this to be covered under national security
and, and that's true. Ok. So let's say the government does bring it to court right
now, let's say if the government loses in court, we're back to business as usual,
right?
Where, yes, there's a law but it's unenforceable and nobody cares.
And, and that does happen,
which means they would have to go back and do some rewriting.
Ok.
Now, let's say the government wins.
All right. So now Apple kind of has two choices.
They can pull out of Australia and say we're not going to work with you people.
And again, 24 million people.
Like it's not, it, it might make their earnings dip a little bit,
but it's not going to end the company by any means.
-- I think
-- you would probably notice more if somebody sneezed on the earnings report.
Uh, maybe, maybe so. Here's the thing. If they pull out of Australia
businesses,
they don't care anymore.
What if the company comes back with? It's not technically feasible for us to do this.
It is technically feasible and they can make it work and everyone
knows that it's just not technically feasible to do it securely,
right?
We have to be very clear on that.
Well,
technically feasible because one thing the bill does
cover is you can't introduce systemic weaknesses.
So they kind of tried to cover that whole. Oh no, no, no, we're not talking about back
doors for everybody.
We're not going to allow systemic weaknesses,
although that's not defined in the bill anywhere we ignore that.
So they've kind of tried to make it more palatable and that, oh no,
this will only be used to target, you know,
specific people or individuals or groups or certain groups of like,
say all the men or all the women or everybody who's right-handed.
Um
But for example, like what if,
because a lot of companies, you know,
they don't just let a bunch of developers randomly like write code,
shove it into a binary and ship it out to people via the app store, right?
Most companies, I know of that size, you know,
you have a bunch of developers, they do a bunch of code
and then Q A yells at them because it breaks their task,
you know, or
in some cases we talked about this on the show, you know, that company,
I forget which one it was,
but they basically had parts of their code that were labeled
as security sensitive and got extra review whenever you touched it,
you know, by other people.
So for example, you know,
it's not like they're just going to monkey with the authentication
routine or with the key exchange routine and be like,
yeah, no, this is fine.
Don't worry about it
and ignore all these.
If l statements around, you know, whether or not the user is left handed,
the company would have to have the entire stack from developers to shipping it
in Australia for them to then be sort of legally compelled to do this.
If you have an organization like Apple, I'm assuming a lot of this is in the US
and that American
manager is probably going to push back hard and
Ame,
you know, Apple's headquartered in America's
in America rather, you know. So
I I find it difficult for this law to work with a company that's international
and most companies are international now.
Well,
but it doesn't matter if it's international or not
if you want to do business in Australia.
And the Australian government tells you you have to do this, you have to do it.
It doesn't matter where you live
and if an American,
-- I
-- won't play
with them,
they're gonna, well, that's right.
That's kind of how the flow chart works is if you play chicken,
-- like
-- Uber.
Uber has done this legal chicken with tons of governments and generally won.
So,
let's face it.
There's most of the governments have as much will to care as the people do to care,
I think is what it kind of comes down to at the end of the day.
And so anyway, we,
we're kind of at the end of the flow chart. Then
let's say Apple pulls out of Australia,
they win. Let's say they don't pull out of Australia.
Now,
they essentially are going to have to comply to this
after losing a court case and we're back to the point
-- of everyone else's
-- and I don't think Australia or Apple
would have to pull out of Australia just for example,
pull your deaf people out, continue doing sales and marketing there.
You think they're gonna let them sell stuff in
Australia if they're not complying with court orders.
-- No
-- way,
I suspect if there's one of the few
things governments could do with respect to technology that
would actually get people in the streets writing it
would be banning the sales of Apple products.
And you know,
that's actually a really good point is
if suddenly the iphone wasn't available in Australia
people would be pissed. Now, people care. Right.
That's what we need to do is we need to tell Apple, like when the,
when the world misses its carbon emissions targets,
like they need to stop selling iphones and then people would be like, holy crap,
everyone stop driving now.
Pretty much. Yeah.
Yeah.
That, that makes me sad.
Yeah, I, yeah. Humanity, man. We're a heck of a species.
-- If we
-- look at this flow chart in big picture mode, right?
There's kind of,
I have a suspicion if companies fight this,
a more things have to go right for
the Australian government to come out victorious from this
than do for the companies, right?
Like this is sort of, if a company decides to fight this, I think the, the,
the weight of, of being, how do I say this? Like, like I, I think just the,
they have to do a lot less work than the government does
to make this happen and I have a suspicion they care more.
So I, my guess
I'm gonna, I'm gonna put 50% odds
on companies like Apple Google and Facebook telling the government.
Nope, go away and I think they're going to end up going away is my guess.
Well,
there's one thing fundamentally about this law that is
pretty much at odds with all Western law,
which is, this is a law that doesn't forbid something,
this is a law which compels you to do something
this isn't us saying you can't do XY or Z or if you do XY or Z, we will punish you.
This is I am going to compel you
to,
you know,
do something to your software or something
to your business or something to your servers
that not only is going to potentially cost you a
lot of money and time and effort but is potentially,
you know, very dangerous and very, very bad.
And so the companies,
the thing is the companies, they don't even have to stop doing something,
they just have to not do what the government is asking them to do.
And
I feel like, you know, this is the difference for me between, you know,
when people talk about free speech,
we have generally agreed that the laws
saying things that you cannot say are in general for certain cases, ok,
like you can't yell fire in a crowded theater
and, you know, you,
you can't threaten somebody to their face with physical violence.
You know, that's, um I want to say that's,
is that assault or battery? Which one is the actual,
the one is the speaking and the one is the hitting, I forget,
I always get the two mixed up.
But anyways, the point is we've generally agreed that you can,
you can stop people from doing things.
And I,
I can't think of any really good examples
where we have compelled speech or compelled action.
You know, you must do this,
-- um,
-- there's, there's some of it in,
in like court cases where they can ask you questions and you might be under oath.
But, like, even in the United States,
we have the fifth amendment so you can escape it.
-- Yeah.
-- Well, the thing is those are very restricted cases,
right? Like by the time you're in a court of law under oath, like,
yeah, the, the, there's a process in the system, this isn't just, you know,
I mean, this is, you know, having compelled things like you must,
uh II I can't think of a good example
of a compelled action that actually makes any sense.
And that's one of the reasons we don't do these things.
Uh,
-- you probably have to listen to police officers.
-- That's a lawful order.
That's a different form, that's not a form of speech, that's a form of, um, yeah,
that's true.
That's fair.
You know, like we have laws that compel you to do things like stop at a red light.
But the inverse of that is what we're, well,
what we ultimately want is we want people to not proceed at red lights,
you know,
uh,
you know, we're not compelling you to stop per se.
It's just we really need you to not go past that red light because
the people with the green cross traffic lights are
not expecting that,
right. So
even in the cases where we sort of have a compelled behavior,
it's typically balanced by like,
because we're compelling this behavior because it balances out this
other behavior that we really need to not happen.
And in this case
that, that I don't see that balance.
I, yeah, I mean, I,
-- I agree
-- and obviously the government disagrees
with me because they passed this law.
You know, they're like, well, we want to be able to monitor these people.
So we think we should be able to compel a software firm to,
you know,
ship an update to a specific person that compromises the security
of the app and their communication so we can monitor it.
Right. Well, and you know what else?
I mean, technically speaking, the thing I love the most is
people who are legitimate criminals.
Now, I, I'll also fill it in with like most criminals are idiots.
I mean, that's just the reality of it, but like people who are actually smart,
good criminals,
they're gonna know
which apps do and don't fall under this jurisdiction, right?
And they're like,
like signal probably doesn't have a presence in
Australia if they have any developers there,
like
that person's either gonna move or they're not going to work there much longer.
Right. And, and
like,
there's nothing you can do about that, right. You've already lost. There is
just the technical stupidity here is maddening.
Well, that's, and I think that,
that this comes back to something we were talking about before the show, which is,
I think most of these lawmakers
don't understand how international businesses nowadays,
you know, I work for a relatively quote unquote small organization,
you know, the cloud security lines and,
but we have,
we have permanent offices in three countries.
You know,
we have people across over a dozen countries and we're,
you know, we're less than 100 people and this is just, this is normal.
It, it totally is.
Right. Look at ala, like you work for Elastic.
How many countries do you guys have offices in?
Oh, man, we're like, almost completely remote as an organization.
We're very, very remote friendly and we have people, I mean, ignoring offices,
we just have people in,
pick a country. If it has internet, we probably have someone there.
I mean, that's just the reality of it.
Like, I think Red Hat was up to 100 and 60 countries or something.
I'd be shocked if that's all it was.
-- I mean, yeah, basically any country,
-- well, there's only like 100 and 84 countries.
I think the 20 don't have internet.
There's a handful that are on a list of, like, you can't do business here. Right.
So, between, like, lack of electricity and don't do business here. A man.
That's not even true. Like,
I know people who have been to what, what we would define as, like a remote country
and they still have freaking cell phones. Like, it's,
-- everyone has internet.
-- This is what part of it is.
They don't understand is I think they're looking at this from the perspective of,
oh, a company located in Australia doing business with Australians.
Those companies don't really
exist in the tech world because let's face it.
If you build something technology wise,
you absolutely want to sell it also outside of your country.
Well, sure where the market is like 90% of the rest of the world,
like you said, Australia, 24.6 million people, you know, Canada,
50% bigger
America is what? 300
I'm
-- spacing out three
-- 100 million in change, right?
-- something.
-- It's more than 10 times the size of Australia.
Yeah. And then the European Union, if memory serves as what, 370 or something
like give or take, so it's comparable to the US,
it's bigger than the U SI know that but not much bigger.
But anyways,
-- yeah, whatever.
-- So
I think
they, they've, they've also not realized that
the majority of tech companies in Australia are not just in Australia from
the perspective of like where they build their software and how it gets built
to think like the biggest tech company in Australia
today is probably Atlassian that's like based in Australia.
And I'll tell you what man,
if, if I was an Atlassian customer,
I would be saying,
-- what are we going to do about this?
-- Right?
I am an Atlassian customer and to be quite honest,
I I need to send in a support ticket today to ask them about this
because this is a
concern.
I mean, I don't see that, you know, I'm not concerned about us being monitored per se,
but I am concerned about their, their cloud hosting solution, you know,
having its security go wonky because they're compelled to do silly things
and that impacting me.
That's, I'm, you know, I'm worried about the fallout from this.
Um,
and it sucks to be them because I know they're not evil and I know they're, you know,
-- they don't obviously
-- want any part of this company.
I'm sorry,
on my short list of companies I'm willing to work for. Right.
Yeah. Well, they're like a supplier.
So, like, clearly I'm, you know, they're decent
and, um, but at the same time it's kind of like, you know, guys, like,
it's nothing personal but man, your government screwed up on Friday.
You know, I don't know how to put it
and, and at the same time it's like you said,
the, the, the people who actually passed this law are, are
probably, I mean, let's face it. They're old white men primarily
-- and they don't care and they don't have to care.
-- Oh, Atlassian revenue,
619.9 million as of July 2017. That's a solid number. That's respectable.
And, yeah, and it sucks because I really do like their software. But at the same time,
you know,
I have to answer to my CEO who's
gonna have probably some pointed questions about this
because I mean, like I said, this is a form of law that is just
egregious.
Yeah.
And, and I mean, ignoring the technical aspect of it,
just II I have a feeling that the social aspect
of this is going to be detrimental to the Australia.
Well, I shouldn't say that
I,
-- I have a feeling
-- you said you were reading reddit and
Australian developers are already looking to pull out because I mean,
especially if I was a security developer,
I can't trust you.
And again, it's nothing personal.
It's just for all I know your government has compelled you or will compel you.
You could be the best software developer in the world but
nothing personal. It's your government man.
That's a hugely, it's hugely problematic.
And I mean, you know,
Australia is very similar to Canada in that
they have a very resource extraction intensive economy
and they have like Canada
seriously failed to diversify
with respect to say manufacturing tech and other sectors. You know,
it's hard to do. I mean, I get it.
We, you know, like you look at a country like Germany, right?
And just their, their export is amazing.
So you know,
the
this is not helpful to your tech industry.
This is quite,
I I literally can't imagine pretty much anything
worse than this because here's the problem.
Not only is this law bad, but it is highly uncertain,
right?
If you pass a bad law that is clear and simple and like, OK, you know, we can't, you,
you can't export,
you can't export 64 bit binner from Australia anymore. Just 32 bit binders.
It'd be like, well, that's the stupidest thing I've ever heard,
but at least I know what the law is and what it
means and I can start dealing with it.
This law has too many unknowns like looking at your flow chart, right?
It's like,
can we legally fight back because inherent in these things
is sort of a in an an inbuilt gig order?
So can you even talk to your lawyer about it?
-- Uh
-- Probably not. That's how this usually goes.
So then do we end up with somebody trying to
file a court case without a lawyer saying your honor?
I'd like to file a court case so that I could talk to my
lawyer about something in confidence and the judge is going to be like,
what in the heck is going on,
you know, and rightly, so I'd be very confused as well.
So step one would be legally, can I even talk to my lawyer about this? Step two? OK.
I've talked to my lawyer, what is,
what do they say?
And then, you know,
can you actually take the government to court about this
and that'll probably have to happen in secret and then,
you know, it's just,
it's just the level of uncertainty and doubt and,
and unknown
problems.
Yeah, I personally,
uh if I was a large multinational,
I would be very apologetic to my Australian developers, but I would put them in a,
in a fenced lot.
Like I would really fence them off from everything else
because again,
we can't trust you to touch stuff because you might be compelled to put holes in it.
-- Which
-- is crazy.
Right. But if the,
yeah, just anyway, I, I feel like
this is
ignoring the technical problems. This is going to be an economic travesty.
Well, ok, I shouldn't say that
I have a suspicion. There's going to be
-- in
-- a few years. It might
be
to it where it's going to take time and it's also going to be,
people are going to see what the government does here because like I said,
in that flow chart, if the government ends up not pushing on this hard,
-- no one will really care
-- as far as I know from what they passed.
There's no reporting requirement for them to say, oh,
we used this 10 times last year.
So we have no idea if they used it.
-- 01 or 1000
-- we'll never know what, what we're gonna have to watch is.
We're going to have to watch companies like Facebook and Google and Apple
and Microsoft and see how they're acting because they're never going to tell us
if this law is or isn't being used. And is, or isn't affecting what they do.
But I think their actions are going to tell us a lot about what's actually happening
because let's face it if,
like apple suddenly drastically changes the way they do business in Australia,
this is probably why.
Right.
And I have a very strong feeling
they aren't going to do anything unless they have to. Right.
They're not going to be proactive, they're going to wait till they end up, you know,
staring down the end of a court order.
Well, I think there will be some procedural changes
like literally having traffic routed from Australia
through an American server back to Australia.
So that, you know,
the whole DEV process doesn't occur in Australia, right?
So there's that balance and check.
Uh, maybe, well,
Github's probably hosted in America,
but not like we're, we're not much better. But anyway.
All right, we should, we should end this, I guess, let's say,
let's say you're a betting man, Kurt,
if,
if you were going to put the money on the
table and say this is definitely happening or not happening.
What, what do you think?
I'm a pessimist and I think that we will essentially end up with
II, I don't think this law is going to go away.
Uh That's fair.
I'm gonna guess 30% odds of this actually being a thing,
70% it just fizzles and never really goes anywhere because it's,
it's Australia isn't big enough to affect the kind of change
that, that you'd really need to, to compel these companies.
Well, and the other thing is too, the,
the smart companies can architect around this
and then play legal chicken with the government
and they just have to drag it up slowly
and that's, that's
true, you know, and I suspect that's what will happen.
Awesome. Well, thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up the show notes.
You can use the Pound Os S podcast hashtag to find us on social media.
-- And yeah, Kurt, you have a great rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye
the.