Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in the New Year, Josh Pressers.
It is, yeah, this will come out. Of course, it comes out in the New Year.
-- Technically, every year is a new year.
-- I have a very amusing story to tell.
So a
listener
by the name of, of Michael, I think it's Michael.
If I'm mispronouncing your name, I apologize. Sends me an email
and it says in the last two episodes you published
there is
a, a high pitched wine in the audio.
-- I'm like, what
-- did you not see the wave form?
-- Like when you edited it wouldn't have shown up.
-- I don't look at the spectrum.
So I load up the
and I'm like, sure enough at 11,700 Hertz,
-- there's a line
-- dude,
my hearing is like,
exactly. And I'm like,
I'm too old to hear this.
And so
then I proceeded to tear my entire recording studio apart to figure out what this is.
And it was a new led light I had
and
I had no idea because I couldn't hear it.
I still have if anyone has heard the, the wine. I do apologize.
I have not fixed the, the MP threes yet,
-- but
-- couldn't you just set up the filter to
like everything above probably eight K or six K?
Just,
-- yes, I, yeah, I can. Yes, I can.
-- It would never occur to me to need to do that though.
Well, right. It hadn't before. It'll be done now.
And I'm gonna make sure I look at waveforms from this point forward as well
just to make sure, like
there's nothing weird in the, in the, because it never occurred to me. Like
there are things other people can hear. I can't.
So I bought a dog whistle and it's a really nice
dog whistle in that it's adjustable like you screw it.
So it gets shorter and longer. And so you can basically,
basically you can,
uh, at its lowest pitch, it totally audible and at its highest pitch, of course,
I assume a dog can hear it.
I don't know, I don't have a dog. But what's funny is there was like a good range where
I can't hear it. And my son Felix is like, please,
because I, I have some 6 to 8 K hearing loss in my left ear here and not in my right ear.
So I've, I've actually had my hearing professionally tested now twice because I,
I have some weird loss on the one side.
Sure. Sure.
Yeah.
So it's, it's,
I feel bad for those people that get older and still hear mosquito tones
because, like, that's a thing. No, that's a thing in, like, Britain.
A lot of countries now where they use these high
pitched tone generators to drive away younger people from,
like, stores and stuff.
-- So they don't loiter there.
-- I've heard of that. Which seems cruel to me.
Right.
And I'm just, like, that is such an antisocial, horrible thing to do.
-- Yeah, I agree.
-- Ignoring that. Like, and I, I don't even like teenagers
and I'm still, like, that's a terrible thing to do to them,
let alone to the older people that can still hear it.
So, anyway, it amused me.
There, there, there is no wine anymore because now the,
the nice light I bought unfortunately is in a bag on the floor next to me.
-- I'm
-- curious, what brand was it or what?
It was a Logitech, I think light. It was
not like, super expensive.
It wasn't cheap and it was kind of nice because it had a real nice, warm light.
So it would have been like the transformer or something in it. Hey,
-- it's led. It probably has some, yeah,
-- they have transformers and B,
or basically the moral equivalent of a, of a voltage exchanger thing.
It's probably just a PWM signal that's driving an led is my guess.
And it only shows up when I turn the brightness down.
It's not present when I turn it all the way up.
-- Oh,
-- so probably something to do with voltage regulation or whatever as
well. Pw.
But anyway,
needless to say
that I spent in quite a bit of time figuring this one out.
You know, I was just thinking because, like, remember Linus Tech tips,
bought that Anechoic Chamber to sound test stuff.
Right. Because they wanted to test how loud are computer fans?
I didn't know they did that, but that's cool.
And it just occurs to me like, I wonder if they're also testing for, like,
high pitched or very low pitched noises that
could annoy animals or people with good hearing.
See, that's the beauty is I have terrible hearing. So, like, it doesn't bother me.
Right. Right. Exactly.
-- But anyway, so
-- speaking of old things. So
I was
-- thinking the other day, I didn't
-- even do that on purpose
the other day is there's been a lot of open source security
related software over the last
forever
and some of it has been hugely successful and we still use today.
Like SSH is a good example and, and to be clear, I want to talk about software,
I'm not gonna talk about standards very much.
Like, I'm not gonna talk about TLS or implementations of TLS. So it's not super,
I was looking at this and because there are things that are
-- like, here's a great example. Has Se Linux been successful or
-- not?
-- I don't want to say no, but I think it's no.
-- Yeah.
Right. And
so, and that's the other thing I was looking at some of these and it's like, they're,
they're ubiquitous, but at the same time, they're not popular or
well loved or well used.
And se link is a great example of like, yeah,
it's kind of on by default and like pretty much my interaction with
se links for the last 20 years has boiled down to like,
OK, I'm just gonna turn it off now.
So a thing works.
I actually used to
have like write Se Linux palsy to try and make stuff work and you know,
read Dan's blog and be like, oh,
that's how he got the printer working in firefox on blah, blah, blah.
Right.
Yeah.
So I was looking at because somebody else mentioned App Armor and I'm like, oh man,
App Armor, like I haven't heard that in forever and it's,
it's actually on by default again in a couple of Linux
distro.
Yeah, like a
bunch.
It.
Exactly. And I'm like, oh yeah, it's, it's installed there.
I kind of forgot about it.
So I, I think App Armor
and Se Linux
are a good example of a technology that started with one purpose,
but we're actually using a lot of that functionality somewhere else
because a lot of what makes like Se Linux and
App Armor work is what makes containers secure now,
right?
So a lot of this technology might start in one place,
-- but we actually still end up using it somewhere else or
-- there's
like a new or better way of doing it like containers because
a perfect example.
So storytime openshift version,
one from Red Hat started out as a bunch of bash shell script and
C groups and Se Linux stuff and I found a couple escapes from it because
well, that's how that's gonna work.
And of course,
then they moved over to like darker style containers and then ultimately
Kernes
which
quite a bit more secure.
And
what's fascinating to me about this is that, for example,
we, computers used to be expensive. So we put everything on one server.
We had to, we,
we put the FTP and the email and
-- the web on one server because we could only afford one server.
-- OK.
So it's funny you say that too because I was talking to someone over the,
the Christmas time break
about this
because do you remember like that was the selling point of Linux
and UNIX is, you could run everything,
the web server and the mail server on one machine
and DNS and DH CPD and like straight up everything.
But if you ran Windows, you could only run one thing on a Windows computer.
It's
true.
-- I know people didn't but you know, you know what I mean?
-- No, no.
Like until Windows 2000 and Iis.
Yeah. No, that thing could not really be reliably made to do much.
-- Yeah.
-- Yeah. Like Windows nt even 2000, I think. A lot of people didn't.
I have an M CS E in Windows, NT four so I actually can speak from authority on this topic
in that. Yes, you could get NT four to serve. But
part of it was
Windows just had so much overhead and compute hardware was not that powerful.
Ok. Anyway, anyway,
-- so
-- this is like, so in my mind it's, it's weird to me though. So
I think we would both agree on the facts.
Se Linux and App Armor are everywhere, but at the same time, they're not successful.
And I would say a large part of that is because
the real use case,
it turns out that we want is containers where
we have a single privileged level within the container.
So we have like a database in the container or a
web server in the container or the application in a container.
And then we have very well defined
communication between them over network sockets,
which are actually really easy to secure
and it's hard to do shenanigans,
you know, whereas if I have access to the file system, your database is running on,
there's a whole lot of weird shenanigans I can do to break into it.
Exactly. So, OK, so that, that's interesting. Now, here's another one.
Why did open SSH succeed
and open BS D
kind of didn't
I have a better example of that I think? And they may be related.
So most people don't know this
but open SSH wasn't the first SSH,
it was
not.
-- The first SSH was, what was it, ssh.com?
-- I think it was. No, no, it was SSH by Tattoo
-- Yon.
-- OK.
I wrote a lot of articles about this guy and this topic. So,
but, but
-- what there was, there was a
-- tattoo wrote SSH, he invented it like he
-- was it GP
-- L what was his original license? Did it have? I don't
even know.
it was a weird license.
And then he tried to take a commercial and
close source it and that's where open SSH would
open the VSD forked and took off and then they improved it
a bunch and made it more reliable and to put it bluntly,
it worked better and it was free
and ssh.com tried to sell some things and add some enterprise stuff
features. Granted this is like 20 years ago,
then they ended up being bought by Tech
Tia
and uh it just sort of, it still exists but it kind of fizzled out.
And as far as I can tell, they went after the mainframe market,
which kind of makes sense because mainframe people are just like they have
money and they just want stuff to work and somebody to yell at.
No, it's a market like,
hey, we both work for restaurant
that's market adjacent.
Ok. The original was freeware.
It was freeware. It was not open source.
Yes. Ok. That sounds more familiar to me. Now, my brain
my brain isn't
going
back 25
-- years. It's
-- a long time ago.
I remember, I remember when it came out
because I worked at an ISP and I was like, oh, this is awesome. You need to use this.
I wrote articles comparing the benefits of SSH versus SSL telnet
uh or just regular tal
net, which is what most people use.
I mean, then there was Curarize
tal
-- net. There were some
-- and
the best
thing is
you cur
tail
net secured your login, but you could still inject characters into the stream.
See this is the beauty of telnet because it wasn't encrypted.
You could, if you could spoof packets,
-- you could inject keystrokes.
-- Well, that's harder.
-- But you could at least eavesdrop on
-- a local land in the olden days when it was hubs.
-- It was
-- all hubs, injecting keystrokes was still hard because you had to hijack the T
P
-- connection.
-- That's really easy in a hub situation because
you have all the traffic
you, you do. But there's still the isn't there? There's the weird prediction of the
sequencing number stuff. But the thing is you have all the data.
Yeah. OK. Anyway, whatever, I'm not arguing with you about this today.
Well, again, this is like so old that before the era of switches
-- it is,
-- it's my brain doesn't,
my brain can't remember how any of this
works anymore because I haven't done any of this
fire without rocks, even
without rocks
but ok, but here's,
I think what makes it interesting when we look at something like SSH,
like SSH, the protocol wildly successful. SSH,
the application,
I think SSH is probably a good example of something that if it wasn't open source,
it was destined to fail.
Right? Because the reality is like, what made SSH better than Telnet?
The killer app was the encryption, right?
Well, and then very shortly when SSH had file transfers
because the thing to remember is file transfers used to be
a
-- nightmare
-- without SCP, you had to FT oh It was horrible.
-- I remember
-- this is why FTP actually has
you can connect to FTP server A and tell it to interact with FTP server B
and
-- move files between A and B without the client even
-- anyway.
OK, we're not talking about, we're not
talking about FTP is also dead, but here's, here's what I think, right?
And, and this is where I think SSH is a really good example is
if SSH
was proprietary and you had to pay for it and
the only true benefit at the time was encrypted communication.
I don't think anyone would have bought it.
I don't think today anyone would buy it because
I think security is one of those things that
it's a really hard sell to get people to pay just for security.
You need other features for people to actually pay you money
and even
more
so like there's the exact corner cases of,
there are a handful of people that would pay for it, but so few that,
that basically proves your point.
It's,
it's enough to maintain a small company, but that's it.
-- But
-- now I think Open BS D, which you mentioned at the very beginning of this section
is the same story, right? Like is Open BS D more secure than Linux.
I mean, it was back in the day. I don't know if it still is.
-- I couldn't tell
-- you it's more secure if you don't turn anything on
-- which it means it's useless.
-- Here's the point, right?
If, if the only difference is more security,
but some of the other features are hampered which they were
that no one's gonna buy that.
And then by, I just mean use in this context, but it's, it's the same story. Like
if your only benefit is security,
you've already lost.
You need other reasons for people to care about and use the thing.
I mean, Se Linux is kind of the same story, right? Se Linux by itself can't stand
but all of the benefits you get from, you know, things like containers.
Now, we've got a story.
Well, and the other thing to remember is
Se Linux came from the NSA specifically
that the dod had use cases of, we have a humvee with seven computers.
We would like to buy one slightly faster computer and
run seven workloads on it that don't touch each other.
-- That's Right. And, and
-- I'm sure they're still using in, in bizarre and amazing ways.
And that's great because, but again,
now they are a very special use case that will
pay garbage trucks full of money for their particular need.
Well, that actually leads to a really a good example of
-- why wasn't mod security more successful?
-- I think it was successful.
-- I just don't think we need it anymore.
-- Well, so, ok. So what is mod security?
Do you want to take that one?
It was a plug in for
a, I don't know if it ran other things other than Apache, but it ran on Apache.
It runs under engine
-- X as well now and a couple others.
-- Oh, it does run on engine
-- X. OK. And
-- IIS.
-- No,
-- seriously
like that's
-- it.
-- It's oh my goodness. That
is po that's poetry. You can't make that up. But
mod security was, it was a plug in that it would,
we'll say stop bad things from happening.
You could add rules to it to prevent like
cross like scripting type traffic from coming in.
It could look for common attacks, it could stop.
Well, actually it did a couple of things.
What's really fascinating is it could filter incoming data,
it could filter the
outgoing stuff from the web server to the application site.
It could filter based on logging,
it could filter based on then the input from the
application back to mod security to the web server.
And it could filter outgoing and modify it.
So for example, you could do things like, wow, we changed our contact email address
and you could like create a MOD.
That's very
clever.
And that's the thing is it could,
it could rewrite both incoming and outgoing data at multiple stages of the request.
That's fair.
It was really just a magic regular expression engine is
-- fundamentally was that
-- had hooks into about six spots,
right?
And I think the thing that made Mod security powerful wasn't even the plug in itself.
It's the fact that it came with some pre
canned rules that people could just basically turn on.
And I think now if you're using basically any cloud provider on the planet,
all of this stuff is just b
well, they've, they've,
they've built something that is morally equivalent to mod security
written in a much faster language with much more capabilities,
right? And they take care of
for you and they're watching for new attacks and all kinds of stuff like that.
And that's what's fascinating to me is so mod security itself is kind of like,
but it spawned
not just not really an industry I'm going to say,
but it spawned essentially a feature that is now
the standard.
Yeah, for sure, for sure.
I mean, I think MOD security I would,
I would say was incredibly successful at what it was, what it did.
Like MOD security itself is. I mean, it probably still exists.
-- I haven't run it in literally decades. It is.
-- It's still around.
Like I remember I tried pitching it at a red hat
so that we could basically,
if we had like a cross site scripting flaw in one of our web-based products,
we could just ship them on security rule
and have it fixed right away with very low risk because it's just a mod security role.
But, and here was my real reason.
I wanted to do it because of all the government customers and stuff
where it's like if you want us to make a change to software,
we have a change process.
If you want us to make a configuration change. Yeah, we can do that.
And so they would have been able to deploy
the configuration change immediately.
Whereas if it's a software, a security update,
there's like a whole process for that.
And I,
and I think this goes to your selling security.
I wasn't even able to sell that internally at Red Hat is a good idea.
No, I'm serious.
-- Like I failed.
-- You need other reasons like by itself, it's probably
-- not
-- worth
it.
It's not so much that I was trying to sell them on security,
but I was trying to sell them more on this, on this, on.
This
will make life a lot easier,
especially for these customers and regulated
industries where a configuration changes,
no problem
-- and a code changes. Well, that's new software. We have to test it.
-- I have a suspicion
that you did a bad job explaining it that way
and you probably focused too much on security.
-- I've known you for a long time and I
-- own that.
But at the same time, like,
man, it just,
it's something that well, I mean, Clouder
does it by default. That's nice of them. Like the log for J thing. Right. Where
Kloer is like, oh, we figured out log for Jay and so we blocked it globally
and
here's the other thing to remember. Kurt is
that was back in the day of security,
just stood around and said we'll be sorry someday to everybody
and they never were.
But
yeah,
-- it happens. Anyway, what else we got on this list? So,
-- ok, so second last one
and I'm going to lump these in all three together is gonna be snort and map and Satan.
Oh, Satan, that's a term I haven't heard.
See what's fascinating to me is not just
all three, Satan and mappin
smart all had kind of rough childhoods, let's say,
well, what are, what are these tools? What do they do? Right.
So, Satan is security analysis tool for networks.
Wow, I'm impressed. You remember that? I have no idea.
S being security is the only letter I remember. And
um, and you know, the guy got fired from.
So because
-- Dan Farmer, right? That was his name. He
-- got, yeah, Dan Farmer, he got fired from. So
anyways and
map uh
network mapper.
That's easy. And snort is just, it snorts up packets
like
-- doing a line of, I mean, snort
-- still exists, right?
This is what's fascinating to me. It's not that these tools. OK.
Well, N map, not so much but snort and Satan.
And actually, instead of N map, you know what I should have gone with was um
NUS which was a security scanner but
snort, Satan and Nus and by extension N map,
not only are still successful and quite widely used, but they've spawned
not just entire industries that are quite successful,
but they are now required by many information, security regulations to be used.
-- Sure,
-- like PC I says you are required to scan your network.
You are required like in the finance industry
specifically, like there's a bunch of tools
NP
kind of got this all rolling or like looking at snort,
there's a lot of finance industry regulation that says you
have to be able to decrypt the data and,
-- and, and archive it or look at it or otherwise make sure it's OK.
-- Tools do that now
and snort was the progenitor to all this
and technically like D
sniff and ssh, sniff and stuff like that from Doug Song. Remember that.
-- But,
-- but snort isn't just about decrypting traffic as well.
It's about like logging and understand, I mean,
if you look at you, you got like Splunk and, and
there's a million SIM type tools and they all do a
lot of this stuff and you can write like rules to
look at the data and the network traffic. And it's, it's amazing now.
I mean, we could, we couldn't even imagine then what you can do with it today.
I think Satan is a more interesting example because Satan kind of died on the vine.
-- I think it never really got its true go
-- well.
But things afterwards like Nessus came out and Nessus was quite successful,
-- not
-- just Nessus.
I, I think Metas
Flo is closer to like the, the spirit of Satan
than any of those other tools maybe Nus.
Well, they all have plugins and,
and Nus had plugins and actually went to that wonky license where
if you didn't pay for NUS,
you couldn't distribute your plugins,
open source or whatever,
if you paid for the license or rather if you used open source, Nus,
you had to basically give your plug in back to them.
And if you bought it, you didn't have to because they, to put it bluntly,
the original author of it got tired of these contractors and consultants
making literal dump trucks full of money off of his open source
code and he got not even a bug report and return.
And so he went to a commercial company and they
wanted to monetize it because they wanted to buy food and stuff.
All right. Well, I keep
coming
back,
people keep wanting to buy food and so they
change their licensing so that they can do.
So
I, I get it. It's a tough one. There's a, there's actually a new story.
We'll have to talk about it at some point.
But Bruce Perens is beating that drum again about,
like what comes after open source so
good for him. I hope it goes somewhere.
I've been. Yeah.
Yeah, that is definitely another topic. Um,
but so,
so what's fascinating to me is like I said that these not only mostly succeeded, but
they spawned
success to the point where they are now required elements for
a
-- lot of information security.
-- Well, it works and
we like it,
data is cool. You can do amazing things with it.
It doesn't surprise me.
I feel like this is kind of the story of good security tech is you invent something.
And then a decade later it spawns like new industries and products
that aren't necessarily having anything to do with the original tool.
But it's kind of the basic idea of it, right?
Although S SSH didn't, did SSH spawn
a product, not really. It just changed the
world.
Like
I think it was what got us rolling on the, hey,
shouldn't everything be encrypted all the time everywhere?
-- I
-- mean, it might have part. No, you know what, you know what SSH really did
without SSH, we couldn't have had like colo type environments really.
And the colo environments eventually turned into the cloud
and without SSH,
we couldn't have managed any of that stuff.
I mean, look at things like answerable, literally use SSH as their transport layer.
This is back to the thing where
it's a, it's a subtle but important distinction.
SSH is not just telnet, SSH is telnet plus our command
plus FTP.
You can, you can still do SSH dash capital Y to have X windows,
things like remote over SS A
and you can do X window forwarding, you can do socks proxy. So I've actually used SSH,
I, I've actually used SSH as a VPN while I'm on the road because
I can ssh over. Well, back in the day, I always ssh over.
I had one running on port 80 because nobody ever blocked that
and then 4443.
But that's the thing, right? SSH is this pipe between end point A and end point B
and
how do I say this nicely VPN S suck and don't work 20 years ago.
Ok.
Nowadays VPN S are great and we actually have a couple
of standards like wire guard and open VPN that actually work.
But 20 years ago, we did not have that.
And if I wanted a Linux machine to talk to a BS
D machine or a UNIX machine or a Windows machine securely,
my only choice was SSH,
that was the only cross platform thing.
Ignoring you're right because ignoring the encryption, it gave me
I can interactively log in I can transfer files, I can send commands.
It did have magic in it. It was amazing what it all picked up.
So I still use it for running X Windows applications on remote systems.
Like I use it all the time, which amuses me.
So I think maybe the lesson here is that well, actually, because how do sort of,
well, if the lesson is you have to do more than security,
you actually have to be useful
for, to have success.
That's not really like with snorting and map and Satan, those things,
those things are kind of fundamentally just security things
that don't really give you a new capability.
How come they were so successful?
I don't think they were,
I don't think they were particularly widely used outside of the security industry.
But then you saw them birth some of this other technology,
you know, things like Sims
and logging class
just for the record. What are SIMS again?
It's si em security information and event management.
It's like Splunk and elastic search and
basically it's more logic data. There's like millions of them
and they,
they ingest tons and tons of data
and then they, you can do magic things with them.
Well, the biggest thing that gets me is the correlation aspect of like,
oh here's a TP connection followed by a weirdly running process,
followed by outgoing data.
That's an attack.
Versus if I look at those three things separately, I have no idea what's going on.
That's right. And you have to be able to correlate these things because if you don't,
you know, it, it,
-- maybe it's an attack, maybe it's
-- every time you hear that story, it's like, you know,
they ex filtrated a terabyte of data from Boeing to China.
It's kind of like,
-- how did you not catch that
-- because people aren't watching
the network logs and there's probably someone torrenting porn already.
So it doesn't matter. So
that's generally how it goes
anyway. Anyway. I mean,
this, this topic amuses me.
We'll have to revisit it with some other things because I feel like
I feel like there's some interesting history behind all of this
and I especially love some of the things like, you know,
how did ssh kind of get to where it is today?
And it, it's like it's magic today. I mean,
dude,
it's on everything by default and it's the
only thing that's turned on by default anymore,
right?
It's like the Ed of its day.
Remember when Ed was the only editor on Cisco routers, you know, you had to learn Ed.
That's why I still know vi I know how to escape from vi I know how to delete lines,
-- find stuff because,
-- oh my goodness.
I,
I have a very funny story to tell you. So the uh Obsidian the, the Note Taking app,
it has a V I mode they added
and to turn on V I mode it says, please type
what you like, please type the characters to exit V I
and if you get them wrong, it says something like I'm sorry,
we can't enable this to protect you.
That's actually not the worst idea because like
that can be frustrating. You get stuck in there.
Like um my old keyboard had uh if you hit control, left alt number,
it would change the keyboard mode
and there was another, I forget what the magic key control was,
but it would disable the windows key and
I would accidentally disable the windows key once every
month or two and then be like hit windows L to lock my computer and be like,
oh, it broke great.
And then I'd have to like Google how to, you know, get this to work again.
And because I can't remember what key code.
So anyways, I replaced it with a nice corsair keyboard
that doesn't do dumb stuff like that to disable the windows key.
It actually has a dedicated lock key on the thing.
Why would you disable the windows key when you're, it's a gaming keyboard?
So you don't want to accidentally hit the Windows key and like
get
out of your
game.
It's actually got a tournament mode, check it out.
So it's got this little switch here with a hardware tab that like locks over it.
So you can put it in tournament mode and
that disables like all the preprogrammed key combos.
And stuff. So it's just a keyboard.
Yeah, it's a nice keyboard.
Yeah.
I mean, I feel like that makes sense anyway. It's the magic of technology, man.
All right, I'll give you the last word on this one.
I still think that we don't do enough post mortems on both
failure and success and we don't know why things fail or succeed.
That's just human nature, man.
I'm not gonna.
-- But I
-- feel like,
don't you think security businesses would do this more
to figure out how to build better products and
succeed? Right? Like that.
-- That's,
-- well, that's a complicated question,
I think with a complicated answer and the way I would answer it is simply,
I think there's an enormous number of security things that
exist that are terrible garbage and should have failed.
And there's an enormous number of awesome products
that did fail and it's really the whole,
you're just, if you're in the right place at the right time, you can get lucky.
I think there's definitely an element of that.
But yeah, I, I just,
I feel like it would be nice to understand why things fail
and succeed a bit more so we can maybe do better.
Like that's this recent thing on Mastodon about, you know, sites that disable
pasting and you can't use a password manager with them. And I'm like,
right,
that sounds not only like a security vulnerability because I'm forcing you to use
bad passwords or cut you know, do some weird stuff
but also from A US,
-- you
-- know, the, the New Firefox has a force paste
good. That's actually a show.
II, I actually wanted to cover ad blockers on the show, but I actually,
what I think we need to do it somewhat is a future show about
how web browsers are essentially having to protect us from websites and bad stuff.
I mean, it's kind of turning into that. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. All right. Anyway, anyway,
uh I would, I would love to say everyone should do post mortems,
but it even postmortems are complicated
because the obvious reason the security product succeeded is because I'm awesome.
And I built it right. That's why, that's why it did.
It's, it's hard to do a proper postmortem
without letting like personal opinion and ego get in the way
also premortem. So I've started doing some premortem stuff and it's like, oh,
yeah,
-- I don't know what that means.
-- You basically, what are my assumptions?
What could go wrong? What could go, right?
-- What might this look like if X that's
-- product management?
Like?
All right, I'm ending this. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you all for listening. Go to open
source security podcast.com. Hit up the show TZ
Pound
Os podcast. Hashtag Find us on
as
on Kurt. You have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye bye.