Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
-- Josh
-- Pressers. All right. I'm excited today.
We have Jay Jacobs, one of the creators of EP Ss Ss on the show.
-- Jay. Welcome to the show,
-- man.
Hey, thanks for having me. Glad to finally be on here with you guys.
It's funny because
epss, this is becoming like a, a very, I, I think
important topic and vulnerabilities and I look back, I'm like, holy crap.
We've almost, we've done almost nothing about it on, on here,
which is kind of surprising to me.
But
regardless
that makes me happy because you're here and you're like, you're the pro.
So let's start at the beginning. What does VPs SS stand for? And what is it?
It is the exploit prediction scoring system
and it does the, the best that it can trying to exactly as the name implies,
predicting
exploitation activity in the wild specifically over the next 30 days.
One quick clarifying question.
So this is exploitation by bad guys or who like pen testers.
Yeah,
that's a very important question because essentially we
have to start talking about the data behind epss
because it is I I was very clear to say exploitation activity,
not necessarily first uh successful exploitations because we're
getting honey pots that will never be exploited
or shouldn't be exploited.
And then DS IP S uh devices, you know,
that will typically like IP S typically will block most of the activity.
And
to your point
when you see a packet coming into your
network probing or trying to exploit something,
you have no idea.
If it's an academic researcher trying to catalog what is good and you know,
like that stuff or if it is a malicious thing, so you have no idea.
And so
it is just pure exploitation activity.
I want to ask about epss versus CV SS because I think
CE Ss is the kind of dominant rating system we have today.
And I think it is universally hated by all security people.
Yeah,
I don't know if I would say I hate it, but I, I think everybody has an opinion
-- about
-- a negative opinion about,
can I
for a thought?
It's,
I think CBS has made a lot of sense when it
was created and for what it was created because for example,
as a security, especially when we worked at Red Hat,
99% of all I cared about is, is this network or not network
and authenticated or not authenticated?
Like I need those two questions answered for every vulnerability I'm,
I'm processing and
CV SS is actually quite useful for that.
And
same thing when I worked at I saw and I defense.
But I think the problem is because it's the only shoe we have.
Everybody ended up trying to climb Mount Everest in that shoe.
Totally. Yes.
So my, my take on it to your point, Kurt,
I think that the individual metrics are super useful.
And I would, I really hope that that maintains forever
to have somebody go in and say, hey, this is network accessible or hey, this is,
this does require some type of prerequisite or something like that.
Um I think that's really, really helpful, but I think where it starts to fall down is
except the two things, one, it produces a score and prior to version four,
the way that score is produced is
interesting. And then
the other challenge is that it, it is a one thing for everything.
Um And so people would use it and typically just the base
score not get into the environmental and the threat stuff and just say
this base score represents risk even though
like the, the documentation of CV SS says it's not risk, everyone uses it at risk. And
you know, I mean, honestly, it is risk.
-- I mean, that's what they're trying to measure.
-- We don't have anything else
to do.
We don't,
there's no other 0 to 10 number than a manager wants on a spreadsheet to offer them
unless well, now there's a new one,
right?
And Epss though, specifically is exploitation activity.
So, like we just said, the base score,
no one gets into the environmental and the threat stuff.
Epss is just that threat side.
It has no idea about the context of the vulnerability, the value of the asset,
what's behind it, what's around it?
-- None of that is just the threat.
-- Yes. And, and so let's talk about that.
What is like, what does that mean? What does it mean to
detect exploit ability? How does that process work?
So
-- you mean like the data that we're collecting or kind of
-- the machine? Right?
Because you collect data and then you do stuff with
the data and then you output a score essentially,
-- but you don't output a score for every CV E
-- no, every CV.
Oh It is every CV E
-- the initial version was not every CV E
-- oh cool. I didn't, I didn't know that.
That's good. I learned something new.
Yeah, we're on the, we're on the third version of the Epss model.
Soon to be
3.1 or four. So I don't know, something like that.
Nice. All right. So anyway, explain the machine to us then what does that look like?
Yeah.
Yeah. And so we get as much data as I can possibly collect and
maybe it'll help actually go back to version one because there was initially a paper
I think it was 2019 presented at Black hat where we presented this paper
on the first epss version and we had CBS S in mind.
And so I did a bunch of data collection and we were working with,
I was doing work with Kenna at the time consulting and,
and doing some research for him and publications and
they had a bunch of data about vulnerabilities.
And we had another client that I was working with,
that had a bunch of exploitation activity
and Kenna had some of their own.
I was like, hey, we could bring these together and create a little prediction thing.
And so
essentially, the first time we were like, all we want people to calculate a score.
So we're gonna make this as the word was parsimonious as parsimonious as possible,
right?
The fewest number of variables that would create a good model.
And I think we had 16 variables or something
and
we created just a simple uh logistic regression which
is like one variable has a weight and that weight
can be combined in a certain way that you
end up with a probability between zero and one.
And
so we expected people to have a spreadsheet
and to implement this in the spreadsheet and go get these 16 variables,
right?
And you get the, the humor
right, right off the bat. And,
and this was problematic and so largely it was just sort of an academic exercise,
release this paper.
And then Sasa Romanoski who works at rand,
um him and I were talking about this and he's one of the
co-author on the original paper.
I mean, he's like, we should,
we should make a go of this and bring this into like first or some group and
stand up a group around this to really help build out what this model can do.
And so we did that and we started having meetings and then
it dawned on me that like this is no longer a spreadsheet world, right? This is
live api S everyone's connected.
Why aren't we just calculating this in one central location?
Uh And so we started doing that, I started producing these scores daily,
given these 16 variables.
And the first model wasn't great,
it was better than CV SS specifically for exploitation activity.
Um And so
that's how it started.
Like with these 16 variables,
you would get them and the model would look at the exploitation activity
and then all this input variable and build a model,
derive those weights based on the outcomes, right?
Um And a very simple, you know,
like the regression was developed 200 years ago at this point.
Um So it's a 200 year old technique that we're doing in vulnerabilities.
And,
and that worked, I mean, like it was pretty good, it wasn't great,
uh really easy to find all these examples where Epss was terrible.
And so fast forward though, we started to centralize it.
And then I was like now that we're centralizing it.
Nobody is going to do this in a spreadsheet.
We can go crazy, right? We can
drop the whole regression simple model. Go to a much more complex model.
We can start to include
every variable,
every piece of data we can get our hands on because no
longer do we have to ask people to go get this data?
Right? They don't have to go look up if something hasn't met us white.
Um We're doing all of that for them and that's what it is now.
So the version two went to it was a I believe,
oh it was a GLM net um
Reg
and Lasso um thing.
Anyway,
so that had like 1000 variables in version two
and then version three,
we went to uh an X two boost model which has a iterative cycle to it.
And so one of the challenges is in version three,
a variable no longer has a single weight.
Um And so people say like, hey, what's the contribution of something being in meta
flight? And you're like, well, it depends on all the other variables.
Yeah, sure, sure.
Well, as it should I, that's one thing that's always drive me nuts is
like, it's this, it's this
really tightly linked in ecosystem of stuff with human actors
and
like there's humans making decisions like II I literally
their process for picking, you know,
what do we write an exploit for was literally like,
three people and then taking a smoke break and hashing it out.
Right.
Yeah.
But I mean, because, and people think there's like, some
big statistical, like, no, it's just like three guys in a room.
-- And
-- I think that is the case everywhere. By the way,
I
don't imagine how it would be anything but that, because, like,
yeah,
and I mean, like, what's interesting is something like
metas so a lot of the
threat intel type sources like metas
point where you've got humans
making a judgment about what to go watch for or to
write exploit for or to scan for anything like that.
A lot of the pen testing tools are this way,
they are highly efficient.
In other words, like a lot of what they choose,
we actually see exploitation activity in the case of metas
that might be causal.
Uh But
for, you know, like a pen testing tool
that is purely correlation.
And so, but their,
their decision to go look at or include this in their tooling or
something is a really good indicator that there's probably going to be activity,
but it's also like only a small fraction of what's actually being exploited.
Um So they're really efficient but they don't have really good coverage.
And these are terms that we talk about in A PSS, the efficiency and coverage
as we try to measure how good it's working.
And so, but back to the model,
um how it actually works. So that's this is how we're training it.
Now, we have all of this exploitation activity.
And the other thing is when we talk about exploitation activity,
we need that temporal aspect.
We need to know there was exploitation activity
last Sunday.
Uh And then was it on Saturday as well? The day before that?
And how did that look for the last two years?
And we need to know that whereas something like,
you know, you look at the Kev list and it says,
yep,
that's all you get.
Yes,
exploitation equals yes.
And that isn't helpful because
you know, I just released some research for the Epss A
saying that you know, what was it like?
50% of things marked as exploited were exploited in the last week,
we had evidence of this.
But then before that, we see roughly like 25%.
Can't remember the exact step, like 25%
were not seen exploited in like the last year.
So a quarter of the things that we saw
exploitation activity for out of like 14,000 CV ES,
we had evidence of exploitation activity.
25% were not seen exploited in the last year. So when somebody says, yes,
I want to say like still is it still exploited?
Let me make sure I understand what you just said because
I'm not real smart. So that feels like
over my head a little bit.
So you're saying if you look at all
of the vulnerabilities that we have exploitation data about
once they become, let's say, a year old,
75% kind of fall off the radar and are no longer being exploited by threat actors.
Well,
you got it, it's, it's way more complicated than that, unfortunately.
So that is not what you said
it.
Right. It's, it's pretty close though.
I mean, like I could say, yeah, that's, that works.
Um
Well, my one question because, OK, so like I know if you stand up a web server,
you'll see people still trying to hit front page.
Microsoft front page stopped existing,
I don't know, a decade or two ago
and
obviously there must still be installs of it
because people keep trying to s swack it.
Um But I'm assuming that there's like a lot of web software
that people just kind of give up on or stop trying,
which is weird to me because like, if I was an attacker,
I would just shock on that sucker.
Like,
right, because what's the downside?
And I guess one of my questions would be, is
these things that stop being, you stop seeing exploit activity for?
Is it
like, do they actually go away? Like are they gone?
Uh
I don't know,
you mean like the technologies go away or the exploits?
Yeah, like,
like are people not trying to break into Mazda cars anymore because there's no
more Mazda cars or is we're actually not seeing that kind of thing,
right?
I mean,
you got to remember like the the actors who are doing this have, you know,
cost versus benefit calculations, right?
And so
one of the things that we do notice is after
a vulnerability is published, like in the first month of any,
any vulnerabilities life.
Um If you actually, if you look at the first month of all the vulnerabilities
and you have that sliding window whenever it was published,
there's a lot of variation.
There's a lot of trial and error that we see in exploitation activity,
we see people sort of trying something. There's, you know, like, I don't know.
Um So many of these have exploitation activity and they
sort of die out after a couple of months or,
you know,
maybe they start a year after it was published and
they try a couple of things and they're like,
hey, we're not getting a lot of hits on this,
let's try something else or something like that.
So,
and to clarify, when you say trying,
I'm assuming that they actually have a working exploit that they're
then trying to see if there's enough people to make it worth
using, like they're not trying to make a working exploit.
That's a theory.
Yeah.
So it's,
it's hard to know exactly what they're doing because
all we're getting is that the signature got triggered
generally. So getting motivation behind that is kind of hard. But yeah, I mean,
so we do see, like, activity
sort of sporadic at the beginning, a lot of variation.
But after, you know, like a year or two,
after publication it all sort of settles down.
And so, like,
week after week you're seeing the same things being
exploited for stuff that's more than two years old.
-- But you're
-- seeing more exploits for things two years
-- again. Like I, I wish I could say.
-- Yes.
That's fine. That's fine.
Well, I, I just heard we should only run software between one and two years old.
Right.
Well, I'm also wondering like, how much of this is Survivor bias of the data, right?
Because
I guess one could make the argument like log for Jay,
you know, cloud Fleer came out that post saying, oh, actually,
whoops, we saw this like, what, eight days or 11 days in advance or like over a week.
Um
And I'm kind of wondering because like,
they're not going to look for every single exploit to
see how many days in advance of it being public.
Was it exploited? Because
-- that would be a lot of work?
-- Yeah.
So this, that you're touching on some something that is
a
really interesting topic that the Survivor bias.
In other words, like
we're seeing, are, are we seeing exploitation for the ones that we're looking for?
Right.
Because clearly, clearly with 240,000 CV ES right now,
we do not have a signature for all of them,
right? And we've got a signature. I think it's like 10 15% of those have a signature
for detection.
And so the question is like, what about the other 90% is that being exploited?
And the way we get around that is that there's nothing in epss
that says this particular vulnerability has been exploited in the past
if that makes sense. So we don't have that's a auto
aggressive feature saying like,
so like we know log for shell example is a great example,
like it would be great if we had a model set,
this is was exploited yesterday and the day before and the day before,
we're gonna expect it to be exploited tomorrow.
But epss does not do that specifically for this reason.
It basically says, hey, this is a vulnerability that has these attributes.
We know that exploit code is published here. It's got exploit code here.
It's this type of vulnerability CV SSS all these metrics
and we have all these attributes.
And then, and then the model says, hey, this looks like
a vulnerability that we see with exploitation activity
over on this side.
So even if something doesn't have a signature,
there's a really high, there's a chance that it may be rated highly
because we don't have that feedback loop directly in the scoring system.
Well,
because I was gonna ask like it from what I
read the paper and it doesn't sound like for example,
you're using the CIA known exploded vulnerabilities catalog
to kind of back feed into like OK,
like this was a good prediction because Kev saw it and I I'm also
guessing part of that is because the Kev didn't really exist when you started,
like it only literally,
it's only in what the last three months or
four months that they've actually been publishing data publicly.
And I'm curious now that they are doing that however,
and being a bit more gung ho on it,
is that something you're looking to maybe use as a
data source now that it is kind of useful.
It's in version 30 OK.
And what's interesting as I was talking about Epss
needs that temporal aspect and Kev doesn't have it.
Sorry, what do you mean exactly by that? Because that's something I think.
Yeah, first of all, what is temporal score mean in CV SS terms?
Yeah, ignore the CBS S temporal.
I'm just talking about a time aspect to exploitation activity.
So Kev like just says, it says here, I'm putting the CV E on the Kev list on this date.
And that's all you know,
and they're saying this is known to be exploited.
They're saying it's binary like there's
either exploitation activity or there isn't
right. And that's not the real world. I mean like the real world is we have super
bursts. We have
like I said, some are no longer exploited,
some are exploited like unbelievably everywhere.
Most of the time, all the time. And so it's, it's not a, it's not a yes or no thing.
And so Kev Kev is an Epss version three, but it is not an outcome variable.
Is, it is an indication.
We use it as an indicator.
In other words like a
CV E. So there's things on the Kev list that we do not see exploitation activity for.
-- Oh, interesting.
-- Yeah.
Yeah.
And that's one thing I was wondering because I,
I assumed Kev kept their data close to the vest because they, you know,
the whole classic
uh what's the term uh sources and ways and means of collection, right?
Because they don't want to be like, oh yeah, this Kev was exploited,
Raytheon on this system one
versus this other one, you know, log
which like obviously being exploited.
And so,
right?
And that's the problem I've always wondered about these data sets is like, yeah,
it literally Stuxnet would be one in, you know, that would be no exploited versus
obviously they're not going to, you know,
probably put that on the list and they're certainly not going to give details about
it.
Yeah.
Yeah. And so that's the challenge, right?
Um We don't know if this was exploited once at one location or everywhere,
all the time.
Um And so when Epss uses it, it says, hey,
I've got this signal just like what analysts say,
hey, I've got this signal, something was added on the Kev.
Should I care about it
next month,
you know, or like it was added six months ago and this just popped up on my network.
Should I still care about it?
And that's what epss is doing.
So you keep talking Jay about kind of the signal and the data you're looking at.
Where does this all come from? The feedback loop?
No, no, I mean, you're collecting like data on if something has been exploited,
where are you getting that from?
Because that's hard data to find
that is extremely hard data to find.
So a couple of sources, the big one is Fort
Fort,
you know, they've got 100,000 devices or something. Um
And they were,
they were an early partner and we've done a lot of consulting with them,
doing a lot of helping out with some of their research and stuff like that.
Um And so they were an early partner and
the way,
unfortunately, the way epss has traditionally gotten data is like for, for
that, I would send an email to the guy. I'm working with the for
and be like, hey, can
early on I was like, I'm building this new thing called epss.
Can I use your data to help train it? And I got an email back saying sure
because I had the date already, right? So this is the data sharing agreement
uh that we have in place, but we're working on, you know,
making that more official and things like that.
So we've got, fortunate
we've got Alien Vault, their, their OTX system behind the scenes reporting on,
on stuff that they're seeing.
We've got shadow server.
These are all on the website and I'm trying to do off the top of my head.
That's ok. I don't remember either.
But you, you have these data sources, right.
Yeah, they are not public except for shadow server. Um, gray noises in there
which I know some people complain about here and there, but I,
I'm OK with it. I think this is hard to find.
And if there's organizations willing to contribute, that's a pretty big deal.
I think.
I mean, I worked in this industry that data sells for a lot of money.
They're not going to give it away for free
because that's
literally
their business model is to not give it away for free.
So I could totally see them maybe letting you use it.
But yeah,
there's no way you're going to get to republish it because that would be insane,
right?
And that's one of the things like people always say, you know,
you know what's exploited, why don't you just tell us, I'm like,
I can't like we're using this data to try and
create something more than what's in the data. So,
-- um yeah,
-- so one question I have is
and maybe, you know, maybe you don't know, but the data you're collecting,
it sounds like would be
mostly dealing with sort of widespread
exploitation versus highly targeted attacks.
Would that,
is that fair to say?
-- Or or are you actually also catching indicators of highly targeted attacks?
-- So
one of the interesting things in a recent report that we released is we found,
I think it was like 75%
of
the exploitation activity that we captured
-- were seen at less than one in 10,000 devices.
-- Oh, wow.
So like
tiny, tiny fraction,
sorry, 75% at less than one in 10,000.
Yeah. So
three out of four vulnerabilities that we have exploitation activity for.
We're super sparse.
Yeah, I don't know what to say to that. I'm literally speechless
on the other side.
So I mean,
we're talking about 14,000 vulnerabilities here
that we have exploitation activity for.
And so it's really sparse.
And so if you, if you take that into account and then go back to our kev conversation
and they're saying this is being exploited and I'm not seeing anything
that may not be weird,
you know, like if
like if Attackers go after something,
they prob I mean, if they're really going after some value,
they're not gonna spray the internet, right?
They're probably gonna do some reconnaissance or something, you know.
And so you were not going to see, we're gonna see, what do we say? Like,
I don't know, 10
I wish I had the, the stat up in front of me, but
like some small portion of cbes are actually seeing
it more than like one in 100 you know,
like 5 10% something like that.
Like some tiny,
tiny amount of actually exploited vulnerabilities are seen widespread.
Let's, let's build off that point because I think that's kind of the,
that is the thing. I mean, as much as I love being in the weeds here, I think that
we have right now 250,000 plus CD ES in existence.
But it's a very, very small number that actually matter, right?
And I think if we look back, you know, 1015,
20 years ago when things like CV SS were being, you know, created and, and all of that,
the number of vulnerabilities we had to care about was small.
And now the number is an avalanche that no one can deal with.
And this, I think is the key to Epss, right? Epss is going to give us
the ability to prioritize this list in a way that is meaningful. Versus
when we try to use CV S SS today,
we just end up with this huge pile of criticals and people are like, holy crap.
What do I even do here?
Yeah.
And you know,
looking at CV S si think it was like over half
of them are marked as high and critical over 70 Yeah.
It's, it's crazy. Yeah.
And with Epss, another, a huge challenge for Epss is that the distribution is not
anywhere intuitive So like
uh some large percent, like, I don't know, 85% are under a 2% probability.
So like most of the CV ES are really, really low chance of exploitation,
which is actually intuitive.
But when people look at the score, they're like, why don't I see a bell curve?
You know,
I want a bell curve on this day,
I want all the scores to be pretty and symmetrical and it's like, no, no, no,
they're way over on the left
and, and you have that graphic if,
if you can send it to me or I'll try to take it up where you show that,
that curve over time
and it really tightens up and yeah, it shifts really left
as, as Epss progresses and your data collection becomes better and all that.
-- It's super cool.
-- Yeah.
Yeah, I'm trying to bring it up so I can get it to you guys while we're talking
so well. And obviously, so how do I phrase this?
There's kind of the elephant in the room here of you're only dealing with CV ES,
which makes sense because as any of our show listeners may or may not know
if you try and track down a vulnerability that does not have a CV E
like you might be able to track down the original issue or whatever in github,
but then trying to find any discussion of it
is basically impossible, right?
You're, you're doing tons of Google searches and good luck with that.
And so
like, is epss ever looking to cover outside of CV or is it just so much of a chore?
Like, how do you match signatures and names to stuff? Right. Without CV.
It's impossible.
So, I'm, I'm guessing that Epss is just like
there's just not enough good data there for us
to even try or is that something you're looking at
long term?
It is clearly, uh I don't know if I would call it like a weakness of epss.
It's a weakness of the industry.
That was gonna be my follow up question actually was,
is this again like this whole sort of we fix
CV ES because we don't have any other fixes,
right? Like literal. No, no.
Like literally, like when we worked at Red Hat, Josh, we did,
we ever ship a security update that did not have a CV attached to it.
-- We would have gotten one if it didn't.
-- Exactly.
And, and so I think kind of by definition people fix CV. S because,
well, that's, that's the only patches my vendor provides me.
Yeah.
And
you know, as we talked about, I think I'm collecting like 30 different data sources,
30 disparate
data sources.
And to your point, Kurt
trying to say if somebody calls it, you know, barking spider.
And the other one is, you know, crawling ants like you don't, they the same thing.
There's no way programmatically
do this. If you want to do it.
You have to go through a manual and there's no way
for every vulnerability to go through every data source and say,
ah I see how this is mapping like that just doesn't work.
But
I think, you know, going back to some of our other discussions offline is what about,
you know, using like the
github advisory uh number or the Red Hat advisory?
They have their own numbers, right? And they,
um, OS V has their own numbering system.
Can these start to be used to, to get more data behind? Just CV ES?
And I think the answer is yes, but that's going to have to be
a, a concerted effort by people collecting data.
You have to have some type of identifier
and it can't be your own internal one and that's it.
Well, something like, I don't think I've ever seen anybody discussing a ghsa,
a github
-- security advisory ID by the GHS A number ever in my whole life.
-- It's possible though
it could happen somewhere.
Yeah, it certainly.
But I, I, like I've only ever seen people refer to CV S and again,
Survivor buys like everything I buy at the store has a barcode on it because
Powells would, they put it on a shelf and sell it?
-- Well,
-- and I, I think what we see happening like this happens in, in the GHS.
A universe is if something becomes important enough, we need to talk about it.
Someone just goes in gets ac be for it. Right.
It's very survivor bias in that regard where it's just event driven.
And I think we see that across every vulnerability
ecosystem is there might be a ton of stuff
that doesn't have a CV E but I also suspect if it had an EP SS S score,
the EPSS score would be incredibly low because if it was high,
someone's going to get a CV E for it, that way we can track it and do something about it.
Yeah.
-- OK.
-- Jay, I want to ask you kind of and I know we're kind of coming towards the end here.
So I wanna, I wanna focus in on, on kind of Epss and, and how it's used,
I think the best and, and I, I will,
I can't wait to see what you think of this.
But I think the best example I've heard of, of how to apply epss.
Well,
the best example that my tiny brain can comprehend will say is
take the CBS S score multiply it by the Epss score.
And now you have something approaching like a
way to actually assess what you're dealing with.
I
want to make a pleasant response but that is I get a very official reaction to this.
-- This is, this is
-- so you hate this. OK. Now I'm even more interested.
That is a terrible approach.
That is
that is I,
yeah, I, I want to throw more cold for words in there to really stress how bad that is
the beeper when I add it, go for it.
So you could just like, hold down the beeper during this whole phrase and just like,
just the whole thing is a beep.
Yeah, it is. It's, I, I can't, you know, it's like what's, what's in, in physics?
And I'm not that great at physics but, you know,
when you measure a particle or something, you've got the,
the direction and the speed
and someone says, well, I want to rank them.
So you take the direction of speed and you multiply them
like you never do that.
That is not a thing when you describe this, you've got the,
the direction and the speed, right?
It's CV, SS and epss are
different. I mean, they're, they're
like to first epss is 0 to 1 and CV SS is 0 to 10. So you
at least get them on the same scale.
But then like if you just multiply them, you've got, you know, up to 10,
multiplying against whatever, up to one and CV SS is gonna wait,
you know, 90% of that score for sure. Um, 99 anyway.
But so like, it's just, it's a terrible idea because here's,
here's why it's a terrible idea.
One. What is CV SS actually measuring?
And this is like an open question and people are going to say, oh, it's not risk,
it's severity.
What is severity,
you know,
like that in all of my studying of risk analysis and risk models that is not a term used
in these risk models.
You've got, you know,
threat and likelihood or probability and consequences impact.
No one says severity, they might say it for an impact. So, is this measuring impact?
No, no, no, no, no.
-- This
-- is, there is one threat model that does consider severity and it's the, uh,
the chemical
engineers one for things like that because then things go boom.
Is that the severity of the impact?
-- Yes. Right.
-- So that makes sense.
Like do basically, and it boils down to will people die,
right?
And so that's the only time I've ever seen that though.
-- So
-- typically, you know, and fair, the fair model did a great thing where they
had this whole taxonomy, but
then they got it right. I mean, like you've got some pressure, which is the threat,
applying some force and then you've got your ability to resist that
or lack of resistance and then you've got some outcome
and this is another problem where you're getting like
when you have the probability of some event happening
and then the outcome,
those are another thing that you never multiply together yet people do.
Right?
Um And so when you take CV SS, which is,
it is measuring, it's trying to be a risk score
even though they, it's not in there,
they try to be a score and then you take epss which is just measuring the threat
and you're multiplying that together. Like, what, what are you multiplying?
It's like, you know,
I've got apples and then I've got a car in
the driveway and I want to bring them together.
You know, it's like, wait, no, no, no, these are totally different.
But I,
I get a number on the other side and people like
numbers because then I can order them in my spreadsheet.
Yeah,
the logic to me always seems struck me as like, ok,
the chances of us getting broken into our 50%.
So like we're going to put locks on 50% of the doors to meet that 50% threat.
Right.
That's literally like, or, or we're gonna, you know,
get the cheap lock instead of the expensive lock.
Yeah,
or another thing is like, you know, taking the CS is people,
people learn about the annualized annualized loss expectancy where you take
a,
you know, you have one event that has $100 impact and then it only happens once a year.
So every year you lose $10
and that's not the case.
Like you're gonna have one year while you lose it all and, you know,
it's not $100 it's $10 million.
So, like,
you might be able to afford, you know, that annualized loss every year,
but when it hits once and it's $10 million you can absorb that,
you know, that is totally different.
I think a big part of the problem is a lot of this kind of thinking about
risk came from the physical world where we
do kind of have large numbers and statistics and
we can sort of box, like if you rob a bank, the,
the most amount of money they can lose is how much of money the bank holds.
Right.
Ignoring costs.
Like, you know, everybody gets killed or the bank gets blown up or something,
which generally doesn't happen thankfully.
But, yeah, with a cyber event, you know, we're seeing
events where, oh,
nobody can get their prescription medication in like half the US for like, what,
two weeks or something.
Oops. So, back to your question, jos,
how do you combine these two or how would you use it in practice? Right.
That's sort of your, your ultimate question.
Yeah. And, and that's, that's like that, that is the final question, right?
So, we've got epss, we have this number
and
what do we do with it?
And I know that in all of my readings and the things you've written and said,
and in just the Epss universe in general is
there seems to be,
we'll say, uh, a
desire to not rank them in order. Right. That's not the goal here.
I mean, Epss is just measuring threats. So you can absolutely rank them
in order of threat likelihood.
Right. So you can, you can rank that
Um And you do,
I think the resistance that we have in epss that
I personally have is to bin them to say like,
hey, an epss score of 50% or higher is a critical
and
20 to 50% is a high, whatever it is,
wherever those thresholds lie for a central body to bend it.
Like that is super egotistical like,
hey, I understand everybody's risk and everybody's risk, risk is the same.
So everyone should have this threshold,
everyone should call this critical like that is not the case at all.
-- Plus
-- 60 percent of the time works every time, right?
So, but how, how to use it. So
one of the things that I've been very adamant about is keeping epss
simple. It is just a score, it is a probability
and there's a whole characteristics of probability that we can exploit here
to combine
multiple things.
And then,
and that's all it is and specifically about
exploitation activity expected over the next 30 days.
And so
in whatever risk model you have,
that is a very nice neat component.
You know, it fits into one of the boxes in the fair model,
it fits into, you know, threat times vulnerability equals impact, it fits in there
and it's only one component. And so
as a consumer, you have to figure out the other boxes in your model and
some people have to figure out what those boxes should be in the first place.
And just from my experience, like there are
for, for everybody doing right,
management. There are just as many, if not more models. Yes,
in Cyber,
in Cyber. So that's part of the challenge. So, back to the whole quick thing though.
So like if you think CV SS is truly
valuable and you've built your entire program around it,
the they have a threat metric in there
and it doesn't quite fit perfectly because it's like
exploit, yes or no or something like that.
I, I can't remember depending on the version.
So it doesn't fit perfectly.
But that's where it should fit is in that threat aspect of CV SS.
If you want to combine the two,
I think, and you believed in CV SS has value,
that's where it should go
well.
And I think that's again,
that's why when you kept using the word temporal
because it's part of the temporal score in CV SS
which always struck me as a very
poor word to use.
But yeah, they've exploit and then they have quotes, code,
maturity renamed to exploit, maturity. E with clear values.
I was being part of the big step up for four.
Yeah.
Can I I want to bash one more thing about CBS S if I could please,
they made the assumption they've always had this assumption to assume the worst
and this is why we've got
over half or high and critical.
But if you look at the, what the data is saying, you know, for all of the data,
I've managed to collect about exploitation activity.
We're still seeing,
I think around 6% of the published CV ES have exploitation activity, 6%.
So
what that's saying is like out of that 6% we're going to assume the worst.
So 94% of the time they are incorrect,
right? It is not the worst. It is, there's nothing happening, there is a zero threat.
So
there's no other impact, right?
Um So why, why not assume the best?
And you're right, 94% of the time,
then you're not creating all of this extra work and stuff like that. And
hopefully you can get more data to bring it around.
-- I can
-- answer that. It's because the people assigning CV SS had missed
work for the government and they have to assign a
worst case scenario because otherwise they'll get nailed for it.
You didn't rate this badly enough, you missed it and there's,
and it's an externality for them like it basically it's alarm fatigue, right?
It's an advanced form of alarm fatigue where, yeah,
everything's high and critical.
So like you better patch now
and, and like you said, very little of it is being actively exploited or used,
it's justified,
but it's wrong.
Well, exactly. And I,
and again, like it's,
but this is how we got here. This is how reality is currently working and set up and
yeah, like if we I don't know what the answer to this is.
Um I, and that's part of what I tried to do with the CV
E
JSON data was to have it, people be able to set their own CV SS score.
So that Red Hat could say one, this other,
you know Sousa has a slightly different flavor of samba.
So it's different
and of course, that never happened.
They just want the one true score which is provided by N.
So that's the one everybody uses. And I think
that's I think is the biggest,
one of the biggest problems our industry has is like with epss,
why do we use epss so much?
Because we, we don't have anything else at all,
but we don't use epss so much. Not yet,
not yet.
I mean, it's, it's definitely getting attention
but I do think one of the challenges to adoption is going to be like, so,
so this whole discussion we've had for the last, you know, like 30 plus minutes
has really been around the fact that
this is an input to a larger machine
and we don't have that larger machine.
And today, if you look at, you know, you go by something like the fair framework,
it's very unique to each organization and most organizations
lack the maturity or know how to apply that.
Yeah,
well, or to have an inventory of their systems.
-- That's a whole another
-- story.
-- I mean, so
-- well, but I mean, on the maturity model like this is,
this is like flying when they're barely crawling.
-- Right. Right.
-- Right.
OK. Jay. So let's, I'm gonna give you the final word.
Just kind of close this out is, is Phyllis with hope and optimism here.
-- I
-- so,
I mean, if you, if we talk about what the,
the logic and the processes that are behind epss,
why can't that be applied to asset importance,
try and measure some of the consequence of exploitation?
Why can't it be measuring
control strengths,
you know, our ability to resist exploitation activity in the first place or,
you know, let's apply it to any sort of thing and posture management or um you know,
tax service management.
Let's talk about
default passwords. What is the effect of that? Well, what is our feedback loop?
You know, and that's all EP SS S is doing, it's just
finding the feedback and closing that loop.
So let's do that elsewhere.
So the final word in my mind is like, this is super hopeful. Epss is not done,
right?
You know, like we, we didn't like create epss and we're like celebrating, hey,
we're done.
No, no, no.
We're like we were working on the next version and
where epss and whatever this is going to lead to,
it's going to be very different than where we are now.
Like we can't just sit back like for sure we're not done
and hopefully we can get to NON CV es we can get to
other aspects and talk about these feedback loops and close those loops.
You just mentioned sort of applying EPSS style
analysis to other forms of data, you know,
are there any such projects underway that you know, of?
Uh
no,
do you?
Oh, no, like, I mean, well, the CS A does it with star a little bit but not,
there's no numbers involved.
It's just yes or no.
I mean, you'll see a lot in academic papers where they try to do this and
I mean, this isn't eps didn't invent this.
This isn't something I was like, oh, this is a great idea.
Now, this is like basic statistics you need, you know,
when you talk about machine learning,
you've got unsupervised and supervised and supervised has a feedback loop.
That's what we're doing like, yeah, that's it.
There's no magic, there's no brilliance.
It's just taking stuff other people have done and
we're going to stand on the shoulders of giants.
I love it.
All right. All right. Thank you, Jay. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. Go to its our security podcast.com.
Hit up the show if I'll put links to all the stuff Jay's talked about today and,
and all the fun stuff going on in Epss Land.
So go hit it up and you Pound
Os S podcast. Hashtag on Mastodon. Kurt and Jay have marvelous. Rest of your days.
Thank you.
Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye. Bye.