Hello and welcome to episode 109 of the Open source Security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
What's new man?
-- Not
-- a whole lot?
There really isn't. I mean, I mean, there isn't at all.
I, I'm quite pleased by the relative lack of horrible
news,
which is
at least insecurity
maybe because everything else is on fire.
But in, in, in fact, now I will say
one of the disadvantages to a slow news week is when you have a podcast.
It's like, what do we talk about now?
And luckily for us, we will never run out of topics.
And, and so anyway,
so for, for you listener,
Kurt and I were going to discuss. So we still will. But I, uh I recently spoke at
OCON the open o'reilly, Open Source Security or Open source convention.
I put security in all the time to everything.
Anyway, it's a nonsecurity convention and it was really cool to go and speak
as a security person because I generally only go to security events.
But, but anyway, anyway,
so I was walking my dog this morning thinking
about what kind of things we should talk about
and something occurred to me while I was also kind of thinking
about and also listening to some security podcast before I walk the dog
about fishing.
And the reason fishing is in the last episode,
we talk about Google claims none of their employees have been fished for a year
and we kind of talk about that. But then something occurred to me
with, with what Google got to say, Google said none of their employees got fished.
Now,
we love talking about things like, oh,
let's do fishing training and we'll reduce the number
of fishes that are successful from 30% to 20%.
And here's the thing that I kept thinking about is if 20% of your users can be fished,
that's still 100% success rate.
That's, that's terrible. Right? A success rate of 100% is unacceptable.
Well, what I love about all this, what,
what people seem to always forget about all these online attacks is
I can execute like 10 million online attacks and nothing bad happens to me.
Whereas for example, if I,
if I walk around the city trying every single doorknob to see if it's locked or not,
eventually, hopefully somebody will call the cops and be like,
this guy is like walking down the street, trying every single doorknob
and the cops will at least like come up to me and ask me, what the heck are you doing?
You know, can you please knock that off otherwise we're going to arrest you for,
uh, whatever attempt to break and enter or something.
But,
I don't know,
well, attempt to break and enter. Right. Like,
um, or, you know, they just talk to the person,
put the scare in them or get them to move on or whatever,
but fundamentally right. There's no consequence.
See, that's the thing, there's no
downside for a failed attack
in most cases.
Right.
And I don't mean even that, that like, there's a chance to go to jail, I mean,
like the attacks are so cheap to execute.
It's like
how much does it cost to send out
one email to every single person of the company?
Like a dollar
mostly in your time in writing the template?
Right? Like that's, you know what I mean?
And if you're doing this at scale, like the incremental cost is basically zero.
And so, yeah, I mean,
if there's no real cost to attacking a whole pile of people and there's almost,
if any downside to doing it
go nuts and keep trying, you know?
Right. Right.
-- No, I agree completely. And so are they
-- gonna block every email domain? No.
Right. Exactly. Exactly. And so I guess
this is where, what Google is doing is so powerful is it, it's not about
fishing training and reducing your net,
-- like 0% is the goal
-- we can't get people
to parallel park properly or stop at stop signs,
I can't
parallel. Right. So
I look at like driver training and we talk about, like, people talk about drivers and
it's weird to me that
we have this like
several 1000 people a year or thousands actually,
of people a year dying in car accidents
and you never hear people going. Oh, well, we just need better driver training.
No.
Like we need people to actually stop and stop
signs and if driver training hasn't accomplished that today,
-- it, it never will.
-- You have to pass the driving test to get your license.
Imagine the train wreck, the roads would be if you didn't need that.
Yeah, exactly.
So, no, I, I, you know, yeah, these systems where it's just like, ok, look,
humans suck at this. We can sort of train them to be a little bit less sucky.
Ok. That's one way to do it.
Or you can, like,
fix the problem some other way technologically or just
take the problem away even in some cases.
-- Right.
-- I, exactly. And I think
it's kind of like, let's say we start training people to stop at stop signs
and let's say 10% of people still don't.
That's still a huge number.
Well, we have red light cameras in the city that send out a lot of tickets.
Those things are money trees.
Yeah. And they should be like you, it's real simple.
If you don't want a red light ticket, don't run a red light.
Oh, man. So I, I have an awesome related story to that is
so where I live
you're supposed to yield to pedestrians crossing the street in a crosswalk.
-- That's pretty much all of the western world.
-- Ok.
Nobody does
wait on a, on a
crosswalk.
-- Mark crosswalk. No light. Then
-- they have the right of way. End of story.
-- That's how traffic rules work.
-- Well, that, right.
Anyway, but you've clearly never crossed the street in America.
Pedestrians always have the right of way, especially in a crosswalk.
Oh, no, no, no, you'll get run over here too.
Right? Ok.
Ok. Good. I'm glad we're on the same page.
Oh, yeah.
No,
the drivers here don't know what to do with pedestrians other
than to try and run them over and see if they're
-- right.
-- Right. Um, anyway, so the police are doing this test where they have a guy
in a bright green vest,
right, just crossing the street and as people don't stop,
there's a police officer pulling him over and they were
basically pulling over people as fast as they could.
And I'm, I'm sitting there watching this and laughing hysterically
because I'm, that's one thing I do.
I try really hard to always stop because I walk a lot. So it's a big deal to me.
But anyway, anyway,
and, and
I just kept thinking
nobody is going to change their behavior because of this.
I wish I could say this is going to fix the problem.
But all it really does is probably makes a crap load of money for the city.
-- I mean,
-- really?
Well, so there was an even better one,
in L A where they had the cop dressed up as an orange traffic cone.
Right. And I, I've put a link in the show notes,
but straight up, they had this guy wearing an orange traffic cone costume,
like bright orange.
So this guy's about 6 ft tall. So we're talking like a 4 ft traffic cone walking across
and like drivers are literally like, I do not see the because what happens,
right is that these cops pull these people around, like, did you see the p
they're like, oh no, I never know this pedestrian. They're like, well, too bad.
-- Here's your ticket,
-- right?
-- And then
-- they
go to
-- you and
-- says that it's like, do you know how fast you were going?
Well, here it's like
you didn't see the pedestrian. No, he look over there.
He's in this bright orange traffic cone costume and they're like, oh, yeah.
No, I didn't see him and it's like, well,
you should have,
-- I was checking my text messages.
-- Yeah.
Yeah, exactly.
I fe I, yeah, so no, they've done all sorts of things like this and yeah, um
I was on uh we have a street car locally that goes from White Avenue just
south of the river across the river on the old high uh high level bridge.
It's a former rail bridge.
It goes a little bit downtown. A few blocks, stops, turns around, comes back, right.
And it has to cross a pretty busy street at 1.100 and ninth street.
And it's not
because the street car only runs like,
once every 40 minutes for like a few months of summer.
They don't have like crossing barriers and lights and stuff.
They just have like a sign saying, you know, railroad crossing
and you're expected as a car to, like,
when you're driving towards the thing to look for,
you know, the 3040 ton street car and if it's there maybe stop,
right? Because it's, if you hit the street car, you're gonna smash
your car up and the street car will get a little bit damaged, but not much
because it's like a train car. Yeah. You know, and it's anyways
and, you know, so we're sitting at the front, me and my kids and like,
we're coming up on the thing and the guy slows way down
and like, yeah, these cars just keep coming through
and we're like, you know, 10 ft away from the road
and then finally somebody stops and somebody else stops and it's, I'm like,
I'm like, wow, they, because he's also dinging, like,
they have this really loud bell and horn on the thing, right?
And he's making noise and
I'm like, wow, they really don't see you do. They, and he's like, nope.
And it's even worse with ambulances and cops.
Right. Because they get that tunnel vision when they're, you know,
because it's just such an oddity. Right. Having an uncontrolled inter
rail crossing in the city.
Right. That's rarely used. So people just don't know how to react to it. Right.
But,
yeah, it was just, it was wild to see, like,
because II I suspected one or two people wouldn't see it.
No. Like
finally somebody kind of noticed this like large green street
car making noise trying to cross the road and stopped.
That's crazy man.
You got to just pull like a Boston move and slowly inch your way out until you,
you're blocking all the traffic.
-- It was
-- basically
what he did. That's what he did, right?
And being a train, they can get away with that,
right?
Oh my goodness. It's
again, again,
we think we can train people
even better. We'll train developers to secure code,
you can train a few developers to secure code
and hopefully they write the framework everybody else uses.
That's the solution you
-- can,
-- I'm gonna say you can't and I'm, I'm I do this in. Every talk
on this topic is I'm going to point at the open SSH developers. They are literally
the brightest security developers on the planet and they still make mistakes,
-- end of story,
-- but
-- they make fewer mistakes than the average.
-- And that's true. I will agree with that.
Like the Linux kernel is a great example of, you know, where Linus Torvalds is like,
yeah, don't break Userland because if you break user land,
you break everything on the planet.
And yeah, I can kind of get behind that,
you know,
and he's also like, we can't like break systems, we can't do stuff that like,
you know, even if only 1/100 of 1/100 of a percent of people
install this reboot and it doesn't work. That's thousands. You know what I mean?
That's a lot of people inconvenience.
It's huge, man.
That's why I'm thinking with the IOT, right?
Even if your failure rate is one in a million.
Well, like when you're talking about light bulbs, that's a lot of people in the dark
and that's why just doing nothing is cheaper than doing anything else.
Yeah.
And safer.
Seriously, man.
And safer. I like it.
I like it.
-- Yeah,
-- whatever.
So what happened at Os
Con?
It was a fun show.
I,
I must say there's a certain amusement
I get from hanging out with nonsecurity people
because first of all, they expect me to be terrible to them,
which I'm, I'm not.
So,
I mean, I, I know I, I address this in my, in my talk and I,
I started out with, uh my name is Josh,
I'm a recovering security person and it's been
two years since I yelled at a developer
and I don't, I don't think it's really been two years, probably less. But it's funny.
So, a
couple of hours.
But anyway, anyway, no, it's, it's good and the craziest thing.
So, for anyone who doesn't know, because I know
Ocon is,
if you're not in the open source world, you might not know about it.
So o'reilly are the book people that make the books
with like the weird kind of pencil drawing of animals,
wood block cuttings,
OK. Wood block cuttings, whatever those things.
And, and obviously, they're probably most famous for,
like back in the day they wrote the pearl book which had the camel on it, which is,
you know,
and which one's the bad book
mail?
It was the 850 page one that you could
someone
to
kill someone with that book. I remember that book. I remember using that.
I spent over $5000 on o'reilly books.
I used to.
Yeah, that's how I learned all my stuff.
I had, I had 1.5 bankers boxes full of these o'reilly books.
I read cover to cover and made notes in.
They were great books.
They,
they still publish good books.
It's just, I think
when I learn something new, I don't turn to a book like
a to, I just find that, you know, online tutorials. But, but anyway, so o'reilly,
they, they do something called
Ocon, which is an open source convention essentially.
And obviously it's the usual convention. You've got the Expo Hall.
You've got speakers, you've got, you know,
whatever the parties and the dinners and, and all that kind of stuff.
And
I've, I've been to a couple of these, my last one was actually five years ago
and
it,
it was remarkable how different it's become in the
last five years because last time I was there
it was, I don't remember, I gave a talk on some open source security thing.
I don't even remember what, but I remember going into the hall,
it was primarily
like, like your Red Hats and Debian and, you know, just open source kind of users
that were either kind of selling something or maybe just showing off.
And there were a handful of companies hiring, like an example is
I still have a Spotify t-shirt. I got from them and Spotify was trying to hire people.
I was like, well, I don't really want to work for you, but can I have a shirt
and they gave me
and I still wear it? It's still in really good shape. Actually,
this annoys me because my partner, she really gets annoyed and she's like,
do you only have computer shirts?
I'm like, yes,
they're free. Where else do you like?
What, how do you, how do you get T shirts?
Not only that, I worked for Red Hat for 12 years
and I have
probably 100 Red hat t-shirts
I actually bought.
It's
great
because they were three bucks each in the fruit of the loom. They are
yous.
Yeah. From the cool stuff store.
Because I wanted, I wanted 20 identical shirts for going to the gym and stuff.
So that, and it's funny because I think all the people at the gym thought I was, like,
borderline homeless because I wore the same t-shirt every day for, like,
a year until I explained that I had 20 of these.
Yeah, that's great.
Now I'll give elastic a lot of credit here.
They're really good about giving me shirts and II I have more
elastic shirts than I can wear between laundry at this point.
So
it's quite nice.
Uh Anyway, anyway,
so,
and, and Oscar,
now you go in there
and
it was Red Hat was there, of course, as you can imagine.
And like Google was there, there was,
uh paypal was there talking about their framework.
The Home Depot was there, obviously talking about the open source. They do.
There was
uh someone from the NSA was there. I got a bunch of stickers from them.
That was really cool.
There was like,
Huawei was there showing off their hardware and open source project.
It was just like,
it's so different now because
everybody is using open source. Right.
-- It's, it's nothing like it used to be back in the day.
-- Well, you, you can't not
use it.
-- Right. Right.
-- Because
like,
I mean, literally the only way you could avoid open source is by being, well,
100% Microsoft, they're really the only
-- Microsoft is there.
-- Exactly.
Well, and I was gonna say, like, in theory you could be 100% close source by, like,
just sticking 100% of Microsoft.
But even Microsoft
is, yeah, I mean,
even they have fully embraced open
source, like,
hard.
Yeah. And they were not just that and, and
Ocon Microsoft is giving away arduinos.
I mean,
what, what has happened to the world? Like this is not the world I grew up in.
Well, Microsoft has their own Linux.
Do they
for IOT?
Oh,
well, that's cool.
Yeah, and it talks to the manager and it,
yeah, they have a, they have their, sorry when I say their own custom links.
I don't mean like some lame like, oh we built the distro on top of something.
No, no, no. They have their own custom Linux kernel
for their Linux IOT stuff. So it's like part of their SDP. It's like
here basically is a pile of software and documents and like
you want to build like an IOT device that does XY and Z cool.
Like you do a little bit of data processing locally
if you want and then you ship it off to Azure
and you get a nice web portal for the users and you know, back like basically it's,
it's
everything from A to Z just plug and play. Boom off. You go
oh
And it's an arm. Linux not like some easy Intel.
Linux, like it's, it's proper iot Linux on an arm.
So, no, like, yeah, Linux
or Microsoft has their own.
Linux
like kernels. Userland everything.
Yeah, it was uh what? Yeah, in April or earlier of this year.
Right. So, it's been around for only a few months but still. Yeah.
No, clearly Microsoft does open source,
open
source one. Right. I, I keep saying that but
I don't know, it amuses
me.
I think a lot of people don't think that yet because open source one everywhere,
but a lot of it is still like way on the back end or like deeply embedded or,
you know what I mean?
Like you don't see
like a great example is
uh, yeah, last night we went to the Italian Center.
It's an Italian store that sells Italian stuff, food.
Um,
and they have this like really good selection of cheese and meat, like,
like over like, I think it's about 100 kinds of cheese.
Like, it's pretty fantastic.
And so they have these giant display boards
showing all the cheeses the cost per kilogram
and like sort of, you know, if it's available or not. Right.
And um,
there was like an error on one of the boards. I took a picture of it
and I looked a little closer and I'm like, OK, this isn't a windows air,
this isn't a Mac Os.
It's, oh, it's Ubuntu Linux. OK.
So they have like an Ubuntu Linux machine.
Running these like six or seven giant, you know, TV,
s displaying their cheese prices.
Nice.
Right?
It's, and so yeah, I mean, because if you went to the store and asked like, hey,
are you guys Linux users?
They'd be like, what, what's Linux?
Right? Can you just buy your cheese and leave?
You know, you're making us nervous
and, and part of me was like, can you guys please just hit the ok on that air?
Like, because it wants to install some updates and just,
it's really annoying because
was covering a cheese I wanted to buy and I wanted to see how much it was.
But yeah, I mean, it's just funny.
Right, because it's like they're Linux users, like
-- they wouldn't
-- know that
and they don't even know it, it's, it's hilarious.
I,
yeah,
-- that's awesome, man.
-- That's how technology should be. It should just work.
-- No,
-- I agree completely.
And, and so anyway, it was, it was amusing to me seeing all this.
It was, you know what the craziest part was.
And this is something I didn't really, it didn't sink in
until my plane ride home is.
I, I go to a lot of security events
and I'm obviously representative
of elastic
and I get asked questions about logging in Sims constantly because basically in
the
security,
like, si em, security incident
and logs as well, which are related
and a lot of people use a lot
for this.
Right. Exactly.
Nobody asked me any of those questions at
Ocon. And it was, it was, it was so weird to me because that's all I usually talk about.
And this time I got to actually talk about other cool stuff and people would ask like,
programming questions and,
and we could talk about using Python and how
that works to solve your problems and stuff.
And it was,
it was very pleasant. I really did enjoy it. It was, it was good. And then
uh I gave a talk about what did I call it? Security as an MVP is the name of my talk.
It will eventually be published. I'll tweet it out when it is.
And I will say the thing that I found the most amazing
was I brought my chromebook I presented off of my chromebook
and when I showed up, they had one USB C cable on the table. I plugged it in
and everything just magically worked.
And I was, I was, I didn't even know
you
-- mean for the
-- display like the
USB,
the display, it was one USB C cable. I plugged it in
my chromebook appeared on the display and I presented it was crazy.
Yeah, seriously, man, I,
I
still,
we are in the future.
So you're saying just because I'm having a hard time
processing this and I just want to be clear,
you had effectively a laptop and you plugged one cable into it and it's worked
without like
working with display settings or changing the inputs or the aspect ratio,
it didn't catch fire,
it
just
worked
it in. I've literally never had that happen to me.
I know seriously, even with, with Windows or Mac or Linux, especially Linux
something
right.
In this one, I plugged it into the chromebook. It extended the screen.
I dragged my window over to the big screen.
I clicked the present button
and
that was all
it was Mandi
man.
I'm not
sure I would know what to do in that situation.
I, I showed up like 10 minutes early.
-- Yeah, I know.
-- Right. I stood there staring at the poor A V guy.
-- I
-- travel with four display adapters.
-- I, I travel with four display adapters for my laptop.
-- Seriously, man.
Like it was, it was amazing.
It was so crazy and, and then of course, you know,
III I did the talk and make fun of security people a lot because it is easy to do
and,
and then there were a bunch of questions at the
end and it was really interesting actually listening to people because
the one thing that really came across and this is in
the Q and A as well as just people talking afterwards is
people just want, they want me to tell them what to do, right.
Someone will say like, tell me which password manager I should use.
And of course, I can't answer that because it's like, well,
they do all different things and blah, blah, blah, blah, blah,
I'm getting over that
where I'm just making a declarative because honestly,
even if you give them not a great answer,
an 80% answer is better than them being stuck in indecision
maybe.
And so the way I addressed that was I basically
said I use last pass for example and then I
explained why I use it because I have some very
specific reasons around the family plan and things like that.
And I don't know, I mean, I guess this is,
I need to think about this because you might
be right that just telling people what to do
and, and if it's 80% good enough that
I generally won't tell them what to do.
But like you,
I will coach it in terms of here's what I do or here's
what I would do or you know what I would recommend or,
you know, at least
because for example, I mean, part of the problem now is, is like
there are so many potential solutions, right? Which cloud providers
are?
I'll be blunt,
it's going to be Google Amazon or Microsoft unless
you have some really ridiculous crazy corner case need
for some local player or a vertical player
that does whatever it is you need to do. But fundamentally, you,
you pick one of those three players because
you know what, like life's too short to, you know,
I was talking with somebody and like, well, you know, didn't,
didn't you do all this research?
And I'm like, no, no, I absolutely didn't.
I picked Amazon because they were the biggest one.
They still are.
I'm pretty much locked into them at this point, but they keep lowering my bill.
So, like, I'm locked into a provider that keeps
me more services and a lower bill every month. So, like, yeah, cool. Whatever.
I don't care.
The cable company should take note of that.
No, I hear you, man.
I totally understand where you're coming from and, and so all right.
So let me ask you this then is one of the questions somebody asked me was
which like like software security scanner
would I recommend for, you know, doing like standard code analysis?
And my answer was there.
It
-- doesn't matter.
-- I would say
Coity because that seems to be the most popular one and more to the point they'll
-- be able to find people who know how to use it and what the results
-- mean.
That that might be fair. I don't, I don't know, does Coity
still back when I used it last? I think it only did C and C++.
I don't know if it does anything else. Oh,
it does a whole bunch of stuff now. But
more to the point.
Well, yeah, without even knowing what language they're using and stuff,
I'm just guessing.
But I would say Colver
because it's got a big company backing it
and
CAV
BC I think, and then C A but,
-- but yeah, so I think C
-- A owns them
part of it honestly, for most businesses is like,
businesses have a problem and you know what,
there is probably like a really good optimal solution that's only going to cost $7
or they can just, like,
pay this consultant to come in and fix it for 10 grand
and be done with it and not have to think about it.
Right. I, I agree with that.
Yeah.
You know, I, I had a small drip in my basement.
Paid the epoxy concrete guy, like 450 bucks problem solved because, like,
what do I know about fishing concrete?
And as it turns out there was a crack in there, right?
So he did the epoxy the injection and then he's like, oh, yeah,
I can see the stuff is coming out here.
That means you have a crack, I'm gonna have to charge you like a little bit more.
It's like 50 bucks more. And I'm like, yeah, I'm ok with that,
you know, and he's like, ok, we, you know, I'm pretty sure it's fixed.
Can you run the hose outside for, you know, like half an hour to soak it like, yeah,
no water came in. Ok, thank you.
Sweet. You know, he emailed me an invoice. I emailed him his money.
Thank you.
Right. I mean, and that's,
and, but see, here's the thing,
that's what normal people want with their security problem.
I called the guy. He came, he poked it, he fixed it,
he emailed me a bill
and like, it was done in two days.
It, it only took two days because he had to do, like, the epoxy,
let it dry overnight and then do the injection stuff.
Otherwise it would have been done in like, three hours.
-- This
-- is, this is an interesting analogy.
-- Right. That's what people want.
-- You. You're absolutely right.
It's what they want and it's exactly what we can't give them.
It's like changing my oil.
I could change my oil.
I could go buy all the stuff I need to change my oil or I can go literally two blocks away
and some guys will do it for 70 bucks and I get to sit in my car and not get dirty
and it takes like, 15 minutes
and, and it costs the same price.
You just
buy it
yourself.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I know.
I occasionally change my own oil in my,
my truck because I like to show the kids how to do it.
And, yeah,
I think it's actually more expensive for me to change that oil than it is for me
to bring it.
So, you know, that's what people want from a security point of view. Right.
Like, my mom
wanted a new lock for her, like,
a gym locker because we were at the store actually buying a little safer.
She's like, oh, I should also get a new lock, you know which one's secure.
And I'm like, I started laughing. Right.
-- And she's like,
-- there is an answer to this.
Well,
-- tell me what you told her and then I'll tell you the
-- right.
I started laughing and I basically said none of them are secure.
The only way to get a secure lock to spend at least
is to spend at least a couple 100 bucks and even those get picked easily.
And I showed her the lock
lawyer where he does
where the lockpicking lawyer did.
Uh, what was it, like, 15 master locks in two minutes or something?
And so I'm like, whatever, just pick this one. It's fine.
-- It's like six bucks and it'll keep normal people out of your locker
-- and,
and there's that, but did you, have you ever seen the, the master lock makes them,
they have like an up down left, right kind of thing on their face?
Yes, I've seen those
so of, of all the locks
that I've ever picked and done research on
that is the one that we still have not found a way.
Well, as of, as of this recording and the research I've done.
I, I will say that because I, I imagine
I'm going to learn if that's not true,
but
that is the one lock you can't break into or
pick without drilling a hole in it to look inside.
Uh, there's a speed dial option.
-- What's a speed
-- dial option
where you can, like, try, well,
what you basically try all the combinations quickly
but it,
it holds like an insane number of combinations.
It's, I'm, I'm, I don't know, it is conceivable,
but this is all, this also comes back to your point.
-- It's like, that's just a brute force attack though. That's not picking it.
-- Right.
That's,
you know, and you can always brute force attack a combination
given enough time
and somebody who doesn't like
and, and my combination on my up, down left, right.
Deo is like,
it's fairly long anyone who is trying to pick it, it would take
the
code.
That would be glorious.
I didn't even think of that, but that would have been awesome.
All
-- that was like the 1234 that jumped into my mind for that.
-- I bet it is.
I bet that's the, I bet if you go to a gym with those, you could try the
Kami code and half of them are going to be the
Kami code.
You just need to glue a BN A button on the side and
good
to
go
anyway. Anyway.
All right. So we were talking about Os
Con
and,
and I mean, we're, we're kind of, we're running ourselves out of time here.
But I guess this is the thing I will say is I feel like people
normal developers
understand the importance of security
and I think they want to do the right thing and I think we're not telling them what it is
and that's basically what it comes down to.
-- No,
-- it's worse that we don't tell them, we tell them things.
Like, well, you should develop securely and not make bugs.
Oh. Right.
That's
exactly. Exactly. Well, it works. It's telling them something of
no value because it's so open ended. The only way
is failure. Right. Like,
you know, we're saying, like, so many security people, mostly in my experience,
I don't not,
oh, here's the, here's what you should be doing,
right?
Like uh the CS A developers came to me and they're like, we should be,
we want to start tracking CV numbers for all the
Ruby Gems and stuff we use and I'm like,
ok,
no, you really don't. And they're like, what?
Yeah, we, we, we, we care about security and I'm like, oh, yeah.
No, I know you care about security but I'm like, I'm like,
how often are you guys doing new builds
of the software and deploying it to production?
He's like, well, you know, like at least once a week, sometimes more.
If there's a really bad CV,
we'll hear about it in the news and you guys will push an update, right?
And he's like, well, yeah, obviously and I'm like, ok, cool, thanks. Right.
Everything else, I assume they just pick up
-- every time they do a build, right?
-- Yeah.
Yeah, they always just run whatever is the latest.
So I mean,
there is in theory the possibility of like a flaw being introduced in a newer jam
that is not fixed.
And so like if you know about it, you could roll back to an older version of the gem.
But the more common corner case is like, oh,
I found this flaw in the gem and we fixed it in the latest version.
That's like 99% of security flaws in my experience,
right? Somebody finds a flaw.
It was,
it was introduced at some point either at the very beginning or between now and then,
you know, when a new feature was introduced or
like the Linux kernel is great for this, right?
It's like, oh, we added this like uh SCTP protocol and
well, you know, there's a bunch of flaws in it.
And so as people extended the protocol and added more and more support for it,
you know, there's
this flaw was added a year ago, two years ago, whatever.
So essentially it's been there forever realistically, right?
And you know, we found it, we fixed it so the news version isn't flawed. Great. So,
yeah, like especially in the open source world, especially with this like,
you know, sort of ruby jams, you know, Pearl C Pan,
no Js type thing.
Yeah, if you're running the latest of everything,
basically, statistically, that's
how you are secure
as far as playing CD whacko.
Totally,
totally. And so I'm like, Yeah. You know,
if there's something really bad, I'll ask you to do an update.
But by and large you guys are doing these updates fast
enough that it's not really going to be a problem.
Plus we have a bunch of layers of other security like cloud flaring,
like other filtering and stuff to prevent, you know,
people from doing shenanigans to our web servers in the first place
regardless of what's running on it.
-- Yeah. No, I, I totally get it,
-- man.
You know,
and I get for like larger applications or stuff you're shipping to customers,
you probably want better, more official CV tracking, right?
Because you can't just be like whatever ship an update and you know,
enforce everybody to use it.
Right. That's the beauty of a service, right. With a service. Oh,
yeah, 100% of customers upgraded. Why? Because we did,
-- right.
-- It's that simple.
-- Right.
-- It's
-- true.
-- You know.
So, so anyway, anyway, kind of back to the topic is
people want actionable useful advice and we suck at that.
And so now this is something I'm starting to think about it,
but cost effective and realistic.
Yeah, that's true. True because I can give insane actionable advice.
But it needs to be practical. That that's a very good point actually. And I have to,
-- I have to consider that
-- in some meaningful way.
Right.
As we found out last episode that totally works.
So
it works all the time.
It's like fishing training anyway anyway. All right.
So, yeah, I guess in summary it's
open source one and people want to be secure but they don't know what to do and,
and quite frankly we don't know what to tell them.
So,
you know,
I guess, well, actually, so here's one of the other things.
So the talk I gave, I took the O
A
top 10 and I also showed the old O
A top 10 and the new one. And I'm like, this is what failure looks like essentially.
-- And I can't wait for the hate mail for saying that
-- it's, well, it's the same list,
right?
-- Every
-- year. It's almost exactly the same
and,
-- and I, I turned it into,
-- well, people keep making the same mistakes though.
So it's, it is the same list because, well, it's like driver training.
People still don't stop at red lights and they still can't parallel park.
-- Sure.
-- Like it just doesn't change.
Exactly. And so basically I said 10 is too many as it is.
And I told them like, here's three things you can do.
Number one was use and like a framework, right?
Don't, don't like, don't do your own html escaping, for example,
just find a framework and use it,
right?
That takes care of like four of the top 10. Basically,
the second one was like, don't do your own.
A
right? There's things like a
zero, there's like Google, there's Microsoft,
there's everyone has like their ability to
do authentication and they have libraries to
-- hook into
-- and more to the point most frameworks have that capability now,
weirdly, most web frameworks, you know, yeah,
they realize they need authentication.
Who knew? Right?
And then the last one was basically like, don't,
don't let humans do your infrastructure, right?
Use like tools and things like containers and answerable
scripts and whatever because obviously if humans touch it,
they screw it up.
But if you let a script do it, you're, it's going to be the same every time. And like,
and for real, like those three things, if everyone did those, you could,
you could almost get rid of the O
A top 10. But again, like
it, it's of course easy to say that it's hard to do,
but at least it's something people can think
about instead of saying here's 10 problems.
-- Good freaking luck.
-- Part of the challenge is, you know, people need
more good generic solutions, not some hyper specific.
Well, like, don't ever write this specific line of code ever again,
right?
Because I've seen that I've literally
seen where people do developer security training
and they're like, don't ever do this, like, you know,
forget the html escape output to your web server.
Well, yeah, but no,
but kind of it doesn't work that way sometimes
because sometimes you actually have to send HTML out,
right?
And sometimes that's appropriate, you know, and so,
but if you have a framework, right? And the framework is smart.
It's like, well, that's user input. So I'm going to escape that.
Whereas this is something I generated, therefore it's OK.
-- You know.
-- Exactly. Exactly. All right, man,
I, I dig it. So,
yeah, I guess
acon was fun. I, I hope to go again soon
and
yeah, I guess
that that is all. So let's
thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com, check out the show notes,
you can hit us up on Twitter at the Pound and Os S Podcast.
Hashtag
you can.
Yeah, and I guess if nothing else, Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.