Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in occasionally being congested.
Josh Bress.
-- I'm
-- not congested. Kurt claims he's sick. I think he sounds fine.
Uh,
my, the inside of my si my nose and sinuses feels very unpleasant. That's fair.
It happens. Anyway. Anyway, I'll, I'll give you a warning.
So I had to bring my son to the orthodontist this morning
and I, we got there like probably 20 minutes too early because it was,
I drop my daughter off at school and then we drove to the Elect.
I'm like, it's a little early
and there's a Turkish coffee place around the corner.
-- So I said, oh, let's go grab some coffee.
-- Wait, how's your son now? 16.
I guess he's allowed to drink coffee.
I don't care. Any kid can drink coffee. What do I care?
I just,
I love how like in North America we have this like taboo of kids drinking coffee,
but apparently in South America it's like, like,
because what else are they gonna drink?
I have no issue with it. I mean, if they can stomach it, they can drink it anyway.
I'm like, so wired from this coffee.
We'll see how it goes. Anyway. Anyway, we have a topic today.
We
-- do
-- github,
github
-- desktop.
-- They had a little whoopsie.
They did, they did it happens. Do you wanna
-- fill everyone in on what's going on or you want me to,
-- uh, code signing certificate?
Got stolen? Oops.
Well, it, ok. That's, oh, come on.
I
just, I can't, your story is terrible and you should feel bad.
Well, but I mean, that's the thing, right? People like
-- fundamentally here,
-- this is not how the storytelling process works. All right,
I will explain what happened in a way that is entertaining and informative,
which is the whole point of us being here, right?
We'll say maybe more entertainment than informative. But
so it
is currently February 1st and I think this was released, what, two or three days ago,
maybe, I don't remember.
There's a blog post, I'll put it in the show notes from
github
and they're saying on December 7th.
So it's been nearly a month since they detected
what's going on and this is how it works.
Like security incidents, take time to understand, to do proper analysis.
So that's fine.
On December 7th, they detected unauthorized access to a set of repositories,
it says,
and I think that's the thing that everyone's obsessed with
the code signing certificates that were taken from the repositories,
but it means someone access
repositories right inside, get a private repositories.
Ok?
-- So I'll just read it from the, like the blog post because
-- anyway, I'm telling a story.
You don't get
to,
you had your chance and you blew it.
So what it is though? And because we talked about this previously,
we just
OK.
And other depreciated github
owned organizations were cloned by a compromised personal
access token associated with a machine account.
I will bet you a dollar
that, that personal access token
was kept in the last pass.
-- It would not shock me if that's true
-- because that was the same time frame that
the CS A got the warning email from github
saying one of our devs
-- tokens was used to access.
-- Ah, now it's interesting
and that remember because, and I, and I posted that on Mastodon
and there was a couple other people in the industry who are like,
reasonably trustworthy who
said, yeah, I, I too have seen this email
and so what, what I really like about this is clearly github
is like monitoring their logs with some automated systems and going like,
like a whole bunch of personal access tokens
were suddenly used in weird ways and they,
they slammed the door on it
and, you know, rotated them and everything.
But I, I will bet you a dollar. This is related to the last pass incident.
I would not take that bet
it would not. So, so, ok, so here's the thing. It is very like we are humans.
We love finding patterns in the noise. It's what humans do and
I think last pass is a plausible explanation for this,
but it could also be just like some random service got popped,
you know.
But the thing is ok, le let's uh, game this, you generate an access token for a,
like a system account,
you feed it into the system account.
Right.
Well, how does that get compromised? It doesn't, what gets compromised?
You make a copy of that token into a secure,
I don't know, some sort of secure,
like password like storage system could be so that, you know,
in future when you have to kick the system over or restart it or whatever,
or reload it, you have the token,
right?
No, I, I get that. I understand.
And I feel like people who work at github
and run this stuff probably aren't, you know,
putting it in notepad on a public Samba share.
I, so I would be less concerned with that. I think
I have a I, I last pass is totally plausible. It could be that.
Well,
the other thing is from a fishing
perspective like phishing somebody's personal access token.
-- Like this is like a recovery password style.
-- This isn't, this isn't fishing.
II, I have no doubt this kind of thing isn't with
fishing. This is
generally speaking,
when you have an access token like this taken, it's usually a service was popped.
Like when,
what was the one that just got popped circle C I right where everyone had
to rotate all their tokens because circle C I was holding a bunch of tokens.
So you've got that situation,
you see people accidentally check this stuff into github
or some other repository.
And I mean, this is why
github tokens now start with what, like GHP or something.
And there's, there's projects that scan all the commits for entropy.
-- So because I used to get that all the time with those email commits with the message,
-- I
don't happen as much anymore.
So Truffle Hog used to be the service that well,
the the the application that did that things would look for entropy.
And actually during there was a time
and it's been a couple of years, but it was I,
I basically spent more time than I want to admit,
looking at various sources of entropy
to determine if you can use that to deter figure out like is a line of code
nefarious, right? Assuming that you've got someone trying to hide intent,
trying to obfuscate
it,
not, not, not
just obfuscation, but like what do you call it when you're hiding in plain sight,
kind of like stenography of sorts.
But anyway, you get the idea,
I
I analyzed many, many things and
there is a shocking amount of randomness in nearly
every line of code just because of all the
weird characters and stuff we use. So to trying to detect just randomness
is less effective than looking for known strings, like known links,
known character sets like github
-- adding GHP at the beginning is
-- perfect. Like begin certificate.
-- Yeah. Right. Exactly. Stuff like that 100% 100%
-- SSH dash RS a space.
But I mean, for real, like that's the benefit of that. It, it works super well.
Absolutely. Absolutely. So, anyway, anyway, let's kind of bring this back.
So github
detects unauthorized access to repositories and the
thing they focus on in these repositories is
it says a set which I assume means two maybe, I don't know what's a set.
Can you have more than two things in a set?
-- Well, it was Adam and desktop.
-- Well, yeah.
-- Right. Adam and you get have desktop and Adam is what their text editor, I think
-- it
is.
-- Yeah, it's a really nice text editor.
-- Uh You know, I never run, I use Vim whatever.
Oh, you know what I was miss, remember
it's Adam that ends as end of life's not desktop.
-- You
-- can't just say I remember now. So before we hit record,
Kurt says while we're discussing, oh, get up, desktop is going end of life.
And I was like, wait, what?
He's like, yeah, I told you that I'm like,
if you told me I wouldn't be acting surprised
or I don't remember which is equally possible.
And anyway, then we spent several minutes trying to find the end of life warning,
I guess.
And we didn't find it.
Yeah, I tried to find a life cycle statement for this and it's, I mean, well,
one thing that's
the, uh, the, the github
web page now says community supported
so it might have end of life in the sense of github
is no longer, like, fully funding it and maintaining it.
-- And it's kind of been passed to the community.
-- You mean, Adam?
No github
desktop?
Oh, github
desktop is community supported.
Yeah, I think I misremembered the github
thing where it didn't end of life or, and like die. It's just github
stepped back and gave it to the community.
Oh, that could be. That could be. But like if they got rid of
github desktop on windows, that's the only good way I know of really for like,
non
technical people.
Well, I'm technical and I'm trying to use VS code with GIT and I'm just like,
I'm still stuck using github desktop. It's just so much easier.
Yeah. It's not the most pleasant experience
anyway. Anyway. All right.
Shockingly
so. Ok.
So a set of encrypted code signing certificates
where I like how they say ex filtrated.
I
don't know why. That just amuses me.
And it's important to note that these certificates were encrypted,
like you need a password to decrypt them to use them.
And that's a big difference.
-- It
-- is
here is
the way I've been thinking about this because Kurt and I have chatted about it
for a couple of days and I've been thinking about it a lot and obviously
is doing the right thing. They're revoking
the certificates,
which is going to break all of the old versions of github
desktop and Adam
for Mac. It says my understanding is, is it just Mac and Windows?
It does affect Windows also? Ok.
Ok.
But they're going to revoke this, which is very painful for them,
but definitely the right thing to do because there have
been multiple incidents in the past where people have said,
oh, the certificates were stolen but they have a long password on them.
So we think it's fine and that's,
that's not the right thing to do.
I heard
that you can build a password cracking rig now with some sort of multi
core
CPU like device that has lots of cores. Now, I think they're called A A GP U
and, you know,
and you can crack these things really quick apparently or so I've been told.
Ok. So I,
I have another podcast called Hacker History, which I want to listen to,
but there's an episode I did.
It's been a couple of months now
and the, the, it's a friend of mine, his name is Robert and he does password cracking.
He like team.
Hashtag actually, I just talked to someone else on team hashtag uh not too long ago.
Um
I forget their name off the top of my head anyway,
it doesn't matter like these password cracking people now have rigs
that are doing like literally trillions of attempts a second.
It is mind
-- boggling how fast they can go.
-- Now, I remember seeing one at RS A like,
I don't know, 5, 10 years ago that was like a quad GP U thing.
And they were using, you know, cracking land,
landman ashes at like some absurd rate.
It's, it's completely insane.
I was just looking at the video cards now and I mean, uh 18,000 cores.
That's
like, that's a lot of cores.
I know that
a
big number.
Thankfully now that Ethereum doesn't use video cards, you can actually buy them.
But that's another story. Anyway. Anyway. Ok.
So, so certificates are ex filtrated. Github
sees no nefarious activity so far to date
and they're
revoking this as an abundance of caution, revoking it on February 2nd,
which is tomorrow for us.
It'll be in the past for everyone listening
and
that's great. Like, so there's, there's two, there's a couple of pieces to this.
I want to talk about.
First of all, github has done everything correct in this instance,
in terms of how they've responded to this incident,
they detected a problem a day later, they started there.
Well, they uh the, the event happens a day later, they figure it out,
they do their investigation and then they tell everyone in public what's going on,
like great, good job.
That is exactly what should happen.
-- Well,
-- and what's interesting they have to make a trade off.
So there's, uh, yeah, so of all the certificates stolen,
only three had not yet expired.
So there was a bunch of certificates stolen, but they'd all expired.
So, like, who cares?
One ex
one certificate expired in the interim on January 4th.
And that was a Windows code certificate,
another one, another Windows code signing certificate expires on, uh,
February 1st, which is, well today, but
there's a third certificate
for Apple signing
that only expires in 2027.
Ah, that's why I kept hearing about Apple. Ok. That makes sense.
That's the one that's more useful.
And so what's interesting is, so obviously the window ones were like,
kind of being planned to roll over anyway.
So, no big deal. Who cares?
-- But that Apple one, they have to revoke and essentially
-- it is a big deal though.
And here's the reason.
So,
and, and, and back me up on this. I'm pretty sure I'm right, but I might not be, but
if the certificate just expires, but it's not revoked,
you can still install the old versions, right?
Versus if it's revoked, you're like, no,
there's no way out now. Like we are not trusting this in any way.
But the thing is you wouldn't, the, the certificate is expired now,
so you can't sign new releases.
Well. Right. Right. Absolutely. So to an attacker, it has
marginal value.
-- Well, no value
-- really. But obviously the Apple one is, that's, that's
that's very useful to put it bluntly.
Oh, yeah. Yeah. Yeah. There's a couple of pieces to this.
I think we should talk about.
First of all, there are many people that are saying github
should have been using an HS MA hardware security module.
That is
absolutely correct.
Who knew?
Well, so, so here's the way I would, I would, I want to talk about this though is well,
but the thing is this isn't like some like little software project.
This is number one. This is very widely used.
OK. That's also true of a lot of open source projects.
But I would also point out github,
I believe
has some money, probably a bit more money than the average open source project.
Yeah.
And more to the point more insultingly, they probably own an HSM.
Like I would assume they, or, or they like use an uh an Amazon, what is it K MS,
you know, key management service or whatever.
I, I would be shocked if they, well, the Microsoft owns them. Are they, do they run in
Azure? Do they run their own data centers? I don't, I don't know the answer to that.
-- I,
-- I don't know where github
is running. I, I think they were out of Amazon originally.
-- Uh who knows, regardless
-- if they're in a cloud,
there are cloud HSM solutions and if they're on Prem
buy an HSM,
-- they're actually
-- not that expensive anymore.
-- They cost about as much as a small car
-- when we were at Red Hat, it was 40 grand,
which for the,
the amount of savings we got when Red Hat got popped. Totally worth 40 grand.
-- Unquestionably.
-- Well, see, that's, that's exactly the thing.
It's like,
that's why I have a spare tire is because I don't want to have to spend my day DP
and around trying to, you know, get towed to a tire shop
and of course, it'll be Saturday at like 6 p.m. So they're all closed and
blah,
you know,
so I don't know, they just
spare
time,
step up. You've got,
we're off the rails.
Here's what I want to say.
So this is where I think the perception and reality clash sometimes,
especially over HS MS and signing certificates.
There is a point
where you should be using an HSM and github
is well past that point.
But if you are a small project or a small company, there is zero shame
in putting a password protected certificate somewhere.
I mean, maybe don't check it in, but that's another story. But you know what I mean?
There is nothing wrong with having a file versus an HSM
if you are small because the reality is HS MS
are expensive and they come with a lot of overhead,
they need care and feeding.
They're like having a child and so small organizations, small projects.
There's no shame in not having an HSM if you
a large organization and you have a security team and you have security budget.
You should have one of these because it saves you.
Like what just happened to
github would be a non-event if these certificates weren't stolen.
I'm just looking at this number of custom
number of symmetric
national calculations.
I mean, you're looking at base. Oh, good Lord.
Um You're looking at literally dollars per month
to use Amazon web services. KM si believe that.
So I, I think at this point
it's more, I would say it's, it's not even a cost issue anymore.
It's more of an organizational expertise issue.
And if you're
like a Corp or a major nonprofit with actual funding,
then this is kind of like having locks on the front door.
I
agree. And, and look, the thing is it's going to save you pain and suffering.
Right?
Well, it's like, you know what the problem is? A K MS or an HSM is like backups.
You don't need it until you need it until you need it. They're useless.
-- It's just an
-- expense
when you need it.
Holy
cow.
And I think that's
again an organization like github who, you know,
talks about being a steward of your data and
providing services with how many nines of up time,
right?
This is, I kind of worry now, what else are they not getting? Right, because this is
so,
so this is part of the, the thing we should talk about, right?
Because it's easy to say, oh, Github
should have done this bad, Github.
Bad, bad, bad.
But the reality is
any reasonably sized organization and Github has what?
Literally tens of 1000 employees.
I don't actually know how many it's, it's, I'm sure it's a lot.
But the point is any large organization has lots and lots of projects.
They have lots and lots of divisions
and the security teams do their best to keep track of this stuff.
but you just can't find it all
-- and it is extremely plausible. They didn't know.
-- Yeah, but github
desktop is a flagship product.
-- I would agree with that
-- github
desktop is literally like how people use github.
Like I've been recommending github desktop for half a decade.
Yeah. Well, because it's on windows, it's like the best way to use github,
-- but,
-- well, even on not windows, it's still the
point is
ignoring that.
The fact is
it wasn't done.
It is quite likely the security team either didn't know
or they had like a transition plan because you also
can't just like say use an HSM now and the
next day you're using it like this takes time.
I'm kind of wondering is the security team actually
responsible for that because in a lot of organizations,
they've kind of tried to
kind of offload that cost by saying, you know, DEV se
ops, which if done properly is good and well done.
But the problem I find with a lot of devs Se
ops is, well, the SEC part, like most Devs don't have a lot of SEC, you know,
and that's something we're working on at the CS A with the working group.
But like the Devs, I suspect the Devs would be like, well, we have a certificate,
we keep it in a github
repo, which is pretty safe because, like, let's face it.
Github repos if they're private are actually pretty damn
safe until somebody steals a personal access token.
Obviously on and on the flip side, like, if the security team not responsible for it,
why are they gonna go looking for more work?
I would say
it is the responsibility of a large organization,
security team to be the steward of, we'll say
encrypted
content like keys and certificates and things like that.
And I think that would be expected and my suspicion is they didn't know about these.
That is my strongest suspicion about this because like
at the, the large organizations I've talked to
and the obviously anchor is very small,
but like elastic and red hat were of reasonable size.
And there were security teams who handled certificates and code
signing certificates in the HS MS and all that stuff
because
there's no way you're going to teach a developer
how to properly handle a certificate or a key.
-- They're going to leak it because it's just hard to do.
-- Well,
well, I mean,
yeah,
and that's what drives me nuts about these code signing keys.
Is everybody pretends somehow like they're hard to get
or you have to steal them or whatever.
And it's like you can get a personal code signing certificate for 40 bucks a year.
Actually, I don't know how the apple ones work.
So for in the windows world it starts at
40 dollars us per year for code signing certificates.
And because that's what drives me nuts is everybody's like, oh,
you can steal these certificates and use them to sign malware.
And I'm like,
-- or hear me out, you can just spend 40 bucks a year and buy one.
-- Yeah. Right. Right.
I mean, malware authors are caught doing that all the time
where they just sign their stuff because it's not hard to do.
Well,
it's really easy to steal these keys from small hardware manufacturers because,
like, again, remember that my webcams
literally are, like, download this software from some IP address in China.
And I'm like, God,
uh,
I think we're getting close to banning that one. Kurt, you know.
Well, but it keeps happening. Right.
Like, it's, it's, that's the one thing I really,
I don't understand with windows is this, like, weird, like, on the one hand,
they have like, good drivers from Intel and those people,
but then they have like this just giant gap where as a windows, you know,
I have to download all this weird dodgy stuff from Lord knows where
to make hardware that I bought in a store.
Or, you know, online from a, a seemingly reputable
-- Amazon reseller. It's funny
-- you say this. So,
you know, I'm helping that robotics team. Right.
And,
and we needed cameras to put on the robot because we're
pretty much of cameras on the robot that we're doing.
Like object detection. It's really cool the work these kids are doing.
It's amazing.
And
so I go on Amazon and I find an industrial camera
because this is gonna get beat up a little bit.
So it needs like a little bit of oomph behind it. Right.
And so I find this nice industrial camera and it's not like, it's 50 bucks,
nothing big, but we need five.
So, like, we need a lot of
and
yeah, well, whatever, it's fine.
So
we get the cameras and the kids open the box and there's like a, a URL that's like,
download drivers here and they go to the URL
and it's someone's like a Google Drive folder.
I'm like, do not download anything in that folder. Like we will not use any of this.
My favorite is when it goes to, what's the one from the new Zealand guy?
Uh, meta.
Oh,
mega download. You mean mega download.
Yeah, that's the one that's my favorite when I,
when I had to get drivers once and they were,
they, it went to Omega and I'm like, uh,
well, now,
and I check it through virus total and it seems clean.
Right. Yeah, that's fair. That's fair.
Anyway, now, for us though, the cameras work flawlessly on Linux.
They're running on a Raspberry Pi because we have a
12 volt battery powering a robot like we're not,
you're not running a PC. Here. It all works. But the point of all this is
the reason you sign this code is for like this reason.
So you're not distributing like random crap out
of random places and people are like,
who put this here? Did someone put this here?
And the certificate Glens will say a minimal
amount of credibility to the thing you're downloading.
-- I won't say
-- it's safe except that don't know the name of
the certificate to match up with the software from the vendor.
Well, but when you, when you run it, like Microsoft will say, oh,
this application is signed by the Microsoft Corporation or
yeah, and that's not the name of the Amazon reseller that sold me the camera.
Well, in your case, no, we know your software is like dodgy. That's obvious,
just like I'm sure there's other stuff.
But the point is if I have an executable and I'm expecting
it to be from github and the certificate says it's from github
theoretically, it's from github.
Well,
I think part of the problem is this works for websites
because I tend to interact with websites repeatedly like walmart.com,
amazon.com, td.com, whatever, right?
I go multiple times.
I don't install my software that often.
That's right. You don't
but the point is it doesn't matter, whatever, this is hard. I mean, it,
ah,
-- oh, my goodness.
-- I, anyways back to the code signing thing is that so, I think github
made reasonable tradeoffs.
I would have kind of preferred that they expire,
they revoke the certificate rather sooner rather than later.
But at the same time,
they wanted to give people a window of opportunity
to upgrade the software so that they have that like
seamless kind of upgrade experience and don't have like this
basically where it slams into a wall,
comes to a screeching halt and they have to like manually reinstall it.
Well, you also have to warn people.
You can't like it's if,
if the certificates were just revoked one day and there was no message from github,
what would you think, Kurt,
-- they got compromised like they did.
-- I would expect
a devastating compromise though.
Right. I would,
I would not expect it to be minor anyway. Ok.
Before we run ourselves out of time,
I have one other point of this whole story I want to touch on and that is that
Attackers took
the code repositories that were private repositories
and no one gives two craps about that.
-- They're open source projects.
-- But the, the stuff they took wasn't open though.
Right. Well, but by definition, every everything running in the github
desktop is from
-- github.com/desktop,
-- except something taken was from a private repositories.
Hopefully it was just certificates and stuff
Well, I don't know what it is, but here,
here's the point of that though is no one's making a big deal about it.
And that makes me happy because I think a decade ago
if someone stole private repositories, everyone would be making a huge deal about,
oh, trade secrets.
And someone took your private repositories and they
might have secret source code and this,
that or another.
And I feel like we've reached a point in,
in the universe
where no one cares if someone steals your source code anymore.
Because I think we, we're starting to recognize, like the source code
has no value.
It's the people.
It's like you always, you always tell me if,
if someone gave me all of the aws source code,
I could do nothing with it and I agree with that.
Well, and especially this
github desktop is an open source software. Like it's
-- right.
-- Right. It's, it's open.
But like, here's the thing, even,
even if the Windows source code was leaked and
I know it's been leaked at least once again.
But you know what I mean? Like, there's no value in that. It, it's, what was it?
The, the, the Russian is it
Yandex? It's called the Russian Google
Yandex. Yeah,
Yandex. It's a 40 some gig repo.
-- Yeah,
-- there's like
two
years
old. No one cares.
Well,
actually one thing that somebody did a bit
of analysis that was kind of interesting was
how do they rank web pages and there was actually,
I, I would not have guessed this number. There's about 12,000 or 1200
signals they used to rank a web page. So that was kind of interesting actually. So
I imagine, um,
now this and this is one of those things
where like this is actually quite useful for Attackers
like seo people to kind of
help bump it.
But it's, it's not like the kind of attack that where you're gonna like hijack and E
or put something in your web page that dam it's at the front of the
pack.
And that's, I think that's one thing.
It's, it's funny because this is coming, um, this is, uh,
happening with the chat GP T and A I stuff is
like,
how do we notice these attacks where it's kind of
like I dial up a percentage point of car accidents.
Like, would we even notice that?
Or I dial down a percentage?
I make like the banking system a half percent less efficient.
Like there's a real cost to that. But is anybody even gonna notice it?
-- I, I
-- mean,
probably not something like that and even I think
knowing how a search engine picks their ordering or,
or, or cataloging or whatever it is,
like there's seo companies you can talk to
that, they've reverse engineered a lot of this stuff because
-- in fact,
-- they do
testing and whatnot.
And every time Google reorders their search, like what is it roughly every summer
there's like this giant apocalypse and they have to like re, you know,
it's a cat and mouse game like
it, they, they, they figure it out and I think that's,
that's what happens a lot.
I think in many of these instances is we used
to think of source code as somehow special in secret.
And I think
the world has gotten so good at reverse engineering,
-- whatever it is you're doing well on
-- fuzzing.
Even you don't even have to reverse engineer anymore.
You just like run American fuzzy
up and like out pops a buffer overflow in about a couple of hours.
Like no, I mean,
it's not that easy but it's,
it's not that hard either.
Well, and actually, I mean, so one of my favorite examples of that is
there are
this just came out so well, I'll start though Mario 64 was
decom
into C
so you can take, they have,
they have Mario 64 C code that if you compile it with the correct version of GCC,
which they use GCC to compile Mario 64 back in the day.
If you compile Mario 64 you literally get the same
ram bite for bite,
meaning it is literally exactly the same
OK. Bite for bite. That's impressive.
-- I know.
-- Right.
See this is why we need reproducible builds is for old video games.
Well, abs,
no, now here's the thing though.
So people are now taking the source code and they're fixing bugs
like
they found, if you just, if you just build Mario 64 with optimism
on, they build it with dash 00 at the time because the compiler was so new,
they're worried about bugs.
But if you just build it with optimizations,
you drastically increase the frame rate of the game just
like it's hilarious
anyway.
And they just did this for the legend of Zelda
linked to the past where they now have C code.
-- Oh,
-- did they fix the graveyard bug?
Did they? What?
Sorry, Legend of Zelda linked to the bat. What's the original one on the,
on the cartridge? From the,
-- the legend
-- of Zelda?
The legend of Zelda?
-- There's, there's been so many I can't which
-- graveyard bug
with all the ghosts and then the whistle that one.
But you need that bug so you can cause arbitrary code execution to,
to beat the game in like seven minutes or whatever anyway. Anyway. OK. All right.
Let's wrap this one all up now. So like
github, I guess
we'll say a bad thing happened.
I won't say they, they didn't do anything wrong, right? I think this just happened.
I think there's a,
an even worse problem here, which is
why the heck is that code signing certificate valid through many, many years? Like
this is one thing that lets encrypt, for example,
has fixed is you get three month certificates.
So the impact of a compromise certificate
is just drastically reduced. Because remember
when web service certificates they used to,
you could buy them and they would last for years, multiple years.
And then the web browsers have pushed back on that now. And you're about max one year
with like, let's encrypting it properly at three months
and I would pause it that well,
this is kind of is essentially it's enforced key rotation.
And I think there would be some real value in like
these code signing certificates only lasting a year or two,
not
-- seven years or 10 years.
-- This is, this is Apple's fault.
Then I'm going to blame Apple.
Well, yeah,
they could just arbitrarily say we'll only
accept one year certificates from now on.
And that, that's what they should do. I don't know, I don't know exactly how co
funding works in the Apple Ecosystem. I don't know how they,
if github
picked that date or the Apple Ecosystem tools
just generated that date or what happened.
But fundamentally,
I'll blame Apple for that, not github.
So that's fine.
And I would expect
any certificate,
user will create a certificate that is the maximum
amount of time they are allowed to create.
Well, it depends if you're paying for it because you're paying for it by the year.
Typically,
like when we did it, we did one year certificates because it's just simpler.
Um But also it depends on how you're doing it because for example,
you can just do it through the apple interface where they just sort of magically
like you generate the keys in the web
interface, you know, developer.apple.com/whatever,
you know,
create the keys, you know,
shove it into your test flight and then shove it into your well
into the cue of like can you pretty please let us release this?
And they're like, no because blah
and I'm like it doesn't do that like it doesn't
anyway. Alright, whatever dragging on, we're dragging on. Alright.
So all in all I think I'll give github
props for detecting this in a day,
which is great
then doing a proper investigation for expiring their certificates. You know,
you know, I wonder if this is what triggered them, looking at the rest of them.
So looking at the timeline, I actually think it's the other way around.
I suspect they noticed this because they say this happened December 6th, right?
-- That is what is in their blog. Yes.
-- Hi, Kurt Siefried.
We're writing to let you know that we
observe suspicious activity that suggests a threat actor accessed
your github organization through a compromised organization member or
outside collaborator account and downloaded private repository metadata.
We are in the process of notifying all identified
affected users and organizations and revoking associated credentials.
What happened?
We do not believe the attacker obtained these
tokens via compromise of github or its systems
because the tokens in question are not stored
by github in their original usable formats.
At this time,
evidence suggests that the threat actors use compromised organizational member
and or outside collaborator accounts to access the following organizations.
Cloud security line syndrome.
Anyways.
And it's one of our Debs Wednesday, December 7th 1:53 p.m. that email from github
support.
So here's my suspicion, they noticed their personal access
to
and
accessing their private repos and went,
what the heck did this happen anywhere else?
-- And then it
-- did,
that feels related
because it's uncanny. But I would also say if they detected this on the sixth
and they mailed you on the seventh,
-- that is a top notch security organization right there.
-- This is why you use github.
Their stuff works
-- and they seem to care about security.
-- Yeah. No, absolutely.
And I mean, look, we, we talked to what, Jill a couple of weeks ago, right? Like github
security organization is, is the real deal.
-- Well, it better because, like, I
-- suppose they host the World software. Like,
I shouldn't be surprised.
So, anyway. All right. All right, I'm gonna call this one.
I feel like it's interesting to talk about if you're a small org,
don't feel bad if you're storing certificates and you get up repo.
But if you're a big organization, holy crap,
-- get an HSM
-- or just rent one online for like, 11 bucks a month.
That's what I mean, same thing. Like, you don't, don't own things anymore.
It's fine. Just rent it. Um, actually fun fact.
I have an HSM in a box in my basement from back in the Red Hat
-- days when they gave me one for testing
-- one of the PC R card ones.
Yes, it is.
And it's got all the black whatever that like,
like resin coating is over all of the chips.
The potting compound,
it weighs a ton. It probably weighs more than a kilogram
on
one card anyway. All right. All right. That's it. I'm calling it. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. Go to social security podcast.com. Head up,
Susie Pounds
his podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the.