Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime.
Josh Bresser.
I miss thought Crime.
Those are better days.
Uh,
that's what you think
anyway.
All right.
So,
-- Kurt, what is the zero day?
-- Well, I can tell you when I see one but
the definition of it is basically terrible.
-- I don't think there is a definition of it.
-- Well, and that's the thing, right?
It's, it's
one of those
colloquial language
things of there's no formal body to define it and even within the text scene,
it has different meanings within different parts of the text scene.
All right. Well, we should first start by, why is this a topic
that we're even talking about today? And there have been
a handful of,
we'll say stories and incidents in the last probably two
or three months where people have called the question.
Is that really a zero day?
And then this big discussion erupts of, well, what even is a zero day.
And of course, there's generally no agreement
and
my answer is going to be the best non answers ever, which is, who cares?
Well,
you're not.
Yeah. No, I, I would, I'm gonna go with, you're not entirely wrong.
I mean, see, to me, part of it,
to me, I think that the,
I think the biggest problem with Zero Day is it kind of goes to this
intent
as opposed to actually defining what something is, right?
It's not so much of an observation of something,
but what is the intent behind that something? Right.
So, I mean,
basically the way vulnerabilities typically work is somebody finds it and
then somebody either tells the world at large or they tell
the vendor
kind of or the upstream project responsible for it or maybe they sell it to bad guys,
but essentially it gets distributed to some degree, right?
And then the problem is like,
I think it's clearly a zero day when only one human being on the planet knows about it.
But as soon as it starts to be distributed,
part of the question is what is the intent of that distribution is
the intent of that distribution to fix it or to exploit it?
And I think traditionally zero day assumes the intent
to exploit is what makes it a zero day.
So,
you know what's actually funny you just reminded me of
also in the way you describe that is zero day.
Some people call O day
and
you know what I came to realize is after talking to a handful of people and,
and I'm doing the, the hacker history podcast now.
Which is one of my other side projects because
I have copious amounts of free time apparently.
And I've realized that old people say, zero day, young people say, oh day.
That is. I've just, there's, I don't know where the line is yet.
I can't wait to figure this out.
But that seems to be what I've ascertained is the, if you're, if you're old like us,
it's Zero Day.
But if you're young and cool,
it's an O day. So that's interesting.
But anyway, anyway,
I don't talk to people much recently.
So I
just, but that's a good point.
I'm going to pay attention because one thing I noticed
at the playground at some point in the last few years
when the kids say, ok,
count from 1 to 10 and then the game starts and all the kids count 1 to 10, like 1 to 10.
That's it.
-- Right. And I'm like, oh, that's clever.
-- That's malicious compliance. I,
I suspect you're right because I have heard people refer to it as an old day.
But I never,
like,
I just
was kind of like, oh, that's weird. You know, nuer,
sure, whatever. N,
yeah, that's, that's the word.
I
know it's nuclear. I know.
I'm constantly correcting my one son because, and I'm like, there's,
and I'll write it out for him and I'm like, there's no, and he just, you know,
he's picked it up from listening to youtube and stuff.
Right. Right. Oh, man. Ok. So anyway, anyway, here is, I think where
I
would like to go with this and this is a
bigger discussion point than just zero day o day.
What is, what it is, what it isn't.
I think we exist in a place,
especially in the security world where we don't often have well defined terms.
This is kind of, one of my complaints is a lot of other
professions have like standards, bodies that help define a lot of these things.
-- And we don't always
-- have that,
you know what? It's actually a lot more subtle than that.
It's not just that the standards bodies define the
language but that they use the language consistently.
They may not even have like a dictionary or a glossary, but the fact that they
use a term consistently to mean one thing and then maybe switch it up
later that gives it that that sort of gravitas that that's what that is.
You know, it's like Schrodinger's cat.
It's been defined because we keep looking at it and agreeing that it looks like a cat.
Oh
man, I'm not,
don't get me started on Schrodinger's cat because the way we
describe it is the opposite of what he wanted to convey.
I know it's the ridiculousness of bla bla bla
anyways. But the point is if language is what people
say it is
right in
the
whole
versus Cracker debate, I'm like, sorry guys that,
that ship sailed sank and it's gone.
You know what my favorite.
And I think that's easier to understand these days is what is, what is crypto
in your mind.
Well, it depends what part of the world you're asking me about because
in my Blockchain world, what is
the question?
You know,
cry,
I'm banging
my shoe on the desk. Answer the question.
So crypto to me used to be just pure cryptography. You know,
I don't care what it used to be.
-- Answer the question, what I would say
-- if somebody said,
can you define what crypto is for me?
Now, I would basically talk about Blockchain cryptocurrencies.
-- And
-- I think that's what the vast majority of people would describe it
as and I'm sure we have someone listening who's yelling at there.
No, it's B GP or GP G or whatever.
-- No.
-- Well, no crypto used to stand for crypto
Gray
essentially, which was all sorts of encryption.
And eventually the word got co opted by the Cryptocurrency people.
And now when you say crypto, it basically means Cryptocurrency. And
like there's plenty of us that are going to die in this hill and don't get me wrong.
I will never use the word crypto on purpose to describe Cryptocurrency.
It always means cryptography in my mind.
But I mean, generally speaking, like society decided we lost, that's it.
Well, and my favorite thing is all these medical terms
but become insults,
right? Things like moron and imbecile used to have specific medical meanings.
So people use them to, you know, insult somebody
and they became insults and fell out of medical use.
You know what my favorite one is actually is the word Nimrod. Yeah.
Do you know the story behind this one?
-- Uh, no.
-- So Nimrod in the Bible is a great hunter, right?
In a looney tunes. Cartoon bugs bunny calls Elmer Fudd. A Nimrod.
Not, not necessarily to make fun of him but to like, be
the great hunter.
Most people decided that Bugs bunny was making
fun of Elmer Fudd because let's face it.
That's pretty much all he ever does.
And so Nimrod becomes a derogatory term
instead of meaning Great Hunter,
which I think is one of my favorite. Just
-- strained, twisting of the language.
-- Well, let's face it.
Bugs Bunny has a lot of pole.
I love bugs bunny man.
Like, you know, you want to talk about being an influencer.
Bugs bunny is an influencer.
-- I,
-- well, he used to be, I don't think he has quite the influence. He used to,
man. I love the loony tunes actually on Saturday morning.
Now, one of the weird, like over the air TV stations because like,
everyone has like 100 TV stations over the air.
One of them started playing looney tunes on Saturday mornings.
And so I'm forcing my Children to watch it with me,
which is lovely and they're just as good as they always were.
At least, I think so. But anyway,
zero day. Right. Let's focus on Zero day. Oh, sorry.
We actually have eight over the air TV channels locally. I had no idea.
Yeah, there's like tons of them now.
And you can actually, I use PLEX to receive the, the signal and on my pluck server,
I've got a little USB TV tuner thing.
You can do, I plug in
and then you can, like, you can even view it while you're gone.
Like I can, I can watch local TV when I'm like three states over. It's pretty cool.
Anyway, anyway, zero day. So I guess here's the thing
I've been noticing when zero days get described.
The historical definition is very much a, this was completely unknown
and all of a sudden it's known and often
it became news because it was being exploited actively.
And I think most of the usage I see now is a
zero day means an exploit being exploited before there is a fix.
Yes.
And not just an exploit before a fix, but an exploit before knowledge of the exploit.
Like we ran into the exploit in the wild.
Not even knowledge, knowledge is irrelevant in this.
From what I've seen, I think it is if there is no fix, it is going to be called a zero day.
So even if they know they still consider it a zero day.
Yeah, I mean, there was, there's been tons of stuff, like,
look at that Microsoft Exchange thing.
-- Where that was.
-- Well today right now, the V eight thing,
there's a, there's an,
somebody just literally dropped an exploit for V
eight Cloud flare had actually a really good
response on hacker news about how they rolled it out in like 23 hours the update.
But all the browsers edge and chrome have not
done it.
And I'm actually, right now, I have the Tab Open in github
with the
javascript. It's 100 and 21.
Actually, it's quite well written and nicely.
It, it's, it's good licensed under the BSD two clause, which I don't agree with.
-- But, but wasn't
-- it, it was fixed in va a couple days ago though, right.
But that's not a zero day then, right? By the traditional definition.
Well, but it hasn't made it into my web browser yet.
So as far as I'm concerned, it's sort of
-- a zero day. Yes,
-- exactly.
I think the traditional definition of
completely unknown obviously is irrelevant.
It got fixed someone from, from what I've gathered and I don't have any secret
here, but from what I've gathered, it got fixed,
then someone wrote an exploit for it, right?
Which is, which is not how zero days are supposed to work. It's supposed to be, right?
The exploit, exploit, the exploit and then, oh ha ha. Look, we found a zero day.
But anyway, it doesn't matter though, right? Because who cares?
You have a functioning javascript exploit that affects Chrome.
Now, now mind you Fran, I mean, hopefully this will be
and
that's true because edges
edges chromium for anyone listening,
this will probably be fixed by the time this gets published.
But
it does
doesn't let you escape the sandbox.
So you also need, you need to use this exploit and then a sandbox escape.
So you need, you need to but whatever it doesn't matter.
So anyway, the point is the traditional definition obviously wouldn't be zero day,
but I'm perfectly comfortable calling this a zero day because this
is an exploit without a fix and people care about that.
Well, without a usable fix, I mean, I've seen exploits where somebody's like, and,
and
here's a code patch and it's like great,
but I need the actual code patched and a binary built and shipped to me because,
well, like a perfect example is open SSL, right?
Open SSL can issue all the software updates, like source code updates they want.
I'm looking suspiciously at my TV.
-- Yeah, that hasn't seen an open SSL update in a decade.
-- Right.
I don't think it'll actually my TV is dumb
enough that it doesn't even go on the network.
So
I,
I
it's funny my TV si buy them, I connect them into the internet.
I download the updates. Then I turn off all the network.
You never, you never need to talk to anyone ever again.
Well, honestly,
even as terrible as the experience of like a fire stick
now it's still better than whatever's built into a TV.
Oh, absolutely. 100% because I actually own, I have an LG TV, and a Samsung TV.
And they're, like, built in everything is terrible.
It is an awful experience and I know they're just spying on me constantly.
Well, that's the whole point of it is for them to make a few more dollars.
That's why those things,
there's a good thread on hacker news about why are there like
no tvs without all those crap reloaded?
And the answer is because preloading that crap is their profit margin.
Yeah.
Right.
Um, but back to the zero day thing,
one thing you mentioned and I think that it just tweaked for me is,
it's a matter of perspective
in the sense of
there are vastly different perspectives for the attacker
for the person who kind of owns and has to, you know,
update the software for the end user of the software.
And so I suspect part of the problem is what is
a zero day also depends on what your perspective is,
you know, and an extreme example, you know, my perspective as a guy with
two windows machines,
a couple of macs and some tablets and whatnot
is very different than a fortune 100 company,
I would hope so
well. But in the sense of if I have a car,
it doesn't matter if you have a fleet of cars or I have a single car a recall is a recall.
-- I
-- mean,
-- yeah, I guess
-- like that's one thing that always, I, I still,
I don't think I fully understand but with technology as
you get fundamentally different things at scale,
especially with numbers and diversity.
Yeah, without question.
And I think in a lot of instances,
the technology is very much like a monoculture
because you think you basically have Windows and Mac
and those probably account for 95% of the web browsers in use on well on computers.
-- I mean, a
-- mobile
mobile mobile is probably slightly different.
So thinking about this is part of it is what is the intent of zero day? What is it trying
to describe or get across?
And in my mind,
it was always here is something dangerous for which we don't have a
way to either fix it or deal with it safely because there are,
I remember there are zero days that popped out and it it was simple,
just turn feature X off and live without it for a day
or two or close off this network port or you know,
whatever do something simple, right?
And it was easy to live without.
And then conversely,
there are zero days like this chrome javascript thing where it's
OK. Don't browse the web well, OK. My web browser is not very useful.
Yeah, that's not gonna fly. I
mean,
II I think the your description of calling it like this is something important.
That's,
I think that's what it really comes down to is like the true meaning is long gone
and it's just, if something's called a zero Day, you probably need to pay attention,
you know.
-- Yeah.
-- I think there is value in, where is this bug in the life cycle?
Because I could, you know, I find the world's worst security flaw on windows 10,
it's remotely exploitable.
And I tell Microsoft, well, cool. but it's
going to take Microsoft more than five minutes to react.
Yeah, for sure.
And I mean,
that's why they have their co ordinated disclosure programs and even bug bunnies to
a degree because it's an easy way to say here's a couple of bucks.
Thanks for helping.
Yeah, we need like a
month or three to actually fix it.
Yeah.
-- Yeah. And I get that right. That's fine.
-- We were on the receiving end of that.
-- How many times at Red Hat? A
-- million?
I mean, and we were, we were pretty quick for sure.
But there were,
there were always things that the challenge there is always and this is, I mean,
this is one of the dangers with kind of zero day.
If you rush a fix, it's not uncommon at all to make the problem worse
than taking your time and doing it right.
Because I mean, shell shock is like the best example of this where they,
they rushed the wrong fix,
what, three times
and
then, and then it was finally like, please fix it. Right.
-- Well,
-- I, I remember the same thing with the uh the qac
stack
vulnerabilities many years ago. And uh here we go, found it. And originally Kace
was like, oh, we can fix this real easy. It'll be a one megabyte guard page and
this should work. Oh, that, right. And off the surface of it. Yeah.
No, no, no, that was fine. And then I'm spacing out the
flooring.
Um,
you know, looked into it and he's like, no, uh the stack
guard page is gonna have to be like, what was it like?
-- One or two gigabytes or something? It was
-- ridiculously large
and ok. Ok.
That's act ok. On 64 bit systems, we can live with that.
But on 32 bit systems, it means you can have three processes.
Right. Yeah, that's not going to work.
And I mean, this was back in the day when 32 bit binary still existed.
-- I mean, they're much rarer now,
-- but I super respect Apple for killing off 32 bit.
I was painful as it is for people. I'm sorry, folks. It's, it's 2021.
I've had a 64 bit computer for the better part of two decades.
Thanks a MD by the way. And prior to that deck alpha.
But you know, like,
-- you know what
-- makes this interesting though is on in the Windows Universe is games
because there's still 32 bit games being created,
but also all the old games that still run on Windows.
-- Those are all 32 bit in
-- Windows.
10, I can still run my D OS apps cleanly and my Windows 95 apps cleanly.
-- So, I sure that's not a problem.
-- What do you mean? It's not a problem.
-- They're running all in the 32 bit user space, but
-- they're running in a VM. Basically.
-- Do they
-- run in VMS? I don't know, I don't know how they do it.
-- Yeah,
-- they're basically running in a, like that, that, what is it?
Windows compatibility mode or whatever it's called. It's basically a VM.
It, I mean, if it is, that's great because that's the right way to do it for sure.
When you have technology that's 20 years old.
It's a lot easier to run it in a VM and have it as
its own separate thing than it is to properly integrate it into the system.
I mean,
I agree the fact that we still have reserved device names
and Windows like com and PR N and stuff like that.
So funny, it just breaks, like
there are so many applications that if you try and pass it as a file name, it just,
it just, wow, it just,
there was something you could, I forget what it is.
Now, there was, there was like a file you could open on Windows that would like,
brick the disk or something.
Oh, the NTFS thing. Yeah and no, no, no.
If you have a symbolic link, it was, it was pretty recent even. Yeah.
If you have a symbolic link and you open it and blah, blah, blah, blah blah. Yeah,
ntfs is really interesting and that they actually
I finally found some documentation on it from
a disc recovery firm because I looked into it about 20 years ago when I did
file wiping utilities.
Because if a file was smaller,
then about four kilobytes instead of storing it on the disk,
like a traditional data, it's stored it in sort of any leftover space in the, in the,
in the master file table.
Right? Because,
well, if I think the master file table entries are like four kilobytes.
So if there's a bit of data in there and then why not
just put the file in there instead of having a second thing,
right?
But the problem is if you touch the master file table improperly, yeah,
you have a dead system.
Your, your disc is like, it's, it's gone, it's corrupt.
Like that's how that, like when you start corrupting your, you know,
your disk system,
well, yeah,
-- it
-- breaks.
I mean,
yeah,
yeah, I buy that anyway.
And the funny thing is the response to that like in the
world is ok,
we're going to have multiple copies of these tables.
I mean, fat does that fat has a backup table because I know
in,
I forget what it was.
I had something, some, like we would call it iot now, but it was,
it was some device I had a long time ago that would only
update one of the fat tables on the like flash card it used.
And so every time I plugged it in windows was like
this disc appears to be corrupt. Do you want me to fix it? And I always click.
No, because if I click, yes, it trashed the disk.
So
it's like this works. I think it was a camera maybe. But anyway, anyway,
so
I think for the purposes of zero day, maybe that's the problem in that.
Not only is it
describing intent, but it's describing intent from different perspectives.
-- I
-- mean, to a degree, but I think honestly if we want to,
well,
the people with different perspectives
aren't going to agree with each other because they don't have
the empathy or the intelligence to go as an attacker.
I'm going to look at it from the defender's point of view and vice versa. Who cares?
I mean, so one of the,
I think this is one of those places where we have to just be like
it doesn't matter because the right way to
handle security vulnerabilities isn't to call them.
This is the Chrome Zero Day.
It's to have easy to acquire identifiers and basically
say like this is what this thing is called.
Is there a fix? Yes. Is there a fix?
No?
Right. And that's when you can start making decisions.
Because I think the term zero day has taken on so much, so,
so much importance because it's all we have and
it's a terrible solution to a difficult problem.
Well, here's another thought is
for more mature companies that are running bug bounties and are running, you know,
coordinate disclosure efforts.
A zero day effectively implies that their system has failed like this V eight bug.
How come
the guy or the person didn't go, you know how come V eight fixed it? And Google didn't,
to me that looks like a failure.
Maybe I don't know the story behind it. So I can't say for sure.
I mean, look even I don't think I would call it a
it might be a failure, it might not be a failure.
I'm sitting here with a vulnerable web browser that's a failure.
Just don't run chrome
well. But,
and that's an option in this case.
But what if it was a vulnerability in Linux or Windows kernel?
It, it it can happen.
So in my mind, this zero day is an indication that the system
failed
that
I, I'm now vulnerable for potentially hours, days, weeks,
it will be days for sure. I mean, you probably can't build a new version of chrome
in under a couple of days because they just,
they do a lot of testing and there's all kinds of stuff that happens from
back in the day when I helped firefox out when I was at Red Hat.
I think it was three days was the absolute minimum
Mozilla needed to push a new Firefox.
And that was like, that was people working 24 7.
-- I don't buy
-- that from Google because they
can massively parallelize testing of this thing.
They probably do and it still takes a long time.
Also. Chrome is their cash cow.
That is
what directly
accounts and well not accounts enables
-- a lot of their revenue. It
-- is the hose from which we all drink.
Yeah.
So I,
in my mind if I,
you know, if it was vulnerable for minutes, sure.
Cool. Hours. Ok. Acceptable days.
-- More than a week,
-- I mean, more than a week would be unacceptable.
-- But I think days is within the realm of, well, it's
-- been almost a week now.
Has it.
That's, see, that's, that's a long time.
Well, and the funny thing is because it doesn't have a CV or anything.
-- I can't, it's a pain in the butt to, to track this down. Right.
-- Right.
Which again is where, I mean, calling it, the Chrome Zero Day is ridiculous.
Yeah, I guess the chrome Zero day of whatever day it was actually zero date.
It's not a name. Right. It needs, it needs a CV ID.
Which of course, you know,
we've talked about in the couple episodes ago about why CVS busted.
-- But, well,
-- the Legacy CV system project is busted. CVE, I mean, the,
is the barcodes work fine. It's the entity of signing the barcodes.
That's not being so awesome.
Yeah, that's,
that's true. They're too slow,
too slow, too complicated, too, too much of a whole problem. Go
listen to the episode, go a couple of episodes back.
We, we take care of that.
But anyway, anyway,
I think, ok, so we've gone to the marvelously strange place again as usual. But
I think fundamentally the takeaway I have from all of
this stuff and everything going on is that firstly,
language is going to evolve.
So what a thing used to mean,
it doesn't matter if it doesn't mean that anymore. Like who cares?
-- It's just how it works.
-- It's
like the consensus mechanism for a language is
if X number of people believe something,
something, it means something.
Yeah, exactly.
Like a perfect example is in English, if I say the word shit, that is a swear word,
the direct French equivalent. Mad, no big deal, right?
It's just, and like the French have agreed that mad is not a big deal.
But in English, there's,
there are literally words I cannot say on this podcast
because Josh will bleep out the fact that I even mentioned
the substitute that we use for that word. He would bleep that out, right?
And, and so, and that,
-- and then there's other cultures where that word is is fine and
-- I, I do detest the way
that
society treats certain words
because I mean, so, so the challenge is the real reason I care is
when you use a naughty word on a podcast,
you have to mark it explicit or Apple dings you
and once you mark one episode explicit, the whole podcast is explicit for everyone
and you can never undo that.
-- So do you think we've
-- accidentally said a rude word in some foreign language?
Hopefully?
I mean,
now I kind of start slipping them in.
It's, it's apple, they're an American company.
I'm sure they don't care at all about any other language except English
and let's face it.
You know what it really comes down to and, and I think this is,
this is kind of part of this conversation a little bit is
if you use naughty words in America,
there is,
there are certain groups that will come and complain,
right? And they're an extreme minority, but they're really loud and annoying.
-- Well, not just complain, they will pitch fork and burn you down. I mean,
-- right.
Like Janet Jackson Super Bowl,
I remember that that was a big
-- deal.
-- It was marvelous.
But you know what I mean?
And, and I think you, you kind of to a degree, like, I think with crypto,
we sort of had this where there was a small vocal group that was like,
no crypto means cryptography and
it was just like whatever nerds, shut up. We don't care and they lost, right?
And it's always intriguing to me how some of
these groups managed to kind of carry this,
this,
this outrage around with them
and managed to get it somewhere. Well, hacker and cracker. Yeah.
But like that one, that one,
no one cared.
No people still, oh, man. Check the comments on the hacker news. People still care.
I'm sure some people do, but I don't think it's, I don't think it's enough to matter,
you know.
No, clearly not. I mean that ship sailed, but
here's the other thing is
people need words to describe things
and they're going to
probably take a similar word and, or co
opt something.
But what's interesting to me is that sort of laziness factor of shorting it,
shortening it from Cryptocurrency to just crypto.
Is that a common thing?
I don't know,
maybe we need to find a linguist who tracks
this because we have to invent new words constantly.
I love the German approach to it,
like the German approach to it. Ok. This thing, this thing flies.
So what do we call it?
Fluky,
literally flying thing?
You know,
this animal, this white animal with a white stripe down its back. It smells bad.
What do we call it? Ok.
Stint
you
stinky animal.
Actually, you know what?
You know what my favorite is my,
my daughter is learning Japanese because she wants to speak Japanese and she is 12
and she told me the other day that the word for penguin,
they don't have a word for penguin.
They call it business goose.
I'm like,
that is the greatest word ever.
Yeah. Like cobra chicken.
-- What's a cobra
-- chicken? It's a goose. If there's a famous meme, some,
you know, farmhand is like, doesn't speak English well, and he's like,
I do not like the cobra goose,
the cobra goose.
No
chicken, you just said?
Yeah, I get that because geese are horrible creatures.
Well, I love that they are fantastically aggressive.
Um,
and also I'm just learning, there's actually,
I didn't realize how many different kinds of geese work
because I've really only ever known about Canada geese,
the meanest of them all.
But it turns out there's actually about a half dozen kinds of keys.
So,
anyway,
-- anyway, anyway, I think
-- so,
basically zero day means you probably need to pay attention to this vulnerability.
Yeah.
People are talking about it and,
and that is interesting in and of itself
because most vulnerabilities do not get talked about.
Right. Right. And I think the, the way I will, I will wrap this one all up is to say that
language evolves and you can stand your ground and be opposed to
some strange new use to a word which whatever it's your decision,
it doesn't really matter.
But I think fundamentally this is one of those things
that if you're obsessed over the definition of zero day,
you are changing the conversation in an unhelpful way because no one cares what
the technical definition of zero day is they just want their web browser fixed.
And I think that's what, what one of our challenges is
that challenges is, that's weird. Anyway,
as security people, it is easy to turn the conversation into something unhelpful.
And this
is one of those
where these people end up arguing technical correctness instead of actually
trying to help fix the problem. And I see this
so much.
Yeah, like no one cares, you know what they're going to remember.
They're gonna remember. You weren't helpful. That's what's going to happen.
Well, worse. It's not that you weren't helpful. You were actively getting in the way
that too.
All right, I'll let you close this one out. Kurt. Final thoughts.
Language evolves.
We should too.
That's it. No, no, no.
And, and, and, and so does and,
and I also realize things like hairstyles and clothing styles evolve and
there's some stuff I don't, I'll be honest, I don't understand dabbing.
I have an irrational hatred of dabbing and I
know it's because I'm old and out of touch.
Right.
So,
but at least I'm aware of it and I just
choose now not to care instead of getting annoyed.
And
maybe, and that would be my advice to people is, you know,
-- just let it
-- go and that's the right way.
That's right. Let it go.
Now we're going to get a copyright strike. But
now
it in, that's too good.
All right.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up the show Note, Suif Pound
Os S podcast. Hashtag to hit us up on social media.
-- Kurt, you have a marvelous rest of your day. You too.
-- Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.