Hello and welcome to episode 42 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried
and my partner in crime. Josh Bresser
42. We all know what that means. Right. Kurt.
How
will they? That's right. Hitchhiker's guide to the Galaxy,
which
I,
I was thinking about this and I, I it needs no intro because let's face it.
If you're listening to the show, you don't hitchhiker's guide to the Galaxy,
it's just like, shame on you.
Right? Like go just shame. That's all I have to say.
I there's no excuse and, and yeah, there's nothing else to say about that. Just
so. Anyway, episode 42 we naturally thought it would be fun to do something.
Hitchhiker's guide to the galaxy related. So, what do we do, Kurt?
Well, I guess we could sort of dissect the film and its various security related.
No, you don't guess that's what we better do because that's what I prepared for.
Like,
well, well, well, anyway, so,
so for those of you who missed the end of the last episode when we,
we kind of told you what was going on is
when we realized episode 42 is coming.
Kurt said we should do something about Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy.
And I thought, yeah, we should read the book
and then look for security things.
And, uh, yeah, it's a really long book.
So we decided that the next best thing would be to watch the movie because that only
will eat an hour and a half of my life instead of probably a week of reading.
So, yeah. Yeah, that's good.
And, and I guess for those of you who don't know and not everyone knows this, I don't,
I don't remember if you knew this before I told you, but there's also a radio show
and the radio show in all seriousness is my favorite of the three formats.
I love the radio show.
Juan, just to be clear,
I have not heard the radio show and speaking of the three formats,
-- there's then also the TV
-- series from.
That's right. That terrible TV show.
It was
terrible. It was,
that's
true.
That's true. It crosses that line. It has like that integer overflow,
right?
It was like the doctor who special effects team from the BBC,
the way they did.
Zap's head is a par cage. I
was
like
paper mache.
It was so
cool. It was clearly fake.
That's the best part is like they, they obviously didn't even try to make it real,
you know.
Anyway.
So
yeah, we opted for the shortest sort of most up to date form.
At the same time and also I guess, be uh
-- be accessible to our viewers.
-- So that's actually something else you bring up.
And this is an important point is
when I watched this movie, I, I get annoyed by it for a variety of reasons,
but I know one of the intentions Douglas Adams always had
was that
his story isn't set in stone at one time.
And so like he helped write the screenplay, you know,
this isn't just some crazy Hollywood screenwriter that went nuts
and he wanted it updated to match the times he
didn't want it to take place back in what,
the seventies or sixties or whenever the original happened.
And so
as much as I get annoyed by some of the things,
I'm very sympathetic to the fact that they updated the story,
like Arthur has a cell phone,
you know, that, that's cool.
And which, which is even funny though because it's not like an iphone or anything.
I'm like,
he's got an old crappy phone
but I kind of like that. They at least, yeah, it's a smartphone, at least.
Although if you'd had a flip phone, it would have just looked ridiculous.
Was it a smartphone? I thought it was just a candy.
Well, it was, it was a candy bar phone but it wasn't like a flip phone or anything
and it kind of had like graphics on it and stuff and, you know.
Right. Anyway,
anyway,
so
let let, let's dive in, man, let's dive in.
I'm gonna start with, with that dolphin song.
I, I hate that song. I'm not even going to pretend like I, I hate that song.
That song revolts me when I hear it and I don't have a good reason for it.
It's just,
I hate that intro and I think that sets me up for failure for the rest of this movie.
Well, I mean, I have six year old so I get to hear, uh Baby Shark 10 times a day.
I do remember those days. And in fact, my daughter was,
what was she about? Six? I think when, when frozen came out and that song let it go.
I heard that at least 10 times a day for months.
And my one son does that song and it's hilarious because he's just,
he only does like the few sort of highlights
and he literally stands there with his hands in his pockets
and like, do a twirl on his heels. He'll do like the hair sweep gestures
and like, just occasionally belt out that
go, you know, like sort of off key.
I'm glad you, you did an escape. You let it go crazy. So, anyway, anyway,
I
don't think there's any legitimate security topics or nuance
theme. What's a huge one? Well, they did say they,
communication.
Yeah. How many, how many times has a firm been warned of
a, not even a potential hack but an actual real hack, like a hack going on
and just been like herb dip
or how many times has a security researcher
tried to report a vulnerability to a company?
Only to be shuffled to, like, tech support.
Who's like, oh, you don't have a contract with us. We can't listen to you.
Uh,
yeah, I, I think that's, but that,
that's an overarching theme to the whole story of the fact
that there are many warnings in many places for many reasons
and they are almost universally ignored and
it's, it's less so in the movie.
But in the, in the book, obviously,
like Marvin warns these guys countless times of
their peril and they never listen to him
-- and they usually yell at him and tell him to show
-- if they did though,
the story wouldn't have advanced,
which I think is also an important because sometimes you have to be
that,
that is true.
So anyway, anyway, let's ignore the movie and we can open up on Arthur Dent's house.
And
so whatever the, the plans are in the cellar.
-- Oh, no,
-- no, no. It's worse than that.
The 1st 30 seconds of the film, he smashes his head on that stairway overhang.
Apparently every single damn morning,
why didn't he put some padding on it or
a welding
sign?
Ok. So they, they miss this in the,
the movie, but in the book and the radio show,
they kind of covered the point that he is hungover.
But that's my point. Right. He should fix, he should deal with that issue.
It
does, like he's gonna smash his head every single day.
Normal humans will smash their head every day and they will never do anything about
it. And that's, and that parallels
our whole security industry.
-- And this is where I actually have
-- to do this on my parents cabin.
There's a stair case and the way it comes down
it's like an inch and a half shorter than me.
And did, did you pat it?
-- I'm actually, I didn't do that last year, but this year I am padding it.
-- You say
I'm gonna, I'm gonna check on you next year and see if you've padded it.
-- It's on my to do list.
-- I, I bet there's a 50% chance of you not doing it.
-- I'm doing it actually,
-- next
-- week
-- now you will to prove me wrong. But, uh,
anyway,
and
smashing my head
hurt.
But, but anyway, so the first thing I realized is
in when,
when Arthur Dent is talking to Mr Prosser,
who is the gentleman with the briefcase who works for the government.
And he tells him that the plans have been on display in the planning department
for, you know, the last six months or a year or whatever it was. And
it occurs to me that
this is how security rules work in most organizations we like, yeah,
we've got all these rules but, you know, like,
they're literally in the basement in a locked filing cabinet, you know, and just
use lavatory with the sign says Beware Leopard. Like that is basically how it works.
Vendors,
how many vendors have a security page where like,
you either know the keywords to find it in Google or you bookmarked it because
you know, some vendors you go blah,
blah slash security and it just works and there's a security page there
but a lot of vendors you do that and it's like nothing.
Yeah.
Right. I mean, that, that's totally true.
Is it, it's very much that when you are dealing with bureaucracy,
if you know the combination to kind of get through all the doors of bureaucracy,
you're fine.
But if you're a normal person you're screwed because there is no
way you're going to figure out what you need to do.
Which, which as soon as I saw that I thought of security
where if you know the security,
magic words and you know how to talk and to the industry and the people you're fine.
Right. No big deal. You can get anywhere you need to go.
But if you're a normal person who kind of just shows up,
you're doomed, you, you have no hope. And
I mean,
-- is that a bad thing necessarily because yes and
-- no, I, I think we, we do miss the, see,
I think it does lead to false,
uh, negatives in that stuff that really should be reported isn't, or,
and, I mean,
how many cases of researchers finding something and giving up have happened?
-- Well, we, we literally by definition don't know.
-- Yeah. I mean,
that, that, yes, exactly. But at the same time
you also can't have your security team inundated with pointless requests.
So it, I don't know, I think there's a balance you have to find and, and I think that we,
we tend to fall more on the kind of bureaucratic,
let's keep everyone outside except those who know the secret knock.
Part of what I've been doing with the DWF is, I mean, that, that's why, you know,
you have to use your email address so we can contact you and also
so long term it's like, oh, that's Tavis Ormandy or? Oh, that's Josh Bresser's.
Yeah, I will deal with him right away because I know it's not going to be very painful
and it's probably real versus, you know, like,
you know, looking at the CV requests. I mean, some of them are just
the terrible, like, just so poorly formatted or the information is so sketchy.
I'm like, I'm not going to spend two hours,
-- you know, trying to figure this out. Yeah,
-- I, I'm familiar with that.
I, I remember getting some of those but, but I must say, uh, if Tavis shows up,
you've got a lot of work to do.
Yeah.
Yeah. Especially if he shows up at like Friday at four o'clock.
-- You know, you're really up the creek,
-- right?
Your weekend is ruined.
But, uh, well, and even simple instructions, like I, you know,
you have to put in a working email address for me to, you know, be able to contact you
to be able to agree to the terms of use, for example. And like people fail to do that.
-- I mean,
-- it seems totally reasonable anyway.
Anyway, let's, let's keep on track because we've got a lot of movie to cover.
Uh So, so the next thing I want to talk about is the Vogons
are an A PT attack
where there is literally nothing you can do
and even trying to plan for
the
time in the A PT attack. It's the uh
well, spoiler alert here, it's, you know, it's the um
need to
say spoiler alert. We've ruined, we're gonna ruin this
movie.
What is
-- the
-- lady
Trisha?
No, not Trisha,
the lady that was the assistant or whatever to
the president and is like orchestrating this whole thing,
you know, the darker lady,
I don't think she's
does she not have, yeah, maybe
she does,
but she's the actual attacker. She's the one that engineered this whole thing.
The Volga
are just the tool,
right? They're just following the paperwork like literally,
you know, there's a destruction order that Zao
-- signed off on. Ok. But,
-- but regardless of who sent them,
the point is that the earth cannot stop the
Vogons no matter what they do.
And basically, unless you are in another, a PT organization,
you cannot stop these people no matter what you do
-- it. And I guess that's part of what, what makes me
-- think
you're going to have some employee that will take a $10,000 bribe
guaranteed.
That's my whole point. Right. That is the point is
anyone who has a PT is part of their threat model, like that's ridiculous.
It's like saying that, that, you know,
-- aliens attacking us is part of your threat model and you're going to defend
-- it as
part of your threat model.
But maybe you either assume the risk or for example,
you have compensating measures like, oh,
we're just going to log the heck out of everything.
So in hindsight, we can figure out what happened or, you know,
roll back transactions if needed,
you know, or chase the money down or whatever, right?
You know, banks are a good example of that, right? You can attack banks
and in many cases they have been attacked and compromised and then they just,
you know, basically, like claw back the money,
you know, undue like a great example, Ethereum, right?
The Ethereum uh Bitcoin style currency, right? They had that
situation where a guy found a flaw and like, you know,
uh
scored several, was it millions or tens of millions of dollars equivalency?
And they just essentially went, yep. No Mulligan do over,
right.
You know, we promised we'd never do this,
but we're doing it, you know,
uh revoking transactions or whatever. But um
yeah, and I think even more to the point though, it's,
it's the whole point of the bypasses is like, why do we do security?
Security has to be done. You have to build security into your product and your,
-- and your company?
-- That's true.
That's
-- true. You've got to build bypasses. This bypass is going to be built.
-- How
many places
like if you literally went up to them and said, like,
why are you doing security would have a sensible answer other than like, well,
because we have to or PC I compliance or, you know, some other form of because,
-- uh,
-- yeah, and, and, you know, actually that's one thing that I talk about a lot is
compliance is a reasonable driver of security.
There's nothing to be ashamed of to say. I'm only doing this for compliance.
Well, and like, as a vendor, for example, we have to do security otherwise, you know,
people won't buy our product.
I mean, that's the whole point,
right is when I'm writing up security features for products,
I will, I, I'm, I'm quite clear, I'm like, look, we're doing this for compliance.
There's no other reason. This isn't about goodwill.
This isn't about because it's the right thing to do what, blah, blah, no compliance.
We're doing it because compliance and then people relate to that though too.
Like, all right, we have to do this because if we don't,
you know, people can't buy a product
and that makes sense.
Whereas it's like, ok,
this is hard to do and I don't want to do
it and it's really just for the good of humanity.
So let's put that down farther on the list. Right.
I mean, that's what happens.
Well, that's what gets me about the whole A PT thing. Right.
Like by definition, you look at any piece of software,
they all have security flaws, they all have new security flaws, by definition.
Any piece of software you look at
is going to have security flaws,
you know,
and what gets me is like even like really dumb stuff,
like you should probably remove code that is no longer active.
Like that is one of the fundamentals of security coding, right?
Like get rid of dead code
and I mean, even open SSH got this wrong. Oh,
yeah. Yeah. Yeah, I
know. You know, and to the point of key disclosure, like that's
like they literally made a rookie mistake that resulted in a terrible,
terrible flaw.
I
know. I know. Anyway, now let's keep going. Uh, do,
do you have any notes before we move on from?
Well, just, yeah, that sort of that whole security notification process
and you know what it really reminds me of is like,
they, well, in this case,
they sort of intentionally made the notification
process difficult so nobody would kick up
a fuss but like how many vendors do that and it just costs everybody like
an enormous amount of pain. Like, that's one thing I love
with the open source world is, you know,
we're going to be moving to a model where every single flaw,
hopefully in the open source world gets a CV E and
that CV gets published in the official, you know, CV, database that mir like
the second or the minute or the hour it goes public either, like,
if it's public to begin with or, you know, once it's an embargoed.
So that, that notification thing
is trivial, you know,
and especially, like, because I just,
I know
what people spend and how much time and effort it takes now to, like,
monitor all of these open source providers
and stuff.
And it's,
you know, like when I found out, like, one of the firms I was working at charged, like,
you know, $250,000 a year for a basic threat feed.
I'm like, well, you know, wait a minute.
That's like two full time people,
two full time people can't monitor all of this.
Right.
You know. So it's just, it's,
you know, we're talking thousands of projects now, you know,
probably a core of several 100 that really matter everywhere.
But, I mean, yeah, these things are, you know, and there's a, like you look at the,
well, the Linux kernel is always my favorite because it's like, you know,
can you imagine reading every commit how big of a team you would be.
Uh one really smart person could do it
just sand.
I
know it's,
it's,
you know, that's, and anyways. Yeah.
So, I mean, it's, I just, I wish people would have more transparency and more,
you know,
better data structured, data collected data, you know,
that, that whole data curation,
it'll, it'll get there.
Well, we,
no one's really in charge of that and I think you
pushing with the DWF will have hopefully some fantastic outcomes.
All right. So the, the one other thing I wanna point out
in,
in, in the beginning
is
when Arthur is at the party talking to Trillion for the first time.
Uh they have a record player there and he bumps
on white like who freaking uses record players at parties?
Come on guys.
That's not believable.
Uh
I don't know. No
way,
no
way.
Were out.
Not in 2005 like,
well, true. Yeah, it was definitely going down the
toilet.
I don't believe it. No way. I
-- mean,
-- it's just one of those movie tropes, you know, I
-- know,
-- I
-- know
-- it's a guy at a party,
it bumps the record just as he says something.
I understand
that. I'm just saying.
Uh
Yeah. Anyway, anyway,
let's keep
one minor point.
So like do you have a plan for the end of the world
or even a plan to deal with your house being knocked down?
Or can you even find your towel?
Most people can't even find their towel.
I
won't have a plan.
-- I
-- look if my house gets knocked down, like, whatever,
the least of my worries is gonna be
anything
but the horrific event that caused that to happen,
which will probably be something outside of the realm of sanity.
Funny story.
Housing demolition companies have been known to get the address wrong.
I
know.
And you google that and it's like, are you kidding me? Like,
but I guess, you know, you're a housing and, and these guys literally are like, yeah,
we started knocking down the house and then we noticed it was full of stuff, but hey,
you know, whatever, we had the paperwork.
I know, but
I, ok, you actually bring up a great point is do I have a plan for my house?
And I don't know,
why would I me spending time on that is ridiculous because the odds of it actually,
I mean,
I might as well plan for winning the lottery
because I suspect there are two very similar events
and
granted,
I know there are people who plan on what they're going to do when they win the lottery,
but practically speaking, like they're wasting their time too,
although their time doesn't have a lot of value, I imagine.
So they're probably not wasting very much
and security falls into this trap is we have to plan
things that matter in ways that matter.
Because if you're doing pie in the sky security planning,
you're wasting your time.
And when you're at a, at a, you know, at a company you're wasting money.
If you're wasting time, let's face it.
Well, yeah, it comes back to that whole, you know,
why are you doing security and most places are not going to present, you know,
a report with, you know, what we're putting in what we're getting out.
-- Most don't even
-- know
is
most don't even know. Let's face it. Most of them have no idea.
I mean, that's the reality of it.
Uh Anyway, anyway, let's keep going. All right, they get on the heart of gold.
And do you know what the first thing I realized
when I started watching that scene this time?
And I guess I, I don't remember this from the last time I watched it is
they say the letter Z
instead of Z
because in all the other media I've consumed
around Hitchhiker's guide to the galaxy is,
it's
right.
ZZ nine plural Z
alpha,
which is the,
the, I guess coordinates of the earth
in the Hitchhiker Universe.
But because this was a Hollywood movie, they say ZZ nine plural Z alpha.
And I remember I'm watching it, I'm thinking this is crazy.
They don't say Z, they say Z
so, yeah, that's funny. I'm not totally not security related but
yeah, yeah,
that was stuck with me.
Oh, actually I did have one thing going back to the beginning, but
here's the thing, it's not so much. Do you have a plan if all the dolphins vanish?
But would you even notice?
I would not notice because I don't live anywhere near the water.
Well, and by that, I mean, like, you know, how many times have there been, like,
situations where people are, like, oh, yeah,
the I DS or the ID P went silent like a week ago
happens all the time.
Yeah.
-- Yes.
-- You know, I, I feel like that should maybe be something people like, check into.
I, well, no, people, people shouldn't do this.
You should have a system in place capable of finding these problems.
Like, if the ID doesn't check in for an hour, you know,
something's wrong and you should be triggering emails
and text messages telling someone something is broken.
Right?
Yeah. People can't do that.
It has to be machines.
So, anyway, anyway,
uh,
the other thing I loved about the heart of gold is the knife that makes toast.
Right. How did they get that past the TS a man? Like for real?
Well, the concern I have though is one side of your toast would be nice and well,
toasty hot and the other side would be cold.
You,
you'd have to cut a slice and then discard the cold piece and then cut a
new slice and then you'd have two very warm sides of one piece of toast.
So it needs to be like, sort of like the Doth Mall, the Darth Maul Saber,
like where it needs to be like two knives.
So when you cut it, you get both sides nice and warm and toasted. But on the flip side,
here's the cool thing for making peanut butter sandwiches.
You would have the side that's cold that you could put peanut butter on and
the side that's hot that like you could hold and put in your mouth.
So you get that like still nicely toasted bread warmth thing going on or
about that nasty melted peanut butter.
Ok.
Have you not ever put peanut butter on a hot piece of toast? Right?
It gets instantly super gross and runny and like dribbles at the side.
I have a handful of, let's say personality quirks
and
one of my personality quirks is that I refuse to eat peanut butter on toast.
And I have never had peanut butter on toast. And the idea of eating it revolts me.
So I will never eat Peter
peanut butter on bread.
I love it. I love it on bread. I eat it on cracker skirt. I eat it with pretzels.
But for some reason
my brain will not let me eat peanut butter. I
want,
I want
now II I, this is terrible twist
but now
I'm imagining some sort of like saw movie plot that
involves you eating toast with peanut butter on it.
Yes. That doesn't sound weird at all
anyway. No, I, I don't know. I've never put peanut butter on warm toast
and, and I
get
it,
I
can imagine
a
war peanut butter it melts. That, that's fair. Anyway. Anyway,
regardless
you're talking about peanut butter.
I'm, I'm complaining about the TS A, letting me take my toaster knife onto now.
Which would be
-- the question.
-- It's a private
aircraft.
Spacecraft. Yeah, I guess it is. That's true. Well, was it who owned it?
Well, the government, but
it wasn't like a public transport thing. It was
-- ok.
-- Yeah. Well,
yeah, I guess it's true because you figure if you got, say a naval vessel,
I'm sure they aren't running all the, the sailors through metal detectors on their
way
stories where, um,
for example,
uh, where military units are being transported with all their gear.
And so these guys are carrying, you know, granted,
they don't have the ammunition with them but they're carrying things like,
you know, bayonets and knives.
But, and they were literally
confiscating like fingernail clippers.
This is way back in the day, like right after 911 when things were kind of insane,
uh, that,
but that's, that's all bogus,
that's all bogus
where
you have your insane list of rules and you're going to follow them no matter what.
And it doesn't have to make sense. You're just gonna follow the rules and,
I mean, unfortunately when you end up in security situations,
that's what happens because
it's dangerous and if you screw up, you're like, I, I followed the rules now, I felt.
Right.
Well,
but I also wonder because sometimes you can't
tell people why the rule exists like that
whole laptop thing in the Middle East on
the airlines that we discussed last episode.
Right. Like,
they can't tell us kind of,
or apparently they can't tell us what the real reason of it,
you know, for a variety of security reasons, you know,
maybe they don't want to disclose the source or whatever.
Ok. Ok. Yes. But let's face it.
If you have soldiers bringing real weapons onto
airplanes and you take away their fingernail clippers,
you're a fool.
Right? I mean, for real,
they don't need a nail clippers. They have a band,
I mean. Right.
But anyway, anyway, whatever
it, it, it is what it is.
Uh, the other thing I loved from kind of that, that whole scene
is the heart of gold flees the Vogons chasing them.
And one of the Vogons says, bring me the request to pursue fugitive form
like that. That is so great. I love the obscene bureaucracy.
They give the Vogons and that's the one thing actually in the movie,
I think they did really well,
is the
Vogons are way more bureaucratic in the movie than
they are in the book or the radio show?
Well, and see that leads
to, um,
sort of one of the questions or points I have where,
you know, they actually have a process in place for that.
You're like, no,
OK. No, no. But it's a, it's a made up story
and obviously they just make the Vogons overly bureaucratic in every possible way.
I mean, it's like later on when they're trying to free Trillion
and they bring
the,
the regular prisoner release form and they
needed the presidential prison release form,
which is blue.
Yeah, which they actually have a copy of I,
-- I made a specific note of that but that small office,
-- of course they do because,
because it's a made up show man,
they can have anything they want
as much as you can hate on the Vogons.
They did think through like pretty much every eventuality and have a form for it
except the the where Arthur goes to get the document, there's like 12 slots, right?
They clearly whatever, it's a movie, right? It's fun. It's fun and funny.
And, and anyway, the so, so also uh the next thing I'm gonna bring up is, is 42
where
I, I realize watching this when they cut to the scene where they show deep thought,
give the answer of 42 is
the answer of 42 is technically correct
because they asked a question and deep thought
gave them the answer to their question.
They didn't ask a question so much.
They did ask a question, they asked the wrong question
-- and well, they asked an overly broad
-- question, but but here's my point is
people come to security folks like us,
they ask us questions
and,
and I,
now I'll say these days I try really hard to ask follow up questions and be helpful.
But I remember there was a day when I
would give them the answer that was technically correct.
It wasn't useful in any way.
And they were usually too embarrassed to ask a follow up question or
ask for proper help and they'd leave and I knew they'd leave,
which is why I did that.
And I think that's very common in, I mean, in the computer industry in general,
but especially in security where we're, we're technically correct all the time.
-- It's not helpful
-- any technical field.
Is that the correct technical answer also has a lot of nuance. Typically,
uh,
you
can
have a really, if you don't have that deep knowledge,
you don't get that nuance.
That is true. I won't just
with that.
So, you know, I do the same thing too now where somebody asks me a question.
I'm like, wait, what, what, like, what's really going on?
Like, what are you really trying to ask? What's the problem?
Yeah.
Like I hear the question you formulated,
but I've heard that question before and I know how this conversation ends.
So let's try something different.
Now, actually, you know,
it's really funny is I'm having a lot of conversations like
that now where I'll talk to certain customers and whatnot.
And let's say
I need Kos
authentication.
And the first thing I say is Kos
is rarely the right answer to any question. What are you actually trying to do?
And it turns out they need active directory
support and they found it like it works with
Kos. I'm like, ok, there's better ways to do this. Like
Kos is terrible. We don't want to use that if we can avoid it.
So
anyway,
that, and that's one of the things I love.
Uh, so going back a bit, you know,
is the whole hitchhiker's guide to the Galaxy book because we
sort of skipped them going on to the Vogon ship.
-- I think we should cover that a bit.
-- Is there anything?
-- But the thing is in the movie, they basically show up,
-- well,
the fact that they pick up Hitchhikers and don't
know they have people who boarded the ship.
-- They don't
-- though.
The Den Tracy did it in, in the book and the radio show, but they don't like,
they cover nothing of value in the movie.
They, they get on the ship,
they get captured, the terrible poetry is read to them.
And
in fact, even on the, once you see the Vogon,
he's sitting on the deer that the Vogon said,
I forget the name of it and he's crushing the crabs.
And there is zero explanation of that in the movie.
But if you obviously read the book,
you understand that what happened on vogues sphere is the vogons of all.
First.
And the planet felt bad and made all these beautiful
other creatures that the Vogons just continue to murder and,
and kill
because that's what they do.
-- And, but
-- anyways, the, the thing I love about the Checkers guide to the galaxy
is, do you remember why
-- it sold so well?
-- Because it is slightly less cheaper than the,
uh, uh, the encyclopedia Galactica.
And it has the words don't panic written in large friendly letters on the cover.
Exactly. So it's not us technically correct,
-- but it's actually somewhat useful.
-- It's not useful.
It just is cheaper and has don't panic written on the cover,
which in fact Arthur says at one point,
that's the first useful thing anyone said all day.
Exactly.
How often have we been in security situations where, like,
literally the first thing is like, don't panic.
You know what's really funny about?
That is a million years ago, one of the first jobs they ever had.
I worked with this guy who was, I mean, he was an old dude and this was in the,
the mid to early nineties
and this guy was already fairly old. So, like, he'd, he'd been around
and I'll never forget that like,
a server would crash or the network would go down or something crazy would go on
and I'd like, run into his office and be like,
hey Pete, it's like,
you know, he'd be like, hey, dude, sit in that chair right there.
You just need to chill out for a minute. I'm like, but, but
nothing works and he's like, it's OK.
We can sit here for two minutes and nothing's gonna break and I'm like,
it's already broke and he's like, then it's fine.
Right?
And I remember at the time I'm like, this old guy is crazy,
but now I'm like,
he got it. Like, you can't, if you panic, you fail.
Like, period, you end up like,
-- deleting the whole file server because you went crazy and type
-- like that
classic, uh, what was it? Git lab
where they, like, just, they had a small problem and they made it much, much worse.
-- They
-- deleted
-- all
of a snapshot.
-- That was a few hours old. Otherwise they would have lost like a day or two.
-- Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah, that's crazy. It, it happens. Oh, man, I mean, I get it right.
I get why it happens
anyway.
All right.
What else you got?
-- Any
-- other? Well, 11 thing that was never really covered in the book or anywhere was
so, apparently the Vogons
are immune to Vogan
poetry.
They write the Vogan poetry.
Well, I could get the author not being affected by it but other Vogons,
other Vogons
are unsympathetic bureaucratic creatures.
Why would they be affected by Vogan poetry? They probably enjoy it.
-- So,
-- I guess, uh, what that kind of leads to is, I mean,
do we have any security measures that we can use to essentially punish back
guys or make their lives more miserable that we are immune to.
Because every time I've seen the security measure
they almost always involve some trade off of usability.
I mean, there's that classic thing of, you know,
like you have to have trade offs for security. I mean, that's the old trope.
Right. No, no, no,
there are no tradeoffs. Security loses and a story.
Well, exactly. Right. And that's the thing, you know. So,
you know, that old trope of, well, you can't have security without, you know,
somehow making it just horrible for people to use this, you know,
which doesn't work.
Um, I'm just, yeah, I kind of was thinking about that, you know, what can we do
to make security better?
That doesn't, you know, hurt anybody other than the bad guys
today. I don't think we can answer that.
Well,
a great example would be like gray listing for email servers right where it's just,
I'm gonna delay you sending the email by a few minutes
because a legit email server will then retry.
-- But like a spammer won't the spammers
-- just,
but that stopped the spammers for a while.
But now the spammers just use like legitimate mail servers to send the mail.
I
mean, they got around
-- it,
-- you know, that cut down on the drive by.
It did. Oh, it did.
And it was hugely effective at one point and I remember when the gray listing
stopped working is when I stopped running my
own mail server because I thought there's,
I, I give up like you win.
Spammers, you win
anyway. Anyway.
All right.
So
if, if we continue on with the story, we end up on uh
wit
Woodle
Six,
which is the, I guess planet of Huma
Kula, which is the leader of, I forget the name of his religion,
but they worshiped the Great Arkels.
They're waiting for the time of the Great
handkerchief. Is it
-- in the
-- world
-- of the Great Handkerchief? Because the universe was created by a sneeze.
-- Right.
Right. And they actually touch on this a little bit
at the end, on the restaurant at the end of the universe.
But they obviously don't, that, that's not part of the movie.
But, but anyway, this part I found really bizarre because
it, this, this story arc isn't in the book or the radio show
and they, like, show up with this planet and
like,
kind of goes crazy and they go down to the planet and
it's a bit ridiculous and it doesn't really fit in any way.
And I don't feel like it even adds to the story. Um,
-- I don't know, it's debatable.
-- The, the only, I mean, iii I don't, I don't like it.
This is one of the, the things I really hate about this movie is this particular,
I suspect they were trying to maybe do some character development.
I don't know.
The one thing I wrote, the one note I wrote from this whole event,
other than it being ridiculous is that the Bogans are worse,
worse shots than storm troopers
because they're shooting.
But then actually later on in the movie, uh, towards the end, let me,
let me find the note Marvin at one point says
Bogans
are the No, no. He says,
I
don't know what you guys are worried about.
Bogans are the worst marksmen marksmen in the galaxy and then he
gets shot in the back of the head by the bo guns.
-- Well, that's how Murphy's
-- law
-- works.
-- I
know
it's Marvin. Marvin, the robot. Uh It's awesome. Uh
-- Anyway, anyway,
-- oh, actually,
so one thing I was wondering is um the background checks they did on Zaho,
right?
Because they can't become a president of the galaxy without background checks
and apparently brain scans because he had to cut out parts of his brain.
-- Remember
-- that's what they say in the,
the, the movie and in the book,
he wipes his memory or something like that and he
buried certain thoughts very deep and that's why he,
and,
and that actually ties into the total perspective vortex plot
arc as well later on a bunch of other things.
-- Yeah, that was missing from the film.
-- Well, it, it comes way later though.
Well, I guess maybe that was sort of the, the gun was replacing that.
Yeah,
that's true. The gun is, I think meant to be the total perspective vortex.
But you got to remember too, the hitchhiker got to the Galaxy. The book
is really like five or six stories,
five books of
alone.
So, yeah.
Right. Right.
And,
and so in the radio show actually does it
the last season of the radio show number five,
I think it is, they kind of go off the rails a little bit.
But other than that, they stick to the book pretty well and they,
they rearrange a couple of things, but for the most part, they get it all.
But,
but anyway, anyway, uh the Vogons capture trillion, which
yeah, whatever, not, not, not a whole lot of crazy security going on there.
But I will say that.
So then they go to Vogue sphere
and this is where I think things get kind of,
I I feel like the story starts to pick up and,
and from the security theme perspective, there's all kinds of crazy stuff.
And
one of the things I love is the spatula things that hit you when you think
that
that's
-- feeding off the mind energy if memory serves,
-- right?
And the beauty of that though in this like
I
can so relate to this kind of from the standpoint of security is
when you're dealing with a ton of bureaucracy and crazy rules like
thinking is obviously not a part of that, right?
You you're expected you follow the rules
because you're supposed to follow the rules
and don't think about
it.
I
can't help but think some of our security stuff is
totally like that where we have these rules about,
oh, change your password every 30 days.
Why? Well, because change your password every 30 days. Granted.
Now I know n is, is change of guidance on that. You kind of get the idea.
-- It's
-- the pro part of it is, you know,
these rules may have been valid 30 years ago when they were
formulated for a specific subset of situations for which they were validated.
But then the problem is like PC I compliance, everybody's like, oh,
we're going to require PC I compliance even though you, like,
don't process credit cards or whatever.
Well, a great example, the European cookie rules, right?
You have to notify people, you're using cookies on your website.
Well, of course, you're using cookies. It's a website, that's how that works.
So every single bloody website has that stupid warning now that takes
up like a big chunk of the screen and you got to,
like, get rid of it.
And then the best part is if you actually do
clear cookies and stuff every once in a while,
then you get it again and again and again and
again,
-- you know, and it's just so annoying. Right.
-- Right.
And, and this is very, I feel like a lot of security rules are like this or,
or my favorite now.
Is, uh,
everyone needs to run antivirus and this
is basically every compliance thing in the world
says you need antivirus on your servers
and let's face it.
I think Tavis has shown us like antivirus is potentially
worse than what it's trying to protect us from.
I
mean, for sure,
the
lower end level, which is basically all of it. I mean,
the biggest thing II I always come back to is, you know, when you ask people like, why,
why are you doing this?
Why should we do this?
And you know? Yeah, I mean,
because,
yeah, exactly
because I mean,
I is there actually can you actually even get antivirus for mobile devices?
I think there is. Yeah.
-- Yeah,
-- you can get these
terrible apps and they like kill
your performance and they don't really work because they don't, well,
you can get some things that will run his route if you let them don't
and all the other stuff just, it's, it's, it's garbage. I mean, I'm not gonna lie.
It's kind of garbage and it's the sort of thing people who use it are ticking boxes,
let's face it.
They're not doing it because they need it.
And,
but I feel like there's, there's a fair bit of security like that, you know, this is,
but this is always going to be a challenge is
you will always have security,
compliance and security rules that were put in place probably for a good reason.
A long time ago.
But getting any of this to change
is very difficult. Like here's a great example is
I, I watched a TED talk one time from this guy who basically
he, he, you know,
he was complaining about car seats because people with small Children,
like the vast majority of them install their car seats incorrectly
and it's actually more dangerous at that point because the seat has
the risk of like your child flinging out of it in an,
in an accident.
So anyway,
what he did is he took like the crash test dummy of a two year old,
put it in various car seats and crashed, right? Got the data off the dummy.
Then he put the kid in a seatbelt, like literally just a seatbelt in the seat,
crashed it
and he brings all his findings to
and it was some like safety organization that specializes
in this and he shows it to him.
They're like, yeah, all this all looks great, you know,
whatever these would all pass.
He's like that last one there. That's just a seatbelt
and they said, ok, that's fine.
And, and then he's like, what do you think of that?
They're like, look man, we know putting a two year old in a seatbelt is just fine.
But he said,
where are you gonna find any lawmaker that's gonna
be willing to talk about changing these rules?
Because you know, the first kid who dies in a car accident
in a seatbelt,
people are gonna lose it.
Well, it's like the whole self driving cars,
we're holding them to a much higher standard than we hold human drivers.
They're still gonna win because they
much higher
-- standard.
-- We have these like self driving car crashes where it's like
the self driving car is just mos along and, like, gets t boned,
like, you know, somebody blows around
or,
you know, and, and people are like up in arms about it. And I like,
you know,
at least, like in theory,
at least the self-driving car has a chance of avoiding this, you know,
where does it can drive?
I've seen plenty of instances where the self-driving
car actually avoided a bunch of problems.
One of my favorite is there's a video I saw where there was a bicycler coming.
It was like a, an, an intersection, a kind of a four way stop sort of deal
and there was a truck next to the self-driving car,
but as the self driving car was pulling up to the stop,
it saw a biker way off on the left.
And so it knew there was a biker basically coming, pulls up and it waited longer than
it should have at this stop
as the biker drives past it because you couldn't see the biker because the truck
was next to it and it's like a human would have hit that dude,
right?
Like, let's face it.
But the car knew it was there and like, that's awesome. Right.
And if,
if I had to guess there are probably 10 to 1 instances
of self driving cars doing something better than a human versus them,
maybe making some sort of minor mistake.
And much more importantly, you know,
once they identify the cause of the accident,
they can hopefully create some sort of software fix or something and then, you know,
update the fleet,
you know, because it reminds me of like all these airline accidents,
I'm reading about where
something terrible happens. So they come up with a corrective action and apply it,
you know, and when they don't, it's, you know,
because there's this one classic air crash,
I forget the model plane but like the door would fall off from the cargo hatch,
you know, and of course the thing would depressurize and everybody dies if the,
you know, pilots really not on the ball.
Um,
and then it happens again three years later and it's the same,
it's like the same investigator.
He's like, he basically, his response is like, God damn it like,
yeah. Uh I, I know what happened here.
I, you know, and like they were supposed to fix this and, you know,
that time around the FAA actually made it like, mandatory to fix
as supposed to like, please fix this. We think you should,
you know.
Um
And I mean, that's the biggest thing, right? Because like, how many times,
uh well, the fact that we have red light cameras in like a lot of cities.
You know what I mean? Like
that, that alone should tell you that people suck at driving.
The fact that they can't obey a red light typically at a busy intersection.
It's not like some,
you know, I could see it like some rural intersection where there's like,
no traffic,
there'd be no economic value to putting it there because let's face it.
The purpose of red light cameras is to make money.
It's not to make anyone safer of any sort. Right.
Uh, I, I would disagree a bit because, I mean, they do here.
Well, maybe it's different in the US than it is in Canada with
the, with the, the fine structures and how that money is allocated.
Um,
but the point is like here, I mean, there's red light cameras and speed cameras,
they, and they publish where the locations are, like,
they have to legally publish the locations even for the ones where it's like,
um,
you know, where it's the mobile speed enforcement, like the photo radar trucks
and like, we know all the locations,
like it's behind the stonehouse on the white mud and like on the pull
off, you know, pull off on the,
you know, on the whatever, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
And yet people still, you know, get nailed by these things constantly.
Uh,
ok, maybe
so.
But the
point is basically humans can't obey red lights and basic.
Right.
Yes. Exactly. Exactly. Right.
And
the red light thing, especially that, that matters. So,
let's stay on this topic of self driving cars and when the
heart of gold gets to me,
they have IOT controlled missiles launched at the ship.
Now,
this is a terrible idea.
If, if you
have missiles, please don't make them auto.
You, you
kind of have to, to some degree because it's
no, no, no, no reaction times are incredibly small in some situations.
So you have to have automated systems that can just, you know,
take care of the situation because
I mean, what happens when you only have 10 or 20 seconds, like, you know, I mean,
the classic example of this is the US
S Finns shooting down a civilian airliner
because they basically just, they didn't have the room to maneuver.
So they're like, well, crap, we have no other option. Shoot it down.
Right. They only had like tens of seconds to deal with the situation,
which was a major part of the problem. Right. They were under that time pressure.
And do you think an autonomous system would have done something different?
Uh, well,
I, I, well, it depends on how it's programmed.
I mean, part of it would be the economist system in theory.
Well, no part of the reason they shot it down, they got the time zones mixed up,
-- didn't
-- we just talk about how bad software is?
-- Oh, ok. Ok.
-- They had actual
data that there was that flight coming out of that airport at that time,
but because of the way the time zones were all screwed
up because there were like three different time zones involved,
like where it was taking off from where it was going
to and then like the time zone of the US S fins
or something,
they, like,
basically messed that up and didn't recognize it as a scheduled civilian airliner.
Ok. Ok.
Uh
You know,
and also the transponder code, what happened is the,
the military was flying jets out of the same thing.
And so the guy initially picked up a transponder code from a military flight
and that got attached apparently or something to the, like
the civilian, you know, radar track.
So again, I mean,
potentially an autonomous system would have
identified it correctly and been like,
nope,
-- that's a civilian airliner taking off on time.
-- Maybe I,
you, ok. I don't know, I don't know, I still feel like autonomous missiles are bad.
Well, the reality is, you know,
weapon systems of the future are going to be more and more autonomous.
Um, and, and again, part of it is that reaction time, you know,
how are you as a human being going to deal with a drone
coming in at you with a couple 100 ft
away from you.
You, you've ruined my ot joke.
So that's fine. That's fine.
And
I mean, I, I'm not generally in favor of, like, automated responses because then,
you know, we almost had World War three.
What was it in like 1983 when the Russian, you know, launch detection system
-- was like,
-- right. Right. It picked
-- up something else and
-- thought it
was, I think it was
a,
it was something ridiculous and,
and luckily that, you know, Soviet General guy was like, I don't think this is real.
-- Let's just wait a few seconds and minutes and see what happens. I love
-- it.
So, so the next thing
while they're being attacked by missiles is
they're, they're freaking out and trying to escape.
And Arthur says, why doesn't someone just push that button?
And everyone's like, oh, we can't do that
and no one knows why though. And he says, well, why not?
And I feel like
this comes back to our kind of compliance based security
advice or rather just old security advice maybe is,
you know, people will say things like,
well, you need to change your password every 30 days or 60 days.
And you could say, well, well, why?
And they don't know, right. They, they don't know. And
I guess the
attacker is gonna sniff your password and then, like,
wait for 90 days to use it.
Well, they're gonna use it, like, right away,
the bigger problem is just that people change your password a lot.
They either pick a really, really bad password or they,
or they make other foolish choices around it.
Versus anyway, the idea is we have lots of security advice where you're like, oh,
you can't do that and then they'll be like, well, well, why not?
And we're like, uh, I don't know.
And, I mean, this,
this comes back to a lot of the discussions
we have where we try to talk about security from
a very practical standpoint and there's a lot of security
people that will disagree with the things we say,
but they probably can't back up their ideas with any sort of rhyme or reason. Right.
Yeah. No, it's, I mean, well, even I, you know, I've stopped running antivirus.
Um, and I do occasionally reinstall it, scan my entire system and I'm like, well,
either I've got like, uh, you know, uh,
like a root kit installed that is avoiding it or I don't have any viruses
and based on the fact that I sold money in my bank account,
you know,
it would appear that, yeah, you don't, well, and, you know, more to the point, like,
especially with on Linux,
like,
I know there are some Linux viruses but they're so rare.
Like they're literally, you know,
you know, what's really funny about that
is
I,
I read a story about Os X last week showing that
the number of Os X malware detections went up by,
by like 1000% or something.
Uh, last year.
And
the, the researcher who found this basically said look,
I know this looks really bad but we're still only at like tens of thousands.
And you got to remember like the Windows World is in the tens of millions.
-- Like this is,
-- you cannot run Java, you cannot run,
you cannot run.
These are
such
drastic
Microsoft office again, Microsoft Office.
I
know,
-- you know, if you're not running in protected mode, your bones,
-- well,
shouldn't we all just be using like office 365 now?
And then it's Microsoft's problem
-- uh that still installs like the clients on your
-- machine
really
haven't used
it.
I had to edit some slides for RS A and keynote,
their keynote templates were just like screwed up.
So I ended up having to use a powerpoint
and yeah, it installs.
But what's interesting is for example, like when you do a file, convert it,
like ships it off to Microsoft to convert the file and then ships
it back to you like it doesn't do it on the local system.
And I'm like,
all right then.
So there's a local client and it does some stuff in the
-- why not just do like
-- Google?
And when I say a local client, like, you know,
it's still like a couple 100 megabytes of installed stuff,
right? But there's a lot of stuff that goes on in the cloud that seems
bonkers.
Well, it makes sense because you wanna be able to have, I mean, here's the problem,
right?
People will, is still need or want but maybe need even
that full offline working experience.
Yeah, but like you can still do that. I mean Google Docs has offline mode,
right? But we're talking about stuff like Excel and powerpoint where you have like
97 billion features of which like,
you know, a 0.03% of people use that feature.
But it's like, you know, all the different people use
may
maybe that's fair.
I,
I admit that's one of the things I love about the Google
Docs experience is it doesn't have very many features because I,
-- I like, I'm really bad at word and I, I use
-- like three things
and I look at the rest of the interface and I'm like, I don't even know what that does.
You know, like I know how to use like drop down filters and like,
you know, you know,
what's actually really funny about that is my wife is really good at spreadsheets.
She,
she got all this training in college and she took all
these classes and stuff and it was like a huge deal
and
every now and then I'll ask her for help.
But like, usually I just write a pearl script, it does whatever I need it to do it,
it like reads in a CS V file,
it does what I need done and then it outputs
a CS V file and then I just reimport that file
and it's really funny because every now and then she'd be like, how do you know how,
how, how do you have to set up to calculate that?
I'm like, I wrote a Python script
and I do the
same with, like
Ain said, and cutting
her. Like,
how did you make Excel do this?
And I'm like, I have no idea how that would work in Excel.
I know the feeling. I know exactly what you mean. Uh You gotta love it.
It, it, it's ridiculous. But anyway, anyway, all right. Uh,
so
the Mariia
scene is also bizarre because it kind of magically shifts from Mariia
to Earth
because their
real
s
Bart
Fasts threats thing was like,
hi.
No. Ok. You need to listen to the radio show and listen to Sy
Bart
Fasts, uh, conversation with Arthur and it's fantastic.
They, they really screwed up the conversation
in, in the movie, but on the radio show it's to die for. It's one of my favorite scenes.
Actually, the way he kind of threatens Arthur with the late, the late Arthur D.
It's, it's very good and the voice is very funny
and just the whole thing is great.
So,
so find the radio show and listen to it and you won't be disappointed in that scene.
So anyway, I can ignore that just because I, I have the,
the happy memory of the radio show.
But then, so, so they're on mega
thea
and nothing overly exciting happens and then they go to the earth
because they're, they're making a new earth, which is insane,
whatever.
Uh And then they're
gonna
finish the,
but
that, that's actually like a huge point actually is
in the original story,
they were going to rebuild the earth,
but it would have to run again for like 10 million years.
And that's when,
that's when they thought, wait, we'll just, uh,
Arthur Dent has the answer in his brain.
We'll just give him a bunch of money if he gives it to us is kind of where that ended and,
and, well,
whatever
and
they, they kind of go back to earth
and Arthur brutally murders the mice, which
I don't feel too bad about it.
-- But it's like,
-- well, they're just a manifestation of that. What is it like 13 to 30
-- entity or whatever?
-- So, are they dead though?
You think they get mad and like kill you or something? Right?
-- Like, I mean, seriously,
-- maybe they're more forgiving than us.
They were going to cut out Arthur's brain.
Yeah. But that was just a purely practical thing.
And remember they remember from the book, it was like,
we're just going to replace you with like a whatever, a little script that says like,
what?
No, I don't, let's have tea,
you know, and then, and that's basically like 90% of what he says. So, yeah. OK.
I mean,
really, how many people could we replace with like 10 lines of dialogue?
We're not judging by the fact that we have interactive voice response
on
phones. Now,
I don't think we should discuss this because I think there's many
layers of nuance and misappropriation that could come into play here.
So we're just going to move on.
Uh So anyway, we, we eventually get to the scene where the vo guns are shooting.
Everyone. Marvin says
Gans are the worst marksmen in the galaxy, which I love because
if you had a group of terrible marksmen, why would you make them your, I guess,
physical security,
right.
-- It's, uh, you know, the lowest bidder on the contract
-- maybe. I don't know. It, it,
you, you'd think if you were over bureaucratic, like the bogus
you
think about, I mean, haven't you read about like those, you know, these stories,
like I know locally there's been, you know,
there's a variety of officer involved shootings and like there's been cases where,
you know, they trade gunfire with somebody and there's like, you know,
50 or 100 shots fired and they, like
the guy is not critically injured.
Well, ok, so
that's a different problem.
-- Well,
-- no, no shooting at anything is surprisingly difficult to do.
Especially in a very high pressure.
Well, actually you and I were just talking about this before the show is I shot,
I, I was,
we, we were talking about firearms and I, I shot competitively when I was younger.
Like I've shot like millions of rounds probably because I was like, I,
I was in AAA team that we would shoot 22 rifles at targets.
And like, I, I've got a box full of trophies. Actually, I was really good at it.
But anyway, uh,
the deal is though,
one of the things you have to learn to do is how to basically calm yourself.
So your heart's beating very slowly because obviously, if your heart beats,
you can't shoot
and you got to think when you're in a situation like that where things are crazy,
your heart's going nuts,
you can't shoot straight and honestly hitting a
moving target is insanely difficult to do.
Even if you're like fully prepared and rested.
Now add in chaos, I get it right. I
-- understand
-- shooting
back at you.
Well,
that's true. I, I've never been in that situation. Right. I've only ever shot a cave.
So,
so anyway, iii I can, I can forgive that. Right. But,
uh, anyway, anyway, Bogans are terrible.
Uh, I love the part where Marvin shoots all the vo
guns with the prospective gun
and they are like start
point
of on the ground,
-- the
-- point,
the point of
view,
not
that
I was
going to say we need the point of view gun,
not so much because we need to make people see security,
-- but
-- we need to understand them.
-- Yeah.
-- Yeah, exactly.
Like,
-- seriously
-- we need like normal people to shoot
the whole security industry with the point of
view gun so we can grasp their frustrations with us and what the actual problems are.
Uh,
yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Anyway, I love that, that part I actually did enjoy
and,
and I must say that
Ellen Rickman doing Marvin's voice is awesome.
I love Ellen Rickman and I love Marvin. And
again,
not that I, I feel that, that I keep bringing this up, but the
Marvin in the radio show is
unbelievably awesome. He makes the radio show
and in the movie, he was kind of minor, honestly.
Well, he plays a reasonably big role.
I mean, without him, they, they wouldn't have gotten anywhere.
I mean, he's a much better driver.
You remember in the escape pod
and, you know, with his hand and all that. But, um,
the other thing, uh, going back to that scene where, you know,
Marvin shoots all of the, uh, the
Vogons just before it, remember there was a group of
Vogons coming around the back
and, um, yes,
uh, Ford Prefect charges them with his towels doing his little war cry.
And I mean,
and I think that's a really important point is like
you have to be able to actually identify real threats,
you know?
Not. Oh my God. Oh, what was it? Oh, yeah, he's got a towel run away.
Now, realistically speaking, if you actually read the books,
the towels can have some pretty significant powers, you know, like his,
for example, has it soaked in my,
for nutrients and it's got some wires threaded into it for strength and some other,
you know, things and
you can apparently buy specialty towels with, you know, various other things.
So, you know, I think
that
the towel could be a realistic threat in that universe.
But, um, that's one thing I look at, you know, in our infosec is like people, you know,
a perfect example.
Oh, here's a great example
tying back to passwords. Uh, do you remember a few weeks ago or two weeks ago?
Somebody threatened to, like, wipe a Bajillion Apple
account if they weren't paid a ransom.
And did you hear what the real deal on that is?
I did not.
So they have a password dump from like a bunch of other stuff of which some are valid
icloud accounts
of
which
reused
their password and of those. Oh, certainly. Like, if you've reused your password
and it's been dumped elsewhere for sure. Yeah, somebody can get into your
icloud and like
from orbit,
assuming you don't have two fa enabled which, you know,
Apple is becoming more and more aggressive about,
you know, like I just set up a new ipad for my son
and it, like, make, like, I don't want to use two fa on it. Right.
Because he's, you know, it would just be frustrating for him.
Um, and you know, his kids' ipad,
uh, you know, and I had to make sure, you know, that thing didn't get enabled and,
um,
you know, that's the thing and, and, and then the guy pointed out, you know,
that Apple too has this list of
accounts and apparently they're taking proactive measures,
you know,
maybe making people change their accounts or whatever.
Um,
but yeah, I mean, and that's the thing that really gets me is, you know,
how often do we correctly identify the real threats?
You know,
just what always gets me about PC I compliance is every
time there's been a major data breach of credit card info,
they've always been at places that were PC I certified.
Yeah. I mean, that's everywhere with credit cards is generally certified.
It's,
it's complicated how it all works together and I
don't think it's a huge surprise to anyone that
PC I compliance isn't a magic bullet.
Now, the one thing I would, I would say though is
imagine what a lot of these organizations would look like if they
didn't have a PC I auditor demanding they make certain changes.
It would be a total train wreck.
Yeah.
Well, like back to that, what was it? Uh, the Dutch one, I wanna say, digi
Notar where they had like the viruses on their, you know,
that certificate authority was like a workstation on the internet
and
stuff.
I mean, how many, how many times have you heard about, like flash drives or other gear
that ship the viruses on it?
Because they're using literally someone's computer
to provision the software. It's crazy.
Well, yeah, the manufactures those digital picture frames that ship to the virus.
Well, no, the phones now that are shipping the Android phones that are shipping with
pre
installed.
I
-- know. Yeah,
-- like that
was a couple of weeks ago and it's,
they still haven't pinpointed where in the supply chain that's happening
to
me. I mean,
I,
I own
one of the phone.
The phone I have isn't on the list,
but it's part of that supply chain which is like horrifying to me.
Yeah.
-- No, it's um, II, I can't tell you like,
-- you
-- know
-- what this reminds me of.
I don't remember if I've ever told this story before on the podcast and if I haven't,
I'm sure I'll tell it again
is
long ago
I worked tech support in ISP and when someone would need the installed discs,
we just literally made the discs off of the
local laptop that the tech support guys used.
And every now and then someone would call up and say, hey,
uh my virus program says your disks have a virus.
We'd be like, oh yeah, that's a false positive. That's nothing to worry about.
Right.
And then one day, uh
I was working on a Saturday, it was a slow day and I thought I'm gonna virus scan the,
the computer here because I don't think we've done it in a long time.
And I wonder if the people calling are calling because there's really a virus
and there was really a virus.
And so we, we basically infected like everyone's computer
and, and I remember I went to the boss. Like, what do we do?
We, we've been, we've infected almost all of our customers
and
we know this and, and the guy was like,
nothing.
We're gonna do nothing.
Just don't talk about this. I don't want you to tell anyone about this.
If anyone calls and ask you, send it to me. Don't, don't worry about it.
-- And I have
-- to assume this is one of the reasons, you know,
a lot of I SPS now offer a security package which is typically like a rebranded
scanner
from whoever, you know. Well, not specifically this but just in general, it's like
now you can be
great
USS. We,
-- we offered something.
-- It's,
yeah, that's probably part of it.
But I mean, man, I just, I remember that it was, it was madness
anyway. Anyway. Uh and that, that basically brings us to the end of the movie, right?
Is there any, any other points you want to hit on before we kind of sum this up here?
Uh Well, uh back in the middle of the film, the one of the scenes I most enjoyed
was the authentication scene between Zaho
and Ford.
Remember when they get on the
handshake
thing with the
-- feet,
-- you know,
the whole little handshake, that little authentication
-- dance they go through,
-- you know,
I mean, the world has had secret handshakes for a long time. Is it a secret handshake?
I don't know. Is it a movie? Maybe whatever?
But you, you have, you have a valid point is
that, that would not be unreasonable to have secret handshakes and whatnot in,
in an environment where you,
I, I guess I had lots of crazy people, lots of silly things going on.
So anyway,
so anyway, here is II, I wrote a little summary here for the very end is
so as,
as I'm sure anyone has figured out at this point that I'm not a huge fan of this movie,
but I love the story
and I suspect a part of that is
uh a, a movie can't capture a lot of the nuance that a book can.
And the reason the radio show captured some of it
is because the radio show is like 23 hours long,
right?
-- They just like the
-- original, the BBC
TV.
And that's really,
it's like eight hours, right?
-- There was a lot of
-- content and that's true and that's true. And, and so anyway, but
the, the thing I kept thinking of as I was writing down my notes and,
and re evaluating what I saw and what was going on is
I, I feel like security has the same problem
where we have a book sized nuance
as to how things work together and how we explain everything,
but we only have the amount of time of a movie to explain it.
And this is,
it does. And this is one of our struggles is
we can't distill a lifetime's worth of security knowledge
into a one hour class or a one page
like uh a little diagram or something like that. And
this is what I feel like is one of the challenges that, that we have to figure out.
And I'm not saying this is optional, we have to figure out how to
tell people what they need to know how they need to know it.
And I feel like in the example of this movie,
they failed
now, I it might be impossible. I don't know
uh if I had to guess it's not, I think you just need someone who's capable
of telling the right story.
And in additionally, Douglas Adams is not a screenwriter.
So he might be the reason
this wasn't very good.
Lord forbid, right?
But anyway, you kind of get the idea right? And
-- you're
-- also
-- going up against um you know, the, the the books just have, it's like the,
you know, it reminds me of Lord of the Rings.
Um But basically I think what it boils down to is apple pie.
Um I knew this baker
who would not make apple pie
just wouldn't make it.
He makes Saskatoon pie, he'd make peach pie, he'd make all the other
-- Saskatoon
-- pie.
Saskatoon berries
berry to see
you just gave me the technically correct answer.
I don't know what you're talking about.
Yeah, it's, it's much better than a blueberry anyways. Google
Saskatoon berries.
But the point is he would not make apple pie under any circumstances.
The reason being is everybody was like,
this isn't as good as my mom's apple pie and then bitch about it.
So he's like, you know what?
No, I'm just, I'm not competing with your childhood memories
-- and
-- he's not wrong.
This is a huge problem people have is they remember what they want to from the past
-- and even security people
-- do that and even if it's corrected, it might not be correct.
You know, this whole thing of like, oh, you know,
don't let the Attackers into your network.
Well, yeah, now we have this thing called platform as a service
and we're gonna sell them access for four cents an hour.
It's true. Right.
You know, it's, it's,
I like almost everything I've written uh at the meta level in the Linux
Administrative security guide 20 some years ago
is now wrong. Like it's literally now the business case is no, do exactly that.
Like, yeah,
let people install the software they want and run it as route if they want.
Like who cares that they're paying us? Sure.
You know, let them have access to hardware.
I remember Google talking about PC I fuzzing because it's like, well, wait,
you know,
we're selling access to GP US and somebody might hack one of those GP US
and then use that GP U to attack the rest of the hardware system.
Yes.
Yeah.
And now, I mean, they're, they're overly altruistic compared to most,
or maybe they're not altruistic.
They just have different problems. But
you get the idea. Uh,
II, I looked at these Saskatoon berries and they don't grow anywhere near me,
which is probably why I've never heard of them before.
I think it's only a Canadian thing as far. It's
very,
it does swoop down into portions of the US.
But, but for the most part, it looks like it's kind of to the northwestern
region of North America,
it looks like Alaska gets them too lucky. Alaska.
Um, anyway, anyway, we've been,
we've been going on and on about this movie for quite some time.
Uh, fundamentally,
it, it's,
I won't complain. Right.
I,
I don't feel like I wasted an hour and a half of my life re-watching this
to take notes and talk about a security
episode based on Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy.
I'm not gonna lie.
I probably would have more fun with the book,
but it would have also been a 6.5 hour long podcast episode.
So
there's that benefit as well. I mean, you figure we're over an hour now.
It's like the Lord of the Rings, right. You know,
I,
I could, I could go on about that one too, but
other security themes today,
there's probably some, I don't think there's a ton.
It's complicated.
No, we're not doing this is that
-- you
-- go to, I think that's your new go to.
It's a very easy way to stop a conversation. It's complicated
and people generally are willing to accept that as an answer I found.
And so it's kind of one of those, uh, magic weapons, right.
Where, where it's, it's, it's not unlike again, we,
we talked about navigating bureaucracy or navigating people.
You can tell them it's complicated and more often than not,
they'll accept that as an answer.
So
there we go. There we go, everybody. It's complicated.
-- Uh All
-- right, man. And it keeps changing.
It does. I know it does.
That's what gets me like bank security is gone. It's complicated.
But they've gotten to the point now where, you know, just bank robberies are not
that big of a deal.
You know, people would rather rob et MS
-- for the bad
-- guy.
All right. I think, I think it's said to call it curry. I'm going to bring it home now.
All right, folks. Thank you so much for listening.
You can go to open
source Security podcast.com
and see
there will be no links for this show because
it's just about the movie.
But you can look at past episodes for example and get the show links on that.
We will have links over to Twitter and Facebook
where you can connect with Kurt and I
and send us various notes Uh
I'm sure many of you will have opinions about this episode.
Please let us know, especially Kurt.
He loves feedback and you can yell at him all you want
and we will probably respond
and I guess nothing else. Thank you so much for listening.
Until next time folks take care and Kurt, you have a fantastic day. You too.