Hello and welcome to the 60th episode of the Open source Security podcast
with myself. Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime. Josh Pressers.
How are you? Kurt?
Uh, disappointed
for any specific reason or just in general? Yeah.
Hurricane Harvey killed my vacation
that
I had,
uh, I had a flight through Houston tomorrow.
Uh,
but Houston is under literally not figuratively nine trillion gallons of water.
That's crazy. II,
I guess on one side of things you're probably lucky
it happened before you left because being stranded somewhere is awful.
Yeah.
Yeah. No, it's, uh, yeah, I'm glad it happened before I left to know
after I left that
on the other hand, excuse to take a longer vacation.
That's exactly right. That's
exactly
right.
And I'm
just,
there you go. There you go. At least you found something good. It, it's,
yeah.
Anyway, for, for posterity's sake, Hurricane Harvey just hit Texas and it's,
it's bad.
-- It's really bad.
-- Uh, 48 inches of rain in two days, I believe in one area.
I think it's more than that. One of the airports is under a foot or more of water.
Yeah.
No, it's just the amount of rain is,
it's literally the most amount of rain ever measured in the,
uh contiguous US state. Uh United States.
So, like,
essentially the way that works is Hawaii gets a ton of
rain all the time because it's like a little island.
So it doesn't really count.
Um,
but like within the continental United States and, or Alaska, like, yeah, I mean,
4 ft of rain.
I, I can't imagine that
it's,
well, and I saw a thing on Twitter as well that they had to, like,
add a new color to the weather map
because the old color couldn't handle that amount.
Yeah, exactly. Like 4 ft is. I mean,
yeah, that's how tall my kids are.
So, I guess that's,
I don't, yeah, I don't know what to say. It's, it's madness.
Yeah.
Anyway, uh,
let's
maybe a happier topic is I got to see a total solar eclipse last week
and it was
that
I
didn't read about any mad max scenario,
breakdowns of society due to the influx of people.
It
was
surprisingly uneventful in that regard.
I was prepared with food, water and toilet paper and needed none of it.
It was very,
very well done nowhere I was, was insane.
And my understanding is nobody had to murder
anybody else and many people saw an eclipse.
So, I guess
from the,
let's all be friendly human scale, it was very successful from the, you know,
I'm hoping to see a dystopian mad max event.
Uh that was a failure but, but the eclipse itself was great
and I got to see shadow bands which were crazy.
-- So,
-- what are shadow bands?
Oh, man. So this, I actually just found out about these.
I was watching uh the, the smarter everyday guy.
The Destin, I think his name is,
he had uh a video
about
the eclipse
and he talked about these things called shadow
bands and I never heard of them before,
but apparently, uh right before or right after totality,
you can get these weird, like, uh light and dark
bands on the ground and they kind of move around almost in a snake like manner
and, and, and scientists don't know what they are.
They, they,
they think they're atmospheric disturbances but nobody
knows for sure what causes them.
And so
it was one of those things I learned about this thought that's,
it'd be really cool if I see them and they don't always happen.
Right. So sometimes they show up at a clip sometimes they don't, you never know.
And at
the beginning of totality we saw no shadow bands, I thought, oh, well, you know,
maybe next time
and then at the end, like they were everywhere and it was, it was crazy.
It was so much fun though. Yeah, it was, it was good. I, I really enjoyed it.
I, I will definitely go back
and watch another eclipse.
So,
yeah,
it's weird, man.
That is the weirdest. I'm sorry, I'm just looking
at
that is the weirdest.
Ok. They think, yeah, they think it's basically the earth's atmosphere.
Magic stuff happens in
Voila.
They don't know.
-- And
-- that seems like one of the scientific
experiments where it's like we're pretty sure,
but we're probably wrong.
Well, and I kind of get it right.
Like, this isn't something that happens every day and you,
you can't make it happen in a lab.
It's
not
-- like
-- you can.
Yeah, do testing this. Like at scale would be difficult, I imagine. Right.
And my suspicion is after this eclipse,
they have a significant amount of data just because there are people everywhere,
recording
and there were, you know, scientists everywhere. And you had,
there was this huge weather balloon program that was going on,
in fact that the place I was at,
they launched a weather balloon with all these sensors and stuff on it.
And so that was really fun to talk to those
guys and just understand what they were up to.
And then of course, you could track it on the internet
and there were like,
probably hundreds of weather balloons launched across the,
the swath of the totality.
And so,
I mean, I imagine it has
some effect. Like I remember, um, going way back in time, uh September 11th, right.
There were no Jet Con trails for what, four days above the US.
And they studied the weather and it made a difference.
So, yeah, I imagine
it's so weird to think.
Like, yeah, it's only, well,
what I noticed here was the light quality was really wonky.
Right. It was like, kind of like golden hour type of light almost.
But, like, you know, at noon. So my brain was like,
uh,
you know, no, my brain did not like it did not enjoy it.
Um, it's very strange.
-- Oh,
-- yeah. It was just, it's not right.
You know,
it
just ain't right.
Uh, and the pinhole camera worked surprisingly well.
Uh, they do, they work well. Did you, did you buy any, like, dodgy sunglasses?
Off the internet?
No,
-- my son and I just made one with tinfoil in an Amazon box and some tape.
-- There you go.
-- We work. It worked surprisingly
well.
Uh, for, you know, something that takes 20 minutes to do.
It took you 20 minutes to punch a hole in a box.
Well, we put some tinfoil and stuff over to make it really light
-- to get like a perfect little nice hole and all that.
-- I'll give you seven minutes.
But anyway,
well, ok, but you do
-- six year old.
-- Yeah, that's true.
No, I want to use the scissors then you just hope they don't stab their eye out.
Yeah.
So we didn't put any sunscreen in our eyes or anything like that. So, that was good.
Good, good, good.
But, uh, yeah. No, it was definitely solar eclipses.
Are a weird thing that, that's all,
it
kind of reminds me of these actual internet incidents of, like, weird, you know,
where an attack is actually, like, widespread and successful
because it is, like, literally that rare and weird,
you know, like the wanna cry thing, right?
Like, everybody just sort of stands there staring at it going, like,
-- what do we do now? You know?
-- That's a fair point actually.
Yes, it's,
huh.
I need to think about this.
You might, you might have a, that might be a blog post that you just came up with for me.
Uh, no, no, you're not wrong though. It, it definitely is one of those things that
humans aren't
used to and we don't quite know what to do. And in fact, when the sun goes away
it wasn't, I guess, like the bugs and the birds and all the,
all the critters that were around, they don't know what to do.
So,
it was
cool.
No, it's funny because like, part of me was like, oh,
it's just getting a little darker out.
No big deal. But it's like that doesn't happen at noon usually.
It, it got really, we saw stars, man in Totality.
It was cool. Yeah.
Oh, that would be amazing.
It was
very strange.
So, I guess on to happier topics, uh, you were mentioning some Blockchain stuff.
I came across an article by Jim Reiss, who is a friend of yours.
I know about what the cloud security lines is doing
with Blockchain and I thought, you know,
it'd be fun to kind of chat about Blockchain at that because
I think we've done it in the past,
but I don't think we've had like a superficial Blockchain episode.
So,
uh, yeah, this can be the superficial Blockchain episode.
Yeah.
So, I mean, one
Blockchain is one of those technologies.
It's basically like the web in many ways and that
there's a whole pile of potentially interesting use cases
and some of them might even make money
-- like, you know,
-- Bitcoin.
Yeah.
Uh
oh man,
just Bitcoin makes me angry because I remember looking
at it at six cents and I was like,
oh, this is totally a scam.
I'm not buying in
and I kick myself every day.
Uh But anyway, so,
so Bitcoin is interesting because this or Blockchain in general
like Blockchain even is such a broad family of technologies,
you know,
you've got public blockchains, private blockchains, things with side chains,
things with,
you know, transactions that can be reversed,
things that have where you can't transfer, you know, reverse the transactions.
Um
You know, the it's a lot like crypto in the,
the math behind it kind of lets you pick and choose
whatever properties you really need,
you know.
-- Well,
-- in
Blockchain means a lot of things today, I mean, back in the day,
it kind of originally meant
specifically the technology driving Bitcoin.
But now there's all these old coins that do all kinds of cool stuff
and
there's various technologies you can use. Um,
there's what, what is it, is it Open Ledger, I think is the
CS A is looking into for their, um,
continuing education?
There's
a,
there's a lot of options,
you know, the financial, uh there's a payment, uh
sorry, a payment industry consortium.
The name escapes me right now but it's all the usual players
and of course they're looking into a Blockchain thing for, you know,
transaction settlements,
uh
stock markets are looking
at this. Um,
all the insurance companies are looking at this for, you know, the paperwork,
um, the housing industry because, you know,
one thing I found out is it's pretty good in Canada and
the US but even in Canada and the US where we have,
you know, pretty solid rule of law and
generally good records
when you buy a house, you,
you still generally buy something called title insurance, which,
which basically says like you bought a house and it turns out
you didn't buy the house because the person
you bought it from doesn't actually own it.
Whoops
or
someone who doesn't own it. There can be liens against the house.
There can be like all this crazy stuff that can happen
with a property.
Yeah, exactly. There was a, a funny case here in Canada where a guy bought a house,
you know, and he thought he owned his backyard. Right?
Most people would think if you have a fenced in backyard that you own
and it turns out it was a separate parcel of land.
Yeah. And the guy came by and he's like you want to buy your backyard
and he said no. So the guy's like, ok, I'll put a fence up.
That's crazy, man. I mean,
yeah.
So anyways, one of the benefits of Blockchain is potentially
uh depending on which properties you choose and sort of how public you make it.
You, you can basically fix all those problems.
Well, you can fix some of the problems.
I mean, you can still have people doing weaselly things against house
stuff.
I mean, so actually this is something I, I learned,
I had a bunch of major work done on my house when I
bought it and I took out a construction loan to get it done.
Which by the way, if, if anyone ever gets any major work done on a property,
get a construction loan, even if you don't need it.
Because what happens is that title insurance?
You get that with a loan too.
And what happens is so I, I didn't know this.
I was educated by the maker on all this stuff and
I was like super excited to learn it and understand it.
But essentially like any of the contractors who work in your house,
any of them can put a lien against your house
for unpaid
-- or,
-- or like for like any reason they don't
even, not even unpaid, but just. Right.
Right. Right. And so essentially by having this title insurance then,
like, yes, a contract you can put a lien against my house. But it's not my problem.
Right. Because title insurance deals with it. Which is,
-- yeah, exactly. It's awesome. Worth
-- every penny.
That's actually really good to know.
Yeah. Yeah, I learned a lot.
But anyway, anyway, the,
the beauty of this though and I'm going to tie this back into the,
the open C pe model that,
that Jim talked about and I'll put a link to it in the
show notes is one of the challenges you get in any system is
people love to go back in time
and try to backdate things and pretend something happened in the past and, you know,
especially when you
like liens against property or you have like public notices saying, you know,
uh so and so died and now the estate is in probate, whatever.
And then people are like, oh, he uh lent me money uh uh 1010 years ago. And uh
yeah, let me, uh let me go get the receipt. It's in my car. Can I borrow your pen?
You know? And
no, he didn't.
But anyway, and so the beauty of something like Blockchain is
once something is stuck into the ledger,
-- it's, it's there forever and it's
-- immediate.
Yes and no,
there are there are you can,
you can choose blockchains with properties that allow you to
either modify or even delete transactions.
But in theory, you would also, even in that situation,
you could have somebody monitoring it that keeps
-- a, like a record of everything that was ever.
-- No, no.
Here's the thing though, is,
is what you're talking about is something similar to it.
It's uh Ethereum I think has the,
the smart contracts
that are built in
the ledger is not modified,
like
the
data
have ledgers that can be modified if enough people, for example, vote on it in
some
totally different. That's Bitcoin
you're really talking about here and
in some cases you do, uh
there are situations with certain types of documents or records
where you do need to be able to back out or cancel or destroy transactions.
And, and ideally, it would only happen in a situation where, you know,
like something obviously went horribly wrong
and you know, everybody agrees that something went horribly wrong.
So like, let's pretend that never happened.
And that was, was that,
-- that was a theorem that happened to you
-- where they got kind of ripped off for like
somebody
stole a million
of coin
and
they
found um
I forget what the flaw was in the, in the smart contracts, but
it was a good one.
in that instance,
what they did is basically everyone decided we're just going to go
back in time to this day and pretend nothing happened since then.
But of course, that creates a bunch of issues because then
anyone who traded anything with each other during that, I guess
magic time those transactions are now gone.
So you have to kind of go back after people and say please sir, you know,
can I have some more?
And of course they could say no and there's probably nothing you could do about it.
Not really,
there was a really good article talking about um
short sales of various uh Bitcoin and Bitcoin alter
was a crazy story man.
Well, but here's the reality, right? The financial markets um are complicated.
I've, I've read about them and tried to understand it.
And the conclusion I've come to is I don't have enough time
to read about it and actually even begin to understand it.
Yeah, I I agree that there's a lot of crazy that goes on and so
do, do you even want to try to explain what happens here?
So, but going back to Bitcoin
and Blockchain in general,
but the beauty of Blockchain is you get to choose
the properties of the Blockchain, right? So for example, an insurance
Blockchain for say a great example, ownership of houses, right?
You might want to actually choose, for example,
to be able to undo transactions so that if there is a fraudulent transaction,
you can undo it.
But you might also then require that like say for example, like half of the
available sort of consensus
people vote.
Yes, on that. Right.
So you can't just have like a few wonky people rolling back transactions.
You have to, you know, you have to have like a majority.
No, I mean,
no,
not at all.
That's, that totally defeats the purpose of having a public ledger
is
well, but the thing is you would still have the record of that event happening
which in and of itself is valuable but the consequences of that event are wiped out.
-- See, and that's part
-- of the beauty. I see what you're saying. And that's
-- like Bitcoin basically can't do that
-- today. Exactly. Well, and it,
and, and essentially if Bitcoin wants to be cash, it can't.
That's kind of the whole
point
of cash,
you
spend it, you get robbed too bad, it's gone.
It's not like Bitcoin is basically that you, uh, you get robbed and it's gone.
If you throw your wallet into a dump,
you,
you shouldn't do that, I guess is the answer.
-- So,
-- anyway, let's talk about the Cloud Security Alliance because
we're getting into precarious territory.
Yeah, if you want a quick overview.
So the idea is essentially, um, C pe continuing professional education. Right.
So a lot of security standards and,
uh, titles and, you know, like ISC Squared, CISSP or
whatever,
have a requirement for continuing professional education.
You know, you can't just like, write the exam pass and then, like,
coast on that for 20 years.
I, I think you can listen to podcasts.
So,
yeah, just hit that back catalog,
-- folks.
-- Exactly.
And so, yeah,
part of it is essentially depending on
which certification is and how they've structured.
It.
Basically, it boils down to, is a lot of them.
Kind of have you,
you need a certain number of points every year to maintain your certification
and you can earn points by doing various activities. Um, so funny story.
The CV E board
uh was uh the Miter Corporation was amused to
find out that actually being on the CV board
and doing that kind of stuff counts in a
lot of things for continuing professional education board.
So,
yeah, I mean, it does sort of make sense.
Um but even things like for some of them reading blogs, articles, reading um well,
magazine.
Do we have information security magazines anymore? I don't
know.
-- I don't think so.
-- I remember the trade eggs, man, I remember getting them in the mail.
This is, it's been years I,
I
think
I should see if I can sign up for them. That would be,
that would be fun to do.
Yeah.
And things like, you know, going taking courses,
especially taking courses at more sort of,
well, things like blackout,
right? They have a quite a bit of training at Black Hat.
And so, yeah, so the idea is essentially you do these courses, you do these,
you read magazines, you read books, you whatever, do stuff
and you apply for your continuing education
credits and then you maintain your certification.
Um, the real pain in the ass is, and I can speak to this personally.
I had AC ISSP certification
and I let it lapse because getting the continuing education credits
and filing them was such a pain in the butt.
I just couldn't be bothered.
Yeah, I, I get that.
I've, I've let many,
many things like that expire just because I was too lazy to do the work to keep it.
Yeah.
So part of the idea behind using a Blockchain for this
is not just that it would make it somewhat easier to register these credits,
but that it would make it easier for various standards to consume these credits.
So, for example, if I go to black hat and take a training,
you know, that would apply to AC ISSP but it might also apply to,
but I, I don't really know any other uh certifications
to be off honest off the top of my head, like me plus a
bunch.
Yeah, there's, there's like a big pile of these globally.
Um But anyway, so, you know,
typically when you take a training or do something like that, it would apply to
probably most of the, you know, the certifications you have.
And so the part of the idea is is that
you have a situation with many producers and many consumers,
right?
So if you take like 10,
uh 10 things of training a year and you have 10 certifications.
Now you have to manage 100
of these relationships. The filing these things
is
a
pain in the butt.
Um, so the idea is basically essentially that you could have, you know,
somebody like blackout training.
Um,
you know, assuming you're willing to, uh, put this in the public ledger, you know,
say though, like, yeah,
like Josh Reser went and took the training on VPN security and
-- totally aced it, you know, because he's awesome. Of
-- course I did.
And uh you know,
the uh the teacher basically gave him a good mark to make him go away.
-- Um
-- That happened to me in college. Actually, I was in a,
I was in a programming class.
It was ac programming class and uh I was young and, and knew a lot of c
and I remember after constantly correcting the professor, he came up to me and said,
uh
if you never come back, I'll give you a B and I was like, done, you know,
and that was the end of that. And I was ecstatic,
but
there you go. Kids being a horrible pain in the ass can pay off sometimes.
Oh, the squeaky wheel gets the grace,
-- right.
-- Let's not pretend otherwise.
So, you know, what else I see as having value here is,
um, speaking of college,
one of the other things I was notorious for is there
were classes I would take where you had to um,
maybe submit
certain things
before the end of the semester.
And of course, on the day before the end of the semester I was up all night long,
doing all of the work I was supposed to have done all semester long.
Right.
Instead of all at once. And so there's kind of that, that fraud aspect you can help
reduce
where people can't backdate work.
I, I can't pretend I wrote this paper, you know, on the 13th of June
because I didn't,
but I also don't want to have like everything dated yesterday that I turned in today.
Right? I get it.
So, and, and part of this too is, I mean, again,
depending on the properties you choose and
how you choose to structure politically.
For example,
you can have a process to deal with sort of fraudulent
claims. Right? Because for example, there are some,
uh, I just took my border exam,
uh, license and it's all online. Right? It's, it's a, it's a 34 hour online process.
You do the web.
Uh, it's mostly so I have a little plastic car now,
which means I don't get like a multi $100 fine if I'm operating a boat and,
-- and
-- let me guess, I bet the vast majority of everything they talked about was, uh,
don't drink in boat
-- and don't be a dick,
-- right?
And wear your person.
And of
course, the life
fest, of course.
Yeah. But seriously do wear that folks
do
like,
really, please do.
Um Yeah, basically and you know,
there's some navigation stuff that was useful and some uh
anyways,
but back to this. So basically the idea is that,
you know, there are,
if you give an incentive for people to have certification,
which like we have because, you know, if you have certifications,
typically it's easier to get a job or especially in some parts of the world, right,
where you're certain through, you know, hundreds of, you know, applicants
and it's a good way to essentially do like a quick,
you know, filter, right?
Um
So there's all kinds of, you know, potential fraudulent claims,
like people taking exams for other people, people
becoming like diploma mills, right?
Like that classic thing where it's like, oh, yeah, totally.
We have VPN training here real good 50 bucks online,
blah, blah, blah, right?
And so part of this beauty of this too with the Blockchain
is that the consumers can not only choose kind
of what and how they consume these things,
but again, they can sort of make that information more public and share it, you know,
like
we've seen a lot of one,
you know, for example,
we've seen a lot of people with this certification take this course and then,
you know, people come back and complain about it.
That's interesting.
And so we need these feedback loops and then
where we can actually do something about it,
you know, so we could for example,
retroactively say like, oh, we're no longer going to um, accept, you know,
uh Bob's House of Pancakes and VPN education.
-- Yes.
-- You know.
And so, OK, but, but here is the question
is
why
do we need Blockchain to do this
instead of just, let's say having a mysql database somewhere?
So that's what came up. That was one of the central questions.
And so this has come up with several other things, but basically what it boils down to
is
if there is at least one
interested party in running this,
it will be alive,
right? And that's the benefit over a centralized like my SQL database.
Like a great example of this is Wikipedia, right? Wikipedia is awesome,
you know,
and anybody can download the whole thing. It's not that big. It's like what?
-- Hundreds of gigabytes I
-- think,
I think the downloads only like 16 gigs for the compressed archive.
I
-- think that's only the text, not the images and video and all that.
-- That could be
but regardless 16 gigs, right? Like no offense that fits on a phone.
Yeah. Yeah, it fits,
you
know, I know the whole thing can fit on a one terabyte drive.
-- Like
-- exactly. That's,
that's walking around storage nowadays, literally that
fits in your pocket
for like under 200 bucks
actually under 100 bucks.
And
right, it's
I was at best Buy just the other day man. And they had
a four terabyte portable hard drive for like, $200. And I thought this is,
-- my brain doesn't even know what to think of this.
-- I
know.
It's amazing.
So, but the problem with Wikipedia is, let's say, for the sake of argument,
wikipedia.org dies.
Well,
hm, ok. Everybody has a copy of Wikipedia. That's awesome. We haven't lost the data.
But how do we update it? Who has the true copy?
I do.
-- Right. Yeah,
-- exactly.
And see that's the problem that Blockchain solves.
We have a true copy. And like I said, as long as there's essentially one
organization willing to run it,
we still have that one true copy.
It's not just that there's some more going on here, that's really important.
And I think the most important aspect of this
is not that
it is that
I cannot change anything in the past. If I say
I'm now in charge of the open C pe program or what,
whatever you guys are going to call it.
And
I say I'm in charge, I'm the only one who cares.
I can't go back in time and change things.
Right. Well, yeah, that's a big thing too. But I mean,
this whole thing presupposes that it still exists,
you know,
and archive.org is a great example of this, right?
They're trying to sort of salvage a lot of our digital history.
Yes.
Yes,
-- they
-- are,
you know,
and quite frankly, if that stuff was in Blockchain,
they could just essentially be part of that
and then just
cop,
-- it doesn't quite work like that. I mean,
-- well,
-- it's,
-- I
-- know,
-- but if you look at, like, the Bitcoin Blockchain,
the Blockchain I've got on my computer is like hundreds of gigabytes at this point.
It's completely insane how huge it is.
Hundreds of gigabytes is not big anymore. My friend, it
is when you're on, like,
some crappy dial up connection and you connect for the first
time and you have to download all of the freaking block.
But I mean,
I would just run it on like an Amazon or Google computer engine machine with 10
-- gig feed.
-- Yes, we would do that. Although even then man, uh
that could get out of hand
downloading all of the Blockchain over your, your,
let me put it
in a
rule
thumb. If it, if it,
if it's important enough that somebody cares,
they can easily spend several tens of thousands of dollars on it
and several tens of thousands of dollars nowadays buys you so much compute time
and data transfer and data storage that
I, I literally without an envelope can't tell you how much that is.
It's probably really cheap.
It's also cheap now.
Like I know what my annual it budget is now and it's, you know,
it's in the hundreds of dollars per year.
It's
for my personal it. And I remember one year I spent $17,000 on computers uh
for your personal stuff.
-- Well, when I was doing
-- contract
that could be.
Um And now I'm down to some raspberry,
I'm actually getting rid of my last two PC servers and I'm
going to go with some raspberry pies and removable hard drives.
Nice. I get tempted to do that every now and then.
I haven't pulled the trigger yet, but I think I'm getting close
because at this point, if I can buy a four gig hard drive for $200
I
already did that.
My kids,
my kids file server is just an external hard drive on the Mac mini in the living room.
Um
So I'm getting rid of those two last big computers.
So then, then the biggest computer I'll have is
laptop slash a Mac mini,
you know, and then a bunch of stuff in the cloud
which no doubt is like a gazillion data servers. God knows where. But
-- on my problem,
-- right.
Oh man, you got to love it.
You gotta love it.
So anyway, we're talking about Blockchain, not, not Kurt's cloud service bill,
-- which
-- well, and another benefit to this Blockchain is that it,
the barrier to entry is so much lower than a centralized server.
And that's
so here's, here's actually the problem is
once it exists, like
working with the Bitcoin network
is trivial today, you download the client,
then you download an insane amount of data off of the peer to peer Blockchain network
and then everything's fine. Right? And, and it does constantly update.
Now, my, my one complaint about the Bitcoin network as well is the,
the volume of data you see coming in and out of your house is quite high
when the client is running just because of the peer to peer nature of it.
So there, there's that.
But, but anyway, anyway, I
ignoring that
if you want to run your own ledger, like you want to take open Blockchain or,
or open Ledger, what, whichever there's a bunch of.
So I actually know some of the numbers for this
outsourcing it.
We're
-- talking about less than 10 grand
-- a month, not outsourcing it.
Right. If, if you work with someone else, yes, that has the expertise to start it
off. But like if you wanted to do it on your own,
the start up costs are substantial because it's actually really
difficult to stand some of this stuff up by yourself.
Oh,
it's definitely nontrivial and more to the point.
There are smart people that will help you and more to the point,
you can just outsource the whole damn thing for like 10 grand a month or less.
You can.
And
that is probably the right way to do it unless you don't have 10 grand.
And then,
which is what I
say.
I view honestly a lot of this like electricity,
electricity is not my core competency.
I, I just pay
Core
Edmonton Power Corporation
like I literally just pay them like,
I don't know 50 bucks a month. I don't even,
-- I think it's 50 a month.
-- A $50
-- bill is super cheap because, or
-- maybe it's more,
I don't know.
But
regardless I pay Epcor and I buy a bunch of a PC Upss
to make sure the power doesn't, like, destroy anything here.
That's it.
II, I like,
I actually know how to rewire a house but it's just not applicable anymore.
It doesn't matter. It's so simple
anyway.
-- It's
-- like buying,
it's like buying bandwidth. I don't know how to buy bandwidth.
I just pay for an Aws instance.
Oh, you're not wrong.
You're not
wrong
and why, you know, I've, I've looked into these things about what it would take to.
Actually a big part of this is like, you know, who do you even talk to, to buy this from?
And are you getting a good deal? Don't know. Don't care.
I pay Amazon like a couple of 100 bucks a month or whatever, you know,
in the case of something like this.
Yeah. Yeah, I mean that, that's fair. That's fine.
Anyway. Anyway,
right.
-- I am
-- speaking to your, your. Ok. So we're now uh yeah, internet 150.
So it's 100 and 50 megabits per second. One terabyte
data allowance is 82 bucks a month.
Um, but I believe for an extra $15 a month you can buy unlimited,
unlimited amount of data.
So
I would assume 100 and 50 megabits per second is probably enough to run Bitcoin
a, a client.
You need like two megabits in each direction, man.
-- Oh, that's it. Yeah,
-- it's, it's not a lot.
My cell phone will do that.
Except in Kennedy, you're going to hit your overage in like five minutes,
right?
4.5
about
that.
Yeah,
I've actually, I'm really proud of myself now.
I consistently get a 95% email warning on my cell phone.
Typically one or two days before my billing period ends.
Nice.
You know what's even better than that is having unlimited data and you don't care,
I'd have to live in the US for that to happen.
Right. Right. Because
that's,
I still love like of all the backwards technology
problems we have like we're getting cell phones mostly.
Right.
So
I'll give us points there.
So anyway, anyway, let's, let's tie up this Blockchain conversation is.
So, yeah, I mean,
I think things like what the CS A is doing here is really clever because
Blockchain is one of those things that has tons and tons of hype around it,
but I've yet to see anything like truly materialized that
that is used
has
not
emerged quite yet. Bitcoin
is
not really
a
-- app
-- today.
Right.
Well, and, and, but you look at like how many transactions per second,
Blockchain is handling compared to say like Visa
and it's so many orders of magnitude smaller. I
mean,
this is why they just forked Bitcoin because there are some
of the miners were unhappy with the essentially block size.
Was it block size?
It was block size. Yeah,
-- they wanted to increase it. They
-- made it bigger so it can handle more transactions.
But yeah, it's still,
it is not going to be capable of handling transactions on a level
that we need in the modern financial world.
-- And
-- well, somebody pointed out the cost in electricity for a Blockchain
transaction. It's seriously hideous.
-- Bitcoin
-- is using so much electricity right now. It's not even funny. And,
and I mean, in all seriousness,
there are many downfalls to this currency and I think
that is probably the one that's going to murder it
because
-- no,
-- it's going to be the uh the the deflationary spiral that'll hit
it.
I
yes,
-- but I question if we will hit that before it just becomes so uneconomical to
-- mine
becomes cheap
power,
power plus renewables.
It's, it's more than just compute power though, man.
I mean, we're, we're bumping into
just the ability to fab some of this Asic year at this point,
right? We, we,
we've just said a whole bunch of things, I bet.
So
basically
what
we're
saying,
the long and the short of it is
Bitcoin is horrifically like literally like like
spiked mallet to the face, horrible
-- energy consumption to what it does. But
-- not only
that at most, there will be 21 million Bitcoins in existence.
And if I had to guess.
I bet there are currently a several 100,000 of them that have been lost forever.
Oh, easily.
Plus all the ones, the original Satoshi
guy, whatever entity mind and
have never really
know
how many he has. I've heard he's a billion.
Yeah, it was a couple of million.
Um, but basically here's the problem, like you can hate on fiat money all you want.
But being able to print more money
as it turns out is kind of a useful,
super useful
it.
Well, and not just print more money. Right.
Let's ignore that.
Even if you can't print more money,
banks have financial vehicles that they,
they make money out of thin air essentially.
Right?
And
with Bitcoin, you can't do that.
There's no way to do like fractional reserve lending with Bitcoin.
Well, there probably is,
but like that's a pyramid scheme at that point and you're going to fail, right?
Yeah,
I think honestly, I think Charles Strauss kind of talks about this, this,
he's a sci fi writer that does a lot of economics related stuff
and money is not
really meant to be like a store of value or a thing of value.
It's meant to be a lubricant to get that stuff moving.
You know, that's fair.
I mean, a great example of this is, you know,
um, the house I currently live in has been sold and, you know, I, I lose it on the 25th.
Uh, but it would be nice to, you know, move into the house,
uh that we're buying
before that
except I don't have like a, you know,
a big pile of money handy to buy a house for like that week
in front of getting the money from this house.
So, you know, the, the bank provides bridge financing
and voila like magic happens and then there's like a week
of overlap where I can actually move all my stuff.
It
is terrible. Oh
-- God,
-- I am so not looking
forward
to
close to you. So you can't ask me to help.
Yeah. So, but basically, I mean, that's the point, right?
Money is meant to be a lubricant.
It's meant to get stuff going like a great example of this. I love it.
Like, like as much as again people hate on stuff like square,
I can now sell my couch and take a credit card.
Yeah, I suppose
I don't want cash because I'm gonna get robbed or something,
you know, but being able to take a credit card, like literally my kids,
if they decide to go into snow shoveling or lawn mowing,
-- they can take credit cards or you can email the money.
-- That's a great idea.
Actually give a kid a stripe reader and be like go go mow lawns.
Yeah.
Yeah, we were going to actually get some teenage on my parents' cabin,
get the teenagers across the street.
Essentially, you email us a picture of the lawn, you go mow.
-- It, send us a second picture of the lawn. We'll email you the money.
-- Now.
Now this is where having the Blockchain would be great because
then they couldn't just keep emailing old pictures of the lawn.
Right.
Well, I'm assuming that they're not smart enough to modify the JPEG XF data and,
like, retake the dates and stuff.
But, and, and worst case scenario, you can have them, like, hold up, you know,
proof of life copy of the newspaper or whatever,
you know.
But I mean, and again,
-- they could Photoshop and stuff but realistically
-- reddit a ma
after mowing the lawn that way you can prove it.
Exactly.
But fundamentally like it gets to the point where the fraud
would be much more effort than just mowing the lawn.
Uh
man, never underestimate people.
There are a lot of people who are involved in fraud that do
way more work than if they were just running an honest business.
This is true.
-- It's the sad
-- truth.
But
yeah, I mean, that's the beauty. Like if you have a, you know,
a decent currency and not only a decent currency
but a way of actually transferring it around,
you know, people can go do stuff and create value and get paid for it,
but here's the thing. All right. So here's the question.
Ignoring your
economic lesson here on why real money matters is
Bitcoin is on fire.
How high do you think it's going to go before it comes crashing to the earth.
I think. What is it?
Uh Warren Buffett's quote about essentially your
ability to survive the market's irrationality.
No, you can't. The, the irrationality of the market will always win.
No, no, this isn't about market winning. My question is how high will Bitcoin go
before it comes crashing down? Because you and I both believe,
I don't think, I don't think it will
crash per
I think we'll have, I think there will be definitely a correction.
But the problem is there's what's called a deflationary spiral built into
the currency and that there's a finite amount of the currency.
So you think the deflation will be slow and steady rather than
fire.
What happens if you had something like Mount
Gox where instead of the money being stolen,
the money was wiped out.
Fox got ripped off the
right.
Some of these Bitcoin exchanges are holding lots of coin
and if they, if they lost their private keys, the coin is gone. Like
these people are not good
at it has happened.
It's a lot of people.
So I my my thought is on the one hand, you have the irrationality of the market,
you have the,
the Bitcoin being used more and more for all sorts of wonky and legitimate things.
But then on the, you know, on the other side, you have this
like the money just goes away after a while because people lost
it or it got stolen and they can't spend it or whatever.
And I don't know what that rate is. I, you know, you'd have to have like a whole pile of.
And again,
this goes back to where I was trying to educate myself on financial markets.
And II, I have a general understanding of
kind of what kinds of charts and graphs I'd want to see. But I have,
-- I would not know how to interpret it.
-- But again, even ignoring all of that,
my suspicion is still that with the way Bitcoin works is there is a difficulty
and basically the, the network wants one Bitcoin to be generated every 10 minutes.
And if it takes less than 10 minutes, it raises a difficulty.
If it takes more than 10 minutes, it lowers it.
And so
at some point,
I suspect the cost of electricity
is going to become too expensive to be
actually doing any sort of legitimate Bitcoin mining
and, and that's when everything falls apart.
Well, and there's the, also the ugly fourth problem hiding in the sidelines.
You have a Bitcoin. How do you turn that into real money?
No, seriously, because it's not
because there's a lot of listeners who probably need
to
figure
there are some shops that will take like Bitcoin, you can buy items there,
there used to be a ton, there's a lot fewer than, than there were,
you can
trade them on exchanges. But
real
money,
if you want cash. You're in trouble. I'm not gonna lie. It's hard to turn it into cash.
It's, and here's the thing,
you can probably turn one Bitcoin into cash on an exchange.
But if you have, let's say 100 of them.
-- Yeah. No way.
-- What if you have a million of them,
then whatever Bitcoin Rich did, I mean,
clue.
But not only that, actually, I also read that the IRS in the United States
is going to apply like they talk about using A I which I'm like, yeah, whatever.
It's probably, you know, a pearl's regular expression.
But, but anyway, they're,
they're going to use technology to try to start uncovering
-- like the real identities of people
-- that's already happened.
Um Somebody applied A I to Bitcoin and some other
-- stuff to find out sex trafficking payment for stuff
-- I heard
about
that
and in that,
that's
really cool.
Uh Well, and actually, so that's a funny thing too.
That's something we didn't even talk about. But, but I know
how Bitcoin is totally not anonymous,
right? How it's not anonymous. But there's other things like Z cash.
An example of an alt coin that Z cash
actually has some really impressive anonymity built into it.
So it solves some of those problems. But,
oh man, we could probably have like 10 episodes about this stuff
easily.
-- It's so
-- complicated
so
long to
buy Bitcoin, it can only go up just like
that
-- 2008.
-- That's
right. Go in,
go in hard. That's what I say.
Sell
your real estate to buy Bitcoin.
Right.
Exactly. Take out loans. Right. Go to your bank.
We
are not
good.
Don't
listen
to anything. We say we are, we are not
people.
We are also not lawyers or accountants.
No, no, we're not.
Oh,
my goodness. I don't know, man, we'll see, I guess.
And, but here's part of it too. Right. Long ago
I remember saying like, Bitcoin has no future. This is dumb.
And II, I had quite a bit of Bitcoin and I got rid of it all because I'm like, it just,
it has no future.
I, I think I traded it for like a $10 Amazon card
and I'm like,
I, I would have been Bitcoin Rich but I'm not.
So
it, it, whatever.
And I still say like this,
this currency has no future and it just keeps going up and I'm like,
I'm gonna be right someday.
-- You know,
-- I think part of it is, is for a certain set of users of money.
Bitcoin really solves a lot of problems.
And so they will continue to use it just like, like let's,
there are still people who slept duffel bags full of $100 bills around.
That's the thing
I remember in the US. They changed the look of the $100 bill at one point
and they said one of the reasons they did it is they were going to tell everyone,
you know, the old $100 bills are no good anymore and trade them in
and they figured there were,
there was a significant portion of the economy that would become useless
because they wouldn't really have a way to turn their old
hundreds into new hundreds because everything they did was illegitimate.
-- Yeah.
-- Well, I mean, you can't just show up.
Well, that happened in, um, a couple of countries now where, you know, like Brazil,
for example, where you had to, yeah, declare all your currency.
And so people were getting their, like, housemaids and their, no, sorry,
it was India.
Remember India did that huge push to electronic currency.
And so people are, like,
trying to get their housekeepers and their maids and their chauffeurs to, like,
declare money
because you're only allowed to declare a certain.
Right?
Because India, one of the problems they have is they can't,
there's this huge, you know, black and gray economy that they can't collect tax on.
Right. So, like, their government is continually broke because
they, they don't have an economy that they can tax.
Right.
And so that happened.
Um, but yeah, if you look at, uh, us $100 bills, something like, uh,
70% plus live outside the US,
the
money. That's
crazy.
Yeah. And that's N pr planet money. So they're probably not wrong.
Yeah, they're, they're legit. I agree.
All right.
So, anyway, anyway, uh, any parting words,
I think it's about time to wrap this one up.
Uh, go along on beanie babies
anyway.
-- Uh,
-- no, that's literally all I got folks. Um,
yeah, I mean, there's some good basic, uh, articles on Blockchain,
especially on Wikipedia and whatnot.
Probably want to read them just to get an understanding.
-- Kind of like the web was 20 years ago
-- and let's face it. It's some cool stuff.
I mean, I think like the CS A thing is the start of some,
some new technologies we're going to see and I'm, I'm eager to see what,
what else can come of it
just because
I feel like there's a lot of potential here and
we just have to start uncovering some of it.
So,
yeah. Well, it's, it's still a lot of it is finding those killer apps that
make sense, make money and also make life easier.
Exactly. And don't consume like 1/5 of the world's electricity.
Yes,
this is true.
Alright.
Alright. Thank you everyone for listening. Thank you, Kurt. It was fun.
As always, if you want links to any of the show notes, you can go to open
source security podcast.com.
You can use the Pound Os S podcast hashtag to get
a hold of us if you have anything clever to say.
And we have a Facebook group.
You can find that on the website where you're welcome to join and hassle us,
ask questions, participate in lively conversations, whatever.
And yeah, I guess Uh, thanks, Kurt.
You have a fabulous rest of your day.
Yeah, you tuning for everybody in Texas, I guess. Yeah,
seriously. Do do what you gotta do. That's, that sucks.
-- All right. All right, man. Talk to you
-- later. Thanks. Bye.