Hello and welcome to the Open source Security podcast episode 34 with myself,
Kurt Siegfried and my partner in crime.
Josh Pressers.
Have you recovered from RS A yet? Kurt?
-- I have and I don't think I even got sick from it.
-- I probably got sick.
II, I felt better. I'm nearly recovered, I would say.
But things,
whatever it is what it is.
Yeah.
I ended up accidentally smuggling my giant
bottle of Purell back through airport security
because I forgot it was in my bag and apparently they didn't realize either.
Oh,
wow.
I always find it funny when I go through my bags
and I realize I forgot something that shouldn't go through security.
And
let's just say,
I don't think they've ever found any of
the things I've accidentally smuggled through the airport.
Well, it's funny because my, my backpack has like this large flat component, uh,
like, uh, area for like a laptop which I almost never used.
And for some reason I had a wire coat hanger in there for like a, why
don't
I, I must have
put it in there for some reason.
I wonder
if a wire coat hanger is on the TS, a approved items list.
Uh, I don't know. But anyway, it was just one of those things where, you know? Yeah.
It's like, why?
Yeah, nobody's, I mean, because they always,
the funny thing is they almost always pull my bag over
for secondary inspection due to the number of batteries and wires.
Um, I made the mistake of that tablet you bought for me.
-- I packed it in my suitcase between two books.
-- Why did you do that?
I mean,
-- come on
-- because I didn't want to carry like six electronic devices in my carry on.
I was getting tired.
I had to,
I had to lug my bag all over San
Francisco for the afternoon because I was sightseeing.
You just bring it to the hotel and say, can you watch my bag for me, please?
And they say, yes sir, we would love to.
Oh, no, I did that. This was the anyways. But
so the TS a goons, I'm pretty sure because they put those little, you know,
the little slip in my bag that said it
was uh inspected or whatever for whatever reason.
And I'm pretty sure that when they repacked it,
that's when they crushed that poor little tablet.
That's sad. It was a fun little tablet.
I, yeah, I mean, all I got to do is turn it on and make sure it works and then,
-- then it was killed
-- and it did and you paid me for it.
And so now it's your problem.
-- I don't even feel
-- a little bad
but you know what I love is they destroy the tablet and this tablet is so cheap.
It's not even worth attempting to go through any process to get it.
Like,
reimbursed.
It was 50 bucks. Like it's just,
you know,
I'd be better off going out on the street and begging for money to replace it.
That would be a better return on my investment of time.
Seriously, man,
I mean, I know exactly what you mean.
There are,
there are numerous things in my life that just don't have enough value for me to care.
And so when it breaks or when I have a problem, I'm like, well,
whatever I want 20 bucks.
That's the way it is.
Yeah. Speaking of which my trip mate doesn't want to talk to USB devices anymore.
Uh, trip mate.
-- Yeah.
Interesting.
So
you plug in a USB thing and it doesn't work.
-- It doesn't see
-- it
just buy a new one. They're like 30 bucks.
Exactly.
Well, actually what I want is I want, I want something a little more powerful. Right.
-- Because the wireless speeds through that thing are pretty pathetic.
-- Really?
I've had really good luck. I get, like,
I, I think
last time I checked it when I connect to my
home wireless I was pulling more than 20 megabits.
Yeah, that's slow.
Whatever mate. Have you used? Hotel wi
fi
hotel wi
in fact,
at
ra I couldn't even use the hotel wifi. It was so unusually bad.
So, thank goodness I had a Wi
Fi in my bag.
-- Yeah,
-- I found that like my connection,
you
know, like the VPN would drop every 2 to 3 minutes.
It's terrible. You gotta love it.
It's all part of the fun.
That's,
you know, I bet.
At a conference. Well, I guess it sort of happened.
I read a thing that there were a bunch of, you know,
kind of man in the middle access points at RS A
but I bet if you went to a hotel and, and, and had an A P of, you know,
SS ID of free Fast Wi Fi or something,
you'd probably have more people connecting to that
than you would know what to do with
the trick is you just use something that
people already have connected to like Starbucks,
wifi.
-- Yeah,
-- that
too, I suppose.
Yeah,
because most devices are too stupid to check the Mac address of the access point.
Yeah.
Well, and even if you did, you just spoof the Starbucks from down the street.
Yeah, that's true. That's true.
Right. You know, and then
Apple
and Windows and everything, a lot of log in,
you gotta love it.
This, this, although, I mean, this is kind of why
everything,
all of your traffic over the internet needs
to be encrypted because you shouldn't have to care
what kind of access point you're connecting to.
Well, you know,
it just speaks to Google's beyond court security
paper where they said even their internal network,
they, they pretend it's the internet.
And,
you know, I've started doing that because I've, I've had to. Right. Because
a great example, you know, my,
my home network has a real nice firewall and it's real nice and secure.
I only have three devices
on my network that generally don't
leave the house.
You know, and that's my, uh
Mac
minis
and my, uh
my Nintendo wii
right. Everything else has, tends to wander around the city.
Yeah, I know what you mean.
It's, it's terrifying to think about where, where this stuff's been. Right.
Yeah.
-- So,
-- I mean, there, there, you know,
that concept of like your devices live on a nice clean network is dead.
Oh, yeah, it's been, it's been dead for a long time.
Well, not only that you gotta think if, if you have a typical cell phone,
it is connected to the GSM network and your home network at the same time.
Right.
That's, and then again,
that goes because I was thinking of segmenting
my wireless network and having multiple networks and,
and I do have multiple networks.
I have like a two gigahertz and five gigahertz
and that's just for, you know,
just like to keep all the old crappy devices out of the way with the new devices,
-- the two,
-- 2.4 gigahertz doesn't work anymore.
Because there's so much crap on it.
Yeah.
I think basically it's just my smoke alarms and
my bathroom scale are on it at this point.
One of those things are really important and shouldn't lose Wi Fi ever.
Exactly. Well, that's the other reason. Yeah.
Um, but yeah, so, I mean, I know it's just, it's,
but I will say for the Rs A, like on the Expo show floor with, like,
God knows how many people
and, you know, vendors and exhibitors and all that other stuff.
Like the Wi Fi worked pretty decently.
You know, like you were able to check email, you were able to look at youtube videos.
It was, it worked.
It was pretty quick considering all the devices spamming the Wi Fi spectrum there.
It,
it was and I will admit that I was guilty to using the
conference Wi Fi at one point when I lost my GSM signal.
So
it was functional
again.
I just, I have that security posture of like, I'm bathing in a, you know, Ebola virus,
bathing in Ebola virus.
-- That's
-- awesome.
You know, if it doesn't kill me, it'll make me stronger or, you know,
my bank account will get cleaned out next week
-- or
-- it will slowly kill you. Right. And you'll be homeless and that might kill you. So,
yeah, winter is almost over. It'll be ok.
Right.
Yes. Just get on a train and, and hobo your way south. It'll be fine.
That's actually a topic we should do for a podcast. But, um,
so,
yeah, yeah,
it's a new movement. But, uh, anyways going back to RS A and so.
-- No,
-- no, no, you can't. No, no, you can't do the, there's a hobo
movement where people are getting on trains and going places.
Yeah. Like, it's like a hipster thing now.
Right.
-- So, it's like there was a vice documentary on it. I mean, there's a documentary,
-- I
don't know what to think of that.
I, I have a feeling
that
being a hobo
is viewed with a certain amount of nostalgia, like on TV.
And in the movies and even in newspapers and what not. But
if I had to guess in reality it's terrible.
And I wonder how many of these people are, like,
beaten to death or robbed or something worse because there are, like,
there are real hobos
and then there's these, like,
spoiled Children who decided to, you know, jump on a train driving past one day and,
and they had no idea what that means.
Wow. Now, but at the same time, part of me wants to, like,
no, I'm not, I'm not investigating.
No, I'm not doing it. Goodness. No, I, I'd end up dead behind a train on day two.
I, I'm completely certain of that.
No. No, I'm more thinking of.
Ok. Anyway, let's move on because we don't need to get in this.
Yes. RSA, a security conference. I've heard of
So, you know, one, so there's a couple of interesting things I know.
See here, number one,
a big Chinese presence on the show floor, there was
a
not just like providers,
not just like traditional sort of network providers and stuff,
but sort of like these, these technology parks
with representing like 10 or 12 companies, you know.
Um
so yeah, there must have been a total of several dozen
-- Chinese firms represented there.
-- It was big and there was also Korea had an area
as
Pavilion
-- Germany always has their Pavilion
-- Germany does,
but I don't remember Korea or China from the past.
So that's very cool.
And um the other thing was, is a couple of the larger ones.
Uh So the way it works at RS A is you have some of these booths when I say booth,
like some of these are 40 by 40 ft with like two stories,
right?
So calling it a booth is kind of like calling, you know, a mcmansion like a dwelling.
Um It's factually correct, but nowhere near reality
anyway.
So some of these bigger ones actually
explicitly have like little Blockchain areas,
you know.
So Blockchain is a thing.
Um What was interesting to me also was like
the no talk of encrypted email,
barely any talk of like firewalls. Uh I don't, I mean, Arbor
was there and a couple others,
but there wasn't really that much of like sexy ideas or, you know,
intrusion detection or prevention or, you know, whatever.
It's just sort of a given now and now.
And the new hotness by far though, I think you'll agree. Machine learning.
Uh, machine learning was everywhere, man. It is.
It was crazy. And end points are huge.
That's, that's how things are now.
Yeah. No, I, I get it now. The thing, I wonder though quite often is
how many of these endpoint solutions actually work
and how many are selling you a fancy blinky box?
I, you know, that's tough. Right? Because
they, they all do such different things, right? Some of them are just sort of,
you know, basically glorified VPN clients,
really.
Some of them are antivirus. Some of them,
you know,
some of them are kind of clever in that they'll try and figure out
like what version of software you're running and if you're too out of date,
it won't let you on the network or through the VPN or whatever,
you know.
So that's part of the problem is this,
this whole Endpoint solution thing is such a huge space right now.
That's not well defined
and they all do machine learning.
Right.
-- Yes,
-- of course.
Oh, man,
-- it was.
-- I
personally,
I don't think Endpoint security is going to work long term for two simple facts.
Number one, bring your own device.
People aren't gonna want to load this garbage on the device and let you remote,
wipe it.
And number two,
it doesn't protect against what is a lot of the real problems,
like things like fishing?
Right. Phishing will only be solved when there are no more people
actually.
Uh, I do know, uh,
there's a local government entity and they solve the phishing problem.
Generally.
Uh, you can't access your email or any of their services remotely.
You have to be physically in the office on a terminal.
That's not.
-- No,
-- they've gone old school.
That's crazy though. I mean, no organization can operate like that.
-- The government can, well,
-- maybe they even, they even, they can't,
let's face it even, they can't.
But even, even if you're internal,
you can still be fish.
Well, true. But it's, it's harder to exfiltrate data. Right?
Because you're not checking it from your phone or your laptop at home or whatever.
Maybe, I don't know, man. That, that sounds
if
you,
if you can,
you know, well, it, it's part of, you know, it's just, it simplifies everything,
right.
But
it might simplify things. But in a lot of organizations you will
decrease
productivity so much.
You might as well just fire those people and not refill the positions.
Well, I mean, that's one of the beauties of the government, right?
They, in many cases have a captive market for their services.
Well, I mean, that part is true.
They, they have a monopoly on whatever it is they do in most instances. But
-- I, I cannot agree with that. I,
-- I,
no, my personal take on it is I, I've just like with the cloud security lines, I,
I don't,
I don't even know or really to be honest
care what people have is their endpoint devices.
And that's the way the world is heading
and by adopting that security posture. Right.
It's just, it, it makes life harder but also easier in many ways.
Well, and that's exactly the right way to look at it. Right. Is
when you try to constrict what people can do
by saying you have to come into the office,
you can only check email from these machines.
You have to log in in this way.
What you're doing now is you're setting yourself up for failure because
you are expecting a certain use case and let's face it,
the bad guys,
they break all the rules
and so they're just,
they're gonna find a way around this and they're gonna
work within the confines of whatever you've set up.
And my guess
is these security people that put all these crazy rules in place,
they're sitting back thinking
everything's ok. You know, it's like that it's a dog commercial or, or the dog comic.
I mean, where it's, this is fine and everything's on fire and,
you know, that's the thing is if you expect hostility,
you're going to be in a better place than the person who
thinks they've solved some of these problems when they really haven't.
Well, it just makes me laugh because they've gone back to a 1999
network security. Like we have a strong perimeter, we have firewalls,
we
only trusted systems internally. And it's like, uh huh.
Right. Let's face it.
Unless you're essentially whitelisting outbound connections,
you're wasting your time.
Well, it gets worse than that because for example,
their policy on USB keys and stuff is that you're supposed to encrypt them
and if you don't know how to talk to your data protection officer,
-- right. That's totally legit. So
-- there's no actual technical control that
-- enforces that or ensures it.
-- God bless the government,
you know. So
yeah, so when I say data ex filtration is harder, it's not,
definitely not impossible.
But
yeah.
So,
-- you
-- know, but
no,
it's really what always fascinates me too is like some of
these companies on the show floor like PK Ware was there.
Like I, I had no idea they were still around.
Yes, I, I think I got a pen from them last time I saw them at a show
and
who buys that stuff? Like who buys their product?
-- I mean,
-- I assume somebody does or they, I mean, ssh, is there too, right?
Like they, they clearly have a business.
I think it feeds into that, you know,
that article about FTP security and FTP needs to die is that, you know,
people are still using FTP and, well, I guess the answer is yes, you know,
mainframes and batch processing
-- because who else would be using FTP. Just
-- don't use FTP. Look
the, the answer. And this is for all of you out there.
If you're using FTP today, stop stop now because it sucks.
It's kind of what it comes down to.
Uh, the article you refer to talks about Java and Python
where they, they kind of have the, the firewall crossing FTP issues.
And
I mean, this has always been a problem with FTP is FTP.
Historically speaking, way back in the day, kind of used two ports
for transferring files and you connect to the server and you
give it instructions and then it would essentially connect back to you
and feed you the files,
which is crazy to think about
well, but it also had capabilities like you could connect to an FTP server
and then tell that server to connect to another
server and move or retrieve the files there,
right?
So what you have to remember is FTP was built back in a time where you know,
you were connecting to the server over like
300 bod dial up like so
300 bod dial up for those of you that don't know,
we're talking about 300 characters per second, not 300 kilobits per second,
not 300 megabits per second,
but 300 like A's or B's or C's or D's per second.
It was fantastic, man, you could watch the screen refresh line by line.
Yeah, those were the good old days. Right.
And so FDP was actually pretty clever in that you could use it
to
well transfer files, obviously,
file transfer protocol and they like over engineered it so that you could
use it to connect to a server and,
-- you know, send files to and from other servers.
-- Right.
Right.
And then
this whole,
because of the way it works,
all these firewall people basically built rules
that let FTP function in their environments.
And it's bonkers though how everything works together.
And these firewalls assume
that if there's incoming traffic in a certain way,
you're probably running FTP
or, or whatever, you know,
as it pays attention to the connections going in and out and, and it's kind of crazy.
And so,
I mean, I would say if you're a security minded individual, first of all,
disable all of the stupid FTP rules on your firewall.
That's like step one, right? Because
whatever you're doing with NAT or even not nat,
the firewall is probably too smart for its own good.
And then additionally, if you have FTP services in house, like just turn them off,
seriously, turn them off, you don't need them.
I was just checking and it's uh I don't know if you remember Dan
Kaminsky,
I'm familiar with Dan.
Yeah.
So I was just trying to remember cause I remember he did some work on this,
uh basically punching through firewalls using things like FTP.
Uh And his presentation is from 2001
Oh man, that's before he broke the internet. Right.
Yeah.
So,
-- no, I, cause I've known, I, you know, this FTP problem, it goes back a way.
-- It's,
it's always been there and it's not a secret.
I mean, the old school people who've been around forever. Yeah.
I mean, I remember setting this crap up. It was,
I've always hated FTP.
Oh, I remember having to, you know,
I remember the transition in Linux from a state or a stateless firewall to a state
full firewall and all of a sudden poof F TB clients worked and it was just,
I do
remember that.
I mean, that's one of the reasons I despised FTP was because
when you try to use it across firewalls it never worked. Right.
And,
yeah, whatever, I guess,
I guess it's a funny thing is if you're around long enough ago
you avoid FTP because you, you hated it because it never worked.
But, and then it started working and now it's like, oh, crap,
turn this stuff off just because you don't need it.
Well, that's what I've noticed in information securities.
We, we, we're doomed to keep
learning the lessons of the past
because
we basically had something painful that we made most of the pain go
away and then somebody found a new way to make it painful,
-- you know, is really what it boils down to.
-- I know
exactly what you mean.
It's, uh, but, yeah, so,
I, you know,
Yeah, I know, I agree with you, turn off FTP wherever you can but the reality is,
you know, people have mainframes and stuff and, uh,
they're probably not going to be supporting web devs
or whatever
is, if you have a mainframe and you have to somehow do FTP to it, that's fine.
But then set up like a special dedicated network
just for the mainframe and just for your FTP,
like,
people should not be coming in off the
internet connecting to your mainframe via FTP.
Funnily enough that
I know a lot of this
process
works, especially with credit card
and
don't know, don't, I don't need to know this. Just know
the answer is no. If FDP is your solution,
you clearly do not understand your problem.
-- Well,
-- you asked the wrong question, I
guess maybe I don't know, just
no, no more. FTP.
So and
oh, well,
I guess asking the wrong question leads to the
next thing that was really annoying to you.
Which thing, the cryptographer panel from R
A,
the cryptographer panel.
So I, I will post a link to the proper cryptographer panel session
in the show notes.
But
there, there's a couple of article here that, that,
that pick on two things they talk about and they're,
they're really interesting topics for very different reasons.
And so the first being
that the cryptographers scoff at the idea of law enforcement
overcoming encryption and overcome is in quotes in this case,
and so
that's such a loaded word
and it was a very loaded conversation.
And, but here's the problem is these guys basically came to the conclusion of
encryption
experts.
Well, well,
they are cryptography experts. All right.
I,
I will not disregard these people for their
contributions to humanity because they have potentially done more
to further progress on the internet than anyone else ever. OK.
But here's the deal is
they're saying, oh,
we don't have to worry about law enforcement because crypto is
coming from all over the world and these algorithms already exist.
And if, if the USA
tries to put in backdoors or whatever, then,
you know, they'll, they'll lose all their business and blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah.
You know, the thing is they're not wrong,
OK? These guys aren't wrong,
but the bigger problem I see is that many of
the people in a position to define this policy,
they don't know what they're talking about and nobody,
and I guess here, here's the issue is the people who understand,
aren't being heard by them.
-- Now,
-- when you say the people who understand, I see to me what it boils down to is we're,
we're actually looking at cryptography through two different realities.
One is a technical reality
and the other one is a government law making policy reality.
And so these
two things can be totally different.
Well, well, they are,
they are totally different and this is exactly where I was going with,
this is the fact that
the people who understand the problems don't use the words,
the policymakers understand.
And so
they're gonna listen to someone that makes sense.
And in most instances,
I think the people who make sense have some sort of alternative agenda.
And
so they talk about things like, oh, let's backdoor encryption.
But the reality is
that would be a massive problem
and, and let's face it if you know that a US firm is shipping backdoor encryption,
nobody outside the US is going to buy those products.
Right.
Well, that's,
that's assuming it isn't actually actively
made illegal in these foreign countries.
I mean,
no offense.
But if China was shipping back door cryptography, I'm pretty sure the FTC or the
man
-- would have something to say about that.
-- They flip out.
Well, not only that, here's, the other issue is the people who are,
will say being targeted
by law enforcement here,
they're gonna know how to get around this stuff because
you're not gonna use a backdoor product.
I mean, yeah, you're gonna catch a bunch of idiot criminals,
which is kind of how it always works.
But anyone with a clue is just going to, you know, like download
this, this pains me to say, but you know, like download P GP or GP G off the internet,
right?
As crappy as it is. It's not backdoor. Well, that we know of.
Yeah.
Well, and, and there was that famous quote, you know,
from that NSA slide basically saying that they love,
you know, people who use P GP because they stand out.
Right.
Right. I mean,
the,
you know, I mean, that's one of the things I like about signal is, you know,
lots of people are using signal, normal people are using signal,
normal people do not use GP G end of story,
you know, and,
and the reality is that metadata piece is far more
interesting in many cases than the actual content of the message
metadata
doesn't matter, didn't you hear?
Oh, right. Yeah. Ok.
So you'll just uh
so I'm sure every elected official will just be
sending us a copy of their cell phone billing
with the uh minute by minute, you know, who's making phone calls to and from them.
I'm sure
that'll happen.
Um I know, man,
you know, I'm, well, it's like that thing on Facebook, right?
Based on like what is it like 20 or 30 likes.
They can basically tell if you know what your sexual orientation is
statistically.
Well, I'm pretty sure, you know,
given somebody's monthly cell phone bill and location data, you could,
you could probably, well, I mean,
you could identify them personally without too much trouble based on, you know,
where their phone sleeps for eight hours a day.
But
even without that, you know, I'm pretty sure based on these things, you could,
you could probably,
you know,
bucket a person demographically without too much trouble.
Oh, without a doubt I have, I have no doubt of that.
So, so anyway, but back to the topic is
so, so the crypto people,
uh, they doubt law enforcement can overcome encryption
being
there.
They,
they don't think the concept of a back door will ever
become a reality because of the technical things they know.
And I think
the idea of a back door terrifies me because of the technical things.
The policymakers don't know
and I don't know how this can be bridged where you need
to get policymakers talking to the technical people who understand this.
But on the other side,
you need these technical people
not to get buried in the weeds.
See, the, I think part of the challenge is, is cryptography is such a fundamentally
different technology than previous security technologies like say,
uh well, because where,
where people keep going back to is comparing encryption to like locks and safes,
right?
And, and no, but that's fundamentally what they keep doing
and that is wrong.
Well, it is, but we're hairless monkeys and we need things we understand,
we understand
locks and
safes.
Exactly.
And like a lock in a safe, like no matter how good a lock or a safe you build, give me,
you know,
the right drilling equipment or cutting equipment and
I'll eventually get in right end of story.
Um, you know, no matter how many booby traps,
no matter how many crazy things you do with it.
Uh Well, that's not true.
Actually there was that case where that, remember that guy built a bomb,
put it in a casino, held them, you know, for ransom.
And then, uh, the FBI, you know, was like, well, we can't diffuse this thing.
So good luck,
you know, we're just going to evacuate the building. Right. And then the,
yeah, but, uh, fundamentally, you know, cryptography doesn't work that way,
especially when you start combining it with, you know, chip
uh hardware, like,
you know, like the apple chips with their trust store
where, you know, long term, I, I assume they're going to move to a model of like,
you know,
the the crypto key is buried in the
silicon that's really hard to physically extract.
And if you talk to it and get it wrong 10 times, you know, it commits suicide
basically, right? Digital suicide.
And it's not like you can easily copy this chip like you can a hard drive.
So we're,
we're actually now approaching the point where I can
build essentially a machine based on math and hardware
that you can't break into reasonably,
you know, short of some sort of magic chip cloning technology.
So you can brute force it
or, you know, something along like essentially the hand wavy magic lines of attack
and you know it, and that's something hard for people to understand.
It's like, literally, I can build
this thing and it,
if it's done correctly.
It cannot be compromised,
full stop.
I mean, fundamentally, yes,
that, that is correct.
I mean, we have an entire FS
140 certification based around this whole premise.
Right? Tamper evident, tamper resistant tamper proof,
you know, 1 40.12 and three, I think
so. And, and those standards are, what decades old at this point?
Well, they, they keep updating though.
Well, no, what I mean is that this is not a new idea,
this is something the US government itself came
out with and officially documented and made a standard
for the stuff they want to use. That is correct.
So that, that, that's what I mean is these policymakers, it's kind of like guys,
you know, a bunch of other policymakers made these laws like decades ago
that basically, you know, are shooting to do exactly what you want to do.
That's the thing is
these aren't really laws, they're,
they're standards that were arrived to by technical smart people.
Yeah.
But I mean, essentially that policy wasn't, you know, there,
there's this intended policy of building devices that can't be compromised.
Yes, that's fair. That's fair.
It's man.
And I guess the other part of it though too,
and the thing I always think of that isn't well
understood and may never be well understood is the fact that
in modern crypto
they never break the crypto,
they always find an alternative means to gain the data they need.
And this always, I mean,
I kind of always bring this back to World War Two when you think about,
you know, the, the good guys breaking the,
the secret code of the bad guys and then because of it, we won the war or whatever.
And
that made sense back then because
there wasn't good peer review of this crypto
crypto.
The enigma was based on, was, was fatally flawed,
-- flawed.
-- Exactly.
-- And,
-- and,
and what's funny is the US tidied up those flaws
and then used that crypto for 10 or 20 years,
right?
And this is the thing, right?
This is the beauty of most of the crypto we use
today is it's been peer reviewed in the public space.
So we understand what it's good at.
We understand what it's bad at and there's always research happening
to
decide if something is still good enough.
And additionally, to find the new things that are going to bring us to the next place
and that's really powerful. And additionally, I mean, adding a back door
man, back doors don't work. I mean, that's the reality of it.
The problem with backdoors is depending on how you do it.
Fundamentally, you either have like a universal key which is going to leak
or you have like
or you have like per device or per session keys,
which now means you're into the whole
whole mess of credential and authentication management,
which let's face it if we could do that.
Well, we could also do like identity management.
Well,
and everybody would have a correct identification and we would
know who everybody is and we're certainly not there.
No, not at all. Not at all.
I mean, the only way to do this is to essentially weaken the crypto
at which point it means the, the bad guys
gain the same benefits.
We would have
already
happened with
the tools I believe it was the, the tools of the technique the FBI used for that.
Um I want to say, was it San Bernardino shooter?
Uh Many
months
ago,
that was the,
what was the name of that company?
Uh
-- uh
-- Anyways, apparently those, those tools and stuff leaked.
-- They
-- did because they, well, it,
it got out who helped them and then obviously
that company got attacked and is it celebrate,
maybe
celebrate
tool
and then someone hacked them and release the tools.
And not only that, look at all the NSA dumps, I mean,
these are organizations that are supposedly the best of
the best and they can't keep their stuff secret.
So,
how on earth are you going to keep a secret? Key secret?
Right.
-- No way. Just it,
-- especially
-- when you intend to use it on a constant basis.
-- Exactly.
It's just, it is an impossible
problem. And this kind of also comes back to the idea of
law enforcement has other means to accomplish the things they need to do.
-- It's not just about, it's
-- actually easier than that.
It's, for example, the UK Rip Act.
If you don't give up your passwords, they just chuck you in jail.
Problem solved.
No, like, really? Right. Like if, you know,
if you're, if, if they think you're a bad guy and they have, you know, reasonable,
you know, assumption for that
in most jurisdictions now, if you're not willing to play ball with them,
they just chuck you in jail for hindering.
I'm not going to get into the, the politics of that decision.
Well, no,
but what I'm pointing out is that even if you
have good crypto and refuse to give up the password,
they can, you know that that's not going to prevent, you know,
it's all these people that are like, oh ha ha ha,
I will clean my device and walk across the border and if they try and search it,
they will find nothing ha ha ha I will outsmart them and it's like,
no, they can just bounce you out of the border for any reason. They feel
like that. You know what I mean? Like
that's
true.
Don't, but you can't mock those people because it's one thing to,
for example, go through airport security
with, with, we'll say normal gear. And it's another if you have like a switch for,
are we talking about airport security? Are we talking about,
I'm just using airport security as my example,
right? Like
you can make good decisions that will lower your odds of getting in trouble.
And I, I think that's, that's a difference. Right.
Is people need to understand that cleaning your gear
at a border crossing.
If you're up to no good, like, you're probably still gonna get in trouble. Right.
Whether you have the
right.
But if you,
it's another thing to also just, you know,
make sure you're not carrying that switchblade through security because if they
look for it and they find it now they're gonna be like,
what are you doing?
It's like, yeah, I use this to clean my toenails, you know, and like,
they're not gonna believe you.
Yeah. Well,
the analogy kind of breaks down because, you know, social media passwords,
for example, right?
You don't necessarily carry those with you, like,
you don't carry your Facebook account with
you because it's what's a Facebook account.
And that's another crazy political problem that I have no intention of addressing
my, my view on it is, uh, historically speaking, the majority of the world, you know,
when you go and try and enter their country,
they have the legal right to search you and your person
and your baggage and belongings.
And I, I can see definitely that, you know,
um,
for example, when I've entered the US, when I was younger, they would ask, you know,
they would want to make sure I had enough money
and I'd be like, well, I have a credit card and they're like, oh, ok.
You know?
Right.
But,
but they basically want to make sure I don't become like destitute
in a word of the state and cost the US taxpayer money.
And, you know,
that makes sense.
So, you know, at what point, where do we draw that line? Social media, do we? You know?
Um,
and that's, you know, and so historically, legally they've had,
the president has been said that they can search through all this stuff.
And so that's,
that's the reality of it.
And if you don't want to play ball with them, then you don't get to enter the country,
you know, it's, it's because it's a privilege, not a right.
So I think fundamentally what it comes down to is that
existing law
hasn't kept up with reality.
And so
you look at the people on the front lines,
people like your border patrol and your law enforcement and, and whoever else
they will use whatever tool they can
to do the best job they think they can do.
Right. But it's also up to policymakers
to rein them in a little bit and make sure they aren't doing things that are,
we'll say willfully dangerous to a free functional society.
-- And I think we're at a point
-- now,
news for you
go read Bill C 23.
But it essentially, it,
so in, in one of the nice things about Canada us, right?
Is we have a long standing cozy relationship.
So, for example, when I fly from Canada to the U si clear US customs in Canada. Right.
There's eight major airports that have this,
I've done that before.
And so it's, it's lovely. Right, because you clear customs here in Canada.
And that means you can fly like some tiny little regional
air jet or whatever to like anywhere in the US,
you know, so you can fly to airports that don't have customs and immigration,
which is awesome.
It's way more efficient,
but I don't have to worry about leaving like six hours between connections.
Exactly. Who knows what customs is like?
So anyways, they're, they're looking at passing a bill C 23. Um
that would essentially give us border,
immigration controls more rights in Canada, including, you know, for example,
they could um arrest
people in Canada
like you're physically in Canada, but you're not
legally jurisdictionally speaking in Canada,
when you're clearing us customs here,
it becomes one of those quasi
constitution free airport
wonky zones,
you know, where it's, it's just, it's not clear what's going on.
Um Traditionally we've had the right in Canada if
I don't like how things are going with the,
the, the immigrations,
I can leave
like, and, and just say like, you know what, this is not going well,
I don't want to answer your questions.
I would like to leave now. Interesting
and that right will potentially be going away with this new bill.
And it's also murky at what point does the US, for example,
what point do their questions become lawful orders?
Right? Like sir, please stay, please answer my question,
you know. And
so, you know, we, you want to talk about these things getting just messy and weird.
I mean, now we're talking about not just legalities but like cross jurisdiction,
legalities between countries.
That's crazy, man,
you know.
Um but fundamentally what I and I hate to say this but generally speaking, you know,
if you're a good guy, you probably won't get hassled that much.
The flip side being is what is the definition of a good guy?
I know.
And so let's actually let's tie that statement right there into the next thing
that gave me Harper from this cryptographer's panel is right is
they basically said they,
they disregarded the importance of artificial intelligence and machine learning
in terms of security. And that right there. I was like, holy cow guys. Like
what?
Just
stop talking, you know, don't,
don't talk anymore because now there's two sides to this.
All right. So number one is
there are organizations that are claiming A I and machine learning
will save the world
and they will solve any problem you have.
It's a bit like uh
the joke I heard at RS A was that there's machine learning washing
where it used to be cloud washing back in the day right now.
Everyone's oh, we're machine learning, you know, we run Grep or whatever in,
in my tool.
But the thing is, here's the thing,
if you look at kind of all of the A I research happening
on the edge on the fringe today,
it is crazy, amazing stuff.
And I think to disregard that
as not being a big deal, especially for security is very dangerous. And I think
this is one of those instances where these guys
should have been smart enough to either say,
you know, I don't know or
let's talk to someone who does,
you know,
-- it
-- really reminds me of sort of the whole prior to the.com boom in the web taking off,
you know, that period 9598 where,
yeah, a lot of people didn't really think the web was going to amount to much.
And it was pretty clear to me that like, no, this is like, wow, this is amazing
and it was even,
it was even way more cool and important than I could have ever imagined.
Oh, absolutely. Absolutely. And you know.
Right. Well, I mean, look at, look at Microsoft. Right.
They did, I mean, so funny enough, uh Bill gates' book,
uh the Road ahead is it? I think
I have a first edition copy of it
and
they,
they actually got rid of most of the first editions because in it,
there's a whole chapter where Bill Gates basically
disregards the importance of the internet and talks about
like these private networks people are creating
and I, I loved reading it.
And I remember II, I bought it after,
uh,
kind of Windows 95 and everything went crazy.
And I remember reading this thinking, like this guy could not have got it more wrong.
I mean, just completely wrong. But that, that's part of the trick, right? Is
when you have someone who kind of got to where they are in a certain way,
they will oftentimes struggle to deal with the new.
-- So paradigm
-- shifts are tough.
I mean, it's not even that you don't understand the paradigm shift.
It's that this is a fundamentally new reality. Right. Exactly.
Like, when I talk to people, I'm like,
my concern is not that 50% of people will be unemployed in 30 years because of a, I's,
it's that 50% of people will be unemployable
and
a lot of them don't get it.
Well, and a lot of them don't understand. They're like, what do you mean? I'm like,
they will not be able to get a job like the, the value out of that human being
will be insufficient.
It, the, you know, unless they get, like,
you will have to have some very niche specialty or whatever,
you know,
something that machines are bad at or that we
don't allow machines to do for policy or whatever,
you know, that
humans can do. Right. And a
lot of these people don't think that's the case.
They think, you know, white collar, like selling houses.
Oh, you know, you need a real estate agent. Well, have you heard of com Free?
I hate dealing with real estate agents.
Yeah. You know,
like car sales, like, why, why is car sales the way it is?
-- Why am I not doing this on Amazon?
-- I agree with you 100%.
I just bought a car and it was just like, oh, this sucks.
I don't want to deal with these people.
So, I mean, that's, that's what gets me is these paradigm shifts. You know, even I
acknowledge this paradigm shift, but fundamentally,
I don't understand what 50% unemployability means.
Well, none of us do. We have no idea. And,
and let's
even if we ignore that
and we just think about artificial intelligence in the context of security,
you think about how much security do we do today
is the problem is really people are slow
more than anything.
And here's an example is aunt at defcon last year.
Uh DARPA,
they funded this program where they basically had a bunch of a is
fighting each other like playing big capture the flag where you had defenders,
you had Attackers and, and they
remember that
and
it was amazing to read about what these things were doing. I mean, you had
like a defender would essentially new malware would come in.
We do a quick analysis of the malware,
understand what's going on and then block that attack
like
this, this would happen in like a second or less.
And you think, how long would it take a human to do that months?
Maybe, like if, if you're good, it might take you a month.
I mean, you gotta think about stuff like that and,
and no additionally on the other side, you have Attackers, obviously, you know,
finding and creating new flaws faster than any human could possibly hope to do it.
And
like this is what's terrifying about this stuff is
you could conceivably have machines.
I mean, it's kind of like high frequency trading in the stock market, right,
where you have machines, making more decisions in a second
than a human could make in a lifetime.
And it's the same deal with security is
once these a is breach a certain point,
we will be unable to deal with them because they
will be so far past the realm of human understanding.
And it's,
it's kind of terrifying to be quite honest with you.
And I don't want to turn into like, you know, this is the future of our,
our dystopian A I.
But like this is something to think about in the context of security. And I think,
you know,
a bunch of old cryptographers trying to blow this off is not the right
message to be sending the right message is we need to pay attention to this
and we need to have a clue of what's going on here because if you don't,
there's going to be trouble
unquestionably
totally. I mean, it's like cloud, right?
Cloud is economically more efficient than all the previous systems.
Therefore, it will win
because if you don't do cloud,
somebody else will do cloud and be more
efficient than you and they will eat your lunch
and the same will happen with machine learning and
A I and Blockchain and a bunch of other technologies
whether or not you think these are good or bad or stupid,
somebody else will find a way to make it work.
Like, look at the social networks, right? I, I
remember when I first saw Amazon and I was like, oh, so they sell books on
and they lose money doing it. That's,
and now I buy like all my dental floss and toothbrushes and like,
what did I just buy um Children, you know, I basically buy everything.
I actually have a policy now of Amazon first
and I will
go
well for food and stuff, but like basically for,
-- for anything that is not clothes or
-- food,
right?
They do.
But like, it's way overpriced and you know, getting so like eggs and milk and bread,
you know, I need to go to the store for that.
Still.
Can I order eggs from Amazon? I should look into this. That could be fun to do.
Yeah.
Um but yeah, so I mean,
you know, it's just
that, yeah,
the reality is people are going to figure out how to use machine learning or A I
and the companies that don't are gonna get clobbered,
especially in the security world. Right?
Like Amazon buying Harvest dot IO to make security decisions about, you know,
this person doing this is safe, this person doing this.
Well, that's an attacker
there.
Yeah, humans are physically incapable of doing that,
let alone doing it cost effectively.
Yeah. Ok. That's, you know, I'll agree with that because
there are people who read log files for a living
and
I can't imagine a worse job. I'm sorry.
-- One event, a 2nd, 10 events a second,
-- not only after like five minutes,
are you actually paying attention? Actually?
You know what's really funny is I just saw a news story the other day
where
apparently Ford is skipping over the uh self driving car
stage where you have an engineer sitting behind the wheel,
like ready to take over because their engineers kept falling asleep because
they were so bored.
Well, see, and this is my concern is
like we've,
I watch a lot of airline disaster documentaries and this is one
of the biggest problems with airline automation is they're not 100% automated.
So you still have the, the cases where the people have to interact and do stuff
and you end up with situations like those self
green pilots flying their plane into San Francisco Airport,
like into the,
into the side of the um, the embankment
because they just came in too low. Oops,
you know,
um, or like this other case where they just, um,
they flew into the side of a hill and it's the cockpit voice recorder recorded.
The first officer, like, basically saying, I think we're doing this wrong.
I think we're pointed at the hill and the first or the pilots, like, no, we'll be fine,
you know, and then, like, yeah, they, you know, like four survivors or whatever.
And, and so I think with self driving cars we have to,
it's either all or nothing because anything in the middle.
Yeah, people are gonna zone out and read the paper.
Yeah, I, I agree. I agree completely.
And I think the, the sooner we stop letting people do stuff like this the better.
And, you know, that's one of the funny things too is people say to me, oh,
do you trust a computer to fly the plane?
I'm like, well, it already does. But yes, I do more than the human that does it today
because, like, oh, we should put a link to that traffic court guy.
The traffic court guy.
Oh,
you
mean the
people
out of traffic tickets?
No, no, no, no, no, no. The New Jersey judge.
So this guy, uh, it's a New Jersey judge,
um,
and he does traffic court and it's like, um,
he, you know, he's like, ok,
so you're charged with running a red light and the guy's like, no, I didn't.
And the judge is like, ok, can we please, you know, have evidence clip number? 27436.
Can you play it? Thanks.
And they play a clip from the red light camera of
like this guy in a car driving through a red light
and the human is like, oh,
I didn't see the red light
or, you know, some, you know what I mean?
Like,
and it's like every time people bring up like self driving cars and trusting them,
I'm, like,
go check how many, like, red light tickets were issued, you know? I mean,
yeah,
and I've, I've actually seen it, like, I was driving once, uh, here on Stony and
I saw the red light camera go off on 1/70 and then it was like, two blocks in front of me.
And then by the time I got there there was a minivan on its side and another car,
you know, off in the weeds,
you know, like, it's like, oh, awesome. You know, like
people run red lights and kill each other, you know, like,
people
somehow don't trust machines.
I know
what
I mean. I know
exactly. Well,
it's,
people are afraid of new and interesting and the same thing with the A I,
people are afraid of giving up control.
That that's a big part of it.
And,
but all of this, you know,
you're mentioning 50% of the population of the unemployable.
And we're saying we need to pay attention to a I with security and
there is the self driving vehicles now that are kind of becoming a thing.
And
the other thing that will be really interesting about all this is
there are going to be unintended consequences to all of this technology.
An example being
they expect self driving cars will decimate the auto insurance industry.
And how many municipalities make a significant
amount of their income off of traffic violations
or what about organ donation is another one, most organ donors were in
auto fatalities.
And so you think about there's all these things you can't imagine. No, no.
Granted, I'm not saying that
less people dying in car crashes is a bad thing, right? Because
without question,
less organ donors is a a fundamentally good thing for society because it was
on
car crashes,
right? And, and hopefully we keep someone alive who
is going to figure out how to grow new livers or whatever in, in the lab.
But you get the idea is
there's gonna be all this crazy stuff that happens. We can't imagine.
And, and this is,
this is the thing I wonder is you
think about the industrial revolution when you had all
of these people moving from essentially rural farm
work in two cities to work in factories.
And
people couldn't imagine what the future was going to be.
And one of my favorite examples is there was some futurist at one point said,
you know,
New York City can't get any bigger because we don't
know where to put the horse maneuver and it's like,
right, good job buddy.
But, you know, that's the thing is there's these,
all this stuff we can't imagine yet.
And, but it makes me wonder,
are, are the things that are going to happen? We don't understand nor can imagine.
Are they going to be enough to deal with the disrupted
change from all of this kind of new A I future
that is in store?
I don't know.
I, I think like, anything, you're gonna have some people who embrace it,
some people who sort of deal with it and people who try and fundamentally ignore it
or, you know, go back to a, a golden time
and, and, you know, we're already seeing that with this sort of automation,
you know, like, or like, uh, with coal, you know,
the coal industry in a lot of the world has flat out accepted that they are
obsolete and they're gonna go away.
Yes. A lot of the people dealing with them haven't,
which
I kind of get it because it's, it's difficult
to say this my whole life is this
and now
it's the last 150 years of this town's history.
Yeah, maybe more in some cases. Exactly.
Like, I mean,
we literally, you know, any, I, I see
jobs and, you know, things where these are like, literally, that's,
that's what keeps this town alive and then boom, you know,
the whole factory gets moved to China or just gets automated.
Right. And then people get mad
and,
well, and funny enough too.
I mean, so one of the things,
this is numerous economists in the United States have talked about this is
even if they bring the factories back, like a lot of people talk about, you know,
the robots are going to run them.
It's not going to be people.
-- So it doesn't really make a difference,
-- fundamental
American wages.
I mean,
well, just at all.
Right, why, even,
even in low cost areas now they're adding more and more automation because,
you know, amazingly, computers do a better job than people who knew.
Right.
I mean, it doesn't matter how much you're paying them, people make mistakes,
people get tired,
whatever robots never get tired, robots never make mistakes.
They do exactly the same thing. 365 days a year without stopping
and they don't have to go to the bathroom. I mean,
you can't beat that. Right.
Well, it gets me to even what I find really fundamentally odd is this dichotomy,
the whole premise of information technology is to, like,
automate things to get a computer and software to do it.
And yet the it industry as a whole sort of is
anti
automation. You know,
-- like I said, people who read log files or people who are massaging Excel tables.
-- But
yes, there are people who do that but I don't think anyone wants to do it necessarily.
I think it's the fact that
depending upon what you need to do
there has been a certain difficulty sometimes
getting certain tools and this is actually
where like a I is going to have a certain amount of advantage is
you're gonna be able to describe your problem using words
and it will figure it out.
That's really cool.
-- Yeah. Well, and that's the thing once we cross that bridge. Yeah, I mean,
-- wow.
And then of course we start getting more philosophical and saying things like,
well, then why does, why do you have to tell the A I,
why doesn't one A I tell the other A I what it wants and then you know, whatever.
Well, it's like you saw that uh that logo I made, right for myself, right? And it was,
it was done through a website,
right?
So,
so the deal is this one guy uh graphic designer
built a website that using some very simple A I
build you a logo for kind of whatever you want. Very simplistic logos, obviously.
But essentially you pick kind of the colors you like,
you pick a bunch of logos you like and then it kind of narrows it down
and you know,
offers you some suggestions based on what you like and it does some clever things to
like kind of apply the logo to a business card in a picture with a hand,
somebody handing it to somebody else, you know.
So you can sort of, actually
you don't have to visualize what it might look like.
You can actually see a photo of like,
what it would look like for you to hand this business card to somebody,
you know, which,
and here's the beauty of it. It was like, what, 25 bucks?
And you think this guy set up this infrastructure
and
it's a money tree now, right?
Yeah, he said he was making something like 100 and 80 grand
a year off of it and that's steadily increasing. That's awesome.
You know, and, and, but he's providing this amazing service because like,
for 25 bucks in 5, 10 minutes of poking at a website and saying which of these designs?
I like more.
I've got a logo that I'm ok with. And,
you know, I've tried working in past with designers, I'm willing to pay them and I,
you know,
they ask me for some information and then they disappear off the face of the planet.
Oh, yeah. Or they go off on some insane tangent.
Come back here, please.
And,
and one of the things that gets me with A I
is in many cases we'll get a good enough solution,
but we'll get it in like five minutes
and, and
I,
I can start working with that solution rather than waiting six months
-- for the human to come up with similar or maybe
-- better.
I know exactly what you mean,
and you know,
that first mover advantage and that speed advantage is going to be huge.
Right. And that's what really gets me about this. A I embracement is,
you know,
you start bringing processes down for months and
weeks to maybe days or hours or minutes.
You know, it's, that's a huge advantage.
Let's just hope no one writes a podcasting. A I anytime soon.
I hope they do because then we could just take it easy.
I mean, as long as we own it, as long as we're like the, you know,
what is it going back to Karl Marx and the owners of the Capitol, you know,
we can just sit back and get rich,
whatever. I'm, I'm voting you off the island, Curt.
Oh,
all right, man. It's been, it's been a while. I'm still tired.
I should, I should go take a nap.
-- So,
-- yeah, I gotta say Rs A this year was, you know,
the best way to explain to somebody was
Moscow.
The
Moscow
-- Center has a certain finite size but the, the crowd keeps getting bigger,
-- man.
It was, I don't know what it is,
but this year it just felt exhausting and I can't explain it, but whatever,
it doesn't matter, it was still fun.
I'm glad I went.
So, thank you folks for listening. I appreciate it.
You can go to open source security podcast.com and get these
show notes for all the various things we talked about.
We have links here to hit us up on Twitter and we have a Facebook group. You can join,
I guess. Until next week.
Everyone, you have a fantastic day or week or month or whatever it may be in. Kurt.
Take care, man.
You too, everybody remember to use that Purell.
You're smuggled American pure
right now.