Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast.
Episode 150 with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
-- Josh Pressers. What's new
-- man?
-- Uh
-- Still enjoying the internet without ads for now,
right. That's exciting news, isn't
-- it?
-- Uh I did a, I did a quick set up Firefox and Firefox profiles don't work well.
Like it's not like
chrome where you can, right click, see all your different profiles easily.
Like there's probably some extension I need for Firefox, but it,
it's very frustrating that it doesn't natively do it very well.
Yeah.
There, there's an extension and I don't even, I still prefer the way chrome works,
but no,
I'm in the same boat as you as I am
now running Firefox for all of my personal web browsing.
And would you like to tell the universe why we are talking about this?
-- So
-- apparently,
uh the nut and bolts of it are,
I'm going to give the technical bit first
and then we'll explain what that actually means.
So
there is a change coming to Google Chrome Manifest V three design, do
development blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah blah, blah.
What it boils down to is they are making
the web request handler
observational instead of uh allowing it to actually do stuff.
So why do we care? Well,
web request uh handling allows you to do things like
lock it.
And so you can have an extension that has a list
of domains, URL S patterns, whatever
that it can block like ads.
And for all the people you know, like and don't get me wrong.
There's nothing wrong with like Pie Hole and DNS based ad blocking.
That absolutely works and will block a ton of ads.
But there's more and more sites that also serve ads from
their primary domain or from within their domain making it harder.
You, you just can't do DNS blocking without sacrificing the whole site.
And more to the point,
I just want to install an ad blocker that automatically
gets updated lists and I just don't have to see ads
and same thing for youtube. Right.
When I go to youtube on my tablets, man, it drives me nuts because I'm like, oh yeah,
there's ads,
you youtube feels worse than ever to me lately because
I will often watch youtube videos while I'm at the gym
and I feel like every 30 seconds there's an ad
and it's like I just freaking watched one of these.
It's, it's not only that, ok. The ads at the beginning, I get it, the ads in the middle.
I hate that.
But what's more annoying to me is that a lot of the ads I'm getting are quite
inappropriate
or especially on kids youtube.
Like, whoa. That, yeah.
Like, I keep getting ads for the Alberta government's opioid crisis stuff.
It's like a public message about opioid abuse and where you can go
some website to find out more. Which number one like? Ok.
Well, not really sure what I'm supposed to do with that. Number two.
This is an awkward conversation to be having with my young kids.
You know, and it's kind of annoying, right?
Trying to explain drug abuse and everything to them, which I do plan to do.
But, you know, maybe
not when they're eight,
right?
You know, I'm not sure that that's quite, we need to do it this early.
Um And then plus, you know, both of them are just like, like the one guy just like,
skip a, skip, a skip a and he's like, poking away at it, like,
waiting for that button to, you know,
-- it's got like a five second counter or whatever
-- gives you something to do at least.
So, but I'll be blunt, like, I,
especially when I browse the web on my phone or my tablet now because I
don't have really good ad blocking there and I should probably set up Pie Hole.
But, oh man, I hate it. Like
mostly what I hate is how
slow the web pages are to load. Like cnn.com is especially terrible. Now with ads,
like, it takes a good 30 to 60 seconds for a page to
render on my phone or my tablet.
CNN has ads.
I, I do not know that
I, I haven't looked at it without an ad blocker ever that I can think of.
Oh, they have so many ads and they have like,
all that sponsored crap at the bottom where it's like quasi
official looking content. But
it's like this one simple stretch will, you know,
fix your back or find out how broccoli cured cancer,
you know, like literally like crap like that where it's like, yeah,
this is not II I don't want to see this.
I don't want to go there.
Um
So well, so especially egregious about this chrome,
getting rid of the um the little hook that lets you do a blocking
is they're only getting rid of it in the sort of consumer facing version.
The enterprise version will still have this capability.
My suspicion for that is,
I bet a lot of those terrible
endpoint applications everyone installs use this functionality
to block malicious content.
Yes, absolutely. Well, for a white list and blacklist, right?
Because it used to be very easy to block web content.
You put a box in line with your network and it looked at all the http requests and
served like an error. If it saw one for something, it didn't like,
you know, like playboy.com or whatever. And now
all that stuff's ssl encrypted.
Right. So, you don't know what's going on anymore.
Well, unless you do deep packet inspection and stuff and that stuff's expensive.
Well, and you need to, they have backdoor certificates on clients and there's,
there's so much hassle there.
Just dumping something on the end point is magnitudes easier.
Oh, yeah.
It's not like some technical change that has to be made, you know, it's straight up.
Let's be real.
The majority of Google's revenue still comes from advertising, right.
They have tried
to break free of that trap, you know, like they've restructured the entire company,
right?
You have alphabet now with all the different subsidiaries
trying to make money. But like, what is it, like, 90% or at least 80% of their
-- core revenue is, is all ads?
-- I, I think it's more than 80%. It's a nontrivial amount.
And that's,
I mean, they, they put in their, their Wall Street statements,
their earning statements that ad blockers are a threat to the revenue model.
I mean,
that
says it all.
Well, they absolutely are and like, I don't know if you've noticed,
but when you do a search on Google now, so let, let me do a search for, um,
I don't know, bug repellent.
Why not
summer's coming? It's
now. Well, what's interesting is the ads are no longer labeled as ads.
They used to the, the little green thing. It used to be a little green thing saying ad
now it's like black and it's much less.
Ok. It, yeah, it's, it's not as obvious, but yes,
they, they do at least still call things ads that are ads.
And I feel like there's more,
I used to feel like there was only one ad when I do a search and now I get like,
five or six often.
The, the first page of my browser is ads.
Yeah, exactly.
I've noticed that on mobile,
especially that when I try doing searches for certain things on mobile now it, it,
it doesn't work anymore because it's just ads.
All right.
So anyway, anyway, let's stop whinging about ads because we all hate them.
I, I don't know anyone who says, boy, I sure like mobile ads.
Yeah, they,
they don't exist and there's also questions
about whether these online ads even work,
but that's another story in itself.
And I guess here's the thing
that
I keep going back to on this topic
is Chrome is the dominant browser by quite a lot.
It's about 60 to 80% of the market most places now.
Right. Yes, it's, it's huge. It's a huge number.
And I feel like the reason they got there is they put
a lot of things before
the Google revenue model,
right? They pushed a lot of security features, they allowed plugins to happen.
They, they did all of this work, they made it fast, they did everything and in I,
-- I don't want to say they pulled the rug out from under us, but
-- it's, this
is classic bait and switch it.
-- How is this? Not classic bait and switch?
-- Right.
-- I have a feeling this wasn't the intent. I
-- don't think they planned it from day one.
Ok.
Yes,
I think now it's pretty clear there's higher ups at Google saying you
can't do this because there's no technical reason to make this change.
There's no,
let me put it this way.
-- There's no benefit to anyone or anything for making this change. There's
-- some,
didn't they,
-- they made up some BS reason I think
-- exactly they made some claims about blah, blah,
blah.
But fundamentally, here's the thing.
Fundamentally so, OK, even if that's true,
then why is this still in the corporate version?
Because they're paying you money
and, and in fairness, I remember a time when you paid for a web browser,
like I remember when Netscape Navigator came in a box shrink wrapped with a CD,
it did a CD floppy disks.
-- Would
-- I pay?
Say, I don't know, 1020 bucks a year for a web browser that supports ad blocking.
I would strongly consider it. I don't think Google will give me that option though.
-- That's kind of what's really
-- annoying. They probably won't.
And that also puts you in a certain,
I guess
we say place in society,
-- there's tons of people that can't afford $20 a year for ad
-- blocking.
-- Well, more to the point. I go to a public terminal or something.
-- Right. Right.
And I already feel like we now have two internets
because when I use a computer without an ad blocker,
it's like what
this is, this place, this isn't the internet.
I don't even, it, the websites and everything are horrendous and
it's, I, I know these ad networks serve malware as well.
So, just from a security perspective,
the ad blockers have a huge advantage there ignoring the fact. I mean, there's,
I know there's lots of ethical ramifications and all of this.
-- Well,
-- no, I would actually,
I would strongly disagree with you because ethically speaking,
if a site wants to serve ads and require that you see the ads to see their content,
they can absolutely do that.
That's true.
And, and some do,
I've been to many sites now that say you appear to be running an ad blocker,
you know, blah, blah, blah, money, money, money,
please either turn it off or, or in some cases they just straight up,
don't let you see it
or in other cases. Uh, what is it like the Wall Street Journal now? You know, log in
and pay to see
the content, right.
So, my response is, well, no, I'm not going to, I'm just,
I'm not willing to give up certain levels of privacy and convenience.
So I can, you know, once a month, see an article at the Wall Street Journal.
Yeah, I'm, I'm comfortable with that.
I mean, I, I pay for my local newspaper because I want them to survive and I read
stories and they have one of those after the third story
and it annoys me because I'll forget to log in or something.
Like, oh, you've read your limited stories this month you can't read anymore
-- crap. Where's my password at?
-- So, I, I would point out that
it's, there's no requirement when I, like, when I request a web document from you,
there's no like legal requirement that I fully process it on my computer.
Like, what if I disable javascript? What if I have no script writing?
What if I have an old, what if I'm using E Links and I can't process javascript,
you know.
So my take on that is
no, there's no ethno ethical conundrum. It's straight up like you're a business.
And if you want to make certain requirements
for people to see or consume your content,
go ahead and do so.
Like you're absolutely
able to say no, you can't
see this without logging in and paying money, you can't see this without logging in.
You can't see this with an ad blocker running.
I'll, I'll, I'll let that go.
And I guess,
you know what I would compare it to is there are podcasts I listen to that have ads
and
I always fast forward through them
and I guess you can make the same argument. Am I stealing from them.
I,
I, I don't think so but I won't get into that.
Well, I mean, there's one podcast I listen to and they have the same ad,
every single part and the ad totally doesn't
apply to me because I'm not doing a crypto
market.
Uh, I don't need to do, um, the, you know, the, the know, your customer and anti
money laundering stuff for a crypto exchange.
Ah, I got you. So, like, this ad really doesn't apply to me. Never will. Hopefully
so. Yeah, I mash, the, the, the skip forward 30 seconds a couple of times.
I don't feel terribly bad about it.
Yeah, that's fair. Ok. Ok.
Anyway, anyway, let's, let's move off of the ethical question of ads for a moment.
And
I guess
here is
the way I see this
kind of all wrapped up in, in a box is
Google has done something that
I don't like. You don't, like. Most people won't even know happened because
-- it makes the internet a worse place.
-- It does. But
I think they screwed this one up because I
think they did it while Firefox is still strong
and Firefox has been losing market share for a very long time.
And I think in a couple of years it's conceivable,
the Mozilla Foundation could find itself in is in trouble.
But everyone I know is running Firefox now.
Well, and I know they've done some, uh, so Mozilla gets
my understanding is they get most of their funding from Google
by making it the default search provider and so on.
I don't know, they switched to Yahoo or Microsoft at one point.
I think, I don't know if they're still
who. But yes, basically they gain revenue from Google unquestionably.
-- Uh
-- And the second thing is I know Google has been doing things to make
their properties generally work better in Chrome than any other
browser to the point where any place using Google Docs.
It's like, yeah, you you use that via Google Chrome.
It is functional in Firefox but it is definite,
you can tell it's crippled because you run in like my favorite example is
when you're using
uh Google Docs on Chrome, you can right,
click and click paste right from the browser menu
and it pastes whatever is in the paste buffer.
Whereas Firefox you click paste and it's like, oh you can't paste from here.
You have to hit control V to paste.
It's like, yeah, OK. Whatever, I guess.
Uh
yeah, this might be the shot in the arm that Firefox needs
to put it bluntly
and, and I I hope it, I hope it gets it. And
this is
this is something I've been thinking about a lot actually.
Not, not in the context of Firefox specifically, but just in, in
kind of tech in general is
as we see a lot of consolidation with some of these larger companies,
it is becoming more obvious as something like a web browser being controlled by
a company that also sells like 60% of the ads on the internet,
like
holy crap. What's wrong with that?
Well, and, and conversely though,
that's one of the only places that has the incentive to actually
pour tens of millions of dollars into a proper web browser.
Let's be clear.
Chrome
is
and well, no, I don't know about is,
but chrome definitely was by far the superior web browser for many years,
you know, the performance.
The for example, it's built in PDF reader and the fact that Google did things like,
oh, you know,
we need to build a secure PDF viewer because it's
been a bit of a train wreck in the past.
And so they did things like OK, well,
let's just build a corpus of PDF documents that
exercise every code path in the PDF browser.
Oh, it turns out we have that because we have like a copy of the internet,
you know,
and so they took something like what was it? Remember?
It was like 21 point something terabytes of PDF and basically boiled it down.
-- It
-- was enormous
and then they fuzzed them too.
-- Yeah,
-- exactly.
So they, you know, II,
I love Google Chrome's PDF viewer because it just works so safely and reliably.
Mac O S's preview is mostly OK. But like
I
-- really, I feel safer with Google Chrome's built in PDF
-- thing when I was running Os X,
I found its PDF viewer to be terrible.
-- I did not care for
-- it. And so it drives me nuts. Right.
Because they built this beautiful thing. And now,
and I get why
doing it. And I,
again, if I was like a sea level at Google,
I probably would be on the other side of the fence and I get what they're doing.
But I don't, yeah, I don't like it and it's frustrating as heck.
Now, here's one thing I will say though is I started using Google Chrome
when I got my Mac
because Firefox, I'm,
yeah,
-- I actually tried using safari for about an hour and then I was, I, I it's
-- so
what's funny to me though is safari on the mobile
isn't that bad?
-- Like it's bearable. But safari on the desktop, I
-- just uh yeah, it was, it was bad.
It was really bad
and, and I, I used to run Firefox for a long time. I love Firefox.
I used to help Mozilla with some security stuff a long time ago.
Well, if you run Linux, what else are you going to run?
Uh Chrome runs on Linux.
Well, it does now. True. But I mean, for the longest time, yeah,
it always has. Uh But anyway, so I,
and, and I started using, I got my Mac, I install Firefox,
I install chrome and chrome was clearly the superior Tros.
It was faster and more responsive and just,
it was a better user experience and I begrudgingly
used it more and more as time went on
and eventually I uninstalled Firefox.
Well,
it kind of uninstalled itself from my disc crash and I had to reinstall whatever.
But that's another story is. Uh,
so anyway,
I, I have a Linux machine now and I, I just instinctively put chrome on it and it was,
I mean, it's fine, you know, it's chrome, whatever
and
all this, all these shenanigans go down and I'm like, I'm running Firefox now,
you know,
and I'm going to take a principled stand on this and say I
disagree with this and I'm not going to run on Google Chrome anymore.
And man, like Firefox is freaking caught up in almost every way in all seriousness.
It's fast. It, it everything works the way other than Google Docs. Everything works
-- like the same. It's perfect. I love
-- it.
I would say, yeah,
to that with the one glaring exception being the way it handles multiple profiles.
Yes, that's fair. I will agree.
It's just so disgustingly painful and I, I use multiple profiles a lot
there. Look at their, they have an extension, go look it up, it doesn't work
the same way chrome does, but you can almost certainly survive with it.
What it does is you have like a new open tab button
and you pick the profile you want the tab to open with.
See, I like Google Chrome because it
shows me which profile I'm logged in as and then
I can just click it and pick another one and
it'll either start up a new browser or fire me off to the one where it is already open.
Yeah. No, II, I do agree with that.
I think that is a better experience, but at the same time, this is a principled stand.
So I'm willing to put up with a certain amount
of nonsense that I wouldn't without such an effort.
So.
Well, I mean, to put it bluntly,
I won't have a choice if they take ad blocking away from me.
I, I can't,
I can't surf the web with ads. It's just, it's too slow, it's too painful.
It's too risky
and it's just too annoying.
I mean, this is, I haven't had cable TV, and
I'm gonna say
89 years, it's been a while, almost a decade now.
And so when I do see regular cable TV, with ads,
it just again, I want to gouge my eyes out because it's so, so annoying.
It is terrible.
I, uh, we actually now that you say that it's been about 11 years since we,
we turned off our cable T VA little, little more even maybe.
And
I have no complaints and, and raising Children without
like commercial television.
It's been basically PBS and Netflix is about all they've ever used.
And it's funny because they go to someone's house who has like, ad TV.
And they come home, they're like,
do you know about this? Do you know about this?
And at one point my son was, like, repeating ads verbatim to me.
I'm like, where did you learn this crap?
I don't know what, no, we're not getting that.
And it,
it, it's terrible. I agree. I agree.
It, it's funny though because with,
with youtube on a tablet you can't escape the ads.
So, I guess they're, they're back to being subjected to ads to a degree.
But, oh, my goodness. I hate ads.
Yeah.
I mean, I, I've literally, I think three times in my life seen an ad where I was like,
oh,
-- I'm actually interested in that.
-- I'm trying to think.
I, nothing comes to mind. I'm sure I, I have and let's face it too.
The vast majority of ads aren't about,
I'm going to inform you of this product or service.
It's to just brainwash you into
like, like, what is it?
They've done studies where kids subjected to, like fast food ads,
eat more junk food.
Right.
And it doesn't even necessarily mean they're eating that one particular brand.
It's just like they're, they're, it's warping your mind
into thinking you want something you don't.
Well, to thinking that it's normal to eat mcdonald's every day.
If you eat mcdonald's every day, we apologize for calling you not normal.
I'm not apologizing.
You
think enough
choices
at least get, mix it up with like Hardee's or Apple or what,
what are those other us chains?
Hardee's and like,
-- like
-- fast food.
Carl's Junior Sonics, whatever. Yeah, something like that.
-- Carl
-- Carl's Junior is Hardee's, they're literally the same. Ok.
The west coast, it's Carl's Junior. East coast. It's Hardee's,
it's mostly Hardee's in the Midwest where I live.
Ok.
But anyway, anyway, so this is,
I sort of feel bad. There's not a lot of security in this one.
It's mostly us complaining about ad blockers and the
fact that we don't like what Google is doing.
But I guess one of the things I keep thinking about,
we don't like ads, we don't want to watch
ads. And I think the fact that Google is doing this
tells me ad blockers are having the desired effect of people not seeing ads.
Now, here's the problem though.
What happens if Google starts getting more and more
angry because we're not looking at their ads.
That sort of scares me a little bit.
Well, so, ok, so clearly youtube, they can jam ads down your throat and there's a well
precedent for that with broadcast TV or cable TV or whatever.
I feel like Google Docs, they can't really do that.
That's going to make business people annoyed and angry. Google search.
Yeah, they can absolutely try and jam ads down and do more sponsored content and,
and what annoys me is once in a while I do actually
more so when I'm looking for a local business where it's like
the local business shows up in the ad and it's at the
top of the page and it's the one I wanted it.
So I'm like, yeah, whatever. Click that. Right.
And I feel kind of bad because I would have hunted them down and found them anyways.
You just cost them a nickel. Yeah.
But I feel like, fundamentally
there is still
some choice. I don't want to say Google has a monopoly.
I would say it's about as close as you can get to a monopoly without being a monopoly.
I would, I think they have a monopoly.
I think the fact that Microsoft was deemed to have a monopoly back in the day,
like Google is just as bad or worse.
Well, it's weird because they have a monopoly,
not in the sense of an absolute monopoly where there's no other choice but they have
a monopoly in the sense of they're so big and so good and so efficient,
realistically, I mean, I could go use bing or something but man,
the results are always a pain in the butt compared to Google.
Like my Google search bubble is so tuned to me at this point.
-- Uh
-- Yeah. Yeah, I agree with that.
God knows how many years of data on me, you know,
things like that were just like Microsoft can't replicate that without
me using Microsoft exclusively for like a year or two.
Right. Right.
And I, I fully admit I've, you know, I drank the Kool Aid
and I enjoyed it.
We all enjoyed it, man. It's, it's one of those things that I'm, I'm hopeful.
We look back someday and be like, wow, we were dumb.
Well,
I'm not sure how else this could have turned out because there's just
certain things at this scale that you can't do without effectively like,
like a good, you know, like tuning a search bubble to a person.
You can't do that without
seeing all their searches
and effectively having that monopoly over their eyeballs
and having everyone else's searches to correlate against.
So, you know, when, when you see the sequence of searches,
the next one's probably going to be this.
Yeah, exactly.
And, and they can do that.
The, the thing I keep thinking of is there,
there's all these companies that have built their futures on ads.
Well, it's one of the most effective current, you know,
for the last what two centuries ish
models that we found for quasi
micro payments,
right? The micro payment is your attention.
And ultimately, I, I serve an ad to a million people and I sell 20 widgets.
So, yeah, on average, blah, blah, blah, the math is all wonky. But fundamentally
how else are we going to do this? Right?
Because people literally,
I see people making as much of a deal about spending five bucks for an app as they do,
like buying a car or buying a house like,
I've literally had people complain about a $5 app and I'm like, dude, you make like,
six figures a year.
Why just buy the damn $5 app?
I've, I've done that before where I'm like, oh, it's a dollar.
I don't think I want to buy it.
I'm like, wait, I just spent more than a dollar thinking about this.
This,
yeah,
-- exactly. No,
-- I hear you. I hear you.
But at the same time it's one of those challenges also where,
like,
I'll give you my favorite example is I pay my local newspaper
so I can read it and I want them to survive.
So I'm happy to give them some money.
I find myself on another news site. They're like, oh, you can subscribe if you want.
I'm like,
I, I don't want to, if I had a way to give you, like,
a nickel for letting me read this story or a dollar or something.
Like I would, I would seriously consider it.
But I also recognize at the same time there is a nontrivial number of people.
Like, let's face it.
There's,
there's some kid in India who's just getting on the
internet for the first time who doesn't have a Eagle,
right? He has no way to get money to America. What now, I mean?
Remember the Ls and Crypt guy, right? The minute you charge even a penny for it. Ok.
Well, how do you get that penny to me?
Now you either need a credit card or
a bank account or some weird Cryptocurrency thing.
That is a pain in the butt. Right.
Whereas you just trade eyeballs and attention and hopefully one in
a million people spend all their money on your widgets.
No. Really?
Like that's, that's what I keep coming back to, you know, is, is the,
the second you require even 1/10 of a penny or a millionth of a penny payment.
The also the amount of infrastructure you need to handle that and charge backs. And,
you know, like, let's put, like,
let's be real if you charge five cents on a credit card.
Number one, can you even do that with a lot of credit card issuers?
Like, are you going to see because some of them charge minimum fees. Right.
They're not going to take 2.5% of five cents.
I have a funny story here is I sent someone, I think 10 cents over,
uh, paypal one time
and they charged me like a dollar service fee.
So
I paid like a dollar and 10 cents to send someone 10 cents, which amused me to no end.
Why did you have to send them 10?
I don't know.
It was to be, it was basically to, to show this is the problem, right.
It cost me a dollar if you send him 10 cents.
And it was funny and we all laughed. Ha
ha ha ha.
So far we've,
we haven't found a business model to, to replace ads
and the business model of charging
for content.
Let's be real that that has not worked yet.
Like, every time I go to the garden,
I feel so bad for the Guardian with their
little yellow notice at the bottom because the Guardian,
for example, is doing actual investigative journalism.
But I'm too much of a cheap bugger to actually give him like,
20 or 30 bucks or whatever, or buy a subscription.
Uh. Right. And I read like one Guardian news article a month.
Maybe it's not enough to justify it. I agree.
And I would love to give them some money, some money,
-- but
-- we don't love it enough to actually go and do it.
Here's where we're going to bring it all
together now because we're a security podcast.
So, here's the thing I have going through my head
now that we've had this weird discussion
is
I have a suspicion this suffers from the same problem.
The security industry does where there is a problem that we think we understand.
We probably don't really, but we think we do
and all of the current solutions to that problem
-- are insufficient in every way.
-- I'm, I'm reminded of the old spam solution chart.
Remember that thing, you know, your solution to spam won't work because,
and then there's like all those check boxes and stuff.
Right. Right. Exactly. That's exactly it. And,
but anyway, the the point being,
I feel like all we do now,
instead of saying we need to rethink the
problems and find new solutions is we're like,
well, just try harder.
Maybe that's the problem.
-- And it's like that is not the solution and it doesn't work,
-- use more paywalls.
Right.
Exactly.
-- We need more ads, everyone, more ads
-- and it's like, sponsored content, make the ads
more sneaky and less obtrusive. It's like soap operas.
I'm noticing that in some of the magazines now I buy, like, there'll be, I'm like,
why is the type font wonky on this article?
And then I'm like, oh, it's not,
it's a four
page ad.
I had that.
I think that was,
I think National Geographic just had one of those where I'm reading, like,
I've lost all respect for National Geographic.
Yeah, I like their pictures.
-- I'm a sucker for the pictures
-- back in and,
and back in the day I remember we fought over who, who got, who got to read it first.
And I, I remember I was so happy when I went to junior high because I could walk home
and I could get home before anybody else. And,
you know,
the mail had been dropped off.
-- So I always got to read National Geographic first anyway.
-- Anyway.
Yeah, I was reading it the other day. I still get it. I love the magazine.
I know they're kind of sell outs for a bunch of reasons. But whatever, I still like it.
And
I started reading, I'm like, what the heck is this article?
And it, like, it basically blended in.
You could not tell it was an ad until you actually stood back and looked at it.
I'm like, oh, my goodness, this is, this is shameful.
But at the,
you know, at the same time I sure as,
I don't have some magical business model to offer these people.
No, no, I, I don't have one and I don't know. And the thing that scares the crap out of me
is my suspicion is more ads is going to be the answer because
they're going to realize as more and more people are using ad blockers,
which it, it, it has to be more common that Google is making this decision.
That just means that people without them,
they're going to put even more ads in front of
because
like, let's face it. That's their solution is eyeballs, looking at ads.
Well, you got fewer eyeballs. So we'll just do more ads, right?
The ratio still works out.
All right. Anyway, we should, we should tie this one up.
Here's what I will say is my parting advice.
Get Firefox, use Firefox support Mozilla. They're doing awesome work.
-- And
-- if you do, you want to donate to Mozilla, go to donate.mozilla.org.
That's
I love it. I, I will donate today. In fact, I should do that. Awesome.
All right, good deal. So, thank you, Kurt. Thank you. Everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com, grab the show notes.
You can use the
Pound Os S podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media, go,
go download and use Firefox and Kurt.
-- Have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.