Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself.
Kurt Siefried and Josh Bresser.
How are you doing, Kurt?
I am doing great.
That is fantastic.
Yeah.
-- Didn't catch that cold, but apparently you did.
-- Oh, man, it's been brutal.
I was, I was really sick last week actually. But I'm doing all right.
I'm doing all right. I blame my trip to Washington DC,
but that's ok.
I go again in, I think two weeks so I'll be better and then I'll get sick again,
which is fantastic.
But
II, I feel like we're going to call this one the,
the, uh, well, or rather let's dedicate this episode to Steve Christie
because a topic came up on Twitter this week that I would love to discuss.
And it's something that's often there's some computer around it, but
the topic is responsible disclosure.
Why don't you tell us what responsible disclosure is? Kurt.
Uh,
jeez.
Uh, I, this is one of those things, it means
basically it means whatever you want it to mean.
It's, yeah, it's a, it's a mess like most security things.
Like most things in security. I think it started with good intentions. And then it
was widely hijacked by a variety of people.
And uh, yeah, currently it literally means whatever you want to mean.
And especially since it grew out of the whole, you know,
the zero day full disclosure.
I don't know if anybody listening to us remembers that, you know, the mailing list,
bug track and full disclosure,
you know, and the guys like eight little green men.
Yeah, just out of that whole mess.
The security industry sort of tried to create some,
I don't wanna say rules but guidelines maybe
on how to handle security data so that it wasn't, you know, a complete gong show mess.
All right. That was a long
explanation.
But I think the,
the important thing
that, that I wanted to push here is that
the term responsible disclosure is sometimes used and it has fallen out of favor.
And Steve Christie,
I I we credit with coining this term
and the problem was I think he was ahead of his time
because a long time ago,
there was basically no disclosure where you would silently fix
things or just not acknowledge the security issues existed,
which is unfortunately,
it was very common back in the day.
And then there is the full disclosure aspect which there's a mailing list,
it still exists.
Actually, I don't know if you knew that it,
it died for a little while and then it was brought back.
But there's full disclosure,
which is where you don't really tell anyone anything in advance.
You just dump all of the public information you
have about a security issue onto the internet somewhere
and this happens. It still happens occasionally.
I don't think it's as common as it used to be,
but in the middle
is where, what we used to call responsible disclosure.
We're now coining as co ordinated disclosure
because it totally doesn't mean the same thing.
Yeah,
I think the problem with responsible disclosure is that Steve Christie,
uh, like many people who are passionate about this
kind of assumed that people and companies would want to do the right thing.
And let's face it. A lot of companies and people,
you know, they, they have different, uh, goal maybe than the rest of us.
Um, I mean, if you look at like,
how long it took the auto industry to embrace security.
-- It's, it's a little scary there.
-- They haven't embraced security,
maybe safety but not security.
Well, ok, you're right, actually.
Yeah, sorry, that was the word I meant to use was safety, you know,
with three point safety belts and, uh, air bags and anti lock brakes and all that.
Um, and, yeah, and they certainly have not yet in, uh,
handled security because actually, for example,
I've now,
twice in two weeks,
uh, had a coworker who accidentally unlocked somebody else's car.
And also, uh, it happened to a friend of mine
where they basically, you know,
did the blip to unlock their car in the parking lot and somebody else's car flashed,
right?
And
as people may or may not know,
uh these current car locks use what's called rolling code.
So they use like a, it just generates a number,
right? And of course, sometimes these numbers are the same.
So, you know, obviously from a security point of view,
accidentally unlocking somebody else's car
would tend to indicate that they, yeah, have not fully embraced security.
Um, but back to responsible and coordinator disclosure.
I, I think, yeah, that the idea was that,
you know,
we would have the researchers do the right
thing in the sense of they would do research
and then they would find something terrible
and they would go to the company or the project that
was responsible for that software that did that terrible thing.
And of course, then we would like,
and this is where the train goes off the tracks is that
we would then hope that the company would be like, oh, wow.
Thanks for finding this terrible flaw.
We'll get right on that and have a patch out and say
2 to 4 weeks or, you know,
-- four weeks,
-- man. Nobody, no company gets patches out in two
days
and, you know, and, and
yeah.
Yeah,
you temper that against reality where the reality is for a lot of larger vendors.
It, it's gonna take a minimum of like 3 to 6 months
because of product schedules and whatnot. Or resource availability.
Um All the way up to
-- several years.
-- This is where the concept of responsible I think was abused
because these large organizations that were
not the fastest moving groups would say
if you don't work with us and you don't follow our rules,
you're not being responsible,
which is
we,
we could get into a very long and esoteric
debate about what defines responsible in this context.
But I think it's safe to say that when there
is a disagreement between the researcher and the company,
that doesn't mean one side is being more responsible than the other necessarily.
Because obviously,
from, from our perspective,
we might say the researcher is more responsible for trying to do it faster,
to publish the information faster.
Whereas some people would say no, no,
the organization is being more responsible because they want to go at the right
pace and properly test and make sure everything's working the way it should.
So this is,
this is a term that is highly loaded
and is very difficult to tie down which side is right or wrong.
Well,
and it also varies too because I've I've seen situations where a researcher thought
they found something terrible and it turns out to be nothing like literally,
that's how that product works,
right?
Like we have to enable,
like we've literally had that where somebody reports something
that they think is the end of the world.
And we're like, no, that's like that's a required piece of functionality.
You know, it's,
it's, yeah.
And, you know, it's,
I don't know if they still have it but I know the Apache project
at one time had to have a little write up about the fact that
yes, their source code is on their website on purpose. It is not a mistake.
It is not a leak.
Nobody accidentally put this there because they would get, like, like once a week
they would get,
they would get someone sending them, you know,
an advisory telling them they accidentally leaked
their source code on the internet.
-- Yeah.
-- No, I can believe that because I've, I've seen that
those same emails sent to Red Hat
about
EP dot Red hat.com.
You know, that and,
and not even that the source code is there but that we allow directory listings,
right.
You know?
Oh, man, I love it.
The source is weird.
Yeah. So
I, it,
with the responsible disclosure, the problem became too,
is that some of these companies,
you know? Really?
I guess I want to use the term bullied people,
you know, and more than a little bit in some cases.
Yeah. I think that's fair.
I think that's fair,
you know.
And, uh, and even now it's, and part of it too, I,
I think sometimes it's just simple miscommunication.
Like there was a recent case where a researcher, uh,
found some flaws in a product, uh, and then, you know,
co ordinated with the vendor,
uh the vendor was, you know,
actually got the patches out in a reasonable amount of time
and then asked the researcher not to publish uh like the,
the real details of the attack
and the researcher kind of went public with, you know, oh,
this big company is asking me to censor my work and it's,
if you read the email this company sent to them,
they're just like we really don't want this information on, on the public web.
We really, you know, it's,
there was no, uh I mean,
given the context of that one email, it didn't appear to be threatening or anything,
you know, in a situation like that, I can't help but wonder, you know,
these companies are being painted with somewhat of a bad brush
when they're, you know, obviously it, it doesn't hurt to ask,
you know, as a company,
you don't want that information being out there because it does
put customers at risk and it makes the company look bad.
And I think part of it, I wonder is,
you know, the researchers and the companies, they don't really
have good relationships by and large,
you know, like how many,
how many firms have a security team
with good relationships with the community?
Two
maybe. Right.
No, I mean, I get that, but now let's bring ourselves out away from responsible
to coordinate.
So what is coordinating mean?
So coordinator disc
disclosure generally looks something like somebody finds a vulnerability
and then they try to do the right thing and then
depending on what the company or project they're reporting to does,
you know, they essentially,
well, I think basically it boils down to treat others like they treat you.
You know, if you, if you go to a company and they're like, oh my God, that is terrible,
we're gonna get right on it
and then they get back to you say, within 24 hours, you know, and saying,
we've done a basic analysis of this and as it
turns out it's gonna be really hard to fix,
but we're working on it, you know,
chances are that researcher is gonna cut that company some slack, you know,
versus if the company
just ignores them or tells them to go pound sand,
you know, in that case, well, then, you know, what, really,
what choice is the research are left with other
than to maybe go public with their findings.
I mean, that,
that's really fair and I think you're pointing
out a really important part of this is that
the goal of coordinate disclosure is
really just communication and cooper operation
rather than
trying to shame one group or the other or
proclaim yourself the savior or whatever it is.
It's really about cooperating and making sure everyone's on the same page.
Yeah.
And part of it too is, I mean,
uh I find a lot of researchers don't,
you know,
they, they say basically well, this is really easy to fix and well, yeah, it,
it actually might be a very easy bug to fix,
but then we need to do testing because we can't just ship stuff
and hope it doesn't break. You know, Red Hat has a generally good track record.
Um, you know, along with a lot of the open source, like, let's face it,
the majority of open source vendors generally don't ship updates that break stuff,
you know, as a rule,
we really try to avoid that.
And, you know, even like the upstream, like the Linux kernel, you know, Linus
tools himself says, basically,
you can't break user space,
right? And most of the time they don't, they, there have been occasional oopsies.
Um So part of it too is with the researchers and all the parties involved, you know,
they may not understand that.
Yeah,
this will take six weeks to fix because we have to do this and
we have to test and we have to coordinate with other people or,
you know, and especially the vulnerabilities that involve more than one vendor.
You know, when you get something like Apache or bind or open SSL,
you know, that's hundreds, if not thousands of people that use that stuff, right.
Yeah. And uh well, that's one of the difficulties I know open SSL has is
this thing is used in
a significant portion of the internet. I mean, it, it's certainly double digits.
It might even be as many as half of the devices on the internet are running open SSL.
And so what do you do about that? And I understand their dilemma
and they, they, I know they've published a lot of this,
of what they do and how they do it online as
to rather than necessarily doing kind of AAA full coordinate disclosure.
They have very defined rules which I think
you could fit into the coordinate disclosure bucket because
there are expectations. Right.
Yeah.
To me, the, the coordinator disclosure,
I think can best be summed up as not so much the Hippocratic Oath of do no harm.
But I think a variation on it of let's try and minimize the amount of harm.
Don't, don't be a
jerk. Right.
Yeah.
And, and I mean, that, that includes too, you know,
like let's give the project some time to fix it, you know,
because some of these projects are literally one guy,
you know, and it's,
you can't really, you know, these people have lives,
they need to sleep eight hours a day.
And, um
you know, and on the flip side too, some of these projects are, are quite massive and,
you know, you might have found a flaw in something that touches,
you know, a lot of different parts of the code base,
you know, especially if it's well like open SSL, you know, those,
that thing touches everything.
Um
So yeah, like I said, it, like you said, rather, it,
it really does boil down to communications.
And
I think that's one thing where a lot of big companies have trouble,
you know, is that
the way that they communicate, they don't communicate like people. Right.
They communicate like companies
and for a lot of researchers they, that can be very frustrating.
-- I, I
-- don't know, current,
I think in the United States it's
been clearly defined that corporations are people.
Well, true. But these are people with, you
know,
multiple personality disorder
and schizophrenia, right?
I mean, well, because you look at it like, uh, you know, some of these companies,
like,
I remember when, um, somebody was talking about Sony and they, you know, they,
they pointed out that one arm of Sony was doing one thing with
respect to copyright and another arm of
Sony was doing something completely opposite,
you know, and it's like, how is this possible?
And somebody pointed out that Sony is like over 100,000 people spanning the globe,
you know.
Um,
and so I also love it
when you hear about these companies that send like cease and desist to themselves
because you have one group who doesn't realize who the other group is.
Yeah.
And I think, you know, I for myself,
it's been an eye opener working at a large company
like Red Hat and dealing with other large companies,
you know,
and that's something, you know, that's new to a lot of secured researchers,
like especially the first few times you find flaws in these, you know,
large companies, products.
You know,
you might be talking to somebody who then leaves the company and you have to,
you know,
you end up talking to somebody else or you're
talking to some group that literally ceases to exist.
You know,
uh like here's a, a brain puzzler.
Let's say you find a security flaw in not to pick on HP.
But uh HP Enterprise is open stack distribution.
Well, they're apparently disbanding that entire group at the end of the month
it was announced. And, you know, there's a real good question.
How do you, as a, as a researcher? How do you coordinate with that?
I mean, that, that's a fair question.
I don't know. I, I don't know if there's a good answer to that.
-- So,
-- I mean, I like that. We,
I don't know if you, anybody remembers,
uh was it Rainforest Puppy wrote the guidelines way back in the day?
I mean, that's got to be about, what, 1015 years ago now,
at least.
Yeah.
And,
you know, well, it was kind of like,
it always reminded me of Martin Luther nailing his, um
what was the name of the thing he nailed to the church door, the precepts, the canon
treatises or something?
I forget,
I think that was the word,
you know, and it kind of reminded me of that in that. It was like, wow, you know. Yeah.
Nobody's ever really defined this at all. We, we should probably do that
well and we still really haven't. Right. I mean, a significant amount of this work
is not super well defined. I know there's some RFC s
are there, are they RFC S, there's,
there's some documents I iso standards something or other
that came out around some of this,
but it's
fairly narrow
and it struggles once you bring open source into the equation which,
and let's face it
as I've said a million times and I will continue to say open source one,
everyone's using it.
And so that's an important aspect of this that has to be kept in mind
when you are both a researcher and the organization
that is dealing with the researchers.
Yeah.
Well, the other thing too is it's, I wouldn't, I'm,
I'm less worried that for example, we, we do have some guidelines and some structure
but there's nobody to enforce it.
And more to the point, there's nobody to really provide training on this or,
you know, as far as I know, there's no good 10 page
document that covers like how
you know, so now you're in upstream and you wrote code that's in, you know,
a significant portion of the internet.
What do you do now? You know, I, I remember one time back oh, quite some time ago.
Uh This guy basically started by writing some docs for Ruby
uh project. Uh Sorry, a Ruby gem.
And two years later, he's the main maintainer, right?
Because that's just kind of how the open source world works. Right?
You, you stick your toe in it and then you get sucked into the quicksand.
I had this poor guy on the phone and he was almost crying.
He was in his, you know, he was, he was a young guy
and there was this horrific security flaw in this ruby jump, like, really,
truly horrible and he was, like,
really concerned people were gonna sue him and people were gonna, like,
lose their minds and, like, hunt him down and, like, it was just, you know,
I felt for the poor guy and I was just like,
you know, trust me as bad as it is,
it's gonna be ok. Right. And, you know, everything turned out fine, of course.
But he was really freaked out because he really wanted to do the right thing.
And he was like, oh, my God, what have I done to the world? You know, I've,
I've built software that's like, I, I think it was like,
something like 10 or 20 million systems use this software
and I've just exposed them to this horrible security flaw. Like, oh, my God.
You know, I'm a terrible human being and I'm like, no, you're just a programmer.
It,
same thing really.
But
you gotta wonder how the open SSL guys sleep at night. Right.
Well,
yeah,
I, you know, the thing they do. A pretty good job. I mean, what really concerns me is,
you know, how much, I mean, as, as bad as these examples we talk about are,
I can't even imagine how bad things are in, you know,
the industries where they don't,
you know, make their source code available or even allow black box testing,
you know, the D MC A and all that.
Uh, the,
the Digital Millennium Copyright Act which makes
it illegal to reverse engineer stuff,
you know,
you not
d
it's much worse.
Oh, yeah,
but nobody's gonna talk about it.
Yeah.
And part of me, you know, and again, going,
you know, I keep going on about sort of these large shocks, but
we don't even have a sense of the, the scale of magnitude
of how bad things are.
Are we talking, you know, like a perfect example being open a cell?
Like are there 10 more really bad security flaws in the current code base?
100 1000 a billion?
Like, literally we have no sense of scale.
I'm gonna guess it's less than a billion,
but more than one,
here's a thought.
Have we ever had a situation where there's more
than one security flop per line of code?
And
I'm, I'm sure it's possible
but I, I'm going to hope it's unlikely.
Yeah.
So, I mean, ok,
then hopefully at the high end we can just say there's X numbers of lines of code.
So.
Right. Right.
There's only that many flaws or less.
Yes,
I can think of.
You could easily have an integer overflow and a buffer overflow in the same
line of code or even multiple buffer overflows.
But
we'll just, we'll just feed AAA stir,
get to a, a stir copy or get string.
-- I don't even remember all those crappy old sea functions. I haven't
-- used
the ones we're not supposed to use anymore. Right.
Yeah. But, uh,
yeah. and I mean,
and this actually goes into a related topic, you know, bug bounties.
And then now we have the whole bug bounty question where
I think
part of it for some companies is trying
to take control of the whole reporting process.
Right. Because,
you know, it, it is relatively easy for a company to say, look,
we have a bug bounty and this person chose not to participate in it.
You know, they're, they're being a jerk because they went public.
Yeah, that's true. Actually, you, you do look like a jerk if you don't do that. And
what was it? Facebook
just had, what, what is it, five years, $5 million or something like that?
-- They just pay
-- $5 million of payouts,
which is pretty solid.
Yeah.
Again, with those, you know, part of the problem is as a researcher, again,
with Bug Ben is now the problem is you're monetizing it.
So people have an incentive to report but you
also get a lot of really garbage reports.
From what I've seen.
That's what I've heard, which is one of the tricks obviously.
Now I'm,
I'm looking here at the notes you wrote down and you said so $5 million 900 flaws.
So figure five ish $1000 per flaw,
which seems like a steal to me.
I mean, now, granted,
I'm sure some of those are really bad and some of those were really lame,
but still
and all right. So, let's say they had 900 flaws.
I would bet
they had at least
reports
and they had to throw away at least half.
I bet it's a lot higher, but we could probably estimate it's half at least. Right.
Well, especially if they're known to pay out. I mean,
yeah, you'd have to assume it would be higher and,
yeah.
No, I can't ii, I wonder what the reporting process is because there's,
there's definitely ways you can make the reporting process, like,
have little bumps in it to make sure people aren't, you know,
reporting complete garbage
where there's a will, there's a way, Kurt,
they'll find a way. True.
So,
I mean, it's certainly cheaper. I, I suspect it's cheaper,
uh, to have a bug found through a bug bounty than it is to have a bug found
from like a full time employee. Right. Because let's face it.
Security researchers are not cheap people to hire,
uh, good ones are, are certainly not cheap. And I think it's also worth noting
that, I don't know,
very many companies that have people on staff who just look for bugs like this.
They're generally part of like an SDL program or they're an analyst or
they have a day job.
And so when they find things, it's not necessarily because they were even looking,
it's just
they happen to find a problem
and let's face it
if you were going to pay someone to only look for
bugs and let's assume the cost is $5000 per bug.
If you're paying someone a reasonable salary,
you're talking about
essentially more than 20 bugs a year.
Do you think a security researcher is gonna find 20 security bugs per year?
That's a crazy number.
Uh, I mean, it, it, part of, it depends, you know,
if it's just cross site scripting flaws and it can be, you know,
I can write an engine that crawls through then, you know,
and manually go through the results then, yeah, that might be possible.
One thing I think too is it's actually more vulnerable in some
ways to have people who are not full time security people because,
you know, a lot of these bugs are
in complicated code and that, you know, especially things like, for example,
logic cares, you know, unless you understand and know a product really well,
you might think that, oh, that behavior is ok.
You know,
I mean, we regularly get internal bug reports at Red Hat where, you know,
some developer or, and especially our QE guys are like, hey,
I was testing this thing and then this thing happened
and it's really not supposed to ever do that,
you know, it's a security flaw and I'm like,
you know, I'll read the documentation and I'll look at them and be like, oh, yeah.
Yeah. No, that seems right. But
quite honestly if I was running that QE test,
I probably wouldn't like. That's a weird glitch, whatever.
You know, I wouldn't have recognized it as a security vulnerability
like they did,
you know,
because they have a much better understanding of what
the product is and is not supposed to do.
On the other hand, I think we do need those pure security researchers because,
you know, some of these things
are just so damn complicated,
you know,
especially new classes of attacks.
Right.
Yep. Yep.
Well, but also I, I suspect there's a certain amount of diminishing return here
where
a researcher can look at something
and they'll find a couple of things relatively quickly,
but then it's gonna drop off fast as well.
So, if you had someone just looking at one code base for a whole year,
I would bet you they'll find 90% of their stuff in
the first two months and then very little after that.
So it just,
it doesn't make sense to pay someone to kind of do this sort of thing full time.
Well, I think we have proof in that,
in the sense of these people who spend all day in the code base don't see the flaws,
you know,
like literally, you know,
like, I mean, and I've, I've seen the case where literally an open source
component was audited by three different people.
Person. A found a bunch of flaws.
Those got fixed person B found a bunch of different flaws.
Those got fixed person C found actually a really trivial flaw which then got fixed,
you know, and they were all fixed. Right.
Yeah.
And, uh, I mean, and yet, you know, well,
these programmers that live in the code base
all day didn't see these flaws or didn't realize
that they were flaws, you know,
and I think at some point your eyes just kind of glaze over, you know, it's like
I've had the experience where I'm editing my own work, you know,
written work and it's just at some point I,
I'm like, uh, whatever, I only do it once now, one edit, that's it,
send it in because I,
I won't see anything else and then I've had the copy editor send it back and I'm like,
-- oh my God, like literally half the thing is
-- red.
I know. I know
that, that, that just happened to me actually where
I sent some work to an editor
and
I'm looking at, I'm thinking, how did I even write this stuff?
I mean, it's like ridiculous mistakes and misspellings. And using, like, like
using the wrong there is one of my personal pet peeves and so I try really hard
to always get it right because I can't be a judgmental,
a hole if I'm not going to get it right every time.
So I try really hard and it, but I still, it's like, man, I, how did I do that?
Well, you know, people are terrible.
We're just fundamentally, like, as a kid. I used the word th, er,
that's it.
They're right.
You know, because I got,
nobody really sat down and explained. They're there and there to me.
So you made up your own
-- word.
-- I just contracted it and used it.
And the funny thing is that if you look at, uh,
apparently I got away with it for a year or two,
they probably thought you were this special kid, Kurt.
Well, you know, or, well, you know,
and that's the other thing too. Right.
I mean, you ask these security researchers,
it's like here's a million lines of code.
-- Good luck. That, that is quite a daunting task.
-- It, it is crazy.
And I,
I wonder if anyone does a lot of manual anything anymore because
most of the work I see these days is you're either doing
some sort of magic fuzzing
or you'll run
like a code sanitizer
over the code looking for obvious mistakes.
The reality is we don't need, you know,
highly skilled artisanal security researchers to find flaws.
Right. Grip. Grip for slash temp.
And you'll always find a temporary file creation flaw
in the code base. It's just, it's a, it's
all right. All right. So you've just, you've just touched on
one of my favorite topics and the thing that I don't always like to talk about,
but I'll, I'll do it here because the, this totally isn't being recorded.
But
so, so I love bug bounties on one level, but on another level,
I kind of have a problem with this because
by definition,
doing bug bounties and response is running as fast as you can just to stand still.
And that's kind of bonkers when you think about it.
Whereas what if we took all this money and started investing
in proactive technologies like flash temp is a great example where
you can have slash temp flaws or you can use something called poly
instantiated slash temp.
And now every user has their own slash temp slash temp flaws are gone
now.
And that, that's actually not new. I mean, that's been around for a while.
So what if we took,
what if Facebook took this $5 million and invested it in
proactive technologies to just remove these flaws from the universe?
I,
I don't know.
I mean, there's not a good answer to this and, and obviously I'm,
I've oversimplified it to a comical degree,
but that's kind of, that's the thing I always think of here is,
are we wasting our money
with bug bounties when the real bounty and I think
Microsoft does this actually where they have a bounty,
like, you can make a ton of money from them if you provide them with
a proactive solution to a fundamental problem.
I think a lot of it, you know, it,
it kind of reminds me of infosec spending in general where a lot of it really,
you know, these people don't even have backups
and they're worrying about advanced,
persistent threats and stuff and they don't even have like a backup of their system
that they can, you know, verify works.
I think part of it is, you know, bug bounties, they get a lot of,
they, they work. Right.
The reality is researchers are willing to spend time
grinding through these things to get cash for bugs
and, you know, the company then just spends money on verifying and fixing,
you know,
and they're not paying for researchers to work on
stuff that turns out to not be vulnerable.
They,
they're only paying for results
and I think that's part of the, you know, that's part of the modern economy. Right.
Like the whole piece work thing. Right. I'm not going to pay you for your time.
-- I'm gonna pay you for the results.
-- That's true. That's true actually.
And that's, I mean, this is very, you get what you measure
and we can, like, Wells Fargo might be familiar with,
with the problem of measuring the wrong thing.
And
this is what I wonder is our bug bounty measuring the wrong thing.
They, you can't argue they aren't successful because there's,
I mean, Facebook got 900 bugs
and it cost them $5 million which seems like a really good deal,
but they got exactly what they were looking to get.
Right.
Well, I would point out that you and I are making a very fundamental as, uh,
assumption
that
squishing security flaws either reactively like a bug
bounty or proactively with things like say,
you know, poly instantiated tamp or like address act
randomization
is actually effective overall for
air quotes here, you know, information security, end of air quotes.
And that's a huge assumption.
I suspect it's correct, but I've not seen it proven to be correct
uh in
-- any formal way,
-- some things. So we could use
stack protector
as the example here where this is a technology in
GCC and lots of compilers have it. So GCC isn't special here, but
I, I know GCC. Well, so we'll use that.
It's something called stack protector and essentially
you compile your stuff with this flag
and it basically removes the stack buffer overflow security flaw.
And now I guarantee
that that has made a difference because at red hat,
when we've done analysis of issues,
it would have been critical without this.
And now it's maybe moderate,
maybe important depending upon the situation that's happening.
But
we can, we can measure
a noticeable decrease
in flaw severity due to this feature.
Some things like a SLR, it's a little less clear there or,
or some of the heap protections that have gone into G lip C same thing.
Well, I mean, more at a high level, for example, are,
are customers actually being attacked using these things or are they being sent
emails that they then open and run the dancing hamster dot EFC?
You know, that's, it's, you know, like this whole thing where people,
you know, back to the last episode, you know, where
security policy for removable devices that a lot of places consists of,
please don't do that rather than having a technical solution to actually block it,
you know. Um
And, and I, I just, like I said, I suspect it's true but I'm not,
I've not seen it proven, you know,
it's like a lot of these economic theories we've seen
and then the people go through and they crunch all the data and they're like,
you know, for every dollar that, what is it like the Park Service spends,
they get like
$2 back or, or what NASA was a good example.
I think it was for every dollar NASA spends, it generates $17 for the economy, right?
So there's like
a 17 to 1 positive ratio of spending money there,
you know, so let's spend some money there.
But with infosec spending, you know, apparently, uh
there was an article
talking about it, uh,
how infosec spending is now rising at twice the rate of overall it spending.
Right. And obviously that can't go for very long.
We're totally getting twice the value every year. Right.
Yeah. You know,
I mean, they're talking about, what was it?
I think by 20 20/100 billion dollars being spent to protect stuff online.
And I'm, I, I
can't help but think, you know,
we're still gonna have pretty much the same level of problems that we have today.
I,
I can't imagine it getting significantly better because we spent more money on it.
May maybe we'll be significantly better off,
they spend more money on it. Right.
Well, you know, I, I'm ok with that.
Uh, no, this is actually a really good topic and I don't know if
or rather I, I don't know how deep you want to go today, but,
so measuring what security features and security practices
and security products and all of this stuff.
What does it mean for the business
is a question that isn't asked very often.
And, and like a, a fine example is when you've got your, your operational security
and people will say, oh, we need a SIM
or we need our IP S or we need,
uh, a si si, em, it's, uh, basically log monitoring right where you're,
you're kind of aggregating all your logs and then you're looking for
what, where are the bad things
and, and generally speaking, everyone just, you know, they install it, they,
they aggregate all their logs,
they're overwhelmed with data and they can't ever find anything.
Right.
But, but let's say, let's say a firewall like that, maybe that's easier example,
if you have a firewall
and you've paid a bunch of money for it
and you've deployed,
can you show
that the money you've spent on that firewall
is essentially being offset by not having
problems somewhere else in the infrastructure,
right?
Or
I mean,
uh another example with the firewall would be
detect outgoing attacks or detect outgoing data,
you know, because that's, that seems to be something that, you know,
has happened several times where companies have lost or somehow managed to have,
you know, multiple terabytes of data sent to China.
And I'm like,
how did you not notice that?
Like, right? Like,
you know, just,
-- you
-- know, I, I have a funny story about this is
back in my younger days, I was a cis
man just out of college
and I worked for this organization and
we, they, they had no monitoring of any sort and being the young security guy,
I wanted to, you know, make my name.
I'm like, hey,
why don't we install a bunch of these monitoring applications in here?
And it was, it was, it was
NIOS now it was called Net
Saint back then. I think this was that long ago
and then we installed uh M RT G to graph the,
the internet traffic off the router and all this other stuff.
And I remember at one point we, I started looking at this and I was saying,
like, like some of this traffic doesn't make sense
what's going on here.
And it turned out that the FTP site was being used to, uh, to serve wares, you know,
Pirated software from, from way back in the day,
which is just completely crazy to be honest with you.
But, but it's one of those things, if, if you're not paying attention,
you have no idea what's happening.
Yeah.
Well, I, a lot of people, you know,
it's what to measure is often way more important than, you know,
actually measuring stuff.
Uh,
I'm always reminded of,
I don't know if you remember back in the day when call centers all
apparently started measuring call time as a metric for how good people were.
And so you get, like, literally people just hanging up on you, uh,
like the three minute mark or whatever,
you know. But again, you get what you measure, right?
Yeah.
Like I know with my previous cell phone company they, I,
they must have some sort of automated voice thing
because at the end of the call they say.
So, have I basically solved, like, have I solved all your problems?
Are you happy with your, your service today?
And I was like, just to be a bit of a jerk to see how far they would go. I was like, hm,
you know, and I, I basically wanted to see how far he'd go to make me say yes or no.
Right. And
he was willing, like, he basically was willing to do whatever it took.
And this was
a human, or was this a,
it was a human being that I was talking to?
He was the guy that had fixed my cell phone problem
and he wanted to
say
yes or no.
Yeah, or something basically, like, you know,
yeah, I got, I, I'm happy with the service today or whatever. I'm like,
and,
you know, it's,
and I'm assuming it's because they have some automated voice recognition
software that checks at the end of each call for that.
And that's whether or not you get your bonus or fired. You know, what is it?
The, the car, the steak knives are fired
and,
you know, it, it's pretty obvious, like I've,
I've also had the case of CV request where it's really obvious that these CV.
S are hooked up to their bonus structure
because like they want, they're like, can we split this into multiple CV s?
And I'm like, no, no, according to the CV, split merge rules, we're gonna do one CV.
And they're like, but it's 50 different issues. I'm like, no, it's not.
That's interesting.
Well, I mean, let's
face
it.
If, if I'm a researcher, if I'm a researcher, I want as many CV E I DS
attached to my name
as possible
because
regardless of bonuses
I want,
when someone searches the CV E database or when someone looks at how many issues,
you know, Josh, found, I want it to be a huge list.
So it's,
I, I get it.
I mean, and so I guess that's, that's maybe our next great challenge in security is
what should we be measuring?
Well, I'm not sure we can, because quite frankly, we have
to,
we
-- have to,
-- we can't say I'm not sure we can
because if we don't find a way to measure our effectiveness,
we are going to fail as an industry.
And I would say there are a few people who would
be willing to say that that security today is a roaring success
and I suspect part of that story is we don't know how to measure what we do.
Well, I sometimes wonder if what we're doing is good enough.
I mean, yeah, there's fraud and bad activity and waste going online, you know,
because people spend
how much money on anti spam. But,
you know, it's, it's much like everybody has to spend 50 bucks on, uh,
locks for their front door
because if you don't, somebody is just gonna walk in and take your stuff.
You know, uh, the,
every car on the planet has to have a lock because otherwise
somebody will just take your car for a joy ride or whatever
and
what the situation we currently have is, I mean, it's not great, but,
you know, the lights are still on and food's being delivered.
But, but then I
can
get my,
but then we have the question of is,
are things good enough because they're good enough or are
they good enough because the bad guys haven't figured out
how to really cause trouble yet. I mean, you could look at the, the Krebs D OS
with, there are literally millions of IOT devices on the internet today
that have little to no authentication.
Is that in the good enough bucket? I mean, I would like to think not,
I,
I think it's going to become more of a problem as Attackers.
I mean,
what's interesting to me is that it looks like Attackers
have figured out really two ways to monetize attacks online,
like really monetize and number one
is attacking banks and financial institutions,
you know,
like that case where they stole, what was it? $68 million from an online bank.
And then the second case, as you've mentioned many times is ransomware, right?
Ransomware is a great way to make money, you know,
uh pay 1000 bucks and uh hopefully learn your lesson and get real backups.
Um I can't imagine things like spamming and denial
of service attacks generate a lot of money.
I mean, well,
they do probably generate several hundreds of millions
if not billions of dollars a year.
But comparative to the effort,
you know, I'm not sure that it's,
you know,
that effective
and, yeah, you know,
I don't want to live in a world full of denial of service attacks and spam and,
you know, my bank constantly forcing me to re
aic who I am.
Uh, because, you know, they get attacked and their clients get attacked so often.
Um, but on the flip side, like, look at spam. Right.
Spam is a horrible problem and we've largely accepted it.
Everybody has spam filters. You get
a few spam emails a day if you're unlucky and
you know, that's, that's it. That's how it works.
You've just hit on something really important I think is you, you framed this
in the context of quality of life.
And today
I think
the quality of life for people due to technology
is currently going down when I think about this because
you think about identity theft creates a lot of problems.
How many, how many new credit cards have you gotten in the last year?
I think I've had all mine replaced at least three times in the last year.
I mean, and it's such a pain in the butt. Seriously.
Dude, I have like I've had, although I travel a lot so
I'm, I'm often in, we'll say, um,
places that I'm not familiar with. So I don't know
sometimes what's going on and, and it, it's very common, right?
But anyway, you know, you got credit cards being replaced, there's
spam we can kind of argue that either way.
But ransomware is a huge inconvenience even if all you want
to do is pay it to make it the hurting stop.
You still have to get Bitcoins.
Well, in some cases, figure out what Bitcoin is, you know,
and kind of start from there, but it is an inconvenience to deal with this stuff.
And so I think the thing we might want to start paying attention to is security
might become more important to most people when
the quality of their life becomes noticeably worse.
And for the vast majority of people, they haven't had their identity stolen,
they haven't had ransomware.
They, they probably had viruses but, you know,
the neighbor kid took care of that whatever.
But I think
if things like identity theft and ransomware become more commonplace,
you're going to see a greater push for security due to the quality of life issue.
If I had to guess
I would agree and I would take it one further to say that
security also a story about quality of life because, you know,
we've always had in the past, you can have security or you can have usability,
but you can't have both.
Right.
Well, the reality is if we're going to have security, it has to be used.
You know, you just, you just hit on, I,
I put something on Twitter right before we started recording actually, is that
I think Mozilla released a report showing that after lets and crypt came out
SSL you know, TLS has increased dramatically the use on servers, right?
Because they need security usable,
right. So saying security or usability, I think is
that that is an invalid argument,
we have to make secure, usable, right. There's no other option.
Yeah.
Well, and, and the thing too is, is easily used security is, you know,
it's going to get used, people are going to recommend it.
You know,
I think a great example would be um
you know, like the iphone passcode, it just your phone's encrypted.
End of story, just enter your passcode,
you know.
Um And that's, I think for example,
why end to end email encryption has always been such
a disaster is because from a usability point of view,
even with like a good plug in, like I have uh you know,
Thunderbird with P GP mail plug in
and it's pretty painless, right?
You click the little block icon and the little pencil icon.
Although it was never clear to me why you would sign
or why you would encrypt but not sign email but whatever.
And you know, if you don't have the remote person's key, it'll be like, oh,
you don't have the remote person's key, shall I go find it?
And you're like, sure, whatever, you know,
good luck and it goes to the key servers and it downloads the key and it says, well,
this key, you know, it says like, it has the right email address.
So, like, shall we run with that? And it's like, well, what the heck do I know? Right.
And,
you know, they, they've tried to do their best,
but I recently ran into a situation where I
was emailing with somebody and then their key expired.
Right. Like, it literally expired, like, over the weekend or whatever.
And,
you know,
common sense goes well, having an,
an expired key and using it for another 24 hours
or 48 hours probably isn't the end of the world.
But P GP
you know, email plug in will just flat out. Wouldn't let me
whi which I think is the correct decision
in the context of this. However,
I, I must say your description of what you have to do to use this plug in
was very rude. Goldberg
and normal people would never do that.
Right. We take a lot for granted.
Yeah.
And I mean, that's the point, right?
I used to sign on my email,
I signed it for a period of three years and then one day I stopped
-- and nobody noticed or cared.
-- I, I never check email signatures
because
who cares? Like, I
mean,
like now if you sent me a mail
that was signed
with extremely questionable content will say
I might check that.
But generally speaking,
if we're just chatting about whatever normal silly things we chat about are,
you know, like you sending me a new story.
I'm not gonna be like, oh is this really from Kurt before I open it?
No, I'm just gonna click the damn link. You know that, that's how it is.
-- So you heard that
-- everybody? That's right. That's right.
You can send me mail as Kurt and I will click the link every time.
Yeah, I mean,
I, you know the thought of like for example,
trying to get my mom to do encrypted email or, you know, like something like that.
I just know
the thought of trying to get my parents to do encrypted email. Like I have, oh
horror, horror is in my mind right now. I I'm not even going to think about it.
Well,
and more to the point you'd be way better off just spending time on getting
them to like have a automated backup solution that would be way more effective and,
you know, talking about quality of life, you know,
I, I remember I was at the Apple store getting uh my tablet fixed for something and
of course they always ask, you know, like, did you back this thing up?
And of course everybody in the store is like, um
may, may. No.
And so then the, you know, the tech is like, well,
is there anything on here that you really need?
Like, you know,
obviously we we're gonna need to do
a restoring your phone because whatever reasons,
right?
And it's gonna wipe everything and you're gonna have to, like,
download all your apps and blah, blah, blah.
And they're like, oh, ok.
Well, I do have some photos on this phone. 00, ok.
Well, you know, and,
and it turns out like every single one of them
had data on the phone that they wanted to keep
when they thought about it. But
at first question, you know, they always were like, oh, no,
there's nothing on this phone.
You can just blow it away
and the texts, like, are you absolutely certain?
Because I know you say that and I know you're lying.
You know,
and every single one was, you know, they, it took a while for them to think about it.
Right.
It's like, you know,
is there something in the glove box of your car that you really deeply care about
first?
-- You know,
-- I
can
say
I have no
idea.
I have no idea.
If, if you,
if you told me you would give me a million
dollars to identify three things in my glove box.
I probably couldn't do it
because I have, I, I think there might be a flashlight in there.
I
assuming that my kids haven't like, thrown it away.
The, the manual for the car is probably in there
and I may have thrown some mcdonald's napkins in there at some point,
but I'm, I'm only like 50% sure
any of those things are even in there,
anything past that would be like a surprise.
Yeah, exactly.
So, you know, people are terrible at remembering all these things because,
you know, that's, that's the reality of it.
And
so I think, you know, yeah, going to quality of life. I mean, that's why,
you know,
I personally, you know, when somebody asked me what computer to buy now I'm, like,
don't get a tablet.
-- Yes, I, I do the same thing, you know,
-- or a chromebook if you really,
really need a keyboard,
you know,
one of my sons really wants a computer right now to play Minecraft with mods.
And the
-- thought of having
-- modern
Minecraft on a, on a chromebook.
I don't know if you can, but then that's the problem.
He might need like a quote unquote real PC.
And I'm just like, oh God, you know, I'm like, I have to set up this PC and lock it down
and, you know,
whatever man just set it up. So it like reims itself every time it boots
like.
Right.
You know, that's, that's a couple of hours of my time, my quality of life, you know,
I don't want to spend time doing that.
He, you can just play, I, you know, he can play Minecraft on his ipad. It just works.
It's not my problem.
Oh, man,
I, I know, I know, I know this story.
I'm dealing with it as well with my Children, but I, I'll tell you what, let's, uh,
let's improve the quality of life.
Of our listeners and let's end it here.
This has been a, a fantastic discussion to say the least.
And, and of course, as always, if you want the show notes or you want to
find Kurt and my Twitter handles, go to open source security podcast.com.
Again, if you have any comments, let us know.
We love feedback by all means, give it to us
and I guess, go and enjoy the rest of your day and,
and thanks for listening, everybody.
Yeah. And I guess
maybe check if you are backing up your systems just, you know, like
-- once in a while that's
-- right, back up your stuff.
-- All right, folks
-- also change the batteries in your smoke alarm, please.
Life lessons from Kurt.
Kurt. Have a good one. Thanks.