Send mail will outlive both of us.
That is absolutely true.
Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner and hopefully never running a mail server again.
-- Josh Pressers.
-- I
will never run a mail server again.
I am confident in saying that apart from the fact
that I'm just not confident enough to do it anymore.
It's such a just,
it's like a den of snakes now on the internet when you're running a mail server.
Well, the other problem is nobody actually wants a
mail server. What they want is
mail, calendaring, file sharing,
collaborative file editing.
Ideally, appointment scheduling, spell check.
They want grammar check like they, they want the whole suite
when they say email. And,
and here's the trick.
Email is the only
sensible working push messages system we have
and I don't count S MS.
It's, it's email.
Email will,
email will last until the sun explodes because
we don't have another push system and we never
will.
Well, we'll never have a new push system because it's been tried multiple many,
many times and they never get traction because,
well, they're basically not as good as email to begin with mostly.
-- And somebody else controls them and wants money for it. Pretty
-- much.
I get it. Actually. It's funny you bring this up because I set up D
mark on my domain, like, some time ago
and there's a service. What is the power D mark? I think. You, you showed it to me
because they gave it to us for free.
Yeah, I've had it, I've had it configured,
like for a year and I basically wasn't looking at it and
I've had some issues with people complaining my mails are going into spam
and I thought, ok, I need to like, figure out what, what have I screwed up?
Like, did I break something?
And I look and like DKIM is set up, I've got what SPF is working, right? All that stuff.
You're like me only use Google now like you're just, it's gmail, that's it.
Yeah, it's all Google 100% Google. It's like I'm like, oh wait, I have power D
Mark set up. Let's see what it says.
And like half of the mail being sent for my domain
is coming from like freaking scammers in Eastern Europe and,
but I had my, my D
mark, what do they call the policy or something? I forget what it is,
the policy I had it sent to none.
Yeah.
So just observe,
-- basically I
-- just said it to reject and now
obviously anyone trying to send mail is me from,
not me gets thrown in the bin
if the mail servers beve incorrectly.
A lot of them actually kind of ignore reject and set it as quarantine some of them.
But
well, by some of them, like I think office.com still does it
maybe
the people I've been dealing with. So it's, it's gmail, right? Gmail.
Users were seeing my mail in their spam folder sometimes.
And so I, I know Gmail will do this, right?
So yeah, that's that.
No, it's I love that like at the CS A we're up 97.9.
Uh sorry, it's 97.7% of our email is dr compliant.
And when I look now like
it's all spammers, like I click on each of the IP S and it's,
it's not like 10 to 50 spam list
which
I am shocked at how many spoofed emails are sent out. Like
I,
you know, like I just,
I didn't think it was that many but it is
which and I mean,
and this is with like gmail doing all the
-- heavy lifting and patching and running the mail
-- server.
Ok. So II I just pulled it up. 81% of the mail sent for my domain today is junk.
It's shocking how much especially I I suspect part of it is because
we have old domain names like they're more than 10 years old.
Probably.
No dude. My email address is like a rash on the internet. It can't get rid of.
It's just, it's everywhere because it's so old.
Well, and my theory is that they basically keep trying and testing domains
to find when they become
misconducting. Somebody tried,
what was it? Eight character long,
like random
letters uh like dot Cloud security lines.org, like tried
it was they tried 100 and 81 different subdomains that
were randomly generated from 100 and 81 different IP addresses.
So obviously they have tooling like they have some system but you know,
they say like go test is
and I think they were trying to see if we had like insecure
sub policy or something said, I don't know. But like, I'd never seen that before.
I've only seen it the one time in like five years.
So it's clear that like
they have automated the heck of us, they've got good tools and like, well, I mean,
-- because spam is still a problem,
-- it's
OK.
I
just realized something we're going on and on
about Demark and spam and all this stuff
and we should explain what this is because
there's going to be people listening who don't,
don't have a clue what we're talking about.
So in the world of email,
there,
you have a domain, right?
Like breast.net, in my case,
and breast.net has what's called an MX record
which tells people sending email where to send my
mail,
right? In my case, it's going to Google, right?
And everything was fine and we use that for
a long time and then people started sending spam
right where they were pretending to be, they would find open relays,
whatever they would send spam saying, oh, I'm Josh Ha ha.
Look at me but they weren't really right.
And then we got these things at
-- SPF is Center policy framework, center
-- policy framework. And,
and it's simple, it basically says who or what is allowed to send it
Email is from this domain and it can be an IP address, it can be a host name,
it can be also a look up record like sales force does that.
And so the idea was like you could say
only Gmail and Sendgrid and this IP address of this
mail server I run are allowed to be pressed on that
for outgoing email
and that kind of worked for a while except the problem is you have major players
that are
doing email for multiple people and don't
always like separate their tenants properly and,
and shared IP S
this is one of the problems I see is because
I use the Google MX hosts
that
there's so many of them that a lot of the SPF
tests are like this isn't a host in your domain.
We don't know what's going on, right?
Like something weird is happening,
we think except that's normal in every instance.
So then we got dkim, which I don't know dkim
-- stands for. Do you know what dkim? Stands for
-- domain keys identified male. Yeah.
So basically you publish a public key in your DNS
and
the private keys used to sign on your email.
And actually what I love about this is less from a spam perspective,
although it is useful for preventing spam,
but we're really
shines is essentially all
DKIM email is now
-- evidence grade evidence.
-- That's probably true.
Actually, if there's a DKIM signature, yeah, you can prove it right.
Because it's cryptographically signed.
Like you, you can't monkey with the time stamps. You can't say,
oh, I didn't send it.
Well, well, your server with the private key sent it at this time.
Right?
But now, now it should be, it should be said though that SPF and DKIM, they,
they fail a lot in many environments.
-- They
-- used to fail a lot recently. I've noticed over the last year or two
it's changed a lot.
And I, I think simply put the reason is,
is because fewer people are running their own broken mail servers.
-- I mean, that's probably true.
-- I used to get enough reports in Power D
mark from the um,
the L A Department of Water and Power that it
showed up because they were like forwarding email or something.
It was broken. And so I was getting
Angeles,
Los Angeles Department of Water and Power.
Yeah,
it was, it was noisy enough that it showed up like it was in the top 50 of my thing.
And I'm like, what's, what's L A DWP, whatever, blah, blah, blah.com.
And I look it up and I'm like, oh, it's the L A Department of Water and Power
and,
and then at some point they fix their system or another good one was duke.edu.
They have two main mail servers that were just
not configured right in some way.
And for the longest time they were in the top 10 of like, broken,
like your email is not properly SPF or Deacon signed.
And I'm like, yes, it is.
And then like one day it just went away like they fixed it. And so what I've noticed is
I used to get a ton of these false reports.
They've all gone. There
are no more.
-- I mean, that's cool. I, I hope to get there someday and
-- a part of it probably is
because if your mail is that badly configured
and you're bouncing email from like gmail,
that's like what, 50% of email on the internet now.
Right. Exactly.
You don't, you don't want to be bouncing email from gmail and,
and there's other things too that, that people have been doing in the,
-- in the universe of, of spam prevention,
-- the blacklist or block list.
-- Sorry.
-- Right.
And then we end up with, with D
mark, which I just pulled this up.
It stands for Domain message authentication reporting
and D mark kind of has two pieces to it
there. Is
you, you configure it, it's configured in DNS, of course, as all these things are,
again, we have nothing else.
How else am I going to publish information about my domain?
-- I mean,
-- what can you trust? Right.
Because you can't ask the mail server because an evil mail server is gonna be like,
oh yes, I'm definitely Kurt and you should definitely trust all of this mail.
But anyway, so, so we have Dar
and in Dar, you can configure kind of a place to send.
Uh I, I guess information about email, right were good or bad.
Well, reports of the email,
like I received this email from supposedly from breast on
that and it was for example SPF compliant or not
-- decom compliant or not. And
-- then it also has a policy where you have none,
you have quarantine and you have reject and that tells the remote mail server
-- if you have a male that fails DKIM or SPF, what should you do with
-- it?
And it's a little more so than that, you can also set SPF and DKIM
policy of like, be relaxed or be strict.
And then so like, that's
what I did with the CS A is of course, at first I had a policy of none because it's like,
observe and report like just,
you know, we're going to sit tight and assess. Exactly.
And you know, and, and I went from like, uh DKIM and SPF from like relaxed to like, ok,
I'm like over 95%.
Set it to strict. OK. That's working,
you know, and then went from none to quarantine. OK?
Nothing too terrible happened then to reject because
like for c.org it was simple c.org, this is Gmail. That's it. Like my SPF record is
include gmail.org minus all my DKIM is like here the Google Selector key
and my D mark is like if it's not from Gmail don't take it.
Whereas the CS A we have like, you know,
like seven mail services we use plus a bunch of,
I had to break stuff into subdomains because SPF has a 10 record.
-- Look up, blah, blah, blah.
-- And that's where things get difficult,
you know.
But the point is it's, it's doable now.
And like I said, I've, I've seen way less false positives because
if you don't have your email set up, right?
People aren't going to get
-- it.
-- We just spent
a lot of show
talking about a
functionally D mark which I'm OK with because I love this.
But we actually have a better topic than just this.
But wait, it gets worse.
So you've done all this SPFD, Kim D mark stuff to dip battle spam.
But hey, you can patch your server. OK? So let's play a game. Guess how many CV ES
there were in Microsoft Exchange so far this year
in OK. So it's, it's October of 2022 at the time of recording. It's the end of October.
So patch Tuesday for October would have come. So that's 10 months,
I would guess. 100.
Oh, well. Ok. You're way, way more pessimistic. Uh, no, it's like 3030 two.
That's not that bad.
-- I would have expected way worse than that.
-- Ok. But let's see, we got a 9.8 we got a 9.8
we got a,
we got some, like, pretty critical remote code execution ones
that's fair.
There have been some really,
really bad exchange issues and maybe that's why
I overestimated it because I assume if,
if they're fixing a 9.8 there's probably like six other lows,
but no one's paying attention to those.
Ok. So exchange is terrible. Ok, let's get rid of exchange and run something else.
Well, we need something that does email calendar and all that stuff. So
the most obvious one that comes to mind is
-- the
-- only other one I can think of is Zambra.
And I know they've also had some terrible issues in the last couple of months.
They've had a bit of a rough year. So guess,
-- I mean, how many have they had, let's say 30
-- 20
but let's see, 9.8339 0.8
like three, basically
-- code execution.
-- They've had a rough, a rough year.
Weirdly, they had a really quiet last year but, and then in 2020.
-- But anyways, how was
-- exchange last year? Can you look up the number of exchange?
I Ds last year. I bet they had a quiet year also. Then is my suspicion.
-- Uh,
-- there was that
one and then to the next page. Um, ok, about another 20. Let's go to the next page.
Uh, oh, ok. Another page. Ok. Basically two pages of results.
So, like, what is that? 40 ish 40.
Yeah, about 35.
-- So
-- that's, that's on track for what we're seeing for this year. Basically.
So. Ok.
Well,
ok,
we obviously have to run these things because like, if you use exchange,
you can't just get rid of it.
Like you can't just be like, hey, folks, you know that thing,
you used to do all your calendaring, email and documents.
We're getting rid of it. Good luck.
Well, there's another piece to that though and, and this is,
I think it was Will Dorman did a lot of work on this on Twitter.
I'll put a link to Will's Twitter account and you can dig through his stuff, but
a
lot of people are running like active directory on
Prem which then gets tied in with exchange in really
weird ways you have to and you can't like,
replace any of this stuff.
If it's running your infrastructure, you're basically locked in forever.
The only thing you can reasonably do is forklift it into Azure.
I don't think you can from reading
a lot of exchanges between
Goss the dog and will that I won't, I don't totally understand because
-- Goss the dog used to work at micro soft
-- when I say that I'm kind of lying.
It's technically theoretically possible.
-- I don't
-- think it is from reading their stuff. It's not possible at all.
Like, if you're talking, oh, perfect example. Let's pick on Maersk.
Right. Because remember Maersk
almost died to not pay yet.
But the only reason they survived is they had that one,
a DS server in Africa that was powered off and they pulled
out of it.
Yeah, if you have something like that, you know, you're not moving to Azure because
it's just not, you know, like I'm saying,
if you have like a small medium business with
like two A DS servers and like 100 people,
you can,
yeah, you can basically forklift it into Azure. It won't be pretty, but it's doable.
But if you have like a major like fortune 500 sit up.
Yeah, that's what you're stuck with
and, and
it's just too damn complicated
and that even assumes like your software is up to date and compatible because,
you know,
-- I
-- mean, so look, look up post fix. I mean, the postfix is probably the next, we'll say
most reasonable mail server. I would say that I would expect someone to use.
-- Postfix
-- has
like
-- one so far this year it had a critical two criticals last year.
-- One is not enough.
One tells me no one's using it.
No, no, it's got, it's got an average of a couple a year.
And
the thing you forget though is that postfix is actually really well architected.
Right.
It's got that master process and then it's got all the sub processes that run with,
like,
not root. And that really does tend to save it a lot.
And then send mail has as one from last year, one from this year one. You know,
it's, I think part of it too is s
mill and postfix 27 years old at this. Well, no, they're actually older than that.
They're like 30 years old. Well, postfix only.
Yeah, whatever point is they're very old, relatively mature.
They've been beat up and more to the point.
I think a lot less people are looking at them than they used to because,
well,
not Microsoft Exchange.
Right. Oh, absolutely. Absolutely. 100%.
And then if you look at exim because like XY, is that like, oh, it's secure blah,
blah blah thing.
There's like four of them from this year.
One of them is critical exim before 4.95 has a heat
based buffer overflow for the alias list and host name.
-- Look up in host dot C when center host name is set. Oh, that's, that's a bad
-- one.
Honestly, I feel like any mail server today.
They, they should be in Rust or something.
Don't?
I feel like every single piece of code that's doing DNS lookups needs to be like,
especially paranoid
because here's the thing I love about it is number one as an attacker,
I control that DNS reply to an absurd degree.
Like I can send binary code.
And number two,
it's actually one of the only things you can really
reliably trigger a DNS look upon is a mail server.
Uh, it's certainly one of them. Yeah.
Well, because you have a web server public facing
and if you're doing DNS lookups in real time to do logging or something,
you're insane.
Yeah, I know
-- a lot of time with
-- email. Yeah. Email has to for anti spam and SPF and all that
stuff that,
you know,
and
so, yeah, I mean, if I had any DNS code that was running in an email server context,
man, I,
-- I'd be so paranoid but
-- regardless, regardless it's
relevant.
Well, the point is we're still making these mistakes 20 some years later.
Well,
we're not though because I think if you look at the vast majority of organizations,
they've migrated to things like
gmail or office 365 or even just running exchange on Prem,
which does suck for its own reasons,
but it's still not trying to maintain like your own, you know, UNIX infrastructure.
But like exchanges. I mean, did you read the past
of where he tried to patch exchange up to date? Like it's, it's impossible.
Oh, my goodness. That was, that was
Gussie the dog. He, he started with a version of Microsoft Exchange
-- 2000
-- 16.
-- Right, and tried to, which
-- is like the second last version,
right.
Apply all the Microsoft patches to bring it up to
current patch state and it did not go real good.
Let's say we'll put a link in the show notes. It was a travesty for sure.
But I, I think this is,
it's not surprising if you are a human being
managing servers these days. Like it, it's not better than it was 20 years ago.
It's still terrible.
Oh, it's worse. The complexity.
This is fundamentally what the, what the topic today started out as is
the real reason we came up with this is because, uh Michael Zaluski, who's what?
Cam
Tuff on Twitter? Ok. I got that right. I think, I hope I did.
He put,
he had a blog where he talked about infosec stuff and he basically
put a post up that said I'm sick of running this blog.
It's too much work. I'm done.
Right. Follow me on Twitter. Here's my substack.
Well, and he was also pointing out that there's kind of potential for a downside,
significant downside if somebody takes real offense to you
or worse the company does and decides to,
because I've had that happen.
I've had companies threaten me over what I've said publicly,
-- not so much recently back in the day, but,
-- but regardless you get the idea is then,
then the discussion curtain I inevitably had is just the
fact that like running a mail server running a blog,
any of this stuff.
It,
it sucks. Like,
like we use uh wordpress for open social Security podcast.com
and I just turned off all the comments because I don't even want to deal.
I don't want to think about it. I don't want to deal with it.
Like no comments, you want to comment, you go to Twitter and I'll delete your tweet.
Like I don't care.
You know,
I consistently read the blog of, you know, one of my favorite,
favorite authors and the amount of time he has to put
into with one or two other mods to police and comments.
He has a pretty small relatively sane community and even still he
has to like yellow and red card people and like it's just
-- no, I'd rather go drink a beer and watch TV.
-- This is Charles Strauss, isn't it?
Yeah.
Right. Because that's the only blog I know that accepts,
doesn't Schneier's
blog accepts comments too. Right?
And I comment there once in a while and,
-- and
-- again, I think he's nuts but whatever.
Well, I I'm pretty,
I'm pretty sure there's like there's an
approval like you have to be approved because
no, no, because
you don't have to authenticate you just put
in like your name and email address and comments
basically and then like it sits there for a while and then magically shows up later.
So I'm pretty sure it's just manual
approval of everything which like at a certain scale works
-- could be
-- if you're also willing to live with. Latency.
Yeah. Yeah.
Well, then he's probably paying a service or something to, to deal with this crap.
He's probably, there's probably,
I imagine there's people that would be happy to do that for him for free just to,
you know,
given his stature and his kind of just his deal in the universe.
I think that it makes sense.
I mean, it's probably worth it to him to allow comments to his blog.
-- Well, and there's some good comments there, but
-- sure. Sure. Right. Totally.
And so anyway, the point is like,
the point of all this is the conversation curtain I have is just about
the fact that like running a lot of this infrastructure these days is horrible
for a million reasons, mostly
to
-- quote
-- that one. I'm going to misquote it. But basically they said, like
your project is finally complete when you have
to build like a content moderation system.
Right?
I've seen, I've seen things like that because I mean, it's funny actually because
I had this discussion with people more than once if you look
at a service like Twitter or Facebook or kind of anything.
And there's always this
idea of, oh, we should have this like utopian free speech zone or whatever.
And it's like
you have no idea what kind of garbage is going to appear on here.
Like you can't just let people do whatever they want,
I live in Edmonton and we have like, people on street corners with bullhorns
talking about stuff that is not very nice, let's just say,
and they're out there consistently, like,
even in winter and it's cold out there and
that's a lot more effort than commenting on Twitter.
Right.
And so my point is like,
if somebody will go to a street corner consistently and do stuff like,
they'll probably also hang out on Twitter and say mean things to people.
Oh, totally. Absolutely.
100%.
And, and so,
I mean, the, the content moderation,
I don't want to get into that because that's like a whole another bag of worms.
Content moderation is basically impossible because no matter what you do,
-- it's like
-- spam, right?
It's spam.
If you have an audience of one person,
you can probably say something without offending them too much.
10 people. Sure, 100 people, probably 1000 people.
But if you say something to a million people, like,
well, anyways, I can't find the tweet right now, but basically, uh hacks were pan
posted like kind of like,
I like ice cream and then, you know, the replies that they would get are like,
I'm lactose intolerant that's insensitive of you or like, you know,
ice cream killed my father or ice cream promotes diabetes or like whatever,
whatever, whatever and like,
you can't even
like,
no matter what you say, somebody on the planet will be offended by it
-- definitely
-- circles are round and I bet I just made some mathematician twitch.
I mean, are they? I don't know.
I feel like I'm going to have to do some research on this. They're not square.
-- I'm comfortable saying that. Are they? I guess
-- not, not in our geometry.
-- I don't,
-- I don't know.
-- What is the definition of round? I don't know. Oh,
-- interesting.
A circle is a round shaped figure that has no corners or edges.
Doesn't it have to have at least one edge.
Does it have an edge? I don't know.
I don't know. I don't know.
Well, here's OK.
OK.
-- There's no
-- difference between circle and round.
I'm
just,
I'm not going down this hole,
-- but that's
-- the
-- point,
-- right?
Like no matter what we say, like the world is round, people are gonna be like, no,
it's an
ate spheroid,
you know.
Well,
no,
no, I'm pulling us out of this hole and we're talking about
the fact that running your own infrastructure is hard and in many cases impossible.
And, and I think sometimes short sighted when I was young,
I ran a lot of infrastructure
and there were two pieces to that. There was a fact that I, I value
the learning I got from it and now I'm
not saying no one should run their own infrastructure.
You will learn a lot if you do this and
I learned an amazing amount about the internet and everything.
But I also recognize that when I was young, I had a lot more free time than I have now.
So I was willing to invest hours a week into maintaining my infrastructure.
I don't have hours a week anymore to maintain infrastructure,
which is why I'm happy to just give Google some money
and say deal with this crap for me. Thank you.
Well, and I think that's part of the challenge, right?
Is if running infrastructure and doing operations was like doing
new things all the time and only doing new things,
I would 100% be into that.
But it's not, it's adding a user deleting a user, adding a user deleting user.
So it's doing repetitive things
that aren't really gonna teach you a lot
when you're running infrastructure for like a company. That is true.
But when I was running my infrastructure, it would be things like, oh,
I'm seeing spam from this domain.
How can I make this spam go away?
And I would then do some reading about anti spam and I'd learn about blacklisting.
I learn about Bay
and filtering and whatever.
And I learned a lot from that, right?
-- But
-- like applying patches every first Tuesday of
the month or second Tuesday of the month.
If you run Linux, it's like every day
and that's not super useful. It's just a time sync.
Uh No. OK. I disagree with that though. When I was learning.
-- Well,
-- the first few times you learned something. But then
no, no, II,
I usually learn something because I almost always
broke my server when I applied patches.
Be it a configuration file changed?
Or some library was moved or some crazy hack I
was using suddenly didn't work because they fixed the bug.
I needed like whatever.
And so again,
when it's
view it as a learning experience, I think it has value.
But as an old man who just wants email, it is totally not worth it.
And I think, I mean, you know,
Cam
is in the same boat where he wants to talk about stuff
and he just doesn't want to deal with the crap anymore.
And he wasn't even running the blog. It was on what blog spot. Right.
-- Yeah. So it was just a matter of like, I'm sick of the crap, I'm
-- out.
And I mean, it's funny because we're doing this podcast and I mean,
what's weird to me is we don't actually
get much hate,
which I'm, I'm always a bit shocked by that.
-- Somebody isn't more offended by what we said.
-- Well, there's two pieces to that.
I think
first of all,
we are mindful of what we say on purpose because there has been more than one time,
one of us has told the other you can't say that
and then
because it's not live, I fix it later, right?
So there's that angle because there, there have been some doozies
you have to listen to it.
Like you can't just search the internet for it or, you know, it's like,
I think that's one of the aspects of the written text piece is like, it's,
it's faster to consume and especially things like Twitter
because they're so short, you know, they lack context.
-- Oh, absolutely.
-- I don't know.
Maybe, maybe the people that hate us get bored of listening to us probably
look,
there have been people who have sent us many emails explaining why we're wrong.
Well, that's different though.
I'm ok with somebody telling me I'm wrong but just saying I hate you or whatever.
Yeah. No, we've never gotten anything like that.
But even when people say we're wrong,
I try really hard to be like I'm going to
understand this and I do some research and I'll,
I tried to give them a legitimate reply.
That's like here is why we talked about this
the way we did or sometimes we're wrong and we
were the ones,
remember when we didn't check that source on that article about Apple,
we did check the source.
It was correct at the time and then it disappeared overnight
because we recorded like on a Wednesday,
we published on a Sunday in the freaking
news article we based our entire said that was
-- some Apple podcast. It was the
-- copyright, the
copyright one
that was so embarrassing but whatever. But again, OK, here's the deal.
Here's a great example.
We screwed that up big time.
And I'll never forget I get, I got some Twitter messages.
I'm like, this can't be right.
And I started furiously looking, trying to prove, prove I'm right.
Which is a normal human reaction. I'm like, ok, at some point I was like, I got it.
I, I'm, we're wrong. Like we screwed this up
and this was like six o'clock in the freaking morning.
I immediately went upstairs to my recording station.
I recorded a new intro that was basically like,
we screwed this up everyone. Sorry about that.
You know, you can listen if you want,
but it's all lies and then I appended the audio file and it's still there.
So anyway, anyway, but that's, that's
regardless, regardless of all this.
The,
the other reason I think that we don't get a lot of
hate is we don't have a massive audience like we're talking about,
I think, what do we get? We get most of our episodes first day, 2000 downloads
and then we'll maybe hit 4000 by the end of the
week and then after one week it's like zero functionally.
That's hang on
-- a second. What is the math on
-- that? It's not that many. It's not that great. Right?
It's enough. But, and I shouldn't say that that's not 4000 downloads.
That's 4000 unique downloads because
the, the system recently changed how they, they used to measure raw downloads,
which our numbers were like amazing.
But obviously some people are downloading it many times.
-- So,
-- so every week we are wasting 2.5 months of people time.
I am so proud of us.
We're not wasting OK. Look. OK.
So, so here's another part of this and this is something quite serious.
And I want to like,
like the audience should hear this as well is
every now and then we try to be self deprecating
and
I, I was reading kind of a,
a beginner podcast thing and one of the bits of
advice was don't be too self deprecating and don't,
don't make jokes like,
oh no one listens or things like that because there are people listening.
And
if you, like, you are doing your audience a disservice by self-deprecating,
you're suggesting they're idiots if they're listening
to you and you self deprecate.
So like we do it a little bit because I acknowledge like Kurt
and I are like old and stupid and I'm fine with that,
but it is fun.
-- And we do have, we'll say a wealth of experience that I'm, I love sharing.
-- Well, it's,
you know what, it's more that we have a wealth of unique experience.
That's fair because that's most people thank goodness,
will never have to do what we've done.
And you've done some horrible, like we've seen and build some horrible
stories and,
and luckily a lot,
like there's actually quite a lot of what we do that's just kind of gone now where it's
Well, the cloud.
Oh, no. Absolutely. But, but some of it, it's funny
because every now and then, like, a weird thing will happen and, like,
I, I understand like, I PV for networking or something and I know how to do, like,
routing and stuff.
People are like, oh, how do you do that? It's like, just don't even ask.
-- It's like
-- the whole Blockchain shenanigans thing.
I'm like, this is just the.com thing 20 years later,
like search and replace Web with Blockchain.
Anyway,
we're in the weeds, we're in the weed.
I want to bring us back so we can end this show at some point in the near future.
I guess the question is. So there's kind of two things here doing an activity
typically has an upside. That's why people do it.
That's why they smoke cigarettes and eat sugary foods and stuff.
I want candy
and then there's also potentially downsides and some of them are like,
very long term, like getting lung cancer and some of them are only potential, well,
like getting lung cancer.
But
the thing is especially with this kind of professional writing.
Yeah, there's the potential to like,
really stick your foot in your mouth and make people hate you or get, I guess fired.
Even if you say something offensive enough.
I think if we think about it in the context of running your own exchange service,
right.
The, the, there's,
there's obviously upsides if you're doing it one of the upsides might be just,
I can't move, like I've done it for so long.
There's downsides, you know, migrating this stuff is hard
and it's not, it's not free.
Like, I,
I can't imagine what it would be like
to migrate a reasonably sized infrastructure from,
say on prem exchange to office 365.
It's, there'd be so many problems. I can't even fathom it.
It's, um, you basically, uh, you pay Microsoft money
to do it
because like, there's no alternative, like
-- that's probably
-- fair.
But even then there's gonna be problems and you're the one,
if you're the it person in charge, you're the one who gets blamed
and you could say it's because Microsoft screwed it up, people are gonna be like,
don't even care, I'm playing you,
you know,
but coming back to all this, I think,
I mean,
one aspect is there's kind of this weaponization
of audiences potentially and weaponization of outrage and,
you know, all that,
which
honestly is,
it's rare enough that it makes the news kind of thing, right?
Like it's actually not super duper common and, but on the flip side, I get,
I honestly, my, my,
my personal thought is the majority of this boils down to most people,
you know, they got
other things they want to do with their life and not, you know,
blog or write or do a podcast or whatever, like they wanna
hang out with their kids,
which is totally fine.
That's the key, right? Is we all have limited time in our days
and it's a question of what do you actually want to be doing?
And this is even true when you're working your day job.
Do you want to be patching servers or do you want to be doing something else?
And that's, that's really the question and that,
that's what we all have to grapple with.
And I think that that kind of sums it up
is all of this, all of this, you know, running infrastructure,
everything is all about like, what do you actually want to be doing?
In some cases you're going to learn and the
experience is worth it and totally do that.
And don't, don't like, don't feel that
I know there are probably exchange admins
that
have friends who give them no end of grief because they're running exchange.
But here's the deal if you want to do it and you like doing it and it's working out,
who cares what they think? Good job for you, you know.
But at the same time, you're an exchange admin and you don't wanna be like,
life's pretty short.
I'd go, I'd figure something out, you know.
Anyway. All right, I'm calling this one. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you for listening.
Go to open
source security podcast.com. Hit up the show, not, it's easy Pound
Osis podcast. Hashtag to hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.