Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
and my partner and
closing bugs, I guess, Josh Pressers.
Yeah. I'm always wondering how you're going to do that little intro because
I, I have no idea what Kurt is going to make up. And
-- sometimes it makes sense and sometimes it doesn't
-- true.
But we actually, both of us used to aggressively close bugs when we worked at Red Hat.
I love closing bugs. Nothing makes me happier than closing bugs.
-- Yeah.
-- So what triggered?
This is, uh, the, one of the main emacs developers closed, uh,
45% of the open emacs bugs
like good for them.
I mean,
yeah.
And then my favorite thing is the top comment on hacker news.
It actually turns out is the person who filed the bug, but he's like, essentially
I filed these bugs.
There was a big discussion and then it got closed without being properly resolved.
And
from the emacs point of view, it's kind of like, well,
we had this big discussion about these bugs that were more like enhancements
and then we asked you if everything was fixed and you didn't reply for six years.
So we closed it
six years.
Yeah. Was it 2015? Right.
So
2015,
I have
probably a unique perspective on this.
And I know you do too because we were on the receiving end of a large
number of bugs for a very long time and to a degree I still am.
And I think
the thing
that often happens,
especially in open source is people think the
bug tracker is a support portal and not a
bug tracker. And so
there's often a lot of confusion and people get
upset when you do something like close their bug.
But at the same time,
maybe, you know, there, there's a million reasons that could happen.
Anything from it gets fixed.
You didn't provide enough information to,
we tried to have a discussion with you and you never answered, you know, it's,
it's complicated.
I think it's even more subtle than that because
effectively if a user encounters a bug by
definition that is a support issue for them.
They
like it,
they encountered a bug that is stopping them from doing something especially.
And no, but here we get into survivor bias.
The bug is bad enough for them to actually tell you about it, right?
Because I encounter small bugs in software all the time and I'm just like,
whatever it doesn't really matter.
Ignore it. I don't bother filing a bug, right?
Like this,
like just now when we were trying to get the show up
and running and I couldn't join because my camera was disabled.
Right.
And you're actually going to file a bug.
I personally wouldn't bother filing a bug because I'd just be like, whatever,
I'll work around it.
-- Well,
-- so here, there, there's a couple of aspects to this.
Now, we use a service called Squad Casts to record the podcast
and
I have interacted with them,
we'll say five times or less since I and I,
I pay them money like I'm a legitimate customer of theirs.
But the thing is every time I talk to them,
I give them an enormous amount of information
because as someone who receives lots of bugs,
I give them way more than they need. I mean, I will give them HTTP headers.
I will give them like versions of everything, versions of the operating system,
versions of the kernel, versions of Firefox I'm using,
I will go and looking at all kinds of wacky Javascript stuff as part of this.
And so when they are interacting with me,
they're getting a fire hose of details, but that's not always how it works.
The problem there is.
I mean that this goes to all sorts of things around expertise and Dunning Kruger.
But fundamentally,
let me put it this way.
If I could actually describe what was wrong with my car,
I'm like 90% of the way there to fixing it. Ok.
Now let's, let's, let's take that from there and, and we're gonna, obviously,
this is the open source security podcast.
We're going to put that spin on it when I go to the mechanic and I have my car, I say
this something is wrong with my car and they'll, sometimes they'll fix it for.
Sometimes they'll say, ok, we'll look at it. They don't charge me anything.
Sometimes they're like, we're gonna charge you 100 bucks to figure this out. Right.
And it depends
and
imagine if you drove your car up to like some guys at
a park drinking beer next to their cars and you were like,
hey,
uh something's wrong with my car, help me out.
-- They were like, what I mean, that's kind of what open source is like,
-- well,
what the difference being those guys in the park having trying to have a quiet beer.
Their name is on the engine part, that kind of is making a weird noise.
I mean, that's potentially fair,
but I don't think that necessarily changes things at all.
Like
they owe you nothing.
That
source owes you nothing.
Well,
and here's the worst thing too is even
if people politely and respectfully ask for support,
just that alone is a tsunami for a lot of open source developers.
-- It, it can be for sure. Well,
-- I, I got emails asking about the UV I
uh data and I'm like, go file a bug.
I mean, that is the correct answer and, and we'll do a show about what UV I is. Someday.
-- I'll put a link in the show notes for anyone interested.
-- But
part of the challenge is, is
people forget.
It's kind of like public health. And
you found a bug that's your bug. That's a precious bug.
That's your pet bug that you're going to keep in a jar and watch
it grow and evolve into a beautiful butterfly that one day will fly away
to the developer. We're dealing with a plague of Locusts, right?
And that's the thing.
-- It's the scale issue like
-- a bug bounty is a great example of that where
you will have hackers submit a bug to you in the bug bounty
and they'll make it critical. And then when you mark it low,
they get very angry that you basically just call their baby ugly. And it's like
it's not a critical bug, please. Here is the explanation.
-- I I
-- remember without getting into details, a large customer filed a bug,
a specific type of security bug that's not
very impactful and there's an easy work around
and they were flipping out and wanted daily updates on the status of the bug.
And I'm like, no. And they got very shall we say touchy about it?
And the way I ended up shutting them up was saying, look,
here is another example of that exact kind of low level like low level security flaw
that's public
like your bug is not that important and even if it were that important there's,
there's more of those, like, it was cross site scripting.
Right. Like, which
in a web application is very, relatively easy to avoid
on the blind side. But anyway,
yeah.
Well, but, I mean, anyways it's,
and that got them to back off. But,
and that's the thing. Right. They thought they'd found the end of the world bug.
And I'm like,
you know,
it's like that scene from, um,
Street Fighter with Bison. You know, for me it was just another Tuesday.
Right.
I mean, I remember at Red Hat, I, I, at one point I think if you still search the Red Hat
BZ
for my work email address,
um,
it's going to take about two minutes to return the query
and you'll have to click that thing at the
bottom that says show more than 1000 results.
-- Right. Right.
-- You know,
but I mean,
so for me that literally thousands and thousands of bugs was just normal.
I mean, yeah, when, when you work in that environment, I mean, so look,
here is what I think we should, we should turn this into is
when you hear about the emacs project closing 45% of its bugs, you end up with.
Some people are aghast
that they're closing bugs that aren't fixed
and statistically, I'm sure many of them aren't right.
You have people like us who are like, yeah, whatever, who cares?
But
we're,
I mean, anyone who's an open source developer, I think is
in a place that is much different from normal people.
And I think normal people will be horrified by the thought of just closing things
-- just
-- because there's a simple thing here though.
There's a big difference between how open source
handles bugs and how private companies handle bugs.
And the biggest difference being is an open source bug typically is public.
Right? It's, it's all out there in the open on the web indexed in Google.
And typically it's actually really, really easy to reopen the bug.
Uh
right, compared to dealing with a private company
where you report a bug and they say no, it's not a bug, go away
and, and you like have to fight them tooth and nail to get them to listen to you.
Open source is different than that typically. Right?
There's, there's a few antisocial open source projects.
Like I remember I found one open source project,
but in an effort to quote unquote reduce bug spam,
you had to go on to an Irc channel and request
like an account in their bug tracker to file a bug
and a bunch of other hoops and steps to jump through.
And
I was like,
I'm not doing that,
but I had to get a B filed because it was a security issue.
And so I ended up just going straight to one of the developers and
full disclosure is for it just send it to the full disclosure mailing list is fine,
-- pretty
-- much so.
And,
and that's the thing is like working at scale is
different and working in open source is different because again,
you know,
reopening these bugs and adding more information is, is generally quite trivial. I
mean, and
the
doesn't,
they're not deleting it, they're not getting rid of it. It's still there.
You can still find,
you said something just now that I think is hugely important
and often overlooked where you said you can, you can add more information
when you file a bug, especially with an open source project.
The intent should be that the information you give in the initial report
is everything they need to test.
The bug is there and verify,
they fixed it when they fix it and even better is if you can include a patch,
that's the absolute best case because these people are
horribly overworked in virtually every instance.
I don't know of a single open source project.
-- That's like, oh, I wish we had more work to do
-- well.
And again, II, I would think that that's the ideal world,
but realistically the majority of users
cannot describe a problem.
Let alone look at the source code and suss out the problem, right?
-- Because they, they can be quite subtle.
-- I disagree.
I think you can make the argument that not everyone can create
a patch.
I'm perfect that I think everyone will agree with that.
Because there are lots of people who are not developers. But I think
you, if you don't have the ability to describe what is going on in a coherent manner,
you have no business filing bugs.
And I mean, this is similar to like, if you go to a doctor and the doctor's like,
what's wrong and you say, I don't know, they're going to be like, get out,
-- you know,
-- but that does happen. People go to psychologists, what's wrong?
I don't know. I just feel bad.
Something's not right with my life and then they, you know, do tests and stuff and,
and you know, there's those famous
cases where it turns out to be some weird brain tumor.
I don't think that's comparable in this instance, Kurt,
because when you go see a psychologist or,
or some sort of mental health expert discovery is part of that process.
When you're dealing with software bugs, discovery is not part of the process.
I also think a big difference there is those experts are being paid to deal with this.
The open source people are not necessarily being paid to deal with this. And yes.
Yeah. And I think that's part of it is the
sort of expectation of
if you actually care about this bug,
like this bug really affects you like this squad casts thing where OK,
I have to like enable my camera in the web browser
and log in and then turn it off and that works.
Ok. Easy work around, whatever I'll live with it.
But if a bug is actually, you know, very
critical to you, like, you can't get your job done or you,
you're somehow relying on it
and especially it's something you're using and not paying for.
Well, yeah, sorry, man.
Like that's, you might have a bad time.
You might have to go hire somebody to help you with this. Like, if you can't,
like there's a ton of open source people out there that actually work as consultants
and contractors, right?
And I think that's part of it is this, we've, we've grown up with this expectation of
I will use this software for free. Cool.
And that's very explicitly what the license like, that's exactly what we want.
But
I don't remember there being this expectation of support.
No, there's no expectation and, and one of the things that irks me is I know people who
they will have open source and like the critical
path of their application of the product they're creating
and they're like, oh,
I'm not paying anyone for that and then they
get really angry when it breaks and it's like,
that's not how this works if this is in your critical path
and you're unwilling to pay the developer and you're
unwilling to hire anyone to take care of it.
Like there's no way around this like failure is what's going to happen.
That's that is how the story ends.
Well, yeah, that comes down to risk management and,
you know, it, it, it's weird to me that,
you know, a company would never think of, for example,
renting or buying a commercial space and not insuring
it.
Like, and I think that's actually generally illegal in a lot of jurisdictions.
You know,
like my understanding is like, well, for example, if you buy a house,
you have to have house insurance because they, you know, the,
the mortgage holder doesn't want to be left holding
-- a debt on a burnt out pile of rubble.
-- Right. Right. Yes, absolutely.
And that's, but that's literally where some of these, you know,
software firms are when
they have a showstopper bug or worse, you know, a security bug that affects them.
So actually, you know what else this reminds me of is I remember back in the day
this was man, this was redhead in like 2005, maybe 2004
where there is a policy of,
we will only release an update when there is a security issue
and there would be packages that developers wanted to update
and they,
they, they were told no, because our policy is security updates only.
Otherwise you have to wait for the next like major release or whatever,
then they would go and find a security issue just so they could release their bug fix,
which, which that amused me to no end when that would happen.
And, and now now let's,
let's think about this from the security perspective a little bit,
let's say someone reports a security bug to an open source project.
Do you think that they should fix it or, or what if they close it with?
Like, we don't care.
Well, here's the thing
and this is gonna sound really privileged and snarky. But
you have the source code. Fix it your damn self.
-- No, I'm dead damn serious.
-- I don't, I don't disagree with that.
I think
if it's that important to you,
you like a perfect example is Google because I know Google does this.
Google takes a big pile of open source software,
shoves it into their own repo so that they don't have to worry about, you know,
supply chain attacks in future.
They cherry pick the fixes and updates they need
and they have dozens or hundreds of people managing this stuff. Yes, they do.
Ok. Cool. Pretty much.
And it's not just companies building some little
product like an air conditioner or something now,
you know, there's cars and large industrial machinery running on open source,
the world is running out everything, everything is using it
and, and it's stuff that has like a failure scenario of human death, right?
A perfect example being Tesla's autopilot is
being investigated because apparently it has a problem
where it just sort of drives at high speed into the back of emergency vehicles.
Yeah, I saw that I'm still, I still want
the self driving world to work.
But the more I learn about it,
the more or I feel my hopes and dreams being crushed under the boot of reality.
What I find bizarre is
if we're this worried about people dying in cars,
why do we still allow cars to drive without the seatbelts being used?
Because I, this is my favorite thing. I love looking at seatbelt compliance
and in the US it's an average of about 90% of people wear their seatbelts. That's it.
10% don't.
Yeah. And here's the best part of the statistic and this is from 2000 and
the latest data they had, I think it was 2017.
Yes.
47% of the people who died in motor vehicle accidents were not wearing a seatbelt.
I'm shocked to learn that. So seatbelts work.
And actually, it's funny the other day, I was actually,
for whatever reason I normally get in the car, put on my seatbelt, then start the car.
It was just habit.
And for whatever reason yesterday, I didn't do that.
I started the car started moving it out of the garage and was going,
put my seatbelt on.
And I noticed for the first time my car has
like a little warning light and an annoying dinger that,
you know, and I'm like, oh, I've never seen that before because I,
I've been trained to put my seatbelt on since I was a little kid.
I actually remember when seatbelt laws became a thing in Alberta. Right.
Because all of a sudden my dad wouldn't let us play in the back seat anymore.
We had to wear a seat belt.
That's right.
Yeah. The good old days, we also didn't wear helmets while skiing or snowboarding.
-- That was great.
-- Whatever, it's fine. I turned out fine. It's
ok.
-- I just don't remember the number seven very often.
-- It's fine. Seven's a dumb number.
So,
yeah. So
it's interesting to me that humans consistently
will freak out
about a new risk, especially if the perception is that,
that new risk is not a risk that they control.
I mean,
and they will happily accept all these horrible
old risks where they absolutely do control it.
Like wearing your seatbelt
or getting your vaccine or eating more fruit
and vegetables and getting some exercise in.
I mean, they don't always control. Here's one of my favorite examples.
What, what I just thought of as you were describing,
this is the whole like closed source versus open source
debate where I still run into people that talk about.
Oh, but this my my vendor will support it and it's like
your vendors stuff is full of open source and I promise you,
they have no idea what's in it versus open source where it's like here's all the code,
here's what's going on,
go figure it out if you really want to.
But at the same time because people are used to closed source in their mind.
That is safer. Even though I guarantee
that closed source vendor has skeletons on top of skeletons on top of skeletons
in that hole.
Well, I mean,
I just remember back in the day you could
run a binary against strings and search for the,
you know, BS D license,
right? And it would just spew out
because
uh well, TCP/IP related stuff or, well, anything web server or anything,
you know what I mean?
Like?
Yeah.
And, and to be clear,
I would vastly prefer that these companies use
an open source implementation and build their own.
Right.
It's going to be less problematic because the
other thing I'm wondering about is there's this interesting
notion of bugs that kind of matter and bugs that don't.
And one thing I was thinking about prior to this show was,
is there a case
where a bug affects me and makes my life worse?
And I sort of don't
notice in the sense of like, my life is just worse, but I, I can't even pin down
that. It's the fault of something. And
unfortunately, there is one great example and that is in Britain.
Uh Remember when their UK COVID results,
they realized we're all messed up because they were using
an older version of Excel that had a maximum of,
you know, what is it?
Like 65,000 roads.
And so
they're like cool cases have stopped rising.
Yeah.
00 no, wait, just the data is missing.
Um and so obviously, you know, that's a very subtle thing.
You have an Excel spreadsheet missing a bunch
of data upon which public policy is made and
well. Yeah. Whoops.
Well, now, so here's a funny aspect of that as well is
so from the security perspective, I would argue that is a,
it is a definite threat to human life,
but at the same time,
I don't think anyone would claim that
Excel old Excel files only supporting 65,000 rows
is a security vulnerability.
-- There's a solution. Use a newer version.
-- It's not the newer version.
The problem was they were using the old Excel file
format which has a hard limit on number of rows.
-- Whereas the new format supports up to a million. I think it's more than
-- that.
And so it's not, it wasn't the version of Excel they were using, it was the file type.
-- They were saving ads. That was the problem.
-- Yeah. Oh, you're right.
The new one is to the 20th just over a million. Yeah.
But anyways,
so because uh well, a good example of this,
obviously Tesla's autopilot has some problems because it,
there's documented cases of it slamming into high emergency
vehicles with their lights on a high speed.
And there's actually a really terrifying video of a guy
who realizes at the last moment he has to swerve,
right? And it's
uh
you know, this is why II I will never buy something that is
not fully autonomous because there's no way
I can safely use a semi-autonomous vehicle
and pay enough attention to know.
Oh, I'm encountering a problem. I need to go deal with it.
You know, because I'm having a
high speed for that concrete barrier
autonomous or not. There's literally nothing in the middle
and I can
-- see there is
-- this silly the difference being with driver assist where,
you know, for example, like it's going to warn me if uh I'm drifting in my lane,
but I'm expected to be in control.
It's just gonna,
you know what a perfect example being the rumble
strips they put on the side of highways now,
you know where they get those little divis
because II, I do remember one time I was tired and I drifted onto it and I was like, ok,
I gotta stop and rest.
And so that's probably a simple invention that
saved thousands or tens of thousands of lives.
I keep coming back to this.
You know, how do we determine which bugs matter and which bugs needs to be fixed
offset by the fact in the open source world?
Yeah, I mean, if,
if this piece of software is that important to you and
that critical to you and you really need this bug fixed,
you have options, you can pay the developer to do it,
you can pay a developer to do it on your own copy.
And is there a carry cost for that. Absolutely.
Like we both worked at Red Hat where backwards compatibility was the word of the day.
Right.
And Red Hat commits to, you know, supporting Red Hat Enterprise links for 13 years.
I know it's so long and, but the thing is people want that, you know,
they have AC NC milling machine
or
water plant.
Um,
you know, I always love it when people are like, oh, these,
these stupid industrial people still use Windows XP.
It's like, yeah, what do you, what do you want them to do?
Rewrite $20 million with software that runs an oil refinery that can't be shut down.
Right.
You know, like a nuclear power plant.
Do you, do you understand what maintenance costs on those things are?
No, I don't because I'm not, I'm not, I mean, it's done in Kruger.
I imagine it's an enormous number, but I have no idea.
-- Well,
-- and the knock on cost of, oh, sure. We'll just take a couple gigawatts offline
or what if something goes horribly wrong when I
try to shoehorn in a new version of Windows.
Like,
I'm pretty sure the upgrade path from Windows 95 to Windows 10
or 11 is not as smooth as we'd like it to be.
-- I bet
-- there's a youtube video about it.
Well, there is that person who did D
OS 1.0 upgrade all the way to Windows 10.
That is
awesome.
And, and that's, but that's just the U si mean
and shockingly if you do run D OS apps,
they do generally run pretty cleanly on Windows 10 and up.
But,
but back to the
point because they're emulating all of that stuff. Now,
back to this. I think that's the beauty of open sources.
If this,
it's a business risk if you are going to build a business
and build a product on something and not properly support it.
Like, I'm always reminded of these companies that use manufactured parts
and then the manufacture of that part stops making them
well, yeah,
you know, I,
I remember I once had to replace the back windshield wiper
motor on my Dodge caravan back when I had a Dodge caravan
and I explicitly bought a Dodge Caravan because
there's been over 10 million of them made.
So getting parts for them is actually quite easy. But here's what's interesting
when I went to buy the new motor, uh the new blade motor,
it was like an extra $100 which you got back when you brought back the dead
unit because they wanted the casing.
They wanted the casing for it.
They didn't care about the motor, they didn't care about the electronics,
they wanted the physical metal casing back so that if they could
reuse it to make a new,
you know, blade motor, like even though I own the darn thing,
I had to like put a deposit down on it and bring it back to get my money back.
I, I get that. It's like the same thing with batteries where you buy a battery.
They're like, we're adding 25 bucks on.
-- You bring the old battery and we give you 25 bucks back. Like I get
-- that.
I think maybe open
source needs to start doing things like that.
-- The challenge being is that people have gotten used to not paying for stuff, kind
-- of,
I, I think there's a couple of pieces to this.
And so I think on one side,
there are businesses that legitimately just had no idea what was going on
where they didn't understand the developers were going out to stack overflow.
They were yanking open source and they were
doing all this stuff because that's just what
developers solve problems, right? Solving the problem.
If you don't tell them what to do, they're going to solve it whoever they want. Right?
So a lot of organizations suddenly found out, oh, holy crap.
We have open source everywhere, right?
And that,
that was kind of the birth of all
these automated scanners that I complain about incessantly.
I think
these scanners are a good thing because they're,
they're making people start to recognize
this is what you're shipping.
And I mean, this is that whole like s bomb conversation, you know,
we talked to Alan Friedman, what it's been like, I think 10 years now it feels like,
but
like same thing actually Alan's uh switching, he, he just moved from,
uh NTI A to Sisa.
So we should actually talk to him soon again just to figure out what sis is up to.
But anyway, it doesn't matter.
So the point is right,
you've got these people now scanning their stuff
and they're starting to understand what's going on.
I mean, there's a long road, of course,
to deal with because the scanners all have some
issues they need to work out and stuff.
-- But
-- this is like people who,
it's not that they don't know that they have cracks in their foundation.
They're not even aware there's a basement. I mean,
-- there's just like a mystery door.
-- Exactly. That, exactly. That they have no idea.
They have a basement under their house. It's exactly that. Yes.
Now,
so you've got
in that aspect, but now let's say you're a company and you're like, holy crap.
I have this open source everywhere. Now. What?
Right. And that's where you can start looking at some of these things.
Like github has the ability to
throw some money at
maintainers.
You've got companies like Tide Lift that give you the ability to pay maintainers.
And so
I think there's a business model in the works here.
I don't know what it's going to look like.
I, I know,
I feel like it's a big pot of ingredients and
no one quite knows what the soup will be yet.
But
I think we are approaching a place
where companies are recognizing the value
in
investing in this stuff versus the holy crap.
Look at all this free stuff I can use for free and it's like, it's free,
like a puppy guys.
Yeah, I'm going to be a bit of a pessimist and I,
I think we're going to encounter a lot of the same problems that, for example,
the media encounters with trying to get people to pay for content
in that.
There's this sort of tragedy of the commons aspect
where I think a lot of companies will,
well, you know, if we wait long enough,
somebody else might find this bug and pay for it to be fixed.
I mean, maybe. And then
the same conversation we had when we talked about the
eu bug bounties where a lot of these companies just,
they can't go pay some random due.
-- Well, no,
-- no, and they won't. That's why you're going to have to work with github
or Tide Lift or someone like that.
Now, here's the thing I would say about your whole, oh, let's wait for someone else.
I think the place we're going to see the pressure really come from is
lots of customers are scanning the software they get from vendors now.
And so like for example,
I this is basically all I do now for
my job where customers take the products elastic makes
scans them and then says, here's a phone book of results, please fix all of these.
And of course, the, the problem is they don't actually know what they're doing.
So, there's a lot of education I have to do.
I have to explain, like, here's what this scan means.
Here's what's going on here is why your scan will never come back clean.
Now, one of the things that scares me
is
just due to the current kind of lack of understanding of what's going on.
I'm terrified that you're going to see organizations that
start focusing on tricking scanners instead of fixing problems.
Well, absolutely. It's easier.
Well, unfortunately, because like, for example, you'll have a customer say,
uh this has a critical finding.
It's like, no, no, that finding isn't critical,
uh NVD rated it wrong or it's not critical the way we're using it.
There's a million things, right? And they're like, I don't care.
It says critical, you have to fix it. It's like,
no, I'm not doing that.
And there's days it's like, I totally know how to trick the scanner.
Like I could totally do it.
The problem is part of it is you're being asked
to effectively prove a negative which is very difficult.
-- No,
-- no. This, I, I can prove this. This isn't like prove a negative territory.
-- This is I can, well,
-- but you have to prove it in a,
that they'll believe.
And that's the problem.
There's nothing I can say, Kurt, the problem is, there's nothing I can say fix it.
Or screw you is their attitude and that's not helpful.
And then of course, once I talk to them and educate them a bit, I ju
I have yet to have anyone come back with. A, no, you absolutely have to fix this.
Generally when you explain what's going on to them in a way,
they understand it solves the problem.
But that's, that's not scalable either. Right.
I feel like we are on the precipice of all of this getting better.
But there's
an enormous knowledge gap. There is a knowledge gap, the size of a huge canyon
that we have to overcome.
Well, going back to incentives,
part of the challenge is there's a huge incentive for these
scanning companies to produce a phone book of scary looking results.
Well,
yeah,
I paid you for results,
you know,
and I
pay
you for an MD
for art.
The reality is again back to this whole sort of Dunning Kruger car mechanic thing.
If the customer is smart enough to actually
look at those results and truly understand them,
they would be probably mature enough from an information security
point of view to really not need the scanner,
not necessarily there's value in it.
-- I think
-- part of the challenge though is this goes back to that Dunning Kruger car
mechanic thing is if you're mature enough to
properly understand these scanning report findings and everything,
you're you're at a very mature place,
information security wise where these reports are
just not going to be that important.
You know,
what my comparison would be actually is I remember the first house I ever bought,
this was like 100 years ago.
You get your home inspection done.
They, they gave me the report and I mean,
it was a pretty good size report as these things tend to be.
I looked over it and I'm like, yeah, this is fine
and the realtor was like, what I'm like, yeah, I don't care this,
none of this matters.
And she was like, well, you don't want to, you don't want to get him to fix anything.
I'm like, no, I don't care about any of this stuff and like,
-- it blew their mind
-- because they're gonna fix it as cheaply and as badly as possible.
-- And,
-- well, right. Exactly. But then I remember when I sold the house,
they, they took the phone book report and the, the,
the people trying to buy my house came back with,
please fix everything in this report.
And I was like,
nope,
I'm done.
And I remember this is actually really funny because my realtor flipped out
is, I was like, no, uh, we're gonna
basically,
the way the contract was written is they're supposed to
be back and forth and if I do nothing,
the contract is null and void, I'm like,
let it go null and void. I don't care. I'm done.
These people are either idiots or they're trying to bamboozle me.
I don't care either way.
And then funny enough they, like,
did expire, they resent the contract with the, ok, everything's fine.
Let's just, let's put all the pieces back together and pretend nothing happened.
I'm, like, see I told you,
like,
yeah, now that I've, I've bought two houses and had,
or three houses and had to do a lot of fixing and stuff.
I know what kind of matters and doesn't matter.
Yeah. Right. Exactly. You know. Exactly. And it's like
where that's like when I bought the current house I have,
that needed the foundation replaced the realtor was like,
do you want an inspection?
I was like,
no, I
don't need one.
I don't even want to see what they're going to come back
-- with
-- and this goes back to that sort of scale argument of.
Most people don't buy enough houses to get good at this
or most people buy a house and they don't really want to
do the handyman stuff.
And, I mean,
disclosure, I come from a family of construction workers.
So there are a few things I cannot do myself
on.
I mean, like, we built houses like that.
I did that in the summertime. Like
you have a lot of domain specific knowledge, right?
I, I know many, many things that most people would.
I mean, same thing with, like, the scanner stuff. Right?
I kind of feel like the same thing just because
the history, like,
I have from working at Red Hat for a decade
and then coming to Elastic and doing similar things.
Like, I know things about how open source works.
I know things about how software is packaged and built
that a lot of people running these scanners don't know.
-- Well,
-- here's the dirty secret. Right.
How many people globally have worked doing open
source security for more than one project.
-- Like on scale?
-- It's pretty small.
There's, there's Thomas and Marcus.
We pretty much all know each other, I think. And it's a pretty small group for sure.
-- Right.
-- It's a couple 100 global
if that, if that, you know. Ok.
Anyway, we need, we need to bring this one home, man.
I guess at the end of the day,
here's the advice I would give is if you are an open source project,
do not feel bad closing bugs.
If you will yell at you and say, oh, you shouldn't enclose my bug, then you just say,
please reopen it and add the details.
I need.
If you're filing bugs for an open source project, please, please,
please make it a game of,
you're going to file a bug and they're not going to have
to ask you any questions because you've given them so much detail.
-- Yeah,
-- I mean,
the difference between having too much information
and going down a false rabbit hole versus
not having enough information and not being able to figure it out at all.
I would much rather have rabbit hole,
-- rabbit holes to chase
-- if I'm a developer and I read your bugger part and it's good.
You've made my day.
Yes.
-- Awesome.
-- All right. Well, thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to open social security podcast.com. Head up our
show.
It's a
Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye.