Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner on Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
All right, I've changed my mind about conferences.
OK.
Yeah.
So
Defcon was over the weekend
and
I had intended to, we'll put the words, attend in quotes and watch.
There were some talks I had in mind there was, you know, I was part of their discord.
I had it all planned
and then like life erupted around me and nothing happened.
I saw none of the talks I wanted to see. Of course, they're all on youtube.
So I'm going to watch them and everything.
But obviously there's part of the fun is interacting with others
and none of that happened. And so I now recognize
that the single biggest advantage to going to a conference
is life can't happen to you generally while you're at the conference.
-- Well,
-- you've carved out the space.
Yeah. So I,
I won't lie
that I still question sometimes some of the value
of the talks at the large conferences will say,
but I'm more amendable now after missing all of defcon.
Well, I'll be blunt, like
most of us professionals generally have more important than w we,
we generally have important work to do
that is probably more important in the short term than, you know,
professional development
and those social networks and stuff.
And so, yeah, sometimes we make those choices and I suspect too, the second part is
the conference would be a lot more valuable from like a
social networking point of view and from development point of view
in person because you can really focus on it and meet people face to face, right?
Whereas online it's like,
well, it's like, you know, it kind of like,
it basically looks like IRC back when we were in our twenties.
Yeah.
Speaking of which, this actually totally feeds into today's topic,
which is I want you to plug something into Google.
All right. All right. In quotes, cult of information security,
but it has to be in quotes,
right? That specific phrase,
-- what
-- is going on? I can't uh Kurt, I, I'm too dumb to do this
full quote. Cult of information security, end quote.
OK.
Right. It says it looks like there aren't any great matches for your search.
Well, I get one result and it's a stack overflow posting.
But what's fascinating is if you do it without quotes, you get 71 million results.
So, so I, I get one result from
server fault,
the site
not
stack, it's part of the stack overflow.
OK? So of course, you're going to get more
findings if you take the quotes away because now instead of doing
a literal search on those words in that order with spaces,
now you just get searches on all of the words.
Well, so what's interesting though is when you look at information security,
I've been looking at it a bit,
there's a lot of people who treat this as a cult. And so I was actually looking up how,
how do you make a cult?
Right, because I've also looked at this off and on for tax purposes and, you know,
for lifestyle purposes.
Well, and, and like every time we go to San Francisco, we would visit a new,
uh try and visit a new cult because there's this one, the, what is it called?
The American Museum? And it's basically a front for an actual cult.
It's, it's pretty awesome.
All the art is done by the guy who runs the cult and it's like, really terrible art.
Oh, yeah. Yeah. You told me about this.
Yeah. Yeah. And so it's, it's in some previous podcast and
it's, it's straight up like North Korean, like great leader, you know,
like did this floor tile and you can like buy the floor tiles in the shop,
you know, so you can walk on great leaders or whatever.
So I was looking at how to start a cult
and sort of the parallels between this and information security.
So I was thinking we should walk through this because to be blunt. I, I'm not sure a lot
of information security is doing so well or doing it very well.
I, I don't think anyone's going to argue with that statement.
So, I mean, number one is easy, choose
an obsession, like, pick something, you know, to obsess about.
Well, we got that,
we're good there. Yeah,
we totally get there and then, you know, it's, it's talking about,
you got to create your own reality
check.
Yeah.
I
mean, you know, what gets me is like, like,
we, we make this out to be like,
what I love is when people talk to me about computer security and they're like,
oh my God, it's so bad, blah, blah, blah.
I'm like, the power's still on and water, tap,
water works and like the stores still have food and logistic like,
you know, and no offense, but COVID was a heck of a lot more of a disruption
than any information security flaw we've had to deal with in the last forever.
Absolutely. And actually, you know what? It's funny you say that is,
there's been,
uh
an idea. I've been kicking around in my brain and it's basically,
you know, you, you and oh, and this came about, I was on,
I think it was an Atlantic Council call and somebody basically talked about, oh,
the market will solve this problem and it
hang on.
We literally have the security that market demands today.
And we all agree that security is garbage.
-- The market clearly doesn't demand security
-- or,
or I would argue the market solved the problem.
The problem is solved as far as the market's concerned.
-- And
-- maybe,
maybe, well, let me put it this way,
roads have potholes typically,
right? Roads need maintenance and resurfacing. We don't always do that. Right.
Like
they, they're still working on that big road next to,
they finally repainted almost all the lines but not all of them,
which I find infuriating
because literally all they need to do is paint a
few more lines and the whole thing is just done.
But because they haven't painted the lines, you know,
the buses keep having to stop and wait for people to
back up so they can make their turn and blah,
blah, blah.
But anyways moving along with the cult thing, number two or number three,
sort of is establishing the rules of the cult.
And I think that would be one of the great rules is most of the more
well,
or shall I say many of the less
effective people in information security in my experience
have very black and white thinking like you're secure or you're not secure,
you know, the whole,
you must have 100 layer onion and
-- well, I mean, I used to think like that I won't pretend I didn't.
-- Yes. Oh me too.
-- And we got
-- better and yeah, and it was also,
I would argue I was completely ineffective
-- with that method of thinking
-- pretty much.
And what drives me nuts is when people actually do
start measuring risk and saying, ok, we'll start making these trade offs.
You know, they get called bean counters or like, oh, you know, you're,
you're just a business person who's not caring about the technology and it's like,
no, they, they don't care about the technology.
-- Like, correct.
-- It's not exciting work either.
I mean,
one of the things I keep telling people now is security should be like accounting
where it's not interesting. You're not a rock star,
you're, you're pushing buttons all day and making numbers do things and
nobody really cares unless something explodes.
Well, and this is what I love about Blockchain now, right in the last couple of weeks,
Blockchain has gone from, you know what it was in the past now to,
yeah, banks, us, banks can offer, you know, deposit services
and there's now a couple of good financial papers about the Ethereum 2.0
changes and how the economics of it are a little bit screwy,
you know, it's like really boring business stuff, which is great. Right.
That means it's there. Right. I, I agree.
So, yeah, establishing the rules of the cult. I mean, this
and I think the black and white thinking is, is the biggest one.
That's kind of a problem.
Well, there's, I mean, you could argue this,
I think in countless different ways there's black and white thinking obviously
you've got the
regulation will save us all thinking you've got the,
-- we just need more tools thinking you've
-- got the IML or whatever the flavor
AO
of Rs A was this year was the flavor of Rs A this year.
-- Not Rs A sorry. Um um uh black
-- hat, I think
like this is boring me. I don't know. It was.
-- Where is
-- that happening in the next few days?
-- No, no
-- black hat happened. It was,
I was not overly impressed by Black hat in any way, I think Defcon and,
and hope the 2600 conference, those two, if you're doing anything online,
look at what those guys did
during,
look at what black I did because I think
it was less interesting than it should have been.
But I couldn't tell you what, like the big thing was at it.
It was probably COVID if I had to guess.
Well,
and I've actually seen a lot of places trying
to tie in their technology and stuff to COVID,
like literally work from home, that kind of stuff.
I
know
not entirely wrong, but at the same time, it's just like,
uh you know,
like when my phone company was phoning me and they're like, are you safe? And
-- like what they're like, are you and your loved ones? Safe press one
-- if you are safe.
And I'm like, I
was not happy with that phone call
because I'm like, what if my
-- Yeah,
-- anyways but, but the point is right, there's,
you can easily pick a niche of silly rules for sure.
So, you know, next, finding a place to practice worship. Yeah. I mean,
and, and infosec is actually in my experience, traditionally tried to
sort of spread out like a crack and, and, and, and touch everything, you know, like,
oh, you, you can't do that because of security but, like, I just want to print
or, you know, I, I, oh, my favorite remember was it Linus Torvalds or something?
He's like, I just want to reset the time on my computer.
Why do I have to give my kid the password for them to do that?
And I get it, like, from a security point of view. Yeah, it's messing around.
System time is very important.
But at the same time I literally, ok, I, I installed windows 10 on this machine
and it chose the Pacific time zone and I'm like, cool.
So I've got the right time but I'm off by an hour. This is not so useful.
So I want to reset it to mountain time where I live. And actually, you know,
and it just didn't want to let me in.
So I ended up doing it from the command line and I'm like, you know, just for the love
of right, like, people just want to have the right time on their computer and, and
because of security, we made it hard.
I have an easier argument for this even is,
this is something I find myself falling into all the time.
And it's a very old mindset of, that's my job
where someone, for example, from development might show up and say, oh,
I want to slim down our container images.
And in the back, the first thing that pops in my head is like, that's my job.
But wait, no, it's not. First of all, I'm, I'm already too busy.
I'm never going to touch this with a 10 ft pole and if you want to do the work,
freaking great, like go do the work.
Well, it's like hit and run management, right?
Like there's that, you know, infamous story from that developer who worked for,
I think it was
Yahoo
and like the manager
came and did a hit and run management about a
single form field for like zip code or something,
you know, and the developer was like, it's cool.
It takes like five numbers or nine numbers or a dash or a space.
It doesn't really care, it just like deals with it and it, you know,
ended up being this like huge bike shedding
thing
for this one little field.
And,
and that's my experience of a lot of security
people is they can't stay involved because quite frankly,
if
they can stay involved,
that means they need to really have much more valuable work to be doing than,
you know,
ding around with container image size
Right. Exactly.
-- Exactly.
-- Like that is not a high value
ad. No, I, I agree. I agree completely.
And what I've done there is instead of getting involved,
I just try and offer advice and mentoring.
So, you know, the classic one is like, ok, well, you know, instead of that,
how about you just start with a minimal container, image,
install everything you need.
That's it. That's my advice. Like that's it,
you know, or like when my devs were like, oh, we need to track CV S and I'm like, no,
you don't
just keep updating the software twice a week like you already do.
-- Yep.
-- Yep. Exactly.
Ok. Anyway, let's keep going.
Here's the classic one and finally keep your flock fixated on the carrot.
The payoff is just around the corner and only they will be the ones paid off the
and they will be raptured up and then boy, oh, boy,
won't all those nonbelievers be sorry.
That doesn't sound familiar at all.
-- I mean,
-- that's basically like the,
the fundamental attitude of security of listen to me
or you'll be sorry and they're never sorry.
And like just today, it's great. Like, it's already
gave me that the security company found 400 security flaws in, you know,
Snapdragon processors used in like 3 billion mobile phones, right?
These D SPS that do like they process media and stuff and
it sounds like what they did is they did fuzzing of media,
like reading between the lines, they did fuzzing of media types
and got like the ability to execute code on the DS P or like just borderline,
brick it and make it non responsive
and make the whole phone non responsive.
And it's like,
yeah, like,
but like me as a consumer, what, what exactly was I supposed to do to avoid this?
Nothing.
And I'm not saying we shouldn't use like a password manager,
encrypt your hard drive, you know, do the basics.
But yeah, some of the stuff I see people advocating for so that you can be, you know,
-- immune to these problems is like, no, I
-- mean, a lot of them aren't.
And this is one of my favorite examples is if you look at
kind of all of the security flaws that came out, let's say, you know,
in the last six months and there's probably 10 or less that would
be critical to the point of people should be concerned about them.
But I bet you the ones that have been actually exploited,
it's probably two or three Macs.
And of course, part of the challenge is figuring out which
two or three it's going to be. But yeah, none of this is ever as bad as it seems to be.
-- Well,
-- and even then, you know, when, when we see these large scale attacks,
a lot of them tend to be using a really old
flaw or even better yet they use something like you know,
relying on the fact that MS SQL was set up with no password by default.
Ok. You know, you should probably set,
well, I mean, how many, you know, uh, mem
Cash.
T is a great example. Right. Mem
Cash t, doesn't,
does it even still
have authentication? I don't think it does yet.
I have no idea. Right.
And it, well, it, it, it certainly didn't back in the day because, well, it's kind of,
its whole use case is like, it's just a quick and dirty
me
cash.
You know, we don't want to have all these bells and whistles, want it small and fast.
So don't expose it to the internet, right? Like
that's it.
And that's easier said than done also.
And, and I think that's another aspect of the cult is the whole, blame the user
-- if you don't set it up the right way
-- and for doing something totally reasonable.
Like, I actually, what's really fascinating to me is in Windows 10 now.
Um, so I, I have, um, I had like Windows seven ultimate upgraded to Windows 10
back in the day anyways. What's fascinating to me is that
like, Windows firewall bought default is on and pretty tight.
Windows defender is on and by default does the right thing.
And what's really fascinating is like,
I actually had to disable a Microsoft security feature.
Um, they, they have this thing now,
malware protection where it kind of protects certain files,
like your documents directory and prevents,
you know, basically, it only allows like,
specific programs to monkey around in there.
And so what was it, like, github and Adam and stuff were just not working? Oh, yeah.
What it was is
I could interact with the files. I could read them. I could write them,
but I couldn't create new files.
Right.
So, it wouldn't let me create new files and I'm like, ok, that's pretty paranoid,
but whatever.
So I had to disable that.
But by and large for most people that's not going
to be a problem because they're gonna be using like,
you know, Microsoft office, not github
desktop. And what, what got me is by default windows 10 is really
doing its best to protect me and prevent me from shooting myself in the foot. And
I also noticed I updated my kids uh phones the other day
and there's new settings under the automated updates,
right?
That make it, you know,
actually more effective and easier to do automated updates of the US.
And I don't remember setting them to the safe defaults. They were just there.
-- I
-- mean,
-- cool.
-- Like, thank you.
Right.
I think for consumer gear at this point,
there's no excuse to not just have sensible defaults.
I think that's true of everybody. If you
have some sort of pathological corner use case where you're like, oh,
we can't upgrade this because
blah, blah,
then that's on you and you need to go, you know,
monkey around with the engine and remove the spark
plugs and replace them with bananas or whatever.
Yeah, I,
I agree with that and I think that was not the way people thought for a long time
and it made a mess of things.
Remember the arguments for like enabling the firewall
by default on Linux and of course,
now is the default.
-- But remember what that took years
-- or, or even.
so I remember back in the day this was, oh man, this was probably, I mean,
it's been more than 10 years now.
I was at uh I think it was a Red Hat Summit. It was something.
And there's a genome guy. His name is Richard Hughes.
He, I don't know, I don't know what he's up to these days, but basically he,
he comes up to me and says,
what would you think if we enabled automatic updates in Fedara?
And I said that's a terrible idea.
And he goes why? And he says, why I said, well, like what's in those updates?
How do we know if they're safe? How do we know?
You know, we don't know what's going to happen.
How do we know it doesn't break something? And he said,
I think for normal users, we should do this. And
of course, I was like, no, I don't think that's right. And now like, yes,
yes, 100% we should enable automatic updates for normal users.
Yeah, pretty much turn it off if you don't want it. But I think
for, for normal people and, and this was,
I don't remember where I found the statistic but
something like 85% of people never change a single setting.
I can actually do you one better. What was it?
So, uh basically uh organ donors,
right?
If, if you make people opt into the organ donor system, you get like 10% or something.
And so like what Holland and some countries have done, I think Singapore,
by default, you're an organ donor and you, you can choose to opt out, but by default,
you're an organ donor and then you go from like 10% being organ donors to like,
90 something percent.
I believe the real fundamental is
people don't
change defaults. People,
you know,
if you give them a choice between not doing something and having to do something,
I mean,
how many people get angry at a conference if they sit in a
chair one day and then the next day somebody different is sitting in quote
unquote their chair.
Yeah.
Yeah. Seriously.
I mean, I'm, I'm totally like that. I'm a creature of habit. I don't know.
I remember when I was at university I'd sit in the same desk every day I could.
And if someone sat in my desk, I'm like, get out of my chair, like,
that's my chair and they're like, no, it's not.
And I'd argue with them. And
it, obviously it wasn't my chair in any way and you could sit wherever you wanted.
But it's just,
it's one of those things I think that is we're strange monkeys and that's what we do.
Now,
I think
something else, I think that's really important to, I wanna,
I wanna bring us back to your cult discussion because I think we
abandoned that very quickly because it is a strange topic for sure.
And I love the fact that we're going to name this podcast,
the Cult of Information Security.
And it will probably be the second hit
when we do this search.
Although, although we'll see, maybe, maybe people will figure out,
you know how happy I was to find only a single men
-- of that in Google because I'm like, there's got to be
-- more,
I think here's a really important thing to consider, especially in the,
in the topic of cults.
And I don't remember where I heard this,
but it was very recent was basically someone pointed out that
nobody sets out to join a cult.
It's,
it's never like I'm going to join a cult today or I want to join that cult over there.
It's always, you find like minded people who think the way you think,
who agree with the things you agree with.
And eventually you're just kind of brought into the fold.
And it's one of those situations where if you,
if you don't pay attention to what's happening
you're kind of carried along in the current until before, you know it,
you're in a cult.
-- Yeah.
-- You're drinking the flavor
and, right.
And, and like,
your friends are there and you don't want to be kicked out
because where will you find new friends and the people you like?
And you're familiar with it?
So, it's like, uh, it's not that bad and, and I think,
especially in the world of security, we all thought it wasn't that bad,
you know, 5, 10 years ago and if you look at it now it's like
it kind of was that bad and our industry kind of blows now because we,
we were more obsessed with strange things than, than real outcomes.
Yeah.
I mean, well,
the fact that I'm looking for even just basic tools
and strategies to measure risk and quantify it and,
like,
I'm currently working on essentially a list and relationships of
attacks against Blockchain and DLT S and nobody has that.
I mean,
that's pretty new. So that doesn't shock me.
Blockchain has been around since 2008 and we've been doing hundreds of
millions of dollars through blockchains over the last four or five years.
Like,
come on
or a simple, a really simple thing.
I know Microsoft has a good attack modeling tool for windows. No, that's it.
There's like, I've, I've looked off and on for an attack modeling tool
to like, model attack surfaces
-- and list them in the relationships with other things. I've never found
-- one.
There's a handful of tools, but I would agree that it's few and far between,
here's where
I'm going to put my cult hat back on. So there's probably someone out there saying, oh
wasp, does this or this group? Does this or this group does this.
And I found the vast majority of these groups are insular
and they don't generally create things that are helpful to the general public.
I am guessing somebody's listening to this podcast and doesn't know what CVE is or
CWE probably
CWE for sure, because so few people know what CWE
is,
right?
And you know, that's just how it is like,
and CVE and CWE have been around for two
-- decades and
-- there's nothing wrong with that either.
-- We should be clear.
-- True. Yeah.
Most people don't really actually know what a barcode is. If you ask them to,
it's ok
to not know what something is
and to go learn about it. And, and again, we've historically been
-- very bad at helping people learn because we ridicule before we educate.
-- Well.
And also why, like, why would anybody want to know this?
Like, I,
I actually know more than I should about plumbing and electrical standards.
Thanks to home rentals. But like, there's no way normal people need to know this.
They just hire a plumber man.
Yeah.
Like, I'm like that for car stuff and my lawnmower,
like I just paid them 80 bucks to fix my lawnmower.
But, like, here's part of the problem is if my toilet quits working,
I know to call a plumber.
If my internet is broken.
What do, what? Right.
I'm going to call the cable company and then
they're going to send someone out and be like,
-- but
-- like, your device is acting, walking, showing weird ads.
Yeah, that's a better example. Like, who do you, who helps there?
And even, even in the context of a business,
there's plenty of ineffective security teams but
people don't even know sometimes that,
-- that they're not doing their job when
-- I see stuff like geek squad or whatever.
You know, those big store tech healthy things,
then you hear the articles like how they're just ripping people off.
Yeah.
I mean,
you can't really blame people for not trusting this
industry in these things and thinking poorly of us.
Here's, here's a better way
to think of this and I know I know what the answer is
but I just want you to pretend that there aren't professional organizations here.
How do you know your accountant isn't ripping you off and stealing
from you or misfiling your tax paperwork or any of that?
Right. Well, in theory they are a CPA or whatever the phrase is a charter.
Let's pretend, let's pretend the professional certifications don't exist.
How would, you know, your accountant isn't ripping you off?
-- Well,
-- you don't, you
wouldn't know
a bunch of them would for sure.
Every time I see information security discussed on Twitter, it's pretty clear
that the cult aspect of it comes out pretty quick,
for sure.
Oh, man, there's so many funny stories about
the madness of that. My favorite actually is
there was someone who put a tweet up. I'll try to find it.
I doubt I'll be able to find it because I don't even know who said this.
But it was basically
infosec Twitter is full of really smart people doing
really interesting work and people with lots of followers.
I'm like, oh, my goodness,
like that's a burn but it's in some ways it's kind of true because like,
I feel like it is and this is just true in general.
I think of, of any community is
having the ability to gain attention to yourself
and have lots of followers on social media
that is a different skill than being actually
good at the thing you talk about sometimes.
-- That's why it's true of any industry.
-- Right. Right. Exactly. Exactly.
-- So, I think that about wraps it up.
-- We're not going to wrap it up here.
I want to like, what next? What does it mean? Right. OK.
So let's, let's assume information security is a cult which
I
don't think we're going to get a lot of argument there.
But, like, what do you do about it? Right.
What's the out, how do you, how do you get out? How do you escape this cult.
What's the answer?
I think the answer and this is nice because it actually helps in users is,
is actually listening
to end users and sort of actually listening to reality a
bit better and being a bit more empathic and kind and
actually sort of helping people and I don't mean helping
people the way you think they should be helped,
but helping people in the sense of actually talking to them and asking them
what do they need and want
-- and, and those are two different things to be clear.
-- Right?
Yeah. What they need is often more important than what they want.
Well, but what they want is, you know, that that's what they'll kill you for sense of
sense of safety, things like that.
Well, no, like I, I want,
I want a self driving car.
Do I need that?
Yeah. Well, I mean, you know, most people don't anyways.
And so I think the industry actually reaching out to people, you know, for example,
if a developer comes to you with a question, you know, maybe
we actually talk with them before giving them an answer to find out, you know,
what it is, they, they're really wanting to ask.
I, I have a slightly better way to describe that I think
and I would describe it as do as little as possible.
And what I mean by that is we are notorious
for a developer saying I would like to write Secure code
and then we start going on and on about security development life cycle.
You have to do threat modeling and you have to do a tax surface analysis and you have
to do this and you have to use these
certain functions and don't use these other functions.
And,
and of course,
anyone who isn't buried in the middle of all of this
is going to just like shake their head and walk away.
right? Because they don't know what to do. I think this is one of those instances.
If someone says I want to write more secure code,
what is the one thing they could do?
That would be very un invasive, that would have an impact
and start there, right?
Do as little as possible because what the developer actually saying
to you is I want to be your friend and I
would like you to help me a little bit and if
you go on and on with a laundry list of things,
they're just going to say, what have I gotten myself into?
Well, and there's always that fear too,
you're going to punish them for getting it wrong.
Well, and actually actually that is a valid fear. But,
but if you even look at it from the, from the like legitimate cult perspective,
if you show up at a cult and or rather, I guess no one really shows up at a cult,
but like a cult leader isn't going to go out and say, oh my goodness,
you have to join my cult and here's our list of 700 crazy rules.
You're going to be like, no,
I'm not doing any of those things and that's not how they get you right.
They get you by becoming your friend and
introducing you very slowly to these concepts.
And before you know it, you're, you're in
and I think in,
in a way security needs to do kind of a similar thing is we
can't show up with a huge list of rules because people are like,
y'all are crazy. Go away.
But if you, if you help and you, you help with one thing, one little thing
that is how we bring people into our fold
and additionally bring ourselves into their fold because they're going to teach
us as much as we're going to teach them for sure.
Yeah.
All right. I feel like this was,
I,
I feel better ending on a reasonable note now
versus before where I felt like what just happened.
So
this is hard though, right?
It's very hard and I'm sure we'll get some flak for calling information security.
A cult, which I won't
-- prove us wrong.
-- That's exactly what cult members would say.
No true Scotsman, right?
Uh
Well, I mean, a cult would deny that it's a cult, right?
I mean, that's exactly what they would say.
That is probably what every cult ever has said.
We should start a cult that is a cult and we acknowledge we're a cult.
I feel like there's some,
there's, there's some traction there we could go with, right?
The motto could be probably not a cult. Anyway. Anyway,
we should, we should make some merch
information security. Probably not a cult
anyway.
All right, I'm going to edit. So thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
The few of you that made it this far you can go to over social security
podcast.com. Head up the show notes, you can use the Pound O
podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media
and Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye bye.