Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
So, what's new? I think it's summer. I got the pool out or splashing around in it.
The water's 11 degrees. So it's a little chilly.
-- But you know, it's fun for like 10 seconds.
-- All right.
So I need to address a couple of points to your statement. First of all,
the thermometer where I live disagrees with you.
It is not summer in any way. The weather has been absolutely terrible.
But more importantly, this is a podcast which gets recorded and then played at a,
an unknown time
for the various listeners we have.
So it may not be summer for the people listening or maybe I'll just
hold this episode now until fall and make you sound like an idiot.
Well, that's a very northeast view of the globe.
I have to say,
-- I mean,
-- what about
you talked about summer?
Well, if you hold this till fall, then it'll be summer in Australia
-- check
-- mate.
Well, it would be our fall. I'm comfortable
speaking
in the context of where we live because you
and I both live in the northern hemisphere,
very north in the northern hemisphere at that.
And so I'm comfortable saying the various seasons and expecting
our above average intelligence listeners to sort it out.
Do we have any data on that? Actually,
that our listeners are above average?
Well, they listen to us, I mean, that's all the data I need.
This is true or maybe, maybe that makes them below average intelligence.
I don't know.
Anyway. Anyway, um So for what it's worth though, uh Spotify
has various like demographic data and whatnot on,
on people because obviously they're Spotify and,
and they do give some of that and we have uh
we are predominantly male, mostly the West, obviously.
Yeah, the, the, the I would say the,
so what you're saying is our listeners look like we do
probably.
And the core of the listeners are like about 18
to 40 make up probably 80% of the listeners,
which I mean,
none of this given AAA Security podcast should shock anybody.
-- I mean, so
-- what you're saying is a tech podcast by two older white guys,
is listened to by a lot of
-- medium
-- to older white guys. We'll say um Yeah, yeah,
it, it right, right now, I will say though we're not, we are like our, our, the,
the countries are very split about half North America, half the rest of the world,
which does make me very happy because
I would view it as a failure on our part. If it was only North Americans listening to us
jab around about whatever nonsense it is we talk about.
Anyway. Anyway, speaking of nonsense,
uh, we're going to talk about what we'll call, issue 101 today.
And
I will give the, the brief overview for everyone since
it's kind of my fault
that this issue is worth talking about.
So,
for anyone who's been paying attention in the world
of security for the last probably couple years now,
there is a group called the Open Source Security Foundation,
which is part of the Linux Foundation,
which I always love the foundation in a foundation foundation section or whatever.
So the the we're gonna call it the open SSF for
the rest of this conversation because it's easier to say.
So the open SSF has a group called the Tech, the Technical Advisory
Council Council. I wouldn't want to say committee, but it's not committee,
Technical Advisory Council, the Tech
and I'm a member of the Tech.
So I obviously pay attention to what goes on and I
get involved in the discussions and all this kind of stuff.
And it's meant to be kind of like a,
a group that helped shepherd along the technical decisions
of the open SSF right?
There's the governing board which is supposed to be
like the people with a bunch of money,
the council.
Um
Sure,
sure, we'll say that.
Uh So anyway, anyway,
someone created an issue,
issue 101 that basically asked a question,
what is a healthy number of maintainers for an open source project?
And of course,
in the past it's seven.
I, I mean, it sure, why not? It can be whatever you want. I don't care.
And, and here's what I will say.
I think we could all agree.
It's not one I would actually disagree. We'll get to that.
I think ideally
you want an open source project with more than one person.
Because if, if I'm the only maintainer and I get hit by a bus or I get sick or I get busy,
no, nothing happens. Right.
Well, no, not true. I mean,
people can hijack the project, they can fork the project.
I would actually argue that having,
and, and I love that you, you keep saying one maintainer when,
what you actually mean is a fraction of a maintainer because none
of these maintainers are working full time on that one project.
And from when I've looked at various ecosystems,
-- there's a lot of maintainers with more than one package to their name.
-- That's true.
Ok.
Hang on, hang on, hang on. We'll, we'll get to this.
I wanna, I wanna set, set the stage first. So
there's,
there's this conversation asking what's the right number.
And of course, everyone chimes in with like, oh, you know, we need a number and,
and whatever, and one is bad and all this stuff and, and then
I have a bunch of N PM data which we've talked about in the past on the podcast.
I'm, I'm working on a white paper
and I'm like, well, I can answer this question.
So I take the graph of the M PM packages and I say, look, it's predominantly one,
like we need to keep this in mind in this discussion because saying
every project needs to have two maintainers is fine to say,
but
where are you going to come up with literally millions of extra maintainers, right?
-- That that's a completely ridiculous
-- goal,
-- not even just the maintainers, but the time and effort to do this.
-- Sure. Right.
Well, I consider that part of part of the equation, right?
Like saying, Kurt, we need a million open source maintainers.
What now we're gonna be like,
no, it's just not, that's not happening, right?
You can't do it, it's just not, not realistic. So I put this graph on
and of course, this is where
the human condition kicks in.
And someone says, oh, but this is all N PM packages.
What if we look at the important M PM packages?
So I'm like that makes sense. Let's look at the important M PM packages.
So I take the top 5% by downloads over the last year, right?
Which feels like a good way to measure this
and the graphs
are identical.
I mean, and that's a fair question because like for N PM and a bunch of others,
there's like tutorials on,
you know, here's how to build a package and push it into N PM.
And so I would expect there to be
of those 26 million releases, at least
100,000 to a million ballpark figure, you know, logarithmic
would be a developer, tried it out, pushed up one release, did a release
and then ignored it forever,
you know,
and that's,
and we can ignore that data because who cares? Right. Right.
But yeah, if it's top 5% by downloads, you, you,
-- those are by definition the packages that kind of probably matter
-- here.
II, I just pulled up the numbers. So I have
the number by, by download, right? Of the percentiles of all the packages.
So you gave me an idea. 50th percentile, meaning
the dead middle of what is it? 28 million.
So you're talking what, 14 ish million packages have 219 downloads or less
like
that's zero as far as I'm concerned.
Well, and again, I assume a lot of that is companies, well,
like yours that scan all this stuff and they
just downloading this stuff because when you mentioned,
I think what was the magic number was?
95 was one of the magic numbers?
Uh 90 0, I forget what the 95 number was.
Well, I, I suspect that's just somebody has run their script 95 times
that
when, when you look at the number of downloads just as an aggregate for some reason,
95 downloads has a significantly higher peak than any
of the other data around that particular number for.
But you're right, it's because somebody downloaded,
like they have a script that ran 995 times when I checked it and well,
probably 94 because all those developers that downloaded it once,
made sure it worked on the tutorial and then abandoned it
and see and
to go into a Segway. But
like Apple on the Apple Store has apparently done a
thing recently where apps that have not been updated for.
I forget the number, it's like 18 months or two years or three years.
Somewhere in there are being kind of kicked out. Part of me is like,
well, we should sort of get rid of dead code. But part of me is also like,
my kids are still pissed off that there are some apps
that no longer work on current versions of I OS.
Like the original Disney Draw program was far superior to the current one.
In my opinion, it was simpler and better or the original Lego Duplo game with the,
you know, with the bunny rabbit and the draft having their adventure,
it's gone and it,
it makes my son cry that it's gone,
you know,
and
also more,
this isn't like a server application that's like processing credit cards.
It's a bloody children's game,
right?
So, like, as much as I had to say there's a lot of, like my mom, I love my mom but she,
for the longest time kept an original Sony Netbook with
Windows 95 because it had the version of Solitaire she liked
and you know what,
fine it's not connected to the internet and she literally used it to play Solitaire.
Yeah.
Yeah. What's, what is, like, there's
the only possible harm is that her
cat kept chewing the keys off the keyboard because they, I don't know,
whatever it was of a, that specific keyboard
was like, he just, the, the way they were,
the cat loved ripping those keys off that keyboard.
You know what already is gonna swallow one. Right.
Awesome. Anyway. Ok. I want, I want to get back to this data.
I, I wanna let me spout out some more numbers before we move on just so I,
I want to set the, the stage here for everyone to understand.
Right.
290 downloads. F percentile.
95th percentile is 22,000 downloads, which is not a lot, in my opinion.
I think we're reaching the,
this is probably used by somebody territory but I don't think,
well, 22,000,
I mean, if somebody's actually using that package, they're gonna download it
at least a few dozen times because
like, when I think about the CS A, like, we're not a very aggressive shop.
We only do like a new build two or three times a week. So
that's like 100 100 and 50 downloads a year.
Every developer is going to download a copy of the package every,
every time you run your C I test,
you know what I mean? So 22,000 is not a lot in my opinion,
but
that's 95th percentile. 99th percentile is 1.2 million, which is still not a lot.
Now, now, the one thing I will say is when we hit 99 percentile, actually, no,
it's higher than that.
It's the top 1000 packages in N PM.
Then we see the split is almost 5050 for one maintainer versus not one maintainer.
-- It's still slightly higher on one maintainer. Yeah, but
-- still 50% 1 maintainer.
That's
like you can't argue with that number. It's not like 5% or 10%. It's 50%
and that number
is one trillion downloads.
That's where we land for the top 1000. So think about that.
-- Those are clearly used literally everywhere on the planet.
-- Like left shift, right?
When left shift or whatever it was called got nuked. And it broke
literally all of the, the internet because
anyway, anyway, OK, hang on. We're,
we're 10 minutes in and I'm not even done talking about the issue. All right.
So we, I post the second graph and everyone's like, oh my goodness.
So then David Wheeler, friend of the show who we both, you know, know and love.
David's like, OK,
let N PM is special because N PM is,
yeah, it's short code snippets.
It focuses on very these small packages that do like one thing.
So of course,
exactly. Of course M PM has
one maintainer packages.
Python will be different.
So I'm like
I can do this. So anyway, I I the, the the story of this is really funny.
So David sends this and I I write a script to start downloading data from the pipe.
The,
-- the PPP YP I is like the Python version of N PM.
-- Yeah, the Python package index.
Is that what it stands for? I actually don't know
-- that's what's in my head
-- probably.
And if it's not that anyway.
Yeah, the Python package index boo yah 20 years of knowledge pays off.
I start downloading the data and it's gonna take eight days because the Python
I, I can't get it from the rest.
API I have to go to the XML R PC interface and let me do one query every two seconds.
You have to hit every package and there's 300,000 packages, right?
And then funny enough a guy I work with his name is Weston.
Weston's like, oh, hey, I found all the data on, on, in that
github repo of all the Python stuff and
it's like current and it's updated every week.
I'm like, holy crap.
You just, and so literally like 10 minutes after Weston,
I know 10 minutes after Weston sends this to me, I've got the data in,
I generate the graph
-- and it's exactly the same.
-- Of course, it is, dude.
If you did this for like, I'm trying to think of.
Probably one of the earliest ones would be C
A the Comprehensive Pearl Archive Network.
I bet you that it would be the exact same picture
-- at this point.
-- So,
so every step of the way
I've fallen in the human trap of being like, oh, of course, it will be different
and, and hasn't, and I, I've reached a point now.
It's like, I'm pretty sure this is reality.
And so if you read the issue,
I will put issue 101 in the show notes because it is a fascinating read.
But at the end, I'm basically like, look, this is the open source.
We have, we can talk about wanting more maintainers and all this other stuff.
But the reality is
there's no way to do that without a massive influx of resources, resources,
mostly being money in this context.
But like
there's just, it, it's unrealistic to expect
any significant number of open source packages to
be maintained by more than one person,
I think at this point.
And so we have to think about that now, like this
is the constraint of reality. What does that mean?
I would say it's even more subtle than that.
It's not just the existing world we have,
this is clearly the world we have going forwards probably forever
because when you look at how hard is it to convince somebody else
to work for free on something?
-- It's very hard that worked
-- on
you.
Yeah.
-- But I mean,
-- like we both do this podcast for free.
The second thing is I would argue that it's actually better
to have this ecosystem with a whole bunch of packages with
one person because it forces us to look at things like,
well, what do we do if that developer is not responsive?
Well, and for example, the uh because what if the like,
what if the developer is actively malicious?
So we just had that happen in the crate rust
ecosystem where there was a malicious package called Rust decimal.
Uh that didn't have the hyphen and it was basically typo squatting
and it's clearly malicious because it's sending like
api keys for AWS to a Hiroko instance.
Like
that's not an oopsies. I made a mistake that is like, I
I'm harvesting credentials to a Hiroko system
that you know, that I run.
And so, you know, the, the, the, the rust crate security team was like, yeah, no,
not cool boof.
And they killed it.
To me, the correct answer here is not, you can't get a million more developers.
So like, don't even
try or pretend.
But what you can do is you can get those,
you know, seven or eight people
to be in charge of the ecosystem and the security to be like, ok,
this package is really sort of important.
The developer is not responsive because maybe they're
dead or they're on vacation or who knows,
and we need to push this patch in
and you have a process for that,
right?
Or a process to transfer ownership of that package to somebody else
who actively wants to maintain it a bit more or whatever.
Like, for example, I took over ownership of two Fedora packages, uh PHP open ID and I,
the media wiki plug in thing
because I needed them to work and they were broken
and they needed like a quick little update.
And there was a process where I'm basically like
the developer of this package hasn't done anything for,
I think it was like three years.
I'm like, it's, they're, they don't care,
like just give it to me and so I can fix it, please.
And then of course,
I fixed it and went to ignoring it and nobody cared because who cared.
Like it's,
-- and that's the thing. It's kind of dead software.
-- Right. Right.
You know, now,
now here is
something else to just overcomplicate.
This is, I think it was literally yesterday from the time we were recording this,
there were
two vector packages found uh
phpass which Ph Pass or, or maybe PHP
si don't know whichever it's fine.
And then uh a Python package called CTX and they were
harvesting Amazon credentials again and shipping them off to I think,
I don't know if it was a Hiroko instant whatever.
It doesn't matter like they were shipping them off somewhere. And
the PHP
as, every time I say it like that's all I think
I will do my best to call it Ph Pass. Uh PH Pass was an instance where
the package was available on github.
And I guess that's how you installed it is you
type some magic into what pair is the PHP package manager
and pair would reach out to github and download the package.
The the original maintainer deleted their github
account in 2019. And then the attacker recreated the same user
name, put the same stuff there
and, and I don't know how many times this was downloaded.
My guess it wasn't very many if the package was disappeared for a couple of years.
But you get the idea
like here, here's a great ex.
This is a great counterexample to saying, oh,
we need more than one maintainer because with
only one shenanigans like this can happen.
Well, and that well,
but that speaks again to the need for having
a mechanism for that one maintainer to go.
Hey, I don't care about this anymore. Can I, can I give it to somebody else or to some
hold in this?
That's fair.
Um And the other thing is I forget who it said on Twitter.
But basically, if you register something with a custom domain name,
now you have to keep that domain name alive forever,
you know, and that's the thing with name spaces like github,
name space or domain name, email name space
if something is registered to like an email address or a get up account or whatever.
Yeah, that name space now kind of matters.
And again, I think that speaks more to the need of not having multiple developers
but having a way to sort of surrender your pa
like to put your package up for adoption basically.
I mean, yeah,
and also for the tooling to be a bit smarter and
to not blindly like a great example is why did PHP pair
go? Oh that
like that github
URL is now 404. We need to scrub this package from the index.
I mean, I
should have
II I do agree.
I think it should have been definitely because then I guess they, they flipped
the package to some other fork as like the official copy.
But yeah, like I, I agree, I think if, if it 40 fours don't, don't point there.
Well, or, or if it's 40 fours for like a month stop
like 1404. Sure, maybe don't kill it yet,
but like a month of 40 fours.
And also the
Yeah.
Well,
and this also speaks to the to the having somebody
like um because it was sneak that was doing this
finding all the sort of typo squatting or, you know,
suspiciously similar package names
or just suspiciously similar or a suspicious package names, like,
like one was like aws something, something,
um,
you know, pretending to, like, be the Aws SDK or whatever.
And so again, somebody, you know, there needs to be a process for, hey,
I found this package.
It's got this kind of like official sounding name.
It has nothing to do with them and it appears to do, like,
it downloads a binary from over using curl from this random system.
Like, can we please boot this package out of the ecosystem?
And I think
things like that are far more important than getting more maintainers because
fixing, even if you get more than one maintainer per package,
you still have the malicious maintainer issue,
you still have the domain uh the typo, the, the spell check squatting issues,
you still have the stuff that
like dies and then
gets hijacked by an attacker.
You still have all these things and for that, you need some
governing security body kind of which a lot of these ecosystems have.
But I think what they need to do now and I
think this is where you and your group should go is
coming up with some best practices and some strategies that
so that they're kind of doing it in similar ways because I,
I feel like there are some best practices here, this, you know,
N PM and PP and
Creighton Rust, I feel like, you know,
there's 90% overlap on how they're going to operate.
Long term.
In fact,
they have a working group,
the various packaging ecosystem leaders have a like subgroup as part
of the open SSF to talk about all of these problems,
like to just come together and discuss it.
So,
so they're, I mean,
they're working on it, of course, it's under the open SSF umbrella,
but they're literally like they, they self, they constructed,
I don't know what it is, self organized.
I guess you'd call it
like they, they're doing this on their own.
This is not driven by the Linux Foundation, which is great. Now.
It's also wonderful that the open SSF gives them like a place to come
and, and be seen, which is also important, I think.
Well, it's like literally in their name, the Open Source Security Foundation,
I feel like they should be providing
resources to open
source ecosystems to do security stuff within.
I'm cautiously optimistic anytime
any new organization emerges. Because I think you and I have both seen
a countless number of open source security groups
will say,
I would say,
-- and die as quickly as they appeared.
-- I would say there's something special here
in that these people are already doing useful work.
I, I agree. I agree. Anyway. OK. OK.
Before we get in a hole,
I want to talk about something really important you accidentally touched on,
I think, but I think it is the key to this discussion
is
when we talk about these kind of problems, we often talk about prevention
as the key, right?
Where we need to prevent this from happening by, I, I argued with Dan Lawrence,
uh yesterday on Twitter last night about
what pinning dependencies and just because I can
and, and
where it'll never die.
But you know what I mean? There's like, oh, we have to prevent it.
We have to take these actions that will prevent the bad thing.
But the reality is, I think if we look at the history of security, especially,
we remember when we obsessed over endpoint protection,
antivirus spam filtering, like all this stuff.
And the reality is prevention,
generally speaking, is ineffective.
What is effective is having the ability to observe what's going on,
see bad things happening and quickly respond.
Well, one thing subtly is prevention implies that,
you know what the problem is and how to solve it.
-- Well, that's just
-- it.
And
so,
I
mean, and that's
a great example of
that works in more mature industries.
Like, so for example,
I actually bought a copy of and read our local electrical code
book and I loved reading it because I'd be reading it.
I'm like, 00, what if?
And then two paragraphs later, they're like,
so that's why you use an armored cable because
if some poor schmuck drives a nail through it,
they don't die.
You know, like there's literally
reading this thing.
It's like, it's real clear that a whole bunch of people got electrocuted and dead
and they post mortem it and then added that
to the code to prevent that from happening.
And so now like
if you have an up to code electrical system,
which almost nobody has because like you're supposed to have AFC I breakers
on all your outlets now and those things cost like 200 bucks.
-- Like they are horrifically expensive. I think
-- you only need.
No, they're not that expensive.
A
lot.
Old code was bedrooms. New code is,
is it all of them?
-- Dude,
-- they prevent fighters.
They're,
and when you think about it, yeah, they're expensive.
But spending like 2000 bucks on AFC I
breakers is cheaper than burning down your house.
-- Typically.
-- I agree. Well, look, they're, they're not that,
so I just bought some, not too long ago.
They're like 200 bucks now up here.
Oh, well, in the shortage, I mean,
-- that's true too because when I bought them there
-- was two by fours or $10 each.
-- There were
-- many, many
breakers at the hardware store and the regular ones were like 10 bucks and
AFC,
the GFCI, I
think between 2040 depending
upon
we need to do some arbitrage because up here again they're like 100 bucks.
I will go, I don't know if that's legal. Remind me.
And when I go to the hardware store next time I will look for you.
But remember this was in the before times I bought these.
So I also made the poor decision of going
with Stab Lock and their factory burned down.
No, I'm serious.
Like the fact that Stab Lock factory and wherever in the US burnt down
a bunch and like there's been a shortage of stab lock brand breakers.
Like, yeah, if you're Federal pioneer seamens, whatever,
you're fine but like stab lock.
Yeah. No, tough.
So, anyways, but back to this, like we'll talk later,
I think. So, prevention is nice, but prevention implies that you're actually
doing good prevention like seatbelts, you know,
three point seatbelts turns out work really well.
But Volvo did a ton of crash tests to figure that out
and I feel like a lot of the prevention in the N PM and pi pi ecosystems
are the packages with more than one maintainer doing
better than the packages with just one maintainer.
What do you mean by better? Exactly?
I mean,
is there an actual benefit to having more than
one maintainer from like a security point of view?
-- Does it actually
-- matter?
The the data I can pull on that is I can what? What?
And this is, you just gave me some ideas. I can pull
uh update frequency on more than one maintainer. I'm also now I want to also pull like
do
do packages with more maintainers, like update their dependencies more often
because I don't know, I I mean, II I can answer that
in theory, they should because they have more resources to fix stuff,
-- the person
-- one would think, but we will find out
again. We don't have to guess because when we guess we're just making crap up.
But also I can look at uh are there more
CV ES for packages with multiple maintainers versus packages without?
And, and now I can tell you the one data, the one graph I do have
is the top 5% of those packages
have.
On average, most of the multiple CV ES, most N PM packages have one CV E, right.
But the packages with multiple CV ES are generally speaking in that
top 5% which I don't think should surprise anyone where people look.
But I Exactly. Right. It's like with the drunk looking under the light for his keys.
Exactly that.
But
we can prove that, which is
I love.
Well, the other thing to keep in mind too is you're operating on a scale.
So you're actually the thing.
And I think this is part of the problem too is a lot of security.
People are not used to operating at scale,
they're used to operating within a company where it's like a sample size of one.
You're operating on a sample size of hundreds of thousands of unique packages,
26 million releases.
And the problem there is is we, we can't,
while we can draw conclusions and learn things,
it's more of a bell. Curve of conclusions.
Like
it's not more maintainers better.
It's like, no, on average, statistically speaking,
maybe more maintainers is better.
It's not necessarily always better. Right.
Because for example,
there's gonna be dysfunctional groups out
there where more maintainers is just worse
and then there's going to be the,
the highly competent benevolent dictator for life who
doesn't want to share their package with anybody.
Yep. Yep. Exactly. And,
and I think this is,
so it's funny you say that that's something I've been kicking
around internally at work about like some messaging and whatnot is
the security as security people.
We love to obsess over like individual vulnerabilities or individual events.
When the reality is we need to take a step back and we need to look at
this data kind of an aggregate and understand
like what are the patterns we're seeing emerging?
What does like the overall vulnerability universe look like?
So you can say, oh, this package has a critical issue, you have to fix it but it's like
let's zoom out a little bit and look like what is, how many issues are there total?
Like
this, this package has one critical issue
and three other issues.
This package has no critical issues and 700 mediums like that is,
well, I can give you an even simpler example. Remember, was it a month ago?
You're like, oh my God,
like Oracle did a security release with like over 100 CV S and I'm like,
yeah, that's, that's how that works.
Like every quarter they released like 200 ish plus CV ES.
-- It was,
-- I thought it was bigger than normal but you,
you assure me it's not and I never looked into it.
But yes,
well, since I started tracking them back at like,
eyesight and I defense which should be in the late two thousands.
Like
they've been doing this for like, that's
how it's been for over 10 years.
And so clearly, it's not,
I mean, it's not great, but it's not
a
world ending problem. Same with Microsoft.
Everybody's like, oh my God, this Microsoft past Tuesday was really bad.
There was like a zero day
that's in the wild that they finally fixed. And I'm like,
do you know how many times I've experienced that? Like, on average, twice a year?
Well, like twice a year for over a decade. Like, it's just,
you know,
uh
Yeah.
-- No, II, I like,
-- it's at scale
and I think again,
like most people don't read 50,000 security reports over a decade.
Uh or, you know, work at like Red Hat and handle thousands of CV S per year.
Again. They,
you
folks, this is what happens to you,
right? Well, it's, but again, it's like, I just, I'm reminded of Bison. It's like,
you know, yeah, like for you,
that was the worst day of your life when I came
in and destroyed your village and burnt down and everything.
And, like, for me that was, that was a Tuesday,
you know,
same thing with firemen doctors. It's like,
yeah, I'm sorry, your house burnt down.
But, like, I mean, it's lunchtime and I'm hungry.
-- I
-- got, I haven't
done
burning house. I've got to go help out with.
Yeah.
So,
and I think that's part of the problem is how do you work at scale?
And there's very few jobs that work at scale like this,
like even within a fortune 100 company,
you're kind of like definitely up the scale ladder,
but you're still not,
you know, dealing with,
well, you also have to deal with it over years to see these trends, right?
Because there's have been definite trends over the years,
right? The industry has changed over years,
you know, Microsoft has gotten better in some ways and in other ways, it's like,
well, we discussed this with our security scale thing where it's just,
they're, they're pushing out so much more code and stuff that, like,
they still have a ton of vulnerabilities.
But
when you look at the size of Windows 11 now, it's like what a couple of gigabytes
that was at one point like the entire open source ecosystem,
right? You are right.
Yes. Like I, my first Linux came on 52 floppy disk.
It had gooey, it had text editors, it had everything,
52 floppy disk, slackware, 1.1
you know. Oh,
my goodness.
And what really annoys me is we've never had the ability to
process this data at scale
because like
now you can get a laptop with 32 gigs of RA M and a ton of storage and a
ton of CPU and slap an elastic instance on it and import half a terabyte of data and,
and start manipulating and modeling it
and even better is
these ecosystems matter.
But they like, basically, there's no, I don't want to say there's no,
there's like there's nobody doing N PM outside of the like no js.org ecosystem.
Apart from a few crazy people like Google
where they basically internalize the whole thing,
you know, again at scale.
But
essentially if you can
analyze the data for N PM,
that's the data for N PM. Like there's
the number of people not using N PM but using node packages
is less than a percent,
right? So
by analyzing these ecosystems,
that basically is reality.
I mean, II I agree, I agree 100%. And I think that's,
that is the story of all this is
everyone is using all of this stuff all of the time.
And even if you don't think you are, you're using a service
that has N PM packages somewhere in it,
you're using something that has go running it.
You know, there's,
there's just these fundamental technologies now that are inescapable.
And,
and so I think pretending you have some level of
control over any of this is laughable at best.
And, and I, there's a lot of people that do that, that,
that, I mean,
there, there's the old adage, oh, I don't want random people updating my packages.
It's like your packages were written by random people.
You know,
-- you use that Linux kernel much.
-- Right.
You, you, we have no idea where this stuff comes from and that's ok though,
that there's nothing wrong with that and it infuriates me
when I see especially open
source people talking about, oh, there's like some sort of trust
they have and it's like you literally don't,
we're all just flying by the seat of our pants.
And the reality is like
the open source is magic and it works
and no one knows how or why,
-- but it
-- does close source is the same except without the transparency
100.
I've been looking at um
at uh crypto wallets. Actually there's about 300 of them.
Um But I'm like trying so I'm trying to track down like who built these? And
Oh
man, in some cases. Ok. Basically there's three buckets of crypto wallets.
There's the ones done by exchanges so that you can use the exchange. Ok.
That makes sense. I understand this, that I get it.
Then there's the crypto walls that seem to be funded
by like a large entity given away for free.
I don't really understand them other than I think they're trying to pump shit coins
that could be.
And then the third bucket seems to be crypto Waltz
done by an individual and maybe it's portfolio work,
maybe they just really wanted to scratch their own niche.
I don't know.
But
that also ignores the fact that
I don't know that that necessarily is the
entity that actually wrote the crypto wallet,
right?
They might have farmed it out to some
random development house
and so of these 300 crypto walls, there's a bunch that are open source.
So you kind of have that transparency of like,
I'm not going to say which person built it, but like which github
I DS
contributed to it
and whether or not you can map those back to people, I don't know. Good luck.
But it, it,
it blows my mind that because this is an instance of software that actually has
like literal real world value. Like there's, this is
crypto wallets. Like if they do a rug pull or they send a backdoor update,
you know, they're gonna pull billions of dollars out
and take people's money.
And so i it's, you know, it's, it's not some theoretical like, well,
if I hack the software, I can make some money or hold them for ransom.
No, it's like this is software that holds money
that's easily moved
and washed well in the grand scheme of things.
Not easy, easy, but well, you know, go check out the show we did with the um
I'm totally spacing on his name, the Blockchain security people. Anyways,
the point is like,
and this is how it's operated for decades because
you can no longer build the software in house.
Like in the 19 sixties and seventies, all the software used was built in house.
There were like, was no software market.
Like you got a bunch of stuff from IBM and then you built the rest yourself.
But nowadays, no,
you,
you pull down 1000 M PM packages and bam it's a website.
-- All right, we need to, we need to close this one up.
-- I want to see more data analysis
and I want to see you chuck this stuff into a github
repo. So other people can,
-- you know, um
-- uh my, my code is in a github
repo. It's missing something. Well, you have to know how to run the code
and
it's not documented
and if anyone can figure it out who's not me. Like I will buy you a cookie because
-- ultimately
-- smart,
it's like Jerry gambling doing those Jupiter notebooks on CV data, right?
We need more of this like Jupiter notebooks is a good example.
Elastic search is a great example, like
analyzing the data so that we're not
just because we can't realistically have like there
are not going to be a lot of people like you and me that have read
20 30% of the CV database.
That's no, don't do that.
I, I guess that's, that's kind of my closing thought is
we, there is the open source,
we think we have and there's the open source we actually have.
And I think
we need to figure out what the open source we actually have is because today we're,
we're making too many assumptions and I think
assumptions in this context are dangerous.
Well, it's also that it's changed
like in the last 20 years.
-- That is true.
-- Like it's changed so much like
the, the whole idea of the like what an N PM ecosystem is.
Didn't make sense 20 years ago because we didn't have web apps.
We didn't have this compos ability. We didn't have C I CD pipelines.
Hell, we barely had source control
like
CV S.
Yo,
what was it? Was it sourceforge? Source
forge?
They're still around and they're no longer uh
putting uh ad software in the binary downloads.
-- Oh,
-- well,
good job guys.
All right. Anyway, I'm going to call this one.
This is, this has been a fun conversation.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to open source security, podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes, Suzie Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag Do hit us up on social media.
Kurt, you have a lovely rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.