Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime.
Josh Resor.
Hey, Kurt, what's up, man?
Uh Not much. Just had a good solid weekend
weekend. That means it's Monday.
I hate my,
I, I can relate to Garfield on this one.
Yeah.
Yeah, I'm a bit sour cause I bought the wrong kind of coffee for my coffee machine.
So I'm drinking brown water right now.
Yeah, I don't even know how to say about that. Um
Anyway,
brown water don't drink the brown water curt.
No, I, I can relate. I luckily have a fine cup of coffee here. So everything's good.
So, yeah, let's uh,
let's talk about the news. You found some really cool stuff, man.
Yeah. So
my,
by far my favorite announcement in the last week is
this uh this physically secure open source computer called Orwell,
which, which is a great name, right? Yeah.
And um
one thing I do like also is the form factor.
It's a really, it's sort of like this little, um,
you know, the game Simon says
the little brown sort of puck thing with buttons on it
that I have one from like the,
the fifties or whenever they came out on my shelf behind me,
one of the lights burnt out and I'm too lazy to fix it. But no, it still works.
Yeah.
And so the idea being is that you have this, like,
small computer that is physically secured, uh, it's, um,
not just, I don't know if it's tamper resistant or tamper evident,
but the idea is if you do try to monkey with it,
uh the hard drive and all the data is encrypted
and it will basically uh crypto shred the encryption keys,
like it'll just delete the encryption keys so you can't get at the data,
-- right?
-- It, it, so in reading this, it says, and I'm quoting the article exactly here.
It says any attempt to get physical access to the internals of your
PC will delete the cryptographic key rendering
all of your data permanently inaccessible.
So I would say that's,
that's relatively tamper resistant, assuming it works correctly, which
I'm sure it doesn't.
Yeah.
And the other concept is it has like uh a little key fob
that you carry with it that and the key fob uh has to,
I guess be in physical proximity
to the computer for the computer to work. So I kind of like that in that,
you know,
one aspect I really hate about a lot of security systems is
they only have one sort of form of authentication or protection,
right?
Like a password or,
well, that's actually typically it as a password.
Um, let's face it, right.
And, you know,
versus something that requires like an external
token that actually does something securely,
you know, like actually does a little bit of crypto on it or in decryption, you know.
So
like, for example, using your smartphone as a token, you know,
with the software loaded to generate numbers on it, you know,
to authenticate to it or whatever.
Um So I like that in this case, you know, that you've got the,
you've got the key fob.
Uh And then you've also,
I'm assuming I'm hoping that you also have to
enter a password to get this thing decrypted.
So they can't just like mug you and take your key fob
and use your computer.
Uh
That's a good question.
And there's also the issue of so one
of the problems with physical proximity always is
if somebody has access to your computer, it's generally game over at that point.
And I know when we're doing
analysis of security flaws, the assumption has always been,
if someone is actually sitting at the computer,
it's not a security issue because
let's face it.
Like if you can plug in a USB drive and crash a machine,
like you can just hit it with a hammer too.
I mean, both of those are effectively the same outcome, for example,
-- or
-- you can hit the user with a hammer
to give
you the pass,
we won't get into that one.
But so in this instance though,
you've got your fob
and you need to log in in some way and it does some level of decryption, which is great.
But I'm wondering what happens when you walk away. Does it power down?
Do we make sure that the key in question is completely gone? Because I mean,
when you're talking about actual hardware,
there's those
various attacks you can do, for example, like, you know,
cooling the ram way down and then yanking it and then reading it for
to get the encryption keys off of it.
Or in many instances, most people probably don't even encrypt their disks.
So you can just literally, you know, yank the disks and you've got what you need.
And so, I mean, this is a tough problem and
I commend these guys for starting down this path because I think as security people,
we are notorious for saying this is impossible to do.
It's too hard to do. It's not perfect. You're a bunch of idiots quit trying.
When in reality,
every time they try to do this, they're gonna make mistakes and let's face it.
It isn't gonna be perfect. There's gonna be attacks on this,
but every time they make a mistake, assuming they learn from their mistake,
it will continue to get better.
And I would love to be in a position where I
have a secure device on my desk that I can trust
-- that would be awesome.
-- Well, you already do.
It's your phone, like, let's face it, the iphone and the, well,
the better Androids have already done this with the
carry it with
me everywhere I go. Right. That is, that is how I secure my phone.
I don't leave it there.
Right. So, like the, the iphone is a good example of that.
I don't know if you remember the San Bernardino attacker, right?
But the idea being that
in the older iphones, you have the the encryption key
and um
it's actually held in like a a chip that protects it, you know, from access, right?
I think you get the 10 attempts and then it wipes itself and stuff and,
but the thing is you can just clone that data and and just sort of keep trying,
it wipes itself.
So you reload the data, try 10 times, wipes itself, reload the data, right?
Um And so it's not until you get like a fully integrated chip that you know
requires you to like physically disassemble a chip in some way to get the data
that you
really begin to get to a secure point.
Because for example,
you know that there was a guy that published the technique for taking apart an iphone
and with $100 in parts cloning the ra M or um sorry, cloning the uh
the storage
so that you can then just brute force attack it, right?
Because that's the thing too, physically. Once you have a computer physically,
you know, rarely is it like the movies where you have, like,
five minutes to decode it before the guy notices
-- you typically have, like, all month or two months or whatever or, or
-- forever.
I mean, let's face it. Even if you have an encrypted disk,
it's probably some sort of password. You have some sort of key
and you can just clone the disk and now you have infinite tribes
to crack the, crack the password. Right.
Yeah.
And so, no, I would definitely like to see more of this because,
yeah, I mean, I,
I have all my computers and all my devices
with encrypted hard drives as much as possible,
but still, you know,
um,
it's so easy to make a mistake or, you know, or even a simple thing.
Like, I just don't want my kids using my computer.
Right. I don't want them mucking up my computer.
Right. They're constantly trying to touch it and stuff.
-- I can relate to that. Man. It's,
-- yeah,
we've had to train my one kid to actually, like,
physically turn his back and move a few feet away when
we enter passwords because he keeps trying to shoulder surf them.
Fantastic.
-- That's great,
-- you know.
Um, but yeah, so, no, I love because part of it too is there's, there's probably some
relatively simple ways that we can make, you know,
the situation better for 99% of users, which is really what matters, you know,
like I, I want, for example, if my phone gets stolen,
I just need a few minutes to go find a computer that I can log in from.
So I can remotely tell my phone to wipe itself
the next time it's, you know,
connected to the network or whatever.
You don't, you don't have that tied into an apple watch that if your heart stops or,
or the phone is separated from the watch by more than 100 ft.
It, it explodes.
I actually looked into that and there's no app for that.
They do have the Apple Watch doing authentication, which,
uh, that's actually, I mean, that's why I upgraded my phone was to get the,
the fingerprint log in so that I don't have to keep entering my password constantly.
-- You know,
-- I don't know if we've talked about this before,
but I actually found out that
in, in the US. At least
they cannot make you type your password in,
but they can force your finger onto the fingerprint scanner on your phone.
So,
yeah, it's,
I,
I'm wondering about biometrics long term.
Uh Yeah, it's, it's hard to change your fingerprint when it gets stolen.
It's, it's tricky, right?
Or the fact that you can, uh, there was a guy that did a,
he basically found with a decent telephoto
lens. You could take pictures of people's fingerprints off of glasses,
like in public?
Fantastic.
You know.
So, and, and as far as I'm aware,
there's nobody has the discipline to wear gloves all the time,
you know,
that, that CD finally pays off. Right.
-- Yeah.
-- Yeah. All that hand sanitizer
go to, uh, or no. What is it?
The, uh, all those movies where they would sandpaper their fingerprints off.
Right. I don't know if that works. I'm gonna guess not because I think if it did,
you would hear more of it
and not in the movies, right? Because we all know that everything in the movie
-- is
-- totally
-- true.
There was uh issues with surgeons using iphones and because
they scrub their fingers and hands so much that they,
they wore the prints down enough that the
sensors weren't able to register them properly.
-- So
-- it does happen
just
the same.
No fingerprint
pretty much. Yeah, I wasn't able to read them. So,
but yeah, no, I mean, one thing I would love to see is, you know,
why don't we have encrypted hard drives by default now?
Because, you know,
as far as I know every single CPU on the planet now has like an AES 256
you know, capability in it.
Right. So we can encrypt everything using
A S 256 for, for basically for free computationally speaking.
-- Yes.
-- I mean, so where do you keep the key though?
Well, well, like in a Linux system, for example,
you have your slash boot partition which is not encrypted, which drives me nuts.
And you
then,
you know, bootstrap into the encrypted system.
Uh Android has their secure boot system. So does Windows.
Um you know, you could, well, you could keep the key in the the T PM.
-- Uh the trusted platform, what is it trust platform, trusted
-- platform module
and Windows does a pretty nice job of supporting this.
Actually, the Linux support is abysmal on T PM.
And this is one of the things we're working on
solving with T PM 2.0 is making it actually useful
instead of a collection of barely working binaries.
Yeah.
And even when it, I mean,
to me, the iphone is a good example of you should just
encrypt by default
and that's an end of story,
right? And your login password or whatever should be able to decrypt your password.
And if you really want, you can set up recovery codes, you know, same thing on Linux,
you can set up recovery mechanisms. Uh It's kind of a chore, but
um fundamentally,
I think everything should be even if it's just encrypted with like a four digit pin,
that's still way better than no encryption.
I mean, I think you could argue things are heading in that direction because
let's face it.
The concept of the desktop is kind of falling
apart these days just because everyone's using their telephones,
they're using their tablets,
they've got all these devices and it's generally not a laptop or a desktop
and like, I encrypted my android devices
and it was really easy to do and it just works.
And I don't know a lot of people who don't have passwords on their phones these days.
I think generally speaking,
most people have a password and once you have a password, you can encrypt the phone.
So
I think we're closer than you think.
Well, and, and this is true of devices and computers that are used by people.
But what about computers that are not used directly by people?
So going to your cloud example,
you know, when, where we,
we used to typically say if somebody has physical access came over.
Well, you know, in the cloud, for example,
I have no idea where these data centers are or what security provisions they have.
I mean,
they, they claim, you know, sock, what is it,
whatever the sock two standard is or the B si standard or the iso standard, you know,
for physical security and stuff.
I have no idea what that actually means or if it's true.
-- But
-- today
in the cloud, you have to trust your cloud provider
pretty much completely because they have
virtually unlimited access to your machines and data.
I'm more worried about silly situations like, oh,
they accidentally throw out a bunch of hard drives instead of destroying them
or, you know, so I want to have my data encrypted at rest. Ideally,
right.
That makes
sense
and in fact, there are a handful of I know products that can do this now
and
there's something redhead's working out.
We're gonna call it network bound disc encryption.
Where the idea is basically, it's not meant to be secure in,
in the context of protecting a machine.
But rather the instance you say about throwing out hard drives where
you'll have some infrastructure set up.
So in a machine boots, it can automatically get the decryption key.
And the idea is if the, if the hard drive is removed from the machine,
you can no longer acquire that encryption key again,
or at least not without like an insane amount of work and,
and local access to the network.
But
it's, it's a tricky problem man. I mean,
I get it and I think on the cons for what it's worth on the consumer side,
I think things are much better than they've ever been.
And I think on the server side,
we're starting to move in the right direction.
I won't say we're there, but I think it's understood where we need to go.
I definitely on the server side.
Um And then, but there's that unfortunate gap in between of like, for example,
photocopiers and
you know,
all the people I've had to explain to now that a
modern photocopier has a hard drive in it and that it,
you know, it takes a copy of your thing and then prints out that copy.
That's what it's doing when it's, you know, quote unquote photocopying.
And they're like,
what do you mean? I'm like, well, when you photocopy something 500 times, right?
It scans it once
and prints it 500 times, it doesn't scan it, print it, scan it, print it right.
You know,
and of course, like any good computer, it simply deletes the file when it's done,
but that actually doesn't destroy the data.
Right. It's just there but, you know, sort of semi forgotten.
And, I mean, I'm sure you've seen this, you know,
the 60 minutes or the various people that
have bought like old photocopiers and stuff on ebay
and then, you know, run disc recovery programs to, you know, un delete the data
and turned up, you know, like medical, you know, offices,
like their last three years of faxes, you know, things like that.
Right.
Um,
and,
yeah, no, I think that that's the frustrating part to me is on the server side.
It's,
it's somewhat easier because everything gets replaced every
3 to 4 years because it just gets
so slow and eats so much energy that we want to get rid of it anyways.
But, you know, people buy printers and printers are forever, you know,
fax machines are forever.
There was that article about, you know,
fax machines running Linux
based firmware from 1999 still in use. And it's like,
and, and the funny thing is that's actually probably
in some ways almost,
uh,
I don't wanna say safer but it would
be more confusing for the attacker almost because,
you know, they would try some modern exploits against it and they would fail because
the software is sold that it doesn't even support that, you know.
But, uh,
no,
we're not discussing that.
-- But I think in general you're right, we need
-- to run software from 1999. That's the,
that's the takeaway. That's true.
Yeah.
But uh no, I think it encryption at all levels all the time.
If nothing else just to prevent silly mistakes.
-- Like, oops, I threw out a batch of hard drives but instead of destroying them.
-- Right.
Absolutely. And, and I think that's the important thing is
there are two scenarios that we often forget about the,
the other is there's always the malicious
attacker angle which we're obsessed with,
right.
We want to stop those Attackers. We have to do what we can.
But then people make dumb mistakes and they do
it all the time and that's the one that's actually
mostly solvable I would say.
And so I think if we're clever,
we're gonna put kind of more focus there for now because let's face it.
The problem with Attackers
is if the attacker is smarter than you, which they probably are,
you cannot stop them by definition.
That is the reality of it.
But stupid mistakes are by definition stupid.
So you don't even have to be very smart to prevent them.
Right.
You know,
I see so many simple things where just a checklist
would have prevented the disaster or the incident or whatever,
you know.
And, uh, I remember, like I remember looking into, you know,
hard drive sort of destruction and tracking and
one thing that, well, didn't really surprise me. But,
uh, was interesting was, you know, I, I didn't realize until I checked,
but I've never seen a,
the hard drives themselves have a serial number,
right. Usually on a sticker,
the platters themselves don't have numbers or serial numbers or any marking.
It's just a piece of metal,
right?
Um, so you have to, you know,
you have to maintain some really serious inventory control to like,
be able to really
no
ones
gonna take a hard drive apart and remove some
platters and then put them into another thing like
that isn't something that happens.
Having the serial number of the hard drive is probably ok.
This is
no, and that's the point is like, nobody, nobody would care about that.
Right.
Because if, if the attacker is able to do that, I'm going to do that then.
Well, yeah, they're gonna do something else.
I don't even know why anyone would do that. That,
that is a crazy attack.
Well, if you were able, for example,
if you were allowed to bring a laptop into a facility but
not allowed to bring a hard drive in or out or whatever.
Um,
-- but
-- you're gonna,
you're gonna take a hard drive apart, you're gonna remove the platters.
It would just buy a sticker. It'll cost you a nickel. You can cover up the.
Yeah.
Well, but this,
the point being is that there's places that
worry about those kind of things and that,
you know, it's really,
they should just be encrypting the discs.
Ok. I'll agree with that.
I
was
trying to get
-- your movie.
-- Plot attack.
Well, that's the
point.
It's a movie
plot thing that doesn't really make sense,
you know, and again,
like for example, with the network bound encryption,
that problem just largely goes away,
right?
It, it almost completely goes away, which is the idea, it,
it wouldn't stop an attacker from necessarily finding the key,
be it in memory on the machine or even
pretending you're the machine and talking to the,
the server, the secret server.
But that's OK
because that's not what we're protecting against.
We're protecting against a hard drive, leaving the data center.
And in which case that happens or
if you, for example, when you're transferring V MS between data centers, right?
If, if the VM is lost or stolen as funny as that sounds,
you don't have to worry about the data, right?
Yeah.
Yeah. So,
no, I think I,
I think we are on the path to sort
of encryption of everything that stores interesting data.
But
the challenge being, of course, it costs money to do this and you know,
for something like a server easy.
You know, it has enough value
and cost that adding a dollar to encrypt everything is ok. But,
you know, the internet of things, for example,
a lot of the internet of things is going to have data on it.
Um,
they just recently here in Edmonton where I live, uh,
replaced or are in the process of replacing
all the electricity meters with the digital ones
and they sort of
didn't come out and say it. Exactly.
But they, they, you know, they made those noises around, oh, it's safe, it's secure.
Don't worry,
you know,
like, just don't think about it. It'll be fine.
But I, I really have no idea how much data it is storing and, but, and, you know,
based on those data patterns, you can, you can tell a lot about somebody's life.
It, it's incredible. Actually, I,
I know somebody who works for the power company in town where I live
and I was discussing this with them and I found out actually
I can make a written request to the power company and they will send me
my usage data,
which I've not done and I kind of don't want to just because I,
I don't want to get fired for, for spending a month,
you know, analyzing data.
But he said basically they take a reading
like every minute or something
and they, they store that data for several years.
So, yeah, there's a significant amount of data stored on your power use
by the power company.
I mean, it, it's wild but again, big data scary. What can we do with it? Who knows?
Magic?
Magic.
So,
and that's the thing I think is, is
we're entering this era where for one thing, storage has gotten so cheap, right?
Like I, you remember I was jokingly saying last week,
I'm not going to buy a new file server once I
can get a five terabyte drive for under 200 bucks.
And then I was like, wait, I wonder what they cost?
Well, apparently it's 100 and 80 bucks now.
That's under two 100 bucks, man.
No, I agree. Just back it up to Aws and keep a massive disk in, in the closet.
Yeah. You know, and so, you know, you can put a 32 gig.
Well, uh what was it? Those new one terabyte SD cards,
right? Like
32 gigabyte SD cards now are, well,
they're like the four meg USB sticks of old or whatever,
whatever minimum size we had back in the day. Yeah.
You know, and that's the thing too is, I mean,
there's gonna be so many of these IOT devices where
you can just add
literally infinite data storage
-- for like 10 cents.
-- You don't need infinite data storage on the device.
Even you with the cloud, you have infinite data storage.
You just need some bandwidth.
Well,
the problem is you also need to then pay recurring monthly cost to store the data,
right?
I would bet you
that
the cost of using
a, a cloud storage system
is
at or less than the cost of purchasing and keeping your, your storage on site.
It is so insanely cheap
for small amounts of data.
That is I would, yeah, that would definitely be true.
Um But what about, you know, things like, for example,
somebody's media center or these iot things that, you know, need to actually store,
you know, and process like
a relatively
like
let me give you an example.
I
have a backup.
I keep an Aws encrypted and do all that, you know, tinfoil hat stuff,
which it should be.
But let me, where's my bill? I just got it.
Guess how much it costs me to store between 7080 gigs of data in Aws per month.
This isn't glacier, this is like the proper S3 storage.
What do you think that costs
one or $2?
It's $3.86
right now,
which is like,
that's so cheap. I mean, you think 70 gigs of disk space would run me, what?
Probably 100 bucks figure because you can't
buy anything less than a terabyte anymore.
But
it, it man, I'd have to have it for what,
like 10 years to recruit my costs at this point.
I
mean, it's crazy, man. It's so cheap.
Yeah.
But um, well, the thing is, it's more to the point, you know,
you have to boot the IOT device so you have to have some storage in it anyways.
Right.
And
the minimum amount of storage you can buy. Now, I'm going to assume one or two gigs.
I mean, I, I think,
uh, like I remember back in the day when, you know, we were buying those, uh,
what was it? W RT
54 G wireless access points from D link that had like what
was it like? Four megs of ram or whatever, four megs of flash?
And that was amazing,
you know,
but yeah, no, I I
hopefully we get encryption everywhere that just works. Um
But the challenge become is how do you do that for devices
that don't have like a user interface or like your light bulbs
or whatever? You know,
I don't know, do, does a light bulb need encryption?
I don't think it needs encryption for data at rest probably.
But for example, it does for like signed up updates.
It does for, you know,
well, but in that case, you just need to store a key
somewhere inside of the device,
right?
To me,
it's also getting to the point to where I
like the data encryption at rest because it prevents
uh tampering. And it also is more, you know, evident if there is a problem, right?
Like if you get data corruption, the whole thing, you're gonna know right away.
Whereas you know, with a typical file system,
uh, granted,
I haven't had this happen in a long time because hardware is way more reliable.
But, you know, it's good to know.
Like, um, I mean, a great example of light bulbs is I bought a whole bunch of those, uh,
CF CS when they first came out and then, like, six months later,
a couple of them burned out
and they were like dark brown where the bulb connected to the transformer bit.
You know, and I wish I'd spotted that earlier.
-- All
-- right, we're, we're, we're in a
hoard.
Let's, I'm gonna pull this out
and let's talk about,
did you hear about the system? D one line crash?
Yeah, that one,
I don't know what to think about that. Like,
it's a, what was it? An assertion failure, I think,
uh something like that.
But, um, it, it,
uh again, I don't, well, I'm not too worried about it obviously because, you know,
somebody with, again,
local access can just typically reboot the system or pull the plug on it.
But
it is
a bit.
It seems to me like this is something that fuzzing can and should catch.
I would expect fuzzing to catch this. Yes.
You know.
So
what really gets me though is ok. So now we've seen this one. It's been patched
but has anybody looked for more of these?
Uh Probably not.
I think.
So, this interests me for a couple of reasons is first of all,
it is always intriguing when you can lock up a system by running just a shell command
as, as a logged in user. OK?
But then the thing I think about is so system d love it or hate it.
And I know that there's plenty of people on both sides and
I am indifferent in the middle where if you are a fan,
boy of it, I will pretend I like you.
And if you hate it, you know. Yeah, down to system D, you know, I'm
I'm quite happy to,
to be the fair weather fan of system D.
But I think the thing here is no one can deny that
system D is potentially heavier than it needs to be where it's,
for example, if you have process one,
which is the init system for the,
I'm not even going to get into the details of what that means.
But let's say you process one
that also is reading
a bunch of crazy data off the network and off the local
system through a socket and all this stuff is going on.
I don't think that's necessarily
a well thought out system.
This is one of those cases,
you really need to be using sub processes to be parsing external data, right?
Versus just doing it yourself because let's face it
someday. And this is a guarantee
there, there is going to be something someone sends you that creates a problem.
And when you're doing it all in a singular process, you have issue.
I mean,
this is why web browsers all have now moved to the environment
where they have individual processes for parsing things like tabs and web content
because it used to be one giant ball
and they got killed, right?
And this is the same story repeating, you know,
history repeats itself as they say and this is it right here.
I think we definitely need to,
you know, somewhat decompose applications and, you know,
sandbox various components, especially something
by definition, something like system D or process one has to be super powerful,
like even more powerful than root, you know.
Um
but at the
same
time, you know,
the
route,
I
mean,
it's, well, you can live without root, you can't live without process one.
And um
you know, especially in things like the container space where it, you know,
you're gonna end up with
tons of this stuff, right?
Um You know, one for each microservice,
right?
Whereas you used to just have one per physical machine
and we've,
I think part of the challenge is, you know, is people want stuff to work.
Like I remember
a few years ago I bought a little GSM
antenna puck USB thing, right?
It's like a little pocket puck shaped thing with a G uh sorry GPS antenna in it,
plugged it into my Linux machine
and it worked
the Linux machine
like accepted the USB device, turned it on and went, oh, this thing requires GPS D,
it,
it started up GPS D and
boom data.
Right. I didn't have to do anything and it was magical to me and,
you know, and unfortunately people want that and getting that kind of thing to work.
Say with the old school in it
is difficult at best,
you know, and we've got all these requirements now for computers that, you know,
nobody would have ever had 1015 years ago.
You know, I want my computer to sleep. I want it to hibernate. I want it to,
uh, I want to be able to
go across different wireless networks and have it
sleep on one and wake up on another,
you know,
and these are hard problems to solve and,
yeah.
Well, like you said, it's, uh,
we ended up with this giant monolithic thing called system D, you know,
that what I really love is that it even has its own internal logging.
Right. It doesn't use cis log. It uses the journal.
Oh, that's not even the craziest thing it does, man. It has its own DNS resolver.
Oh,
yeah, exactly.
I, I'm just,
I'm trying to imagine a situation where you have
a system without a DNS library because typically they,
that come, that
those batteries are included.
I'm not even gonna ask,
I, again, this comes back to the system D fan system D hater.
And
rather than have an opinion,
I'll say
it seems a bit odd to me, but I will not judge
because I have not written the internet system.
So I can't really say if this is functionality we should have or not.
Yeah.
So,
yeah, I think, well, and it's, I see,
I've seen this with a lot of software projects where rather than, you know,
trust somebody else's implementation or use it, they write their own.
Uh
sometimes because they do need something a
bit more specific and sometimes because,
you know, not invented here, syndrome is strong and,
-- well, it's fun Droid code,
-- I think not invented here is
more common than not
because
if something doesn't do what you need it to do, it's open source
patch. It,
right. Everyone's always saying patch is welcome
but
it's, it, it's easier said than done, of course.
Yeah.
So, yeah, I suspect at some point we'll see system D
will probably have to be decomposed if nothing else for performance. Right?
Because if you have,
if every single container has system D in it, that's a lot of overhead.
It is. And I don't even think it'll be performance as much as space
because right now system D is pretty big
and when people are worried about having containers
that are a couple of megabytes in size
that becomes an issue.
Yeah.
And uh, yeah, I've, I've always wondered why, you know,
we have this sort of UNIX pendulum of going between, you know,
on the one extreme we have that do one task, do it well.
And you know, you get some pretty extreme tools like that.
But then on the other hand, you know, tho those tools slowly grow over time, like uh
Grep said,
a,
you know, those things have become,
I, I'm pretty sure ac is turning complete and I think set is as well
-- because it's got pattern back referencing.
-- Matt.
I'd be surprised if they weren't.
Yeah.
And I don't know that Grep is turning complete, but I'm guessing somebody could,
but I'm guessing somebody somewhere has done something terrible with it
and accidentally spawned an A I that then committed suicide.
But yeah, so, I mean, it's, yeah, it's interesting to me like,
I don't know what the answer is but I'm pretty sure what we currently have
is going to be found to be wrong in five years.
-- Like everything else was
-- everything is wrong. Kurt, it's all wrong.
We know that.
Uh so anyway, I think if we want to sum this one up
is,
first of all, I guess, let's say this too. Uh People make mistakes
and so I think being too hard on the system to
developers is wrong because anyone can make a mistake like this.
Now, granted, fuzzing could have caught it.
Yeah,
we should fuzz it whatever and we can blame ourselves for this as
well because we work for a company that is funding most of this development
and the security groups are part of have not fuzzed. So there's that right.
But there's also the fact that it might be too
big and it might be time to start thinking about
is this set up in the right way, especially from the security point of view.
And so that's potentially something for us to talk about in the future,
but fundamentally,
uh, love it or hate it.
It is what it is. Right.
Yeah.
Well, and it's, it's, I don't know if you've seen,
but in the cloud space there's been a couple of major companies
that have gone back to monolithic designs saying that it's easier.
It's,
you know, it's actually it works better for them in some ways.
So, like everything, you know, I think part of the problem with software is
there's like 10 right ways to do it
and then there's like a billion potential ways to do it.
And the problem is I find oftentimes those 10
right ways to do it often look vastly different,
you know,
and with a slight variation then they're also terrible.
Um, but more the point having working code is amazing. Right.
That's something that always gets me is that any of the stuff I turn it on and it works
for some definition of work.
So,
all right.
Moving on.
All right. So let's, let's bring it home. We've been chatting about this for a while.
Now, there's a story you found here about the need for an open security journal.
Yeah. I, this kind of comes back to that whole thing of like, we don't even
know what we've forgotten because it's not documented anywhere.
Like
what we know,
like, the fact that when it comes to, for example, for cryptography, the still quote
unquote best reference is applied crypto version, what two second edition.
And that's like,
so
actually,
if you talk to most
crypto guys, they do not like that book.
Yeah. Well, exactly.
So
we have
-- nothing
-- old. It's wrong,
you know. And that's, and that's the point, right is
for example, where, where can I, oh, here's a really simple question.
How much, you know, how should I securely create certificates
for SSL and TLS web servers?
Right? And, well,
most people are going to go to stack overflow to find out,
right? And there's some, some
not entirely correct stuff in there. And
-- how do I tell? Which is, which
-- I'm gonna be lucky if I get to stack overflow.
I'm just gonna type into Google how to make a certificate.
I'm gonna click the first link and then that's what I'm gonna do.
This is actually where, where I think let's encrypt is doing some really cool stuff
because they've taken away all of the dumb questions and you just
run a command and you fill in a couple of things and,
and a certificate appears and it's magic and I love it.
Yeah. As ugly as some of their code is. And as ugly as some of their processes. It's
way better than
the majority of the current system. Like,
it's, yeah, so it's as ugly as it is. I mean, we don't
have far to go to get better.
Um, so back to this, I mean, I,
because I've been reading some fascinating papers recently where
instead of just talking about stuff, they actually had data,
like, they actually had crazy.
I know it's so wild to like,
uh what was the one like talking about, you know, users clicking on links and typing,
you know,
just doing random stuff and they actually had like
a really decent sample size of a couple 100 people
that they, you know, tried this out with.
And so they actually had statistically significant results.
And
unfortunately, you know, again,
how do I tell those good papers from those bad papers?
-- It's
-- hard man.
And this is one of the challenges any journal has is there's always bad content.
In fact,
a number of journalists have recently come under fire for producing
bad content and it's not that they even knew it.
It's just that people were submitting poor quality stuff
and it's,
it's hard to tell what it is and security
is even harder because security is often very binary where
there some advice can be questionable and that's ok
and some advice can be dangerous,
right?
And that's, I mean,
like rolling your own crypto would be a
great example is if somebody published a paper about
their new crypto algorithm.
Would you want in a security journal? Would you want people implementing that?
Because let's face it in, in 99% of those situations that is,
it's just completely terrible. And you should never be done
right
now.
At the same time,
I also don't want to be the naysayer that just
def we keep saying everything is impossible and nothing is real
because that's not helpful either.
And so this is, this is a tricky one man is,
how do we do something like this that makes it useful.
But also doesn't just burn everyone out involved because face it,
anyone who's gonna be reviewing these papers,
you're gonna, after reading about five you're gonna be done is my guess.
Yeah, I can, I,
I wonder if the journal format is the best way to do this because for example,
I look at something like Wikipedia, which is amazing for general knowledge stuff.
But then it's, it's, oh, I forget what that, um,
something amnesia where you basically read like a newspaper
article on a topic you're familiar with and they're,
they're wrong about stuff
and then you read other articles in that same newspaper here and you just,
you think they're correct.
Right. And
I've read Wikipedia articles about topics I'm very familiar with and noticed,
you know, errors and inconsistencies,
-- you know, you can fix those. Right. I,
-- I have, I have and,
um,
but then it makes me, you know, I kind of,
I'm guessing the rest of Wikipedia is just as wrong.
But it's, you know, it's vastly better than, well,
what we have in the security industry, which is basically nothing at this point.
I,
yes,
I, I've written about this before, even the fact that
if we had tribal knowledge that would be better than what we have today.
So, and then the other thing too is there's so much,
I mean, there's potentially so much shenanigans going like,
because the security industry tends to attract trolls and, you know,
other annoying people
in a way that other industries don't sometimes.
-- And, you know,
-- I mean, do you think we're worse than anywhere else?
I, I honestly don't know, I feel like maybe we are but
I think for a lot of people it's, it's, you know,
how many people would love to prove Bruce Schneier
wrong.
And so, or, you know, those people that submit those like Markov
chaining generated papers to, you know, journals that were just gibberish,
you know,
they would love to do that to security people because again,
security people tend to be so binary and they tend to be so mean to everybody else.
I mean,
let's face it, right?
The security industry is not generally full of nice understanding, kind,
caring people,
you know,
they're typically burnt out because they're, you know,
equally frustrated by everybody else.
So I suspect this journal idea would be a lot
harder just on a process level. But
the other problem too is, I mean,
you might write a paper that's entirely correct today
and then tomorrow somebody finds out the math is wrong
but, you know, you based part of this on or something like that.
-- I mean,
-- but that's true of any industry.
I mean, there are medical papers that were published five years ago that we now know,
like, are, are dangerous to do these things, right?
This is,
that's totally true in any industry.
Do they have feedback mechanisms for that? Like, do they update the papers or
I have no idea. That's a really good question. Actually, I'm not sure what they do.
One thing I'd want to see is, you know, the ability to curate and,
and keep it sort of up to date to say like, yeah, this paper was correct
on this date.
But now it's like really, really bad idea because, you know,
Josh figured out how to quantum
entangled
photons
of prime numbers or God knows what.
And that's part of the challenge I see in stack overflow whenever I look for,
you know,
uh
answers is, I mean, some things are so generic that OK, that's fine.
You know, they, they're always correct or whatever. But,
you know, some of these things have changed drastically.
This,
we just talked about this earlier is I was doing some work with go over the weekend
and I realized that the,
the math slash rand
random number generator in go is preceded by default.
So it is an insecure random number generator. And of course, the DOCS
say
exactly
you can, you can add your own seed.
But this one and, and the DOCS even say like do not use this for crypto operations,
right?
No question that that's fine.
But
if you're doing a search for, say how to generate random numbers and go,
you're gonna get this example to pop up.
And of course, the example doesn't say don't do this.
It just shows you how to get your job done. And so
I actually, I did some digging on github
and I found a handful of uses that, that sort of scared me a little bit.
But at the same time, the thing I keep coming to here is this is 2016.
We have no excuse for having an insecure
random number generator available in a popular language.
-- And they all do
-- though.
One quick question, dude. Not only OK, so it's deterministic by default,
I'm assuming also if you see it twice with the same number,
you get the exact same output.
-- I mean, that's how seeds work with random number generators,
-- right?
Well, some are, you know,
they have mixing in to try and make it somewhat non deterministic.
But um so it's not even, it's, it's
basically what I'm trying to get it from a security point of view.
This is great because
it is
a random number generator.
Uh that is not really,
it's not pseudorandom even.
It's just deterministically give it a seed and it grinds out some determined
output.
Right.
And,
-- and so, so let's tie this
-- to
explain that to a normal person. I fear and why that they're wrong to use. This is,
you know, I, I fear that that's not going to be an easy conversation.
No, I, I totally get it.
And so, but let's tie this back now to this concept of a security journal
is
we've been making this mistake
since we've started using computers and it really
no one cared until maybe five years ago.
And so this is a great example of where you're, you know, five years ago,
this advice was bad and now now it's something or five years ago,
the advice was fine and now it's bad.
Right?
How do, who decides that? Because I guarantee you, I've not done this.
But if I go to the go upstream guys and say this is nonsense, this thing should be
random from the start and because people are going to use it,
you know, they're gonna come back with me and say,
but the doc say not to do it.
And that's
bonkers. Right.
Well, to me it's, you know,
I tell my kids not to run with scissors and I also put the knives away
because they're kids, they, they make mistakes and
I feel, you know, that that's one of the things that gets me about programming.
Programming is always, you know, I want the choice,
I want the tools I want to be able to do it my way.
Because what if I have this weird requirement? Corner case. Well,
too bad, you know, if you really do,
then you can go spin some crazy monstrosity yourself.
But
yeah, like you said, for the majority of people, if you call like a random number,
it should be
not just random but like cryptographically secure random
because people are probably going to use it in that way.
-- They're
-- totally gonna
use it.
People
do.
But here's the thing. All right.
So running with scissors playing with knives, bad ideas.
We have a journal of
Children
and you publish an article that says you shouldn't do this.
And what happens when half of the board says Kurt's an idiot,
kids should know better.
And the other half says, yeah, that's good advice to publish this.
And I, I fear
that is we.
Uh so I guess going to the fundamental core of security
is I don't feel like we have enough kind of foundational elements
that we could even have a journal without it being just a massive flame war.
Well,
I would go even further to say we don't
even have like a basic ontology of vocabulary for.
And I actually just got, if you actually just
one hour ago, a good old Harold booth from Nest posted to the CV editorial board
basically saying that they are working on
uh
a draft announcement for, you know, a vulnerability description ontology
so that we can describe vulnerabilities
-- and we all use the same language.
-- I love that
-- it's 2016 and we're just getting around to this. And
-- how many pages is this draft
like 27,000 or
I mean,
it is
establishing a secure connection?
-- That's good, of
-- course, and,
and let's face it without you telling me if it's more than three pages,
nobody's going to read it
except maybe like you and Art Mann. Right.
Here
we
go.
Uh It's actually only 37
pages,
only 37 pages.
And you know,
that that's gonna be fascinating edge of the seat material. Right?
Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. And I mean, but the reality is we, you know, like
here's the
two
together
like you get, yeah, you get an engineer from India,
an engineer from Australia and an engineer from Canada together
and they're gonna be able to have a conversation without
you walk into a bar.
Yeah. You know,
except maybe the American engineer who wants to use like foot pounds or whatever,
foot
pounds.
Yes.
And I hate the English system so much. Actually,
I'm,
I'm brainwashing my Children to love the metric system
and despise English units because they're so stupid.
But that's, we're not going to get into that today.
But uh anyway, so, I mean, yeah, that's the thing is you know,
all these other industries are mature enough that they just
take this for granted that they have a common language
-- or that they have a language
-- I want, I mean, I guess you're right,
but they also, it took them time to get there.
I mean,
the medical field certainly didn't show up one day and was like,
all right here is the way it's gonna work guys.
You know, they, they,
they were murdering people for thousands of years essentially.
And then they finally decided, like we're gonna figure out what's going on here.
And I imagine the auto industry is probably very similar
and I suspect every industry has gone through this.
And,
I mean,
man, being in the middle of security some days, I feel like we're too slow
in other days.
I feel like this is impossible and other days I feel like, you know, maybe,
maybe we're getting it, we're figuring it out.
So,
I don't know. Today is, uh,
I, I think today I feel like we might be figuring it out.
I
just, I wonder if we have enough time because, you know,
as I pointed out before everybody that ships,
stuff is shipping stuff with software on it now
and all this stuff is being attached to the internet.
-- Yeah,
-- that, that is a good question and I don't even think it's a good question of,
do we have time?
I mean,
we don't need time. That's not our problem.
How how bad does it have to get before people start caring
is maybe the right question to ask because let's face it.
In general. People don't care about security because it gets in the way.
I mean, I think, I think deep down they, they want to,
but when it comes down to it at the end of the day, this is kind of like
if I have tools with a safety guard on it, the safety guard gets in the way,
I'm taking that thing off.
You know, I picked my table so I did that on it.
It came with a nice little kick back guard and,
and
seriously, the first time I used it, it got in the way.
I'm like, well, that's enough of that and off it went, it's never been back on since.
Oh, dear.
I just,
I just haven't used my table
so
saw enough to actually want to remove it. I'll be honest,
my
fee,
my chop
saw has that little red line on it saying
don't put your fingers over this red line and I
-- do it constantly.
-- Totally do all the time. Yes.
Right.
I get it. I mean, I get it. I'm not saying it's right, but I get
it.
So, I mean, we can't even get people to look both ways before they cross the street.
I,
yeah, walk in Boston for a couple of days and you'll, you'll fix that.
You learn quick,
especially on one way. Streets.
I
think
how, I guess going back to your thing? Yeah. How do we decide, then who gets to decide?
Right. Who's, do we just leave it to Bruce Schneier?
-- No,
-- I think you should listen
to me.
I will be the decider.
Uh, no. Well, ok, so, you know what, here's the deal is,
I think
if we have a more scientific rigor to our industry and this comes back to NIST,
putting together
that kind of, you know,
fundamental language we get to use and this needs to exist elsewhere.
I think once we have a more scientific basis to kind of decide what we're doing,
it will become easier
to decide what is right and what is wrong in the context of security.
Because today, it is almost entirely based off of opinion.
And of course, my opinion is the right one
and that's basically what everybody thinks except, you know, obviously in my case,
it, it actually is right,
which is again
and you end up with this where everyone's like, oh, I respect your opinion.
Well, except I really don't.
And it, it's kind of a mess.
And we see this though because we see it when people argue about how to fix
certain issues or they argue about is this particular bug a security issue or not?
I mean,
you see this all the time, man, you've got a researcher shows up and he's like,
I've found the worst security bug ever.
I mean, bad luck is a great example of that. Right? They got
the Domain, they made a big deal. I mean, they, they should have had a theme song
for the thing
to
-- remember
-- and it came out and we're like,
this is, it like, this sucks. What's up, man?
And, and,
yeah, that was the sam
of one that, uh, Cerne did
and the poor researcher who found it, like, yeah, that was good work.
And he got killed
in, out there in the wild because we decided it wasn't good enough.
Well, although honestly, I think
nothing short of some sort of root level
worm
would have lived up to the hype.
So
don't hype your issues guys.
We
do tend to eat our young in the security industry.
Yeah.
Yeah, I think that's fair. But again, I think part of that comes back to
it's so heavily based on experience and opinion.
It's difficult to kind of bring us up to the next level.
And there are very few people who can objectively look at things
without bringing, you know, kind of their own personal feelings into, into the mix.
Yeah.
But no, I have hope like, I mean,
nist is a great example. They've done some really good work, you know.
Um, and more to the point they actually publish their stuff
and it's,
they keep it up to date. That's the biggest thing too I find is,
you know, I've read a lot of these things where people talk about these things and it,
it was written five years ago
and
is it still correct? Is it
not? Is it?
Well? And this comes back to the journal thing is if you're not paying people to care,
they don't.
And in fact, uh
it, this is one of the great challenges is it's easy to say,
I'll volunteer to work on this journal and I might for a month.
But then when real life kicks in, it's like,
well, this sucks.
I mean, I don't want to work on this stupid journal anymore for free.
And so it's tough, man. It's, it's a hard problem.
I don't, I don't know if we have a good answer for it today. But I guess
let's, let's take it home.
We think.
And again, I, sadly, this is opinion,
but
we think one of the bigger problems here is the fact that
we need the science of security and we don't have that today.
And so
to all you listeners out there,
if you have ideas or there's something we're not aware of
or you think there's something we should be paying attention to
let us know. We would love to hear from you about the science of security.
All right.
And with that,
any final final thoughts, Kurt,
if you have data, please share it.
Yeah,
in a friendly format.
Not a PDF.
Every time somebody sends me a PDF with a security thing,
I'm just like uh run it through virus.
Hope that for the virus,
right?
Oh, I love it.
All right. Well, I guess until next time. Thanks for listening folks.
Again, if you want all the show notes, all the fun links,
all the stories we talked about it will be on open source security podcast.com.
-- And I guess, yeah, until next time. Thanks for listening.
-- Thanks.
Have a great week, everybody.