Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 51 with myself,
Kurt Siefried
and my partner in crime, Josh Bresser.
Hello, Kurt. And today we have a special guest with us, Dan Ed Anel
who is lead cybersecurity engineer from Miter.
Can you say hi, Dan
Dan.
Fantastic.
Of
course, silly
joke.
Funny, funny. Yeah.
Yeah. Thanks for having me on.
No, no, we, we're excited.
So, actually,
the topic and the Reason Dance here is Dan is the guy
who's kind of in charge of CV E common vulnerabilities and exposures project
at, at Miter.
And so we thought Kurt and I talk about CV, all the time, but why,
why should we talk about CV E when we can
get someone who's literally the expert on CV E?
Uh I wouldn't quite call myself the expert.
Um
And, and I, and I'm definitely not in charge.
I'm, I'm one of the, I wear many hats in the, in the project.
Um My uh
I have three roles actually.
So one of the roles I do is about a year
ago I took over working on communications for CD E.
So that's just the general outreach and writing and,
you know, publishing sort of thing.
Another hat I wear is the operations lead. So we have a small team of tech techs who do
um
all the
technical content production type stuff
and I, I oversee them
and then I'm also the CN A coordinator. The CNAs are the
CV E numbering authorities.
So those are institutions or entities that can assign CV E ID themselves
without having to ask me
for CV ID.
Every time they want to actually do something and
we'll talk a little bit more about that.
I guess my first question would be to back this up a little bit.
What exactly is the Miter Corporation? And why do they, why do they do CV?
So the Mir Corporation has been around for many, many years.
They started out and continue to be a, a not for profit organization
that operates a number of federally funded research
and development centers for the US government.
So those are FFRD CS.
So we aren't an FFR DC. We operate FFRD CS. Very subtle difference there.
And the idea is that Mir
has
a
large number of technical expertise in many different areas.
Uh We, we specialize in systems engineering,
meaning that we take
uh
all these skills and all this experience in building large complicated systems
and help the federal government and state government, local governments and
more and more our international partners build these very complicated,
either technical creations or
organizational creations. So for example, if you have ever used GPS,
GPS was created at me,
if you've ever seen in a war movie, one of the a
wax planes flying by with the big radar dome on top of the radar, you know,
disk on top that was, that was developed at MTR.
So we don't actually make stuff, but we help,
make the projects happen and we help our sponsors in the government and their uh,
the people who work with them
do things better. We are for the public good.
That is our, you know, one of our, our, our, our driving forces. So,
you know, we, we are doing all that work in a
not for profit setting because
unlike other contractors who
for better or worse are in it for the money,
we're not really in it for the money, we are in it because we believe in the mission.
So I can literally blame you for my phone map not working in London.
Sure.
Yeah.
Or you could blame the eu because, you know,
that's, it's, they were probably, I
blame the, the narrow roads,
tall buildings and the fact that it looks like they gave
a child a crayon to draw the map of that city.
So
well, it's
that they let the cows do it
-- anyway.
-- Anyway. All right, cool.
That, that is a fantastic explanation of my, in fact, I've been working with Miter
for a long time and
I didn't know most of those things. So, so awesome. Thank you.
So, now that we know what miter is, I think the natural question next is,
so what's CV E?
Right?
So back in uh back, back in the, in the heyday of, of early internet, back in 1999
the world was, was a little different than it is today in that
there wasn't a common way to identify vulnerabilities between different tools.
This was sort of the root case that caused all this.
So one of our, one of the people working with the Steve Christie,
who is the one who came up with
the CD idea,
he was tasked with
looking at the different scanning tools that Meer
was using for just looking at their own internal systems.
And he noticed that when he looked at one tool,
it gave a list of vulnerabilities that were
discovered and he looked at another tool,
it gave a different list of vulnerabilities,
but he had no way of knowing if they were the same vulnerabilities or not.
So
he started asking the question, why is this, why,
why should I have to do all this leg work to
figure out if this vulnerability is the same as this vulnerability?
Do I have 20 vulnerabilities or only 10 or 15?
So, he
developed this idea with some other people at Miter
and
convinced Homeland Security. It was a good idea.
I guess Homeland Security is the primary sponsor behind this project.
So it started out as a minor project,
sort of, we,
we do some internal projects just to kick start some things.
But then when we found the sponsor in
Homeland Security or Homeland Security didn't exist,
then I forget who it was before Homeland Security.
Strictly speaking,
we uh
we,
you know, that was the creation of the project.
And since then, it has had the mission of uniquely identifying vulnerabilities.
And once they are uniquely identified, giving them a name
and
using that name as a pivot point around which
tools and other conversations, other research can happen.
So that, you know that when you're talking about a particular vulnerability
that, you know, you know,
that that vulnerability is what is
different and unique from other vulnerabilities.
OK. So why don't, why don't you explain the name
a little bit because I know actually
it sounds like this should be boring and straightforward,
but the CV E names have actually have
a bit of a fascinating story behind them and, and how
that's where we are today.
So you mean the actual CV?
But what does it look like for someone who maybe doesn't know anything about CV?
E like what does it look like?
And let's explain what they used to look like versus what they look like today,
right? So when it started the, the,
again, the internet was a very different place. Um And the the
understanding of how far this could go was a little different.
So
the original CV ID was
CV E hyphen the year hyphen a four digit number.
Um,
you
should,
they were can
as well, not just. Ok.
Yeah.
So this is prehistory. So
originally the way that something was given a CV ID number was that it was,
it was made a candidate
and there was a board that oversaw
the, uh the assignment. So
as opposed to having like an operations group looking at these things,
doing the research and then spitting out the results,
there was a board of, of people who had some idea of what vulnerabilities are,
how they worked.
And that board would vote on whether or not a candidate would become a CV ID.
So
uh the process I believe was something would get nominated to be a candidate,
it would get submitted,
it would get it be assigned a candidate number, AC A N number.
And then they would do what we call counting decisions,
which is, is it a vulnerability per the CV definition of vulnerability?
And
how many vulnerabilities is it actually
uh is it one, is it five, is it two depending on the situation
of the, you know, depending on the details of the bug that they're looking at
and then the board would, would vote
and uh when they voted for something to be given
us to be, to be given the, the full CD status,
it would become
the CV E version of that number. Instead of the can version of that number.
The hilarious part of that is you think about the number of I DS we
have today and if we had to have people actually voting on all of them,
it's,
it's just comical at best. Right.
But again, I mean, we were talking about what,
a couple of 1000 maybe back in the day and now we're,
we're in excess of 10,000 per year.
Yeah. And this problem actually, I mean, it's, it's the,
the
ridiculousness of it extends not only to thinking that a board of people could do it,
but that even a small team could do it for all
the possible vulnerabilities that are out there in the world.
And
you know, this has been a problem with CV E since uh since then,
the internet has grown, the number of vulnerabilities.
Well, just the amount of software,
the number of lines of code has increased exponentially, right?
The number of vulnerabilities therefore has increased
exponentially if not at a higher rate.
Um
Funny how code works. Um The funding and the staffing for CD has been flat
the whole time,
maybe a little bit of an increase. But in general
CV E today is a team of less than 10 total FTE for all the different parts of CV E,
the number of people doing content
is less than five.
So that's for all vulnerabilities that are out there in the
world in every domain that everybody wants everything from an IO
device to a skateboard, to a toilet seat, to their computer operating system.
Well, and I think that brings up a good point because, you know,
when I first started dealing with CV, it was back in about, I think 2001, 2002,
you know,
and you guys covered kind of all the major guys like Microsoft HP Cisco whatever.
And that was fine back then.
But yeah, now literally everybody and everything is a software developer, right?
I can't think of a single device that costs more than 50 bucks
that doesn't have software in it to some degree. Now, you know, even
a
I think it was Miko, I'm gonna butcher his last name. The guy from
uh oh
shoot Mio,
what's his name?
Yeah,
he was up
in
the show.
Yes, he talked,
he gave a talk attended in the Netherlands a
few weeks ago and he pointed out that IKEA,
right? The the the people who make your cheap furniture, right?
They have a smart light bulb
that based on what he's seen is actually one of the best
designed smart light bulbs out there.
IKEA,
the guys who make, you know,
flat pack furniture and really yummy meatballs and cinnamon rolls.
They actually have great coders working on their systems.
Like apparently the smart light bulb is up update.
It's pretty opaque to the network, you know, they, it's hard to hack
and that's that's IKEA.
Um,
and then you have car manufacturers, you have health care devices. You've got
aerospace stuff. Right.
You've got fly by wire airplanes that are completely networked now.
Um,
and it's just ridiculous. Uh, the, the, the, the, the
not ridiculous, it's actually wonderful.
Also frightening because there's so much
code out there and so many vulnerabilities
and we need to manage those somehow.
Well, and I think Schneer
said it best when he said it's, you know, these aren't just computers anymore.
This is a
or rather these aren't cars or fridges anymore. It's a computer
that makes your food cold or it's a computer that moves a two ton box of metal around,
you know, at upwards of 60 miles an hour typically.
Um So yeah, we,
we've crossed that threshold of like these
vulnerabilities can now very easily kill people,
right?
And I think what's important is that, you know, again,
it's not just about naming the vulnerabilities, it's about managing
the disclosure and the hopefully fixing of these vulnerabilities. CV.
E is just a small part of the bigger vulnerability management space.
And, you know, we recognize that we're not, we're not the end game.
Some people consider getting a CV ID sort of their goal and that's it.
But really the CV idea is just the start once you've
identified the thing that's when you can actually start fixing it
and managing how that gets disclosed, who knows about it when they know about it,
how it fits into scanning systems
or other risk management processes,
how a company will work with other companies when they
have shared code bases that share the same vulnerabilities.
Um How you can update these things, you know,
the actual processes for firmware updates or software updates or
you know,
whatever all these different pieces come out of
just the fact that there's a vulnerability.
But until it's named,
you can't easily collaborate and coordinate outside of your own,
your own infrastructure.
And that's where CV fits in.
So we try to, we try to keep ourselves humble.
Um You know,
we're trying to position ourselves as just a small piece of infrastructure.
But just like if the plumbing went away,
life would become very difficult.
If CV E wasn't here, life would also be difficult or something like CV E
so well.
And I think that that coordinations aspect you mentioned is a
good thing to bring up because I think a lot of people
are blissfully unaware of what actual software is in their devices. And I mean,
um I know we discussed this a few shows ago, well, many shows ago,
but somebody actually went
and apparently figured out got a list of all the
open source software that was included in uh Mercedes cars.
Now,
Josh, you were talking about this, I think,
and it was over 100 pieces.
I remember this. It was, I think it was a proper security research organization
and,
and it was a ton of stuff but it was
also some incredibly old libraries at the same time,
which is, I mean,
it's totally unsurprising because let's face it any time you've got developers,
they basically are going to go to github
or somewhere they're going to pull in what they need
and they're never going to think about it again.
I mean, that's just the reality of how it works.
Yeah.
Well, especially something with the lead time that, you know, of building a car.
You know,
I can't even imagine what the software is like on some of these airplanes where,
you know, we're talking about 1020 year lead times to build these things.
Yes.
And now, actually,
I do have some knowledge about that because I know the FAA
has very strict rules about what they will allow on an airplane.
And I believe to date
there is no general purpose software actually flying the plane.
It's very specific and very, very well tested. And in fact,
they, they, you have to justify every line of code
in these things.
But of course, there are people trying to soften those rules, which I,
I imagine it will eventually happen.
And so then, yes, someday, uh, Linux
will fly your airplane. So,
Linux
and right now,
Linux or some other operating system is probably powering your MRI or your,
you know,
so, you know, it's,
these, uh, these issues,
this vulnerability management problem is becoming literally life and death.
Uh,
well, look at all the pacemakers and in fact,
this is what Steve Christie is doing now, isn't he?
Is? He's working on the meds
stuff and,
and talking to him and just paying attention to what's going on.
It's like,
I hope I never need anything implanted into my body
ever because I don't want that crap in me.
You hear about the pacemakers and the insulin pumps and it's just,
it's madness.
Yeah, that, that whole community is, is some of them are aware of it.
Some of them are blissfully unaware of it.
Um The ones that are aware of it are trying real hard to bring
the standard up.
But in general it seems like and I talked to Steve, he's probably said this, you know,
they,
the whole meds
environment is probably 15 years behind where the internet is today where the,
where the it environment is
and
considering the difference between not getting your
email and not getting your insulin.
You kind of wish it was the other way around.
Yes, I will agree with that.
Ok. So anyway, let's move on to happier topics.
So we've kind of talked about CV E what it is.
We understand why it's useful. I suspect.
So I guess the question now is, let's say I'm a guy
with a project on github
and someone says, I think I found a security issue in your thing. What, what do I do?
Now,
right, let's say I want a CV E ID. What now?
Alright. So
getting a CV ID is much easier than it used to be.
Um and it's very so it's the the
the easiest method
is you go to our website, we have a web form that was put up last year
CV E form.miter.org.
And of course, put a link to that in the show notes
and you fill out the information that's requested on the form.
And if what you've sent us is enough information that makes it clear that this
is a unique vulnerability or looks like it's going to be a unique vulnerability.
We send you the CV ID right back
now that CV I at that point, depending on the information you give,
you've given us may or may not show up in our database.
So getting the CV
is one part of it,
having it published in the database is a second part of it.
So
what you need to give us in order to get
a CV ID comes down to some very basic information,
but it's important information because again,
we need enough information to know that this
is a unique vulnerability and not just us,
anyone who is consuming the CV database.
The CV list has to know that they are looking at something new
and they have to understand what the implications are of that new vulnerability.
So
we need to know
the product
seems straightforward, but we sometimes don't get that.
Let's clarify this one though because
you say product, but doesn't necessarily mean you're a company selling something.
You can literally have a project on github
and that could be the product in this instance. Right.
Absolutely. Yes. Products a bad term because of that,
um,
where the product is the term we use. But yes, it's whatever
software that you're dealing with, whether it be a library
or a piece of hardware or you know,
an operating system or some component of an operating system, you know,
it's up to the person writing this up to be as specific
as they need to be as far as what exactly it is that
has the vulnerability in it,
the more specific, the better obviously,
along with that is versioning,
we need to know if it's affecting a particular version,
everything before or up to or after a particular version, right?
That versioning information is important because CV acts as a snapshot
in that we're not continuously updating this information.
If somebody comes to us and says this needs an update,
we will update the information in the list.
But if somebody is looking at a CV entry from five years ago and it says
all versions of this software, well,
does that include all versions up to the point when it was published or all
that have come out since then
you wouldn't know.
So you need to give some kind of,
you know, again, the more specific, the better it needs to indicate where,
you know, where on the timeline of that, of that software's life cycle.
You are actually saying everything is affected as of this time in this way.
Um So product inversion
and then
a general understanding of what the problem is. Now,
we usually, when we publish CV entries, if you look at CV entries, you, they,
they usually are of the form flaw in product version of software
um
creates
an impact
when
a certain attack happens.
And that's the form we like, that's the cognitive information we need, we need,
we like to see again what the flaw is in general.
Uh
Let's
OK. Great, great. So buffer
overflow cross
scripting. There's, there's
CWE, right. AC we
is the type of law which is a common weakness enumeration, right?
We do, we do well, you know, we,
we're that close relationship with the government and
the military. Uh the
um
Yeah, and CWE actually is a great shortcut for that if you,
if you can nail CV E or CWE to it,
that again, that gives us a lot of information that we need right there.
Um We also need
a reference CV I DS can only be published in our list.
If there is a public reference for them,
we will not publish something in our list unless there
is a reference A URL that we can include,
that says the information that is here in
this CV entry
is also out here at this public reference.
What can that public reference look like? It could be a
advisory, security advisory.
It could be
a
patch note, it could be a,
um,
a code update
uh
as long as it's public and it includes
at least if not more, hopefully the information that you've given to us,
that's, that's good enough for a reference.
So C DS, therefore, I'm not used for things like,
uh let's say you've internally, let's say you're a company
and you are developing your software and you find a bug
and that bug never goes public.
That shouldn't have a CV idea. I know Kurt will have a discussion about this,
but
this is a matter of debate in the board right now, but, but this is how this is,
this is what we're saying right now.
Um
-- So
-- one thing to keep in mind for our listeners is like
CV E has a bunch of rules and a bunch of processes
and these have changed drastically over the years and they continue to evolve. So,
you know, because part of, you know what the reality is,
the software environment has also continued to evolve and change quite a bit.
You know, I,
I would not have guessed that I would have software on my light bulbs 20 years ago.
Right? I would have thought you were crazy.
Um
And, well, I still do, but, you know,
you would be wrong
all the while through all that evolution,
we also need to create some sense of order and consistency
in what's in the database. So
the data, the CB list is going to change over time, like the,
the, the how it looks, what information has in it that will inevitably change,
but
it can't change so dramatically that it will
cause the consumers of the CBD list problems.
And that's, that's the balance that the CD E team is constantly trying to,
to keep is we want to be responsive to what
people need and to the evolving nature of vulnerability management.
But
people are expecting it to look a certain way to
sound a certain way to taste a certain way,
right?
It's the new Coke problem, right?
If we change things too quickly and in a really bad way, people will reject it
and you know, we don't want that we want it to remain useful,
but then you can bring back the old one and be the hero.
See, I, that was
a
or,
or, or, you know, we, we did it,
we did it so that we could find a cheaper way
to do it because there's that whole corn syrup conspiracy.
But
anyway,
but uh
yeah, so um so it's tough.
It's, it's a, it's a difficult problem because we do have so many stakeholders,
you know, we, we, we look at
if you consider all the stakeholders
that are involved in this project, you've got
our government sponsors, the people actually paying for it.
You've got
um
the software vendors who are
uh
have vulnerabilities that they're trying to manage the
software vendors who are using our information to
um
to load their scanners or their, you know, other databases with information.
You've got individuals who are looking to
use CV E or, or derivative of CV E to understand their risk.
Um You've got uh researchers who are
trying to find vulnerabilities and everything and,
you know, trying to,
you know, some of them are maybe doing it to try to make a name for themselves.
Some of them are doing it because it's the
right thing to do and that's what interests them.
Um
You've got the press who again, you know, because CD acts as a pivot point,
the press needs to know that they are all talking about the same thing too
when they are having these public discussions about, you know, oh,
there's a flaw in Xy and Z.
Um
So we've got all these different people,
all these different entities that need stuff out of CV.
And that's a lot to joke,
but we're trying.
Um
So
I, I, and then one other thing before I lose, lose the thread,
what you need to submit CD ES.
So I said the product, the version, the type of vulnerability
of reference and then
a description.
So this is, this is the biggest change that's happened in the last year
up until this past year,
all the descriptions you saw in the CV E list were written by the content team at CV E.
Uh
There is an analyst who would sit down and write it up
and then submit that into our C MS.
So every single
vulnerability that needed to be published had to be handcrafted.
And obviously, that does not scale.
And that was one of the big reasons why CV was falling behind on requests.
We'd have lots of people sending requests in
and they wouldn't hear anything back because we had this immense backlog
and that was just bad and
probably, you know, bad planning.
You
guys,
you guys have pretty much cleared out the backlog now and you, you know, CV,
assignments are happening pretty quick.
Well,
let me rephrase that well formed CV E assignments are happening pretty quickly
because I've run into this problem with the DWF
as well where I've had people request CV S
with very little or mangled information and then they get very upset with
me when I don't give them a CV right away because I'm like,
I don't understand this. You need to explain it better,
right? And that's it. They have to explain it. Now.
There we are, we are asking people when they submit CV ID requests as you are
with the DWF to give you to include the description, description writing is,
is surprisingly hard
um for a number of reasons, one,
not every like right now CV E is exclusively in English
that's going to change. By the way, we're heading toward a direction where
we can handle unicode.
We can't right now.
Um But in general, you know, analysts in the CBE team only speak English,
only read and write English.
So they, we haven't been,
had to have the capability to support any language other than English
as we allow people to write their own descriptions
as long as they are following the guidelines that we've set.
If you are a Spanish software company
and you want to
publish a CV ID for your,
you know, software that's only used in Spain
and it's only in Spanish,
you can do that. Now,
um the CV entry might show up in our directory as in Spanish,
but then
you know your public, the people who actually need to see it,
they will be able to understand it
because it's, that's who your, who your customers are.
Um where we've, we've been working with Japanese,
the
Japanese government through JP CERT CC for a number of years.
And they are starting to bring in more Japanese companies for the same reason to,
to give them more access to CV E
and they are going to be
publishing in Japanese once our database is ready for it.
Um
So that Japanese only software
can be covered by CV and the public in Japan can utilize
the information that we are publishing without having to translate it.
So um that description writing,
it's putting a little more of the burden on those who are submitting information,
but the benefit is more information can get in there from
a more diverse set of people and it can scale better.
Well, I think it's also part of the maturing, you know,
aspect of the information security ecosystem, right?
Like if you look back 20 years ago,
the number of people that had the skills to research and request A CV
was maybe a couple 100 now, you know, it's well into the thousands, right?
There's tons of people doing good research and requesting CV S that are like,
I, I've actually had some CV requests that are like so well formed, I almost cried
like they were just amazing,
you know,
um I just,
I'm recently dealing with an issue where a security vendor
found something and like the security advisory they wrote up
was like eight pages long. It was super detailed.
They had, you know, like it literally you read this advisory and it's like, oh,
I completely understand this issue now,
you know.
Um So that's one thing I'm finding is I think it's
ok for us to start raising the bar now because,
you know, everybody's getting better at this
and you know, as more countries develop different legal,
you know, reasons to do vulnerability management, right?
What they will need to include in advisories,
what they'll need to include in things like CV, that's going to be different
all over the place. So one size will not fit all,
you know,
the EU will have certain standards or individual countries
in the EU will have their own standards.
The US is developing their standards, but it's probably going to be more on a
uh a domain level like health care will
have standards and automotive will have standards,
but there won't be an omnibus standard for everybody.
Um
You know, and so we need to be flexible, we need to allow for,
for that and there needs to be a common bar below which we don't fall.
But
from there, we should be able to accommodate
anybody who needs to use this kind of resource without
in a way that they don't have to rebuild it. You know, we're not saying we're the best
out there.
Um
But we're saying we have this infrastructure, let's use it
and let's make it better.
So let's say, for the sake of argument, our listeners are now really gung ho on CV.
They want to get their CV S
so much so that they may want to become what's called a CV numbering authority.
-- How would they go about that?
-- Right. So the CN A program,
so CNAs are
entities, as I said before, they're entities that can assign their own cvs.
Why would they be doing this? Well,
if you're,
let's say you're a company and you have a vulnerability management
process that you follow at some point in that process,
you'll want to assign a CV ID to vulnerabilities that you found
in the past. You've had to go to Mir,
ask for the CV ID.
Um, let's assume that we're, we're doing it in a timely manner.
You'd get the CV ID back from us and then you'd be able to move forward from there.
Wouldn't it be easier if you just had a block of CD I DS
just, you know, 1015, 20 of them,
depending on how many vulnerabilities you think you'll have.
And you could just take one off the stack and put it in there.
You can put that all into a nice automated system.
It would all just be, you know, work magically.
That's the idea is that we are trusting these people
to
assign CV S per the rules that we have called the CN A rules.
And in those CN A rules are the counting rules that I mentioned earlier.
And as long as they're following those rules, we give them a block of CV IDS,
they assign them
and they describe them and then when they're ready to go public,
they just have to send us the information that we need
in the format that we need
and it gets published,
we should speak briefly about the counting rules because I think
that's probably the most complicated aspect of all of this.
And without question, the most confusing for a new person.
Yes,
So what is the vulnerability? Josh, what's a vulnerability?
It's whatever I say it is Dan. And I will take no arguments against that.
Kurt. Kurt. Kurt,
what's the vulnerability?
Whatever Josh says? Right. Kurt.
Well, so for the purposes of what is a CV E vulnerability, I've typically gone with,
um
the,
the sort of the lowest common denominator is that it
needs to be something that has a negative impact and
is trigger
or controllable by an attacker.
So, for example, we can't just, you know,
if you have some random race condition that just
happens and the server crashes once in a while,
you know, and there's no way for an attacker to influence that behavior.
That's, that's not really a security flaw, it's just a regular old, you know,
your software is terrible flaw.
Um So that,
that is generally what I've gone with as
my framework for defining what is a vulnerability.
So
you two are, are slightly divergent in your definition
of vulnerability.
The question is who is right? If Josh is the one editing the podcast, he's right.
Um
So,
but um yeah,
but this is the problem.
You go to, you go to 10 engineers, you're going to get 12 answers as far as what?
So how do you decide what a vulnerability is? Well,
if you say that, well,
anything that anyone says is a vulnerability is a vulnerability,
you're going to have arguments, especially
when you're dealing with things like PC I
compliance or just any audited compliance exercise where
the auditor says, well,
this says you have 50 vulnerabilities and you look at it and go well,
that's actually only one vulnerability and we took care of it like yes,
but you have 50
right?
So people, if you, if you're,
if the understanding of what the vulnerability is, is,
is not clear or what the implication of a vulnerability,
not all vulnerabilities are equal.
Um You have these arguments,
you have these discussions and this problem has been
discussed in academia for years continues to be discussed.
There are many definitions for vulnerability
CV ES definition for vulnerability is
the counting rules.
So
inside our CD E rules document or CN A rules document, there is the appendix C again,
we can link to the rules document and appendix C.
We have all of the CV, the counting rules for for assigning a CV ID.
The first section is what we call abstraction
abstraction. Is, is it a vulnerability
in the past? This is more complicated today. It's a little
simpler. There's really three tests.
The first test is if the developer of
the software says it's a security vulnerability,
it's a vulnerability.
So that that one's easy, right?
If Microsoft says this is a security vulnerability, then it is
and we're just, and that's just the positive case, right? If somebody says it, if a
developer of the particular bit of code says it's security vulnerability,
then it is,
let's say that they don't say it's a vulnerability or there's no, no answer there.
So then the next question is, does it show that there is a uh uh a
security
boundary that is crossed because of this
bug?
Right?
There's an unintended consequence from this bug that
showed that a security boundary has been,
has been breached.
That one's a little trickier, right? Because then it's a matter of, well,
what does that mean? What does it mean to have a security boundary um broken?
Sometimes it can be very straightforward, sometimes not,
we just recently had this come up in a private discussion where,
you know, this one set of set U ID utilities can be used to escalate to root and it's,
you know, it's a very fine line with set U ID utilities
is,
you know,
is doing stuff as root sort of a security breach
or not when we're talking about set U ID apps,
right?
And
yeah, it, it got a little bit hair splitting.
But um so yeah,
it can definitely get a bit complicated there as to what is a security boundary,
but it, it, you know,
you can at least sort of think of it in those
terms and it helps whittle it down a little bit.
So, you know, that abstraction thing, I mean,
that's usually that's the biggest argument, right?
Because you have a vendor who says something isn't a vulnerability and you have, or,
and a researcher who says that it is,
it's hard to know who's right. Um
So
I'm, I'm, I'm looking at the actual rules here, so I want to get this right.
So the first question,
it's so obvious, right?
It's so
obvious.
-- So it's
-- actually
quite simple.
It is and it isn't right. It's simple. Once you accept that this is how you do it
again, we're not saying this is the best. We're not saying this is the only,
but we're saying this is the one we use consistently.
And that is that's important having that consistency
because so for example, there are other vulnerability databases out there.
And if you look at the number of vulnerabilities that they have identified,
it's typically bigger than CBES,
the number of them is bigger. So why?
Well, one is maybe they scaled better and they can process these more quickly. OK.
Fair.
Uh Another argument might be that they have looser guidelines
as far as what one vulnerability is versus five vulnerabilities.
And a good example there is we had a customer report like,
you know, they,
they claim to have found dozens of
cross site scripting vulnerabilities in a product.
And it was just a single function, right?
That had multiple, you know, that processed multiple text fields.
And so in the cases of CV E,
that would be a single vulnerability, right?
Because there's that single underlying root cause even though there's, you know,
multiple avenues of exploitation like essentially a whole
pile of text fields in the web interface.
There's just that one underlying, you know,
um
function that just needed a, you know, an escape for HTML when it output
data, right?
And so that's a good example of where the actual person requesting it
was effectively trying to get one CV E per like text field,
right? Because they wanted a big pile of CV S
um you know, because they're an auditor, right?
So they wanted a big pile of CV S to show their clients,
right?
And, and so, you know that again, it's, it's, it's a, it's a tight walk,
a tight rope that we're walking, trying to, trying to balance these things between,
you know, completeness, but also just definition,
we're going with this definition and it, it, it's not the best definition,
it still leads to some ambiguity,
but it, at least we feel is good enough and it's good enough to,
to wrap the rest of the program off of it.
And again, this has evolved since the beginning.
This is much simpler than it used to be.
Um
So you've got the counting rules which include things like, is it a vulnerability?
Is it independently fixable? Um Which is another thing if, if,
like you were saying,
you know, there might be a situation where it manifests a number of times,
but you fix it in one place in the code and it's fixed everywhere.
That is a single vulnerability,
um
if it's a part of a shared library or protocol, that's a factor.
Um We need to, you know, understand how it
uh if
it should be a separate vulnerability or if it's
in a vulnerability that's some in part in,
in like that shared library.
So if there's already a vulnerability for the shared library,
should you sign a va separate CB ID for
software that uses that shared library?
So a great example there Dan is heartbleed,
which almost everyone knows about right?
Heartbleed was basically one CV E ID.
That's right. Although I think heartbleed actually got two accidentally
due to a due to a communication and coordinate issue. But
yeah, but that would be
that,
that right? It makes sense that it's one CV ID because it is one
vulnerability, it manifests in
hundreds of thousands of software, however many software packages we're using it,
right?
But using us that,
you know, had that vulnerability in it.
So um
yeah,
so that's, yeah, that's an excellent example.
And I, I think that that, I mean,
because that's one thing I run into a lot with a lot
of people is CV E stands for common vulnerabilities and exposures database.
And so it primarily tracks vulnerabilities and exposures,
but people forget that it also tracks the fixes, right?
When a vendor says here we release this update that fixes this CV E,
you know, we're, we're tracking the fix.
And so one thing to keep in mind too is that CV is not just, you know, for the,
the vulnerability portion of the vulnerability,
but also for the fixed portion of the vulnerability.
And so, yeah, I mean, that's, that's something I've taken into account, you know,
where we've had.
Um
I remember there was one really weird case where it was actually
two distinct like CWE vulnerabilities fixed with like one line of code.
And so then it becomes like, well, is that like one or two vulnerabilities?
It's got one fixed, like, you know what's going on here, right?
Um Actually we just had that at Alastair
where we had a security issue that was basically one fundamental flaw in the code.
It was literally one line of code,
but there were two very different.
In fact, we were, we were tracking them as two separate issues and then we realized,
holy cow, this is,
this is the same thing even though they looked incredibly different
when you were actually trying to exploit it.
And funny enough, they were independently identified as well,
which made it and at the same time, totally different things.
Same fix, right? So see the ID for them both.
That's a good, actually, that's a tangential topic.
I,
I think I've talked with you Dan about is what's the upper
bound for how many CV S A piece of software can have?
And I was working on the hope and assumption that it would be at most.
Hopefully, one CV per line of code.
And apparently that assumption is wrong.
Well,
so,
right. So um
so, I mean, I guess the question is there, I mean, does that fall into the whole split,
merge decision?
Right.
Um
So CV E has, if you look in our, in our list, we list,
there might be some entries that have that say they have been split or merged.
So a split is where you have a single CV
ID that actually turns out to be multiple vulnerabilities.
And so it
gets split,
you have
multiple vulnerabilities that are
that we merge together into one
uh for, for some reason. Uh
And then you have the duplicate,
the idea of there being two CV ideas that are identical,
they are exactly the same thing and then, you know,
one wins over the other and there's a whole logic tree for who wins in that case.
So, you know, in this elastic problem was example,
it could be a duplicate or it could be just a merge, right? Two different
22, the same vulnerability that manifested in two very different ways
and had two very different. Um
uh Was it, was it two different
uh
uh impacts
uh no,
the impact it sort of it was it involved um user permissions and one involved doing
an operation to kind of become a user with higher privileges and the other was just
an operation on data.
But fundamentally, it was a logic error in the way we decide
what kind of permissions a user has.
So it was a single
route,
but they looked very different
in terms of what was happening and, and what the bad thing was that was going on.
Yeah, see II I now
I'm sure
this, this would be a great thing to debate, right?
So the question is, what is the debate matter?
I did email you and you told me one is fine. So
don't be getting me in trouble here. No, no, no, no.
Well, what I mean by debate is that you could sit down, I mean,
that answer came after debate after we discussed it internally and sort of look
at, figure it out, right?
So the question is really for you and elastic is so the next time this happens,
will you be consistent?
Yes. Oh, that, absolutely. And that,
you know, I,
I've been doing CV ES for longer than I can remember and consistency is key, right?
Even if you're wrong, as long as you're consistently wrong, you're at least that,
that's better than being random.
Right. That's right. And that, that is exactly right.
So these, these counting rules,
again, there's still a lot of weight room in these things.
And what, what we,
what we especially like about having CN A is that they take
these rules and hopefully they're going
to build them into their internal processes
and if a company is worth its salt, it's going to be doing things consistently,
you know, mature organization,
they have processes and procedures that they follow
because that's even if they are wrong,
it's how they do their, their job. Right.
And so you get an output that's, that's predictable
and that's what we want. These are the starting point. CNAs
and we'll go back to them when we have to think through a problem where there,
there might be an inconsistency.
But if you're consistently inconsistent
with a certain set of rules, you know, for example,
there are some companies who will only assign CV I
DS to things that they consider to be critical.
OK.
So strictly speaking in the CD rules, that's not quite right.
It should,
they should be assigning to any vulnerability and
it shouldn't matter on the criticality of it.
That is not a factor in counting criticality is not a factor
C CBS S score is not a factor.
It is strictly the, the, the facts about the vulnerability on a technical level,
not the risk that's inherent in there.
But if the company is consistent in
doing that and their customers are expecting that
it makes it harder for us to say they're wrong
because the market does drive a lot of this v
you know, again, we're just part of vulnerability management.
We want to encourage proper vulnerability management practices
and we try to do that with our rules. But at the same time,
who are we to say to Microsoft, you're doing your job wrong.
Well, that brings up a good point because we've also had some recent debate about,
you know, traditionally CV S are for issues that are public
and there are some vendors that have flat out said, you know,
if somebody reports an issue to us and we fix it, we'll assign that A CV.
But if we internally find an issue, we will not assign a CV.
You know, we'll just quietly fix it and go about our way.
Um, or another vendor that would, you know, essentially with the logic,
apparently of, well, it has an auto updater.
So you're gonna be forced to update. So we're not going to give it a CV.
Um You know, and so we're obviously the board is having some debate over, you know,
what does public mean now.
Um So these things do evolve a bit and
I,
I think one of the key pieces though is to
start educating consumers of these software and CV S,
you know, that maybe,
maybe they want to ask
their vendors to do more CV. S or, you know, or quite frankly, maybe
a lot of these orgs will probably be quite happy without CV. S, right?
Because, you know, once
I've had the experience of like,
literally you can know about a security flaw and that's great.
But the minute it gets a CV, it starts like a 30 day countdown clock, you know,
for the organization to deal with it.
And, you know, and so they, in,
I've had literal cases where people report issues and they
kind of don't want it to get a CV until,
like the very last minute because then
they don't have to deal with it till then, you know. So
that's something to keep in mind for our listeners is
that there's a lot of different organizations wrapped around CV,
both on the
producing CV. ES
uh and consuming CV S side.
And a lot of them have different, you know,
process and political motivations for kind of
wanting CV S early or wanting CV S later or not at all.
Or, you know, wanting a lot of like, I actually had one open source project argue,
they wanted more CV S for like, they,
they had like three issues and they wanted one issue split up into like four things.
And I was like,
that makes no sense at all. Right.
But they wanted a lot of CV S to show that they were fixing them quickly,
which is, and then you have companies who are like, well, if, if we have a lot of CV S,
it shows that we have vulnerabilities in our products and that's bad,
right?
And then the company next to, but then the company next to them will say rightly, no,
it means that people are finding the vulnerabilities
and that you're fixing them as opposed to if
we don't know about them somebody else is
exploiting them and you don't know about it.
There is
a,
there's a line of,
if you're above the line,
you have too many CV I DS because your software is terrible. Right?
And if you have zero, that's kind of the same problem.
It's that, that magic middle, that, that we need. Right? Some CV E I DS are good.
Too many or none are bad.
Well,
and part of the thing to remember about this too
is we don't have very good data for this.
I mean, for number one, you know, security issues tend to be, you know,
it's we don't have a good sample size because these things are self selected,
self reported.
Some companies kind of bury them quietly.
Um The other thing is we don't have really good data on, you know,
when are these issues actually reported versus
when do they actually get fixed and released
combined with severity, right?
Like if you take a week to fix a low severity flaw, like great,
like kind of that's actually pretty good versus, you know,
you take two years to fix a high severity flaw.
Well, what if that high severity flaw is very complicated and was found internally,
you know, it is very difficult to explain. That's
so that's one thing, I mean, I know Stephen Christie has given talks on this,
you know, about how your, all your security metrics,
especially if you base them on CV, are completely wrong.
That's right.
Yeah,
it, it is one indicator of a, of a bigger, uh,
sort of health measure.
Um,
I think it, actually this makes me think of cholesterol.
because I'm kind of hungry. Um, but, uh,
but no, there's, there's good cholesterol and bad cholesterol. Right.
You can't, you, you know, you hear, eat a low cholesterol diet.
Well, yes and no,
you're supposed to have a certain level of certain types of cholesterol, right.
And even a little bit of bad
cholesterol doesn't necessarily mean you're unhealthy.
It just means you have a little bit of that. Right.
When it gets too high, that's a problem. The good cholesterol gets too low.
That's a problem.
So, I think, you know, that people have come to understand that
hopefully they'll, they'll think of
vulnerability disclosure in the same way.
Well, to me, the biggest part of CV is,
you know, if an organization
like, does CV, that means that they have a pretty high, you know,
minimum competency standard.
Right. Because you basically can't do CV S without having some sort of security team
and some sort of security process.
And then even more ideally, you know, if that vendor is a CV numbering authority,
that means they're, you know, even more competent.
Um, and so, for me, you know, when I see these vendors that have zero CV.
S or don't even know what CV is, it's like, oh, dear,
you know, do you have a security team
at
all. You know, that's, I start to wonder things like that. And
so I, I think that's one thing is, you know,
people need to understand that CV is a good indication of security maturity, right?
Especially if they're being fixed. If there,
if there's a ton of CV S in a product that have never been fixed,
that's also a good indication that maybe, you know,
things aren't so good with that product,
right?
And I think a good, a good example of what you just said is that there are a number of,
of national level um
uh uh processes that have started that will include as part of it
CV assignment. So,
uh again, you know, J PC has been involved with this with us for a long time,
but Korea and Malaysia are both actively building out a
vulnerability disclosure process that is rooted in national law,
not just sort of best practice, but actually in the books
of how vulnerability should be disclosed by vendors within their country
and how that's all going to get administered.
Um The EU is working on similar things in different countries. So,
you know, there there's that understanding that this is,
this shows maturity, this shows that you're actually,
you know, doing the right thing and doing,
you know what's best for your business and for your customers.
So it's crazy man. And then to CV E is like the one ring that binds them all then
it's U PC
code.
That's
awesome. I like my analogy better.
We, yeah, and, and the CN A program, one of the, the,
the way we're hoping to scale it is, is speaking of, of
models, you know, you've got your,
your uh
uh ISBN number on books, right?
Those are given out by a central authority,
but they are not individually given out for each book that gets published.
A block is given to a publisher and the publisher takes those and publishes them.
So we're doing the same thing on the national level.
So individual vendors might have their own CV ID.
Uh The Netherlands might have a block that's given
to them and then they distribute it out.
Kurtz DWF has a block that they're given and they distribute that out.
Um
So, you know, with that,
that helps federate out the operations of this so that we scale better and again,
it's more flexible, more people can do it the way they need to do it
well.
And it's also important just so our readers don't get
or our listeners don't get the wrong idea is that,
you know, there,
there's a difference between the governance model and the operations model.
So the governance model is very much
similar to DNS because quite frankly, that works and that works well.
You know, we have these hierarchies like
JP Cert does Japan, which makes sense because I don't speak a lick of Japanese.
And I'm also asleep whenever they're working.
Um,
conversely on the operations model, you know, we have a lot of,
sort of cross communication and
in fact, currently I believe, well, we even have two individuals,
Josh Pressers being one of them and Larry Cash
being the other
who
uh, exist as CNAs
in multiple hierarchies or Josh maybe. Yeah.
Well, because technically you're an individual CN A
-- and AC N A with an elastic,
-- right? I'm AC N A with TWF, not with miter,
but yeah, elastic is also AC N A with lighter.
So,
so
the thing to remember is, you know, it's, it's, for example,
Josh exists in these sort of two hierarchies, right?
On the one hand, you exist in the elastic CN A and
also in the DWFCN A hierarchy or, you know, Larry cash
dollar who exists in the miter hierarchy and also the DWF hierarchy. So,
um
well, like most things in life, you know, we've, we've learned that we have to,
you know, where the boundaries get drawn is kind of squishy and, and messy,
right? But
like you said, there's also we, we're trying to keep that separate as we,
as we grow this thing, that's an administrative boundary and that's there because
there needs to be lines of communication and escalation
if there's a problem or if there's something,
you know, we need to communicate whatever
the operation side we're definitely pushing toward a more peer to peer model
where people are, can can submit things directly.
They don't have to necessarily go through a chain of command.
They might need to if like it's a national level, Cert,
the,
the all the people in Japan might want to go through JP Cert because
JP Cert told them to and JP Cert certainly wants that for reporting purposes.
But then, you know, that's their decision.
Another country might say, yeah, just send it all to me
directly and we don't care, you know,
so that you know that we don't,
we don't want to have this hierarchy and this structure
weigh everybody down from being able to do the assignment.
It's more the
training and documentation and best practice, you know,
learning the best practices and communicating
and knowing who you can talk to when there's a problem,
that's where the administrative structure comes in.
So it's again like all of this is very hybrid
and we're going to see how it goes.
Awesome.
Alright, I think it's it's time to bring it home, Dan,
do you have any any parting words for the audience?
So
if you are interested in participating in CV E program at any level,
whether you are a developer or researcher or a vendor,
uh national government, a spy agency, I don't care,
contact us through the web form CV E forum.mir.org http S CV E forum.mir.org
um or you can email us at CV E at miter.org
and we'll talk to you and try to figure out
how best to get you involved with the program?
Fantastic.
And of course,
we will have a link to that in the show notes which you can find
at open source security podcast.com where we also have the Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag We have links to Twitter.
I'll have a link to Dan's Twitter probably in there
so you can follow him and ask him silly questions
and we have a Facebook group.
You are welcome to join where you can harass Kurt and myself and if nothing else, Dan,
thank you so much.
This has been a fascinating conversation. Kurt, thank you as always everyone.
Thank you for listening and everybody have a fantastic rest of your day.
Stay safe, everybody.
Thank you very much for having me guest. Awesome. Thanks, man.