Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast
episode 176 with myself, Kurt Siefried
and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
-- All right.
-- So I just need to clarify for everyone listening right now
that Kurt wants to do a predictions episode because we're
at the point of recording, we're at the end of the decade
and I think prediction episodes are dumb
-- and predictions are dumb.
-- And I predicted you would say that
you,
of course, that's not a prediction.
That's because I told you they're dumb yesterday.
And
in all seriousness, unless your name is like Arthur C Clarke,
your predictions are terrible.
Oh, I'm, I'm ok with that.
So
I was recently reading one of Charles Strauss's blog postings and
talking about basically how the future is.
Like 90% of it is basically here right now. It's just going to be tweaked a little bit
and like 9% we can sort of extrapolate out, like smartphones will get smarter,
they'll get more capability faster, better, you know, like, you know,
you can extrapolate out
but, and then there's like 1% that just doesn't exist
at least.
And, and he suspects that number those ratios have changed.
You know,
so there's more that doesn't exist now that will because I think part of it is what
makes predictions so tough nowadays is the adoption
cycle for technology that is successful is short.
Maybe we'll put the chart in the show notes.
But that adoption chart of like, what is it?
Electricity, radio TV, phones, internet, smartphones, right.
And for it to get from like 0 to 10 to 20 to 80 whatever percent adoption,
you know,
-- being shorter and shorter and
-- shorter.
I believe that I don't know if I've ever seen that chart.
I suspect I have, but I,
I always think back to the fact that the iphone came out at what, 2006
and
I couldn't imagine living my life without a smartphone.
And I don't even mean in the context of communicating with people necessary.
Just the fact that everyday life when I go on a trip now
my phone
is my ticket.
It's how I get my taxi.
It's how I know where I need to be at any given point in time.
-- Like it is, it is an amazing tool
-- one first,
I just upgraded from an iphone se because I managed to cook the recharger on it,
hot air like it was mounted on my car,
the hot air, but I thought it was closed anyways
and I upgraded to an iphone. Um jeez, I don't even know. I want to say an eight maybe.
Ok. So not like top of the line, but, you know, a lot better than iphone. I see.
And I'm already noticing between that and I also got an Apple watch,
like my usage of Siri,
some of the stuff I'm doing and able to do now so much easier and new capabilities.
And
I mean, if you made me go back to an iphone se I'd hit you with, I'd hit you with a hammer.
I believe that my, my example actually would be Alexa,
which I'm still morally opposed to the surveillance society it represents.
But
I got some smart light bulbs as a Christmas gift last Christmas.
And I'm like, what do I do with these things?
And I'm, I thought all right, you know what, I'm going to get an Alexa
and I'm going to see what I think of this.
And my house is filled with smart light bulbs now
because not having to get up and turn lights on.
Has for whatever reason,
I love the fact that I just scream at a machine and it works the lights for me.
-- It's marvelous.
-- I actually have two Alexa little routine set up.
One is Alexa Good morning and one is Alexa Goodnight and the good morning, one
turns all my, uh, the lights in my room
tells me a joke and tells me the weather report and I find that that actually
helps wake me up because like, otherwise I wake up and I'm like, well,
if I don't get out of bed,
I don't know if there's no lights on and the bright lights don't hurt my eyes.
So I'm just going to stay here where it's cozy.
Yeah, I, I should do the, I should try it good morning.
So I tried to set up a good night routine
and for whatever reason,
it turns off all my lights because I actually have
some lights on my garage that turn on at night and
-- turn off in the morning.
-- You gotta build groups like the light bulb.
I have, you can set,
I did that. I have groups and it still turns the stupid garage lights off.
And I've tried like everything my guess. I don't know
if I, if I email them or call them, they're gonna tell me, oh, just like,
remove everything and start over and re add them all and I'm too lazy to do that.
So, whatever I will survive without Goodnight.
-- Well,
-- I've already had to do like one complete reset of all my light bulbs and like
them and just, uh,
-- I
-- don't
-- want to do that.
-- It's a chore.
-- So anyway, predictions, we are not predicting anything at best.
We're discussing
-- our dystopian present
-- came up with sort of four main predictions
that are extrapolations of what we have because quite frankly,
I can't really that, that creating the future
whole
cloth
anyway,
security predictions or just predictions,
predictions. Yeah,
excellent because this is a security podcast.
The first thing and this is a clear extrapolation because
I got an email from Google about it last week
is that
the usage of passwords for very high value
accounts is going to be strongly discouraged.
So what's happening with Google is you can use your
Google account for single sign on with other stuff,
right?
And you can also have apps that for example,
make use of your Google account for something like uh
like caliber
Ereader to send email.
You, you put your pass,
you put your user name and password into the app so that
the app can connect to your Google account and send an,
you know,
to your Magic Amazon or whatever account to get the document onto your Kindle,
right?
Ok.
I didn't know it could do that, but I'm not surprised to learn it.
Yeah. And so basically Google is phasing out what they call less secure access LS A.
And so essentially sometime next year,
you basically won't be able to register any new LS A integrations.
So we have a bunch of Gmail accounts, you know, that are fed by aliases. And
basically, you know, email goes to the alias goes to the
email account and then Jira connects to the Gmail account.
Like I think it's every 10 minutes or a half hour
or whatever pulls up the email generates tickets from them,
you know, the usual right?
Ticket to or email to ticket integration thing.
And of course, it uses uh you know, user name and password. Well, that will
stop working, you know,
in uh I think they said the drop dead date for all of this stuff is in 2021.
So at that point, like if you want to access your Google account, you will have to,
you know, do it properly.
Like
if you want to set up an integration with something, it will have to be o
-- off.
-- I think that's great.
-- Yeah, I agree completely.
-- That's your prediction.
So
my prediction is, I think Facebook will do this.
I think Google will do this, maybe Twitter and a couple of the other big guys.
And the second part of this and Google is doing this
already again is the sanitization of passwords in Google Chrome.
Now it automatically checks your password to make sure
it's not in the database of publicly known passwords.
That's not a prediction either.
No,
I'm predicting that more people will do this
and hopefully it becomes wide scale adoption.
OK? I mean, this is an easy one. I think I feel like we're already on this path.
This would make a big difference because like the recent ring quote
unquote doorbell hacking was just the
fact of
his own credentials,
like
publicly disclosed credentials to get into people's ring accounts.
And like on the one hand, I'm like, well, that's not really hacking. It's like,
you know, you find a box of keys on the street.
So you just start going up to doors and try all the keys,
you know?
But at the same time, yeah, I mean,
it is hacking or cracking in the sense of malicious activity.
Right.
You know,
even if you find keys on the street you shouldn't
just go randomly trying to go into people's houses.
It's still illegal.
Yeah. It's very much frowned upon in most places.
-- Right.
-- Because the, the sad reality is passwords are here to stay.
-- We, you know, we might get rid of them in 50 years.
-- Now. That's a prediction. I, I
-- don't
-- know.
I have a feeling that, you know, we're,
we're stuck with them because it's what we have.
-- It's what we know. That's just how it is.
-- Ok.
-- Ok. What else you got
-- as far as encryption goes? So,
-- IPs a clearly didn't win. Remember IPs a 20 years ago?
-- Thank goodness it lost. I hate
ips.
-- Now we're shoving wire guard into the Linux kernel. I like
-- wire guard. It's,
it's pretty nice,
but I'm predicting that application level encryption will continue to win.
So, an example of that would be DNS over http S Kurt,
we call this zero trust networking.
It's, again,
this isn't a prediction.
Well, I'm,
I'm guessing though that wire guard is going to essentially go the way of IP
where, I mean,
do you think it will ever see adoption of more than 1% in the Linux server market.
No,
no, I don't because zero trust networking is like you said,
all about kind of application level encryption where you're just
using HTTP S or TLS within the app itself.
And the operating system honestly doesn't care.
And additionally, I mean,
just common practice has shown that trying to pretend that firewall
-- is going to save you is stupid and doesn't work
-- well.
I think it's even
simpler than that.
If I do my encryption at the application level,
I can then say for sure this application has encryption and protection.
Whereas if I'm relying on the underlying os to do encryption, yeah, maybe it does,
maybe it doesn't,
-- I
-- mean,
I don't know, it probably doesn't because it's hard to set up. Right.
Exactly.
And especially in sort of cloud environments.
For example, if I'm doing a platform as a service or something,
can I even see what the underlying platform is doing?
Like, how would you validate in a platform as a service situation that it
is enabled?
Well,
it's even harder than that because a favorite example
I have is if you're running on something like
Kubernetes,
you're encrypting the traffic,
essentially one or more layers above the container itself.
So there's literally no way for the containers
to even know there's encryption on the wire.
Yeah,
-- or what it is is a compliant
-- metaphorical wire. But
so I, I predict that encryption will continue to move to the application
space and that's not to say that, you know, for example,
people at Google won't like encrypt all their backhaul links just to be extra safe.
-- I mean,
-- they, they did that.
Yeah, they did.
But I'm saying,
but nobody will rely upon that or nobody with any sense will rely upon that.
Right?
And I, I agree with this and I would again counter this is not a prediction.
I, I have a feeling I know
where all of your predictions look like. And I'm going to save it to the end
to pontificate to you about it because
-- this is, this is interesting and special. What's happening here. All
-- right.
This is completely confirmation.
All right. Next.
And I'm guessing the whole, you've heard about the whole cyber hygiene movement,
which I, I don't, does that, what does that mean?
Well, this whole idea that, you know, this, we've had this for, well,
it's been around for decades but
this idea that,
you know, people are going to do some certain baseline of activities so that
they're not so insecure that it's embarrassing when they get hacked.
What is basically how I would put it to be blunt?
Well,
I was just watching a news report about this police
force that quote unquote got hacked and it was,
you know, it was ransomware.
And I was kind of wondering like, is a non target,
like when a ransomware escapes out into the wild,
like not pia is that actually hacking
you know, because we don't call somebody,
like somebody from a foreign country who comes over here
and sneezes all over the place at the airport.
-- We don't call that like a biological attack.
-- It could be based upon intent.
Like if you injected yourself with some,
like let's say smallpox and then you start traveling the United States.
Yeah, that's a biological attack.
But I'm talking about the case where, you know, somebody makes some ransomware,
maybe targets one or two
specific organizations.
And then of course, you know, being
how secure we are with the modern world that escapes out into the wild and rampages,
you know, does, if anybody here is old enough to remember the,
I love you virus or the Melissa virus, I mean, those things went global and
well, back in the day it was days or hours now it's, you know, minutes, right.
And those things weren't meant to, you know, impact the entire world,
but the intent was nefarious from the get go.
It wasn't like this was an accident.
They knew what it was going to do. They just didn't expect it to be as big as it was.
Yeah. So I think it's intense.
I think if it's ransomware and a bad guy releases it into the world
and even if their target audience is meant to be small and it explodes.
Yeah, the, the intent was nefarious that's attacking.
So I'm guessing the best way for most organizations to deal with their cyber
hygiene is to outsource probably and to continue aggressively doing so because I,
I still see so many.
I was watching this channel and it's so weird to me. This guy does like server
level hardware review
and he's building like a single machine with like two A MD Epic CP
US with like what is it like 6400 and 28 cores each whatever?
And he's really going on and on about this, my, my one thought was like,
and how do you even measure a Google container ships full of servers,
library of Congresses of servers,
football fields. I don't know. Right.
And,
and it was just so weird to me because he was going on and on about how this a MD
Epic server you can consolidate and he shows like three
racks that are like mostly empty now because they've been consolidated
into literally a two U machine
with like two big cats
use or like a pile of NVME storage.
And if you use the cloud, your rack is empty
and somebody else actually maintains it for you.
But he was going on and on about your
choices of hypervisors and he actually went over one,
an open source one that I've never heard of called
open container visual uh something virtualization or
something like I've never heard of it.
It's like a bare metal hypervisor thing anyways,
but it just got me thinking it was so
I I get that. Some companies and industries.
For example, if you're like,
if you're on like an oil platform in the middle of the ocean,
maybe your internet isn't good enough to have, you know, access to the cloud.
But I feel like for the majority of companies like
having on premises equipment just that needs to stop.
-- Like, nobody generates their own electricity anymore.
-- No, no, they, well,
most, most places don't. Actually, there was so funny enough.
There was a factory in town
that up until last year
she had a coal, like a coal power plant on site
that and of course, we're like, guys, you got to like, quit burning F and coal.
This is ridiculous.
Right. Seriously.
And it took a while but it's gone now.
But
I think there are niche use cases that we always want on prem.
it's kind of like email is the easiest poster child.
Are you hosting your own email? And maybe you are. Do you have a good reason to do it?
And like, for example, in the case of you and I like, no,
no, we don't have good reason to do that.
And so we let someone else do it because they're quite
-- frankly more competent and I'm too lazy to do it
-- just,
and from a cost, like,
I used to run my own email and even I had it down to one or two hours a week
of managing spam and tweaking
a
week
that's
the
goal.
Uh
Yes, I agree. I agree. And again, this is not a prediction.
Alright, let's keep going. Let's do your next prediction.
So, and this one is, I think really obvious because it's been so successful. But,
and because you were mocking this, actually the other day,
I love mocking things. It's
-- that whole
-- ecosystem marketplace idea.
And so we're not going to name the company.
But basically Josh showed me this site and you're like, I thought this was, you know,
satire at first.
And I'm like, no, it looks really cool
a
company
that has like a market.
-- Let's
-- call this out.
You can become a certified Slack engineer like Slack, the online chat platform
and
we'll, we'll put a link in the show notes, but it's like Slack certified.com,
I think it is.
And I thought
it was a joke at first and I'm like, holy crap like this is the real deal,
but here's the deal.
It's really well done, right? I, I will knock them because why not? It's Slack.
But like for real, if you're gonna do certification,
like copy what these guys are up to.
-- It's really good.
-- Well, see, and that's something I've
noticed is I've, I've used some integrations with other platforms and,
and they've been terrible.
Like some of the early Gmail integration stuff was just
uh
you know, or some of the,
some of the early Google Drive integration stuff was just,
all right. Hold on. What's your prediction though?
I suspect that this is what maturity looks like for a software company.
Uh, that's probably fair.
And I think you could easily argue that slack is pretty mature.
I mean, they're basically running the world now
and,
yeah, which is
kind of scary because they have a lot of,
you know,
I know it's Attackers. If you're looking for a target, I'm just saying.
But, yeah. Yeah. No, I, I agree. I agree.
So I, and again, I mean, I, I'll be honest, I,
I thought about having some really wild predictions but I mean, you know,
I might as well be predicting like I
predict everyone will own a purple hippopotamus.
Uh They might so, ok, so here's
these all were exactly what I expected where you are just pointing out
obvious
minor changes to the things that are already happening now.
And what you did was you took the coward's way out
of predicting the future because you didn't really predict the future.
You're just talking about things you know about and most people don't. Ok.
So
here's my view on all of this and why I think
trying to predict the future is never going to work.
And obviously using the word never is always a famous last word.
We have reached a point in security
where
the thing the changes we're seeing are incremental because we are,
I hesitate to call us a maturing industry necessarily,
but we are an industry that has bumped up against the ceiling of innovation,
-- I think maybe ossified.
-- Yeah,
maybe, I don't know,
ossified to turn into bone or bony tissue.
Second definition to cease developing the stagnant or rigid.
-- I would say
-- I've never heard the second definition of it.
And that's where
ossified, I think applies here.
Maybe, I mean, but so either, either description you want to call it right?
But the point is
we've reached a place
where
we aren't going to see massive innovation
with the technology we have, we've basically reached, we will see
small incremental change. Now
the industry needs
new innovation. We need a disruptive technology to appear.
-- I think we
-- need multiple disruptive technology,
probably more than one. I agree.
But the point is we, we definitely need disruption at this point. And
the problem is it is virtually impossible to predict disruption.
It's just the nature of disruption because if it, if it was predictable,
you wouldn't call it disruption.
Well, I mean, if you,
you basically would have to make enough
predictions to cover everything and be like,
-- see I said it would happen,
-- which is equally ridiculous.
And I think given what we have the idea
because instead of expecting massive change,
we have to kind of accept the reality we have,
which I think a lot of people still haven't done
because you still get into arguments with people saying,
oh, we'll just train everyone to not move
and it's like no you won't because if you could, we would have done that a decade ago.
So we're going to see this incremental change and things are going to,
I won't say get better
because the bad guys also have incremental change. And
in some cases like ransomware was their disruption.
And then what was our solution to ransomware?
Like thoughts and prayers pretty much.
And that's my favorite from that,
that article with the police department that got ransomware is like,
then we talked to our T people and they advised us to pay the ransom
and,
-- yeah. Right. Anyway,
-- I think, and I think it's actually worse than that.
We need innovation at the technological level. I think we need innovation at
not just the legal level but at the sort of societal expectations level
because quite frankly, as long as people are ok with
all this stuff getting hacked and
whatever,
you know, as long as it's an external cost for most companies, why
would I spend money on fixing it?
Right. Absolutely.
And this is where things like GDPR are meant to rein
some of the costs back into the organizations holding your data.
I mean, we'll see if it really matters.
There's actually a good website showing GDPR fines. But the reality of it is
last I checked, there's still huge numbers of data breaches and,
you know, the, I mean, the, the,
the cookie click through on every website now just makes
me weak because I suspect that actually probably has a,
a carbon footprint equivalent to some small country,
forcing people to look at that and click it and like, waste a second of their day.
Well, and I think that the place where GDPR might have fallen short is again,
you know, in the legal framework there is the concept of intent
and as long as you're not willfully malicious,
your GDPR fine isn't going to be that crazy and let's face it.
Nobody's willfully malicious. Right.
It's just the fact that like,
you suck at what you're doing and you let everyone's
data escape and yet you had some controls in place,
but they weren't enough and your, it people don't know what's going on.
And so they're like, oh, well, here have a cookie. It's ok.
Whereas they should be like, no,
no, no, like here's the minimum fine. You screwed up, pay it.
Here's an interesting thing. So I'm looking at the GDPR fine amounts.
There's a couple of big ones.
-- Uh, 50 million for Google, €50 million for Google, which is
-- zero for Google.
Yeah, basically 99 million pounds for Marriott International
and 100 and 83 million pounds for British Airways.
But then it basically, it drops off to like,
and, and then there's one internet provider,
one on one got dinged for just under €10 million.
But then it basically, there's a couple of like 100,000 ones and then it just drops,
it's going to be long tail.
Well, no, not really a long tail because there's only about 50 or 60 of these.
-- Oh, really? Wow. I would expect more.
-- There's not been a lot of GDPR fines.
And what's interesting is when you read them like there, for example,
this one unnamed medical company not appointing ad po not publishing
its contact details or reporting those to the supervisory authority,
obligatory consent of data subjects,
blah, blah, blah. I feel like there's a lot of
companies are doing that.
Probably, I also have a suspicion.
The GDPR regulators probably don't have the bandwidth to process everything.
So they're going to try to pick out big ones. It's probably like speeding,
right?
You know, they don't pull over everyone's speeding,
they just try to get the worst offenders and that's
the hope that people will play it nice anyway,
back to the
the concept of predictions.
I just don't think in our space we can make predictions.
It's kind of like, you know what
I would say, if you think about what would a prediction look like in,
let's say the building industry today where you've
got traditional style building using wood or stone
and then all the stuff that goes in it.
And now there's obviously things like 3D printed houses
that are kind of becoming a hip new idea.
And I actually saw some pictures on,
on Twitter the other day showing off like a 3D printed house and
like that's new and interesting and it has the potential to be disruptive,
but I wouldn't say it is disruptive today.
And
would I predict that's going to take over? No, I would not.
Technology takes just because you have working technology,
you have to make it acceptable to the mass market, bring the cost down, make it work.
And that stuff is hard.
Like
only anybody can build a rocket but,
-- you know, try building 10 or 20 rockets but work reliably,
-- that's fair.
I would not get inside of a rocket you built under any circumstances.
I wouldn't even go near the launch pad.
Right. Yes. Exactly. Exactly.
Yeah, actually, so I was listening to the radio last night
and they were talking about Boeing is going to suspend production of the 737
max aircraft because obviously they're all still
grounded at the time of this recording.
And like Boeing has a ton of them in a parking lot.
Basically that they don't know what to do with.
And they were talking about how these
aircraft are hopefully will be cleared for flight
in the beginning of next year, next year being 2020 at the time of recording.
Well, it should be 20 this will be published in 2019. But anyway,
and, but then they said,
but the problem becomes what are airlines
gonna tell the passengers everything's fine,
trust us.
Like would you get on a 737
in the beginning of the year.
-- Well, I don't know. I think
-- about it. I would prefer not to.
Right. Exactly.
-- But at the same time, do I realistically have a choice? Uh,
-- you might not.
And I won't lie if I had to go somewhere and the only aircraft available is a 737 max,
I'd probably get on it and just be like, well, that was neat.
But, and the reality is, it's probably going to be fine,
but at the same time
the general public is going to see that and be like, no,
statistically it will be fine, but it's not fine if you own one that crashes.
But
stat, I mean, that could be true of any flight.
Well, you know, it's like my feelings about air carriers in general.
If you look at their safety track records,
like for North America and the Western Europe and whatnot, it's, it's fine
as
most of, you know, the developed Asia is great and then it starts to drop and by,
you know, if, if you go to the poor countries, like, it goes off a cliff real fast.
Sure. Sure. Yeah, I don't know. That's a good question.
Would I fly in a 737 max if I have to, you know,
fly to Vancouver hour and 14 minute flight?
Because westjet uses, I forget if they have Maxes or not. Yeah. I don't know.
I, the reality is, I mean, you,
I was still more likely to die on the way to the airport,
like on the drive to the airport
-- and
-- you know, it would make me feel better,
but I suspect I'm in the vast minority here
put a Boeing executive on every single flight.
No, no,
I would feel better just reading the FAA S
report and if the FAA explains what happened,
what Boeing did to fix it and this is why everything's going to be ok.
-- I would probably accept that. The
-- problem is it's worse than that.
It's not just a technical failure there. The FAA allowed Boeing to self certify.
Boeing wanted to self certify because apparently
the deal was, they, they,
the 737 max is technically a 737, but
really it's not.
And, but the main thing is this, the,
the pilots don't have to get a new, what is it called,
a flight certificate or whatever?
Right. So, like you have to get rated, like you can't just, like, learn to draw.
Well, it's the same thing with cars. Right.
I have a class five vehicle license in Alberta, which means I can drive like,
you know, reasonably sized cars.
But if I'm in a semi truck, well, number one, that's assuming I can even get it moving,
but let's assume I get it moving and I get pulled over,
I'm going to be in all kinds of trouble because I don't have a class one license.
And so what worries me is why do we think
the 737 max is the only plane with this problem.
And by problem, I mean, don't,
I don't mean this specific technical problem but I mean,
this general problem of they push the design to the limit
to keep it quote unquote, the same flight certificate.
-- You know,
-- I haven't seen any research into that question, but that is a very,
-- very good question
-- because the 737 1st came out in,
-- oh, it's like the seventies or sixties, it's old.
-- First flight was in 1967. So it was
design. So, I mean, that's
right.
It's needless to say the plane they're flying today is not the
plane they were flying in the sixties back when computers weren't real.
So anyway, we are nearing the end of our time
and I feel like
again, we will see countless predictions about security in 2020
it's probably going to run the gamut of every possible thing you can imagine.
Some of them will be right. Some of them will be wrong.
There's gonna be ransomware. Maybe there will be a big worm attack.
There's probably gonna be iot problems.
I bet there's gonna be two or more intel CPU timing attacks.
It won't shock me if we see some A MD timing attacks because they're like,
they have the same problems.
It's gonna happen when the researchers look.
It's like more of the same man.
Like that's the prediction for 2020 2020 is gonna look just like 2019.
Maybe with the knob turned up a little tiny bit.
-- So there's just a little bit more crazy, but that's it.
-- Well, here's a thought.
When do you think the A IML boom will end in security
will end?
Well, you know, before, like, because remember when, you know,
I DS and ID P and all that stuff was the hot stuff and now it's like,
-- whatever it's people do it sometimes they don't,
-- whatever.
It's gonna be the same slow burn where it was, the hype curve was huge.
And we're like, oh my goodness, it's gonna change everything and now we're like, eh,
whatever
and it'll just slowly get better.
And then one day we're going to wake up and be like,
when did this robot steal my job and move into my house and teach my kids?
And I think that's what it's gonna be.
It's like every new technology, it follows that crazy hype curve. Right. Holy cow.
This is gonna change everything.
And here's the thing,
some disruptive technology does change everything.
The smartphone changed everything like the hype curve.
It was crazy except, oh wait, we're just gonna keep going up because it's awesome.
But
you look at like A I and ML and they were hugely oversold and they under delivered.
So now it's just going to be that slow burn until they reach a point of usefulness,
which they will someday.
But I don't think it'll be next year.
I would argue that they've already reached a point of usefulness.
Oh, they have value. Just not the value we were promised.
All right. Now, I have a good question for you.
Self driving cars. Do you think we will see a fully autonomous
trip from one end of the United States to the other?
-- Didn't they already
-- do that with butter? No,
I mean, like a real one.
-- Not like they're fake on the highway. It
-- was
-- a
-- semi truck full of butter,
did they? No, was it? No, no, I don't mean a semi truck full of butter.
I want to see a, like a, a Tesla, a vehicle a, a normal consumer can acquire, right?
Not like some contrived test or something like it will be contrived.
But you know what I mean? I'm saying? Like
I want to know when will a,
a vehicle a human can buy you or I could go and purchase
now will make a successful autonomous trip from one end to the other.
Do you think it'll be next year?
Uh Well, people already have claimed to make it back in 2018. Really?
Ok. Then I guess sure.
Now here's, here's one thing. So self
driving cars because you brought this up.
I was reading an article talking about how Mercedes engineers
have made the decision that the Mercedes car will essentially.
Ok. I'm going to make a statement. You tell me what's wrong with the statement?
The Mercedes will choose to protect the driver of the car.
Like in a self driving car scenario,
it will choose to protect the driver of the car in the event of an accident.
So for example, it might run over some pedestrians.
-- What is wrong with that
-- statement?
-- I I saw that there's nothing wrong with that statement
-- because if no,
there is why are we using the word driver?
-- Well, the the the occupants of the vehicle I think is what they actually mean.
-- See,
now, let me ask you a second question.
The taxi driver of a taxi with or without passengers
will most likely choose
to protect themselves rather than for example,
veering into certain death to avoid running over a pedestrian.
-- Now all of a sudden we're much more ok with that sentence, are
-- we, I mean,
I think there are some that might, there's some who won't.
I think humans are unpredictable in those situations.
But compared to making that statement for an autonomous self driving car,
here's what I will say about that.
I read that and I've thought about it a lot and we won't
talk about it in depth because I think it's a bag of snakes.
But fundamentally, if you want to sell cars,
you don't want to be like, oh,
and by the way the car is going to
kill you if you're in an ethically questionable situation,
right?
And be like, no, I'm not buying that car.
I'm going to buy the car over there that promises to kill the
instead of me.
Right. I think it's a business decision
whether you agree with it or not.
-- I understand why they did it
-- and it's already
a decision we've made and accepted with humans.
Right. Humans do dumb stuff all the time
driving into people or other cars or other objects to try and save themselves.
I think it's unpredictable though because I think some humans will make a conscious
decision to put themselves in harm's way instead of harming a group of people.
Some people won't make a conscious decision because they're incapable of doing it.
And some people will say,
-- you know, I'm running them over because I'm saving me.
-- Well, let me put it this way.
If we really cared about that,
then why aren't the penalties for drunk driving so much harsher?
That's fair.
Like I said,
we've already accepted that people will easily put themselves in
a situation where they will easily choose themselves or,
or create a scenario that is so full of risk.
It's, you know, it's so full of risk. We've decided that it's illegal.
We're veering into a
dark place
and I'm gonna stop us because we're out of time and I don't want to talk about that.
I'll answer your question though. I predict
probably not next year.
Uh, not in 2020. That is, but probably I'm guessing early to mid 2021
is when we'll see, for example,
something like Tesla have enough software upgrades to be able to
essentially let's use the Cannonball run as an example. Right.
You drive from, what is it New York to L A as fast as you can
for, I think another year, year and a half. And I feel like a car like
Tesla or something would be able to make
that Cannonball run probably without killing anybody.
Yeah, that seems fair. But I feel like it's sooner than we think.
I hope so because I, I'm gonna need a new car in like a year or two.
And I really would like to buy a self driving vehicle because I hate driving.
So
here's hoping crossing my fingers. All right. Anyway, we need to end this.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you
for listening. You go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up the show notes.
You can use the Pound Os S podcast hashtag to hit us up
on social media and Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye.