Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in enjoying surprise topics, Josh Pressers.
I hate surprises so much. So you're going to like this one.
That's what you keep saying.
So I generally talk Kurt out of this,
but he won't crack this time and he says it has something to do with
video games. And I really like,
-- ok,
-- I love video games. So I'm gonna let this one go.
But generally speaking, I would have browbeat Kurt into not surprising me. So
let's go.
So it's basically,
there's, there's two parts to this.
The first part is the classic. When does a bug become a vulnerability?
And the second part is
the heist. So, and, and it's two different games.
Very popular games though, Starcraft two and Minecraft the heist.
I don't know that.
-- No, it's not. I'm talking about like a bank heist in
-- Minecraft,
a
bank
heist in
-- Minecraft
-- basically. Yeah.
So the first bug is ok. So Starcraft two, let's give a little back history.
Starcraft two. Aficionado. So you tell us,
I watch quite a bit of it online like I
anyway.
Oh, hey, good. News, Nova War and Maxima's back are black.
Uh They're back, they, they, they took like an eight year hiatus and they're,
they're now back in casting.
So shout out to them. They're doing great content. We should put a link to them.
I have no idea who that is. But,
but OK,
they talk about mac and cheese
anyway. So uh pig who's an Australian caster? Streamer? That
person? I've heard of. OK. See, so he was talking about the Colossus Range bug. So
Starcraft Two right now is kind of on life support.
Like Blizzard isn't putting a lot of effort into it because to put it bluntly,
they've sold 99.6 percent of the copies of the game they're ever going to sell.
Probably,
right.
So thanks that they're still running the servers
and they're still sort of pushing out new maps
and balance patches because this is my favorite
thing about Starcraft two is at any point,
the game is inherently unfair and unbalanced,
but it's
overall unbalanced and unfair enough to everybody that
it kind of works between the three races.
That's kind of how these games work.
But there's always like a map with a spot for a siege tank that like, oh dang it,
you know, like you just, it's a, you know, instant win
kind of thing. So
they pushed out an update to Starcraft and there's a bug in it
and it's the colossus that Protos
unit that has like the little laser beam lawn mower thing.
It's got a range bug.
So instead of when you upgrade it, it adds one to the range, it adds three to the range.
And
as you can imagine,
plus three range
-- is not balanced at all.
-- Is it, is it game breaking?
Oh,
-- absolutely.
-- Have the patcher fixed it for Blizzard.
The mod community has
and tournaments are running with mods by and large to undo this bug
because basically what happened is they,
they bundled up a bunch of files for an
update and something slipped in that shouldn't have.
So my question to you is, is this a security vulnerability?
-- I'm inclined
-- and I'll remind you there's money on the line because tournaments,
well, that's just it.
I'm inclined to say no, I feel like a, a bug in a game of this nature
feels like not a security vulnerability.
And I would also lean in the direction of this is like expected use.
You're not doing anything sneaky to exploit this.
You're just, it's literally how the game works.
However, in, in what you mentioned, there's money on the line,
there's real money in video games now and
a bug like this gives someone
a substantial advantage.
So I would argue, maybe not exactly a security vulnerability,
but it's definitely on the line of this needs to be dealt with because it is,
it is significant. It's kind of like the example I'll use when I worked at elastic.
Obviously, we dealt with security vulnerabilities all the time,
but we also had data corruption bugs, things where
nothing a user couldn't trigger it.
But like just through a series of events,
you could corrupt data and data corruption,
bugs were treated even more seriously than security vulnerabilities
because they are more serious.
And I think this is kind of the same thing where when you have a game
that
is especially used by professionals, any sort of bug
that gives one group an advantage over another.
I maybe not a security vulnerability technically, but it is in the same
-- level of we have to do something about this.
-- See, for me, it ticks a few boxes.
Number one, is it a problem? Let's not even talk about Attackers yet.
But is this bug a significant problem?
Like, remember when manage,
uh when we uh they shipped an update to um manage iqevm and had a like a classic memory,
free memory leak
where it basically didn't free memory.
And so like it would run for a day and a half and then,
right, like, because it just ran out of memory and, and
I, I remember because I was talking to them, they,
they were supposed to be also fixing some security bug and they're like,
they told me why they were late on this moderate security flaw.
And I'm like, oh yeah, no, go fix that first. Like, I don't care about my moderate bug.
You have to fix that right now. Tell me when you fixed it and, like, get back to me
because
we can't have that for customers. Right.
Like that's, that's worse than any security because it's inevitable. It's, it's
anyways. So I would say first of all, it ticks that box of. Is this a problem? Yes.
Number two can an attacker actively exploit it?
Like your data corruption bug is a good example of, well,
the attacker can't intentionally trigger it,
but as the defender,
I
don't really care if my data is corrupt, my data is corrupt.
That's a problem for me, for sure. Right.
Right. Regardless of why it happens, it's a problem.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. And, and personally I think security bugs need to be
spread out a bit to encompass not just what Attackers can trigger,
but regardless.
So, but this one,
an attacker obviously can trigger by choosing
a build that involves building colossus,
right?
Because you could do like a, a three robot
with, you know,
immortal sent drops or whatever
and, and ignore colossus. No, my point is you don't have to use this.
Like there's a lot of players that don't use certain
elements of the game.
OK. Right.
There's players that play Bio, they don't play Mac or they play Mac and not Bo,
right? So
the can an attacker exploit this in the sense of like they can choose to use
classes and they can choose to do the range upgrade and get that plus three.
Sweet, sweet game breaking. Goodness. No.
So the videos of this thing happening, like the clauses are like, just
like they're, they're like almost off screen mentally for me.
I'm like, what, what are they doing there? And they're like zap, zap,
zap. And I'm like, what the hell? Like I'm like that
you need to be, you, you can't do that.
Like you're, there's rocks in the way you can't, the, the range and then it's like,
oh, it's a bug.
Ok.
So it definitely can be exploited by Attackers.
And here's one thing that always, I personally found not as defining security bugs,
but really kind of pushing them over the edges.
Can it be fixed?
And the answer is yes, you can install a mod for tournaments or,
you know, you could agree to play on modded, whatever and, and
make the bug go away.
Right.
So it's not like some inherent design decision.
That's just like, oh, this is how the unit works. Too bad. No, it's like
you, you change this one number and it goes away basically. Right.
The problem goes away.
-- Why
-- hasn't blizzard just
released
on life support? It's going to be a few weeks or months.
-- So they're going to fix it just when they fix it.
-- Well, I, I would hope so.
But more to the point like the mod community, there's mods that fix it, right.
I mean, there's mods for Starcraft that allow you to do
pretty much anything. So,
so,
so we've now established that there can be bugs in video games that are
not traditional security vulnerabilities, but
do look and smell a lot like security vulnerabilities and especially
there's often money on the line.
Uh Sure.
-- Which means now Attackers have incentive before
-- I technically correct you on this.
-- I want to see where this is going.
-- So that leads us to the Heist. So Minecraft.
So there's a bunch of big public Minecraft servers.
Like
-- when I say big, I mean, like 1000 concurrent players,
-- that's at least
-- they're huge.
-- So
there's a really good video that was put out.
Actually, it's a year old now and it's about two B two Ts.
It's one of the biggest Minecraft
-- anarchy servers.
-- It's, it's fabulous.
I, I've logged in like twice and every time I basically died immediately.
And I'm like f this,
-- you
-- like my topic. You're smiling, this is
great.
I love video games, you know, this.
So basically there was
a,
a bug in the game
that could be used to track players in
if you exploited it properly in near real time.
OK.
And so what happened is
on Minecraft,
you can
harvest resources and build items and harvest rare stuff like
end pearls and build really cool items like diamond armor,
enchanted swords, blah, blah, blah.
And obviously some people like us filthy casuals just want
to log it in and have a good time.
So maybe we're willing to spend 10 bucks on
a suit of diamond armor and some other stuff.
So we don't immediately instant die to
the people who
-- are 14 years old.
-- Can, can you buy gear on two B, two T, I don't even know,
but you can buy gear anywhere because it happens outside the game.
-- I see. I see. Right.
-- I mean, we have a market for illegal drugs.
That's a lot harder to deliver that online craft sword
-- and maybe added to be two t like that place is brutal.
-- Well,
so there's an actual act of competition between the ST
the stores
and there was this one group that was grieving and blowing up all the stores.
And they're kind of like, well, how are they finding us?
And they basically did a bit of research.
They had, there were all these accounts that were logged in 24 7
and they were using this, uh this bug,
this exploit to track where everybody was going.
And so the thing is kind of like cell phone metadata.
I, I know where you live now because you know, you,
your phone spends eight hours a day not moving
from like midnight till late. So like that's where you live.
Right.
And so they were able to use this bug to
find where all the stores were and go grief them.
Right? Because they try and keep the location of a lot of these stores hidden.
So, but they don't get grieved.
Exactly.
So this group spent several months planning this
and the idea basically was, is they were going to build
because they got grieved. And so they were gonna build the biggest store
and their operational security was insane.
So for example, one of the rules was you can't walk, like you can't go to the,
to the place and come back like walking.
You, you have to teleport
using pearl except that's not secure enough.
So they used a bug in the uh under Pearl Teleports, which is if your,
let's say your character name is Bob and you throw an
pearl,
ok over into an un rendered chunk,
it stays and floats there until that chunk is rendered.
OK?
And the bug is the ender pearl.
The thing that teleports to it is whatever character has the name of who threw it.
So
you your Us Bob, you throw a pearl to an un rendered chunk
and then you change your character name
to something else. And then on your second account, you change that one to Bob.
Now this is not an instant thing. These name changes take a month or two to take place.
So there's a degree of patience here. That is
impressive. Seems
bizarre. So basically they preloaded with dropping these
pearls so that they could teleport to them in future.
That was the first stage of their security. The second stage
was they had to get all the 24 7 accounts
to not be online.
And they found another bug in minecraft that
allowed them to basically denial the service the server
so that it started bumping users and it bumps the users who sent the
most data first and puts them in the queue to log back in.
And the accounts that have been in 24 7,
obviously, like they're the ones sending and receiving the most data.
So basically, what they would do is they would doss the server.
It creates about aw it's straight up, creates like a 22nd gap.
So it's straight up like a heist film where it's like, OK, we do this,
we do this and the security system is off for 20 seconds and then we go into the vault,
right?
There'll be a link in the show notes to
the video that explains this in much more depth.
It's about a 13 minute video. It's
-- awesome.
-- I can't wait to watch this. This sounds amazing.
So
they did all that.
They built this
man
and, and then here's the problem. How do you hide something this big?
We're talking,
it was like over 1000 double wide chests full
of stuff full of Shulker boxes full of stuff.
So they
built
a base that looked like it had been attacked and grieved.
-- Oh
-- Clever, clever hiding in plain sight.
Basically masking,
right? Like ignore this rundown house. That smells funny.
It's totally not a CIA hideout.
It's just full of boxes of guns in the basement
anyways, they did all this and of course,
then once they established this and got their store going,
if you have a store, what's the best way to drive traffic to your store?
I
mean, probably ads,
you burn down all the other stores.
I mean,
that is one way to do it.
And in Minecraft on two B, two T
-- that's, I mean, that seems like the easiest way I would
-- agree.
So they went around,
they used these bugs to find out where all the other stores
were and they went and blew them up and burned them down.
I mean,
that's just like classic, old school capitalism right there.
-- You know, like
-- I solved the,
you know, like, hey, we're in competition with this other restaurant.
I boss, I solved the problem.
That's right.
They didn't pay their protection money.
Yeah. So,
and, and the thing is like they had about, it was $14,000 roughly worth of inventory,
you know? Which sounds, well, that is a lot.
But it's funny because in the grand scheme of things,
considering how many hours they put into this,
it's probably less than minimum wage.
I would think so. But,
wow.
So, and, and so here's a question,
should that be treated like a security incident or is it all?
Oh ha ha. People playing video games and, like, doing little bugs?
I mean, I think that is definitely a security bug in that context
and an attack, I would argue or a series of attacks.
So I think you just set me up for what I was going to technically say a little while ago.
I think we have this obsession in the security industry with security bugs
and everything else, right?
In our Venn diagram,
we have security things in one circle and like literally the whole rest of the world
in another circle. And we're like, we don't care about that circle of
and I, I think we have very tunnel vision often
and I think this is an instance where if we call it a security bug,
now we suddenly care about it.
But the reality is
this is probably technically not a security bug
from the purest technical definition of security bug.
But the reality is
this is AAA sequence of events that creates risk.
And I think in the security world instead of thinking about
like security bugs and security incidents and security events or whatever,
it's more of a risk
conversation. And any time you have an item of value,
there is a risk associated with that item.
Be it, someone breaks into Minecraft and steals your, your item of value.
Well, or even I think it can be expanded beyond that. Like
that, you don't even have to have the item of value.
There can be a, a potential market where people want to buy stuff and
an attacker can
take control of it or get an advantage there.
Like, in the real world,
if a business does better advertising does a better product,
we all agree that that's fine and kind of what we want
but what we don't want because there's a high
negative externality is like businesses burning each other down or
-- crashing their cars into their competitors store to shut them down.
-- Probably bad.
I, I feel like that's not a good thing for a long time.
Now,
I've been beginning to think that maybe
security vulnerabilities should be more defined by.
Does it give somebody kind of an advantage or a capability that they wouldn't?
And I hate to use this word because it's really wishy washy but shouldn't have.
And secondly, as part of wrapped in with that,
does it then also create this negative externality or internal
that we don't want because like if there's,
you know, inventing better products
and patenting them and producing them, that's what we want to happen.
But patent trolls where they patent stuff and then don't let anybody build it.
That seems bad.
I mean,
that
seems like a problem. Patent trolls represent a risk to nearly every industry today
-- and take back human innovation.
-- It certainly does. It's a huge deal. And I think
in the context of video games, any sort of bug or behavior or ability
that
creates problems like this, I mean, that poses a risk.
Like I, I have a marvelous example, I run a Minecraft server for my kids
and there was one time they invited one of their friends to
the Minecraft server and the friend showed up and literally trashed everything
and they're like, what do we do?
Seriously?
Yeah.
-- Right. They can have kids, man. Kids are
-- weird.
Do they know that they're playing on somebody else's Minecraft server?
They don't care.
And that even ignoring any technical rollbacks and stuff,
like you don't go to somebody's house and piss on the rug.
-- I mean,
-- generally speaking. Yes.
But now, but, but here's the thing,
I think video games are a little different because, yeah, if the kid,
I went to my house and trashed it, I'd be like, I'd call his parents up and be like,
you're, you're fixing my house,
you know.
Yeah, that's illegal.
But if someone shows up in your Minecraft server and trashes it, I'm like, well,
the lessons, like, don't invite a holes to your Minecraft server kids.
Like,
I don't know what else to tell you here and I had
a backup so I put it back in place and stuff.
I mean, they lost a bunch of stuff but whatever. And obviously it's,
I have magic God powers on the service.
I'm like, here's like a million diamonds shut up
and they were happy.
But I, I think again, this is like, this is part of the risk discussion.
If you have a thing
and you
apply value to it,
what are you going to do to protect it? And if you invent
invent, if you invite a massive a hole into your Minecraft world,
they might trash it.
They just can do that.
But see, the, the challenges, for example is I might have things of value,
but I can't spend a ton of money protecting them.
Like my house has windows.
I like them.
They let the sun in.
But I, I can't
like to spend money to prevent somebody from throwing a rock through.
One would be cost prohibitive
-- and ugly.
-- But you have insurance for that.
Right.
But what I'm trying to get at basically
is we can't protect everything that has value.
Right? And we can't,
-- we can't insure it always either. And,
-- and that's part of the risk decision, right?
Like the, the odds of someone throwing
a rock through all your windows for no apparent reason is probably very low.
The odds of that annoying kid, you know,
at school trashing your Minecraft server is probably pretty high,
but it's also, it's interesting to me that there seems to be like this.
Oh, it's a video game. It's not real. And I would point out like
there are Starcraft two champions who've earned
over a million dollars in tournament play.
That's
real.
Oh, for sure.
I think this is similar to
the, the universe of computers.
I, I found a funny meme the other day that was something like mom.
Can you help me fix my computer leaning back and share.
Oh, remember from 1994 to 2006 when you told me to get off the computer?
Like, who's laughing now?
And I think
any time you have a new technology or environment,
it takes a long time for the,
I guess the masses to recognize this is an item of value
because I think many of us still view, view video games as a frivolity. frivolity.
Like what always blows my mind is
go to the Apple Store and pay attention for a few minutes
when people come in with their devices that are kind of broken.
And what's the first question? Basically, the Apple people ask them.
I don't know, I don't go to Apple Stores. Is this thing backed up?
Do you have an icloud account? Do whatever?
And I remember sitting at a table because I had to get my iphone, the speaker broke
right in my old iphone. I see the, the speaker just broke.
And this lady was like, oh, I've been waiting here for four hours and I'm like,
she's like, how long have you been waiting here?
I'm like about seven minutes because like, I, I booked an appointment. Like,
anyways,
and it's funny because the guy like comes up to me and he's like, oh your iphone. I see.
He's like, is it back? I'm like,
it's fully backed up. It's on the icloud.
I have a verified backup from like two hours ago. He's like, oh,
ok then. And he, like, just turns around and leaves.
Right. He doesn't, he doesn't even bother talking the rest of his spiel.
Yeah.
Yeah. And the lady's like,
it's backed up and I'm like,
yeah. And she's like, how did you do that? And I'm like,
you, you log into icloud.
No. No, it's. No,
-- no.
-- And I know,
I know. I know. But, but the,
the thing is Apple's made it as easy as possible.
But the point I actually want to get to is people say, oh,
there's nothing important on my phone and you say, ok,
all the photos on your phone are gone.
Would that make you sad? And they go
oh,
yeah,
-- I would rather lose my wallet than my phone. It's
-- way
-- to replace
-- for real,
right? Like,
well, actually in this case, like, yeah. Oh man, those two of a things
like,
I don't care because everything's backed up off my phone except for some of the
two of a stuff which is not supposed to be backed up or whatever,
that'll be a pass key show sometime in the future.
But that's the thing, right? Like, yeah, it's
people sort of still view digital as being like,
not
real and not
valuable, even
not people,
people of a certain age
because we,
I'd say people our age and above probably are willing to pawn off a
lot of video games and digital things as having little to no value.
Whereas young people, I think often see the value in this. I have
kids who have spent
like hundreds and hundreds of dollars buying virtual crap in a game. And I'm like,
-- I feel like you're wasting your money but you like it so good job. Like
-- there was a,
there was a good thing on a side bit on Linus
tech tips or one of their things where they were talking
about the whales in these online games and how they'll basically
make items specific to that whale because they know that that
whale wants to collect like all the big blue swords.
And so they'll make one that cost 10 grand and that
they'll sell one.
But I mean, if it takes your art, everybody to, you know,
a day or two to make the sword and you sell it for 10 grand,
that's a no brainer.
Like there's just, there's these whales that dude, we spend four bucks on coffee.
-- That is some people's food budget for the month.
-- I don't, I'm a cheapskate.
How much is that microphone you're speaking into? Worth?
Like we, we have things that we like to spend money.
It's funny you bring that up is I recorded some
things for work the other day and they're like,
wow, your audio is really good.
And I said it better be, I'm talking through $400 worth of audio equipment.
Like my voice to my computer passes through $400 worth of gear.
And in fact, I just bought a new thing that's coming in the mail today,
which I'm very excited for.
I was, uh Paul Aci
who listens to our show.
I found out and we were on his show at one point, I'll put a link in the show.
Not so I'll dig it up.
But he put a link on Mastodon to a cough box he uses,
which is basically push the button mute yourself.
Well, I didn't buy the one. He suggested because I found a different one
that has a switch for either push to mute or push to talk so I can switch it.
I'm like, oh, this is really cool. Yeah.
Well, but does it work? I don't know. It was,
I did well on Va Nature's website and I ordered it and so we're gonna see how it works.
But if it works, yes, I will totally send it to you because there are,
there are instances where I want to push to mute and
there are also instances where I want push to talk.
And so having either or is immensely valuable to me.
No, that, that seems like an obvious thing to put in.
Like if you're building push to mute, why not?
And if it's like a $5 item,
whatever, make it as cheap as possible, I'm guessing it's not $5.
Uh No, this one is like 60 bucks.
I think it's still like here's the thing I
love is most audio equipment because it's targeting like,
like
musicians with no money. It's usually pretty cheap. Like, and I love that.
So you just keep buying stuff.
It's like, what's the answer to how many guitars is the right number of guitars?
One more than you have. How many bicycles is the right number of bicycles?
One more than you have. How many microphones is the right number of microphones?
One more than you have.
-- I
-- say this. Yeah, there's, let's see, all my death. There's 12,
-- there was only 23, not counting the headset.
-- I have
about five and in the, the dresser
in front of me because I put all my audio equipment
in a dresser because II I expanded too much for the,
the crate.
I
had it done
anyway. Anyway.
So back to this, I think, I think we need to, like you said,
we need to expand the universe because to me there's like,
there's,
ah, this is what's replacing potholes,
the sewer line.
So theyre paved the street a chunk of it. It's, it's gloriously flat. Like, oh my God.
-- So flat.
-- I play some street hockey on that side
-- and, well,
-- it's pretty busy. Bit of road.
Just put cones up. It's fine.
But
cor was out doing stuff in the sewer line again. And I'm like the heck
and I, I actually, as I'm driving by, I pause and I'm like, hey, I'm like,
what are you guys doing?
You cleaning the sewers? He's like, yes, I'm like, didn't you guys do that?
Like, three or four months ago? And he's like, also. Yes.
And I'm like,
what?
And he's like, one of your neighbors is dumping a lot of grease down their drain.
And I'm like, is it you? Yeah.
And I'm like, well, it's not me because, like, I eat all my bacon grease.
My mom's German. We don't waste, like,
grease is food.
You don't
throw it away. It is food. It's like I fry my bacon
and
I leave the grease in the pan because the next
morning I'm gonna fry some eggs in that delicious grease.
I do not leave grease in the pan. I filter it that way.
It doesn't have chunks of garbage.
I like it.
I, I have a joke with my kids where I'll make something and they, I'll be like,
do you know what the secret ingredients is, is kids?
And they'll be like, love. I'm like, nope, it's bacon grease,
butter
and
bacon grease is just butter with salt.
It's just salted butter.
It's bacon flavored butter.
Pretty much.
So. Anyways. But what's interesting. So, it's a 10 inch sewer line
and obviously it's got a bit of slope to it.
But I was like, how much I'm like, so it's getting like fat birds. He's like, exactly.
Yeah.
And I'm like, how much does it, like, how bad is it?
He's like, honestly, like, once you get about an inch, it's a problem
and it kind of makes sense because it's not, it's not under pressure being pumped,
it's just free flowing.
Right.
Like, I remember talking to a city engineer about their Y2K plans and he's like,
well for the water system,
there's about 2 to 3 days of water in the system under pressure.
So we're good.
And as far as sewage goes, like
gravity,
like that's, that's our answer to Y2K compliance is gravity.
But that means if you get like a one inch kind of little dam at the bottom.
Yeah, that's gonna cause problems. It's gonna be pretty damn gross.
And it got me thinking about this, like,
people dumping grease down their drain has a massive external impact for, well,
literally everybody upstream of them.
Yes.
That's right.
And I, I think that's kind of how,
that's sort of slowly where I'm starting to
push my thinking about these security vulnerabilities is,
it's more like,
is this a situation where somebody has to come out and clean the pipes?
Well, I think the other, well,
the other piece of it though is if I can make this someone else's problem,
I don't have to care.
Right.
And this is the same thing with, like, look at two B, two T, it's not their problem.
They don't care.
And, well,
and that's the thing though is I do have to care because I'm upstream of
them on the sewer line and I would like to flush my toilets and,
I mean, you do.
But they don't.
Well,
yeah. And so I like, again, back to L TT.
Uh, I think it was Luke was commenting, you know,
where would this industry be if we didn't have to worry about security?
Right. How much advance
stuff would we have if we didn't have to spend
all this time doing compliance and security and risk management?
-- You know,
-- I mean,
-- that's a ridiculous statement. I think it
-- is but it's,
well, uh chemical plants, for example, by and large,
they put a fence around it and that's their physical security.
They don't build the plant hardened.
So that like if somebody gets in and starts trying to blow it up,
it's gonna be able to withstand that.
Right. The assumption is you just keep people out of it and whatever.
Uh I've been watching a lot of those chemical safety board videos recently.
There's some good ones.
Uh, there's a lot of like welding defects that result in the kaboom.
I, I have no doubt. I have no doubt and
stuff. I think you can look at the history of pollution.
Like companies were just like, we'll,
we'll build our factory on the river because then we can throw whatever we
want in the river and it floats down the river and it's fine.
I mean,
this is why the south side of most North American cities are the less desirable place
to live. Because historically,
because the rivers flow,
you dumped everything into the river and no
one wanted to live downstream of the factories.
So the land was worthless
because you needed the water and to live. You know,
and I think security is a similar situation where if you ignore it
and you can push the, the, the,
the risk and the problems onto someone else.
Not my problem. I don't
care.
Yeah, the cost. There you go. Cost cost is
the
cost.
Yeah.
And,
and this is where I think sometimes you
need things like regulation to step in because
I mean, let's face it if
I was talking to actually, uh uh
one of our local government representatives here one time and it
was about cybersecurity because this guy was really good about it.
And I made the comment, I'm like,
look if companies could make money throwing puppies
and wood chippers and get away with it.
They do it like we need regulation because there are,
I'm not saying like there are good companies
but there are plenty of companies that like,
all they care about is making money
and that's it.
Like,
-- it doesn't matter
-- how one thing I've noticed is
when I talk like locally here in Canada,
we have a lot of, I would call evil companies.
Like every phone carrier is evil.
But when you actually talk to people that work for them, they're not.
Well, no, the people
are good.
-- It's just
-- the,
the
op
oppo
corporate structures that have become
a
de facto standard in Canada.
They're problematic.
Right. I pay, I pay
basically my internet and phone bill
is the equivalent of like, what a small neighborhood in Europe would pay.
I believe that
I've seen those European bills and I'm like, oh, my goodness,
you have no idea how good you have it.
-- It's like
-- 25.
But that's also my cable bill. So it's ok. And I'm like, well, what now? Huh?
Yeah.
Right. Exactly.
Why is it so expensive Europeans? No, I know. I pay
100 bucks for internet every month.
Gigabit. I mean, it's gigabit so I'll take it. But
I still think like 100 bucks for internet is preposterous.
It's way more than it should be,
but whatever, whatever. All right, we gotta wrap this one up.
We're running out of time.
I go watch that youtube video.
It's seriously, it's 13 minutes of, it's a, it's a heist movie.
-- It's awesome.
-- I'm excited.
I, I also love heist movies. I will say it. It
is like one of my guilty pleasures.
My joke is always,
I only watch movies with wizards or spaceships in them except heist movies.
I love heist movies and you know what the best part is.
I'm not a particularly smart person so I almost never
figure it out until the reveal at the end which just delights me.
There's nothing worse.
Than watching one of these movies with one of my kids or my dad because they, like,
figure this stuff out right away and they're like, oh, that guy did it.
I'm like, don't you ruin the movie?
I,
I wanted to figure it out.
-- But anyway, anyway, I
-- was an aside,
if you want to see a really great classic
heist movie that isn't portrayed as a heist movie.
-- Inception.
-- Is that a heist movie?
-- Yeah, it kind of is, I would,
-- I, I'm not kind of, it's,
they literally break into the guy's,
I suppose
that's true.
Apologies. I should have said spoilers ahead.
Maybe bleep that part out
at this point. Everyone knows.
Uh
There's gonna be somebody who hasn't seen it yet.
I'll bleep it out.
-- Yeah,
-- just bleep it out. It'll be funnier. It's like the thing with Memento, right?
-- There's still people that don't
-- know.
I've never seen Memento. I don't even know what that is. Is it a movie?
Yes.
Ok.
I don't
very, very
clearly doesn't have a wizard or a spaceship in it or I might know about it, but
that's a wizard. Technically
I need to find him. But uh
yeah. No,
I really, I think you're right about the Venn diagram of where we, we,
it has to be serious business security.
Yeah, for sure.
But I, I
think this is where I would encourage people don't
think about security issues or bugs or events.
Think about everything as a giant
risk discussion.
And I think that makes it easier to bring much more reality into the fold.
That's what I found.
And any time I can,
I talk about risk as the driving force behind something.
And it's amazing how much that changes the discussion
when you're, especially when you're talking to security people out for blood.
All right, I'm calling it. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to open source Security podcast.com. Hit up the show notes, UZ Pound
podcast hashtag on Mastodon to get our attention. Have a marvelous rest.
Why do you keep laughing every time you say that?
Like uh X is, I mean, it's just we both turned our accounts off. It's done like, yeah.
Right. I know.
Anyway,
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You
-- too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.