Hello and welcome to episode 110 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
-- I
-- mean, it feels like I haven't talked to you in, in years
and it's been what, like two weeks,
it's
2.5, 3 weeks.
Yeah,
I guess this is one of the funny things about doing a podcast is we
can just Precor some episodes and then still publish them in a regular cadence.
So
to the Real World, we're still talking to each other, but in real life we're not.
Yeah. Yeah. No, it's been a good summer.
It, it has, it's been, it's been busy, uh, was at Black Hat last week.
That was,
I don't know, man, I, you know what I feel like when,
when I go to the show now and I look around and this
is kind of true of Rs A this year as well is,
it's
II, I feel like it's getting boring
and, and I think that's a good thing, right?
Because there's not like crazy new products and crazy new research and,
and I feel like,
well, well, things are on fire for a variety of reasons.
-- It's not like the giant tire fire. I think it was a couple of years ago.
-- I,
I would disagree. I think it is still a giant tire fire. We've just become used to it.
It's literally that comic everybody uses with, you know, it's,
everything's on fire.
It's ok.
It's fine.
You know, it's,
people are finding new classes of attacks, people are finding, you know,
um, just giant.
Well, that, that thing they did, it was,
I think it was at defcon where they had a bunch of kids hacking election systems.
You know, they recreated a bunch of election website systems and,
you know, they had, I think it was,
they were posting the numbers and it was like, they had like,
36 kids hacking into these and like, only three of them failed.
I
doesn't surprise
me.
Well, I mean,
-- I mean, we're talking like eight year olds, you know,
-- I think they were 11 and 12
but
it seems
to
indicate there was a pretty good range of ages but
really young kids
and they're all terrible and we know they're terrible
and
I don't know, but
I think a couple of years ago I would have been like, oh, my goodness,
look at how bad this is and now I, I feel more like.
Yep.
Ok.
-- Well, I think
-- it's
bad.
I think it's bad but we've also learned that it's generally not the end of the world,
like, no offense.
Even the elect, like,
uh,
reminds
me that a hacked election doesn't end the world, like,
-- a year or so. Yeah,
-- exactly. But I was gonna say more like, so locally, you know, like,
there's, there's the crimes that make the paper basically. Right.
And some of them are, like, really kind of sad and dumb, you know,
where somebody dies because basically can't drive so good.
And, uh, oh,
even better example, people keep burning down their condos
because they smoke outside on the balcony
and then they stub out their, uh,
their, um,
cigarette butt in a
potted plant.
Now, here's the thing. Potted plants
used to live in dirt,
right? You'd go get some dirt, like, like black dirt,
you know, or maybe some slightly fancier black dirt potting soil.
Yeah, it's fine. You can, you can,
it doesn't burn,
right? So you can stub out a cigarette in.
It turns out, turns out nowadays, potting soil, uh,
especially as used
in the plants that you buy, like in the store that are already in the dirt,
like in the pot, you know, that you hang up on your balcony or whatever,
that looks pretty.
Uh, it's not dirt.
It's, it's essentially a like spongelike medium designed to hold water.
It's, I think mostly old sawdust
pretty much is what it's made of.
In
fact, the only reason I know that is
I, I met a guy once who is in charge of dealing with like the, the basically,
I guess old sawmills used to just pile up sawdust
and apparently that's an environmental hazard now for a variety of reasons
and they're selling it basically the companies that make potting soil.
Now it's what they're doing with it. And I'm thinking that's
crazy.
-- But
-- ok, if, if you don't know much about wood,
uh wood burns better when it's dry and it has a lot of surface area.
So,
sawdust is essentially the
literal definition of what can I make that will burn the best out of wood.
Although, although a pile of sawdust doesn't burn terribly well.
No,
but when you
burn.
Exactly. So,
but this is kind of like a sponge like material.
So, what will happen is it smolders, which means it's not
technically burning burn,
but it will smolder and then it'll catch light and then it'll burn down.
Uh, the building basically. Right. And, and we've had several major fires.
The, the most recent one was, I think it was 84 people are now homeless because of it.
-- Wow, that's crazy, man.
-- Yeah, that's,
that's kind of,
but the point is as terrible as that is.
Ok.
Thought experiment,
we can spend 1% more money on all these
condos and make them not burning down from cigarettes
being put out on the balcony proof. Is it worth it?
Does it cost more or less to just burn down a few
buildings or to spend 1% more on all the condos being constructed.
That's a tough question.
And I know you're going to frame this in the context of security.
And you could say if we increased all of our security budgets by 1%
what would happen?
And the answer is probably nothing.
-- No,
-- not a whole lot.
-- I mean, that's the sad reality
-- of it. Well, and here's the sad reality.
What if we increased our security budgets by 500%?
Uh,
-- probably we get five times better security.
-- No,
I would be shocked if we got 5% better.
I mean, I feel like there's like this,
it's funny because like, you know, everybody talks about the Mythical Man Month.
But I think there's, that's also true of budgets to some degree.
But yeah, it is.
And, and however, however my quality of life would probably go up substantially.
So there's that
it is
anyway. Anyway. I, ok. So,
-- so you think everything's still a giant tire fire? And, and maybe you're
-- right.
And we've also developed coping mechanisms, like, for example,
um
No, no, no, no, no, no.
What happens if your, if your cell phone gets screwed up, you just factory reset it,
log back in and boom, all your data is back.
Yeah, that's true. If my cell phone got hacked, I would just, probably
if somebody ransomed
my cell phone,
ok.
I would just factory reset it
and go into time machine and get the unencrypted get, go get an older,
an encrypted copy of the backups.
Same thing.
Like, if my Mac somehow got ransomware, I'd be like, oh, that really sucks.
Thank God for Time Machine.
Uh, yes, I would also do that.
I, I
do have some level of backups for almost everything.
It, I mean, I'll admit some things are better than others, but generally speaking,
the really important stuff these days I mostly keep in, like Google docs.
Yeah.
You know, and part of it is uh ok. Email.
Well,
email is a whole lot more secure now because most
of us are using large providers with really good antivirus scanning
and more.
So I know for myself,
I haven't actually used a male client really in over half a decade.
I used the web based emails which means if you're going to attack me by email,
you first of all have to get it past Google
and then you have to get some malicious content into a web browser.
So essentially your best bet is like fishing or social engineering,
not like a technical attack because
chrome is pretty secure. At this point.
There was an article I read that said
something like 34,000 plain text emails got sent over the Black Hat network.
It was like some enormous number
and I'm just thinking, who's freaking sending mail from their MT A
Google? I don't think even supports non SSL TLS anymore,
do they?
No, that's true.
At the, at the carrier level, they will take non TLS SSL connections.
But if you're a client, but if you're a client of, like, if you're Gmail client,
I don't think Gmail will let you talk unencrypted anymore.
Right. And most of these providers like outlook just
you, you have to TLS or no hablo email.
My,
my assumption for this is people are literally connecting to port 25 somewhere
from their mail client and it's not using any sort of encryption,
I guess. I mean,
not even starting T OS
because the only thing because basically what I'm saying, what,
what I'm kind of wondering is, you know,
how do the only way to set that up is to
basically set up your own email server now really badly?
Like you kind of have to go out of your way to do this,
you know, is what I'm saying, right? Like
it's like, it's like,
it's like putting TLS around your website now
you with, with things like cloud flare and lets encrypt and, you know,
I remember paying 500 bucks for an SSL
capable web server
and now every single device I have has,
you know,
-- some TLS capable web server in it
-- because of open
source.
Yo
Exactly.
So at this point, if, I mean, if that's a problem for you, then you're basically,
you have so many problems,
-- but
-- here's the other part of it is you would expect most of the people at Black an
to be
more
than most.
Right
there.
A
lot of,
well, first of all, there's a lot of less, I'm not gonna say non technical, I,
I should have gone with less technical people there, like managers and whatnot.
And
there's also a lot of people who quite frankly don't care.
Maybe you
don't.
But
I would assume if you're a manager you're probably using something like gmail.
Right.
Well, how many people, for example, don't understand.
Well, here's a tangent, why are reproducible bills important?
And the answer is not really because of security,
but it is security in the sense of reproducible builds are extremely critical for
security in the sense of you can actually push an update out quickly,
right?
That's it.
Right. Not this bit for bit thing. Who cares? But the fact like if my, you know,
who cares? Like how many vendors are there that literally
will tell you,
you know, we,
we can't push this security update out because it takes a month or two or three.
Right?
I had that Twitter conversation with
those people talking about hardware security modules
where they only get updates from the vendor like once a year.
And I'm like,
oh,
ok, then I, I don't really know what to say to that other than really that.
Well,
man,
wow. You know,
you have problems if your software only gets updates,
I don't care if it's security or nonsecurity update, but just updates once a year,
like,
yeah. Wow.
Anyway,
and how many people don't understand the importance of that, of being able to push a,
a software update quickly.
Right. A lot of people would be like, oh, what's the big deal?
There's, there's enough.
It's
right. Anyway,
so anyhow, black hat was, I guess, uneventful, which is good.
There was, there was nothing crazy.
I did not stay for defcon and thank goodness I didn't.
Hm.
Because all the hotel shenanigans I read about were, were crazy.
Well, it makes sense from their perspective. Right. They had this
horrible incident where, what was it?
48 people got killed and almost 500 wounded and
so. Ok. Well,
yeah, how do you deal with that?
Well,
I guess surprise spot checks of people's rooms to make sure they're not bringing in,
you know, multiple suitcases full of guns or something.
I guess
I'm not gonna get into this one because I
think you can argue it in many different directions.
I think the problem is not so much what they're doing
but how they're going about doing it and that there's no
consistency
and it sounds like too, like,
like I know when I'm staying in hotels depending on the quality of the hotel,
like somebody knocks on my door and I'm like, go away
and if you knock again I'm calling security
except it was hotel security.
-- Yeah,
-- exactly.
It's like, it's like whenever, um, well, not so much now because all the,
all the meters are wireless.
But remember back in the day when like,
your local gas company guy would show up at your door in summer, you know, in,
in like, in like um
shorts and like with that big handheld monstrosity of
a
portable.
And they literally, yeah, they literally had to like,
it's like I need to read your meter and it's like, ok, well, you know,
I'll walk you down to the meter in the basement and he'd like literally glance at it,
tap, tap, tap and then like run out
and I kind of always let them in because realistically like,
uh looks somewhat legit, but fundamentally, I mean,
I don't know what a gas meter reader guy ID looks like,
-- you know,
-- and
this is so right.
Iii I don't know the answer.
-- I mean, there's
-- two guys in suits, you know, looking grumpy.
Yeah, that's probably security
maybe
like,
I don't know,
here's the point
is
when you stay at a hotel,
you're going to have to listen to them.
And I know there have been court cases revolving
around privacy and a whole bunch of other things.
But I mean, fundamentally at the end of the day,
that's what's gonna happen.
Well, you,
you can push so far and if you push too
far then you're annoying to them and they'll boot you,
you know,
and that's, I mean, that's kind of the problem with a lot of the,
the new online sharing economy.
Right. Like that guy that got booted from Airbnb and he can't find out why
is
something happens.
You annoy the company enough and the company fires you as a customer, you know?
And yeah, when you're at a hotel staying for a week, that kind of gets inconvenient.
Right.
I, yeah, II, I don't know
what, what to even say necessarily, but it's,
I, I'm glad I wasn't there,
I would say at
a
minimum,
like,
I love this because my bank will call me.
And I'm like, how do I verify you're from my bank? And they're like, what
I'm like, how do I verify you from my bank?
And they're like, uh the phone number and I'm like, no,
like, seriously,
it's like I keep getting these phone calls from stats Canada
to the best of my knowledge, stats Canada doesn't randomly phone people,
-- especially from no caller
-- ID.
Are they looking for itunes gift cards by chance
or personal information? I don't know. I just hang up on them
because realistically, here's the thing,
realistically if the government wants to get a hold of me, they, they know where,
well, clearly they know where I live because they have my phone number too
and they'll send me registered email with, you know, grumpy
letters in it.
Right? Like that's, that's how revenue Canada does it? Revenue?
Canada flat out says we will not phone you, we will not email you, we will send you mail
and if you don't reply to it, eventually we'll start garnishing your wages
and,
and, and I guess that's,
that's always the difference. Right. Is historically, I think
most of the law enforcement activities and responsibility has
been the job of the government and they,
I feel like now
we're seeing
it's right in your
place, like hotels starting to kind of do some of this and
it's,
I,
I don't know what I think of that.
It's inevitable. That's the, that's the reality
-- is it?
-- I don't know
because the hotels don't,
the hotels I think partly have to be seen to be doing something.
So there, it's kind of like the TS A and airport security, right? They fail.
-- What is it? 90 plus percent of the security tests where people
-- trying
to
look in my room just have a scary looking guy by the elevator. Right?
And that'll make most people feel better,
but part of it is also the liability. Right?
And, and here's the reality, like a room check like that.
It's probably more about your body language and kind of how you're behaving and,
you know, are you getting real squarely
or are you, like, pissed off?
But like, whatever just can we get this over with like,
like most of us with the Ts A when they want to do the pat down
those guys, you know what I mean?
Because it's kind of like, yes, I've been through the pat down can we just, like,
I would like to go get my,
you know,
I'd like to go plug my laptop in and get a beer and just relax before my flight, please.
-- Right.
-- And think about my poor
life choices
and got me here.
Yeah.
Right. I, I don't know. I don't know. And, and I guess this is
the other thing to remember too is these are
security measures probably being thought out by people who
aren't.
I don't want to say they're not very good at security,
but they're probably not putting a ton of thought into it.
It's just like we have to do something, let's do something quickly. What can we do?
-- Room checks? Boom.
-- You know, that's actually a really good point.
Then you just hit on something and you made me think of something else is, is
people love doing security things that they think will make a difference.
But don't,
and the easiest example I'll use is going to something like Blackhead or defcon.
People are always saying, oh, I'll just get a burner phone.
Right. And it's like what that doesn't
help you, but they think they're doing something important.
Right.
And, and I think this is one of the
burner
phone for that place
because people think they're going to get hacked and, and lots of people,
somebody's
gonna
hack you. They'll just
yours.
-- Well, exactly. That's right. A
-- burner phone doesn't work. And in fairness. Ok.
So in fairness. If, if you have like, especially an android phone,
uh what was it here? Uh Do, do, do,
-- do all
-- of them except the pixel.
Yeah,
pretty much all the android phones are like out of the box full
of flaws and whether or not your carrier will let you do updates.
Yeah, millions of android devices are vulnerable right out of the box. Yeah.
And sadly, so this is one of the reasons II I choose Apple is because Apple
actually provides security updates for at least three years for their devices.
Typically usually about four or five,
right? Like my kids ipods that I bought them.
Wow, five years ago now, no, four years ago
are old enough that, you know, they're on I OS 10 and they'll never get updates.
But you know, the kids use them to watch uh kids youtube and like play um,
a couple of games.
Ok. Who cares?
Their, their ipads, I did, you know, bought them new ones that are up to date. But
yeah, fundamentally, um
part of my strategy is I use devices and services where basically if you can hack me,
then
you can also hack major banks.
So the provider kind of cares like Google or Amazon or Apple.
And by and large, these large guys
are showing that they care now, like they're,
you know,
uh Google just announced they're now expanding their bug bounty program to cover
uh service abuse.
Sure. Right. Right. But
I mean,
we're still talking about the fundamental point of
normal people want to feel like they're doing something
and they maybe don't know what to do.
And so they're going to do the thing that they think makes sense. And
this is one of the tricks I think, especially with a complicated topic.
Like security is the things we think make sense don't always make sense.
And, and there's,
it's one of those examples where I feel like
whatever I think the answer is it usually isn't.
-- And I'm comfortable accepting that. What I think something should be isn't
-- the
way
people suggest solutions for traffic problems on Reddit.
And then a traffic engineer will actually step in and drop some truth
and,
-- oh,
-- ok.
And I find myself thinking,
legalizing drugs
decreases drug use. Right. And it's like what
that doesn't make any for.
Exactly.
Yeah. We've got what? Uh, yeah, October 17th here in Canada. Uh, federally it, yeah,
pot will be a thing.
Uh, most of the provinces seem to be on the ball except for Ontario as usual.
-- And,
-- um, and I guess this is, this is the thing, right? With,
with human beings is
we,
we want to do something but we don't know what something always is.
And, and this is, this is true security, right?
It's, it's especially true of security.
Yeah.
Well, the other problem is how many people think of the 2nd and 3rd order effects.
Like my favorite example for this around security is
crime reporting
being put in public websites. Right.
So, uh, the Edmonton police has a really good website for this where, you know,
they'll show you the crime stats, you know, last 30 days, 60 days, 90 days locations,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Uh, what happened in London
is they actually found that this crime reporting stuff online,
like making it all public
has actually led to a decrease in some areas of people reporting property crimes.
-- Sure. Right. Nobody wants,
-- they
didn't,
-- exactly,
-- they didn't want to bring down their property values.
Yeah. And, and you hear about this as well.
I know with the,
the whole immigration issue in the United States is
now that they're cracking down on illegal immigrants.
People who, who live in immigrant,
heavy populated areas aren't reporting crimes because
they're worried even if they are legal,
-- they're going to get hassled. So they just don't
-- report crimes.
You mean the people who the immigrant?
Oh, yeah,
because an immigrant can't report a crime now because they'll get deported.
Well, there's the illegal immigrants, right. Obviously, if they
get deported,
but there's people who are here legally that are concerned,
-- they're just going to get
-- harassed
legally. Legal immigrants were getting refused entry into the United States.
So the legal immigrants would also be worried.
-- So,
-- so you get the point though, there's all these second
level and third level issues and,
and obviously my guess is what, what these hotels were doing is going to have
ramifications. They can't imagine
at some point
-- where II, I don't know
-- because the thing is, especially in Vegas, it's not like you,
you can't not go to these hotels.
And the thing is so the Defcon guy,
remember there was a posting a few days ago about how he's like, oh, this sucks.
It's terrible. We're going to maybe move the venue
and they're talking about moving it to a different venue except that different
venues owned by the same group that owns little like little Caesars.
Did you just call it Little Caesars?
Is it? Sorry? What
Caesars?
Little Caesars is a pizza company.
Sorry,
-- I'm actually really hungry right now.
-- That's fair.
I would, I would rather go to a pizza conference, I think, than a security
conference.
The
pizza conference.
I
wonder if
-- the vendor
-- hall
it would be,
I would be so sick by the end of it. I want to go somewhere.
I'm gonna, I'm gonna look this up and see if there's like a national pizza company.
There must be, man, there's like, I would
think some companies,
pizza ovens, pizza paddles, whatever. Anyway. Um,
but back to this. So, so it's kind of like the online thing.
It's like, oh, I'm not going to use Gmail or because Google spies on your email.
Great. Well, because like Microsoft sure as heck doesn't do that.
Oh, wait, everybody does that now. Like that's just how the industry is,
you know,
um, or it turns out they're all, you know, when people were saying, like, oh,
what was it?
Git Lab, like, oh, they're using, I forget who was evil that week.
And they flipped to somebody else and it's like,
you know, they're on Microsoft and then they went to, I think, Google. Yeah.
I think that's what it was.
Git lab went from Microsoft to Google or something And everybody was like, well, no,
it's less evil.
It's all good. But
I mean,
you know, it's like with hotels you can't just sort of, especially in Vegas,
there's the hotels on the strip where
like, no offense. But
if I have to go to Black Hat or defcon,
I am absolutely staying in the hotel where it's happening because
walking outside in Vegas or taking an Uber is such
a chore and hassle and it's so disgustingly hot.
-- Uh
-- It is, I was, I was there, it was 100 and 10
°F and
Celsius.
I don't know. It's a big number, probably like 40
and it was, it was crazy.
And I did go outside a couple of times
-- and it was, it was, oh
-- jeez, man, that's 43 and a third degrees Celsius. That's,
yeah, it's pretty hot.
It was hot, dude.
-- I'm not gonna lie.
-- I,
I've been to Vegas and, and the thing I remember was like, oh,
this is what it's like to live in a hair dryer,
like the inside of a hair dryer. It
was, that's what it felt like when you went outside,
it felt like someone was blowing me with a hair dryer.
The whole,
it was, it was crazy. Anyway, anyway, anyway, we are discussing
bizarre security, I guess 2nd and 3rd level effects.
Well, and, and the fact that people
try to find a solution or they, it's, I'm trying to help.
Great, but sometimes, you know,
not doing anything is also acceptable. Like,
uh,
well, look at car crashes, right. We're
to put it bluntly, we're not doing anything to actually fix car crashes.
Like, have we improved driver training? Uh, no,
we've definitely improved cars and there's car
safety
has gone up a ton,
but we're not actually doing anything to
really stop people from driving
like idiots apart from removing them from the equation as much as possible.
And, and I, I think that's where security fails a lot is.
We are obsessed with training people
every time somebody's like,
we'll just train all the developers to write secure code and I'm like, we can't
train them to write even.
Ok,
we, we, first of all, you need working code
and that in,
in and of itself is a huge problem. Right?
How many people can't even get their project to work,
let alone get their project to work without really horrible bugs,
let alone to get their project to work without
really horrible bugs without really subtle security flaws,
right?
So training developers not to write
security flaws is like
-- so far down the chain of competency,
-- it's not something you can do. It's impossible.
Right. We might as well train developers to look for Yetis.
I mean, that is the same thing.
Open BS D and Open SSH can't even do it.
And all they basically care about is security.
They're literally the smartest people on the planet and they
screw it up if they can't get it right.
There's literally no hope.
They're one of the few groups willing to sacrifice features for security.
That's true. They are and they still speak
up.
Yep. You know,
and I mean, can you imagine trying to convince Google or, well, not even Google,
imagine convincing anybody with a software product
to cut features because it'll make the product more secure.
Uh
You're gonna get fired.
Yes,
I don't, I don't imagine anybody doing that. And
more importantly,
is it going to matter?
I mean, the answer is probably not,
not really, no.
And that's not to say we shouldn't maybe drop some legacy stuff and features like,
you know, dropping ts 1.0 or dropping ts 1.1 or,
you know, dropping
support for, you know,
things that are now understood to be really dangerous and actually not that useful.
And so there is some of that, which is good.
Um But by and large, yeah, it's, those are corner cases, not the standard
Right. And, and definitely not training.
No.
Yeah, it's
actually, you've got me thinking now because you're right. When, when there are,
when there are car accidents or there's something happens.
Nobody ever says we need to train the drivers better.
It's always, we need to make the cars safer.
-- Well, yeah, we, we gave up on that a long time ago.
-- Like,
right. And, and I,
we suck at that in computer security.
We, we suck at it so bad.
I mean, look at the number of places that do, like root cause incident analysis and,
you know, some of them there's a few that do, uh, cloud floor and Google come to mind.
Right. They, they post those really big long, good write ups and they really,
and you'll notice that
they talk about doing a whole bunch of, not just to solve this specific problem,
but in general like, oh,
we're going to be more careful about how we pushed production.
We're going to have more checks and balances, you know, we're going to have more,
you know what I mean?
It's like the whole air incident,
you know, crash investigation thing where it's like, ok,
why did this mechanic screw up?
Well, you know, he screwed up because, oh,
it turns out like the flight crews and mechanics getting enough sleep is important.
Right.
Unfortunately, it's hard to regulate.
But, you know, we're at least aware of it and we try,
you know, I mean,
how many computer software places actually have a policy of like,
maybe we shouldn't put all these random software developers
on call 24 hours a day to fix stuff
to make sure that they get enough sleep so that they don't like,
write bad code.
I'd be shocked if anybody had that policy
and it would, that'd be really interesting actually to, to map like,
code quality and,
and volume versus
like what,
what someone's schedule looked like where they were
maybe working really late one night or,
or something like that.
The
reality is we
know that people,
when people don't get enough sleep,
they're cognitively impaired to wrap very rapidly to a high degree.
Like it,
it doesn't take a lot of lacking sleep to,
for people to be pretty useless.
Uh, especially it's something as, you know,
creative and as sophisticated as writing code.
Right? Like people who are tired can keep a car on the highway
most
of the time. No, most of the time,
you know,
and that's a relatively simple task compared
to like writing some code implementing,
you know, a complicated business concept.
-- Right? That, that's a pretty high cognitive task.
-- It is. I, I agree. I agree.
I, I feel like
this is
we just keep talking about this. Like people are the problem, right?
And the solution is always
the problem, less people doing stuff
and
technology that helps the people and make
sure like things like lane departure if every
single car on the highway had lane departure
and the you're about to rear end somebody
-- that would definitely cut down a big pile of accident.
-- It certainly would.
And, and when it comes to security, we have remarkably few guardrails.
Here's a great hypothetical.
Imagine if everybody had a continuous integration system
and actual
code tests and function tests and unit tests and actual smoke tests and actual,
like we build the product and have a thing.
Click through the web U I test.
That would be fantastic. That would be amazing.
And we will never get there.
I'd be shocked if even 1% of software has that
and, and does it matter? Right.
I don't know. I don't, I, apparently not because the world keeps spinning
and, and that's the thing.
I mean, I, I have a feeling it will matter in something like automotive or meds
because some group is going to make it matter. But, but for like,
you know, I'll pick on Slack for a service like Slack
is, is
right? Granted, they do a good
job.
They actually do a really good job.
But, you know what I mean? Like,
I,
I, there's so many little startupy type
services that have terrible security and it's
probably never going to make a difference,
-- you know? Well,
-- they have so many real existential threats trying to kill them.
But like,
basically if, if security becomes your problem, you've, you've won,
you've survived long enough for it to be a problem. Right.
That's a really good point.
And, you know, really interesting.
I mean, for security to matter,
you actually have to have users and value in your system
-- and,
-- and like money. Right.
And how many start up never get there.
Most of them,
like 98%.
Right. Right. That's interesting. You know, that's, that's a really good point.
Uh,
I, I think we should, we should call it there as our, our episode,
which show notes were filled with,
with ideas
and we got to do, who
-- cares?
-- I mean, oh, guys, guess what another speculative execution
because,
well,
because we did all this black magic to make computers faster and as it
turns out some of it was kind of running around with scissors dangerous.
Uh,
-- you
-- know, that happened.
Yeah,
it's anyway,
and it's gonna keep happening.
It's like,
it's like people who write web products and they're
shocked when there's cross site security flaws in them.
That's just the nature of it.
Yep. Yep. That's exactly right.
It's,
oh, well,
-- I
-- buy canned beans.
That's right.
Stack up until the canned beans get too old and kill your botulism or something. So
you can't win. Like, there's, there's no, there's no way out.
-- Oh,
-- funny story.
I, uh,
I watched a youtube video the other day and I
actually learned how to use a can opener correctly.
I've been using it wrong.
What kind of can opener?
Uh, like the rolling one, I've been putting it.
So I've been cutting through the top of the lid, not the side of the lid.
And they suggest you cut through the side.
Yeah. And it rolls it.
That's actually how you're supposed to use a can opener as it turns
out because it rolls the edge and you don't get a sharp edge
and it also takes the entire thing off.
And so there's no lip
for,
to get
-- caught
-- on my, uh, I bought one of those can openers that like cuts.
It's purposely meant to do that where it like cuts around the edge of the cans
because I got sick of cutting myself.
Well, but that's what normal ones do as well.
Normal ones can do this too.
I haven't either. I mean,
I
think,
think that,
you know what, I think the trauma,
well, here's the thing, I think the reason is
because when we invented canned food,
we didn't invent can openers for about another 50 years.
And so the way you open a can with like a, a tool is you, you know,
you punch in through the top and you, you knife it open basically, right?
Like ridiculous
army knife. I can actually do this.
It's,
it results in basically the most dangerous thing you can possibly hold in your hand
is,
yeah.
But anyway, so, and I think that's why I,
I always used a can opener that way was punching through the top because that's how
you do it with like a mechanical tool.
And it just never occurred to me to put it on 90 degrees sideways.
And it turns out it works much better.
-- It's easier and it works much.
-- II
I want to go try this. Now, after we stop talking, I've never done that before.
We'll have to post a video to it.
It's a video of Kurt slicing his hand open.
Well, it's like when I learned I was,
I was opening bananas from the wrong end because again,
I saw monkeys at the zoo doing it on a youtube video and I was like,
-- you're supposed
-- to open bananas from the end without the little knob.
Yeah,
you hold the knob and then you just pinch the top and peel it.
It's much easier. You don't have to saw it open with a key around it.
I, but you saw your bananas over with a knife. What are you eating?
Like green bananas?
Well, no, no, no, because I used to like, try and crack the top and if it didn't crack,
you know, you get kind of mushy at the top.
So I cut it with a knife or saw it with my key. If I didn't have a knife handy
and crack it open and hold it from the bottom,
hold it from the stem and pinch and peel,
I'm
gonna,
you might not be wrong. But I don't, I'm never gonna do that.
In fact, I don't even like bananas very much, but
I, I feel like you're,
no, no, you know, you are,
you're like the weirdo who does everything wrong and people are just, like,
look at that weird guy
and then they don't listen to you because they assume you're a lunatic.
And so I'm not going to do that because I have enough trouble relating to people.
Like, I don't need
to be eating my bananas upside down, right?
Like here everyone come eat bananas and open cans with me. You know,
I don't need that. I have enough problems
anyway. All right, sweet. I'm calling it, man. Thank you. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. You can go to opens
source be
podcast.com.
Hit up the probably show note for this one and then,
and then you can use the
Pondo
Ss podcast hashtag on social media to get our attention.
And yeah, I guess if nothing else, Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks. Thanks everybody. Bye bye
the