Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast
which uses wordpress to run its blog with myself,
Kurt Siefried
-- and Josh Pressers,
-- not your partner in Thought Crime or something.
We do use wordpress.com and
I've been thinking about this a lot lately because I would i it's not gonna go away,
but there's definitely some,
it, it weighs on my mind more than I wish it did.
I'm going to take and this is not the stance I'm taking,
but I'm going to point out that the vast majority of entities using
wordpress.com are using it because they just
want something that works basically well.
Well in that, that's how we got there. Is we originally used blogger? I think,
I think blogger,
I have no
-- idea.
-- I don't, I don't remember. I'm pretty sure it was blogger way back in the day.
It was the Google one and then they screwed something up.
-- I don't remember the details.
-- Well, I think they took it away like they canceled it
-- as Google
-- does.
It might have been that and then I moved to wordpress.com and the only
reason I picked them is because they had like an import plug in thing
that let me just automatically import the blog and back then we, we were in like 100
some episodes maybe.
And I just manually went in and fixed the
broken links and stuff because it wasn't that huge.
And now we're at 400
something. So, like the thought of having to migrate.
I know. Right.
It hurts my brain. I don't,
I don't want to.
Yeah, I think so. This is going to be an interesting discussion. But I think
part of it is we're in a bubble of people who care very deeply
about not just technology but some of the ethics and morality about
it.
And I'm going to,
I'm going to offer a theory which is
the vast majority of companies paying for wordpress.com.
Don't really care about the ethics or morality of anything.
-- So
-- they,
this is a good question because they don't care about the ethics of the morality,
but they don't like chaos and unknowns.
-- And that's a, that's a different topic though.
-- It is a different topic.
But I think it's heavily related because I know you
have been insistent in talking to me over the last,
since this whole debacle started of like, oh,
most companies don't care and I think most of them didn't care until now.
But you're assuming that they even know about it.
I have not seen any real coverage of this apart from a bit in the register,
but this is not like going to make
the national news as like
-- Microsoft or something.
-- No, no, of course not.
But here's my counter argument to that is if you are a marketing person,
this is in your circle somewhere. So like
my example to you was the marketing person I work with is like, hey, what's going on?
Do we need to freak out?
And I was like, we don't need to freak out yet, but we should be prepared to freak out.
Well, here's the other thing, if you're heavily invested in wordpress,
which by definition of views in wordpress.com, you kind of of
our,
what's your alternative?
This is like this is like when people
dis windows and Microsoft saying Microsoft did terrible,
terrible things.
-- Yes. Yes, they absolutely did.
-- OK?
No, I'm going to bash you for this because you always say this like, oh,
what's your alternative?
And here's the thing, the alternative always exists.
It just depends how much pain and suffering you're willing to put up with. Now,
in the case of wordpress, what's your alternative? There are alternatives.
There are many alternatives you could self host, you could use WP engine,
you could switch from WP engine to wordpress.com.
You can migrate your website to a different technology.
I meant more in the sense from moving
from wordpress to some entirely different technology.
There are, there are options all have pain.
And what happens though is you always like to say, oh,
what's the alternative in your snide snarky way.
But the reality is there is always alternative
and eventually
this will reach a temperature where any alternative is better than the status quo
and we're not there yet.
But if things keep going, the way they're going,
the alternative,
whatever that may be is going to be less chaotic
and less painful than dealing with what we have now
thought experiment for a moment.
Let's say wordpress.com goes full evil 100% full evil
and like, chokes out like pretty much all the major paid plugins.
Like, what was that most recent one they did was automatic fields
-- forms. I always get the sorry, automatic custom fields,
-- right?
Which they renamed and we'll cover that in just
a moment because that whole thing is nuts.
Well, and let's say they go full evil on all that
again.
I suspect a lot of wordpress.com people,
like users of wordpress.com will just carry on, right.
I've seen the same arguments made against Red Hat. Red Hat's evil.
And I literally would ask people like, what specific evil thing did Red Hat do?
And they're like, well, it's just evil and I'm like,
I'm like, do you mean the one time we shipped,
like close source software?
Like, yeah, yeah, that and I'm like, ok, well,
what happened there is they acquired a company,
the
VM and they, you know, had a Windows, binary blah, blah,
blah and they actually in the next version got rid of it and manage to open source.
So, apart from that one, technically evil thing they did for a little while.
Give me one and, and nobody could ever come up with one.
Now, what's interesting to me is I'm not sure.
I'm, I'm wondering about the legality of this too because automatic custom fields,
like, like they forked it to secure custom fields
and essentially
hijacked it.
They totally hijacked it.
What the difference is normally you would fork the code
and then people would choose to use it
of their own free will.
But in this case,
that's not what wordpress.com is doing.
They're going to be flipping people over from a CS to
the,
from automatic custom fields to secure custom fields.
And I mean,
I seem to remember a company called Microsoft being accused and Google
being accused of all sorts of monopolistic practices of using like their search
or their web browser to push their search engine
and so on and so forth. And this sounds a lot like that.
It might be.
I mean,
I don't know if there's that sort of involvement from the antitrust regulators.
I hadn't even thought of that.
-- Honestly,
-- they, they're literally using their market position to say like, yeah,
you don't get to use AC F anymore.
We're swing you over to SCF Yes. Pray I don't alter the deal further.
-- I mean, kind of
-- how is that not exactly monopolistic behavior.
Here's the other piece of this though.
Kurt, I think you're not considering is you say, oh, if they went
on evil, like, what are you going to do?
Here's the thing. So
it's never like one thing.
It's not like when, when Anakin goes and murders all the Jedi,
like it's never like that.
Right. That's not how companies turn evil.
What companies do is they erode trust and sometimes they
erode trust quickly and sometimes they erode trust slowly.
But as you erode trust, you are hollowing out your customer base.
And in the case of wordpress, they had this whole community behind them,
which is almost certainly damaged beyond repair.
At this point,
they have their customers of wordpress.com, which has its own set of problems.
They have WP Engine who
in all normal sane universes would be the villain of the story. But they're not
because, because like the whole thing is beyond nuts
and the reality is, it's not about what are you gonna use?
It's not about, oh, companies don't care about being evil.
It's about the fact is like if a disruptive technology,
if someone showed up at my door and said, hey,
we have a different web hosting platform that
isn't wordpress and we can import your site
with minimal errors.
And I, I don't even care if it'd be more expensive. I'd be like, holy crap.
We're in like, I'm down, get me out of this madness.
And again, I'm not in favor of this position,
but I'm going to point out wordpress is a lot
more complicated than that because it's not just my content.
It's my plugins.
No, I, I get that. I understand.
I'm saying though,
if someone could show up and say we
can migrate you off wordpress with minimal disruption,
I wouldn't even think about
it.
It would be a done deal because this is chaos and stupidity,
which is the worst two combinations.
Yeah. Well, and I mean, that's, that's literally like WP Engines business model
is
we'll do it slightly cheaper than wordpress.
And that's literally WP Engines business model is we'll do
it slightly cheaper than wordpress.com because we don't put any
as much resources into the engineering and the hosting of the plugins and blah,
blah, blah.
Right.
And they let you run like whatever dodgy plugins you want,
which is the other reason people love them.
But, um,
the thing is people wordpress sites are rarely just the content.
It's those plugins and that,
-- that plug in ecosystem is why wordpress
-- one. No, I get that. I understand.
And it doesn't matter whether it is or isn't the
plugins at this point because of the chaos and stupidity.
I'm certain a significant number of people would gladly abandon it if they could.
They can't yet,
but I'm sure they would.
Here's a thought question is,
are the alternative platforms anywhere near in
terms of plugins and ecosystem support?
-- There are no alternative platforms.
-- Well, no no
one massive benefit of wordpress is where's the number
wordpress powers? 43.5% of all websites is their C MS. Sure.
Around 478 million websites are built on wordpress,
which means if I need to go find a wordpress developer or admin,
I literally could like, shout from my front yard and probably find one.
-- Yes, they're easy to find. I agree. Right.
-- And that's one massive
thing that I love about. Wordpress is like if I
there's just so much talent
and it's like it's versus, you know, these so m
uh these more niche solutions for
sure,
findings.
And again, like if even if you want to switch and kind of get
away from this risk and this chaos, I'm not sure the alternatives are,
are that much meaningfully better for.
There isn't an alternative yet
yet is the key.
They have opened the door
to someone with a good idea
and the willingness to be flexible to disrupt Wordpress. Yeah,
that is one of the things now let's talk about.
I want to start the actual like meat of this conversation with a question for you.
-- Is this a supply chain attack?
-- So I would say
yes,
in the sense of if it walks like a duck and talks like
a duck and the duck catches fire and burns my house down.
-- Yes, it's a problem.
-- It has Giaan
energy.
The, the, the challenge is attack implies intent
and
I honestly, in this situation,
don't care so much about the intent as I do about the outcome.
And the outcome is, for example, I have two sites running wordpress,
one on wordpress.com and one off wordpress.com.
Because fun fact getting zap your automation to work with wordpress.com.
I
in theory, you can get it working,
but you have to like poke a bunch of holes and allow IP S and
basically it's, it's,
it uses the XML R PC call stuff, which is like all security lockdown. And
so
I literally just run a light sale instance for six bucks a month
with the, I think it's the bit nay,
I
think Amazon ripped off the bit nay
apps for their, you know, like you want wordpress, click 11 click install, right?
And so yeah, I use that, but in
this case, I don't care about intent so much as like, I'm pretty sure he's in like
to put it bluntly
WP engine did the classic thing of we're going to free ride
on an open
-- source
-- project to a degree. Yes, for sure, for sure.
That part I'm ok with,
yeah,
but the part that becomes a problem is they also free road on wordpress.com
infrastructure.org
dot org,
which is,
and I mean,
we can pretend that wordpress.com and wordpress.org are different things,
but they're not
-- like let's be real.
-- They are technically different things on paper, but
-- these are two different fingers, they're
-- just attached to two different fingers.
You have more than one finger card.
Yes, I hope so.
It would
be very
awkward.
If
I can see,
I can see multiple fingers. It could be
-- a,
-- I
-- count them.
-- That's right.
Why do you have 12 fingers?
Yeah, but that's the thing right is so I'm,
I'm ok with them using open source and not giving back or even so many go
bug report. That's fine. That's how open
-- source usage
-- works. An unfortunate aspect of open
-- source. Yes.
-- However, running the wordpress plugins distributions.
Well, yeah, I mean,
they kind of maybe get to say who plays and who doesn't get to play with them.
Twitter, for example, Twitter has filtered all the Amazon
two IP S as best I can tell from even
like remotely connecting to the site for scrapers and stuff.
Yeah.
So I have that thing that like checks what your Twitter
web page is and it's hooked up to a VPN.
So it goes through um I want to say like Nord VPN or somebody
use an IP address that Twitter essentially hopefully can't
block because so many people used to actually access
Twitter
but they can't block it.
Yeah, apparently the real way to do this is to use the mobile IP space.
So you get a bunch of SIM cards
because like they don't want to block mobile
clients because those are people with money,
but back to this.
So I would say this is one of those beautiful.
They are technically correct in being able to do what they did.
I don't know if they are actually.
So,
but morally and ethically the second order and third order implications of
what they did was a really bad idea because now we're talking,
I'm going to point out now we're talking about it on the podcast,
which means you've done fed up.
I, I would agree with that.
Like, generally speaking, if you're being featured on podcasts such as this,
like nothing good has happened.
But so here's the thing, here's the thing.
So first, let's just explain kind of what happened.
And there have been this, there's this crazy timeline.
I will link to the wild timeline in the show notes.
But is this the one that also includes like the, the venture private,
the private equity fund?
And
it's
good
because that's something most people are ignoring on this is like
private equity firms are involved in this. So it's like, it's not as cut and dried.
-- It's actually kind of messy, right?
-- And so I'll just run over that quick, right?
2005. Automatic is founded 2010
WP Engine is founded
in 2011.
Automatic,
made an investment into WP Engine
in 2018.
Apparently, they divested that investment,
which I assume they made a bunch of money in that at that point,
they'd be idiotic not to.
Well, they sold it to private equity and private equity is infamous.
For over paying for stuff and then trying to strip mine the value back out. Yeah.
Right.
But then, so July, mid July of this year 2024 it says
the wordpress Foundation was granted the
trademark managed Wordpress and hosted wordpress,
which, all right.
-- Weird. But, yeah,
-- it's
-- a
-- little,
I
-- feel like it's a little late in the game for that.
-- I mean, kind of, but I don't know.
And, and anyway, so it says September 20th, uh Matt Muller
sends extortion like messages shortly before his talk
to go. He says he's gonna go scorched earth nuclear uh
September 21st.
There's um he Matt post an article that WP engine is not wordpress on wordpress.org.
And then we kind of have this just like back and forth madness until pretty much now,
which is what mid
Oktober. And what happened is wordpress
has a plug in called advanced custom fields that I think that I don't know if WP engine
is the primary author,
but it is a, it is a four page plug in in the wordpress ecosystem.
It's like pretty much of the default one if you're using forms
to take in data and email it or put in the database,
like
I even use it
like it's,
we do not,
but I'm, I've, I've heard of it, right.
And so then
there's, let me,
let me just pull up the actual blog post from the wordpress people on October 12th.
They say that they have,
they have forked advanced custom fields into a new plug in,
called secure custom fields.
And here's the thing,
it says SCF has been updated to remove
commercial up cells and fix a security problem.
And the security problem is the angle they seem
to be focusing on to justify their actions.
I found the security problem, they fixed.
We'll, we'll get to that in a moment.
But here's the thing.
So
the other piece of this is there's something called 0.18
in the plug in directory guidelines.
Now I'm going to read these to you and I would like for you
to tell me if you think anything we have talked about or seen so far
kind of falls under this.
So it says 0.18 we reserve the right to maintain the plug in directory to the best of
our ability seems sane our intent is to enforce
these guidelines with as much fairness as humanly possible.
We do this to ensure overall plug in quality and the safety of their users.
To that end, we reserve the following rights
seems reasonable
for number one
to update these guidelines at any time. Very low. Right. Fine.
Number two to disable or remove any plug in from the directory,
even for reasons not explicitly covered by the guidelines.
Ok.
-- Well, because
-- somebody will find something new to do. Right.
Sure. Sure, for sure.
And I agree with that. And that's probably the line that was used here
three to grant exceptions to allow developers time to address issues,
even security related.
OK.
Then to remove developer access to a plug in in lieu of a new active developer,
I mean that's a good one. Honestly, we've seen issues with N PM there
and then lastly, it says to make changes to a plug in without developer consent
in the interest of public safety.
Now, now here's the kicker in return,
we've promised to use those rights sparingly and with as
much respect as possible for both end users and developers.
So can I just summarize what you just said?
Which is
we own all the plugins? You submit?
-- Basically.
-- No, not, basically we own all the plugins you submit.
-- I mean,
-- that is, well, that's on the, the hosted plugins directory.
-- No,
-- no, but we own them in the sense of like we have control and we own them, own them.
Like let's not like we'll pretend that you have ownership and control
but
-- you don't.
-- Well,
that's what happens when you host a registry.
Like
same
thing with N PM N PM
owns everything on N PM functionally.
And yet we somehow play this game of pretending like
they don't like somehow the developers have final ownership.
I don't, I don't think it's a game.
I think if you look at like how it has worked historically,
it has generally been the developers do their thing
and then they submit things to the registry
and then the registry publishes whatever the developer did
this historically has worked because everybody actually does make
a good faith effort to behave reasonably well.
Wordpress has not broken any laws. They probably haven't even broken any rules.
-- Well, especially when the rules are, we can do whatever we want basically.
-- Right.
And I don't think
this is,
I don't think they're going to stop down the
path they're on because they have no reason to,
you know, there,
it's conceivable there would be enough community push back that they might have to,
but I suspect not because I don't think they care.
Well, the the challenge too is like,
OK, for example, let's say all the paid plug in developers go OK?
This is a potential problem because like it turns out press can just yoink all of our,
I'm sure they've all done that already.
But the thing is what can they actually do
the OK. So this comes back to your snarky. What are you going to do?
It's not meant to be snarky. I'm just genuinely asking.
-- No,
-- no, here's so here's how this works, right? This is
any time you are existing in an ecosystem, this is true of like,
let's say the Windows Universe.
A great example is how many times have there been some sort of
product or add on to like Microsoft Windows or Os X or whatever?
And then one day Microsoft or Apple are like, oh,
we're just going to add that functionality right into the product.
Actually, you just used the word ecosystem.
This isn't an ecosystem, this is like a managed ecosystem.
This isn't like a free market ecosystem.
With this is a managed like owned by somebody ecosystem.
Well,
but that's different because like open source is an ecosystem in the sense
of I can download Linux from a million places and I can install
hell, I don't even need to use GNU, right?
I could use her.
But this is not that like ultimately, we
just owns all of this. This is like
this is like calling a forest a forest when it's one of
those forests in Germany where all the trees are 10 ft apart,
like perfectly spaced.
That's not a forest. That's a tree farm.
I, I think you are correct. Oh, a tree farm. That's a really good analogy.
-- I think that's exactly it.
-- Right.
And like apple like, yeah, they, they added,
they made the password manager first class
-- application in IO 18. Now, thankfully, finally,
-- that's a great example.
Like that's going to hurt the existing password managers,
the organizations for sure. Unquestionably.
Now you,
I think you raise a very good point with
the tree farm analogy because I think historically,
when we exist in a universe,
be it like Apple or Wordpress or Microsoft or Aws or whatever, like look at,
look at all the Aws products.
I mean, Amazon
has notoriously murdered competition because they were like, oh,
that's a good idea.
-- We'll build that
-- well, but that's how that's their cultural DNA of.
Like I literally remember buying
No, no II I want you to.
That's not the point. The point is
that I think we as
like tech practitioners
have failed to recognize the difference between like
an open source or just truly free universe where you
can kind of do what you want and have your things
available versus
the I am living inside someone else's sandbox. Like video games are a great example.
If you're not publishing on Steam,
you don't have an audience.
But at the same time,
Steam gets to tell you exactly what to do and they get to take 30% of your,
your money and what are you going to do about it?
-- You can't do anything about it because you're living in their sandbox
-- well,
and this comes back to the whole like these sort of social
contracts and systems work when everybody behaves well and nobody kind of
used
to grab too much money, too fast,
but then they start to fall apart.
And we're seeing that in the real world where, you know,
wages have stagnated for the majority of people,
food prices have gone up quite a lot and the rich are much,
much richer than they used to be.
And
I am now seeing the social contract fall apart in Canada like
and one extreme example is Quebec and I thought this was Beaverton.
But no,
it was a CBC article where the Quebec government is literally advocating that
healthy people don't need family doctors.
So like
if basically, if you're generally healthy, you don't get to have a family doctor,
you can go use emergency when you need it.
And that way there will be more family doctor resources for 60 months.
And of course, all of us are like, but that's kind of how you stay healthy
anyway,
I digress
but this is showing that this kind of whole like as long as wordpress.com
in return,
we promised to use these rights sparingly and with as
much respect as possible for both end users and vs
like when they take out some like Chinese backdoor thing, everybody's like, OK,
yeah, that's reasonable.
Or you know, a developer throws a tantrum and refuses to fix the security bug.
And wordpress is like, well, we're fixing it anyways when you calm down,
come back and we'll talk or else you're gonna this to somebody else
again. Everybody's kind of like, OK, that's,
that's better. But in this case, it's kind of like, whoa
pause because I think a lot of it, it's, it's like
people
ignore that these things are possible until you kind of
shove it in their face like the car hacking thing,
like until reporters in the car and the
car accelerates while their foot's on the brake,
they're like, oh,
and I think that's what's happening here
is people are getting more and more examples
of these PP and N PM ecosystems having to do these things
or doing them because they want to, in the case of wordpress.com.
And I think they're beginning to get a little
nervous because they realize how little control they have.
I
-- mean, that's fair. That's fair.
-- Again.
I, I don't say this to be snarky but I'm like,
well,
what's like the alternative of building it all and rolling
it all myself so that I have that control.
That
is a lot of work and introduces risk because I'm not necessarily as good at this as
-- like 100 for
-- sure,
for educated professionals.
Now, now here's a better question than,
than mindlessly discussing what we can do about it,
which is virtually nothing right now.
But does every ecosystem
eventually bend
into this space or eventually the ecosystem ha does something incredibly
stupid because they just quite frankly lost touch with reality.
-- I
-- think the first step is you haven't ecosystem that represents value
because there's, there's like people use the ecosystem because there's value in it
and you
try to capture that value because they want to pay their rent and not do it for free.
That is also true.
Like you work for a commercial open
source company.
Yes, that is correct. You guys could do this for free.
Uh We give away a lot of stuff we do
-- and you'd also like to be able to buy food
-- for. I do
-- enjoy eating food.
-- Yes.
Because, sadly, that's how capitalism works.
And
I would argue we are much better off with Anchor
being a commercial company offering a good,
like,
high quality commercial product and being able to put
a lot more resourcing into the open source side
because you, you guys are paid enough money to eat food and, you know,
-- that's how
-- it works.
But people forget that.
Like, if you had to do this as a hobby,
you might only spend five or 10 hours a week doing it, whereas it's your job.
-- So you can spend 40 hours a week doing like with
-- 40 hours a week. If only.
So, then people forget this, right?
Like there's a big difference between five or 10 hours a week of kind of
sometimes work versus this is my short time job and I get resourcing and,
and help and they send me a laptop and,
well, look,
this is part of the Wordpress story as well
without automatic funding all of the wordpress developers.
-- There basically wouldn't be a Wordpress today.
-- Wordpress was ok
before them,
but wordpress after them was like, it just works
like it's so easy.
And
I remember looking at,
I was hesitant to buy wordpress.com.
So I was like, oh, I don't want to spend money on this. And then I did the math. Ok.
It's $300 a year. That's less than three hours of my time.
I pay like $50 a year for our site.
But I have the cheapest possible option, which is the other challenge. Yes.
I can't even run a vps for that amount. Not counting my time. I know. Right.
That's why I did that because it was obvious and makes sense.
Well, and more to the point,
how much value can I really add to patching a
server running wordpress and doing a bunch of other stuff?
And the answer is none.
Yeah. Right. Right.
Oh, and that's the other reason I use, uh,
my lights sale instances because I needed to do
something that wordpress.com didn't want to let me do.
That's fair.
And then I got rid of it. Turns out I didn't need it, but
I ended up using tax.
So, which is,
it is a taxonomy plug in for wordpress that puts all your
stuff into a taxonomy and it makes it really easy to,
um,
basically it takes everything intelligently which makes it,
I get that nice word cloud and I can navigate my stuff,
you know.
Well, if you have a lot of like this thing, I have, you know, I generate 30 posts a day.
So
if I ever want to find them again, good luck. Got you. Got you.
But back to this, I think the challenge is, it's like a,
to use a parasite as an analogy.
If a parasite latches onto a host and, like, just sips a little bit of blood
and it's a little itchy.
Ok. Kind of annoying. But, you know, whatever,
not the end of the world.
And maybe it does something useful like those birds that eat the bugs off of hippos
or whatever.
-- Like, I don't think they're parasites though.
-- They're symbio.
And that's the point is you can also be a symbio
where, like wordpress.com for the sake of argument.
Offering the,
the plans at 50 bucks a year or 300 bucks a year is cheap enough that it's actually,
well, it's just, it's, I'm financially better off paying them than doing it myself.
And if you do a lot of that, you'll, people will be generally happy with you, right?
But then you start turning the thumb screws and like
trying to squeeze out that last bit of juice,
like a perfect example.
Ok?
This blows my mind because Windows is primarily
a corporate platform that also ships to consumers because
they make a lot of money.
And also they want to hold the gaming market
and some other stuff considering the value of Windows
licenses in the corporate world especially and to some degree the consumer world,
the fact that they're trying to shove advertising into the consumer version,
there's no way it's making enough money to make it worth the
backlash and yet they keep doing it like it blows my mind.
That's a really good example I think. And that's probably part of this is,
let's say
Wordpress did manage to
ma make WP engine look bad. Let's say like, what's the, what's the end game here?
-- Are they trying to get their customers? Are they trying to shut them
-- down?
Like half a billion dollars a year in total revenue?
-- Like it's
-- a, you're not going to capture it all because you know what I mean?
And I think the windows example of putting ads
in the operating system are another good example where
this feels like a very short sighted behavior
that if you actually like graph it out for, let's say a couple of years,
you're going to be like, this is incredibly stupid and no one should be doing it.
-- Do you
-- know much junk?
I've had to turn off in the windows interface to get like
it kept showing me random NFL results on the task bar.
I literally quit running windows because I'm just like I'm done.
And you know, it's funny,
I used to run it for games.
So I just switched to Linux and I'm like, I'm going to figure out if wine works.
There is a thing available now called the Heroic launcher,
which will launch like Epic Games and Steam Games and some other a bunch of, well,
Steam runs pretty well these days.
So I don't, I don't use it for that, but like
this thing is top notch and like per game,
it has very specific settings for like wine and proton and things like that.
Like
I'm like, holy crap. I don't need windows at all anymore.
And I, honest to God have not run windows in over a year now, which is marvelous.
I suspect windows 11 will be my last windows.
Although it sounds like it will be the last windows for everybody.
They've said that like five times
and,
but the thing is the Mac hardware is finally fast enough and cheap enough
that I wouldn't have to spend like 20 grand to get the equivalent hardware
as I can get in a PC for like
towards
the cost.
Like I just bought a new Mac mini and that eight extra,
like I went from eight gigs of ra M to 16 gigs of ra M because I'm not a maniac.
That makes a big difference.
That was 240 bucks,
240 bucks for eight gigs of ra M versus I just bought about 100 and 28 gigs of ra M.
It's
-- 200
-- and 70 bucks.
-- Now, the game makers just need to support Mac
-- Os.
Well, the
apple silicon.
That's true. That's true.
That's a big difference.
But this is,
this is why
the work steam has been doing or Valve has been doing
with the steam deck and things like that is amazing.
And thank goodness, even though I don't have a steam deck,
I benefit from their hard work.
So thank you Valve for working with Linux.
So, but back to the Wordpress thing.
What do the one thing that really amuses me is wordpress
uh WP Engine sorry is kind of the
like they're just
a free rider and all this whatever kind of not the nicest people,
not the worst people.
They should be the villain in this story
and they,
they managed to not shoot themselves in the foot and keep
their mouth shut and not end up looking like complete jerks,
-- which I applaud them because
-- they probably listen to their lawyer.
I promise you if the Wordpress lawyer hasn't quit.
Like I can only imagine the number of emails and voicemails.
Well, not emails, they wouldn't send emails. But
yeah,
I can't imagine
so. Yeah. No, this whole thing, like again, I don't mean to be snarky but literally
the thought of having to, uh,
moving all the content is relatively
places have gotten good at that.
-- The challenge is all the plugins. I want all my plugins to work.
-- Yeah.
You keep saying that we know
we get it.
That's plugins.
And the thing is the thing that's compatible with all the Wordpress plugins is,
well, Wordpress,
-- that's correct.
-- And
if you built something completely compatible with
wordpress to run all the plugins,
it would be probably a lot less work to just fork,
Wordpress and maintain your own fork of it.
Maybe I'm actually surprised no one has forked it yet.
I feel like a Wordpress fork has got to be imminent
just due to everything going on.
It's,
-- yeah, I'm
-- not saying it'll work. I just feel
like, well, it's, it's,
I feel like a fork is one of those classic things where people think it
a, they think the fork will accomplish things that it won't accomplish.
And b it's actually a lot of maintenance and work more so than they thinking.
Yeah,
there's not a lot of forks that have
-- been particularly successful because
-- here's the thing.
You don't just have to fork wordpress.
Well,
you also apparently now have to fork
all the freaking wordpress plug-in stuff because they're
gonna block
you and lock you out of it.
That
infrastructure is easier than it used to be. I will give you that.
Like, it's still hard though.
But compared to 20 or compared to 15 years ago when they started, like, for sure,
like you and I could build something like 10% of pipe pie in an afternoon.
I don't know about that.
And it would suck, but it would be, it would, but it would ship a lot of packages.
Right. Whereas 20 years ago we couldn't even,
-- I could
-- run a web server with packages on it.
-- But I don't know,
-- years ago we couldn't even dream of it.
Uh
-- Like the fact that it's even possible now is kind of amazing to me.
-- It is. It is. So,
I
man, I don't know, I feel like this is just
this whole story is bananas. I don't know. Where this is going to go.
It is from my perspective, as a a human existing in this space,
I feel like this is a left pad style incident.
I would suggest my closing thought is there's a lot of in theory,
benevolent dictator for life is an open source.
You know, Leis
Torvalds, Guido Van Rossum.
And we generally don't hear about them unless they either do an
-- exceptionally great job like Linus Torvalds or Daniel Steinberger or
-- no,
we never hear about Linus doing good work.
We only ever heard when he was a massive a hole.
-- Ok.
-- Well, he's doing a lot less now.
And I was about to say that the second part though is we'll
ever hear about them when they massively mess up and say stupid things
or
make some decision that everybody hates,
which there aren't very many of those. I can't think of too many
man of decisions. Everyone hates from Python or Linux
or even like curl, nothing springs to mind.
-- They've
-- done a reasonably good job of not annoying people,
which at internet scale is pretty magical
because, you know,
I could say I like vanilla ice cream and somebody
listening to the show will take offense to it.
-- Vanilla ice cream is like the worst one, man.
-- Come
-- on.
-- It's my favorite. It's good.
But, um,
I think in this case, I'm hoping
that kind of like
a lot of situations where the company might reel in the
CEO a bit because that has been a common truth.
I don't think they can though Matt's too,
he, he, he is automatic,
-- but
-- that's what I'm kind of wondering here.
Is, is there anybody who can stand up to him?
-- I
-- don't
-- think so. If they could, they probably would have by now.
Well, I'm sure his lawyers would have told him not to speak about this in public.
You don't have to listen to your lawyers though.
If you don't have a board or anyone that can hold it over your head, you know.
So, I don't know. I don't, it'll
see. Here's the thing, here's the thing, right?
This is, I think how I'm going to end this show is every week.
This feels like it crosses a new line of, like,
dumber and weirder than I could imagine.
The word you're looking for is normalized deviancy.
Like the Challenger disaster where they kept launching
in kind of colder and colder weather and then
-- one day they,
-- that's fair went, boom.
-- That's true.
-- That's exactly what this is.
And II, I feel like next week some,
I think even weirder is going to happen. I'm actually glad.
So, Kurt and I are recording this on the same day.
I'm going to release the show, which I haven't done in a really long time.
So, like, I have several hours of,
a lot of work ahead of me right now to actually get the show out quickly.
But hopefully the thing doesn't explode
-- and that's
-- just it.
I'm like, if we would wait a week to put this out,
this whole conversation would be completely invalid by the time it came out,
I suspect.
And there's nothing more terrifying than being in that
sort of situation and it's just like no one,
like
I have enough stupid crazy stuff going on right now all around me.
Like I don't need wordpress the word.
-- Like
-- the whole reason I use wordpress is like, I turn it on,
I shove content into it
and people read the content and I don't have to spend
time fixing or maintaining it and it just freaking works.
-- And that's all I want.
-- I
know
-- it's anyway,
-- you know, that's all I want from most of my technology. Now.
That's all I want from everything. Like I want everything to be born.
Everything should be boring. Like the excitement of my life should be watching
like a, a, the deadpool movie or something. That should be my excitement.
But it's not, that's the most boring thing.
Yeah, I, I hate that.
That's why I have a pluck server is because
stuff goes randomly missing from streaming services or youtube.
And my poor son is like,
where's Pink Panther? And I'm like,
Reed Hastings killed him, son.
That's where he went.
But anyway. All right. All right. I'm like
this whole thing. I don't,
I don't even know what to say.
I'm just gonna end the show because I don't think there's anything
good we can even say here other than just like madness.
Well, I think part of the mature thing for me is to accept that as,
as bad as the Wordpress situation gets.
It's probably still better than me trying to do it all myself.
And that's sort of the reality of it. Like there's burritos are a good example.
What
I can make a good burrito. I,
there's like most of the burritos in Edmonton are terrible.
They taste like wet cardboard. They are not good. There's like,
there's like three good Mexican ish restaurants here that
serve a decent burrito and it's not cheap.
And so I just kind of have to accept that my choices
are either pay a lot of money for a good burrito.
I no longer buy the cheap burritos because they,
they literally just don't taste like anything.
And
I can't be bothered to make the burrito myself because to make a good burrito,
you know, you're talking seven or eight fillings.
-- That's
-- a
lot of
work.
It's a lot of work,
right? I'm literally gonna make a Mexican meal tonight. I'm making rice.
I'm reheating some corn. Um uh Flautas, the little, the little like micro to,
I love those things and I'm going to cook. Um
God, forgive me, I'm gonna make some chicken fingers.
Your Mexican food.
I know, right? Because I realize I have nothing else meat wise in the freezer
and
it's not going to be great, but you know, it's food,
it love salt on it.
-- That's fine.
-- You live in Canada and you're, you're German, like
right
next,
I'm gonna give you a link to put in the show
notes that is totally topical and also fits into the,
the package arriving for you.
You have to, no one knows what any of that means.
Oh, sorry. So, about once a year now. Kind of a tradition before Christmas.
I mailed Josh a package of food
of like weird stuff I can't get in the
-- United States and
-- it's not just Canadian stuff like,
uh, one year it was cheesy and Coffee Crisp.
Uh,
another year it was um, uh, Italian Rio tuna packed in oil and like a German like
Renee uh fish, which is my favorite brand because
I,
I actually been to the Island of
Rugen.
It's a very nice island, very cold water.
You gotta get this story.
Uh, I sent
Josh this year a package of, um, cup of soups from Cnor
and from a Dutch brand who I can't even remember the name of. But
Kor has a recipe website,
including Mexican recipes.
I mean, of course they do.
No, no, no, but there's, but you don't go to the American website.
You go to the German one and the stuff that they sort of say is Mexican food.
How exciting
-- it, it's just mind blowing
-- like it's just so
off the walls. Insane.
That
sounds
-- amazing.
-- I love
it.
It's like
bratwurst tacos or something like it's just
we call that fusion, it's fusion cooking.
-- Yeah, exactly. There you go. All right.
-- I'm ending this show.
I'm ending it because you can't get weirder than this. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you for ever listening. Go to social security podcast.com. Head up the show
on Susy Podos
says podcast. Hashtag on Mastodon. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks
-- everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.