Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime.
Am I supposed to talk or?
Hey, I'm Josh.
Oh, you were gesturing at me? Yes, of course. I saw that through my
speakers
but I guess Happy Cyber Monday. Kurt.
Yeah. Yeah, I, I cheated and did all my shopping on Friday
on Black Friday.
Cyber Monday.
But you live in Canada. So, do you have Black Friday?
Yes, we do. Yeah, we celebrate Black Friday and Cyber Monday
after the fake Thanksgiving, right?
Yeah.
That's not last week. Too close to Christmas, man. It's just crazy.
So.
-- Well, so I think we kind of have a special Black Monday episode.
-- Cyber
Monday.
You could call it black.
I think
by the time we're done with it, I think Black Monday will be appropriate.
That's my childhood coming out.
Uh So, yeah, so it's Cyber Monday,
which means we're all supposed to be shopping online.
-- Um, more than we usually do
-- I
think. You mean
we're all supposed to be having our identities and credit
cards stolen online as we purchase crap we don't need.
Yeah. Yeah.
So
what, what I love about this is if you Google it, there's like
a ton of sites ranging from like what you
would expect like uh say trend Micro or Tom's guide
ranging all the way to like NBC
uh talking about
uh safety tips for cyber Monday.
Uh specifically, I guess with shopping online,
-- I would
-- expect everyone to want to get in
on this just because security is super exciting now.
And so Lord forbid you miss out on, on a hip exciting story. Right.
Yeah. Yeah.
And uh, so anyways, so we've got,
well, basically here's my thought, I'm gonna read you. What I think are some of the,
I, I think that they're well meaning security tips.
But what really gets me is, I mean,
I in general a security tip, either you use it or you don't,
it's not just one day of the year.
Right. Right.
And, and well, ok, so I'm gonna take issue with the concept of security tips,
but that won't stop us from, I, I assume
going through reasonable and not terrible advice, but here's the deal is
you shouldn't need security tips
to stay safe
and let's face it.
Two people aren't going to follow this stuff
because they either don't care or they're gonna forget
or, or whatever. Right. There's a million reasons.
And so
telling people like if you do these things, you'll be more safe than if you don't, is,
is madness.
It, we have to make this stuff. So you don't need tips
to not let yourself on fire. Right.
Well, I think one of the challenges, not all these tips are technical in nature.
Right. Some of them are sort of more processed.
Like what, what this kind of reminds me of is, and this is a terrible thing.
Uh,
in the last two months here in Edmonton we've had
two pedestrians run over by city buses in marked crosswalks.
Uh, and in one case, the bus driver didn't know he ran over somebody and he kept going.
I'm
not,
it's terrible.
And I mean, you know, here I am, I'm,
I'm at the stage right now where I'm teaching my kids like how to cross the road
and,
you know, normally it's like, look left, look right, like, or a four way, look like,
look behind and in front, like, look all the ways
and then proceed when it's safe.
But now, you know, there's, I,
it's kind of like those Halloween candy scare stories.
It's like, but,
you know, buses might run over you.
Well, no, apparently this actually does happen and it's happened,
like I said twice in the last two months.
Apparently these buses have a bit of a blind spot or something in the front of the bus,
which is
like,
I don't understand.
Yeah, exactly. So,
you know, I'm having to,
I'm having to teach my kids to cross the road the way I cross it, which, you know,
having lived in Europe is, look all the ways.
Take a step, look all the ways, you know,
you look all the ways all the time or you get run over.
Right. Right.
-- You know, but North America people don't do that.
-- So,
so my, my joke actually is, is before you go on,
I, I always say that I look both ways before I cross the street
in London
and Boston
and especially in one way streets
for, for very different reasons. Right.
Because London, obviously they drive on the wrong side of the road
and in Boston
everyone drives like crazy people.
Yeah.
So I think the reality is like,
either you do these things kind of all the time and then hopefully, you know,
because what, what,
what I really wonder about is how many people almost got run over by a city bus.
But we're paying attention enough that they, you know, dodged at the last second.
Right.
You know, because I,
I can't imagine these two incidences are the only ones that have happened, like,
or would have happened this year.
-- But anyways, so,
-- so let me, is the city doing something about this?
Have they decided they're gonna somehow make the buses safer or they just be like,
whatever,
it's, it's a bit of a outcry because the first, uh, you know, the most recent one was,
I believe it was a 13 year old girl
and, you know, obviously people are a bit annoyed about this.
Um There's talk of this blind spot on the buses in the front
which even if there's a blind spot on the front of the bus,
like, as a driver, my understanding is like,
it's literally your job not to run over people, right?
Like, I'm pretty sure that's in the job description or a part of the driving test,
you know,
don't run over people like literally.
So I, I don't know what's gonna happen, but obviously, you know,
I mean, it's a statistical aberration, right? Because
this doesn't hopefully happen that often. But,
you know, two in two months is obviously people are a little bit, you know,
concerned.
That's terrible.
Yeah. So, and that's kind of what these tips remind me of, right?
Is like, well, if these are good security tips,
then shouldn't you do that all the time and not just Cyber Monday?
All right. Let, let's hear a man.
II I can't wait.
So
now we should say for the enjoyment of the audience that I, I have no prior knowledge
of these, what I assume are fabulous security tips.
So I, I, I'm very excited. I can't wait to hear what you have to say.
All right. So, uh well, let's go with this one.
Buy apps only from legitimate stores like Apple Store and Google Play.
Ok.
I can you buy
some
on your phone?
I know that's what I was thinking. It's like,
unless you've jail broken your phone, in which case you're, you're obviously
there.
Android
stuff. Actually, you can side load apps fairly easily. So, I guess you could
conceivably
trick someone into doing that. But you're still,
man,
-- I would
-- like, I know from my Mac,
I buy stuff directly from vendors that don't sell through the Apple store.
Like, for example, um,
uh, the firewall, little snitch. Right. Great product.
And as far as I know it's not in the store,
right?
Yeah. Could they be talking about?
I don't want that.
What else you got?
This doesn't make sense.
Don't buy
from somewhere else.
Don't buy apps from a guy like on the street, I guess, you know, a guy, I just,
I have this mental image of him opening up a trench coat full of like, you know,
QR codes
lining the inside, right?
Uh So here's a great one. This is my all time favorite.
Uh Don't use free public Wi
Fi to do your shopping.
Oh, man, I'm always torn over free public Wi Fi. It's,
you can tell people not to use it all you want, but like, like
let's face it, man.
Everyone does it. I bet you do it right.
So my I one of my I SPS Shaw, the cable company, they also run this thing called Shaw
Xo or Shaw
Open.
So basically, you know, if you buy a cable modem from them with Wi Fi capabilities,
boom, you're part of the, if you're a business.
You're part of their public hotspot monstrosity, right. Which,
you know, so, like, 95% of the time I don't even realize I'm using
whatever wifi because, like, my phone just
logs into it automatically. Right?
Because I've told it to, like, you know,
it's like every time I walk into a Starbucks anywhere on the planet, it's like, oh,
I'm on Wi Fi,
you know.
-- Um, so you join once and
-- then? No, no, here's a question though. Ok, so
we love to demonize public wi Fi.
But
does anyone have any statistics on how often this stuff actually gets hijacked?
And your data is stolen off of it? I mean,
I, I, if I'm just gonna guess,
I bet it's not that often.
Well,
you need physical proximity or you need to
have hacked the access point in which case,
like you're gonna hack an entire is P's worth of access points
and just hijack
you could, you could hijack one shop,
right? It's not out of the question. But I think
when you think about how many, there's got to be literally millions,
probably tens of millions of access points
in, say just North America,
I'd be more concerned about situations where you're at somewhere,
like say a Starbucks and you join, there's like two Starbucks wifi.
I mean, because the thing is you can,
you can spoof the SS ID and you can spoof the Mac address and everything.
So if I just walk around spoofing that I'm a Starbucks coffee shop,
wi fi access point,
like 95% of all the phones and tablets within
range of me are gonna automatically join me,
right? Because they have in the past
um
So on this, I ascribe personally, I ascribe to the whole sort of
uh what is that Google project called again?
Uh I wanna say New Horizons or Google,
the thing where they're basically, they,
they no longer believe in a network perimeter.
Everything is like
untrusted essentially,
you know.
And so the idea is, for example, like,
I don't,
I don't really actually go to any websites
anymore that are not http s encrypted because,
you know, it's just not a good idea, especially if I'm gonna spend money there.
But, but you can say that,
but I guarantee you if, if, say my parents
open up a laptop
and it brings them to the Google login page, they're just going to log in,
right? Regardless, they're not going to look at the URL.
Yeah, I,
well, the thing is there's no way to manage this properly, right?
Like my phone just automatically flips on to Starbucks wifi or onto
the shaw or on to, you know, it was funny actually when I was on my last trip
because I've been through some of these airports before
my phone just automatically
joined.
Yeah.
You know, like in Chicago and in DC and in, um,
Toronto,
it just automatically, you know, jumped on the Wi Fi because, hey, I know this one
so
-- well,
-- but you can even say that
the cellular networks aren't necessarily trustworthy because I,
I read a report I remember at, at Black Hat.
Was it Black Hat? No, Defcon.
At defcon. The number of three G towers like doubled,
-- which is clearly not because they added more capacity.
-- Right.
Yeah. No.
So, so for our listeners that aren't aware,
there's a couple of different cell standards
and so there's a couple of different cell standards and the um
sort of the one of the more popular ones is three G.
It was a former, you know,
global standard still is a standard obviously.
Um but the encryption used for it is incredibly weak by current standards.
So as an attacker,
um if you, if you want to spoof
a tower and be able to, you know,
monkey with the encryption three G is a great way to go because
you can basically do it in real time on a modern laptop.
So, yeah, I,
I don't know, I mean, personally this is why I do the majority of my shopping online
at home.
-- Right? It's just one less thing to worry about.
-- Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
But you and I are probably not normal,
but I guess,
well, so
you know what else though? So here's, here's the other half of that though.
So let's say
I go to Starbucks
and I connect to a mini
malicious access point
and I buy things
and my credit card gets stolen.
I just get your credit card.
Right. I mean, let's
face it.
There's limited damage that happens here now. Yes.
If you're doing your, your online banking and your bank account gets, you know,
robbed.
Ok, that's bad.
But
it,
you know, I,
I'm
gonna
give
my
own cyber
tip
your
own.
Now, I haven't read it yet,
but this is, you should probably shop at sites
that you've already shopped at and have.
And this is the funny part
that store your personal data because
my one thought would be, you know, I don't care if my credit card gets stolen,
I can get a new number in like five minutes.
Right?
You phone the company, you say my credit card was hacked or stolen and they're like,
yeah, it's canceled.
Here's a new one
before
you
do.
Exactly.
But you can't change your personal info, like your name and address,
like without moving and filling out a lot of paperwork.
Right.
So my thinking is like, for example, if I shop at Amazon,
Amazon will never prompt me to enter my name
or shipping address or anything because I already have
and, and they've, I've told them to remember it.
That's actually fantastic advice. And it may be the only piece of usable advice
that we're going to talk about today.
So,
-- congrats
-- preregister with the vendors you want to do business with.
You don't have to.
That's true because I always, I guess I always view it as just
ease,
but it, it really does add a certain level of safety because I'm never actually
physically typing in
any personal information
-- when
-- I use
a
lot of
entered
about once every,
essentially whenever I move,
I have to re enter my, my address and my billing address and that's it.
And then whenever my credit card rolls over, I, I put into my new credit card number.
So about every two years, maybe three years at Amazon, I,
I enter some information but apart from that, I don't.
So if they asked me for info, I would be a little suspicious.
I'd give anything for one year.
Although I'm,
I'm going on like probably four months without
having my credit card stolen at this point.
So
I consider that a success.
That's awesome.
Uh So here's a, here's my uh favorite one
-- only shop on sites which start with HTTP S in the address bar.
-- That's good advice.
-- This
-- means they're secure.
That's bad advice. So,
yeah, see, and this is one of those terms where like for you and me,
the word secure has a lot of meaning and for the average person,
you know, it's, it's like whatever, right? And
so to me it's fundamentally you shouldn't shop at a
place that does not use HTTP S because it's free now
right to get it.
Yeah.
Well,
or cloud flare.com and they'll even serve your content
for you and make it faster for free.
Um
And let's encrypt is uh for those of you who
don't know let's encrypt is uh Electronic Frontier foundation.
So the eff nice people,
uh they basically decided that the whole
certificate authority hierarchy and the way that they
uh the amount of money they charge for these things is a bit obscene and,
and it sometimes is a bit obscene.
So they basically got a
certificate that is trusted by your web browser, be it Chrome Firefox Safari,
whatever
and they issue what are called domain validated certificates.
So this basically means that all they validate is the domain name
that the person is asking for for the certificate,
which dirty little secret is like 99.8 or 9% of all
the certificates currently in existence anyways, right? Very few people have
what's called extended validation.
So if you go to like paypal, you know, you get that giant Green Bar saying,
but this is paypal as opposed to just the name is correct.
So in my mind, if,
if an online shop can't be bothered to even implement free security,
that takes about 15 minutes,
you really don't want to shop there.
Are there, man, I don't think I've even seen a
dodgy website that doesn't have HTTP S
you know why?
Because especially with online shopping, they're all consolidated now, right?
They're all like Etsy or ebay or um like I
buy stuff on amazon.com all the time from who knows?
Like, I don't know who it is because it's like third party reseller or whatever.
It's cheap.
II, I,
I, a couple of years ago will say, purchase some dodgy video game equipment.
Ok. We'll just leave it at that
and,
and I bought a prepaid credit card to do this because I
wasn't typing in a real credit card number into the site.
But they still had hetps man.
And, and the stuff did, it did get it delivered for what it's worth.
So I wasn't, I wasn't stolen from at least.
Yeah. Well, that's the thing too.
I mean, the Attackers are going to do HTTP S because,
uh, I don't know if you saw recently but I, um,
people, you know, like, for example, like ebay.com.
Well, what about like Ebay, like ebey.com? How many people wouldn't notice that?
That's not ebay.com, you know, or,
or some of those, uh,
unicode characters where you've got like those funky GS that look like normal GS,
you know, they are not
the normal G.
Um, but I mean, again,
that would take more of a targeted attack or some spectacularly poor typing
for you to end up there. So again, I wouldn't worry too much about that.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, that's fair.
So, to me it's more like I won't eat at a restaurant that doesn't have bathrooms,
like a sit down restaurant that doesn't have bathrooms.
Does such a thing exist.
Yeah, there's a Mexican place with really good food here.
So they're an exception to the rule,
but they do not have a public washroom, which is technically not 100% legal.
But
in general, like, especially when I'm in larger cities, you know,
to me it's a, it's a signaling indicator if they like part of it is,
I want to know that they have a bathroom and that they're like, you know,
because most i most jurisdictions require, if you serve food
and drink, you have to have a bathroom available. Right.
Sure.
But also it's like, because I like to see the bathroom,
you know,
um, great example I walked into, uh, there's a bar near my house from the outside.
It looks beyond terrible.
You walk inside and it's like, oh, ok, it's clean,
you walk into the bathrooms, they're spotless and they smell nice
and it turns out the food there is awesome.
And, and
what is the point of this story again?
Well, so basically it's,
it's one of those things where I want to know in advance whether or not,
you know, they're good or bad guys, like, are they keeping it clean?
Are they taking care?
Right.
And, and that to me is what HTTP S is, is if you can't even be bothered to do that,
then you're probably not keeping your bathroom clean and you're probably not,
you're probably keeping my credit card information on like a you know,
a text file on a public web server or something.
So,
I mean, like I said, though, I, I haven't seen a shop in forever that didn't have
HTTP S so let's,
let's move on to the second part of that though is the
thing, right? People doing the like fire sheep
style.
That
actually completely correct. Right. Absolutely.
Is if your man in the middle, someone could be stripping
the, the HTTP S off, you know,
essentially removing the TLS and serving you up things in plain text.
So,
so that, that's fair. That's fair. But let's talk about
the it's secure part
because I think a lot of people do kind of have that feeling of look,
it shows the lock everything's fine
when in reality
everything is not fine.
Perfect example, right? You go to my domain
cree.org
and it's HTTP S totally encrypted, secure great configuration, right?
Well, except that's the Cloud flare edge servers,
right? And from cloud flare to my servers, it's uh i it's encrypted, but
I think I have some of the lax settings on for some reason I should probably update it.
But,
you know, you don't know that that connection to the back end is secure and, you know,
especially with more and more traffic being
served through places like cloud flare.
I mean, it looks secure but is it,
who knows? That's a
good
point.
I guarantee you that.
Well, I mean, let me put it this way cloud flare offers a variety of options.
You can have uh like really strict ssl between cloud flare and your servers.
Like the certificates have to be all correct up to date
completely legit
all the way to. It's
like just old, plain old http with no encryption at all.
Right. Because
you know, some people can't offer that. Right.
So just because you're seeing http
all that means is that you're, you're definitely getting encryption
to their edge server.
Now,
whether or not their edge server is actually
like the server serving the content or is it
a service or is it like a load balancer? Like who knows?
Right. Right.
Right. So
to me, I
would say basically boils down to if you see HTTP run away,
it's definitely not secure.
But if you see htps, it may or may not be.
But even Google is starting to rank HTTP S search results higher than http.
So I think it's fair to say like
the, the death of HTTP is, is certainly
on the horizon.
I also wonder how much of that was prior to
certificates being free through places like Lutz and Crypt.
Because
one of the things uh that I've consistently seen with the bad guys,
they don't want to spend money
on things that they don't have to, right? Like
uh domain names, you know the back,
I don't know if you remember way back like 20 years ago,
you could actually get domain names for free.
Right. And of course, that led to a ton of abuse. So they started charging money,
but they had this idea of, and this is the, one of the,
as it turns out most stupid things ever uh for like
unanticipated effects
they had what was called domain test
tasting. Do you remember that?
Oh, that's where you could register a domain for free for like a day or something,
right.
Was it? No, you get a refund or
-- you basically,
-- I think it was about three or four days.
You could use the domain before you either had to pay or give it back.
And that's exactly what Attackers wanted was like, I want domains that are,
I only need them for like two or 34 days
and, and you know what they did to really cut down on that and make it
like, just to basically get rid of the problem,
they charge 25 cents,
right? And that's enough
to, to largely make the problem go away.
Now, now, I, I think though there, there's two sides to that is,
there's the people don't want to spend money angle,
but there's also
when bad guys spend money,
it leaves a trail.
Even if it's stolen credit cards or prepaid credit cards or whatever,
you're still leaving a trail behind. If you're doing something with that Bitcoin
anymore.
Not with Bitcoin. That's true. That's true. That
is being accepted at more.
Bitcoin has
a certain amount of traceability to the. Like, for example,
there's uh
there's the San Francisco. No, no, no.
But here, here's the point is so, you know, the San Francisco Municipal,
uh whatever it is had the ransomware attack and
they, they were supposed to send $73,000 in Bitcoin to a certain address.
And so some clever people were just watching the address
to see if it had been paid yet and,
and last I checked it had not
so like Bitcoin, I won't say it's anonymous.
It's better than a credit card, but there's still certainly
a certain amount of traceability. And so I think any time you're talking about money
there is,
it's never gonna be totally anonymous.
Well, maybe the cash, but we won't get into that today.
Bitcoin is not technically totally anonymous, but it's very close.
If you look at some of the Bitcoin washing sites where they,
they do what's called tumbling the Bitcoin.
So they basically break the Bitcoins up, break onto lots of loans.
Exactly.
Like,
so they basically take all these different transactions from all
these different people and basically put them through a blender
and then the stuff comes out and you have no idea, you know where it went basically,
although in theory,
you could track it down if you were sufficiently sophisticated.
Um,
yeah,
and, but at the same time, I suspect the people
the criminals are trying to avoid
are sufficiently sophisticated.
One would hope
-- so.
-- Anyway,
here's,
you know what I gotta say, this is actually a decent tip pay by credit card.
You'll have less liability in the event. Something goes wrong than with debit.
Absolutely. I, I know a ton of people
that have come to me and been like,
someone stole my debit card and I lost all my money and
the bank said it'll take a month to get it back.
And I'm like, yeah, you use your credit card, you know, they
just don't use your debit card.
I guess. Maybe these people don't have credit cards,
although you can get prepaid credit cards.
I don't know any, everyone I know who's had this happen to them,
they were just using their debit card for whatever reason and they had
credit cards and now they use them exclusively after they had their incident.
So
there's,
I mean, whatever, why someone who was doing this,
I suspect it's just they opened their wallet and they picked out which
thing was in front
and
what? Right. And, and that's just kind of how it was.
So, I,
it good advice. I don't think anyone can complain about that.
Well, I'm also wondering like, yeah, I guess, yeah,
I forget now that my debit card does have that long string of numbers on the front.
-- That is technically a credit card number format. So I guess it is a
-- credit card.
Yeah, I mean, basically,
ok,
I've actually never used it as such because that just strikes
me as a really terrible idea because that's not my money is
and here's what I love because it's sort of true, but it's such a pain.
Nobody will do it.
Uh,
sorry to give a spoiler,
but keep an eye on your bank account to spot unusual transactions early on.
I
mean, that's
sure.
Yeah. But who's gonna do that?
I do.
Um,
I am meticulous.
I can tell you where every penny I've spent for like the last 20 years is gone.
I guess if you, if you're using something like mint or those other money sites,
that would be a lot simpler.
No,
man, I'm hardcore.
I use G new cash,
which is like the most ridiculous train wreck of accounting software.
But the things I've been
using
it.
Yeah. Yeah.
It's still taken care of and I've been using it for so long at this point that I'm just,
I'm so invested into learning this program that I'm totally unwilling to change.
Even though I know there are alternatives that are magnitudes better out there.
This is the sunk cost fallacy at work right here.
-- Yeah.
Yeah, I was gonna, well, but it's true,
especially with the accounting records and legal records.
Like, once they're in there getting them out,
I honestly, I've never even investigated how hard it would be.
But, but the point is I think
regardless of Black or not Black Friday,
Black Monday, uh regardless of Cyber Monday or online fraud or whatever
it is wise to understand your finances and to pay attention to them.
-- Right.
-- I mean, that's just that, that's like the, the human 101. Right.
Yeah.
Uh, sorry, I'm just trying to find one of the more hilarious bits of information.
Sorry.
There's, there's like, it's weird, there's so many of these lists and they're all,
like, five or 10 or 12
and there's like, very,
like, there's a lot of overlap, sort of, but not really, it's really quite bizarre.
But anyways, uh, I can't find it right now,
but basically the one piece of advice was saying, use the vendor apps
don't use the web browser because the vendor has more
control over the app and thus it's more secure.
Like, like, you mean the Amazon app or
do they?
Yeah,
like, so, yeah, like, say the Amazon app on your phone, which you can buy stuff,
which I'm assuming it's just like a little bit of stuff wrapped around a web browser.
Probably un unless you have AAA Tesla
app that keeps your authentication in plain text
on disk. Right.
Yeah,
-- it's that,
-- that, that could be good advice.
I, I guess, I don't know enough about a lot of these apps to say one way or the other.
Oh, here's the weird thing.
So they, ah,
here it is fine vendors have more control over
their own apps than they do over mobile browsers
which often don't display the web address of the
sites to which you're giving your credit card information.
Well,
yeah, they do. They have like the address bar at the top.
And then, I mean, if you,
-- if you
-- use your phone
look at
the
form where it's going,
address
right
on my
phone,
you can see it but you have to
make, you have to do something to make it appear right.
-- Safari shows it all the time on
-- your
iphone
iphone. Yeah. Yeah, I'm looking at, I'm looking at it right now, like when you
select something. Yeah, I'm like just looking at it and
uh, when I scroll down the web page,
it kind of smooshes the address bar a bit but it still shows the address bar
and
an Android.
As soon as you kind of start scrolling around, the address bar disappears.
-- Oh, even if you, like, what happens if you pull the web page down,
-- then it comes back.
Oh, this is weird
when I go to my, my own personal website which is, you know, HTPS.
It shows the little lock but that's it for the icon.
I thought it would have showed it in green or something.
Um Oh, here's interesting.
It shows the address bar when my phone is like vertical but when I put my phone flat,
like to make it wider.
Uh, the address bar only shows if I like scroll the web page.
Like if I scroll all the way to the top and kind of do that pull down action.
Interesting.
So, ah, I never really paid attention to that before. Ok. So,
I think that's not the greatest advice, but at the same time
it's probably relatively harmless advice.
Assuming the app doesn't do something stupid.
Like, I don't know if you remember all those banking apps,
somebody looked into a few years ago
and found out, like, almost all of them were keeping your, like,
password in plain text,
which is just like the Tesla problem.
Yeah, exactly. So, you know,
oh, let's see. Let's, let's look for some Canadian tips. Oh, this is a great one.
Never send a check or cash in the mail.
See, I feel like that's not advice for Cyber Monday.
-- I feel like that's advice for life in general.
-- Human 101 advice
also. Isn't it illegal to mail cash?
I don't know if it's illegal. It's dumb.
Uh,
the
US postal service loses very little stuff.
They, they do. It's still dumb.
Well, no, no, here's the problem with, with cash though.
And, and I've actually been bitten by this in a handful of times where
my kids will have some event. They're in a club or a sport or whatever.
And they're like, yeah, we need, like, five bucks and I'll just be like,
here's five bucks.
Right.
And I give it to him then a week later, like, hey, they give me five bucks and I'm like,
dude, I handed you $5 last week.
He said, well, I didn't, it's not written down. I'm like, oh crap.
-- And I just pay him again because it's
-- not
your video on your iphone or on your phone
-- or
-- just, like, find, like, send them money another way.
Even this is actually a place where checks are superior to cash
except for the minor.
Like, I can steal your money when I have a copy of your check thing.
Yeah.
And you have to pay like two bucks to cash a check.
Uh, not here. It's still pretty much free in the US.
Guess what? It would cost me to get 50 checks printed from my bank.
And I'm talking about the super generic checks with like
-- the cheapest checks I can get from my bank.
-- 50 checks.
Yeah, that's the smallest number they'll do.
-- I actually
-- need to order new checks and I order them in batches of 100
it cost me $13.
Oh, here my bank charges $53 for 50 checks.
Yeah, they really don't want you using checks
and I, I won't do. You can email money. You can text money in Canada now.
I
can
text you my worst thing ever. I, I hate checks.
They, they, I, I loathe them.
I refuse to use them
and like everybody I deal with now it's like, what's your email address?
Ok, I will email you the money and they're like what you can do that. I'm like, yeah,
so I find
people use
it,
have some sort of,
-- uh,
-- the,
uh,
the, uh, uh, well, technically it's branded through interact.
They're the people that do the debit cards
here in Canada.
-- So it's kind of like a visa type deal. But for debit
-- cards.
So,
interaction fee
on that.
Uh,
yeah, there is, but it's like a buck or a buck 50 which is basically
about the same as a check, but it's way more convenient.
So, but cashing checks is free in the US. At least for the banks I, I use
here. It varies. Some are free, some charge.
Most of them charge though now because like I said,
they just really, they want to get away from paper. Right.
Oh,
no, I get it. I totally get it.
Although what's crazy you can do now is,
so, I, I've, I,
I did this once and I've never done it since because it kind of freaks me out.
But
with the app on my phone,
I can take a picture of a check
and deposit it into my account
and the picture apparently is good enough.
Yes. Do you know why that is?
-- Because
-- interstate
banking laws?
No, it's because back in the day and I mean, by back in the day, five years ago,
tens of billions of dollars worth of checks were
flown across the US every day to clear them.
Right. Because you had those, all those banks that couldn't go beyond
like the state line, right?
Banks were restricted in the US to being within a single state.
Um So anyway, so in the US, you have like,
well back in the day you had like literally thousands of banks, right?
Which means if you write a check from a bank in Wisconsin to a bank in Hawaii,
they physically had to transport the check there before it would clear. Right.
So,
you know,
checks in the US or I know us checks here
would take something like 30 business days to clear.
Right.
Yeah, here in Canada
because we only ever had like six major banks.
Now, it's like four, we had a centralized check clearing house for like ages, right?
So checks in Canada were always clearing within a few days. No big deal.
Um
And in the US, obviously, I mean,
that's a huge expense flying like having to physically move checks around to,
you know, to clear them.
So that's why they went to the picture thing because let's face it. Right.
Check fraud by and large
is not a huge problem anymore.
Like I don't remember if you ever saw Catch Me If You Can, you know the Frank F
nail story.
Yeah.
And if you want to learn about check fraud, that is a great
movie for learning about check fraud.
Although none of that stuff works anymore because of, you know, computers,
right?
Uh Let's see. Here's
a,
well, and here's one that I just find kind of annoying. It's like,
basically almost every site has this one and it's ensure your
system has the most recent recommended system and security patches.
And in my mind, either you, you're either updating on a regular basis or you're not.
And if you're not, you're,
-- you're basically up the creek
-- if you own a modern computer.
Is this something you can even
do anymore? I mean, because Macs Auto update now. Right. Windows, I think
still disable it if you're really, you know, wanting to.
But
by and large they want to update by default,
this stuff all updates itself magically.
You know, what's
really got me is, uh, in the second or third last iphone update,
they added a thing basically saying automatically update if your phone is
plugged in like between the hours of like midnight and five.
Nice. So, just overnight. And I'm like, that's exactly what I want,
you know, just because I'm not, I'm not using my phone.
I don't have to worry about losing any data. Right.
Because all the apps are happy about being turned off and on,
you know, my desktop computer annoys me to no end because I keep getting, you know,
oh, I wanna update and I'm like, no, no, no, I, I'm working on a file.
Don't, don't bug me right now. Stop. No, don't reboot, you know.
Oh, man, that's,
I have a, I have a Windows computer for the kids
and, and every time, like, they do something ridiculous.
Like kids, they break stuff and I don't know what they do but they, like dad,
the computer is broke again and I'm like, I don't even know what you did,
but then I managed to reboot it and I know
every time the thing reboots the windows is like,
please wait, Windows is applying updates and they're like, what's going on?
This is weird. I'm like, yeah, go find something else to do. Be here a while.
That's actually the reason I disabled automatic updates on my Apple TV is because
I would turn it on and it would be like updating and I'm like,
-- no, I wanna watch something now update at
-- like 2 a.m.
I know, but it's not that hard.
Yeah. Oh,
this is silly. Monitor your credit through a third party for identity theft.
Didnt
Symantec just buy Lifelock
$2.3 billion.
Didn't that guy
have his, the CEO, didn't he have his identity stolen something like 13 times?
It's been a lot,
but he did put it on the side of a truck that I was driving around the country,
-- but
-- that's like literally their whole stick.
You know,
you don't have to worry about this.
So I know they've been fined by the FCC a couple times.
I, I honestly don't entirely know. However, I will say regardless of whether
you think the Identity Protection Services work or not
any time there's any sort of incident at an organization.
What is the default response? One year of free credit monitoring? Right.
So, like that, that's a, it's a money tree right now because, you know,
as more and more companies get hacked,
what's gonna be the solution? One year of free credit monitoring?
Dialing it up
in a previous episode we talked about was it, it was a chiropractic,
a chiropractor or whatever it's called clinic member that got hacked and like,
and they basically said,
like it was too expensive to offer credit reporting to people.
So like, too bad.
Yeah.
You know,
and I guess that's ok. Now, like, that's just how that works.
I,
I don't know about that. I, I suspect that's gonna end up in court
but
it's
anyway. Anyway. Uh,
-- right. Let's not get into this rat hole. Let's go over to
-- Britain for a moment.
The Merit Summit.
-- Let's go to
-- Britain for a minute. Britain apparently does Black Monday too.
-- Um,
-- we keep calling it Black Monday.
This is a good one.
Don't trust whatsapp messages offering
cash even if they're from your friends.
Ok. This week action fraud warned consumers of a new whatsapp.
How do I pronounce that by the whatsapp?
Like, what, whats
app?
I think it's
supposed to be like,
what
like was
it?
Ok.
Um
Anyways users have reported receiving messages
offering Topshop and Sainsbury gift cards.
Uh, so I know Sainsbury's is like a grocery store. I'm assuming Topshop is like
a shop of some sort
with
top end gear.
Um,
well, not a top hat shop but anyways, uh that appeared to be sent from a phone contact.
The link takes you through to an
official looking site which requests personal details.
Of course,
action frauds and clicking on the link would also allow the fraudsters to collect
personal information from your device that could
track you delete messages like these,
even if they look like uh they've come from someone
you trust and install security software on your device.
Stupid question.
So I know there's antivirus for phones, but does anybody actually use that stuff?
You know, I,
I've never met anybody with it. I don't use it.
-- I mean, I
-- don't know, I remember I looked at some of it once a long time ago
and I was incredibly unimpressed by it.
Well, and so here's the other half of that problem though is
by definition, these apps can't really interact with each other.
And so there's not a lot they can do.
And the only way to let them interact with
each other means you give it elevated privileges,
which means you've now kind of ruined your phone security
by giving one app magic.
Well, and especially an antivirus app like um so for our listeners,
um there's a guy named Tavis Ormandy who works for Google works for their project,
which is their sort of security one of their security groups
and uh a
few months ago and continuing, he's been looking at antivirus songs.
He's been looking for a long time and, and,
well, not only that. All right.
So Tavis is super freaking smart and like,
I think once the vendors find out he's looking at their stuff.
II, I can only imagine they,
they buy a bunch of whiskey and just start rocking
in the corner because he's gonna tear it up.
-- And that's just,
-- well, my favorite was,
did you see his tweet from this weekend or last week where
a vendor took a, a safe function uh called STRN copy.
So it basically copies a string of data
and like, make sure it isn't like way too long or some other insane value
and they replaced it with the unsafe version STR copy,
which just does whatever it's told to do.
Um
because it's faster,
it speeds up the scanning time.
You know what the thing is though?
I mean, you're talking about a difference of probably
if I had to guess,
maybe 10 instructions at this point because we have this stuff pretty optimized.
What are they doing? That? Saving 10 instructions makes a difference.
I know in my workstation there's over a million files and I like have no, like,
I assume maybe it's time machine backups.
I don't know, but there's like apparently over a million files on my workstation.
And so scanning this thing with an antivirus scanner. Now takes forever. Right.
Because just going and opening every single bloody file, even if it takes like,
only a millisecond, that's still a lot of milliseconds.
And maybe, I don't know, still d
don't, don't do that.
Kids don't use, drink
coffee.
Oh, and here I think is our final
tip.
Uh, and it's an oldie, but a goldie. And it's terrible, in my opinion,
use a unique password and log on information for every site you visit.
Ok. Ok.
That is correct
because your password should be coming from a password safe
and not written on a sticky notes stuck at the front of your
sticky notes taped to your monitor at home, I think are not that bad of an idea
because there's
-- somebody
-- break
into your
house. I
-- mean,
-- they're better than
using the same password everywhere,
but the correct solution is to use a password manager.
However, however,
now we're back to that problem of how do we get normal people to
basically a adopt a behavior they don't understand or know about
nor will be able to find out about
yet. The solution is
phenomenal to this problem.
You know, part of me wonders and hopes
maybe the next PC I so uh payment card industry security standard,
maybe the next one could require something like
either using either proper two factor authentication.
And by that, I don't mean like two separate passwords because that's just silly.
Uh So requiring either proper two factor authentication.
So, like an app on your phone,
um or requiring you to use like a secure login through another website, like,
say Google or Twitter or Facebook.
Because quite frankly, that's one thing I love is when a site is like,
you can log in via Google.
I'm like,
-- great. That's one less account I have to go create.
-- I totally agree. In fact,
I found myself recently
where if I go to a site and it wants me to create an account for something,
if it doesn't have a Google log in, I'm like, uh I don't really care
and then I move on to something else or I look at an alternative
that might happen and then I'll use that instead even if it's worse.
Just so I don't have to add another thing to my password safe,
which is currently enormous.
Well, here's a question. When you talk about a password safe.
Are you talking about a stand alone application
or
for example, something built into your web browser?
Because for example,
I use the safe password feature on my web browser all the time because like
-- I at last count have over 1000 accounts.
-- Does it generate random passwords for you?
Uh No, but I just mashed the keyboard.
So
what happens if you have to enter it twice?
Uh I mash it into notepad and then cut and paste.
Um Although uh on my phone, it does auto generate safari on the phone.
Is smart enough now to generate a password.
So I just maybe
you know what it is.
I use chrome on my Mac, not safari.
So I bet safari on the Mac does it like the password generation?
So I actually use uh I, I run Linux
as my desktop which you have to be kind of a special,
sort of crazy to do that to begin with just because it's,
yeah, it's, I, I still iii I don't value my time,
but
actually, it's not too bad these days.
But anyway, I, I found this,
this safe called PW Safe that I've been using for a long time.
And the thing I love the most about it is
that when I go to paste the passwords,
it opens a connection to the X clipboard
and it tells me which app got the password and it only pays it once
because I know like some apps will just put the password in the clipboard,
which means anything that, that, that can listen to the clipboard
will steal it
and like, literally everything could do that.
But with PW safe,
it only gives it to one thing
and it tells me what took it.
And so that pleases me greatly. But at the same time, I also, I found a bunch of bugs.
One time there was, uh,
like a VNC viewer or something and the VNC viewer
was just like eating everything put into the clipboard.
And that annoyed me So I,
I found a new VNC viewer obviously because there's no reason for that.
But
that's why I think two factor authentication is the long term.
I, I think basically how do I securely use a password? Is the wrong question?
I think the correct question is how do we get rid of reliance on passwords?
Totally, man. Passwords are dumb.
It's what we got
it. It is what we have.
Although I will admit that I don't know if you've
ever looked at the U two F tokens that exist.
Now, they are very cool.
I've been meaning to buy one because now chrome supports it.
-- Uh
-- If you get a AUBK
four,
it comes with U two F as one of the
countless options that are built into the little device.
So you can buy like the U two F standalones, which I, I actually, I have a, an older UI
key
and a U two F key. So I have two and I have a UB key four in my desk drawer
that I'm just quite frankly too lazy to set up.
But when I do that, I will have one instead of two.
But the beauty of U two
F is, it's basically kind of like an RS a key on board.
And
when you go to a website, because one of my complaints with using two factor
off on my phone in the app is I have like 400 sites
in my Google Authenticator app.
And I've got to figure out which site it is and, and then type in the little key code,
right?
But with U two F, it's 11 token
and it works with like all the sites just
because it kind of does some challenge response with,
with uh public key encryption,
which is super cool,
aren't they using like o
author or
something like that?
Something
like that?
No, no, no, those are, those are kind of different.
This is, I don't know what the protocol is called necessarily, but it,
it's essentially like RS A, right?
We're like
you hand out the public key and you keep the
public,
right?
I mean, that's basically what's going on where I ha I, I tell the website,
here's my public key.
I keep my private key, everyone's happy
and then I can give every website the, the pub public key obviously.
And everything's cool
and it's a little more complicated than that. But
how does this work? Say on a phone where you can't plug a USB thing in?
Yeah, that's uh that's one of the problems is,
could I ask you questions, Kurt?
The idea, I guess is to have some sort of Bluetooth functionality eventually.
But for the moment,
-- I'm just nervous
-- about turning Bluetooth on in public spaces
and you should be,
but
it's
also not a topic we will discuss today on, on Black Cyber Monday.
So, yeah, I think that about summarizes sort of the main groups of tips.
Um,
you know, one thing I'm curious,
what does anybody out there have any other tips that they think are useful or not?
Completely insane?
No. No, they don't.
Well, you know, ok, so, so here's the thing
that kills me with all these tips
is
we are security people.
We've been doing this for a long time and we
read this stuff and we laugh at it because we,
we know it's ridiculous and we know it doesn't work for whatever reason
or we can pick it apart and find all these problems with it.
But
let's say we had to make up a list of five things for people to do
to stay secure, let's say all year long.
And
I guarantee you, we could spend a week building a list
and as soon as we showed it to one other security person,
they would tear it apart.
Right.
Because this is one of the problems I see is the
fact that there isn't universal agreement on what's good or bad.
But I think more importantly is just,
you can't expect people
to change their behavior.
We have to change the things they interact
with to do what's right versus expecting people
to do what's right because people will always pick the lazy way out every time.
It's not even a lazy way out. It's like, quite often. I don't
know,
like what is the secure behavior? Right.
And I know instinctively based on the physical world, kind of what I would do,
like lock the door or look both ways before I cross the street.
But,
you know, for example, uh,
you know, when I go to buy something online,
is it good that they store my information or bad?
You know, and I, I choose to believe and hope that large sites like,
say Amazon are doing it securely
-- because if they're not, I'm up
-- the
creek.
Let's face it. Google and Amazon and Facebook know more about you than you do.
So
I think giving them your address is fine.
Well, I mean, more, I'm concerned from the point of view of like, you know,
they get hacked and all that data gets leaked and I have to deal with
it. I'm
not
so
worried
about the tax
of Amazon and Facebook and Google is,
there's nowhere to store all the data if someone
wants to steal it because there's too much.
So, I don't know.
I mean, I, I generally this is one of the reasons I, you know,
keep my shopping down to a few major sites is to, yeah, is to reduce that risk.
Uh, and you know,
and where possible I use paypal because then
they don't even get my credit card number.
Although I have no idea what the charge back process is like with paypal.
I've never done that. Thank God.
-- I've
-- heard it's fairly,
uh, pro buyer.
No,
when, when you have an issue. I've never, I've never had a problem,
but I've read horror stories of sellers dealing with difficult buyers and
apparently like a buyer who's just, like, purposely a jerk can like ruin
paypal for you.
Well, in fairness, I just did have the experience of buying a laptop on ebay,
paying through paypal and then 20 minutes later getting a refund because, you know,
the, the product is supposedly not available.
Why,
-- what
-- exactly they said the product's either damaged or not available.
So you don't get to have it.
Uh What I suspect is is because my bid and
in general,
the bidding on this product were about $50 lower than comparable auctions.
And so I think they just want more money. So they're just gonna relist
it in a week or two and
-- isn't
-- that fraud?
Well, there's,
-- here's
-- the,
there's no way to report it.
I was digging through the messages in the web interface
and there's like no way to leave seller feedback,
right? Because I wanted to leave feedback saying these guys are jerks.
So if they don't sell it to you, you don't get to leave feedback.
No.
Well, here's the thing.
Technically, in my opinion, they sold it to me because they took my money,
right?
And then they gave it back, which is nice of them
that all of the money back or was there?
Like
it was a
full
refund?
Uh Wait, actually, I got to double check that now that you mentioned it.
Uh It looked like it was about the right. It was only about 100 and $80 Canadian.
So it wasn't too much like it was, I think
the one came,
it was a used Lenovo think pad that I want to get for the kids, for
Minecraft
-- laptop for the kids.
-- Yeah.
Yeah, because you know, mods, it's a thing.
Diamond Mine Cart, man. Diamond Mine Cart.
It's a guy on youtube. Apparently my kids watch him a lot.
Um But yeah, so I mean
that to me, it was like I've never seen, I've never had this happen before, right?
And that to me is a really interesting way to hack the whole ebay process because
yeah, if you take them, like, if you somehow cancel the sale or something,
my understanding is that, that kind of, you know, that gets logged and stuff.
But if I take your money and then refund it
fully and give a supposedly good reason for that,
then apparently you get away scot free because like I said,
I cannot leave feedback to these guys
saying that, you know, I'm pretty sure they're
not happy because the laptop didn't sell for enough money.
Uh And now that I know this, you know, I'm kind of tempted to like,
use this, you know, instead of setting a reserve price, you just do this trick.
Wow, that's crazy, man.
Now that you've said that on a on a public podcast, you
uh
-- you can't do that
-- well.
And hopefully other people don't too because I'm guessing ebay has this
data and they must be able to look at these people and,
you know, to, to run the numbers and see, like, look, you know, these guys,
when the bids are a couple bucks lower or whatever.
Do they
-- do this? You know shenanigans? They
-- might do, they care.
I don't know. I mean, it's crazy.
This was a high volume seller with like over 30,000 sales.
So like
ebay is probably gonna let them do whatever they want,
you know, with the amount of money they bring in.
Crazy man.
So, well, you know, that's the thing, right? You have a marketplace.
People are going to try and game it.
That that's like
the history of the world, right?
Pretty much.
-- Oh
-- man.
All right, Kurt.
I think it's uh it's time to put this uh Cyber Black Monday to bed.
Yeah. So I guess the moral of the story is
don't use public wi fi
just don't, don't do anything right? Like living life is dangerous.
That's the moral of the story.
-- Stay in your house and cover the windows in tin foil.
-- That's right.
Just drink and rock in the car quietly.
All right.
Well,
you have a good night and everybody else stay
safe and hope you had a good Cyber Monday.
-- It's
-- been fun. Thanks everybody until next time. Bye bye.
Bye.