Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my totally nonsocial friend, Josh Bresser.
I'm a non paras social. What does that mean?
So I learned a new term today from the Twitter leak, which is paras social paras,
social interaction
refers to a kind of psychological relationship experienced by an audience
in their mediated encounters with performers in the mass media,
particularly on television.
Oh, I've heard of this before actually.
And Twitch is a great example of this where they sort of take that mass market TV
concept and try to personalize it a bit, you know,
with like the text chat and stuff where basically if
you donate like 10 or $100 to a streamer,
they'll be like,
thanks Bob
and moving along. And so you get your like five seconds of fame.
Right. Right. There's a video I think it's a,
I watch that discusses all of these weird relationships and,
and everyone talks about their like Twitch community
and it's not really a community.
I would try to dig it up and put it in the show notes, but I make no guarantees.
Like I don't think you and I have any illusions about our listeners.
Like, and
they, they're like victims at best.
Yeah.
I mean, at least we have the moral high ground of their, their willing victims.
That's
true. That's
true. Like they came to us. We did not advertise. Yes.
Yes.
So, yeah. So the reason I bring Twitch up is because apparently somebody leaked
all the Twitch, like back end source code,
including for products they haven't released yet.
And also streamer payouts and the streamer payouts were,
I mean, it's a classic power distribution curve with, you know,
there's one person at, what was it?
$752,000 a month. Some of these people make Mad Bank
again.
I, I understand power distribution laws like there's Michael Jackson and you know,
Britney spears at the top and then everybody else at the bottom, but
like three quarters of a million dollars us per month
is,
wow.
Well, I mean, that's how
youtube has similar
for a lot of these, these creators.
And it's,
it is not surprising to me in any way.
I think if you look at any of the entertainment personalities over the decades,
the people who are at the top of the list do very,
very well and I don't think streaming and youtube are no different.
It reminds me a lot of software in that
somebody builds a software package or something that is very useful.
And yeah, you can,
you can sell it once or you can sell it 10 million times basically the same effort.
And
that's what always blows me away about this digital economy
is,
yeah, like 80% of the cost is that first copy,
19% of the cost is, you know,
marketing and paying your account and lawyers off and then
1% is making copies of it and distributing it.
Which
and also now 20 years later is comically cheap.
Like cloud flares are two, was just announced. It's like
basically, well, you know, it's,
it's X pennies per month per gigabyte.
Oh,
and there's no egress fees like if it
gets downloaded three trillion times good on you,
you know.
Um Yeah,
stuff like that blows my mind. So
yeah. So twitch, all the stuff got leaked. I don't,
here's the thing I keep coming back to, especially with these cloud services.
Like does it matter at all if their source code gets leaked?
Well, so I would argue the source code is probably mostly irrelevant,
but I think the data on the streamers is going to cause them a lot of headaches.
I doubt it unless they haven't been declaring their taxes.
I,
I bet there are some streamers that are going to be unhappy with what they're making.
True.
Oh, you mean for the ones that
I would say that there's probably some in the middle or on the,
the higher end, but not the top that are going to look at this and say, wait a minute,
what is the deal here?
Why am I not getting this?
I mean,
this is like the fundamental problem with
why companies don't want employees sharing salaries,
for example, because as soon as people start talking, you like, hold on, hold on.
Why, why?
Well, I guess ironically we exist in a society now where many of us were,
were kind of brainwashed into instead of saying,
why don't I have that saying that person should be down here by me.
I should be up there by them.
Yeah, exactly.
Yeah.
Raising up everybody rather than trying to drag
everybody down to some version of equality.
But I mean, so look, I,
I think the topic of if your source code leaks doesn't really matter
and I think
you're gonna have some people say, oh,
now the bug bunty people are going to have a field
and they probably will.
And,
but at the same time like these already exist, you want them to.
So who cares? There is the issue of all?
This is my intellectual property and it's very important and whatnot.
But I, I guarantee you
if I gave you a billion dollars and said, Kurt,
here's the Twitch source code. Go make Twitch.
I would have no money
and not Twitch because Twitch is a brand. Twitch isn't source code.
But even even more importantly, it's, it's execution,
right? And that's what counts, right? Because to put it bluntly pretty sure.
All the source code that Red Hat Ships is out there. Same, all same with your company.
Elastic.
Yeah. Right. And no offense.
But building a team that can actually keep that thing
up to date and building a team to support it,
you know, tier 12 and three phone support for that.
That's right. That is,
that is what we call in a, you know, a complicated problem.
It is, there's even a large well known cloud provider who's trying to do that
and will say they're not failing,
but it's probably not going as well as they would hope.
I
here's the thing, something like S3 is conceptually very simple, put objects in,
take objects out
oh dates and you know, like metadata or, you know, automatic archiving cool,
but something like elastic is
much less trivial
and you can
credibly complicated.
It's like
you can't just hand a nuclear reactor over to somebody and be like cool,
like turn it on and you'll get a couple of megawatts of power.
I mean, well,
actually that's becoming true because we are getting turned key nuclear reactors.
But you're talking about like the existing boiling water nuclear reactors,
they require a literal army of people to keep the thing from breaking.
Didn't this happen?
When was it the Chinese or the Russians stole the plans to
some American like fighter plane and there was like a hole,
an accidental like screw hole or something somewhere that
they also put in the screw hole thing you're
thinking of is from a world war I I
bomber where they basically captured it was like a bee
17 or whatever.
And it had like a manufacturing defect and they included that in all their copies.
And the real problem was converting all the sheet
metal thicknesses from imperial to millimeters because those,
those things didn't exist like the same equivalent.
So the plane was much heavier anyways.
But no, there's there's been cases of,
I mean, well, the worst example would be the capacitor. Remember the
a Chinese firm stole a Japanese firm's capacitor recipe
and apparently they didn't get all of it.
So you remember for about that five year period
back in the early two thousands with all the,
you know, the popping capacitors and motherboards.
So this is an issue with, with video games because those rotten capacitors
are used in a lot of video game consoles. And there is obviously a lot of
and old computers too, but there's this effort now to preserve this old hardware.
And like when you have some, in fact, I have a game gear in my basement
that I need to recap at some point because the capacitors are shot.
And we know and funny enough,
you can go on ebay now and they sell just like
little bags of all the capacitors I need to replace.
So like car which is,
yeah, it's super easy. I just need to do it. I'm lazy and I don't want to
one of those things where,
when you actually get set down and to do it only takes a few hours but getting set up,
getting all the parts,
you know, getting your fume hood up and running.
So you don't get, you know, mad hats, whatever.
Got to breathe in that sweet, sweet Cider vapor.
And folks don't use that lead free garbage.
Actually, I have a roll of leaded solder.
I keep for special occasions just because you can't buy it anymore.
What?
Seriously?
Not that I, all the solder I've bought in the last like, probably decade is lead free.
I haven't looked to see if I can find leaded solder. I have some.
So I don't really care.
But, yeah, like it's definitely long term projects. Leaded solder doesn't crack.
So it's much better. But obviously
lead
whiskers
in the proper lead solder. Uh,
yeah, you're right now. I never noticed that. But yes, you are correct.
I just checked. Amazon has all the leaded solder. Oh, they do? Oh,
so this isn't special. I thought I had a special thing.
Anyway, don't use lead.
I was
going to sell my, I have like, most of the roll left.
Well, no, no, it's like,
because there actually is a market for old stained glass windows.
Yeah, that's true. You need, you need lead for those. Well, you need
isotope free lead for certain things
and the only way to get that is to get lead.
That is several 100 years old and conveniently enough.
Not only is the lead in a stained glass window old,
but it's provably old because it's like when that church was built anyway, we're,
we're at holding,
uh, Twitch.
So Twitch, basically everything got leaked.
I, like you said, the source code being leaked, I don't think matters at all.
And the payouts is interesting.
I don't think anybody's going to really care
or stop donating money to these people because,
well, if they were going to show some sense they probably would have by now.
No, no. Ok. Look, no, don't, don't, don't say that it's not about showing some sense
when you are receiving
a good someone is producing and in the case of something like Twitch,
there is a creator that is making a thing that you may enjoy
and so paying for the thing you are consuming is completely reasonable.
It's just in our old person brains. It feels weird to pay for that.
Well,
true.
But some of them,
apparently some of the streamers are making a lot more money
than they claim to be and they're whining on stream about,
you know,
having had to spend like this one streamer
was complaining about having to have spent,
you know, $5000 or $4000 in some event with friends
and then it comes out what this person is earning and it's over six figures.
A month and it's like,
ok,
that's,
I guess, well, that, that game's done now. So, anyway, anyway.
Right. Right. Uh, leak, leak source code.
I
don't think it matters.
I think we exist in a world now where actually releasing
your source code to your product is beneficial to you.
I think there's some,
we'll say rough patches you might go through at the very
beginning because I'm sure there's some demons in there that,
like the buck hunters might find.
But I think in the long term, it's definitely
a beneficial move.
I mean, yeah,
which leads us to Apache who has had their source code in the wild since, well,
forever.
Yeah.
Well, even prior to it existing because it was N CS A.
That's right. That's right.
And they, they patched it. So it was Apache web server.
I love it when you tell people that they're like what it's like.
Why is it called Apache? Because it's
a
patchy web server and they're like, oh,
anyway, anyway,
we should explain what's going on at the moment because this will not be true.
Probably by the time the podcast is published.
I OK. Yeah. Um,
so long story short, uh, patchy
fixed
uh, Apache,
cha OK. Let's backpedal. Apache changed
some quotes handling in strings for the, well, the previously, the most,
I'm gonna say the most recent version of Apache, which was then,
uh, 2.4 point uh, what 49.
Yeah.
And that introduced
a bug
that was then found by,
um, Ash Dalton along with the C panel security team so good on them.
They fixed this bug,
yay and push out the fix. And that was yesterday, it was no big deal.
It was kind of like this weird bug that could,
um, I actually posted a tweet about it because one person pointed out that it changed
the behavior of how it parses the config files on windows.
And so they actually had to remove the
quotes from something because basically this Porsche guy,
you know,
upgraded his Apache web server and spent half an hour
fighting with the config trying to make it work again.
And the trick was he had to remove the quotes around the file name.
And
for anybody that's ever administered a UNIX C piece of software on Windows,
like the first thing you do is you put quotes around
those file paths because your spaces and junk in there,
right?
So you always put quotes around those file paths because of the way windows. It just
like even I know that and I haven't administered a Windows machine in 10 years. So
anyways, uh and then we wake up this morning and well,
it's our show topic because it turns out to be a remote code execution flaw
with an exploit that fits in a tweet.
Well, no,
OK, you jump too far. I think they're the intermediate step where
Apache publishes their
security advisory calling it a
path traversal flaw,
not arbitrary code execution
are extremely different
from. Well, the thing is it is a path traversal flaw that leads to code execution.
And I don't,
I
don't
know pedantic.
Well,
but no, no, it's important because the remote code execution is the outcome,
not the underlying flaw.
Um,
and it's not,
I suspect that they did not know this.
I suspect because here's the thing with open source,
we have enough bugs and flaws to solve that.
Like somebody reports one. Ok, whatever it looks, it's,
you know, you look at a path traversal flaw and my mind would immediately go to ah,
crap, you know, file disclosure.
Ok.
Ok. Great. Ok. We got to fix string handling, ok?
We fixed it, it stopped doing that and the files not being disclosed. Ok.
Push out a fix call. It done. Let's go for lunch. Now, I want to explain why
this happened and I think I know how they got here because I have,
by the time I press the publish button,
some of this may have changed.
So mind you, this is we are literally hours after learning of this particular issue.
So here's the deal, a path traversal is where you put lots of like dot dots in a path.
And so obviously you kind of walk the directory tree backwards
and then you can walk it forwards to whatever you want,
say like Etsy password or
some other sensitive thing. OK. Now what was happening in apaches?
This generally Apache has these rules that say things
like you can't look at files in this directory,
right?
They have like their allow and deny and all those rules.
Now, it sounds like what happened is they added a directory, traversal flaw.
Once you escape the directory,
it was applying the allow and deny rules for kind of where you started.
It's like if you start in slash icons,
it's going to apply the slash icons rules to wherever you end up.
After all the
treating it sort of like a, a symbolic link almost
in a
of like where it's applying the local directory policy but to an object,
that's actually somewhere else.
That's right. But now what's the special thing about the CG I bin directory?
Uh Well, you get to run things. That's right because
it was awesome.
And I remember trying to make it work.
I saw cgib in this exploit and I just had like a flood of horrible old memories.
My stomach is actually feeling a bit yucky right now just saying that word, I,
I need to go wash my hands now or something anyway.
So here this is how it works though, is like many,
many years ago when Kurt and I were we lads,
there was this concept called CG I bins, which was common gateway interface.
And the concept was you would basically your web server.
This is so insane when I said your web server would run an application, a binary
or a script or whatever and then basically dump a
bunch of data from the client straight into it
and then return back whatever the script or executable.
Like I, I had a job at one point writing CG I in the C language.
Well, and that's the thing, right? It is.
It's a chicken and egg problem of we didn't have any web
languages. I'm gonna say
because we didn't have any way to pass data around.
And so literally, this is one of those classic UNIX clutches of, hey,
you guys have heard of pipes on the command line, right?
Yep. Well, I just, that's what CG I bin. Is that
right? That right.
But anyway, OK,
so what happens is the slash CGIB directory on Apache by
default has very special permissions where it says you may execute code
or executables, I should say from this directory.
And so what it looks like is happening is people are using slash
CG I dash bin slash all the dot dot magic slash say KC
dot exe on windows and it's running
C dot exe because Apache thinks you're in the CG
I bin directory where it's OK to run executables except,
oh no, you're not.
Yeah.
And this drives me nuts because like,
I'm trying to think if I've even seen AC G I bin in the last decade,
like this is something that probably should be Well,
I want to say it should be removed from Apache.
What it should probably be do
is be turned into a module that's not installed by default. Almost definitely. I
know,
I, I see CG I type behavior often in
like IOT type
pieces because
they literally,
well, and the beauty of CG I bin is
if you can write a shell script,
you have a web app. Well, it also has no overhead.
You have to remember when you're using like let's say PP or
Pearl or no Js or whatever those interpreters exist in memory.
Even when they're not doing any work even worse. They, they require some expertise.
Whereas writing,
like if you want to have a light bulb turn off and on and
you have a local binary that actually talks the hard one does it,
I can whip you up a bash script in five lines and stick it in CGIB
and we're just done.
That's true because you just have to hit the end point and then it will run.
And so it's,
it's not
in and of itself a bad thing.
It's just one of those really old sharp dangerous tools with no safety guards.
And we should probably not include it in the toolkit by default.
I mean, I agree. I, I don't think it needs to be there.
And now,
now it should also go with saying there's a lot of hoopla going on on
Twitter at the moment about this and there's a couple of really important things.
First of all, the Apache advisory and the CV E description
have not been updated to reflect, this is an R ce which I think is
unacceptable. Apache has had more than 12 hours at this point to update this. Like
anyone in this situation should have been freaking out
and at least put a big banner up.
That's like we are investigating reports that this might be an R ce,
except in this case, there's literally
R ce demos on Twitter that work. I am like I am a bit disappointed in Apache
because they are big enough that they should
be able to have somebody pull the fire alarm
like a one person show.
I also love that
the NVD has the entry up but no CV SS score
and they need to have somebody go in there manually and type the number 10.
Just type a TED. It's a TED. We all know it's a TED now and again,
they are in a position
where they should be able to pull the fire alarm. They're Eastern Standard.
They've had two hours to do this already today.
Like it's nine in the morning right now. It's 11 o'clock where they are.
It's, it's 1130
at the moment
and that's a lot of time, a lot of time. And I would, now
this is probably
not accurate, but I,
I would think they've had people for more than five hours
paying attention to this at this point or maybe not.
I mean, probably not. I don't know,
you would think.
I'm just trying to think because you and I are on Twitter and that's a normal thing.
I'm kind of wondering, are the NVD people, like,
do they have somebody kind of on Twitter monitoring it because, and,
and this is one thing I find fascinating and this is
part of what we're working on with the UV I,
right?
Is,
is from transforming this from an infosec problem
to a web search and discovery problem because
like the people on Twitter talking about this are all
highly trusted, like easily verified in
information security weirdos
like goss see the dog, like,
like when you said when you posted that link in, in signal, right?
My first thought was like, why are you posting me Twitters?
And then it's like, goss see the dog? Oh crap. What happened now? Right?
It's like seeing Tavis.
So
in a, in a Twitter string, it's just like, oh boy, that's right.
And then hacker fantastic post the X flight.
And it's like, well, it's over because when goss
the dog posted, I'm like,
i
it's probably this but um I'm gonna look at this and
then I saw the hacker Fantastic tweet and I'm like,
it's over like this is it, it's the real deal.
And so, and that's an interesting thing because
getting this data sort of through the normal channels.
You know what, somebody emails, what, what is it?
It's security
apache.org or whatever. And then they process it and then they push it out and then
as a CV numbering authority they would have to poke miter with a sharp stick
and try and get some sort of emergency update to the CV
database which I know can be done but it can be.
But look, let's,
that, that process is really broken. We can ignore the CV E description.
Yeah, exactly. I will bet you a dollar.
But by the time you're listening to this podcast on Sunday or Monday,
the CV entry still might not be updated.
It wouldn't shock me. It would not surprise me at all. I would not take that bet.
No, not even for a dollar but, but I Apache should be doing better.
And now here's the one redeeming factor in all of this is,
this only affects one version like one single
release that I bet not many people are running today.
Well, it affects
that one version that is current.
So anybody who actually is running current is kind of up the creek.
But I would also suspect and hope I think is
the word that the people running current are also doing things
like containers where it's not full of like BS H and
things that or even if you get remote code execution,
it's not that big of a deal.
I would hope so. But I think we both know. That's not true.
Well, it's interesting that the C panel team found it. So they,
I, do you think I'm just, I don't even know if C panel runs.
Like, I have no idea what version of Apache they're using.
I couldn't tell you. I haven't looked at C panel in years. I mean,
now there's one other
kind of wacky thing in all this. I've been thinking about as soon as
I read this was an R ce I saw people posting
log files showing like this was being actively exploited on the internet.
And I feel like historically, it might have taken a day or two, but in this case,
it sounds like it took about 15 minutes.
I mean, there's those men
scan tools now that can scan the entire I PV four space of the internet in about what,
1015 minutes.
Yeah, really fast.
And so to essentially run this exploit against every I
PV four on the planet is maybe an hour tops.
Well,
and you could even use something like showdown to specifically figure out what,
what are the versions of a pan?
Like these versions of Apache? I want their ips
and show Dan could totally give you that well or are you just fired
at every I PV for on the planet and be done with it?
Like really it's not expensive. It's not hard. No, no, I agree. It's
man,
I remember when some of the first scans of the internet happened back in
the nineties and people were talking about taking months to scan I PV for the
same thing as the human genome project. Right.
It started out, we might sequence a human DNA in
decades.
If we're lucky,
then the technology got a little bit better and
a little bit better and a little bit better.
And here we are with, what is it? I think it's 25 minutes on the high end for a sequence.
Like, it's less than an hour now
and it's affordable.
You know, I've just the fact that my kids like the science museum we go to,
has a scanning electron
scanning tunneling electron microscope,
like
for public use. That is pretty wild. Right.
And, and I was kind of like, wow, a, wow, two man.
That's a, it's a really cute looking little,
I think it's from GE and apparently it only costs like 100 grand.
Which, yeah, only 100 grand.
But still, like for a piece of technology that, you know,
we used to watch documentaries about in school.
Yeah. Right.
I
remember when I went to university they had one and I'm like, this is amazing.
You have an electron microscope and it was like
millions of dollars for this thing.
And I think every time they started it up,
it costs like thousands of dollars to run because it had like the cryo tank outside
the perfect vacuum. And that's right. It was nothing like it is now.
And, and that's the beauty of technology, right?
So,
yeah, no, this, this Apache thing is really fascinating because it, it does really
the whole defense in depth thing is still needed because, and I hate to say this,
there's these just ridiculously
exploitable, silly flaws,
but literally the exploit fits in a tweet and lets you run like BNSH with arguments
on the host. So for example, if you're using a container
and you've removed all the shells,
what I remember this person did a thing where they basically tried to figure out,
you know, which Linux binaries are quote unquote safe. Like can't be used to hack
and there's a number of them like I think a
is one where a
like will and can talk to the network.
Oh yeah, there's loads of stuff. I mean, most containers,
I should say most it is not uncommon for a container to have system D in it.
For example, system D has a ridiculous amount of functionality built into it.
I mean, this is, you know, in the attacker space
or the defender space. I should say they call this living off the land
where Attackers basically look at what's there and they figure out
how to abuse the tools that are already on the system.
Because obviously a lot of these sensors will say, oh no,
a binary got uploaded alert, alert, alert.
But if someone's running curl, whatever curl gets run, it's fine everybody.
And it's like, oh, not fine at all.
Yeah. And on the flip side you have, like, oh, my, oh, there's a copy of,
you know, network CNC installed.
It's a hacker tool because they'll use the pivot and it's like,
but the, you know, and like, well,
windows were moose til net now and a bunch of other stuff for kind of that same reason,
which drives me nuts because
very handy tool for, you know, testing things.
But um
yeah, no, it's, I, I,
I don't know what the answer is here because I, I am firmly in the camp of, well,
we had bash shell shock a few years ago, which was kind of the same thing.
It was like, whoops this, you know,
remote code execution that fits in a tweet and here we have it again, what,
five years later, seven years later,
no, about five years later.
Uh
yeah,
about that.
And so like, well, that seems to be about the cadence is about once or twice a decade.
It's just going to happen. I mean, it is going to happen and look,
I think the message here isn't to mock Apache for making a mistake.
They made a mistake, it happens, whatever,
they also fixed it quickly
and that's good.
But they, they, there's more work to do because I think the severity of this is not,
it
is not documented appropriately.
And I think all of these security things,
the key isn't to not make mistakes because we're all going to screw up all of us.
It's just life.
The key is to be able to move quickly
and remediate your mistakes where I feel like apaches
only done half that well. And, and, but also you say remediate the mistake.
And it's interesting because they did remediate this specific mistake, right?
They fixed it,
but they didn't do
maybe a crash investigation and say, oh, look, CG I bin is really dangerous.
Let's turn it into a module that's not installed by default.
Right?
And that's one thing that always gets me with the airline industry is
they don't just figure out why it crashed and like, oh, you know,
the person should have put the right size bolts
in the windshield so the windshield didn't pop out.
It's like, oh, were they sleep deprived? Ok.
Look,
maybe we need to change the rules around mechanics and crews sleep
requirements so that they're not so dang tired and making these,
you know, mistakes that result in massive problems.
And so my hope would be is that Apache maybe uses this as a reason
to do some re architecting
or some tidy up, especially around CG I bin because,
yeah, I don't think we can just get rid of CG I bin. People still need it, but
people generally don't need it by default.
Yeah.
Right. Right. Because I'm just trying to remember if CGIB I
actually
a module or Oh, dang.
I'd be shocked if it was. I bet it's like core functionality.
I'm pretty sure it is. Whatever, who cares? Fix it.
And I would say if you run Apache,
make sure you've turned that stuff off because
you can disable it in the configuration file.
Like CG I bin doesn't have to be turned on.
Yeah.
Don't turn it on unless you're using it and if you're using it, like,
containerize the crap out of that stuff,
you know. Yeah.
Yeah.
Unfortunately that turning it off then means every time you do an update it's like,
oh, your config file is different than the one I want to install.
Do you want to keep it? And sometimes that breaks stuff and,
uh,
yeah, I mean, that's another problem though. I wish we had seen our defaults.
Well, yeah,
but that's, that's another conversation.
So. Ok. Ok.
We've made, we've picked on Apache a lot, I guess at the same time,
remember there are, people don't, don't yell at them like, no, I would say this is
an instance for growth.
Where, why, why did this take so long to update, like, figure it out?
Make sure it doesn't happen again. You're a patchy.
You're not Josh and Kurt, you know, there's,
there's, there's some expectations I think. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. That's all I have. I have.
One last thing I want to end on that I think is super cool.
So I upgraded my laptop to windows. 11
the day came up. Actually, it was technically the day before because it worked.
But whatever
I can run X 11 apps
on Windows natively,
my head exploded
and it,
well, but the thing is not just can you run natively,
but it actually works out of the box with zero setup
like it just,
well, you have to make Windows subsystem for Linux
work. You literally type in WSL two
space hyphen hyphen enable or something.
That's it like that's,
yeah, it's pretty easy. And you know what the craziest thing of all us though
is.
So when you press,
what is it like the little window key that
brings up whatever the start menu is called now
and it's all in the middle, of course, because being in the middle is cool again.
And so you hit the button
and
it shows like recently run applications,
it showed the X 11 apps in that list and when I clicked them, they ran
like it.
I don't even,
I
don't know what to say. Like that's the year of the Linux desktop.
If you would have told me a decade ago that I would be able to run X 11 apps on Windows.
I would have laughed in your face and said,
that's the dumbest thing anyone has ever said.
So it's been 23 years since the Halloween documents actually.
Almost, yeah, almost exactly 23 years since the Halloween documents in 1998.
It'll be 23 years on Halloween, maybe
close to October 31. Anyway, I
don't know what to say. Kurt, it's
of the Linux desktop.
It's always the year of the Linux desktop.
It will always be the year of the Linux desktop.
It will always be the year of the Linux desktop. There you go. That's the show, folks.
The only constant I have in my life is the year of the Linux desktop.
Alright.
I'm going to call it. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening. Go to omit
our security podcast.com. Hit up the show, not, it's Suzy Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag Hit us up on social media. Kurt have a lovely rest of your day. You too.
Thanks everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the