Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in reminiscing about the past Josh Pressers
-- reminiscing. It's, this is the freaking future, man.
-- No, I'm gonna read something
I wrote over 20 years ago
that applies to this.
Linux has gone through a series of firewalls. The most recent is IP tables.
Most of the people listening to the show probably don't know what IP tables is.
Thank goodness. But I continue
sometimes to his net filter preceding this was IP
chains and preceding this was IP firewall admin,
which I'm guessing.
Absolutely nobody knows unless you've been using Linux since
the nineties
as well.
There are a number of other files such as IP F and Sinus Firewall,
some of which only work on 2.0 and 2.2 series kernels.
So are largely obsolete.
I would recommend using a 2.4 kernel with IP tables
if possible since it offers state full packet inspections,
which makes firewall
calls such as DNS and FTP properly a lot easier.
OK.
And
that is a lot of the context for like our discussion about Cups today. Is it,
it is because
OK, here's the thing. So
remember like I found a remote massive code execution that affects all Linux
by default, blah, blah, blah. And it turns out to be a fla
cops,
right? Like,
which is funny because you had looked at kind of like, what could it be like?
OK, system D
uh I forget one or two other things. And then you said cups
and
I remember looking at the cups get history
and like half the commits for the last two months,
literally just like glancing at them.
I'm like that they all smell like CV ES because they're all like, no, they're,
they were horrifying
and I don't think those were any of the security fix. I think one of them was.
Yeah.
But yeah, they were things like
this thing crashes because of this magic number that we
now account for like it raps to zero whatever and
oftentimes those tend to be security flaws. So
the,
the long and the short of it is if you're attaching
a system to the internet with a public facing IP address,
it probably shouldn't have that many public facing services
unless they're like, really kind of well hardened things like a web server
and to put it bluntly cups is not one of those.
-- And
-- that's easy to say.
It is
-- easy
-- to
-- say and it's also
-- correct.
It's bold of you to jump to the end with your conclusion
-- and semi actionable advice
-- and it also boils back to my,
remember me saying, I don't care, argument where this is a perfect example of, like,
I don't care because
if people actually understood kind of what cups is and does,
they would never expose it to the internet.
I suspect most people didn't do it on purpose.
That's my guess.
Yeah, they just attached a thing to the network and, and,
and they might not even know it's running cups.
I think a lot of them probably don't.
And I bet a lot of printers run cups by default. Now there's all this wild software.
What else would they run? Like
you think a, the company is going to write their own printer software when they
grab cups,
they're already running Linux.
I want to rewind us to the beginning of this whole
debacle because I don't think Cups by itself is very interesting.
I think the chaos surrounding this entire event
is vastly more interesting to talk about.
And it is a case study
in how not to disclose an issue.
And the ironic thing is we
just literally as of yesterday also have
Akamai and Larry cash
dollar guest of the show. In the past,
they published that blog entry where
uh long story short,
you can send one UDP packet to cups.
And of course, Cups very helpfully replies with a whole bunch of stuff.
And
the trick is because it's UDP, it's trivial to spoof because there's no TCP,
sequence number to guess or anything like that.
And so
a
I published this blog saying basically, you know, you can, you can,
you can use this for traffic amplification to a degree that is,
yeah, it's a problem. And of course, being
Akamai, they, they released this kind of in a very boring like here it is everything,
you know, here's the fix, here's the problem, here's the explanation, blah, blah,
blah.
And that was kind of the more in my opinion,
professional way to handle something like this,
right? Well, then Larry's done this many times before. He definitely understands.
We'll say the the process.
Now, whether the process is right or wrong, it's wrong
is part of the discussion.
Also, I would agree and to be clear when I said professional,
yeah, may not necessarily correct or the best way
I wanna, I wanna tell the story.
Let's tell the thrilling tale as it unfolded because I think it is,
it's interesting.
Well,
it starts out with a couple of mastered on tooths
which in the past it would have been tweets.
-- Technically Twitter.
-- Oh, was it Twitter? First?
The person in question evil socket.
They do not have a Mastodon
-- was one of those republish things.
-- Ok.
Yes,
because I think I retweeted,
I don't Twitter anymore.
I mean
-- X sorry, X,
-- who cares? I'm calling it Twitter until I die. I literally don't care.
So, you know, this
interrupt, somebody pointed out that this gives whoever acquires Twitter slash X.
The easiest way to fix the brand, which is we're dropping X and going back to Twitter,
I, no one's gonna acquire it.
It's, it might be, penny's not like
-- it's not gonna be that expensive to
-- acquire.
I'm willing to purchase Twitter for $17.
Actually, the thing is, it has such a negative value. Now,
the cost of running it versus the actual revenue is,
have they sorted all of their lawsuits with their employees or former?
I'd be shocked if they have anyway. Ok. So this person Evil Socket,
they, they tweet
that they found in.
I'm I'm gonna read the some of the, the highlights here because it's, it's,
it's spicy.
They say there's an unauthenticated R ce remote code execution
in all the new Linux
like that.
They put the canoe there,
all the new Linux systems plus others in parentheses disclosed three weeks ago,
right?
First of all,
if you're a security person that is like your
spidey senses just went off and you're like,
oh, what's going on?
And then they say full disclosure happening less than two weeks still,
no CV E assigned there should be at least three, possibly four, ideally six.
Ok. What do we get? Four out of this? I think
anyway, still not working. Fix which whatever.
And then it says canonical redhead and others has confirmed the severity 9.9
check screenshot and then they have a screenshot of some CV SS calculator
because as we all know, screenshots cannot be faked,
obviously,
who cares? You can just make up crap. It's the internet.
Well, it's, it's, but this is an interesting thing because I've seen
a
of people posting screenshots and posting videos of things to like,
prove that it's real.
And I'm like, like we've literally remember at Red Hat, like I had,
we had people sending in videos of like, hey, I found a flaw in Linux.
Here's a video of me
exploiting
for a long time.
And I remember when I worked at Elastic and I, I was,
I built their bug brownie program and we stood it up.
We at first didn't have a policy of like no videos
and people were just sending us videos with no other evidence.
And we're like, this is meaningless to us. We need like
something, send us a a URL to test, send us anything.
And so we had to say like no videos. But anyway,
so then, but here's, here's the bit that I think is most interesting.
It says I've spent the last three weeks of my sabbatical,
working full time in this research, reporting,
coordinating and so on with the sole purpose of helping and pretty much only
got patronized because the devs just can't
accept that their code is crap responsible disclosure
no more.
Uh The other thing is uh which devs
specifically he talking about because cups is forked,
no cups is not forked.
There's only one cups. There's the open printing cups.
-- Yeah, that one because, but then there's the original one that's not
-- cups anymore.
Apple,
apple bought cups and then they spun it back up. So that is, that is Cups.
Well, yeah, because they had like, one commit in like, five years or something.
-- Goofy.
-- I still don't know why they bought that but whatever.
Oh, well, because it runs on Mac O,
-- like, that's the Mac O printing subsystem. But now
-- here's the thing.
So this person
puts this tweet out
and of course,
the first thing that any good security person is going
to do is they're going to start like looking at,
what is this person putting out on Twitter?
What are they talking about? What's going on?
What's their history? And
the thing is though, if you look kind of back in time a little bit,
this person had a handful of other tweets where
they talked about some of the things they found,
right?
And they were talking about
this is from a couple days before the, the the thing I just read
where they just said, I'm finding myself in a situation I've never been in before.
I don't know what to do.
I found an unauthenticated R ce on a very
common good new Linux network service enabled by default on
ubuntu in several other majors.
That's data point number one,
right?
Already confirmed public facing services, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah,
the main author
bonded, blah, blah, blah, blah blah. Should I just go public disclosure?
What am I supposed to do?
And it sounds like they ended up going to cert and,
and kind of letting cert help with the disclosure.
But here's the thing. First of all, they said it is enabled by default on ubuntu.
So obviously, what's the first thing we do?
We install
ubuntu and we say what are the things enabled
by default that are also listening on the network?
There are two things, there is system D and there is cups.
And I remember when,
when I think I, I sent you the first tweet
and then we had a little chat and I'm like,
I think it's system D because obviously like
from the perspective of difficult developers installed everywhere,
remote RC, I'm like, it's got to be system D.
System D has,
has a legendarily difficult to work with upstream and it's a little better.
Now, some of the, the original developers left,
there's some new blood in there that's a little easier.
But
what's sad
to me is this kind of stuff poisons the well around system D.
And you know, there's been a lot of pushback on it. But it's like,
trust me when I say we do not want to go back
to writing shell scripts to make your GPS USB device work.
When you plug it in like system D is the future
-- we had to move to
-- it. It already won
it.
So anyway, OK, so they do that right? And I'm thinking, OK,
then,
then they, they put a,
an image up of a showdown, I query search. I don't know of a map, right?
And obviously that is meant to be proving how widely deployed
the service they just found the the issue in was,
but here's the thing when you look at it, it's a really weird map because Korea
has
-- like
-- to be clear, South Korea, is
-- it
-- it, what did, what does it
say?
Well,
because can you imagine if we actually found a service that was heavy in North Korea?
-- That would be extremely weird.
-- I, I don't know.
Let's look at that. I have a picture actually.
-- Let me, let me look at, yeah,
-- Republic of Korea. So South Korea Republic of
Korea.
Yes. Korea comma Republic of Yes. Ok.
So, and it shows 20,000 and the next is US with 10,000.
So like that's a pretty significant grouping, right?
So the first thing I do is I'm like, well, I'm gonna go check show Dan,
so I check show Dan.
And
if you search for cups,
I got almost exactly the same results.
The numbers were a little off which was filtering time of day, whatever it,
it could be a million things right now.
It says 14,000 for the US.
Does it for cups?
Well, they probably turned their cup scanner up to an 11, right?
And then
you look at
like system D
and there's literally nothing, nothing, nothing reports back as system D,
which doesn't mean it's not on the internet.
It more means system D doesn't report back in a meaningful way that shin
can interpret.
So I look at all this and I send you a message, I'm like, it's cups,
it's definitely cups.
And so then of course, you know, you start poking around in the cups, github
repo and stuff. And actually a, a guy I work with
made a comment to me that
he read this person's comments
and then the first thing he did was he went
and looked at what repos has this person recently forked?
I'm like, oh, that's brilliant. And they'd forked all of the cups, repos.
So it's like, oh, it's obviously cups.
But so here's, here's what I love about. This
is when you are trying to privately disclose, disclose a security issue.
If you say anything in public, no matter how inconsequential you think it might be,
you're leaking valuable information. And here's the thing, I'm not that smart.
There are people who do this kind of research every day, all day
that I'm sure they saw the first tweet and probably
had it figured out in like less than 10 minutes.
This all took me like two hours.
You know what it reminds this reminds me of is like the Geoguessr
where they learn just all these obscure facts of like, how are roads mark,
what do road signs look like?
The plants, the vegetation, the dirt
and like,
that's like what you and I have done when it comes to like open source security.
-- Oh, no,
-- not me. I'm not gonna pretend I have that.
Well, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
But you have an inherent knowledge of open source. And you know,
for example, the fact that if somebody says, hey, this guy just recently cut forks,
you're immediately like, 00, ok.
That's
like, you know what I mean?
That brings alarm bells for you.
You might not have thought to do it yourself.
But when somebody says it out loud, you're like, oh yeah, I get it.
That's and also saying like it's, it's installed by default that
tu like firing a boon.
I
actually had to download the IO I did not have an
Iso boom too. I've been running almost all de
and lately but
download the
ISO install it. Look at it, run that stat like boom, I see it right away. Right.
Like it took,
I don't know, 1520 minutes maybe.
And most of that time was just spent because I was on
Wi Fi instead of my wired connection on that particular computer.
And that's the thing when you have these kinds of skills and this depth of knowledge.
Yeah, this is really easy.
It's like the lock picking lawyer, you know,
all his videos are like five minutes or shorter.
That's what always gets me. I'm waiting for the day he posted a video
that's like 20 minutes long. And then that's like, ok, now I know which lock to buy.
I doubt it. I doubt there's any lock he can't pick in 10 minutes.
But that's the thing. Right. Like it, you're right though, is even, even
just tiny hints like 100%. You can find my house on satellite imagery. Why?
Because I have two trampolines in my backyard. Boom. Like I've talked myself,
you figure you live in Edmonton, which is not a secret. You've talked about it a lot.
And yes,
you say you have two trampolines in your yard and there
are probably some like Geoguessr types that could find your house in
less than an hour. We'll say probably a lot less than an hour.
I'm not going to dig up the video, but I remember on my games done quick.
They had like a Geoguessr, I don't know, game or match or something where these,
these two people were just cooperating.
Basically,
they were playing the two player Geoguessr game
where only one person can see the screen,
the other one can see the map and you have to like, explain to them what you see
like.
Right. Yeah, you have to like, figure it out.
Well, no one person sees the like road view and the second person
has.
No, they, they, they had,
they're zooming in on the map trying to figure out what the other person and they,
they can only communicate with voice, right?
You can't see each other screen.
But anyway, they did like a, a demo before this, right,
where one of the users were like,
here's how this works and he would open a screen and be like, oh,
we see this on this side and this over here and there's over here like this is,
and they're driving on the left.
This is Germany or this is Ireland or whatever. My favorite, he pulls one up.
He's like, this is Japan for too many reasons to explain. He just moves on.
-- And I'm like, oh, my goodness. That's so funny.
-- Well, that's the thing, right?
Like, for example, if you drop me in Germany,
I can tell you how far north or south I am based on the shape of churches.
No,
the more,
the more onion doughy they get.
Oh,
interesting.
Interesting. Anyway. Ok. So
that, that whole, like, don't, don't talk about what, you know, like,
-- that's obviously really hard as humans and
-- don't even talk about that.
You're doing that
because
there are people who, when they say I found a vulnerability, I'm like, oh,
you found another vulnerability and x and they're like,
yeah, I'm like, because that's what you do,
right?
There are some security researchers that are like, that's,
there's like they have a specialty.
So when they say I found something, it's like,
well, it's probably the thing, they found stuff in the last 50 times.
-- So
-- I remember there was some time ago when I,
I can't remember which particular TLS bug this was, but there was
one of those TLS bugs back when people were, like,
able to take
like, compress TLS streams and things like that and,
and just discern information about them.
And someone basically says, like, oh,
I found a bug in this TLS version with this um this library.
And I remember some of the really smart security researchers were like, oh,
it's probably this bug
and they were completely right and,
and it leaked basically because someone gave out
what seemed like no useful information at all.
And the experts were like, yeah, we know exactly what this is.
This is almost definitely this problem
and it's, it's fascinating and wild and, but now as humans,
we love talking about what we're doing.
-- Like there is nothing more exciting than learning.
-- I have a secret,
right?
Or learning a new thing and being like, let me,
let me show you the new thing I'm doing like this is exciting and fun
-- and it, it's a very human thing. Well, they
-- want validation for
sure, for sure.
It's just, it's,
it's part of what makes humans so interesting is
we have to talk about what we're interested in.
Well, I mean, and maybe we'll post a link to it,
but remember Will Wheaton talking about like,
what is a geek and what is a nerd that famous?
I think it was Comic Con talk he gives
Yeah. Yeah. Right. Maybe post that.
-- But that is the essence of this for
-- sure, for sure. Now
there's another piece of this
that I think is an interesting conversation and
that is the whole responsible disclosure no more.
You and I both
have been part of probably hundreds or thousands
of we'll call them co ordinated disclosure events.
I'm not going to use the word
responsible disclosure because responsible disclosure is a term
that was co opted by Microsoft to me do what Microsoft tells you to do.
And if you don't,
-- we're going to yell at you
-- well or not pay you a bug bounty or not put you on the
list or not give you credit. And that,
that was a huge thing like when I worked at Isight and I defense
that
credit was like
they would do whatever they needed to get
that credit because that credit sold subscriptions.
Right?
Well, and, and that's even, I mean,
bug bounties work the same way where if you don't play by the bug money rules,
actually, technically, this was just at the cusp of bug bounties because actually,
was it eyesight
burners was the first company to pay for exploits like to pay a bug
might
have been.
No, we, we were, we, we were like, well, the first legal,
obviously
the black market was doing it before us
but, and it was funny too because we were like,
we, we immediately tell the vendor to want to get it fixed.
Like that's our whole shick and everybody thought we
were being evil and it's like we're not evil,
we're not rich enough to be evil.
I remember that
anyway.
But here's the thing,
it is really hard to be part of any sort of coordinate disclosure event,
especially if there's a large company involved.
And obviously, in this case, there's a, there was a a again
another image posted to Twitter
that showed the screenshot of the companies
involved on the cert reporting platform.
And
Apple was on the list. HP was on the list. Dell was on the list.
Like these are not small organizations,
they are legendarily large and they're going to be hard to
work with because they also have
-- significant resources internally
-- what's happened.
And uh open SSL is a perfect example of this
where Open SSL has learned that they cannot work with these
vendors because every single vendors like we're big and important and
we have like three bajillion TV S running this vulnerable thing
and thus the world will end if you don't let us do it our way.
And of course, they all want it done their way, which is like,
can we basically hold off on this as long as possible
without having to actually do anything?
And so like,
I believe at one point openness sl straight up said like
you kind of, everybody gets the same notification.
We don't do like pre notification because we just can't, it's, you know,
same thing with the Linux kernel.
It's like we can't make a tier list of like who's more and less important.
Like, obviously to some degree you could like,
like steam de or maybe less important than
all the oil refineries in the world. Running Linux.
But at the same time, like there's
all the stuff running Linux,
like breaking it out into what's critical and not critical. It's, it's impossible
-- and it's subjective.
-- It is, it's an impossible task.
And right, and this is exactly why open SSL ended up doing what they did.
And I get that, I'm completely receptive to this.
Well, because also it, it kind of comes back to the,
even if you want to do it the way the companies want you to do it, it,
-- it won't
-- work and it never does.
You end up, well,
you leak,
you leak crap all the time because there's someone talking about something.
Well, companies leak stuff. We've had that happen. Right.
It's, it's persistent for sure.
My favorite always was, I remember when we were at Red Hat,
we would watch lots of other bug trackers
from different Linux distributions and projects and things
and it was very common.
They would file a public bug and then hide it and we would catch it before they hit it.
Well, that happened with oracle and Myers QL and they totally, you know, II,
I was like, literally just like,
I
want to sign this anyways. They were a nightmare to deal with and I just gave up.
But I mean, the other thing to remember is like,
it's not a secret once you've told 10 or 20 or 30 or 40 companies,
I'm not even gonna say people because there's like, more than
that number of people. Like, there's,
it's just, it's a, it's, it's ridiculous to me that,
yeah, like every time government conspiracy stuff comes up, I'm like,
all that stuff ends up being public at
some point because people suck at keeping secrets.
Right?
And I, my favorite is always if someone asks one time, it's like,
do you actually think the government is competent enough to have done that?
And they're like,
no.
-- Yeah, the government is just people like us
-- basically
back to the. So
I,
yeah, that's the thing.
So the,
the whole thing leaked and of course it turned out to basically be a nothing burger.
I feel like the co ordinated disclosure like let's keep secrets. Thing
is definitely on a downward trend these days because
a lot of things just come out well,
it doesn't work anymore.
It probably never did occur.
It also with the number of vulnerabilities we're handling.
-- Now,
-- do
-- you
-- remember when Google Project Zero said 90 day embargo,
-- no questions
-- asked.
People lost their minds.
Right? And then it turned out everything's fine.
And I think this is an example of, back in those days you would have organizations,
especially the big ones, like a Microsoft or an Oracle or someone like that.
-- That would literally take years to fix a bug.
-- Oh,
yeah. Those timelines were bonkers. Like, I think one was eight years with oracle
and it was a normal
code execution. It wasn't like a minor thing.
Yeah. Right. Right. Exactly. And, and if you think
the
A PT style Attackers
didn't know about this stuff, like you're, you're fooling yourself.
Of course, they did. They have people on the inside, they're watching everything.
I mean, heck, I remember when we, we knew vendor
se
the,
the, like, secret mailing list for Linux distributions, we knew it was backdoor.
Well, and it was,
it, I mean, not to throw solar designer under the bus, but it's run by a guy in Russia.
-- Like, no,
-- no,
no. So solar designer runs the distro list now.
I don't know if he's moved the servers out of Russia.
I know he was trying to get funding from the,
the Linux foundation to help with that vendor
se was run by, um, Germans.
It was the sous guys and we knew it was hacked and we couldn't do anything about it.
And that's actually because eventually we just shut, the vendor
was just killed and like, we can't fix it like it, it's dead by.
And that's when solar then set up Os S security
and distro list which now there's like a bunch of distro list variants,
which is where the distributions can speak in private about various things.
Why is this run by a single human being?
Because he's the only one who is willing to do it.
Here's the reality. This is like you and I argue about this in private all the time.
Like the whole, this is the security, the market wants.
That is the security, the market it wants because when,
when Red Hat or Su or anyone else was asked to step up and help with this,
none of them did.
But solar designer was willing to do it and it's no doubt been significant cost
and time on his part over the how many decades he's been doing this now?
Well, I mean, case in point,
you can see Red Hat CV as she once falls off a cliff after I left
like it's done.
I, yeah, that doesn't surprise
me
again though. This is what is, what is the market want? Right?
And, and the market doesn't want good security. The market wants good pr,
well,
I think the market wants good security but also I want the good
-- security without having to pay for it or do anything or
-- no,
that doesn't.
That's not how the market works. That means the market doesn't want
it.
Yeah.
Well, the market's not willing to pay a market rate for it like there.
-- Then
-- the market doesn't want it. That's how that works
anyway. Anyway. So, here's my take on this.
I do think the researcher
-- is a little complaining.
-- Oh, there was, there was way too much drama.
It was very drama filled. And I think the reporter was definitely part of that.
I'm not going to put this, let, let this person get off the hook by any means.
-- No, 100
-- percent. Like they, they created this drama.
But here's the thing
I think given the way everything has been working for
the last 20 plus years in the world of security,
I do think embargoes are less important than they maybe were in the past.
I feel like most of the truly impressive security vulnerabilities we have
seen in the last couple of years have not been privately reported.
There was not time to patch and, and test and all this.
We were thrown into the fire and quite
frankly, I don't think they turned out that bad.
Well, there's also a lot more compensating controls now, like back in the day,
having
firewall was like, whoa,
-- you could buy them. People sold firewalls.
-- Yeah.
Well,
like literally the Linux administrator security guide talks
about stuff like turning off default services,
right?
That was a big deal in the nineties that was like
-- a major way to do security was turning
-- off the cups.
Resolver
is one of the ways to mitigate this.
But then that became like an industry standard where,
remember at one point finally Red Hat was like, yeah,
everything's turned off by default except ssh, so you can SSH.
N
and that took a major amount of teeth gnashing because customers are like,
I have to turn stuff on and it's inconvenient and it's
a pain in the butt and it just doesn't work,
you know,
and we have a lot more compensating controls now where
the reality too is everything. Every piece of software we have,
we know has remote code executions in it
because it did, like, and
-- they're not all fixed or gone,
-- they will never be fixed if it's written in C,
even if it's not written in C, it probably has problems.
Yeah, I was gonna say, even if it's written in rust, you'll still have logic bugs.
It, yeah, it just takes away the memory safety issues.
Uh, but the thing is like, we, we can't make a perfectly safe, secure the world.
Right.
We just recently had an oil well, catch fire and explode and, like,
really harm five people down in Calgary,
uh, made the news and it's like,
obviously,
you know,
there's an incentive to make these things somewhat safe
because they're really expensive when they blow up.
But, you know, we can't make them 100% safe
and for sure to do, like, we talked about that with the house fire stuff.
Like,
could we build fireproof buildings with fire suppression that can't burn down?
Absolutely. We could,
would it be cost effective? No,
no,
no, for sure, for sure. But I mean, this is the concept of risk.
I mean, this is one of the things I think
the infosec universe has gotten wrong over the years is we try to eliminate risk.
We don't try to reduce and control it. I think it's getting better in recent years.
But I think fundamentally
an enormous amount of our industry was built around this concept of elimination,
which doesn't work.
I think what and what you just said is, it's,
I think the problem is not trying to eliminate risk.
It's thinking that we can
and we can
and that's,
that's a maturity step of saying, you know, like,
yeah, we can't accomplish this perfectly. But can we make it bearable?
Can we make it? So,
you know, the world works basically, like,
we don't have constant major cell phone outages like Verizon
or Rogers here in Canada did that one time,
you know, maybe we should have some change control.
-- So we don't push out a bad B GP route. Take down the half the internet
-- or crowd strike.
Yeah.
You know, like,
and apparently crowdstrike had really poor internal testing
and gating of updates and everything and like,
and, and, and, but here's the thing, I would point out it was totally fine
until the one day it wasn't.
That's right. That's right.
And I mean, that's, that's kind of the story of disaster. It was fine until it wasn't.
Well, I mean, I've, I've accidentally left my front door unlocked and then, like,
come home
and gone to grab a package, you know, go into the garage,
come out through the front door and look at my front door as I'm leaving.
And I'm like, oh, I didn't lock it. Oops.
You know, and it was unlocked for a couple of hours.
Like, granted,
I would have gotten doorbell alerts that somebody came to my front door
and I would have noticed if somebody, like, walked in through my front door. But
the reality is,
it's not like people are constantly trying to break into my house and, like,
jiggle the front door and see if it's unlocked.
-- Right.
-- Right. Well, and this is how disastrous work is, is
there is
generally speaking, a disaster isn't like one
singular event.
It's like 10 things that all went wrong at
the same time that led to some horrific disaster.
Yeah.
And we don't think like that in security. We often think of singular events.
So, anyway. Ok.
Ok,
we're kind of running ourselves out of time here and I feel
like we have danced all around this because that was the point.
-- I
-- have
-- a proposal.
The new metric for
vulnerability disclosure
should be measured by causing the least amount of drama. I mean,
no,
and, and I don't mean like you, you're gonna roll over and play nice to the companies.
I mean, things, like, for example, Google saying 90 days
done
and, like, the companies threw tantrums and Google's like, no, it's like a parent,
right?
Like I hear you screaming. I see that you're upset.
-- I'm still not buying you seven candy bars.
-- I mean, so, look, Google was in a position.
They could
exert that pressure with impunity.
They, they weren't worried about very much if you are a security researcher.
That's part of a bug bounty.
Yeah, you're not going to get paid if you don't play by their rules.
That's how that works.
Yeah. Well, and that's part of the not causing drama. Like
they have set these rules if you want to get paid, you do it their way.
I, I guess that's fair
if you don't agree with it, you can also just push it out publicly and not get paid.
I mean, and, and that's kind of this sort of situation, right.
This is an example of the researcher
to the best of my knowledge was not compensated in any way for this
and they tried to do the right thing and they
got hung up in the madness of coordinate disclosure,
which is really hard to do.
And they did say in one of their many, many messages
that the ubuntu security people were doing a marvelous job trying to help, like,
bridge all the gaps and keep everything under control, which it's very hard
to be in that position. Like I've been there. Many times it sucks.
Everyone hates you because no matter what you do,
someone is disappointed.
Well, and that's why con honestly,
if somebody came to me and said I have a massive security flaw,
I really don't want to deal with it.
I'd be like, do you want me to just post it anonymously on your behalf? So, it's done.
-- So.
-- Ok.
So let, let's close out with this. Let's say they did,
let's say they did post
not anonymously. Let's say they posted it as themselves.
How many people would be like, oh, good job.
And how many people would be?
Like,
you're a terrible person and you're destroying
the planet by posting this publicly.
-- I think
-- there would be a lot of people
complaining that it was posted publicly with no notice
and you can't win. Right. There's, there's no way to win this.
I, I think if I was a security researcher and I found, I found something bad,
I don't know what I would do. I would think about it.
-- I'd probably talk to a couple of people I know first, but I
-- have
straight up notice things and websites I use and just gone.
I mean, sometimes you do that.
-- I, I get
-- that I'm not going to try and interact with the bank.
-- Uh
-- I would not want to interact with the bank,
but that's also kind of different. Like
that's a singular customer essentially of,
of like the, the bug, right?
Versus let's say you find an R CE in open SSH.
What do you do?
You go to open SSH and be like, hey, I found this bug. Would you just post it in public?
Are we talking like, like a like basically like worst case scenario,
single packet remote,
the worst
case scenario, the absolute worst bug you could possibly imagine.
I mean, what would you do? Like
-- there's, I, I could make arguments in every direction
-- my thought would be, oh,
and this is a kind of a jerk move.
But I know enough people in the industry that I would just
anonymously send it to a bunch of them with AC C and it's
-- their problem. Now.
-- That's true. That would be one of the ways to do that.
But the secret is like,
I know these people, I know who they are.
I know their personal email addresses and
stuff like that's not the normal situation
-- like we're cheating basically.
-- I mean, and that's part of it too.
Like, for example, this reporter went to Sirte,
I would not go to Sirte in a billion years.
I've dealt with CT and they are a very heavy,
difficult organization to work with. I found
and that may have changed in the last like five or 10 years since I've talked to them.
But I've, I've never had a lot of positive experience with cert,
remember that uh point of sale system company in New Zealand found that
uh http or http S proxy bug that affected like multiple web servers
and reported it to Red Hat.
And then like I ended up having to report it
to Microsoft because we literally said to these guys,
like,
do you want us to help?
And they're like, yeah, they're like, we make point of sale software.
We don't want to deal with this global security thing.
Also time zones suck because we're in New Zealand
and like we handled it for them and it was,
it was tedious, I would say, not a nightmare, but it was tedious.
-- It is
-- easy to say, just don't, don't try to do coordinate disclosure. Right.
Very easy to say. Would I do that?
I know I wouldn't work with c my,
my suspicion is if I found something bad and it affected a Red hat,
I would go to them just because I know a lot of Red Hat people.
I know they're gonna help me out. I
think that's part of the story is there's also an aspect of
how much personal pain and suffering am I going to endure?
If I try to do this, we'll say the right way and we'll put the right way in. Quote,
what you just said, Red Hat will help me. Why have Red Hat helped you?
Why not just have Red Hat do the work? It affects them.
-- Well, that's what I mean, they would do all of the work.
-- Oh, ok.
That wasn't clear, like it sounded like you were going to still be involved.
-- No, I would expect them to do, like, 99% of the work I
-- would just throw, I would,
I would basically tie a note to a brick and throw it through the window and run away.
I mean, maybe, and that's the thing. Like,
there are other companies that I know would be very difficult to work
with in an instance like this and those are the places I might not
have any desire to interact with.
Yeah, I might not even,
I wouldn't even throw a brick through their window. Maybe not.
And I think that's part of it and I think that, that also kind of tells the story of the,
the things that are truly significant
that are going to affect a large percentage of the internet
are almost certainly going to be an open source software
-- or windows,
-- even, even windows.
I don't think there are that many windows bugs that would, I would care about.
-- Not
-- Peter.
Maybe. I mean, that was not, that was an attack though. It wasn't a bug. Right.
Well, no, it was a, it was a known security flaw that had been patched and leaked and
I can't even wrap my head around that because I don't, I don't even,
I don't even run windows like there's,
there's a 0% chance of me finding a windows vulnerability.
Like, it's just not going to happen.
Right.
And so I, I don't know. I mean,
I don't have a good answer for this. I feel like
I feel like if I can't tell Red Hat or Ubuntu,
maybe Debbie and, or su
I would feel bad for Debbie though because they're volunteers. But, like,
I don't know what I would do,
but I think I'm willing to say if it's something that they would,
those large Linux distributions were involved with,
I would almost certainly go to them right away
because I know
I would have a reasonable experience.
I don't think I would ever go to cert,
I think I would opt for a public disclosure over going to cert,
I might report something via a bug bounty. Maybe it would depend who it is.
Again, I think that's part of that whole, like
depending on the company, I'm going to think long and hard about this.
But yeah, I mean, I guess, you know, that's, that's the story here, Kurt, right?
Like that's the thing to tell is
there is no singular answer to problems like this.
It's easy to say you should always do responsible disclosure.
It's easy to say you should never do responsible disclosure.
But this is like everything.
It's this big muddy gray space in the middle
and that's
in this particular instance, like
it got reported and it got dealt with it did leak early.
So I wouldn't say it was a particularly co ordinated event.
Ok. I've got one last kind of point to,
to, to leave on.
So once
we figured out it was cuts,
I was thinking I could publish this
and say, hey, everyone, this
is Cups.
And the reason I'm telling you is because I'm not smart
and smarter people than me have certainly figured this out.
But then at the same time, it's like, if I do that,
if I do that,
I'm gonna be the bad guy to a whole bunch of
people and I just didn't want to deal with that crap.
Ditto. I like, literally look, it's like, like I'm like, should we post about this
-- and,
-- and yeah, yeah, it so I, I don't know.
I mean, this stuff is always so hard to do and I guess
-- there's, there's just never a good answer.
-- Is there any possible benefit?
Not just to us, but will this actually make the situation any better?
I think it might have actually because it would have made everyone go
public finally instead of pretending it was a secret because it wasn't true.
And if it is cups then everybody's like, ok,
I don't have that uh exposed to the internet.
So me,
I
mean, yeah, that's basically kind of how I felt about it.
Well, except a lot of people do like 100,000 people have cups on the internet. So,
yeah, but I mean, at the scale of humanity, like 100,000 people have a cup of cite
-- in their bathroom
-- and that's not a lot. Right. Right. Ok.
All right. So in summary, we have no idea.
Try not to make the world a worse place,
but it's not your job necessarily to go out
of your way at significant personal cost to try and
help make the world a better place. Like
be reasonable.
And I think that boils back down to a lot of this open source developer
burnout where they really are taking the weight of the worlds on their shoulders.
And it's like, like one of the no, like it,
no,
like companies that benefit from this and make money from this.
-- Maybe they can step up and do a bit more.
-- Agreed. All right, I'm calling it.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you for listening. Go to
source Security, podcast.com. Head up to
shout, Susy Podos
says podcast. Hashtag I'm as
on Kurt. Have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You
-- too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.