Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 78 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
We've been doing this for a while now.
And if, when we started,
you had told me that we would have an episode where we talk about a,
a missile attack warning.
I would have said you're crazy.
Yeah, I, I'd agree. These things aren't supposed to go wrong like this.
I,
I
don't even know what to say.
I, I actually,
I wrote a blog post that that's going to be published at some point in the near future.
And like I started out and I'm just like,
II, I don't even know how to frame this because
I don't know what I would do if, if something like this happened, it's just anyway,
why don't before we get too crazy,
why don't you explain to the audience what event has just occurred
that has like made all of our heads explode.
So Saturday morning, there was apparently a shift change at the
Ha Hawaii Emergency Management Agency
and apparently as part of the shift change, they test
the emergency alarm.
Uh sorry, the emergency alert system and the emergency alert system.
Uh, well, the old timey parts are like actual physical, like giant sirens that go,
you know, w or whatever.
Do you guys have that in Canada?
We used to and actually there used to be one down by the traffic circle on 107 to 1 42nd.
But they removed them about. Hm. I'm gonna go with 30 some years ago
-- because quite frankly
-- the alarms,
the
physical giant sirens from like the 19 sixties,
we still have them all over the place. In fact, at noon on Wednesdays they go off,
you
-- probably get like tornadoes and stuff. Right.
-- We do. Actually, that's true. The
tornadoes are when they generally go off.
I know if it's not noon on Wednesday, like something bad is going to happen
unless a tornado happens on. No. Well, we'll get, that's another
failure
we'll get into.
But
on
Wednesday,
yeah, Edmonton is lucky. We had a tornado
known as the Edmonton tornado. So
we don't, it's not really a problem
anyways.
So, uh, the emergency alert system, uh, is also, you know,
where you get that horrible noise on your TV.
That sounds like a modem connecting,
which is actually audio encoded information followed by the e,
you know, splitting beat
and then whatever message, you know,
and then also now because, you know, we're not living in 1990
although the telecoms are still apparently,
uh, they can just broadcast alerts out to, like, all the cell phones. Right.
Which is, let's face it, realistically,
I, I don't know anybody now that,
like,
doesn't have a cell phone
to put it bluntly,
except
for maybe my kids and it's more a matter of we're buying them this year.
There are corner cases. I'm willing to agree to that.
I think fundamentally you're probably covering more than
80% of the population at this point.
Well,
and more to the point they have their cell phone
with them and it's turned on whereas like a TV,
I,
I don't, I haven't had broadcast TV now in
seven years.
Yeah, seven years.
Um, I admit I have it but it's rarely on
or the other classic one being radio,
which again, you know, very few people have a radio on, like,
some people at work or whatever, I guess.
But in general it's not like we listen to the radio
all the time, like
whatever.
Uh, so anyways during shift change they test the alarm, the alert system
and apparently somebody literally fat fingered it
and sent out an alarm,
an alert saying, you know, inbound missile
which
like, not a drill.
And then they sent out another one about two minutes later saying this is not a drill.
This is for real.
Right. Right.
And
that's the thing that kind of blows my mind is when I read this story,
the first thing I thought of is like, well,
why didn't you just like send a whole bunch of sorry, just to test
say there's no fire when you said there's a
fire until you officially can say there's no fire.
And that requires for example, getting the military to confirm that there is no.
So, so
yes, that I agree with that, but from what I gather,
they knew within three minutes
that it was verifiably false
and then it took them 38 minutes to send a whoops, sorry message,
which is,
well, this is one of those
minutes, man, when you think you're going to die is a long, long time.
Well, a perfect example of this is during the Edmonton tornado back in the eighties,
uh Alberta environment,
basically kind of didn't know what to do
because they've never dealt with this before.
And so, for example, they had a confirmed tornado touchdown sighting.
And uh my mom used to work there and like, literally, she's like, so like,
what do we do now?
Do we hide in the parkade?
Like do we move to the middle of the building?
Like who, how do we send out an emergency alert? Like
it literally had never come up.
And so the tornado alert was delayed quite a bit because basically, like they,
they didn't have,
well, there's two parts of this one, you have to have a plan and two,
you have to actually test the plan and train to the plan.
So,
so you're saying they knew there was a tornado
and because they didn't exactly know what to do,
they didn't tell people there was
-- a,
-- there was no way to tell them really.
There was no plan, there was no training who do we contact.
And more to the point, like, once we've done that do, like,
literally do we all go hide in the park?
Like, what's the deal?
Do we drive home
straight up that?
No. Seriously.
Actually, that's the whole point of the blog post I wrote was the fact that like,
I don't know what to do.
Well,
I kind of do now because actually you and I
did some talking about this over slack or yes slack,
no signal uh signal yesterday.
But this is one of those things that like,
I didn't know what to do
during a missile attack. So,
like,
what would I have done?
And, and look, I'm, I'm
one of the things I've realized is like, basically in almost any situation,
the best advice is just don't do anything right?
Like sit down and cover your head literally like rock in the corner and
-- sob
-- is this literally happened at probably about the best time it could,
which was a Saturday morning
-- because imagine if this had happened when people had their kids at school?
-- Oh
my goodness, man. That would have been crazy. Holy cow.
Although I bet schools have a very defined lockdown procedure for
funny enough, I bet they schools probably have a plan for this.
It's, I'm sure it's in an old binder from the fifties.
That's anyways.
Um, but, uh, the real pro, well, for example,
one of the real problems in Hawaii was everybody was going, some of the people,
not everybody, rather, some of the people were going batshit crazy and, like,
driving down the wrong side of the road at 100 miles an hour,
apparently trying to get wherever they felt they needed to go.
But I believe that because people panic and they, they make poor decisions
and no, I, I totally get it. And actually that's one of the things
I talk about as well in, in my post was that look, when,
when you don't know what you're doing,
you can't plan for the unknown and,
and like poor decisions are basically the
-- only decision
-- I'm gonna disagree with you.
You can kind of roughly plan for the unknown by having some general guidelines,
like, for example,
uh having seven days of food and water in your basement
because something undefinable bad might happen that,
you know, prevents food and water from being available for a few days. Right.
Um, the real problem is like these, you know, these people had absolutely no plan.
Like, what do, what do I do? Do I hide? Do I get my family together? Do I,
you know, what do I do with the pets? Do I let them loose? Do I put them in a kennel?
Um,
I
mean, it used to be that people would have, you know,
maybe a shelter in their basement and,
or at least a few days of food and water or for example,
know that maybe you want to fill out the bathtub
with water so that you have a few weeks of water
in the event of the water supply being cut off.
I mean, you know, I, I won't disagree with you.
There, there are probably certain things you could do and I think you're getting
maybe a little more advanced,
but for example,
here we can have a really bad snowstorm that messes up food deliveries.
That, that has never happened.
But realistically, I mean, where I live here in Edmonton. Yeah, it could.
Ok. Look, now, you, you just made the point. I was hoping we'd get to eventually is,
yes, it is conceivable that could happen,
but it is far more likely that you're going to slip
on the ice in your driveway and hit your head.
You have people worried about planning for, you know,
crazy events when just like go buy some freaking salt for your driveway, man.
And, and you're going to be way better off than that. Right.
Well, to me, part of it too is like, it's like having a spare tire.
If you have a spare tire and you have a flat tire, then life is annoying but not so bad.
But if you're in the middle of nowhere with a flat tire and no spare,
you kind of now have potentially a crisis
-- at the
-- same time though.
Are you carrying around extra antifreeze, extra oil,
extra transmission fluid and, and you know, a few extra spark plugs just in case,
right?
Like
those things don't break, but I do get flat tires.
Well, they, they do break, but I think flat tires are, are infinitely more common
than many others.
Well, and not only that, like,
I guess if you kind of look at the,
the events that could happen to a car because let's face it,
everyone's cars are breaking down all the time.
Uh, flat tire is pretty universal
and then it's like long tail after that, right?
Where, who knows what's going to happen
and the vast majority of other things you just can't prepare for.
And that's kind of,
that's the thing I keep thinking of in the context of something like this is,
I mean,
how do you just, how do you deal with something like that? Right.
It's crazy to think about.
Well, I mean, this is for me where it comes back to, you know, for example,
most government, uh,
sort of preparedness websites go with the general guidelines
of having three days of food and water,
you know, so you basically can like,
bunker down in your house for three days and not die or get hungry.
But not only that, I,
I think that one is more important because in most emergency situations, like,
don't go anywhere
is the most important thing you can do. And if you don't, unless
it's
clear water, you have to go somewhere.
Well, unless it's like one of those, you know, a great example,
being a hurricane where like, no, you need to get out of the way of that thing,
you know. But in general, in many cases, yes,
you know, hurricanes or like a tidal wave.
But in general, like those, well,
hurricanes are a great example because they happen like every year,
several times a year, you know, like we, you know, even, you know,
predefined hurricane season,
like this is not some unexpected. Oh my God, this has never happened before.
No, it's like
literally like
those poor islands in the Caribbean statistically
get clobbered by a hurricane every,
you know, number of X decades
they do.
But now,
like what happened to Puerto Rico is a fine
example of that is not a common occurrence.
And,
and that was the sort of thing that you couldn't
really prepare for in any meaningful way right now.
Granted, I, I mean,
we could argue and I don't want to get into the politics of
it all because obviously the clean up effort is going very badly.
But like
there, there are events you just cannot plan for and, and I think,
well, it's, it's not
for them. It's uneconomical to plan for them.
Ah, yes, that, that does make more sense. Right.
Because actually that's a great point because, like, I could,
I could build a house out of, like,
concrete and lead and probably survive a missile attack.
But the reality is, well, I probably can't afford it. But even if I could, like,
-- I, I probably wouldn't ever see a return on that investment.
-- Right. Exactly.
Well, no,
that's why I think something like three days or seven days of food and water,
you're out maybe 100 bucks.
And it's one of those things where,
you know, I can also use that to go camping
when I have to rotate in
-- early or whatever.
-- I mean, we have a freezer in the basement and,
and we have like,
like a cabinet full of food down there as well where we put the extra stuff.
Right. Like,
I suspect if you, if you have kids
you probably
about
-- three days of
-- food.
Uh, no, if the electricity dies, well, my freezer would probably, it's,
it's relatively,
but
it would be frozen for a week. I, I bet I can get a week out of it.
And, well, that's like, uh, who was it? Someone told me once that in Florida
when the hurricanes are, like, after a hurricane and everyone lost power.
All you smell is cooking meat because everyone's like cooking
all the meat out of their freezer on their grills,
which is pretty sweet.
I mean, one of the best easiest ways to do this is just basically, if you go camping,
then by definition, you, you tend to have kind of the,
the minimum to survive out in the middle of nowhere.
I, I camp in a hotel.
I, I despise camping.
So,
um, but anyway, so back to the, the Hawaiian thing, I mean, so it literally, yeah. Um,
yeah, so quoting the thing,
you just pasted here from a drop down menu on a computer program, he saw two options,
quote, test missile alert, unquote and quote missile alert.
And you want to bet they were next to each other.
Well, it would be a pull
down, right?
So it would be one over the other and you know, yeah,
you missed that click by a millimeter and
I guess there was no like, are you really sure you wanted to click that?
And, and not only that,
how much do you want to bet that the user interface was one of those like train
wreck interfaces that has like 75,000 controls on
it because it can do a million things.
It was designed by someone who has no idea what A U I should look like.
Well, and here we're going to put this XK CD in the show notes, but it's, you know,
welcome to missile missile launch web interface.
Enter the targets coordinates,
enter your email address for our records into your email address again.
That's great. The coordinates are one, the email address is twice.
I mean, how many times I've seen that on like so many things anyways. But
so yeah, I mean, this is a great example of number one you had,
well,
obviously kind of a not great U I that made it very easy to choose the wrong thing.
And then like
when you were doing something that's going to have some real repercussions, like
at a minimum, you know, you do this at three in the morning,
it's going to literally wake everybody up.
Which kind of sucks
actually. So waking people up, that's a really interesting
thing you bring up. So, uh, my wife has a friend in Hawaii
and apparently he had like do not disturb on, on his iphone
and it didn't wake him up like he got the alert
and then he woke up and looked at his phone.
It was like, holy crap, what's going on
and obviously everything was like long done by then.
But, you know, like he, it did not wake him up and I'm thinking
on one side like
it won't be so bad, you know,
this will come still sleeping, everyone's happy, but on the other side, it's like,
man, that seems like a huge problem.
Well, the part of the problem is there's, there's not really
all these emergency alert systems were designed and
implemented like a decade or two ago,
right? Like the current one in Hawaii runs on two G,
not three G, not four G,
probably never five G
um you know, you gotta remember these things were designed back in the day of like,
ok, you know, Conal rad, we're gonna basically interrupt all the radios,
you know, and then they had the TV system with that, you know,
clever audio encoded information and some other hackery to kind of
push this thing through the TV system and even those fail.
Right?
Um And then you, you know, they try to go to cell phones.
Um What's really got me now is, you know,
that official kind of comment of like check the TW like
they, they didn't push out the uh update to the phones as fast as they could,
for example, update their Facebook and Twitter.
So like the emergency management agency,
like literally updated their Facebook page and feed saying like, whoops,
sorry about that,
you know, before they could push it out to the phones and stuff.
I mean, and the reality again is as ridiculous as that is, let's face it.
You know, if something goes weird, what do you, what's the first thing you do?
You Google it,
you check your Twitter, you check your Facebook,
I check Twitter usually because
what was it?
I think I read a thing once that, that some university researchers realized that
they could find out about earthquakes
like two minutes faster using Twitter than, than traditional uh
seismic
equipment they had available to them because on Twitter, obviously,
as soon as anyone feels anything they're like, they're all over it, you know?
And no, I find that because I remember
there was one time something happened, I don't even remember what it was.
It was a fire or, or,
oh, some sort of event I can't for the life of me remember now.
But, yeah, the first thing I did was check Twitter and sure enough,
like people were talking about it and I figured it out.
Well, I mean, Twitter is sort of the ultimate in that sort of crowdsourcing.
You know, you got your trending tags,
right? So as soon as an event has a tag and people start using it.
Yeah, like you're gonna see it
-- whether you like it or not.
-- Exactly.
No. Exactly. But, but I will say
I remember on September 11th, I was, I was working, it was my first job out of college,
in fact.
And like the internet quit working
and now granted, it was a different internet then than it is today necessarily.
But I'm still confident that
if something truly horrific happened,
the internet would probably struggle to keep up.
Well.
Yes and no, because for example,
you've got companies like cloud flare now pushing stuff out to the edges
and making it a lot more robust. Um, do you
remember CNN was their text only web page you could choose.
I do remember.
What event was that?
Oh, that was, that was the recent one.
And it was still like two megs but on 911 CNN went to a text only web page and it was,
at that time it was small but that was
before everyone had a million javascript trackers and websites.
But yeah, yeah, there was something that recently happened
-- and they went to,
-- it was, it was the hurricane
in Puerto
Rico
because, you know, people were on crappy cell phone, you know, with like
everybody else on their cell phone trying to figure out what's going on.
So, yeah,
-- they went to a text only except
-- wasn't the
text only page still like two megabytes or something.
-- It was
-- pretty tight.
Was it,
it was like straight up
like a 1980 well, 19 nineties html web page. Like it was it loaded fast
and that's cool. I mean, I, I think that's totally the way to do it without question.
Yeah,
but um so in this case, I mean, apparently one of the big problems is that the uh
the telecom lobby who we all love.
Um,
speaking of which I gotta go yell at them about a cancellation fee, they charge me
for upgrading my service.
Um But anyways, um
apparently they've been lobbying against, you know,
letting these people have like a proper testing
of the alert system and everything because,
you know, it'd be kind of
difficult
to do and it would acquire some new standards and money and stuff.
So obviously they've pushed against it.
Um
And that's part of the problem here too. Right.
Uh I'm here to quote telecom companies are currently only required
to offer messages with a maximum length of 90 characters.
So that's like half of the old Twitter
uh of text. The one who I sent was 87 characters long until recently.
So called alert, originators could not send clickable links or phone numbers.
The geographic targeting of the alerts isn't particularly good
and they're presented only in English.
Uh And they don't tell people when an alert should become inactive,
which is a great example of something, right?
Because something like a hurricane or a tornado does kind of have a lifespan,
right. Oh, yeah, definitely.
-- Well, even a missile attack technically has a lifespan, right?
-- Yeah.
And then the systems infrastructure is based on two G cell phone
technology which allows the alerts to be pushed to users simultaneously.
Yeah, I mean, so you're, it's the classic thing, you know,
this was amazing and awesome kind of when we built it 10 or 20 years ago.
And
well, here we are,
you know, this is one of those things I think about a lot,
especially in the context of security is
it's really easy to try to say let's go to the new hip thing.
And now mind you, I'm,
I'm not defending these people because I think they're way behind the times.
But,
but it, it,
it can also be tricky to know where to draw the line and to
say this is what we need and this is a level of reliability because
I think uh emergency alerts are one of those examples where they're,
they're aiming for 100% coverage, which of course is impossible.
But let's say they had 75% coverage is that enough is 80% enough is 90% enough.
And of course, it's easy for me to say, oh sure, 80% is enough
until I know someone in the 20%.
And then I'm going to be like,
why didn't you tell my brother or why didn't you tell my uncle or my mom
is
lack of society in general,
has become really safe so much so that a lot of people have forgotten sort of
basic survival things like having a few days of food and water
or like having an emergency radio that's like crank or battery powered.
I, I do have a crank radio actually,
I probably need to replace the battery in my
crank radio because the battery is really old.
I wonder if I could get a capacitor thing to put
in there because capacitors charge quickly and they never wear out.
I should do that. That'd be fun.
I
mean,
it's,
yeah, I don't know, like on the one hand,
I do definitely want to take care of people in society, but at the same point,
you know, how far can we go to kind of
handhold everybody?
I mean,
a great example being all these people in hotels in
Hawaii who were panicking and the staff were panicking and,
or going home or whatever.
Right.
Some of them, you know, talked about how they felt they had a duty of care to the,
you know, people at the hotel and other people were like, screw this.
I'm gonna go see my family because
what else am I gonna do? Right. It's not like we have a bunker in this hotel,
you know, and, and so even there, like, kind of,
yeah, like what happens if you're, you're not at home?
Like Hawaii is a major tourist destination.
How do you like? What do you do for tourists who maybe aren't,
you know, a tidal wave warning comes and do the tourists know what the heck to do?
-- The answer is probably not.
-- Uh, no, they, they totally don't.
And, and this is something I remember I took a cruise many years ago
and they had like an emergency drill after
one hour after leaving or something like that.
And I remember all I kept thinking was
if anything bad happens,
like this place is going to turn into a nut house and none of these people
are going to listen or do anything remotely
close to what they're being told right now.
Do you remember the cost of Concordia disaster?
Oh, yes. Yes. That was the
Italian.
That, that
wasn't it.
That's
right. Well, its
because, well, technically didn't sink, sink it kind of rolled over and took a nap.
Um, but like, at one point there's that audio of like the Italian Coast Guard, like,
being rather annoyed and telling him to get back on his ship and deal with it.
Right.
Because the captain wanted, you know, he was like, oh, I'm evacuating good luck,
everybody,
you know,
and, and that captain was, if I'm, if I'm remembering
right. He was a bit of a clown.
And,
I mean,
that's different. I think though there are,
there are situations where you have someone
in power that is knowingly or willingly incompetent
and that is actually more dangerous than we'll say like an uncontrolled disaster.
Something like a hurry
or
an earthquake.
I would like to know.
Are there like, so for example,
you have the Innkeepers Act which defines things like if I don't pay my bill,
they can keep my stuff and sell it at auction or whatever,
you know.
Uh But for example,
is there like any clause in the Innkeepers act
about them having to like take care of me in
the event of say a fire or a flood or
like dinosaurs being released from the local zoo or,
you know, whatever, right?
Like,
I don't know, I'm kind of curious about this now because
there was some, you know, I was reading the Reddit threads and this one guy is like,
he tried to shelter in a store and they wouldn't let him,
they told me to get and that's kind of like, wow, dick move.
Uh
You know, I would agree with that.
II I feel like though at the same time, this is one of those situations, if,
if you are a hotel
and
you have guests,
there is nothing you can really do against
a disaster that's going to happen quickly. I mean, like fire is a great example.
If there is a fire,
there's nothing you can do. It's up to the guest
assuming
you even see it, right. Someone will assume can pull the fire alarm,
but like you're not going to go find people, you're going to get out
and it's up to people to either get out or
for professional help to appear and deal with the situation.
And I, I think this is exactly the same and, and I, I wanna tie this into cyber security
at the same time because like
we try to plan for ridiculous. Well, ok, let me, let me back that up. Not everybody.
There's always a subset of the population.
I think we would call them preppers in many instances.
Not, I'm not using that in a negative way. Mind you please don't harass me on Twitter.
Uh There are people who are preparing for
catastrophe and that's fine if that's what something you enjoy doing or want to do.
That's great. I have no problem with it. Right.
We look at like a lot of security teams and
they often are in what I would call the prepper camp where they're,
they're planning for catastrophe.
When in reality it's like you don't even have a front door in your house.
And
I
think as
well as
-- disconnect, they
-- see
we have the same problem in medicine, for example, you know, it's a lot
more sexy, especially as a doctor to, like,
fix heart attacks than it is for people to go jogging more
and eat,
you know, less
-- food.
-- Right?
-- No, II, I, yes, I totally like, I
-- look at,
I look at infosec and the number of places where I'm like,
tell me. Exactly.
And what version of stuff you're running and the look on their face, they're like,
I'm like, I know you can't tell me that.
Like,
just,
yeah, exactly.
You know, like they don't even have a remote inventory of what's going on
but they think they do or
whatever.
Um
You know, just, yeah, that basic, you know, flossing is not fun.
Nobody likes to floss,
dude. I floss religiously.
It is.
-- Do you do it because you like it or do you do it because it's good for you
-- because
I do it because it's good for me because if I don't floss and I go to the dentist,
my gums bleed and they yell at me.
But if I do floss, I go to the dentist, they say, hey, good job flossing. And I say, I
think
that
remarkably like how infosec people operate.
No, they don't, they don't operate like that at all.
They don't floss and then they use
for having bleeding gums,
you know, you should have updated, you should have installed this patch
maybe. Yeah, I guess you get some of that. It's,
yeah. Yeah. To a degree. That's fair.
I still,
I still see the infosec people yelling at everybody even though it's
certainly not something in many cases the users couldn't even control it.
But
yeah.
So,
So, and then the, the other thing that gets to me about this is just, yeah,
like I said earlier, how much the world has changed from, you know,
things like Conal rad on the radio, you know, the little circle with the triangle,
that's your civil defense station.
Um,
you know, to like, check your Twitter and your Facebook and let's face it. Those are
because one thing that really got me is that
new sites didn't pick this up like
you, like, you know, uh you would have,
I would have thought that like cnn.com within three or four minutes of like,
oh my God, like our, our Hawaiian bureau is like all hiding in the basement
telling us that they're about to get nuked.
You know, maybe we should put that up on the website and apparently these
or, or was it because they were trying to fact check it but they didn't put it up,
which could, you know, kind of is a good thing because it turns out it was not true.
Right.
And having that on cnn.com would have panicked the whole pile more
-- people
-- that's ignoring the fact checking part of it because I think
fact checking in journalism today is, is of dubious quality at best,
-- but
-- it still happens.
It kind of does. But you have to
figure
out,
think about CNN. Right.
The, the, the warning comes out
how long until somebody in a position of,
we'll say any sort of influence learns about it.
Let's, let's say five minutes, right. Which I think is generous.
My guess is it's long past that
five minutes, then they're gonna say, all right, like is this a real thing?
And they're gonna find some way to double check it. Let's say we're at 10 minutes now
and then they're gonna say,
all right now we need to get something up on the website and on air.
So that's probably another 5 to 10 minutes there and we're already at 20 minutes in.
Right? I mean,
I would bet you the way traditional media works.
Best case scenario is gonna be a half hour turnaround.
Whereas something like social media like, yeah, 10 seconds, man.
I bet the first person got that warning message
and it was on Twitter 15 seconds later.
Guaranteed.
I mean,
it's a tough one too because you don't want people to
just grab stuff and run with it because when we,
you know that happens 10, you know,
people tend to make mistakes or put out the wrong thing
and
is a danger as well because, because what happens if someone puts on Twitter, like,
I, I see a missile coming into Hawaii and now all
of a sudden
everyone's
out.
-- Not
-- exactly
-- no.
-- Remember there was that famous webcam in San Diego
and like, they're like, oh my God, that looks like a missile launch. And it was just uh
uh it was a contrail from a plane that was just at the sort of right angle and,
you know,
um
it, it really did look like
a
Yeah. Right. Right. No, I remember that now. Yes. Yes.
You know, so, and, and people were kind of, well,
not freaking out about it because it's kind of headed out over the ocean.
So they're just like, what the heck is that? You know, it's not like inbound.
So, I mean, yeah, these, these things do happen.
But yeah, to have it come from the state agency, you know, and, and be,
and then followed up a minute or two later by like, this is not a drill.
This is real like, yeah, that's definitely a little bit more uh
scary.
Yeah. No, iii
I totally get it. It's,
this is a hard problem.
And
one thing I'm wondering is how many people are,
are going to actually now do maybe a little basic prep.
Like, for example, like one thing I realize if my phone dies,
I don't know any phone numbers other than my parents' phone number and like 911.
Do you need other phone numbers?
Uh, like, I don't know, my parents' phone numbers, like their cell phones. I don't
know. I
don't actually even know my partner's cellphone number.
And when I have get cell phones for my kids, I probably need to, like,
maybe memorize those numbers I feel or print them out on the card.
But if you don't have a working cell phone, do you have access to another phone?
So you've never dropped your phone?
I have not, you,
I, you would not believe the care I take to not do that.
Ok? But I'm just saying like I could see
it's, it's not even like in an emergency, it's like I dropped and smashed my phone
but it's all in the cloud.
Can't you just like pull open a computer and, and just log into something.
But I mean, it might also be handy for example,
to have a laminated card so I can use somebody else's phone to call them.
So
I'm
gonna be late because I gotta go buy a new phone.
Let's
let's go with this because this is something I think about a lot.
And this is a great example.
So you're gonna laminate a card and you're going to put it in your wallet
and
-- the good news
-- is phone numbers don't change anymore.
Uh
It's,
well, they kind of used to but even then man,
it was a number of changes were pretty rare.
It wasn't a huge deal and
I'm less concerned about numbers. But,
so let's say you, you print out this card, you put it in your wallet,
you might need it someday. Uh,
are you gonna remember? It's there
-- is it
-- number 17 things in my wallet? So it's going to take up a lot of room and annoy me.
That's fair. Ok. And that's fair.
That's fair if that's the case because actually I
was cleaning up my wallet the other day.
I, uh, I
remember why I was going through it. There was something I was looking for
and I found a little print off of what I assume were old two factor off codes for.
I don't even know what. Right. Like I'm like, I have no idea what these are.
I,
I'll just burn this because it's clearly not of value to
me that I couldn't tell you which service they're from.
But that, that's what I feel like here and
now, now
it's not just about some massive emergency.
-- It's about like I dropped my phone in the toilet. I need to like
-- I get that
and let
them
know I'll be late.
Uh,
but
maybe this is one of those situations like putting
a card in your wallet is very low cost
and it's easy to do
and it could have, we'll say moderately high impact
in the event of your phone being lost or broken.
Which is
a
great
example. At some point I need to get my kids to memorize my cell phone number.
Uh my kids know my cell phone number
and, and they do, they call me when they're somewhere and they need access.
But, you know, you know, I've been thinking is I'm like,
wouldn't it be just easier to give the kids like a crap cell phone?
Then they don't have to know my number and they
can send me text messages or call me whenever and it
again until they drop their phone.
And part of that, you see, but part of that plan is buying them a phone that you could,
like, run over with a truck and it won't matter because it's like some, you know,
like old crappy super durable phone
because I know they're going to drop it and I know they're not going to charge it.
And so I, I wanted to have like a month of battery life and, and you can like,
literally flush this thing down the toilet and then go
fetch it and it still will make phone calls.
Right.
And, and so anyway, anyway,
so
I guess here, here's my thought on all of this and I know this will be vast,
grossly unpopular. Many people probably even you is
I basically don't prepare for anything at this point because I, I, I've decided,
I have consciously decided
that if, if something bad happens
I almost certainly can't do anything about it and I accept my fate
because like, like my favorite example of this is,
let's say you live in this, in a city like a real city
and you have food and water in your basement
and let's say, like society breaks down
and there's a mob outside.
Is that food and water gonna have any value to you? No.
So now let's say I buy a gun to protect my food and water.
You're gonna shoot 200 people. No. So effectively
you can do nothing,
right? Like at best,
I'm not worried about that scenario. I'm more worried about,
uh,
there's like a disruption or a heavy snowfall because
we have had super heavy snowfalls here that like,
have completely effed up the roads
and, you know, it's a complete nightmare to go and buy
anything.
It, it, it is possible that could happen.
But at the same time,
how, how much snow are you gonna have to get?
Well, or a great example here in northern Alberta,
kind of the top, uh, maybe 10th of the provinces is anyways. So it's a big area
and they had, uh,
I forget what the problem was with their natural gas distribution system,
but essentially the pressure was low.
Oh, yeah.
It's because we had, they had a cold snap and some of the pipes actually froze.
And so these poor people living way up in northern Alberta had
no natural gas which meant like for a lot of them,
they had no heat,
especially in a modern building, right?
Like I live in a house with a real,
you have a fireplace, you have sleeping blank uh sleeping bags,
you huddle in a room with a small propane stove and be very careful not to die,
carbon monoxide poisoning.
Um or in this case, you know, they opened up schools and stuff and heated them to like,
have the people take shelter.
Right.
But for example, well, no, no, just for example,
can I finish, please? For example, if you live kind of in the middle of nowhere
because I know people that live, for example, on acreages
and they do actually
regularly get snowed in for two or three days
because there's like a foot or two of snow,
they don't own like a massive jacked up truck and, you know,
the county doesn't get around to plowing them out
for two or three days because they got to do the roads first.
I think if you live like out in the boonies,
having a couple of days of food and water is totally reasonable.
I think having like a propane tank on site is totally reasonable. Right.
And if I lived in the middle of nowhere, I would totally do that.
I live in the city.
And
if, if I need
two days of food and water and I can't get it.
Like there are way bigger problems going on
than,
than anything else. And that's kind of the way
I
like the hurricane in Puerto Rico.
But how would you compare
to that?
I mean, let's face it, man. They haven't had any, any
realistically speaking. They, they've been broken for months now.
Like, if you had seven days of food, like it's long gone.
Right.
-- It's long gone
-- now.
Well,
if I lived in a hurricane zone I'd probably have
30 days of food and water because I mean,
you look at even civilized places like Hurricane Andrew in Florida, right?
It knocked out
-- power infrastructure for, for weeks and months and,
-- and I agree with you
that
if you live in.
Ok. Ok.
Let me, let me rephrase this because I think we're on to something important here is
you have to prepare
according to where you live, like me preparing for a hurricane would be idiotic.
Right?
And I think in the security universe
we have people preparing for hurricanes who live
way up north.
Right.
We need to understand what our potential threats are
and prepare for them as needed.
And like in my case, you know,
my biggest fear is my biggest fear is losing power for a couple of hours.
And so I have like a battery backup that I can use
to power my cell phone and computers if I need them.
And
that's something that has huge impact on my life if it goes wrong right
now, if I get like so much snow I can't leave my house for three days.
I don't think that's going to happen.
And so I'm not going to prepare for it and that's just the way it is.
And if it does happen, I'm going to be in a world of hurt,
-- but I don't think it will and it probably won't
-- part of it too,
is to remember that planning doesn't necessarily have
to be buying a crazy amount of stuff.
It can be something as simple as like
getting the stuff you would need for camping anyways or for example, in my case,
we have a lot of extra stuff now for when we go to the cabin,
my parents' cabin out in the middle of nowhere, even though it has power and whatnot.
You know, there's still
kind of a lot of other stuff that's not available or if you want to go buy it,
you have to go drive an hour.
You can't just pop over to 7-Eleven.
-- Uh,
-- yes, I, I can relate to that. My folks have a cabin in the middle of the woods and
I had to actually, uh, I re plumbed it for them a couple of years ago because the pipes.
It does. Uh,
it does, it is very nice plumbing now,
but it was, it was like pipes from the forties, right?
It was super old and like they were falling apart and terrible
and yeah, I had to put together my parts list
before I left because I couldn't get parts after I'd left.
And I like overbought like crazy
knowing I will just bring everything.
That's exactly, that's exactly it. Right. And like,
that's a good example of being prepared. Right.
And, and this is, this is kind of my,
like the thing I keep thinking of and the thing I
want to keep tying this back to is the fact that
insecurity
I feel like we spend so much time preparing for events that will never happen. And,
and like my, my favorite example of this is, you know, knowing people who are,
are obsessing over,
say having their I DS set up correctly
and they don't have two factor authentication.
It's like that's,
that doesn't make sense. Like two factor off
will have drastically better results on whatever you're doing than having an idea.
Well, like unquestionably,
and I feel like our priorities sometimes are incredibly out of whack
and it hurts us in the end because I think it also makes security
in general look like a bunch of clowns when we're doing this wrong.
Well, I, you know, it reminds me a lot of just in general
um
what the hurricane in Puerto Rico is a great
example of uh Puerto Rico apparently turns out something
like 10% of all the uh like IV drugs and what not used in the American hospitals.
And um so now there's like major shortages because let's face it if you take out
5% of production of something
like medical supplies, let alone 10% for a few weeks or months.
Yeah, that's gonna have a huge impact because, you know, the whole world runs on.
See, that's the other fear I have is the whole world runs on these,
just in time delivery systems
and the majority of cities now have three days of food.
That's it,
I
believe.
And it's efficient and it, it's, it's cheap and it means I can get avocados.
I live in Canada.
It's,
I don't think there was probably an avocado in Canada until like,
probably 1970 or 80.
-- If I had to guess
-- you should be living off of like seal blubber.
Exactly. Seal blubber and wheat and root vegetables. Right.
And, you know, and so it's,
I,
if there is a major disruption to the food chain,
uh, or the food supply system, yeah, I mean,
it's probably something has gone really horribly wrong.
But
the thing is, there are realistically
ridiculous events that do happen, like the ice storm in Quebec a long time ago.
The main problem there being is, you know,
it knocked down like literally all the power lines,
you know, they had heavy ice on them and they, all
the problem was it was all the long distance transmission lines.
They,
they fell down and cascaded and so they
literally lost thousands of miles of high voltage,
you know, back haul transmission lines.
Which
you can't replace that stuff quickly.
You basically have to rebuild it
and they, they showed them rebuilding it next to it.
They didn't even bother to demolish the old stuff.
Right. They just,
well, they didn't have time. Right.
You're gonna spend time demolishing this old crap,
or you're just going to build a new one next to it
once it's built and everything's fixed,
then remove the old stuff.
Yeah. Yeah. II, I guess that makes sense.
And like that's another good example of that is a,
an uncommon event that sounds like it was dealt with appropriately
and, and how
you plan for that.
Right. Like how, how are you going to plan for that?
-- Could you, could they have in their wildest
-- dreams? What they do
is, for example, every,
I think it's 10th tower is reinforced so that you don't get that cascade failure
and, ok, that's fair.
I mean, I, I think that makes sense and that sounds like a good idea. Right.
Right. Because the problem was, it was,
most of the towers are structurally fine.
It's just because one or two collapsed, put enough load on the next one
and, you know, you had a domino failure basically.
Right.
Which again,
they've never anticipated when they built this thing originally because,
you know, we had never had an ice storm that bad.
Right.
Um,
so, but I mean, and that's the thing, right?
I think what fundamentally, whatever preparations you make
uh, generally speaking, you have to have
some, either a return on investment or be cheap enough that they're not a problem.
Right. Like we're not the US government that can keep,
you know, nuclear missiles on standby,
uh, or, you know, keep planes in the air 24 7, things like that.
But they did and they had to, because the potential downside of,
like a nuclear strike was
arguably about the worst thing we can have ever in the history of humanity, right?
And so did it make sense?
Well, I mean, the fact that mad kept everybody from nuking each other for 50 years,
I would say it was worth it,
man being mutual assured destruction.
Um
You know, for example,
basic hurricane prep like maybe at the beginning of hurricane season, you know,
fill up a 50 L uh or whatever 10 gallon can of uh gas so that when you have to leave,
you don't have to stop for gas on the way out.
Uh
That always
-- seems to be a problem
-- that that might not be terrible advice. It's,
and I,
I guess that's the thing
I I'm
starting to realize with this,
especially after our discussion about because like when we started talking,
I was under the impression most nuclear weapons would annihilate like
the island of Hawaii.
-- It turns out that's not the case.
-- Military ones would
not even
man,
like there's only a couple of nuclear weapons that could annihilate the Island.
Like, it's
-- most of the
-- basically America
and Russia.
Let's face it. No, if, if you want to talk about
real nuclear weapon, like city, like things at a level of city that's,
that's America and Russia, basically
-- China. And
-- even then it's,
it's unlikely those are the things they
would send because those aren't ICBM weapons.
Right.
Those are like,
the submarine is towing it underwater sort of thing
because it has a range of 100 miles.
But anyway, anyway, here's, here's my point is
I,
my assumption was
a, a missile attack would basically, there's nothing you could do and,
and there is something you can do and you know what it is, it's,
it's just do nothing right.
Stay indoors and, and get inside your house as far as you can.
Well, somebody pointed it on a red thread.
The, the, I can't pronounce these Russian names but the, the media in Russia,
uh member that got like all the coverage because it was
during the day and people had all their cameras on and stuff
and one of the problems is everybody went to the window to look at it and then the
hit and they all made
-- a face full of
-- glass that is in my blog post as well.
Because like, like that's another example,
I would have looked out my window if I saw a bright light like that. And I know now
that if you see a bright light
don't look out the window.
Right. Like
maybe,
uh, yeah, I think she was a very good one too.
We've all seen Die Hard and, uh, you know,
the scene of the, uh, in the computer room where he shoots out all the glass
and poor Bruce Willis doesn't have any shoes on. Right.
Yeah, that's fair.
Uh, but, but I guess here, here's my point. Right. So,
my new advice is if any sort of thing happens, like, basically do nothing.
-- And I guess what
-- is Check
Twitter
in your bath
and
tide in the bathroom and check Twitter?
That is the best advice for any sort of emergency situation.
I think anyone could possibly give. I love that.
But, but here's a question.
So
in, in, let's face it in 80 plus percent of natural disaster situations,
like literally hide in the bathroom and check Twitter is probably very good advice
and something like a hurricane will ignore
because you're gonna know about that beforehand,
right?
You're not gonna like all of the sudden.
So anyway, here's my question
from the standpoint of security
today in the environment we exist in
what is the equivalent advice or doesn't even exist
of go in the bathroom and check Twitter.
I would say probably the number one biggest thing.
Uh Well,
basically the two biggest things I keep coming back to are use a password manager,
which essentially implies that you're using
good strong unique passwords everywhere.
Because one of those sites is going to store your
password improperly and it's gonna get cracked or just read.
And number two is backups because, and
for me, backups are less about a security thing and more about,
like dropping your phone in the toilet.
Yeah. No, I, I agree with that completely.
And,
and my backup plan to dropping my phone in the
toilet is just going to be the fact that I can
log into Google and look at all of my contacts
like
that is the backup plan.
Of course, I, I currently have, well,
and I guess that's the beauty of it too is I have a U two F key now for logging in.
So even if Google authenticator is dead, my U two F key,
like I could drop that in the toilet,
I could probably flush that down the toilet and then go
get it and run it over with a truck and,
and hit it with a hammer a few times and it would still work.
-- Like that's all you
-- have your printed out codes for your Google account.
I,
because that's something I do every once in a while I go through all my accounts print
out
of
-- them in an envelope, put them in my safety deposit box. See it like
-- that for
situations if the code is at the bank, is that helpful? Really?
Well, in general, I would have to destroy my phone, destroy my U two F key,
destroy you know, I mean, like it would be a house fire situation
and so
it
would be
ok.
That's fair. I guess.
Also the thing to remember too is this is actually the, the recovery codes
are not so much for me, but for my next of kin,
because if I get hit by a bus or something,
you know, my sons might want control of
creed.org
whatever. Yo.
Ok. That's fair. That's fair.
Anyway, anyway, we've kind of rambled along with, with this one for a while.
I think, I, I don't know, man, I just,
I keep thinking about this in my brain and I feel like
there is,
it is difficult to prepare for nearly anything and, and I just keep thinking like
there are fundamental basics that will have
the far biggest out impact on whatever is going on and, and it's like,
it's literally like, yeah, go in the bathroom and check Twitter.
Anyone can do that. Anyone can remember that.
And yeah, like I think from the security perspective, like
password manager and backups are probably 80% of the game
and, and after that, and let's face it too. Like
if, if your threat model includes say China attacking you, like
you can't beat them,
you're going to lose
-- the US
-- government.
-- Even those guys clearly can't,
-- I wasn't going to say you can beat them but you can,
you can,
you can deal with it in a meaningful way.
Yeah, maybe, maybe I Yes, I, I think you're right. But again,
like,
that's a different universe. Right.
Like, the military planning for a missile attack is going to,
their plans are drastically different than mine.
But that's one thing that frustrates me is where people sort of try and
view a problem as a single homogenous problem. Right.
Like, when I look at prepping here,
I actually view it as several problems. Like, number one is
something
likely but not, you know, terribly impactful.
Like, just really terrible whether and I can't get to the store for a day or two.
So, you know what I want to make sure, maybe I have
like some bottle, like a case of bottled water in the, you know,
basement in case the whatever Epcor messes up somehow or having things like,
you know, uh, a week's worth of medication in case, I don't know,
the pharmacy is closed or the pharmacist is sick and they can't get a replacement,
you know, whatever. Right.
Um, but it, to treat it as a single problem, I,
I don't think it makes sense because for example,
like my house burning down that is something that is statistically, you know,
much more likely to happen than say getting nuked.
Right.
Um,
you know, and so do I have a plan for a house fire?
Yeah, I mean, it basically consists of get everybody out and then, you know,
phone the insurance company,
-- but straight up, that's
-- my plan. I don't know if I'd call that a plan.
Hey,
I just renewed my fire insurance and there was
a really sad thing about a guy locally who,
uh, he rented, there was a fire and he didn't have fire insurance.
-- Yes. Like you didn't have renters insurance.
-- Fire insurance is good.
Well, yeah, I mean, it's, and it's cheap.
Um, but yeah, like you said, some people are pouring it. Really, that's a tough one.
but like literally my plan for fire is ensure and eat the risk.
Well, you're not getting a risk. I mean, there's just, there's nothing you can do.
I accept the risk,
you know,
I mean,
well, I could actually, I could spend about five or $6000
and have the house retrofitted with sprinklers.
God, that's probably not worth it, man. I mean, let's face it.
Well, we're talking about uh, well, not we,
but uh they're talking about it for the new
building code coming out in 2020 in Canada,
um for new builds because the reality is in a new build.
Of course, you can, you know, run a sprinkler system without too much hassle.
Whereas with an existing building, right, you got to rip all the ceilings apart,
which is, that's going to cost a lot of money.
But, um,
like long term would I prefer that?
Yeah, because for example, most houses now are kind of more open plan,
they burn faster and they're full of stuff with plastic.
I, you know,
I, I have no problem
with,
with doing things that, that can make a difference.
But I guess at the same time, I would want to understand
if you did this,
what is the result going to be? Right? Like, tell me
what kind of return we're going to see on this sort of investment.
Well, more importantly with housing, you know,
the the fire marshal talking about it literally flat out said though, you know,
we need to be careful though because we can't
make houses so expensive that people can't afford them. And a few $1000
is the difference for some people,
you know, and when you, you multiply a few $1000 times every house in Canada.
It's like, well, that's a, that's actually a lot of money.
Well, well, it's, it's bigger than that even because
let's say everyone starts needing this.
And now are you going to have like dodgy
sprinkler systems on the market that don't even work?
And you know, it, I
mean, this is,
this is crazy stuff is, is one of the problems and I guess
the fact that we can't have a nearly
hour long conversation about emergency and preparedness and come
up with anything close to reasonable advice other
than hide in the bathroom and check Twitter.
I this is a big hard problem
and I, I think that's all we can say, man is, it's just,
it is big and hard and there's, there isn't a good answer and there, there may never be
that, that just might be the way it is. So, I guess
let's take it home.
-- Any closing thoughts,
-- uh, go to your local governments,
get prepared or emergency preparedness website and
see what they say because honestly,
I've looked at a few of them and most of them are
quite sane and basically it's just having enough stuff for 72 hours
and it's nothing too ridiculous.
My advice is hide in the bathroom and check Twitter.
So there we go.
Kurt's more proactive, but I bet we both have the same result
anyway.
All right, man. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everybody for listening.
If you want the show notes or if you complain at us or anything else,
just go to open source security podcast.com.
You find links to our Facebook group.
You can hit us up with the Os S podcast hashtag on Twitter
and yeah, uh I guess let us know what you think.
If you have ideas, questions, comments, we'd, we'd love to hear it.
This is, this is one of those topics that I imagine will,
will rear its head again and just doesn't have good or easy answers.
-- So, yeah, I guess Kurt have a, have a great rest of your day,
-- man. You too. Thanks
the