Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner and making fun of my lumpy head Josh Pressers.
We are, I don't know if it'll make it into the free role. Kurt has a bump on his head.
He was actually mocking himself.
I said nothing but I think my silence conveyed more than words. So
it worked out.
Yeah, my doctor said it's ok. I didn't pass out. So
he's just like, that's weird.
I've never seen it before, which is not what you want to hear from your doctor.
I agree with that anyway. Ok.
Open SSL
is our lead paint.
We all know it's bad. We all know what we have to do.
-- No one really wants to do it because it's gonna be expensive and hard.
-- The problem.
You know what?
It's not lead paint, it's asbestos because it's embedded in everything.
Lead paint is everywhere.
No, no, but like, but like lead paint, you can just sort of paint over but like,
asbestos is in everything.
Like to, to remove
it
is a massive problem. And that's where Openness cell is.
Like, you can't fix Openness Cell on your TV, like your TV maker has to want to do that.
-- You know,
-- I can't
-- fix
-- lead paint in my house.
Either you strip it down and repaint or, or you just paint over it.
Well, you paint over it. That's actually the right way.
And see. The problem is you can't do that with open SSL though
because,
and,
and I think this is a big part of the problem that people don't kind
of think about really consciously is if you have a network service by definition,
what's the first thing that gets touched nowadays?
And it's the TLS layer,
right? Oh. Right.
You know what I mean? And that's part of the problem is like,
like I can write a terrible CG I, oh God, that's how
II, I still think of them as CG I apps. Like a web app.
I can write a terrible web app but like,
I can stick a web server in front of it that sanitizes input.
But you can't do that with TLS.
Like whatever is handling the TLS
is handling the TLS unless you have another TLS proxy in front of it.
All right, we hold on. Ok. You're, you're, you're off in the weeds.
I, I think we're gonna start at the beginning.
-- Well, no
-- part of the problem is there's, there's no easy remediation.
You either have, you have to rip it out and replace it with something better.
Nobody wants to do that because it's a pain in the butt
-- because it's expensive and it
-- sucks.
But it's worse than that because what's the replacement for open SSL one?
Oh, it's, oh, it's open SSL three?
Oh,
no. The replacement
is, what is the name of that isg, the
-- thing we talked to Josh Os about
-- Russell's?
-- Wasn't, didn't they say it was called Russell's? Russ TLS?
-- Yeah, that sounds right.
I think it was Russell's.
Yeah, he pronounced it. Russell's, didn't he? Which I found weird, but whatever.
Yeah, I know. That's why it stuck in my head. That is
-- the
-- answer. A new language.
We, we have to use
a memory safe TLS library and they have one.
Well, I mean, it's simple, right? We need modern tools.
But again, this is why I like lead paint is my analogy
because
there was lead in paint
and then we were like, that's bad. We shouldn't do it.
Someone made paint without lead and they were like, well,
that's more expensive and it sucks and we don't
want to use it and eventually we just had to
now
ignoring marine paint. That's a whole different thing.
-- What's wrong with
-- green paint? No,
marine paint. Like
-- does, does marine paint still have lead in it
-- because it
works.
-- And generally speaking, people aren't out there looking at,
-- I mean,
but it's leaching into the ocean
-- like that place with the fish we eat.
-- Yeah.
But if that happens in international waters, did it happen?
Uh anyways,
I lead paint is the perfect analogy because
if it's still in use then
yeah,
like open SSL will be used in some places forever
even though we know better and we shouldn't do it
because it's easier. Let's start at the beginning.
It is Tuesday, November 1st that we are recording this particular episode.
The Open SSL issue in question, there were actually two
dropped.
What, like not even 12 hours ago at the time of us recording this and
a week
ago exactly was the Tuesday before this
open SSL released an announcement saying on November 1st
at whatever, at some time range, I forget what it was like 1700 to 1900 UTC, I think.
Uh Tuesday first of November 2022 between 1317 100 UTC,
which is essentially morning in North America, evening in Europe.
And if you're in Asia, you're, you're drinking coffee and staying up late.
So
they, they say they're going to release an open SSL update
and it has a critical vulnerability in it
-- and the world lit on fire
-- and partly too because
the announcement wasn't good.
Here's the announcement,
the Open SSL project team would like to announce
the forthcoming release of open SSL version 3.0 0.7.
0, ok. That's normal so far so good.
This release will be made available on Tuesday
first of November 2022 between 1317 100 UTC.
Hey,
fine, cool.
Well, but it's still 3.07 is a security fixed release. OK.
The highest severity issue fixing this release is critical. Whos
boom
end of message
like could we maybe have an impact?
Like are we talking key disclosure, remote code execution?
-- Is it in a default configuration? If
-- it's critical,
-- it's almost definitely remote code execution
-- or
-- key exposure.
-- That's true. That could be critical in that context.
They,
they actually have a security policy with their specific threat
model and severity and to read it critical severity.
This affects common configurations
and which are also what
this affects common configurations.
Oh, they don't need the word and there which are also likely to be exploitable.
Examples include significant uh disclosure of the contents of server memory,
potentially revealing user details,
vulnerabilities which can be easily exploited
remotely to compromise server private keys
or where remote code execution is considered likely in common situations.
These issues will be kept private and will
trigger a new release of all support versions.
We will attempt to address these as soon as possible.
Yeah,
sure. So information disclosure, key disclosure
and well,
obviously code execution is like the the the real dark boogie monster in the closet.
But the problem is like, yeah, I mean, well, here's the thing,
what else are we supposed to do other than speculate?
No, I'm serious, right?
Because like they didn't even say explicitly that open
a cell one is not affected in that announcement
that was only done on Twitter from,
you know, the, the account.
Like that's true. And, and I was like, like,
well, he is, he like, he is literally Mr open his cell.
So I doubt that he's lying or incorrect, but
-- it's not in the announcement.
-- No, no. And that was from uh Mark Cox's Twitter who?
Kurt and I both know Mark, he's, he's a fine person.
Yeah. Oh, he's a good guy does a thankless job.
He,
he does a lot of this work and he gets a lot of crap and
I'm sure he's not gonna be really happy with us when we're done with this,
but we love you, man.
We, we know we know you're, you're doing a thankless job. But,
but the reality is, I guess here's the way I think of this. Ok.
So we had this announcement,
we have a week of basically speculation.
But then what makes it even more bizarre is like
GSI, the dog is talking about the press and,
and companies contacting him asking him to sign NDAS to
look over the details and
that's not how disclosure works.
And of course,
Mark hears of this and is
-- obviously unhappy. Well,
-- because it was on Twitter and I
replied and tagged him into it
like,
well, and then he said he was hearing all sorts of other weird stuff and I mean,
and that's part of the problem is because there's an information vacuum
dude. It's just, it's exactly like the Twitter
debacle with those, like, two guys pretending to be Twitter,
data analysis employees or whatever outside of Twitter saying, you know,
I was just fired from Twitter and they're like, a couple of reporters were like, oh,
let's interview you and, like,
actually maybe not verify that you ever worked at Twitter.
Oops, because, you know, we're in a rush
and
part of the problem here is
ok. So it's like the classic, you know,
um, somebody says something, the reporters try and confirm it and of course,
the response from the US government or whatever is like, no comment.
Right. Right. Well, crap. What do I do now?
Well, the answer is you print an article,
like you put an article on your website and get some clicks and ad revenue.
Yeah. And there were tons of news stories talking about what's going to happen.
There were tons of blog posts from vendors talking about what's going to
happen and none of them knew they were all making crap up.
What really actually makes me angry is that I kind of had the question of like, well,
who's actually shipping this?
Right?
Because I know Red Hat Nine is uh Red Hat Enterprise Linux nine. Sorry.
And, uh, also turns out I think, what is it? Ubuntu 20.04 or whatever,
-- the,
-- the new distributions I have it
and, and you told me no JZ
-- Yeah.
-- No, Js is a big one
for Sure. So basically,
so uh but here's the thing, rail mine dropped in May
and
rel customers are not exactly like
by definition, if you're using REL you're,
you're not a bleeding edge kind of person.
Right. Right. No, I agree. I think in the Linux distribution universe, the amount of
open SSL three use is pretty low.
But node, node is the thing
that I think you need to worry about the most just because
node Js is widely deployed and to make it even better,
node Js has open SSL three statically linked in the binary.
So you can't even like look for files on dis, you have to know it is affected, which is
a treat.
But I think even with no Js,
the majority of web stuff is now being deployed behind a proxy in general.
Like people use C DNS like cloud floor
-- A II. I,
-- I don't think that's a fair assumption.
I,
you told me this on signal and I don't think you're wrong but I can't prove
-- you are or aren't
-- well part of it too is that like Hiroko for example,
like stuff deployed on Heroku doesn't
like there's, there's a proxy element and stuff, right?
But anyways ignoring all that
part of the point is is that this isn't like affecting Windows 11,
like if something affects Windows 11,
-- it's a big deal.
-- That's right. That's right. So here's part of the problem
is if open SSL had a legitimate remote code execution vulnerability that
affected a an enormous number versions that would be incredibly serious.
And because open SSL is in literally everything, I bet if you connect to
arbitrary ports on the internet that are open,
I would bet you somewhere between 30 50% have open SSL.
On the other side,
I remember auditing Red Hat for seeing like what SSL were they using?
Because
Oh yeah, it was during heartbleed. Yes. Now I remember.
Yeah. So
this is why this seems so familiar anyways.
Um,
and I remember looking for stuff that was specifically
using new TLS and the answer was like six.
It's very small.
Well, at one time,
Red Hat put significant effort into trying to port as much stuff as they could to use
GTLS
and it just
never happened.
It's, it's hard to, it's hard to move
-- and this is why we're still using open
-- SSL.
Well, especially with something as big and complicated as open SSL.
Yeah, you're going to end up with a monopoly like a single
entity because
-- just recreating that code in anything else.
-- No, it's recreated in rust. Shut up.
-- It's there. We just need to use it.
-- Well, no, but what I'm saying is it's so much work.
Unless there's a compelling advantage and
rewriting open SSL
in C with a slightly different license is not
-- really all that compelling.
-- Here's a compelling advantage.
Our Children are going to look back on us the way we look back at our parents
and be like, why did you paint everything with lead?
You knew it was bad
and you did it anyway.
-- But like
-- what I'm saying is
GTs doesn't offer a compelling alternative.
-- The alternative is rust.
-- And that, oh wow. Like, so all that memory stuff just.
Nope, it's fine.
Oh, cool. Like this is why I do Python because I'm not smart enough to manage memory.
I know this.
I'm
-- sure
-- no one is smart enough to manage memory. I don't care who you are.
The one.
Openness Celtics is literally instead of greater than
it's greater than equal to like boom.
Just that one.
Just
right. Anyway. OK. OK.
So
I want to
this today. Anyway. OK.
I wanna, I wanna kind of reel this back a little bit also way back to heartbleed,
right?
Remember heartbleed. That was open ssl also
heartbleed happens.
And that was especially fun because at first it was like, oh,
it kind of maybe discloses a bit of memory and then it turns out like, no,
-- you can basically walk memory and like get it all,
-- all
-- the
-- memory, right?
-- So
-- anyway, well, no,
but it was funny because internally our response went from this is really about to
oh no, let's all get a drink.
Yy.
Like I remember my stomach just dropping when, when I
and the funny thing about this is
uh I worked for Mark Cox at that time. He was on vacation.
I remember that it ruined his vacation
anyway. Anyway. So, so here's the thing. So Harple happens. There's
all this activity you've got like the
Linux Foundation launches our core infrastructure initiative.
You had all these companies offering to spend money.
Open SSL actually did get like more people in funding.
But then I feel like we kind of hit a wall
and we just stopped.
-- Well, budget
-- cycles and, and that's probably part of it. Sure.
But the point is I think about that momentum we had and
then it just kind of died off and now we see it again
and
nothing will change. Now, I want, I want to be very clear.
This issue was not big enough to change anything.
We're just going to make fun of it for
the foreseeable future is all that's going to happen.
But anyway, ok, so,
oh my goodness, we are the worst storytellers on the planet
so often SSL makes this announcement,
everyone is whipped into this. Just panic. No one knows what's going on.
The thing is too, there were like some pretty highly competent,
intelligent people speculating quite a lot,
like looking at code changes and dips and, and I was like, wait,
but they didn't fix it yet.
-- Like what, what are they talking about?
-- They were looking for hints.
I mean,
because wasn't it, there was one of the, the,
the TLS attacks like beast or crime or something like that.
I remember researchers
gave a little bit of info about it, like a preannouncement
and using that.
-- It was, I forget who it was if it was like, yeah,
-- they found, they figured it out
like it was like, oh, well done to you.
And, and I mean, that's the danger, right?
Is if you give any details, people can usually figure that stuff out.
Well, here's the thing.
It depends,
like if you say the impact is remote code execution and
that's enough for them to figure out what the flaws.
They
probably not that they could have figured that out in the first place.
But if you say something like,
yeah, it's in like X 509 email handling,
then people would have definitely found this in 48 hours.
Yeah, maybe not. This one, maybe not. It doesn't matter anyway.
Ok, so we're all whipped into our frenzy
and then we're waiting for the announcement today on November 1st,
which is also the day after Halloween in the United States.
And so I've been eating candy for almost 24 hours to this point because
obviously I start eating the Halloween candy
long before Halloween starts in my house.
So they announced the
the issue and we're, I remember looking at it. I'm like
there's two high issues here like where's the critical? Because they also
there was the email announcement
which I got
which linked to the vulnerability page which was empty.
So I of course,
hit reload on it as fast as I could for probably
20 minutes until the text appeared and then when text appeared,
it had two high issues.
And I'm like, where's the critical issue guys?
And then so of course, I'm like,
I need to go on Twitter and see what Mark Cock is saying.
-- I go on Twitter.
-- Oh Wait.
So the current page content wasn't there originally where
it talks about why the critical is missing.
-- It
-- was
now,
but it did not say anything on that. On the vulnerability page.
The blog post talked about
why it's not critical.
So I'm like, where's the critical guys? What's going on?
And I'm of course confused.
I managed to find the blog post eventually and
this is like 30 minutes after the release drops.
And of course, I've got everyone at work is like, what's going on, you know,
is this an emergency?
What, what should we do?
It's like, I don't know yet, just hang on.
So I will say one thing in my old age is I become very good at at we'll say
slowing down
and being like, let's just chill out for a minute.
Like if we do something now or we do something in 30 minutes,
it really isn't going to matter.
And in my younger days, I would have been like, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no,
we got to do it.
-- But anyway,
-- goalkeeper stolen, right? You need the appearance of action.
Something must be done.
Well, and I'm old and I don't care anymore.
Yeah.
And now it's like, well, here's the thing,
I always come back to go watch videos of firefighters run to fires and they,
they almost never run.
Like it is so, so rare
-- because
-- if they run, they're gonna die
because they're carrying, like, you know, they, we,
you know, they got 50 to 80 pounds of gear on,
-- they're
-- running into an environment that doesn't have any oxygen in it.
The only oxygen they're getting is on their back.
If they run, they're going to use that up faster
anyway. OK.
So go to the blog post and the blog post basically says, oh we called this critical
and it's actually high
because it's a stack buffer overflow
and
-- it's probably not an issue. Oh
-- yeah, compiler protection.
They basically said there will be uh here.
However, as open SSL is distributed as source code,
we have no way of knowing how every platform and
compiler combination has arranged the buffers on the stack.
And therefore a remote code execution may still be possible on some platforms.
But they essentially, oh sorry.
The the first one was firstly, we had reports that on certain Linux distributions,
the stack
layout was such that the four bytes
overwrote an adjacent buffer that was
yet to be used.
And therefore there was no crash or ability to cause remote code execution.
Secondly,
many modern platforms implement stack overflow protections which would migrate
or sorry,
mitigate against the risk of remote code execution
and usually lead to a crash instead.
So they're basically going on to like hopefully people compile this correctly.
So it doesn't like go kaboom. And that's probably mostly true.
I hope.
-- No,
-- I, I take a ton of issue with that.
They should have called it high from the start because make claiming that our, our,
our project is distributed as source and we don't know
exactly how people are going to use or compile it.
Well, I mean, by that reasoning, every single open ssl issue is critical.
I mean, that's ridiculous. Come on.
That is
that is, that is like a technically correct move that I cannot approve in any way.
That's
that it whipped everyone into a panic and it made a freaking mess.
And now the funny thing is though,
I have lots of people contacting me that are like these guys are a bunch of idiots.
It's like
they're not dumb, they're not bad.
Like please don't think less of them, but they did screw this one up.
Well,
I think the challenge is always that if you
have to downgrade a severity rating after the fact,
it's more acceptable and it's kind of a pain
because you kind of have to prove a negative.
You have to prove this critical is not a high, right?
Whereas the flip side is
upgrading a severity later on is
in some ways easier because it's like, oh, we have to upgrade the severity because ha
you know,
clever person over here came up with exploit code and it really is exploitable.
Oops.
-- But politically and, and, like, culturally now you're done fed up, you
-- mean,
-- going from high to critical,
-- like, after the fact, like, remember shell shock,
right?
Like, there was just such a train wreck.
I mean, look, I don't think anyone would have blamed
open SSL for calling this high out of the gate. I mean, it's four bites
-- written to the stack.
-- Well, my one thought is that it's simply put moving forward.
They could say, look when compiled with reasonable and sane flags,
like which to be blunt, everybody should be doing at this point.
It's 2022. Like, come on.
Right.
To be blunt. If you're like,
not doing this then.
Well, that's on you.
-- I like, I'm sorry. That's, that's just how that is.
-- I agree.
I agree completely.
So, yeah, to be clear, I think I, I wish openness as hell had just gone with,
had gone with high across the board and been like,
assuming you have a same compiler and like if you have an insane compiler, well, two,
like you have bigger problems than this.
-- Right.
-- Right. Absolutely. So anyway, it comes out
and it's high and then
the thing that amused me the most is, of course,
at
-- work we had been preparing ourselves,
-- there's no logo. I'm so sad.
Well, well, so, but here's a funny thing
in one of
GSI, the dog's tweets. He claimed there was a logo and it had a good name. He said
I'll see if I could dig it up and find it, put in the show notes.
But yeah, apparently he claimed it was a good name,
which made me sad because internally I've been calling it
uh open SSL for Jay all week,
which amuses me to no end still.
But
anyway, and, and I would have loved an MS paint like open SSL for shell.
But,
but the point is so
all of this happens,
all of these organizations, no doubt had done a bunch of prep for a critical open SSL.
I know
a number of people I've talked to
who like, worked
in like sock, like environments like they were ready to go. Right.
They were ready for patches. They were ready to detection.
Like they'd already started looking into where
they had open SSL in their environments.
Well,
I feel like that stuff should have already been done like
-- that should be part of your posture and I
-- mean,
it's getting there like it, it, it's a long road.
Here's the thing.
I live in a relatively safe part of the country where, ok,
we technically have tornadoes.
There was a big bad one like 40 years ago
and there have been tornadoes
reported in the news, like within 50 miles of the city.
But like, it doesn't really, like, I, basically,
what I'm saying is I don't have a go bag ready to go.
But if I lived in hurricane alley or tornado alley,
yeah, I should probably have a go bag ready to go because that's part of life.
I feel like if you are not yet at the point where
I will excuse people, not having a full inventory. That's hard.
I don't even have a full inventory. I'm confident I'm missing at least one thing.
But I,
if you don't have a full inventory
of like public facing revenue generating systems and
like what
stuff kind of core stuff they're using? That's negligent in today's world.
It's, it's 2022.
No, it's not. Not yet. It look, it's, it's coming a lot,
I think Log for Shell is what really kicked a lot
-- of this off
-- and that was all about a year ago.
Yeah,
I know that it's not quite a year because I've been at Acor a year in log for Shell came,
saw the
being,
you're taking a
divisive stance on this, like everyone is working towards this,
but we all have limited budget.
We have limited resources saying everyone should be doing this now
is absurd.
-- Well,
-- what I'm saying is if you're not doing it at this point,
it's just not gonna happen.
-- It's clearly not a priority, whatever.
-- No, no, I think you're being a jerk.
I'm gonna,
anyway, we're moving on.
So
the issue comes out. Everyone's like, like the panic dies down.
There's a bunch of blog posts that are kind of lame because you could tell, like,
for example, in the one I wrote
it had a bunch of the word critical in lots of places.
I'm like, well, I better search for critical and make sure I take them all out.
But
it's
at the same time, I'm ecstatic. It, it was boring because I, right now I'm very busy.
I don't need another log for shell at the moment,
right?
-- It's just not something even if it
-- had been critical,
remote code execution in the default configuration.
Yeah, it was no Js some ubuntu and red hat.
-- So
-- no, no, here's the problem from my perspective is I work for a company
that builds software to break things open and look inside and,
and like build those inventories.
And so from our perspective,
we have people saying I don't think I have this anywhere,
but I want to make sure you're going to help me find it.
And so that's the difference. And in fact, one thing that's really cool is
uh the, the S
bomb scanner sift that, that
Acor
is the primary contributor to. It's an open source project.
And
one of our developers like worked all weekend long name is Chris Phillips.
Super cool dude,
worked all weekend long
and added the ability to start like detecting binaries on disk and figuring
out what well for now it's just node because that's the most important.
Like he, he built the structure
so we can start classifying binaries.
But then what's even more crazy is he realized that we, we're, when we're,
we're breaking these binaries open and like basically running strings
on them to do some figuring out what's going on.
Here's the thing,
there's an open SSL string.
You can reliably detect when someone compiles open SSL into a binary. And I'm like,
oh, that's exciting.
Anyway, I feel like putting all of these pieces together, right?
Like mixing it all up into the big pot and just kind of looking back at what's going on.
And I feel like
-- we have no excuse for where we are today.
-- It's simple economics.
I have open to sell my product, open to sell probably version one because, well,
version three only came out recently, like in
general terms of products, not software.
You want me to upgrade to open SSL three. Why?
Because one is less than 33 is bigger than one? No, I'm serious. Like
literally the only reason somebody would kind of have to upgrade
to open SSL three is for quick support qu IC,
the new protocol thing that's
going to eventually become very important,
especially if they're like moving video and stuff and all that kind
-- of junk around whatever
-- you need to upgrade because open SSL one,
-- it's going to be end of life in 2023.
-- Yeah, that's next year's budget problem.
And also hear me out, we just keep using it.
No, that's it.
-- That's
-- maybe
-- what do you think your TV is going to get an update from Openness
-- L 1 to 3?
-- My TV doesn't connect to the internet so I don't care.
So,
but no, I, I agree. I understand what you're saying.
I'm just saying the intent is, people should start upgrading from 1 to 3.
But here's what I'm telling you.
Here's the call to action for everyone out there
don't upgrade from open SSL 1 to 3.
Switch to the Isgs
Russell's
which is the Russ TLS library
-- and
-- the
thing that is what we should all be doing.
It's probably about the same amount of work there is in theory, more risk, but
you're, you're eating more near term risk of like,
well, here, let me rephrase it.
There's more risk in the near term of upgrading from Openness
Cell one to Russell's than from Openness Cell 1 to 3
because like maybe Russell's doesn't support it whatever feature you need or not,
but that's going to be readily apparent.
And that's the problem with security flaws, right?
Is security flaws aren't apparent
until they are. And then
you got to deal with them whether you like it or not on a weekend maybe.
Whereas if you choose to go from Openness Cell one to Russell's,
oh, it doesn't work. It's missing a feature. Ok. Let's go bug them.
Help them whatever, get that fixed
and you can do that Monday to Friday, 9 to 5 and not on a weekend or over Christmas.
And I think that's part of what people forget, you know,
is that,
yeah, there might, even if there is more risk and more work
you can define when it happens, it's not an emergency response situation.
It's like, yeah, we can just budget that. It's gonna take six months,
you know,
and I think a lot of people forget that because
there is a big difference between like Josh,
you spend four weeks working Monday to Friday 9 to 5
versus spend two weeks of doing complete crazy panic response.
Which one do you want? Well, obviously the four weeks of 9 to 5.
Yes, of course.
And, and that's what people forget is.
And I don't want to say Russell's will have no security flaws.
Like it will absolutely have security flaws, but they won't be things like that.
They will,
it will be in some ways, I think it'll be harder because
all that common stuff is like gone.
You know, it's like when you start using a web framework and all the
cross site scripting and all the authentication and stuff, just poof gone,
you know, and some poor pent tester has to have a run at your thing.
And it's like, it's, it's much harder. They have to be more creative.
I think more importantly,
how do I put this nicely the kind of bugs you find in a rust application are
you learn from them?
Yeah. Whatever. That's a lie.
We clearly have not learned from like c memory management flaws because,
-- well, here we are.
-- No, we can't learn. There's nothing to learn.
-- It's too complicated for humans.
-- Whereas with,
you know, something like a rust based program with
whatever flaws they're gonna,
they're more likely to be in logic and in
other things where we can actually learn and maybe,
you know, build better test cases, build.
-- No,
-- no, not at all.
They aren't more likely.
That's literally where the bugs will be
because memory management isn't the problem.
Like,
and we just can't learn. If you
writing an X 509 interpreter,
there's nothing to learn.
It's insanely complicated and you're going to
make mistakes because you're a human being
and there's nothing to learn.
You're also going to make mistakes because it's not,
the specification is not clear.
Like I, I
remember when, uh jeez, what was it?
The one, not the A sn one stuff, but whatever the last A sn one related one was.
And I'm like, oh, I'll just download the A sl one spec and give it a quick glance.
No, like it's 800 pages for the overview of the spec.
Yeah, they're all like that. That's normal, you
know,
because they have 30 some years of baggage attached
-- to that.
-- They were designed by the International Telephony Union who
vastly over specs things.
But, but what the point is, even though you have 800 pages of specifications,
there's still a lot of not well defined behaviors and things in it.
You know, like the same thing we discovered with TCP/IP.
The, let's encrypt people, they get this, you know.
Come on,
I'm not anyway. All right, we're, we're kind of running ourselves out of time.
I want to wrap up our, our tale, which is,
we'll say weaved itself an interesting web
and
I, I want to kind of set the stage for the future is open.
SSL is going to have more memory safety issues. They may not be critical.
I mean, the last critical was in 2016 if you look at their vulnerability page.
So 2016 to 2022 is a pretty good run, especially for
one of the most
hammered and researched and just everything libraries on the internet.
Right. So, like they're doing all in all. I think they're doing very well. Right.
But the reality is,
it is 2022
C is
a
pain in the butt
to deal with memory management in.
-- Well,
-- you provably can't do it safely.
Yes, absolutely.
-- Nobody can like open SSH can't do it. Open SSL can't do it like,
-- absolutely correct.
And so the reality is
we need to plan to go to something else and I would love it
if the OPEN SSL developers were a
part of this transition because generally speaking,
what happens in open source is these projects will hang on
years longer than they ever should.
When the reality is the open SSL developers have
an enormous amount of knowledge around the protocol and
how to write libraries and how to run a project to a degree they need to work with.
The next thing, in my opinion, it's, is G's library.
Maybe it's not, maybe there's something else but it's not c
that is the only thing I think we can all agree on.
Well and more importantly, no matter what happens,
whatever is going to come replace open SSL has to do so economically.
So the more compatible it is
the cheaper it will be.
And
well, yeah, those are the people that would
be the ones to help that happen, right?
I would love to see a rapper around Russell's that
just literally mimicked open SSL like warts and all for now
as a drop in replacement and then
fix it all later.
Well, but the thing is that is a challenge because even opens us all three had to,
you know, say like this internal function no more touching it like it's, you're
not supposed to be doing that.
And so part of the problem is you can't necessarily wrap Russell's because
-- there's also like, but we need this like incorrect behavior,
-- right?
-- No, I get that,
-- you know,
but fundamentally
what it boils down to for me is applying more
effort and human engineering to a thing based on sea.
Yeah, you're just gonna have
like, you're just gonna have more memory vulnerabilities. That's it forever.
Whereas you start using an entirely new tool set like Rust Rust,
like the Linux kernel is doing and I suspect that's going to be one of
the things that's really gonna drive rust adoption is in one or two years.
People are gonna start noticing, hey, like all that Rust code in the Linux kernel,
uh It's not really causing any problems, is it?
I have a funny story for you as I was talking to someone today
and they made a joke that in two years, the Linux kernel will be rewritten and Rust.
And I was like, oh, I, I hope that is true. I truly do.
And they were not expecting that response to their joke.
Yeah, I dude, you just gave me a warm tingle because
seriously like
that would be like 90% of the security vulnerabilities would just
-- kind of go away.
-- Well, no, no, that's, we can't say that
we have to be mindful. Rust isn't magic.
It just doesn't have memory safety issues.
That's the thing is it doesn't,
you have to be magic. This is like,
like I drive a 2015 Kia Optima. It
is a nice cheap four.
It's like the kind of car your kid would draw when they're five.
But compared to a model T Ford,
it is basically magic because Yeah,
it's got all these just normal safety features now and that's
kind of how I feel about rust and C is.
Yeah. C was,
well, you gotta remember
but that, that's all we like.
That's all we had 2030 40 years ago and worse.
It was a major step up though, from things like assembler.
It was a major step up like,
and also all the heavy lifting is taken away and,
but now we take more heavy lifting away like memory management because
like,
why would I make you do memory management when we
can have a framework to it or a language?
Because we're dealing with legacy architecture. Like, don't pretend
like this is some decision people made and they picked memory management.
This is legacy code.
I'm going to,
I'm going to end this because we're just going to end up in the weeds if I don't.
All right, thank you, Kurt. Thank you all for listening. Go to
Social security podcast.com. Hit up the show note, Susie Pounds
as podcast. Hashtag hit us up on social media. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too.
-- Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye
that.