Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siegfried and my partner in about a quarter century of it work.
-- Josh Bresser.
-- Has it been a quarter of a century?
Probably 2000
ish.
-- It's 20 three.
-- I mean, I started when I was 17 and then
that's
true
when I was,
when I was like 20 or 19, I guess
my first it job,
I was tech support at a local ISP back in the dialect days I was in high school.
Like if you're getting paid to do it,
I would have been
probably 95 or 96. Like it was a long time ago, man.
So also a quarter century old now is the furby,
right?
We're not going to be talking about the source code,
which apparently they actually released the source code.
And it's like, well,
you sent me the source code and I freaking spent like an hour looking through it.
-- We're talking about that source,
-- but something better.
I'm going to read you an article from the CBS from 1999
talking toy or spy in terms of sheer numbers.
Furbies present a significant force more than
2 million of the fuzzy owl like creatures
have infiltration in American homes with incessant
chattering that delights Children and aggravates adults.
But you won't find a single furby here at the National security agency reports.
CBS news correspondent. Bob Orr. Oh, my God. How old is that guy now?
Holy cow. That's a name from, well, forever. Anyways,
uh, the US, it's like Dan rather. Right.
The guy's still alive and being snarky on Twitter. It's awesome.
Like I remember my first, my formative childhood memories
are Dan rather in the CBS evening news,
you know. And anyways,
uh the US satellite intelligence operation has banned furby in essence,
accusing the toy of being a Chinese manufactured spy,
a secret stealing bugging device capable
of eavesdropping on sensitive conversation.
So pause for a moment. How many listening devices are around you right now?
-- So like your, your watch your phone, your ipad.
-- I'm in a small studio.
So all I have is my phone in my pocket.
Normally in my house,
I have an Alexa
on each floor that I yell at to turn lights on and off.
And that's the thing that gets me is in 25 years we've gone from, oh my God,
it's like this thing that's dangerous and the NSA must ban it too.
It's just
-- now the default. We, we
-- haven't at all though.
Look at the conversations about banning tiktok.
It's literally the same conversation. Oh, the Chinese are spying on us.
-- But the
-- hardware that it's running on is in everybody's pocket.
I mean, I, right. Absolutely. And that's made in China, almost certainly.
Man, there's so much, I think fundamentally the NSA
doesn't have
Alexa. Right.
I'm, I can't prove that,
but I'm comfortable saying that and I don't think anyone would be like, oh, yes,
they do.
I
mean, but for example, do they ban Apple watches on site?
I don't know the answer to that
and it would
shock me if they don't have some sort
of device policy depending upon where they're at.
Because like there's obviously a skiff which I never remember
-- what skif stands for but
-- secure compartmentalized information facility.
Thank you.
And I'm certain you're not bringing Apple watches
and phones and things into a skiff.
-- Yeah, but
-- where do you put them if you're
not? They have the little lockers.
-- No,
-- but a skiff could be like a temporary thing.
Like they have those tents, they have, you know, it could be a closet, it could be,
well, like an entire, I think the one in date,
there's like one in Utah that's like an entire data center because this is the
thing that always gets me is like like a good example is my kids' school,
right?
Like they, every kid has a cell phone full stop. That's just the default now.
And so they have like those shower curtain pocket hangers on the inside of the door,
you know, the clear plastic pouches to put their phones in,
which is a really good solution because you can see that your phone is there.
It's easy to find. It's, you know, nobody can, like, swipe it easily.
But, you know, when you start talking about, like, let me put it this way,
how comfortable would you be leaving your phone in?
-- Not your pocket? I
-- mean, it depends on the situation.
Like I've been to facilities where I had to put my phone in the little locker,
but there's also a gentleman with guns at the door.
So I'm comfortable enough with that.
But I mean, when I go to the gym, I put my phone in a locker and it gets a lot.
Actually, I don't, I carry my phone and listen to music on it.
I would, I
would,
if, if I, if I was going to do something that didn't require my phone at the gym, like,
swim, actually, I used to swim a lot
and I don't anymore for just because it's cold and I'm old,
but I used to swim a lot and I would leave my phone in the locker at the gym and that,
that didn't bother me at all.
It had a lock on it. I controlled the lock and that was great. I, I had no issue with it.
Like, would I put my phone in a little hanger on the backside of the door? Like,
well, but this is in a classroom? Where you've got like, 30 kids and a teacher.
-- And, you know,
-- so my concern with that is,
I would worry someone would accidentally take my phone.
I wouldn't worry about malicious intent. Right.
But now would I go to your house,
set my phone on your counter and then use
the toilet without bringing my phone with me?
-- Absolutely not.
-- What about at your parents' place?
No, no, I trust them even less.
But see, this is what I'm talking about. It's just this, we've gone from 25 years ago.
Oh my God, this, this is a real concern too.
Well, I mean, yeah, we know tiktok is spying on us.
It's been banned by one or two countries and
we're the US is even talking about banning it.
Like I said, the hardware, it runs on the fact that like on my desk,
I have the Google thing of a jigger but with the microphone turned off,
I have an Amazon Alexa in the other room.
I have, well, hey Siri,
of course, it doesn't work this one time.
It goes off all the time when we're just talking.
It made a weird noise and oh, it says there's an update available.
Odd.
Anyways. Um
wait, there's an I OS update. Ok.
Anyways, well, on that ipad, apparently anyways, but it's like jaywalking.
Jaywalking was a coin, a term coined by the car industry
to essentially like de
normalize people walking on streets because streets
used to be for people and horse carts
and then cars came along
and the car industry wanted to like den
normalize people on the street and make it for cars.
And so it's j it's not crossing the street, it's jaywalking.
You know, they're strutting across the street like they own it like those
people,
Jay. So Adam ruins everything. Adam Adam Conover
does, he does a lot of debunking stuff.
There's a show called, he had a show called Adam Ruins Everything and he did,
I don't know if it was a whole show or a segment
on jaywalking and I'll put it on the show notes. But apparently a Jay
was a derogatory term for like a hillbilly.
And so they, they basically used it as a way to be like, oh, you live in the city?
You don't cross the street where you're not supposed to,
you're smart and intelligent, you know, not like those out of towners.
-- It didn't
-- work in Europe.
My goodness. Like, good for them.
This, this whole thing, we've just super normalized.
Things like roads are for cars and
crappy sidewalks. If there are even sidewalks are for people.
Just this whole furby thing amazes me because, well, yeah,
we've gone 100 and 80 degrees, the opposite direction
-- and the thing is we can't go back.
-- All right.
I want, I want to clear up a couple of things.
So, first of all, I spent a lot of time looking at furby source code.
So we're going to talk about it for a minute.
I do not see any obvious Chinese backdoors in the source code.
Not that, that means they couldn't have changed it before they burnt it.
I feel like if you're smart enough to put back doors in a furby,
you're smart enough to not publish them in the printed source code.
You think, you think?
Well,
though
the source code is very well written and very well commented,
it's actually quite a fun read.
-- You know what it
-- reminds me of the NASA Space shuttle stuff.
-- I've not looked at their source code. Well, because
-- it's not just like
the comments are not just the what but in many cases, the why
like Josh, why does the microphone turn off when the furby starts moving?
I didn't notice that electrical noise,
the electrical noise from the motors and crap
was triggering the microphone and the sound sensors.
So essentially when the furby starts moving, they're like,
well, we have to kill the microphone for a few seconds.
Otherwise it kind of gets the feedback. That
makes
sense,
but that those comments are in the source code, right?
It's not just like, oh, disable the microphone because the motor's moving.
-- It's like, no, no, why I
-- want to reel everything back.
So there's a sensationalist article about
the NSA not allowing Furbies because now Furbies did record audio from
their surroundings and would play them back at inopportune moments we'll say.
And, and here's a, here's an interesting thing.
It's important to kind of make a distinction between
what kind of recording and it wasn't like recording it
onto permanent long storage media because that just didn't exist
25 years ago in sufficient quantities in that toy.
Like, it's not like an iphone with,
-- I think iphones are up to two terabytes now or something stupid.
-- Right.
But the furby recorded little snippets and then
-- would mutate them and play them
-- back.
-- Yeah, recycle them and, and so
-- look,
I think your story is just your usual sensationalist.
Here's a new thing.
Let's find a way to make fun of it or something because negative, I mean,
this is like the social media story,
negative content elicits a response from people that positive content doesn't.
-- And I think that's just classic
-- true.
But in fairness, this is something entirely new.
-- Furbies
-- aren't interesting now because they were novel
when they came out and now anything can
record a couple of seconds of audio mangle it and spit it back out to you.
-- Like that's just not interesting.
-- Right. Sorry. There's also sorry.
There's just this one bit. I got to read.
That's not to say furbies don't present some threat.
The FAA has banned their use during takeoffs and landings.
I would worry that furbies like CD players
and laptops may interfere with the plane's instruments.
I feel like if that was ever true, we would have had planes just crashing
-- out of the sky.
-- It was never true. Everyone knew it wasn't true.
And the real reason they banned that stuff, I think Mythbusters did a thing on this
-- so you could evacuate the plane quickly.
-- Right.
It's because you don't want someone's laptop, like,
flying across the aisle and killing someone.
And I get that I'm comfortable with that.
Like, heavy things shouldn't be out during takeoff and landing because like,
99% of incidents happen during takeoff and landing.
Like that is common sense. I get that anyway.
Ok.
Now I want to address your question about we are surrounded by listening devices.
I think the situation we have is that we have
decided these new and novel things make our lives better
and you can obviously argue any which way you want.
Like I know for a fact that my Alexa spies on me because I will
talk about a thing and then start getting ads for the thing on Amazon,
like guaranteed that is what is happening.
However,
it is very convenient to me
that I am able to
yell at a device and my lights turn on
at 530 in the morning when I wake up
like
I am comfortable with that trade off.
Some people aren't and there's, there's nothing wrong with that, right?
This is just kind of that personal threat model of what do I care about. And
I
feel that the convenience of the Alexa
is outweighed by the 100% guaranteed spying being done on me.
-- Well,
-- and I think this is what one thing I find interesting is we're using words,
like recording and listening and they're very nebulous terms because I think
most people like myself included would be applying sort of humanistic
behaviors to it. Like what does listening mean?
And I think listening is an interesting word because it implies that something is
not only hearing the audio but like processing it and like understanding it right?
Because that's a big part of listening is actually understanding
the meaning of it which in this case with the Alexa
and most everything is means it's shipping it up to the mothership for processing,
you know, like what was it?
Oh yeah, those anchor you
cameras that are like, oh they don't use the cloud at all except well,
they do and they totally ship your images up to the cloud or,
or like Roombas apparently rba's taking video or pictures of people talking on
toilets. And I'm like, well, it's got a camera in it. So like
the doy like of course it's taking pictures of stuff and sending it to the room.
But I wanna say
even if I had a robot that was completely self-contained,
I don't want pets or robots or anything
observing me in the bathroom, no matter what I am doing.
My son's cat loves watching me go to the bathroom.
That would not. No, that doesn't work in my world.
I got over it because my other son would, like,
need tech support while I'm on the toilet.
And I'm like, fine,
you know, because, well, he's, you know, he needs help typing.
So
I just, I find it really curious how things that,
well, it's like that. What is it, the overton window? How things go from, like,
scary and weird to like,
like 50% of American households have one.
-- Yeah.
-- And we stop
and more importantly we even stop just talking or thinking about it.
-- Well, what's
-- the conversation you're honestly going to have? You know what I mean?
I think this is one of the things I think about a lot as,
especially as a security person is we love to make big to dos over
whatever the hype Du Jour
is. Right.
It could be some sort of vulnerability, it could be some programming language,
it could be some library.
Cloud, whatever.
I mean, remember a decade ago when security people were like, oh,
Cloud is someone else's computer
and like, there's still people who say that,
but it's definitely a lot less than it was.
You know what electricity is?
Someone else's generator,
you know what water is?
-- Somebody else's water plant like, yeah, that's how industrialization
-- works.
It is. It's commodity infrastructure.
You own a car,
go make replacement parts for it.
Your car is somebody else's supply chain. No, I'm serious.
You want cough syrup? You can't buy cough syrup.
Everything is somebody else's computer supply chain, whatever.
-- Like I can't, I can't make anything myself
-- part of existing in a modern society.
Like I don't grow my own food. Right.
That's why I'm not starving to death.
Right.
I'm a bad farmer
but I'm good at other things. So it's fine.
And,
but anyway, I, I think this is a place security.
People often could stand to step back and think and observe
because the behavior of people has never changed throughout history.
Right. There's always new thing comes out.
Some subset of the population complains about it and partially out of fear,
partially out of like it gets the clicks or the eyeballs or
you're looking for. Right.
And then you also have part of the population that embraces
-- it because it's interesting and new and fun for whatever
-- reason,
it might make their life better.
Like, you know, people who are paralyzed can now turn their lights off and on easily.
That's right.
Exactly. You
know, and so,
but security people, I think love to just pick up position and be like, I'm right,
you're wrong.
There's no discussion
and
I think we're getting better at that a little bit. I feel like 5 to 10 years ago,
security was much more rigid of like, you must do it our way.
Or else where I, I see,
I see people in organizations that are now saying things like this is the existing
universe, work in,
how do we help reduce risk in this world instead of saying
you have to do it our way and if you don't,
you're dumb
and we won't help you.
And then they're like, well, fine, I guess we're dumb and you won't help us and they
do it the way they want to.
Well, it's,
it's funny because I was having a similar conversation
about cloud versus on Prem and I'm like,
part of it is
on Prem. Used to be the only way to do it. Sure. There was no cloud 20 years ago. Like
there, there literally was nobody to outsource this to.
You had to go buy your own hardware and get your own network and figure it out.
But the world changed. Same thing with electricity. Like,
you know, go watch the original prisoner series from what is it?
1960 1970 anyway, somewhere in there.
And remember he takes the helicopter tour of the island and he's like,
we have our own running water and power and it's like, well, of course you do,
like you have a generator and like a, well,
if you have an island, you probably need that. Right.
But that's the point is like they're living
on an island running like this weird prison.
So they have to do it themselves.
Everybody else, you know, we phone Epcor and are like,
can you please turn the electricity on to my house?
Well, ok, so actually this is an interesting analogy because
there have been,
we'll say numerous catastrophic weather events
in North America so far this year. This is the very beginning.
Well, not this year but the, for the last six months,
we'll say this is the very beginning of 2023 when we're recording this.
And
I know people who didn't have electricity from the grid for more than a week.
And if they owned a generator, they were just fine.
And if they didn't, they basically packed up and left because you,
you can't survive without electricity in modern society.
That's just the reality of it.
And I think this is kind of one of those examples where you can say like, OK,
I'm going to completely outsource to the cloud.
You have no backup. And if the cloud goes down,
there's literally nothing you can do. You have to just sit there and do nothing.
One difference being is that for example,
Amazon Google and Microsoft are generally incentivized to run a good cloud.
Like you look at the Texas electricity grid
and
yeah,
I'm sorry, I don't want to say the things I want to say about it,
but like I live in Canada in Edmonton specifically, it's interesting, for example,
Alberta actually overbuilt our electricity transmission infrastructure
a few years ago because they were,
they basically were projecting usage and got it wrong and good.
Well, it's not good because we basically spent a couple billion dollars.
We didn't need to spend,
that could have been spent somewhere else doing something useful and good.
I mean, maybe so. That's the thing.
There's no, it's not like yay, we have extra electricity transmission potential.
Well, but we don't use it and it's a waste of money
and that money could have done some good somewhere else.
Once electric cars catch on, you'll be glad you have that. It's fine.
Well, but the thing is, I also live in a, I say, newer neighborhood,
it's a 19 eighties neighborhood and all the lines are underground.
And so I basically have zero power interruptions.
Like I made a conscious, I mean, I have UPSS for all my computers just for,
it's for power conditioning more than power outages though, to be clear.
But I, I very conscious, like I looked back in the day into getting like a gene
15 K, you know, natural gas powered, cut in, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah thing. No,
I, I have so few outages here. It's basically about one or two hours a year. Yeah.
And I'm, I'm in the same boat. I live in a city. I actually have overhead lines. Yeah.
-- But
-- if I lived in Texas I would buy one in a heartbeat
and, and I agree.
Or if I lived in the country because all of the people I know who
lost power for a significant amount of time are not living in the city.
Well,
the problem is because those are the people that get service fixes last because we
can fix this line and it'll fix it for 100 people in an apartment building.
Or
we can fix this line and it fixes it for one guy living on an
ebb.
I actually, the first house I ever owned was on this, like Power Island.
It was this block that had one power line connecting the block
to the grid and we lost power all the freaking time.
And yeah, it'd be like it, we lost power,
I think for like 36 hours one time because they were like, yeah,
there's six houses on this block.
Like we'll get to it when we get to it where, you know,
there's 10,000 people over there without power,
we're gonna go help them first and I get that like I get it.
I did not miss leaving that house
because
we lost power a lot. But anyway, anyway. All right. All right.
I wanna, I wanna reel it back all the way to what we were talking about, which is furby
and new and novel devices kind of entering
our sphere of life
and how people react to those things.
And I think we can,
there's the security angle that we obviously have discussed and how new and
different things sometimes and how we have to adapt to what we have.
And I think the fundamental message I have around all of
that is just the fact that it is very important,
I think to look at
how things are
and start there instead of saying this is how things should be.
Right.
Well, and more to the point there's
obviously some sort of business case or need
or reason for this technology to take off.
Like
I remember mainframe people complaining about TCP/IP, like, oh,
you can't really control it.
Like anybody can, like, anybody from the internet can connect to your system.
Well, yeah, that's,
that's the whole point of the internet is anything on
the internet can connect to anything on the internet.
-- And, well, it turns out that was actually really good
-- Ethernet versus Token Room.
Remember all that? Like, oh, how can you possibly use this type of network? Like its
over at 80%?
Well, yeah, it 100% like
I ran, you know, the hubs that, like, you hit that 80% utilization and
the Ethernet just poops itself.
-- And then we got switches
-- even before switches, it was just so easy.
Everyone used it like there was no contest
and if you unplugged the cable it affected one system, not the whole bloody 10,
2 network,
you know.
Oh, yes. Yes.
I remember stories of people that were at universities
where there were like long runs and people would unplug
the, the computer, like,
on one far end of the building and no one knew what
was going on and all of a sudden the token ring failed
and they're like running around the whole building trying
to figure out what got unplugged and where?
Well, 10 base two, right? You had a long, essentially coax
cable. But with T connectors and if any T connector got unplugged, it broke.
If any, if either of the end caps got unplugged, it broke.
If the cable got punctured
and grounded slightly, it broke like it just
a lot of, and then it broke.
I know. Oh, man, anyone who talks about the good old days of networking is a moron.
Like it was
what gets me is they were so awesome at the time.
Like I remember when I first deployed 10 megabits
at my parents' house and I had my two,
our three computers all networked up and like had an NFS going and it was awesome
and then,
you know, got a 10 megabit per second cable modem and like,
yeah, compared to dial up, that was amazing,
you know, 10 megabits symmetric.
So I, I do like the old days in the sense of like
it was progress and we've come even further since
I don't want to go back to them
to be clear. But it was like,
it was good to learn that.
Like I'm,
I'm glad I know kind of how web servers and stuff work at a very fundamental level.
Whereas most modern people don't because they just use a platform
as a service and it mostly works until it doesn't.
And then they're kind of up, you know, then they, they're like Kurt
and I'm like, oh, let me go figure out what's going on. It's DNS. It's always DNS.
It's,
it's always DNS.
I
know,
but that's ok.
You know, that's something I catch myself doing
on a regular. So I was, I help with that high school robotics
and we have our own, like,
mini network where we have all kinds of devices hooked up to and we communicate with
the robot and all that kind of stuff and it stops working the other day.
And one of the kids is like, it's not working. What do I do?
And
no, no, no, that wasn't the first step.
The first step was I said, all right, let's, let's figure this out.
I'm going to teach you some things ping this IP. And let's see. Can we get here?
Can we ssh into that like,
yeah. Yeah. Yeah. And we did a little bit of stuff and at the end we just
it off turned it back on because
that was,
that was literally what needed to be done because the machine
we were trying to connect to was unresponsive and was headless.
So like we had no choice but to turn it off.
-- But at the same time it was like,
-- but now, you know, it's the machine, not the network.
-- That's right.
-- That's right. And it was, it was amusing because
at the same time they're like, how do you know all this stuff because, like,
I know all the private IP space and it's like,
be thankful you don't need it.
You know, it's funny because I had
same problem on my true net scale box where I set it up by default,
set up a VM and the VM can't talk to the host, which I needed to, to
NFS mounted directory.
And I'm like the heck so the VM can ping my gateway and it can reach the internet,
but it can't ping the underlying host. I'm like, what the heck.
So I a quick Google and it's like, yeah, it's a known problem.
You got to set up a bridge network. And I'm like, oh, and I didn't even have to read the
like how to set up a bridge network because you and
I are old enough to remember how to do that,
right.
So I set up the bridge
work reboot. I broke it, set up the ridge network correctly the next time reboot.
And yeah, it just works.
But on all these poor people on the internet that like, you know,
we're struggling to get it to work.
So it's well like the cloud flare in the mail channel thing.
I actually wrote a document from start to finish on how to get it working,
pulling documentation from three or four sources together.
And that's that again,
that's a problem is this documentation is always out there somewhere on how
to fix it but it's not necessarily like from A to Z,
you know, in a complete set, like,
you know, and it's funny because the mail channels person was like, oh, can we,
can we use your documentation like, yeah, sure.
Like it's, it's here and it's open source license. Like go for it like this.
Like I'm like I wrote it because future Kurt is going to have to,
you know,
rotate the DKIM keys in six months and he's not going to remember what the heck he did.
You know, I'm gonna have to look at that stupid open SSL command again.
-- Yeah,
-- you don't need to rotate those things. They're good forever. It's fine
until I check them into
github or do something stupid like that.
Yeah, I know. I know. I'm familiar with that problem
anyway. All right. All right. We're off in the weeds again.
So, but, but again, that kind of feeds into the whole, like,
we need a few masters mechanics because 99% of fixing your
car is plug in the OD BC reader and be like,
this piece needs to be replaced.
We replaced the piece. Your car works pretty much.
My son's computer had a problem in the power supply and I'm like,
what's like now that we fixed it?
What do we do? And he's like, uh, do we, like, you know,
take the power supply part and figure out what was wrong? And I'm like, why?
Like, what's the is there any value in that? And he's like, well, we know it's broken.
I'm like,
and is there any value in us knowing that he's like,
well, not really.
I'm like, yeah, like, maybe for the manufacturer,
if they had hundreds of these things failing
to find, if there's a, you know, a manufacturing flaw they can fix.
But for us it's like
we throw it away now it's e waste.
Like
we replaced it
and the old one gets thrown out.
-- Yeah,
-- I get that. I totally get that.
And probably there's people on our show listening
to it yelling at their computer right now.
Uh
Yeah, probably, probably. All right.
I wanna, I wanna end the show on one fun topic and that's,
this is what I expected us to discuss today,
which is what I actually keep prepared for,
which is
the archiving of stuff because like the source code,
Kurt sent me was the furby source code from 1998.
It was in a patent application and it got scanned and uploaded to archive.org.
It was in a patent application.
That's what it said in the You didn't even read it. Did you,
-- you sent me this crap and I spent hours reading it. So, you know,
-- I send
-- you
-- lots
of random links. I don't expect you to read all of it.
I read most of it but,
you know,
-- I
-- feel bad.
I feel bad too.
But
so anyway archive.org has all this cool source code.
They've, they've archived, I guess that's what they do
and
imagine that.
But
it's something I was thinking about is when we, like, as security people,
I feel like we're constantly just running forwards where there's, you know,
new time
technology, new event, new, whatever and we rarely stop and look behind us.
And some of this archive stuff is really cool and really fun to look at
and not that I'm saying it has like enormous value to what we do.
I mean, you could make an argument of, oh,
you should archive all viruses or something
and whatever and maybe maybe you should,
maybe you shouldn't.
But
I do think it's amusing to look at some of this old
archived content to see kind of how things used to be.
Maybe in some ways you can see progress and
sometimes you could maybe claim it was better.
It probably wasn't, but
it's just, it's really fun to do.
You know, it, it really was enjoyable to just poke around in that archive.
Archiving data is a critical like think of the library of Alexandria,
like archiving human knowledge,
culture data information is really critical because
um
for example, like river flow data or temperature data might turn out to be very,
you know, important for figuring something out in the future and having
10 years of data versus 100 years of data versus 200 years of data.
That's a, that's a big difference,
you know,
I'll agree with that.
And especially now with digital storage being what it is and more importantly,
not just digital storage, but
like the ability to index and search it being well used to work for elastic.
So you kind of know about this. I'm familiar with it.
It's all like, again, it's a,
it's available and achievable and costs in a way that 20 years ago we couldn't have,
it just wasn't possible.
Yeah.
Oh Yeah.
And, and now there is one thing I was thinking about in this context and that is
archiving
asset inventories over time
where the example being when something like log for shell comes out
and you have to say, have I ever run log for J ever
in my infrastructure?
And
if you have the ability to go back, say five years by looking at, you know,
builds or materials or acid inventories or whatever you have and say like, oh,
we ran log for Jay in December of last year.
That has value, especially when, you know, like this is a time span.
We have to look at logs, we have to understand and if you
have log
for J deploy during whatever the time span is, you care about who cares?
You're good, you know, and that's something that can save a lot of time, which is,
which is awesome.
Yeah, I remember getting those questionnaires from, you know, various
companies saying, you know, does the CS A use log for J and what's your position on it?
I'm like, thanks. No, no, J
none at all. Like we got some ubiquity gear to update, but that's it.
Yeah.
Well, I mean, the,
the circle C I thing that just happened actually
kind of comes to mind because we had to,
obviously at work we rotated all our credentials.
Great. We rotated the credentials. Now, I have to go
through logs and artifacts to make sure nothing was touched.
And it's like I, I get that,
but at the same time I knew exactly what I had
to look at and that saved me enormous time versus saying,
I don't know exactly what was using this.
-- So now I have to go and spend like weeks looking through logs instead
-- of
basically it, I mean, it's the difference between a library with a card catalog.
If anybody knows what that is still
-- there is one without a card catalog. Computers.
-- Now,
actually, where was it? I was that a library? So I'm a huge nerd.
Obviously, when I go to a new city, I go to the libraries. Libraries are amazing,
but
I never thought that you were a nerd.
That's fair.
But I love going to the library. It's like it's one of my favorite things
and I was just at one,
I don't remember what city I was in and they still had the old
wooden card catalogs and I went and opened the drawer and I'm like,
holy cow.
There's cards in here
and then I was like,
I should, I wanted to go talk to the librarians about it.
I'm like, no, they're probably busy.
They have, I'm sure they would have talked to me for hours. But,
like, part of me was wondering, like, do they keep it updated?
Is it just like a historical artifact now in the library? Like,
it was amazing.
That's one of my favorite practical effects is
the card catalog scene from the first Ghostbusters
with the cards shooting out of the catalog.
-- Like, it's just such a great practical effect and it's so effective.
-- That's
true. That was really good.
That was, I forgot about that. I haven't watched Ghostbusters in a long time.
-- As
-- far as I'm concerned, there's only two Ghostbusters films.
-- Sorry,
-- I haven't seen the new one even. I don't, again, I don't watch a lot of movies.
It doesn't make any sense.
That's fair. That, that's what I feel like for most movies. It's kind of like what?
00, you know what I did.
So, uh, just totally off on the side tangent,
which is fine because we don't ever have whatever.
So I was playing the original Lego Star Wars game because I set up Steam
Link to my downstairs computer so I could play it in all this stuff.
Right.
And I'm playing it
and I'm playing episodes 12 and three and I'm like, oh,
these are kind of crappy episodes and then I
play episodes 45 and six and that's where,
that, that game stops there.
And I thought, you know what, just like it jogs some memories and stuff and I'm like,
episode 78 and nine were like,
they're really bad.
Like, when I think episodes 12 and three aren't that bad in comparison.
I know some
-- made a huge mistake because those movies are terrible and, and 78 and nine,
-- I, I,
I'll be honest, I haven't even seen them.
-- Don't just,
-- I
can't be
-- bothered.
-- Did you watch the Matrix movies? Matrix 12 and three.
When they came out back
in the day?
One was amazing.
Two was pretty ok.
It
-- wasn't.
-- And then, well, no, the V FX and stuff were cool
and then three
and then the plot just fell apart and it was like, well, I saw that one coming and like
I remember walking out of Matrix Two and I turned to the people I was with and I said,
I feel like I've been robbed, like I paid money for this,
but then I walked out of three and I turned to the same people.
I was like, this makes two seem not so bad, doesn't it?
I don't know.
I just,
I, I feel like it's this curse of like we made a successful film now make me one.
That's exactly the same, but just different enough to get people back in theaters.
I mean, yes, that's always been the case of countless
just movie
trilogies or whatever. Like this is something I watched a show about Star Wars,
episode 655, return of the Jedi
and actually not return of the Jedi Empire strikes back.
And this was one of the concerns the studio
had is they said like Sequels never do well.
This movie is probably going to flop and
it didn't obviously because it was a masterpiece,
but
everyone expected it to fail because it was a sequel. Like this is not a new problem.
This has always been a problem in movies. It's just we feel like it's new
because there are a lot of Sequels right now.
But anyway. All right, we're far enough in the weeds.
I think we should just call this one.
Anyway, I'll, I'll put, I'll put the furby source code in the show notes.
It's a fun read. Go, go look at it. So, thank you, Kurt. Thank you all for listening.
Go up with our security podcast.com. Head up the show notes. U
Podos
Podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.