December 8th door number eight.
We're getting ever closer to the final day
security periodic system security check on open BS D.
-- Why is it,
-- why is it on day eight
though?
Because it's
section eight of the Man pages,
-- which means what most people don't even know what Man pages are
-- anymore. God,
you're right.
Old man yells that cloud.
So man pages were
uh uh
so like section one general commands then system calls library functions,
PERL library
and
you
keep a
man space command.
And so some commands existed more than once.
Uh like in the sense of like, um
-- I'm trying to, I can't print F.
-- Print F is an easy example
because print F is in lib C which is in what? Section five I think?
No, that, well, depending on is that Linux
-- bs D is
-- different, whatever
I use. Linux.
And then obviously like Bash has a print F command also.
That would be in, I think two or is two. Li I don't know whatever
matter it doesn't matter anymore. I haven't, I haven't looked at man,
well, I shouldn't say that I look at Man pages all the time.
I, I still read Man pages once in a while because I just got to find that, you know,
like, it's like, I know this will do it.
Which freaking switch because, like, I tried hyphen hyphen volume.
Oh, it's like hyphen volume or like,
because I know it's not hyphen V because that's verbosity. Right.
Except when it is hyphen capital V or, or just,
right. This isn't an episode on Man pages though
-- or, or it could be.
-- But anyways, it's just, it's comical
that this old stuff because this came up on Twitter a while ago about, you know,
the links to
Australia security guy. And I'm like, this stuff is so out of date.
It's hysterical, but it's like
this is what I love because it basically assumes that you have a system
and that's it. Like you have a system,
right? Nowadays, we have, I believe virtual machines and also
more than one computer because computers kind of got cheap. Like
I'm trying to,
I think I have three Raspberry pies floating around my house right now.
I have at least that I might have more
-- 10, so
-- it's interesting,
this is the angle you're going because I was
thinking about this in a completely different way,
which is
so this the security command and open BS D
and I will obviously put a link in the show notes,
it runs every day and basically sends you the crown output.
And I thought the interesting part of this is, it was all about, like,
let's just automate some really simple checks.
Even though you could argue today, they're kind of useless.
But like that automation is key.
Well, they were useful 20 years ago but now they're useless.
But 20 years ago they actually matter because you
had more than one user on your system.
Yeah, that would have been super common and just doing this automatically is huge.
Well, here's the thing I love about automation is it does
four main things. Number one, it automates it. So it actually gets done.
Even if you don't feel like doing it, it gets done. Number two latency,
things that are automated tend to take less time and
things that require you whipping a human to do.
Number three, it forces you to like write down your assumptions
and essentially
what does this actually do? Oh, we're doing a security check. No, no.
What does your security check actually check? Oh, all checks this and this.
What about this? 00, crap. We should check that too.
Sure. Number four is it allows you to, to then iterate and improve it
and share it right? Because
like I can't, I can say blah, blah, blah,
cool.
I give you a bash script. That's, that's shareable.
This comes back to I think the long running theme
on the podcast of artisanal security is bad and dangerous.
Oh God, yes, I'm going through this with threat modeling.
I'm using spreadsheets so we can share it.
That's it, we can cut and paste and share it.
-- It's
-- massive.
Even though this,
this program is almost definitely out of date for the threats of today.
-- The concept behind it is
-- check user home directory permissions.
Like how would they even get wrong? I it happens and more to the point
why would you have more than one user on a system?
Now, you would just container those buggers.
It's uncommon now.
So actually, in all seriousness,
I could see that check being hugely important because one of the favorite
tricks we would use back in the day when we were pranking our friends
is we would get them to do something that
added the right permission to their home directory.
And once we had that we were home free,
-- do
-- I remember back in the day when home directories weren't secure?
Like in the sense of
only Bob had access to Bob's home directory,
like it was just world readable by default.
Well, right,
you make it world readable because then you can tell people to just
jump in your home directory and copy some stuff out of it.
I remember Linux back in the day didn't do that.
-- It was just everything was public by default because wouldn't you want to
-- share it?
It was way easier, man.
Like honestly, in all seriousness when I was in college,
we had a lot of shared systems and it was super common to say, oh, I've got it in my,
you know, whatever directory in my, in home, go grab it from me.
Just
read
it like we did that all the time and it was no big deal.
But today that sounds horrifying to me
because it is.
Yeah.
Right. Anyway, anyway,
so I
like, I love how security evolves and changes and gets better,
but at the same time the basics, like automating stuff
are the same.
I don't think automation is a basic but it should be,
-- you
-- know, I agree. Yeah, you're right. Automation.
See,
you
see you December 9th.