We can link this in the show notes. But it's my interview with Elias Lovey from 2001.
-- God Almighty. That was a long time ago.
-- That is a long time
ago.
-- That's two
-- decades. I bet half our listeners weren't alive in 2001. Kurt.
Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in being old Josh Bresser.
It's true. Well, you know, it's funny because, I mean, it's
like my parents just, they're at the point where, you know, if you ask my mom,
how long have you been married?
She has to think about it and she's like 52 no, 53. Like, you know, it's been a while
and I get that, you know, like I'm at the age now where I'm kind of like, yeah,
I'm just old.
Like I've stopped caring about the number because it's just,
it's old.
But
yeah, today is a special anniversary.
Well, it's not technically today,
but
we'll say
in the,
in the recent span of days, I, I guess I would call it industry changing,
paper smashing the stack for fun and profit. When appeared in Frack, 49
was published. I mean, 25 years. That's,
it's old enough to drink in the United States,
uh,
in pretty much every jurisdiction in the world even where it is.
You have to be 25 or something. Ridiculous.
I don't know if there's any, there might be, but
there are some, it's really funny because I remember when this came out and it was,
it felt big back then
and I think it is even bigger today because there's
so much of, of our whole industry
that I think you can trace roots back to this particular paper.
Well, and not just the paper but the one.
Uh
so for those of you who don't know, he goes by the uh the hacker handle A F
one. And if you want to read about why that is, it's an actually uh
we'll post on the notes, a
link to an interview I did with him back in 2001
like so old. But what's fascinating to me is his Wikipedia entry.
Uh entry is super short,
but I would say between smashing the snack for fun and profit
and oh, you know, the minor thing of moderating bug track,
he had a very formative like like a madame
C level of formation on our industry.
I mean, I agree. OK. Why don't we set some of this up?
Because there's going to be people who don't know what
bug track was or what Frack is Frack still is
and
all of this. So let's start with bug
-- track. What was bug
-- track? Bug
track was? I think basically the first security mailing list that was public.
It was, it was always back in the day.
It was bug track and full disclosure were the two. I
think everyone paid attention to
and bug track through a series of acquisitions is now dead. And I love that
the, the latest holder of, at accenture announced, you know,
we're shutting it down on January 15th of 2021.
And then the next day they're like, oh, January 16th, they're like, oh, no.
Uh, there's push back and people cried
and we're going to do something with it and of course, nothing has been done with it.
It's dead, like it's
dead dead. Like, like not Princess Bride dead, but like proper dead.
Well, I, I think
that is a normal human response is people like us hear about a thing that we hold
in a special place in our, our memories, like bug
track and we think, oh, you can't possibly shut that down.
-- But those
-- stupid little mcdonald's cookies.
-- Yeah.
-- Right.
But when, I mean, when was the last time bug track had, like,
legitimate and serious mail sent to it.
Yeah.
Well, even though
it's,
-- it's there, you know, it's just vendor announcements basically.
-- Now
I would say the communications mediums for security teams
has changed.
Right. It's no longer mailing lists like it used to be and that's ok.
Like things change. It is how it works.
Yeah. And so,
ok, so, bug
track. What about Frack?
What is Fr?
Yeah.
Well, and that's the thing, some of these things, just like the Eff and Frack,
I think they'll probably be around in 200 years.
-- I certainly hope so.
-- Yeah.
So, Frack is,
well, I mean, what can I say? Other than it's the
hacking magazine,
it's not a magazine. It's an e,
sorry e,
you
know, come
-- on.
-- I just in my mind, well, I think in my mind,
well, and that's interesting because, yeah,
back in the day magazines and books were
legitimate and this online stuff was not legitimate
and now I would say the online stuff
is probably more legitimate than printed out crap.
So, in my mind it's, it's a magazine, it's legit, it's online, it's the real deal,
you know, it's not some
wanna be the
kitty website with some content on it, you know, compared to the, like, oh, like,
I literally wrote the security column for a Linux
journal for eight years monthly and it was,
like, real because it's in print and, you know, that impressed a lot of people
whereas honestly, like
Frack has better content than the stuff I put out.
Oh. Right. Right. Frack is some of the best
-- agreed quickly on that one.
-- It's not, yeah,
I'm not gonna pretend
like there's no point in lying
but and FR
is still being published. Episode, episode
issue 71 came out a couple of months ago.
So that's awesome. I love seeing some of this stuff continue its life.
It's, it's marvelous. Ok.
So Frack issue 49 we're on issue 71 now to
give you an idea of what we're talking about here.
And this
is an easy, that comes out
maybe once a year, sometimes
when it's ready.
Yes, that's exactly. Exactly.
So, in, in issue 49
which was published in 1996 to give you an idea,
which
I was a teenager in
the
46.
I don't,
I have a 46. I might,
I was
still on my 386.
-- I
-- probably, I was either. So
I had a 3 86 25 megahertz with four megabytes of ra M. Mind you any 100 meg hard drive.
It was very nice.
Yeah.
And then I went from that to a Pentium and it would have been right
around this time that I made the jump because I went to a Pentium.
-- Was it 166?
-- I think it was,
that would have been a fast machine back then.
I remember it came with a, a four gigabyte hard drive and I was like,
I will never fill this out.
And
it took about three months, I think
downloading wares off of FTP sites.
But anyway, anyway,
so
if one publishes smashing the stack for fun and profit and
this changed everything for a lot of people because I think
smashing the stack for exploiting vulnerabilities. It wasn't a new idea,
but it was very dark magic.
-- I think prior to
-- this,
it was simply like launching a rocket to the moon in the early sixties.
-- Yeah.
-- Right. Right. It was, you had to have
very specialized knowledge.
And I mean, this,
this paper is where I gained like all of my knowledge around how to
exploit buffer overflow stack based buffer overflow
specifically because back in these days,
we didn't yet know how to exploit
buffer overflows correctly.
So, but at the same time,
like everyone used the stack for everything because we sucked at programming.
-- So it's fine.
-- No, it's well.
And that's the thing you said, not, it's not just the knowledge but the tools,
right? We we barely had,
I remember seeing my first hack editor and I was like, whoa
I'm looking at the code like, like, you know what I mean?
Like it was that scene from hackers or whatever,
like literally tools. Like I remember when debugging tools
as terrible as they were
like, were a huge,
huge step forwards from having nothing.
Like literally you had a crash dump and a hex editor. Good luck.
That's right.
That's right. You know, break points, what the heck's a breakpoint.
And so
one of the reasons we want to discuss this paper isn't to
go on nostalgically about how amazing it was but rather to talk about
kind of how did it help usher us into where we are today?
Because for example, if you take smashing the stack for fun and profit today
and you sit down on a Linux machine,
you can't actually go through
the exploits
because there's a bunch of things in place now that make it not possible. I mean, you,
you could
configure the system in a manner that makes it possible.
But by default,
it doesn't work anymore. And that's really cool.
And you can trace all of these modern protections back
to this paper, which is cool.
So, let me, let me kind of start explaining what we have here because I, I think
given it doesn't work.
Not everyone understands what smashing the stack even means.
Well, in fairness, there are people who are,
even if you're not
younger than this paper. Like, if you're 40
you were 15 years old when this paper came out
and basically the fixing the,
like, fixing all this stuff happened before.
You probably learned a lot about computers. Like, it's just, it's so old. It's like,
it's like, um,
I'm trying to think of, it's like whooping cough.
Right.
Most people don't know what the heck whooping cough is because it's so old timey.
That's right. That's right. Yes. Ok.
So here's how this works is back in the days of yore.
Well, even today, I guess so, in the, in the world of executing computer code, right.
We're talking binaries here running
on the CPU doing their business. There's kind of two
things you have to think about.
There's what's called the heap and there's what's called the stack.
And the heap is like when you hear people talk about allocating memory,
you're allocating memory in the heap. OK?
And when you're like an old school c programmer,
you have to allocate memory and then you have
to free the memory when you're not using it.
-- Modern languages don't have this problem.
-- Garbage collection is a, is a good thing.
-- Yeah, it's, it's very hard to do,
-- right? Not only is it hard to do, right?
But efficiently
if you want right hand efficient, then you, you need wizards.
Uh
you need rust. But
so, so the stack is what we're going to talk about today.
So the idea behind a stack is you have your program and you call subroutines
and you have variables that live on the stack.
And the stack is literally think of it like a stack of stuff. OK?
Where it's the idea is last in first out where you can
push things onto the stack and you can pull them back off,
but you can only pull things off in order.
Yeah.
So what happens when you're executing a program is, let's say I go,
I jump to a subroutine.
What it's going to do is basically push the
current state of where I'm at onto the stack
and it's going to jump into the subroutine.
And one of the things that is pushed onto the stack is the address to return to
when we're done with our subroutine. OK?
Now,
the way this works is let's say we have some variables in
the subroutine we jump to that are what's called a stack variable.
OK.
Stack variables on the stack you can imagine, right? So we're piling these things up
and as you write to them, if we imagine the stacker from the bottom to the top,
as you write variables,
you write them from the top of the variable to the bottom of the variable.
OK?
Now the address we return to is underneath these variables.
So if I have, let's say a string
and
I can write as much data as I want into the string,
I can overwrite the return address
that's on the stack. And so that means when the subroutine
exits,
we now jump
to whatever I wrote
into the return address.
And this is well before
address stack lay
randomization and other such tricks were even
even thought about let alone implemented.
Well, we'll talk about those in a minute because those are very,
very important for this story.
But so the idea is
I if you read snatching the stack for fun and profit,
they they explain all of this much better than I am for sure.
So I I would highly recommend going to read it.
But then so basically it just explains to you how
the stack works and it shows you how you can exploit
security issues for stack buffer overflows to overwrite the return
address to then execute the code of your choosing.
When you hear about people talk about shell code.
The idea behind shell code is I put some special,
I basically put a program somewhere in memory and then I tell
II I as part of my attack payload, I then say, OK, jump to the,
the code in this location, which is my shell code I put in
and then that makes the program execute whatever I want it to. And back in the day
it was just a bash shell. It was
-- maybe not even bash and I was
-- going to say it,
yeah, it would be a local shell.
It wouldn't even be like a network listening shell because again,
we hadn't invented that yet.
I remember the first time I saw a network listening shell and I was like, yeah,
my jaw dropped because it was amazing.
That's right. That's right.
So OK,
so that's kind of the, the poorly described primer
on what
smashing the stack means.
And again, go read the paper. It does a very nice job. And when, when this came out like
-- this changed everything for everyone. He
-- showed that it was possible
and not just that he showed it was possible like did a demo on stage,
but like here's the instructions you can replicate this.
That's right.
And it was very easy to replicate because there were,
there were basically no protections.
I mean, this wasn't an attack anyone
I think had really understood and it was, it was, it was black magic.
And so it was easy to disregard as, oh, we don't really have to worry about that.
Oh, there's a stack buffer overflow. Yeah, it's a bug, whatever.
We'll just fix it later.
And
this, this brought this knowledge down from the mountain to the masses right
now.
The really cool thing though is so, so some of the reasons this doesn't work anymore,
I think are really important.
So I talked about overriding
the variables into your return address, right?
So the way we fix that was really clever.
We created this thing called the step canary.
And so what happens now is between the return address
and the data,
there is what's called the canary and it's just basically
a little bit of information that's a random string.
And before we jump to our return address, we say has this string changed?
If it's changed, we know shenanigans are afoot
and we should just crash the program,
right? Don't execute it.
And like that, that sounds super simple. But this was a huge deal at the time.
Yeah, I just, I had to look it up because it's so old. I,
I honestly had forgotten about
secondaries because it's been, they were invented in 1997.
And they just
work
kind of mostly.
-- Yeah,
-- I mean, they, they're so stack canaries.
It should be said those are compiler technologies. When you compile your C code,
I think they're on by default. Now, in all the compilers they didn't used to be,
but
not these days when you build ac program into a binary,
-- it's going to insert stat canaries all over the place
-- and sorry.
This is another
I remembered it was, it was invented by Crispin Cohen,
who's the guy that also invented app Armor.
Yeah, that's right. That's right. And he was working, I think, was it Nets
D at the time he was working on,
-- that was so long ago. I mean, it's,
-- my brain doesn't even
remember. This
is like discussing the middle ages,
the
dark
-- ages.
-- It is, I mean, it is the middle ages of computers for sure.
I would agree with that.
Yeah. Chrisman Cohen did the work and
it's funny because I think now if someone did this,
they probably patent the crap out of it.
And
like,
but
it,
so I don't think it is a coincidence that
smashing the stack paper comes out and then
Chrisman Cohen invents stack canaries a year later.
I mean, that was kind of a stick was inventing security technologies to, you know.
Yeah,
that's kind of what he does.
Yeah. Right. I mean, it's your typical game of cat and mouse, right?
Where you have the Attackers attack and then the defenders can defend.
Well, and I mean, it still goes on today, like my favorite being, um, a few years ago,
all those CPU hardware
ish, I guess, issues,
you know. And,
yeah, I mean,
the new CP US, you look at some of the capabilities in the new A MD and Intel CP US.
And it's like, oh, man,
like, I wish you had that 10 years ago, but, well, we have it now better, you know,
better now than never.
That's right. That's right. OK. So let's keep going. So let's assume
we turned off stack canaries in the compiler which you can do.
It's a flag and I built the C program,
it's still not going to work, right?
Because we also have this really cool idea. We call address space randomization.
It's a
I address space layer randomization that that's what it is, right?
And so one of the,
I guess interesting things you will learn if you read,
smashing the stack for fun and profit is
you compile a program
and then you run it and the memory location of all
the stuff is the same every time you run it.
And that's really important because basically you run your program, you crash it
and then you look at the memory locations,
then the next time you run it, you know what the locations are.
So you can start inserting
like correct memory values to jump to the places you want to jump to, right.
That makes sense.
Was it Gen two Linux that basically you compiled from scratch every machine?
Yes.
And so I remember one security consultant arguing that Gen two.
Linux was the best Linux for security
because it had to be compiled on every machine. Every instance of Gen two.
Linux was unique. And the
essentially, it's somewhat randomized layout of the memory on a per machine basis.
I mean, that is technically true.
It, it wouldn't work given the techniques we have today that probably wouldn't fly.
-- Yeah. No,
-- now it wouldn't work. But back in the day
it might have, it might,
I mean, one of the favorites now is you just need to get close to the memory address.
And in gen two, we're, we're talking about you'd be a couple bites different.
You're not going to be like huge amounts different when
you would recompile something necessarily because the compilers are,
are fairly reproducible in that regard.
And so one of the things you do now is you create what's called a Knop
sled
where you basically just have a bunch of no operations in memory.
And you know, you'll jump to somewhere around this space.
And as long as you manage to land anywhere in your Knop
sled,
the the execution by the CPU, then just like slides down into your actual shell code.
So you don't need to be close.
But that's
another story. So anyway,
the reason it wouldn't work today with address based randomization
is what happens now is when you have a binary
instead of having the same memory addresses everywhere.
In the application, when you run it,
every time you start a binary,
the kernel basically says here's a random base address
and then everything else is based off that.
So the way like a function call would be stored is in the past,
you would store the literal memory address, right?
So jump to this memory address exactly.
Now
what happens is it basically says jump to
the
random address plus,
you know FF and that's where this function lives.
And so that's what makes this attack
very before you can execute it. You need a way
to ascertain
the the random memory address, which is cool.
And I remember it used to be again
black magic and now there's all, there's quite a few common techniques,
but we've also have created workarounds or, or protections,
I guess is a better word,
you know, for determining what's your address and memory, right?
Because if you look at security databases, there's there's a ton of, you know,
this vulnerability results in
the uh
the the memory address being disclosed, which shouldn't matter,
but it used to matter because we didn't have all these fancy protections.
So like the minute you got that stack address or that memory address,
all of a sudden your exploit became
trivial.
Well, no,
I mean it still matters today because if you
can figure out what a memory address is somewhere
in your application,
you could then generally use that to ascertain like where to jump to, for example,
using another exploit.
But the important part here is this is kind of that whole defense in depth story.
You hear people talk about all the time is
by now instead of needing one exploit, you need two,
right? And that's what makes these technologies so powerful.
And I mean, like with stat Canaries are another example is
when you have Stat Canaries now you might need three or four things instead of one.
And that's kind of the power in all these technologies.
You always, I mean, I remember back in the day
like I'm super guilty of this where security people would be like,
oh but that doesn't stop this corner case and that's stupid.
We shouldn't do it.
But the reality is when you pile up like
three or four things that aren't perfect by themselves,
but you put them together and now you've
gone from being mostly hard to nearly impossible,
which is a huge difference.
Yeah, I mean, you look at modern, well,
like modern web browsers, you need 10 or 15 exploits to go from.
Here's a web page to I now have control of your system.
And the one thing that gets me about all this old stuff is
the
the the
the pace of change, right? I mean, back in the day, if you had a memory address,
uh disclosure bug in your code.
Yeah, you could spend months fixing it. There's no big deal. There's no rush.
And,
yeah, that's not the case anymore. You need to fix that quickly.
And I think that's part of it too is like I was just looking at some of these dates and
like the Knop sled, the first sort of detection of it came in 2002, uh,
from an attack in the wild no less.
I believe that, which is really, that's one thing I love too is when,
I mean, it's one thing for somebody to do a cool bit of research and release it,
that's relatively simple and understand, like, straightforward, but
to, to, to, to find an attack in the wild and actually, you know,
do the forensics on it and go, oh,
here's this totally new thing we've never seen before. Right.
That to me is always amazing, you know,
and so I, I still wonder, like, who invented the knob
sled,
right? Because some, some bad guy did it.
Right.
Um,
yeah, there's so much we just take for granted now, like, well,
like all the bits of memory protection.
I just,
when I think about we were literally running
around without pants on back in the nineties.
-- I mean,
-- yeah, but
this is what progress looks like. Right.
I mean, there were things that were very difficult to do.
I mean, so, like an easy example, right? I, I graduated from college in 2001.
And we had to do, we had to build a senior project. And what the group I did,
the group I was in,
we built what we called a wireless serial port
where we basically turned serial port data into infrared,
transmitted it to the receiver, received it.
You could go back and forth and like our big demo was playing Doom,
right where you had two computers playing Doom.
And everyone's like, oh, that's amazing, you know,
and
back then that was extremely difficult to do.
But now like with a raspberry pie, I could do that in two hours, you know,
like it's not impressive.
Well, I would just buy an off the shelf part,
right?
Like we, we literally, I remember we had to program an F PGA,
which an F PGA is called the field programmable Gatorade where you basically
like build,
what do
we, we had a language? Um I think it was called vhdl. If I remember correctly,
it was
basically, we had to, we had to build a program to read data from the serial part
and then send it out to an infrared sender and receiver.
And it was,
I mean, it's so wild.
Well, and here's the trick too. You had to do so
quickly and efficiently, which again,
I remember having
serial ports with no U arts to buffer the data. And so literally
like running a 9600 bod modem like 9600 characters per second,
destroyed my CPU on my machine.
And then I got, I bought uh like an add on
isa like this is going back a ways, you know, a thing with comports with U art.
So there's buffer chips
and all of a sudden my CPU usage dropped to like, you know, from 40% to like 1%. Right?
-- And
-- you just reminded me as well. We, we had to use U Arts on this.
Yes, that's right. Oh, man, I forgot all about this.
Like the idea I remember like, well, again,
like you look at interrupt driven CPU stuff now and it's like, sure,
what's the big deal?
It's running at like four gigahertz.
Yeah, interrupt driven stuff on ac pu is actually a real problem of like 100
hurts.
Right. Right.
Well, and there's multiple cores now.
So whatever one core is dealing with interrupts, who cares?
They've got 16 other cores doing nothing.
It's, it's a very different world and it's cool though. I love the progress.
I think it's very exciting.
So, anyway, anyway,
we have a topic here is what
fills me with joy
when I look at Frack and I look at smashing the stack for fun and profit
is,
I think all of these things have remained extremely relevant
because
they are a very pure place where people are allowed to
experiment and try things and share knowledge and that's hugely important.
And I know there's always people who say, oh, we used to do so much better at this and,
and
a lot of people don't care about the knowledge or whatever.
And there's, there's a million arguments, especially for us Geezers.
But I, I think the, the way I always describe this is it's just changing.
There's still knowledge transfer.
It's just the things we thought
were important aren't necessarily important anymore.
Like if you're a security person and you don't have to,
you don't know how a stack overflow attack works.
Who cares? You're probably never going to see one in your entire career now.
Well, you know, I think about my kids and,
and they'll never set up a network because you just,
like, I recently flushed all my Google Wi Fi devices, factory reset them and,
and basically network setup consisted of
plugging them in
that. No, that was it. Like there was no set up,
there was no going in and changing numbers and changing this and changing that.
It was just plug it in
and set the Wi Fi password.
That's it.
Yeah.
And that's ok.
I mean, I would compare it to automobiles when you owned a car in the 19 twenties.
You needed to know how everything worked and you probably needed to fix it every day.
-- You
-- needed expert knowledge to start it
-- correctly without breaking your arm
-- that too.
Yeah,
because you had to turn that crank and I've heard it would
kick back and break people's arms if they didn't do it.
Right. Which
I have no, I have no knowledge of and I'm glad I don't.
I know I'm absolutely the next lawn mower. I get it better be electric because I'm
-- pulling on that rip cord,
-- man.
You know,
I did some research into this and the problem I see at the moment
is it sounds like most electric lawn mowers can run for about 20 minutes
and it takes me around 30 to 40 to mow. My.
-- So,
-- no,
the deal is you need to not do your research
on lawn mowers sold at Home Depot and Lowe's,
you need to go to
Husna
or a real brand.
And like Husk
-- Carvana has lawn mowers that will run for 40 50 minutes.
-- Oh, that'd be perfect.
But they also
-- cost like three times as much.
-- But, I mean, I'm, I'm comfortable with that.
So, actually, it's really funny. It's the lawnmower I have now,
I have not changed the oil or done any maintenance on in about five years.
I've been secretly hoping it will die
and it, it just won't. So
it's like the undead lawnmower
and, and, yeah.
Yeah. So, anyway,
from a carbon footprint point of view to those lawnmowers and those two
cylinder, two cycle engines are, are basically
the only thing worse than them I think is like a container ship burning bunker oil.
Probably.
No. Absolutely. So, anyway, anyway, smashing the stack, I
it, I
read it turned 25 and it, it made me smile because
I look at all the progress we've made since
smashing the stack for fun and profit came out.
And
I know there's a lot of security people and even
I'm guilty of this sometimes where I complain about.
Oh,
nothing's really different and everything's still terrible and
we suck at security and all this.
But like,
we've made a lot of progress.
There's a lot of really cool stuff we can point to and
say this doesn't work because of this thing we did here.
And that's awesome.
Yeah.
No, I'm really grateful that these people invented these technologies and,
and gave them away for free and
not just the technology but the knowledge and
one thing that always gets me is how well written some of these frack articles are,
you know, they're
like to put it bluntly their thesis level stuff.
Oh, yes. Without question, the early frack is amazing levels of detail.
But I, I mean, here's the thing,
if, if,
iff one
didn't go into the level of detail
he went into when he wrote, smashing the stack,
no one would have understood it because it was a topic that was so, I mean,
I remember when I was young,
I read it
and then I read it again
and I'm like, I don't understand most of this stuff.
And then I started,
I started trying the examples and I would learn and I would read and I, I,
I guarantee I spent more than 100 hours of my life reading this
document and going through the examples and
trying to understand what was happening.
And it was very difficult without question.
I was watching this documentary on a Japanese Michelin star chef
and he went to one of his restaurants to make sure they were making the,
the Udon noodles correctly
and he made them make it nine times before.
He was like, OK, yeah, you guys aren't totally screwing this up,
right?
And that's the thing like, like this just that,
that this is a level of not just a level of knowledge but of sort of mastery.
I think mastery is the word, right? That's,
that's what it really is, is in order to write this,
you need to have a level of mastery over the Intel CPU at the time.
Yeah, I was just about to say his knowledge of, of hardware would have been like,
oh,
I don't know. Well, literally outside of Intel,
he would have been what, like, one of five people
there probably weren't very many for sure. I mean,
you could
maybe,
I
mean,
ii I can't think of anyone off the top of my head.
I knew that I didn't know a lot of people back then, but
it was definitely an art form that was not common.
I mean,
look back in the nineties just like being able to compile the
Apache web server was a feat of strength for most people,
you know?
Oh, I know. I remember hand patching code constantly.
Like, because stuff was you'd run make and it would,
it would fail and,
and it was normal to ship source code that was broken by default.
-- Actually,
-- you know what's really funny you say that is,
I remember back in those days I would become extremely concerned if I typed,
make and something didn't go wrong.
Like
-- what's, what,
-- what happened? Like when it returned, I was like,
like this shouldn't happen, something's wrong. What have I done?
And now like
when I, when I do I build something and go or rust or whatever,
like almost any language these days,
it never fails. It's, it's so different. But, but again, it was,
they were different times and
I know some people love to talk about how much better everything was.
It was terrible. Never believe anyone who tells you anything used to be better.
It was terrible.
But it was,
of course, because I'm old now. There's a certain nostalgia.
I feel where it's like, oh,
remember what that was like spending two whole days trying to compile a kernel.
I actually had a friend who we did the math and it was faster for him
to compile the kernel on my machine and then download it at 9600 bought to his machine
because he didn't have a numeric
Coros,
right? He had a 36 SX
25 or something.
So, actually, that 386 sx my 386 we talked about at the beginning of the show,
it was an SX 25.
After
we'll say when my parent it was my parents' computer, they got a new computer.
I took the 386 and I, of course, the first thing I did was install Linux on it
and
I had to build a new kernel to support something.
I'd forget which piece of hardware wasn't supported by default.
And it literally took two days 48 hours to build
the kernel on that computer because it was so slow.
Yeah.
No, that, that math,
I remember when my friend actually bought the math co processor and it was not cheap.
-- No,
-- all
-- of
-- a sudden,
no one even knows what that is. Kurt, you have to tell people what a math
process.
Um Well,
uh
CP us didn't
used to do math so good.
That was, that was an, that was an,
-- like, that was like an optional add on straight
-- up
just
to do
the math.
Well, to do math fast.
Yes. Yes. That's right
because so the reason being there were certain math operations that were part of
the intel spec that if you did them on say 386 without a math co
processor, they might take hundreds of clock cycles to complete.
But if you had a math co processor,
-- they might take two or three
-- clock and in fairness most people didn't need them.
No. No, totally not.
I mean, until
-- video games came along.
-- Yeah, games were the big one.
I think that that really made a difference.
And anyway, now these days all of the chips have what we would have called a math
coros, just part of the chip,
-- they
-- have just insane numbers of instructions like hyper specific, you know, Shaw
512 or
various decoding stuff or
whatever. Because you know, like honestly nowadays a couple billion transistors,
whatever, no big deal,
I mean.
Exactly.
Ok. Ok.
I'm gonna, I, I think it's time to call this one. I guess
I can only think of ending this in, in one way
and that is to say
iff one and Frack
are truly legends and I am eternally grateful for all they have given me.
I would certainly not be where I am today
without both of those resources.
Yep, I agree.
Awesome.
Well,
that was fun. Thank you everyone for listening.
Thank you, Kurt. You can go to social security podcast.com. Head to
Susie Pound Os S Podcast. Hashtag to hit us up on social media.
Kurt, you have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks
-- everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the