Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Pressers. What's new? I'm sad because I ran out of cream. So I'm drinking
coffee with milk in it.
I made the decision a long time ago to just learn how to drink black coffee
because for one thing, obviously, the number of calories in it is so close to zero,
it's
effectively zero.
I think it's actually a negative calorie drink.
Technically because the caffeine stimulates you.
-- That could be
-- actually, I've never,
I think it's kind of like celery
interesting. But regardless,
obviously there's the calorie problem,
but then there's also just the issue of if I put cream and sugar in my coffee,
I have to find cream and sugar
and that's a hassle. So I went,
-- well,
-- see I went with the whole full fat keto.
Ok.
Well, to be clear, I'm not on a keto diet,
I just like to eat keto things because full fat is delicious, right?
And so like
in fairness, my milk is 3.5% milk because that's the highest fat milk I can buy.
And then for cream. I buy the, you know, the 35%
which is again the highest fat.
And I mean, what I love is when my one son, he likes to drink it, he drinks the cream.
Yeah. So I only let him have a little bit.
Right, because it's, it's kind of rich, you know, just the look on his face of,
just because, you know, the mouth feel of cream is, I mean, it's just silky.
It's, oh, it's amazing. It's fat curt. You're drinking,
it's like drinking clarified butter,
-- which I may or may not have done.
-- I don't think I've ever done that.
No,
-- you
-- should
-- try just go get some ghee from the store and
just warm it up a bit and don't eat dinner anyway.
Oh,
yeah. And coffee is technically zero calories.
So, yeah, it's a negative energy drink and that just swallowing it.
-- You're going to burn calories.
-- It can't technically be zero calories.
-- There's stuff in it.
-- Not that your body can process for energy.
-- So
-- that could be right.
Like you could eat a piece of wood and
you can't, you know, process.
Ok. That's fair, I suppose. Eating, yeah, eating a piece of wood
has no nutritional value to me in any way. Styrofoam.
It probably has bad nutritional value.
So, yeah, I mean,
there's lots of things you can eat that you're not
going to digest like a penny and to be clear,
-- we're not telling people to eat pennies or styrofoam or wood
-- if you do let us know.
-- Yeah, take video, put it on youtube.
-- That's right. Anyway,
so, yeah, so that's, that's my sadness but overall, you know, it's, I'm kind of glad.
So, Krebs on security who, I don't always agree with him,
but I would say one thing in general he does that very few other security people do,
which is,
he actually gives useful and actionable advice that normal people can use.
-- You know,
-- what my suspicion is on that.
-- Actually,
-- maybe he's a normal person and not actually a security person.
-- He kind
-- of is right because he actually,
I mean,
the beginnings of his career was in journalism and
then he ended up kind of sucked into security.
He's got a really interesting story.
I'd encourage anyone to go read it because it's fascinating
what all happened to him and like the guy,
I think he learned Russian as part of his research because obviously
he was Impersonating bad guys on these forums and it's wild,
but I do agree.
I feel like he doesn't just write stories.
-- He also includes, maybe you should think about doing this
-- because
there was a recent article on the CBC
website talking about these sort of fake Kickstarter and
gofundme campaigns for various tragic events and that you
should do your research and check them out.
Cool.
And I'm scrolling through the article and I'm like, how,
and they talked a little bit about how go fund me or whatever.
And Kickstarter have slightly better fraud teams now
that loot these guys out if you complain,
but how do I find out if they're real or not?
So, I emailed the lady, you know, kind of very respectfully,
kind of quoting her article and I'm like, cool, I agree with this.
-- How do I do this and never heard back from her? No,
-- you,
-- they don't, they don't
-- know.
And I mean, somebody claims I'm raising money for this tragic event.
But, ok, like, and you're not
a, ok, like, step one. Are you a registered charity? Well, obviously not.
If they were a registered charity,
they probably wouldn't be on gofundme right away.
You know.
So, ok, you're not a registered charity. There's no, like, sort of legal framework.
Ok. Now, what? Right do I do?
I call Go Fund Me and be like, I want all the details on this campaign. Well,
-- no, they're not going to tell me. They
-- probably don't even know.
-- Yeah.
-- I mean, well, all they would know is whatever
typed in which maybe it's true. Maybe it's not true.
You know, like I'm going to raise money to go send it to this person.
Do I contact that person and say, do you know about this?
I guess if they didn't know about it, that might be a red flag,
but fundamentally to validate any of this stuff, you know,
you're going to need like P I or information that you're kind of not supposed to have.
I would agree with that.
The point being is that the majority of
the articles about the stuff where they're like,
oh, you should look both ways from crossing the street.
It's simple. It's clear we teach it to four year olds. Right.
You know, versus like, oh,
-- you should be safe when crossing the street.
-- Yes, I do like that comparison.
And my, my go to always, especially from the security perspective is people say,
check your links before you clip them.
What does, what does that mean?
Well, especially when they go through a link shorter.
I'm like, oh, it points to t.co something.
-- Even
-- if it doesn't curt you can, how many times do you hover over a link?
And it says I'm going to go to blah blah.com,
you click it and then you actually go to like Google's ridiculous
tracking service and then sends you to blah blah.com.
And like, what, where did that come from?
When you log into the provincial health link service?
Here you go to the, you know, main government website, Alberta dot C A.
So that's, that's pretty clearly Alberta's government
and you click to go to health link and it bumps you through,
it's like a SDFJQ dot C A or something.
It bounces you through there and then off to the health link site.
What does that even mean?
It's like some interstitial site that handles the login
right. So basically it goes from like Alberta dot C A good legitimate, easy Domain
and you eventually you end up at Alberta Health
Services dot C which again,
but it bounces through this provider that does the authentication using some Won
Domain. And I literally tried to track it down. It's all private and everything.
And I'm like, did I just get hacked or is this like, set up?
Weird, I tweeted them and they're like, yeah, no, that's, that's correct.
Like, that's how the login system works. It goes through this weird domain.
I mean, you know, cloud security line says that we have a
zero dot Cloud security lines.org, which,
you know, we had to pay extra to get that custom domain so that, you know,
when you're logging in through off
zero to our stuff, we didn't want it to look weird.
So we paid extra for that and I get that. Well, I guess not all sites do that.
Well, just going back to your, make sure the link looks safe.
Well, I can't because like I googled this and there's
like, it's, it's a ghost.
Let's just face it when a security person says don't click on shady links.
That's basically just saying,
I have no idea what to
tell you.
-- Good luck
-- or the ever infamous, you know, only open email from people you trust.
My job is reading email from random people on the
-- internet
-- and also people get hacked and then you know,
their account sends out like, hey, I'm stuck in Romania.
-- I need a $200 Western Union transfer.
-- Yeah, that's true.
That does happen, you know,
that hasn't happened to me in a long time now that you
-- say
-- that it happened just recently to a relative of mine,
you know, he got an email from like, his son or whatever saying, blah, blah, blah.
And he's kind of like, nope.
Right. Right.
And I mean, I do remember a couple of years back, this was a huge problem with,
with my family because one of them got popped
and they were sending executables out
and you could see who was all getting popped
because I kept getting emails like every other day
from a different person who clearly opened the executable
and then was sending it out and I'm like,
oh my goodness.
And that was an unpleasant,
probably two months of my life because I had to fix a lot of computers.
So basically your family had email syphilis.
-- I mean, you know,
-- like that's what it sounds
like. That's a marvelous description.
-- I will never tell them. But yes.
-- Yeah. Yeah.
This is why I forced my parents on to Max and Chrome and Gmail.
That was my biggest piece of advice was quit running windows again though.
I mean, how do we get
people actionable advice?
And so what actually before we go on more, why don't you explain this Krebs story?
-- Because it's, it's quite good and impressive and frightening.
-- Yeah.
So,
so the premise is Attacker calls you and
give the title because the title's marvelous.
So, the title is, oh, I thought I said it already. Sorry.
The title is, I've forgotten it already if you did.
And it's the advice itself when in doubt, hang up, look up and call back.
I like it because it's short. It fits into a sentence. It makes sense. It's
consistent. It, you know what I mean? Like
you say it and you don't really need to explain it in depth.
It just is that it's like a gin and tonic. What's in a gin and tonic?
Well, gin and tonic,
maybe an ice
and lime, you need lime. It's no good without lime,
depending on the tonic you use, right?
You got, have you been buying,
they have craft tonics now that are amazing anyways segue
back to this.
So, basically,
and I've actually had this happen where my bank called me and they're like,
can we speak to Mr Kurtz?
And I'm like, uh huh.
And I, you know,
I try to make my language as non committal as
possible because Attackers also do stuff where they like,
try and record your voice saying yes or hello or whatever to play back to, you know,
voice authentication systems.
Interesting.
Well, my one bank does voice authentication over the phone and they're like,
do you want to sign up for that?
And I'm like, no,
I, there's like hundreds of hours of
high quality recordings of me online.
So, anyways, like, one time my bank did call me and I'm like, cool,
how do I verify you from my bank?
And they're like, because you could be anybody. Right.
And they're like, well, I'll check the caller id and I'm like,
-- really
-- that fixes everything.
-- Right.
-- Like, I too have run a PBX. You don't even
need a PBX.
You could, there's like websites,
-- you could use services that spoof caller id
-- anyways.
And so, you know, the whole thing anyways back to this,
what Attackers are doing now is because
banks are doing like two factors authentication.
Like for example, we will email you or text you a,
like a six digit pin code that you then read to us on the phone so that we know you're,
you sure.
Well, the problem is Attackers can intercept that relatively easily.
It's a bit of work, but basically an attacker calls you says Josh, oh my God,
your bank account's been broken into and we want to get this sorted out and
I'm your bank and I'm not even going to ask you for personal information.
So in order to sort this out,
we're going to have send you a six digit pin that
I'm going to need you to read back to me.
So that I know you're you and not some person pretending to be Josh and you go, oh, Ok.
Right. It's, you said you've said you're my bank.
The caller id is correct and you're not asking for personal information. Right.
Except they're asking for the pin number.
But regardless,
and then a second person with the attacker phones your bank and says, hi, I'm Josh.
I think my account's been hacked. I need to validate with you.
So, can you send me the pin to my phone? Right. Right.
So the bank of course, goes, certainly Mr Bresser sends the real Mr Bresser,
the pin on the phone.
You real Mr Bresser reads the pin off to the attacker,
the attacker, you know, turns to his friend next to him and says, you know, Josh,
just read the pin number.
It's 123457 and that person then repeats that number to the bank. Pretty
clever.
You think you're talking to your bank?
So you're not super worried because you've
checked your balance online and it's like,
all screwed up, you know, like somebody just withdrew 5000 bucks.
But, you know, you just spoke with the bank.
Well, like every time I get a refund from these companies, right.
Like when I pay them it's like, bam,
it's instantly out of my account from my credit card.
Yeah. Right. But, oh, a refund.
-- Yeah, those take like, 3 to 5 business days to protest.
-- You're lucky.
-- This is an interesting attack.
-- Well, they're adapting to what has changed.
Right.
And I have two thoughts on this. So on one hand, this is highly targeted
and
-- stopping motivated, targeted Attackers is,
-- well,
it doesn't have to be that targeted.
All I need is a list of phone numbers and names.
I mean, yes and a call center on CBC Market Watch.
They've been working with Indian police recently to
break up these call centers that target Canadians
and they're, they show them raiding these buildings and there are multiple stories
there.
Like they showed a truck full of P CS being guarded by the Indian army.
Like they literally had like a giant, you know,
2.5 ton truck jammed full of pcs that
they'd confiscated from one of these call centers.
There's a podcast.
It's, I think a two or three parter I will try to find and send a link to it.
I don't even remember who did it anymore, but basically,
there was a reporter got called by one of these scammers
and he ended up going to India to meet them. Like it's ridiculous.
But at the same time, yeah, this is like Crime Inc, I mean,
that's going on right here is what's happening.
So,
Cripps case, the guy almost got robbed of about over $10,000.
And so I'm thinking if I have a list of phone numbers and names of,
say Bank of America or whatever customers to pick on them because it's just a
Bank of America that I know the name of because it's Bank of America,
I guess also City Corp would be fair game.
But anyway, so given a list of customers and their phone numbers,
you just start working it.
Now, I'm guessing that the success rate for, like,
talking to a human and convincing them, even if it's only like, one or 2%
if you can rip
offer 10 grand, that's an average of 100 bucks for making a couple of phone calls.
Right? It's, it's the same deal as
the like Nigerian print scams that we're all familiar with
where they'll send out millions of emails and they might get 1000 replies
and they might only get two people that they can actually scam.
But hey, two people is two people and for these people running the scam,
it was totally worth it.
Well, and that's why I'm so hopeful of, I don't think this Shaken
Stir protocol stuff will help much,
but it should hopefully take out the bottom player.
So what shaken and stir are,
is an attempt essentially to prevent caller ID spoofing
on public telephone networks to put it bluntly.
So the idea basically being right now is you have
a void provider that's hooked into the phone system,
you know, the SS seven control layer
and they can basically do whatever they want. And again, back to the Voyager.
So this used to work because buying an SS seven capable
switch was like somewhere on the cost order of you know,
a building
and there wasn't VoIP.
So you had to like, literally plug into the network with a hugely expensive machine.
And so there's no authentication really or anything.
So, you know, now getting SS seven or SS nine capable equipment is, well,
there's free software that does it like asterisk, right?
Like, literally, I don't know if asterisk actually does the signaling.
But anyways, the point is, it's not hard.
I don't even think the telephone company does like old school signaling anymore.
I think it's all
-- IP basically on the back end
-- locally.
Tell us, went to an all IP back end, like, almost two decades ago.
And why wouldn't you? Right.
-- Because
-- they were basically like, oh,
-- we just run a network through this
-- one wire that has six connections inside of it.
Oh, no, no, this was on their backbone.
On the front end, there's still like twisted pairs and pots and everything.
But the back end is all just one because what
happened is a lot of telephone companies ended up running
the circuit based network and an IP network.
Right. Right. Which is, I mean,
like, I'm not running two networks on my, like, when I moved in here,
the first thing I did was I physically ripped out every
single bit of cabling that wasn't electrical or the one Ethernet line
or my thermostat. I left that line.
Yeah, that's fair.
You know, I hear you though.
So, back to this I mean, these scams, exploit flaws in the security system,
but also they exploit flaws in the advice because the advice is don't give up your P I,
your bank will never ask for P I.
-- And so the Attackers are like
-- whatever
always asks for my P I.
The problem though is by asking you for the pin number,
you've been trained that that's ok to be asked for by your bank.
Like you have to be asked for your bank to verify who you are. At some point.
There has to be some exchange of, you know,
information or bodily fluids for you to prove that you're Josh price
to your bank.
Now, ironically,
there's never a flow the other way which drives me
nuts because most of these entities I deal with,
I set a pin number with them that I then use to validate to them that I am Kurtz
Fried. You know, my pin number is 1234. Why can't I also set a pin number on my file?
So the bank's pin number is, you know, four and 321.
-- And they have to tell me that
-- I could think of a couple of problems with that.
Well, it's again, it's not perfect but you know what, it's better than nothing,
which is what we have today.
It's not that we don't have nothing today. We have insurance today.
And so this basically costs the bank nothing.
It's my problem and it's the bank's insurance company's problem if it happens.
I mean, functionally the bank has just moved all of the risk away from them.
And that's, I mean, that's functionally how most of these systems are set up.
Well, yeah, you externalize risk if you can.
The company, the risk is my problem. It's their insurance company's problem.
And this is why they never set a pin because let's say,
let's say I set a pin for the bank.
Am I going to remember that pin? There's a 0% chance. I'm going to remember that pin.
-- All this crap's
-- in my password manager.
Like, well, ok, you can actually, I should do that.
So like my favorite example, I have a safe deposit box at the bank.
I go in, they say, oh, you need to type in your safe deposit box pin on this keypad.
And I say, I don't remember it.
And they say, well, we'll just change it for you.
Then here, wait a second and then they change it
and then I type in the number I just gave them and then I forget it again.
-- But
-- they validate your ID or something.
-- Well, yeah,
-- I've
-- got
-- to, I bring in ids and well,
and they know who I am because I go in and do this on a regular basis. But
regardless the point is if I gave the bank a pin,
there's a 0% chance I'm going to remember it and I
actually didn't think of putting that in my last pass even.
-- That's what the notes field is for.
-- I'm going to do that now.
Well, next time I go in because I don't remember what the pin is anymore.
But next time I go in, I'm going to do that. But I mean, you get the idea right.
-- Is every time I go in it costs the bank money
-- I personally would
prefer not to have a PIN number and have them actually check my ID.
-- But yeah, that costs the bank money. They don't want to do that.
-- They
-- do
-- both
and whatever they check my ID, they ask for my pin
and then I don't know my pin. So they change my pin and then I type in.
It's like it's completely ridiculous.
But yeah, it is what it is.
Well, I mean,
in theory for people who check their safety deposit box a lot and remember their pin,
-- it would be not a
-- safety deposit box.
-- It's a safe deposit box.
-- Right. You're correct.
I am technically correct. Yes.
Did we
talk about that on the show?
How some bank did the wrong safety deposit boxes
got rid of them and basically said tough.
And then
apparently that's what the law is. What do you mean
there was a documented case where a guy basically went to a safety deposit
box and the bank had drilled it out and gotten rid of the contents.
I'm sure it can happen. Yeah, here we go. We'll put this in the show notes.
This is from July of last year. But basically when Philip
pots opened box 105 at his local Wells Fargo and
the paywall just popped up and I can't read it.
Oh, good job. New York Times. Ok.
Well, anyways, the point being the bank drilled,
the wrong boxes got rid of the contents and that's too bad.
Like safety deposit boxes. Well, they're not safety deposit boxes, right?
They're safe deposit boxes,
but the bank actually doesn't,
apparently in most of the US have any actual sort of liability
or actual requirement to make sure that your stuff is safe,
like if they accidentally sell it off or get rid of it at auction, but that's ok.
So this guy is currently trying to sue his bank and I don't
remember how it turned out or if it has turned out yet,
I would hope that the bank is going to be on
the hook for whatever was taken from that box because look,
it's humans are involved and they make mistakes.
Well, part of the problem is what was taken from the box.
-- I mean, that's a reasonable problem because yes, my bank
-- doesn't. Right.
-- Like, dude, I had the Mona Lisa in there.
-- Right. Sure.
You actually, I have, I know someone who keeps precious metals in their box and it's,
I don't know what it's worth because obviously they won't tell me.
-- But I know they have a nontrivial amount of precious metals.
-- Here we go.
There's, there's no federal law that says the bank actually has to, like,
keep this stuff safe.
-- That's
-- interesting.
Well,
it makes sense in a way because I think it's probably one of those things where
nobody ever thought to make a law because
it was just so strongly implicitly implied.
-- It's a safe deposit box. Like it's in a vault in a bank.
-- I would argue
that this is not a common problem because part of the reason
people use these boxes is because they have a reputation for being
very secure.
Well, generally speaking, yeah,
I would assume when they get rid of a safe deposit box, like when they,
the owner dies and stops paying or whatever and you know,
and they drill the lock and get rid of the contents, but they like triple, triple,
triple check all that paperwork.
-- I
-- mean, one would hope so.
But people are people, man, right?
-- They make mistakes,
-- drill box 137 the accidentally drill box 136 nobody notices.
And now whoops. What did I just do? Wow, that's wild though.
-- Or
-- in this case in California,
a Wells Fargo customer said the bank accidentally re rented her boss.
No. You know what?
Actually, I don't, I don't buy that story because so here's the deal,
let's say the bank drills out my box they get rid of it.
No, no, because they would have the key.
But like, fundamentally, I have a key, they have a key.
They cannot get into my box without my key.
So the only way in is to drill it, but then once they drill it, obviously,
-- my key has no value, then, well,
-- the lock's dead.
It doesn't matter. That's why they charge you.
Like, that's why in fairness, a lot of banks charge you, you know,
an upfront fee to rent a safety Paul Paul's
-- box because basically they're the cost of that
-- lock.
It's really cheap. It's like 70 bucks.
-- I had to pay for it once because I accidentally
-- lost the key.
I mean, yeah, if you lose your key, I think they ding you for 50 or 100 bucks here.
It was 75 bucks. Which was, I'm like, that's really cheap actually.
That's actually cheaper than getting a locksmith because it
was funny because what happened was I emptied the box
and then I was like, oh, I've got to go get the other key. I'll come back later.
No idea where the keys went.
He disappeared
and I called the bank. I'm like, I lost the keys.
I'm really sorry, like everything's out of the box, but
I can't give you keys. Like, yeah, we'll just charge you 75 bucks. You'll be fine.
-- And I'm like, wow, that's
-- cool.
And it sounds like the bank actually has a process for dealing with
this case where they accidentally got rid of this person's safety deposit box.
Because, like, I,
I got a call from my bank branch one time.
They have different sizes of safety deposit boxes. Right.
And most of them are that sort of small, you know, it's like,
what about two or three inches high and about maybe seven inches wide.
And so I have one of the bigger ones where you can actually put legal
documents in it without having to fold them or mangle them or jam them in.
And, you know, and I'm, I'm not giving that up
and I've literally had them phone me once or twice saying, you know,
you don't access your safety deposit box a lot.
No, like I access it like once every five years, you know, it just holds paperwork.
Would you consider giving it up and renting a smaller one? And I'm like, nope,
I'm in the same boat actually. So when I, when I moved,
I had to get a little one and I said, I want you to put me on a list for the big one.
Like what size I'm like, I don't care bigger than this.
Like I would literally,
and I just kind of slowly worked my way up till I had the box I wanted.
And,
and even now if they called me and said we
have the bathtub size box on the bottom row open,
I would be like, yes sign me up.
I will take that in a second. I don't need it, but I don't care like I could like put
something in it. I don't care. I love having the space.
Yeah, I'm super greedy like that.
But anyway, anyway, we are rat holed again talking about safe deposit,
-- I think
-- fundamentally. So, I mean, it kind of boils down the same thing of
a safe deposit box is, is again, you know,
I have a bunch of paperwork that I would be such a pain in the
butt to replace if I lost it or it got damaged or you know,
destroyed.
So I keep it in a safe deposit box, right? That's supposed to
see how you do that
and it turns,
you know, that's like 99 point a bunch of nine safe but not 100%.
So the answer is ok,
there can be problems with safe deposit boxes where like they re rent it
because they think I stopped paying or they drill the wrong one or?
Oh, I don't know the bank falls into a sinkhole point.
Is am I going to stop using my safe deposit box to store these documents? Good Lord.
No, of course, I'm going to keep using it because this is as good as it gets.
We're talking about actionable advice and
we'll say
unique situations where an attacker is specifically targeting you.
Even if you're part of a big list,
you have a human actually interacting with you and they're determined to acquire
your money.
In this case,
I still bucket these things into two groups where
there's the kind of drive by accidental attack.
So I just mailed emailed a million people and then there's the,
I'm going after Kurt and be it a safe deposit box,
be it someone trying to hack into your bank?
There's a lot going on and think even with Krebs advice,
which I think is fantastic advice.
You should never interact with your bank when they call you.
Best case go into a branch. I mean, functionally if an attacker wants to get you
and they're calling you on the phone, if they want to,
they're going to beat you because they have more motivation than you
do because you don't even know what's going on in many cases.
I mean, I guess the good news here is that these are not super targeted attacks.
These are, you know,
here's a list of people and phone numbers keep calling until you get.
That's a sucker, right?
Because it's, I mean, my,
my favorite example of this is the big 2009 bank of
Ireland robbery where basically a bunch of guys with weapons,
took the bank manager and his family hostage
and basically told him you have a choice, right?
You can take us to the bank and open it up and we'll
take all the money or we can do terrible things to your family.
So he of course,
-- went to the bank and opened it up and
-- I'm sure the
bank would even tell any manager if this happens to you.
Give them all of the money.
Well,
you kind of have to do that because otherwise your
employees are not going to think highly of you.
Well, insurance, you have insurance for crap like this.
I mean, that's the reality of it and this is even true of humans in their daily lives.
I have insurance for my car. I have insurance for my house.
I have insurance for my life.
Unfortunately, I don't know of insurance for things like fraud for normal people.
Sometimes homeowners or contents insurance covers that.
I wonder actually because in fact,
I know my homeowners actually now that you say
that my homeowners covers my safe deposit box contents.
Now that you say that I remember that because
that came up because my insurance man said,
you know, do you have a safe deposit box?
I was like, yeah, I do.
He's like, ok, fine, you know how much coverage you need on that?
I'm like like, I don't know, 50 bucks
like
nothing in there is technically valuable from a monetary perspective.
But yeah, yeah, I mean that's fair, but maybe that's the key, right?
-- Is maybe things like homeowners and renters insurance need to start covering
-- well,
the problem then is you enter a situation where
people are less wary about fraud because hey,
I don't need to worry about being ripped off because
-- covers it. Yeah,
-- but if you keep getting ripped off, then your premium goes up.
It's the same thing like I could say,
I don't care if my house burns down insurance will pay for it, but if it does,
holy crap, my insurance is going to get expensive.
Yeah.
So the problem with that is that like look at car insurance,
there's people out there,
like my favorite was Canada's worst driver because it's real and to be on the show
you need to have a valid driver's license and you have to have valid car insurance.
And some of these people were like, oh, you know, I've had 30 or 40 whoopsies and,
you know, Andrew Youngblood is like, excuse me, what now?
You know, she's like, yeah, I've 30 or 40 accidents in the last five years. Right. Or,
you know,
just these people where their car insurance is like one or $2000 a month on a
car that costs like 4000 bucks because they just keep getting in so many accidents.
And I think part of the problem is that some of them are from jurisdictions where,
you know,
the insurance is government provided so they can't
be priced out of the market really,
or, you know, refuse service.
But basically the problem is, you know,
you will have this small minority of people who honestly they should never be
allowed to drive and they should be forced to take public transit because they have
so many accidents or collisions. Rather these aren't accidents.
This isn't like their carfield. They're like, like the one lady drove into a store.
He's like, what?
And she's like, oh, I got confused, you know,
or my favorite was the little old lady who's like, well,
I only drunk drive on the way home from Bingo
and it's not a very long drive and he's like,
you know, or the best is they go to this testing, they go to this place to do it.
It's like usually an abandoned aircraft base or something, you know,
with lots of room to drive around and not hit stuff
and they make them have like a dash cam in their
car while they're driving from like Toronto to this place.
It's like 100 miles and then they have a former police officer review
the footage and kind of clock how many moving violations they made,
you know, and, and I'm not talking like little things like lane changes.
I'm talking like, driving on the wrong side of the road, blowing red lights,
you know, things like that.
And like some of these people make over 100 you know, the guys, like,
basically based on this footage, I would revoke your license.
I don't, what I'm saying is,
I don't think insurance will work because there's
a subset of people who will be like,
cool.
I don't have to worry about getting ripped off
now and they will cost us a disproportionate amount
of money because they keep getting ripped off and
I don't want to blame the victim again.
But
at some point,
people who leave their car running in winter with the keys in the car unlocked,
it's like, again,
people shouldn't steal cars but you also maybe shouldn't leave
your car running with the keys in it unlocked.
Yeah. But at the same time, if I do that enough,
-- I'm just not going to get insurance
-- again in some,
in some jurisdictions you can't get priced out of
the market because of the way it's set up.
-- I feel like that's a failure of Canada.
-- Well, that's not a Canadian thing.
It's done provincially. So, like BC next door to me is government provided in
based on how long you've been driving and here's the best part they didn't
charge you for your insurance based on how much your car was worth.
So, these people with super cars got in accidents and like,
kind of came close to not bankrupting the insurance system, but like,
they cost it a lot of money.
That's idiotic. I mean, I'm sorry? Like, that's, that's just stupid.
Have you met the government?
-- Well, yeah,
-- and that's their problem then for being dumb.
I mean, this is like, anybody, if I do something that costs more money than I have,
I don't have any more money then.
Like,
well,
but what I'm getting to is the problem is like
you can do this with the best of intentions.
Like in Alberta,
they put caps on insurance rates for soft tissue
damage and a bunch of other stuff trying to,
you know, prevent insurance rates from going up.
And of course, lawyers found ways around that and now, you know,
insurance rates went up in some cases, 2030 40%.
-- All right.
-- Why are we arguing about insurance? Let's ignore the insurance problem.
Insurance isn't the answer here.
-- I don't
-- think maybe it's not and I'm not saying it is,
I think it might actually make it worse.
I don't know. Maybe it maybe,
I mean, but here's the problem. So what's the answer?
There's literally nothing we can do. We cannot stop these attacks full stop.
There's no way to stop them. So what does that mean?
For example, we train people when in doubt, hang up, look up, call back.
So for example, why can't my bank call me and be like Mr Siefried?
We think there's a problem with your account.
Please call us back with the number on the back of your card. Thank you. Bye. Click.
-- Well, sure they can do that but the Attackers
-- won't.
-- No, but we can train people to do that.
-- Just no, we can't, we cannot train people
saying we can train people is una actionable advice.
The reality is people are dumb and they make
stupid choices and that's never going to change.
As long as we have people someday,
the machines might take over and solve that problem for us.
But until that day, we have to accept the fact that if you cannot solve something,
using some sort of technical or policy control, there's nothing you can do.
I would say the problem with that though is that
we're currently training people to do the insecure thing.
We're currently training,
-- run across the road without looking. Are we
-- training them?
We're not doing anything in most cases.
Well,
my bank has literally called me up and started asking me
for P I to prove who I am to them.
Sure. And it's not their problem.
They are training their customers to get ripped off.
-- And
-- I'm telling you that if the bank cares,
training you to not do that isn't the solution,
the correct solution is to somehow implement a
technical control that will do it for them,
right?
But my concern is my bank is actively teaching people, hey,
when you pick up the phone, so
start asking you for P
I it's ok to answer them and give it to
-- them
-- and they don't care because it's not their problem,
right?
-- But that's not great for the rest of us.
-- Well, it sucks for you.
I mean, like for real, that's the thing. We can't fix people.
I mean, that's just the way it is no amount of training,
-- but we
-- can stop making it worse is what I'm trying to say.
Maybe. I mean, ok, but why does your bank care? Right. They need an incentive.
What's their incentive?
They have no incentive,
you know, ideally to do the right thing or to, you know,
what, what bank has ever said? Oh, let's do the right thing. Like, screw that.
We're going to make money.
Number one, make money. Number two, make money. Number 30, make money.
Yeah. No, I get it.
Like every, every vendor that asks me, you know, oh, you're using your credit card.
We want to see ID. And I'm like, no, they're like, what?
And I'm like,
you can make a code 10 called to Visa to validate my identification or my,
my account rather.
And they're like, yeah, but that takes time and I'm like, well then too bad.
And I've literally walked out of a store that wanted my driver's license.
They wanted to photocopy my drive.
-- I would not let someone do that better
-- yet. You know what?
I was buying a computer mouse now, granted, it was a mighty mouse and they're like,
you know, they're not cheap.
They're like 70 bucks us or whatever they are. But I'm like, you want to photocopy my
driver's license so I can pay for a computer mouse with a credit card.
And they're like, yeah, and I'm like, I hate them all. I'm going to the Apple store.
Goodbye. But like, clearly they're, they're still in business.
So they that policy, you know, now I would call the privacy commissioner and be like,
hey, a lot of people don't know or care and again,
what's the negative consequence for most people in that situation,
-- their identity
-- gets stolen?
But does it,
how do I know that that person working the front desk isn't just running some scam,
photocopying people's driver's licenses?
-- I
-- mean, you don't know, how do you know,
I'm not in some long con to steal your ID by hosting a podcast with you, right?
Like you don't know. And in most cases, people just don't care.
That's the reality of it.
I mean,
ok, so we're out of time.
I
-- love the twisty universe. We've weaved
-- here, Krebs on security.
He is trying to make the world less worse
in ways that are simple and reasonably effective.
I will agree with that. Let's be blunt.
If 100% of people did the, when in doubt, hang up, look up and call back,
then Attackers would not be able to randomly cold, call people and rip them off.
-- But 100 percent of people aren't going to
-- do it.
And you know what 100% of people aren't going to look both ways in across the street.
No, absolutely not.
And I also think that's a dangerous goal because it's unrealistic here is the way
I always look at this and this is even true of this podcast we have.
If I can take actions that help even one person
and I make their life better in some way.
That is a success. And that's really the measure.
-- It
-- has to be cost effective though we can't spend $10
-- million preventing one burglary
-- cost effectiveness kicks in at scale.
But I mean, fundamentally like this is my advice,
this is my actionable advice to the people listening to us right now is
if you can give out advice to one person that makes their life better,
that's ok.
That's good enough.
Whereas saying I have to give out advice that will affect everybody
that will never happen. Don't try to do that.
Oh, yeah. No, I would agree with that.
And at the same time though, that advice has to be, you know, helpful, useful,
-- real,
-- I will agree with that saying, don't click links is not actionable.
Well, it is actionable advice. It's just not useful, actionable advice.
Well, I mean, before the show, we're talking about this and there's every,
every link I hover in Twitter goes to t.co slash something like
whatever. I don't, I don't even look half the time. I'm like whatever.
I trust my browser, I run Linux. No one hacks Linux
that pretty much, yeah. For now, I can't wait to be targeted.
-- Hey,
-- it's the year of the Linux desktop.
-- You're saying
-- it's always the year of the Linux
desktop. It will always be the year of the Linux desktop. That is my prediction.
All right,
I'm calling it. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening. You can go to open
source security podcast.com. Hit up the show note, Juicy Pound
Oss
podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media. Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too, everybody. Thanks. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.