Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast
episode 153 with myself Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Pressers.
-- What's
-- New Kurt Road
construction season?
-- Summer slash road construction?
-- Right?
Yeah.
My host was vibrating yesterday because they're,
they're working on the road behind my house.
My house backs onto a major road. There's a, thank God there's a sound barrier. Yeah.
So there's going to be road construction until October 31st.
Oh, that's very exciting. How much fun is that?
Yeah. And that's the,
that's their hopeful date. That's not the real date.
-- Is,
-- is that, I mean, you're in Canada?
Is that normal to go over the date horribly or do they generally?
Yeah, they go over the date horribly.
Uh, hang on a sec. Uh I, I forget how long it took us to fix or to finish the Anthony Hende
uh Ring road, but they finished the Anthony Hende Ring road
and then they had to start building all the overpasses because to save money,
they built the ring road first with most of the overpasses,
but not all of the overpasses.
So you literally were on a ring road and you would come to a red light.
Sweet.
Guess what happens when you build overpasses on a heavily used ring road.
Nothing, nothing bad, I'm sure.
Yeah. So it's, but at the same time, right, like infrastructure has to be fixed.
It's technical, it's literally technical debt.
So apparently what's happened is all the sewers out here in the west end, uh,
were supposed to last 100 years
and a lot of them are only lasting about 40.
Whoa. That's a big difference.
-- Yeah. And fixing sewers is not cheap. That
-- sounds like every it project ever.
Yeah, we'll be
good for 56 years.
-- Three months later.
-- I
think that's why contracting and consulting is so, um, enviable
because you get to leave.
Uh,
you do get to leave and then come back a few
months later to fix all the things you broke maybe.
Yeah. But, uh, anyways, so this episode,
yeah, I just so much, like, again, it's funny because the world is
on fire as usual and there's even no
on fire.
Well, but there's even more amusing piles of fire now. Like people are really true.
-- That's true.
-- Like this Facebook A I image thing.
All right. Why don't you explain it?
-- Just so those in the audience who may not be aware of this.
-- So
you can upload pictures to Facebook
and
you can share them, you can make them public, you can make them private,
whatever people seem to,
I think misunderstand this because what happened
apparently is there was some weird Facebook,
they say it's like a server configuration glitch and I'm like that whatever.
Basically, it wasn't serving the images,
but you could still see the alt text for those of you that don't know what Alex
is.
The people who did the original like
hypertext transfer protocol standards weren't completely stupid.
And so when you display an image,
they were like, hey,
what if the image doesn't load or
what if the user is blind
or can't see it
like text, web browsers, man.
-- Yeah,
-- or yeah, you're running E
links or links. I mean, because
Elin Man, that, that was actually fancier and came after links,
but you're running links or something
and you had what's like literally
alt text equals and then you could have like
a description like closed captioning of the image,
you know, like this is a picture of a sunset with a dog chasing a stick
or whatever.
And so of course, when people upload images to Facebook,
they're not putting in all text.
And sadly, most websites don't even do that anymore very well,
but Facebook does it for you.
Now, how do we generate alt text for?
You know, I'm, I'm gonna guess on the order of a couple million images an hour,
-- minute, probably an hour, maybe a minute,
-- uh probably not,
maybe less than an hour or more than an hour, but it's definitely not going to be by.
Yeah, it could be by the minute. It's a lot though. Right.
Well, it's gonna be more than even a couple 100,000 humans
classify and deal with.
I would. Right.
There are more images coming in faster than an army
of infinite monkeys could definitely do anything with that.
-- So how would you create all text for these images?
-- I would build an A I
that could analyze the images, uh extract user data,
triangulate that sell it to advertisers and then also add all text.
That's basically what I would do.
And that's basically what
Facebook did
because what else are they gonna do? Like literally
and people are freaking out about this?
And what's interesting
to me was the specific phrase from the article was
this is how Facebook's A I is judging you.
And what's interesting is at first I was a
little bit offended by that because I'm like,
well, only humans can judge but then I know whatever.
Anyway, semantically aside,
this is a very human perspective on
something a non a fundamentally nonhuman system is doing.
But at the same time that fundamentally nonhuman
system that a IML whatever system doing this
is programmed by people is built by people, right?
-- It didn't spring into being magically sort
-- of.
But also I would like to add if you build an A I uh make sure
it knows how to judge people because I think that would be a really cool feature.
Just I'll throw that out there.
That, that's a real thing. Remember? Because they found errors in the
thing. I thought we talked about it. Once
-- we talk about a lot of things,
-- there's,
-- there's the parole board ones and there's
-- anyways.
Oh, that's true. That's true. That's, that's fair.
So, we have built a, is to judge people. Yes, we have.
Absolutely. So, anyway, but, so here's the thing I keep thinking of is Alex
Stamos had a tweet where he's like, you know, this is great for people who have,
you know, need screen readers for example.
And
I don't disagree with him.
But the thing that I think that that is interesting
about this is I feel like normal people are starting
figure out everything Facebook can do
because I don't think they have a freaking clue
and it's starting to scare them to death.
And I would say more in general what technology can do.
A
perfect example of this is
50 years ago. We had phone networks and fax.
-- Do we have fax 50 years ago? Yeah, we did.
-- Uh sure it would have been very new, but
I
pretty
sure but we did not have the computer
processing power or storage
to log and record all of it.
Right. Well,
yeah, that, that happened a decade or two. Something changed. Yeah.
And, and I think, you know, my, because we've already been through this once.
Remember Google, I'm familiar with them and Google Mail.
And remember when Google Mail started inserting ads and people are like, oh my God,
they're reading your, the email.
And it's,
and see this is the problem is this is a very
subtle thing.
And from the outside we actually don't know exactly what's going on,
but we can make a reasonably educated guess that no
Google in the sense of like, people at Google are not reading your email.
Like, I,
I'm a system a man and I could read people's emails and I'll tell you the truth.
I don't, it's
like
I would, I, it's boring. And also I don't have time for this.
I have enough of my own email to read.
And if I did have time for this, I'd go watch Netflix, I wouldn't read your email.
-- That's true.
-- You know, like I have way better things to do with my life.
That's sort of the first thing is it's not humans at Google, reading your email.
It's an automated system.
And the thing too is, is the automated system, reading your email and then
say, drawing some characterization or judgment on you
and then feeding that into another system
that's been stored and used later in a way that negatively affects you or is it like,
simply put an advertising thing?
So it's kind of a closed loop and that it stays
within Google and it's only used for the specific purpose of,
you know, oh, my favorite thing right now. Twitter is displaying ads to me in French
constantly in French.
I'm like,
-- what did I do wrong? Canada
-- wasn't French one of your national languages.
We have two official languages, French and English.
And I mean, I had French in grade one through nine and uh Jean
palais
de
Fran,
Parle
Anglais
SIV
play,
that's basically my French.
-- Uh What was that? I do not speak French.
-- I do not speak French.
-- Do you, can you speak English, please?
-- Got you.
-- Uh
-- And uh what is it?
Jacques
Ave a
cinema I
think is the correct form.
Uh And that's it. That's all I got. I have no idea what that was.
Uh Jack went to no crap. Is it goes to the cinema or he went to?
That's
damn it, it's gone.
I'm down. OK.
Well, the good news is I'm still my,
I do have the one French phrase I can ask you if you speak English or German.
My German is better than my French. Fair enough. But um
anyway, so, I mean, the,
you know, a great example of this is, well, Google and Amazon both
extensive
data processing, mining extraction,
whatever you want to call it on your behavior on your, on their sites.
But then they tend to keep it in house, right? Like, so Amazon,
you know, Amazon is getting kind of freaky at like,
hey, do you want to buy one of these? And I'm like, I kind of, do
you know,
you know, you want it.
Yeah.
And
fundamentally, I think,
you know, as a human, I'm a little bit more OK with that than, for example,
if Amazon were to data mine all that and just sell it to whoever
some other third party company and then it escapes into the wild.
And the problem here is that
though, as a consumer, I have no idea what's going on. Right. There's,
you know,
and I think part of it is we're sort of used
to this idea of sort of passive versus active hosting.
You know, like you remember back in the day, like if you uploaded a picture to the web,
it was very passively hosted in that, here's a blob of data
and it's up to another human
to find it,
look at it and interpret it.
Like the computers
just were like,
I think it's a JB,
I'm not even sure,
but it
j
the thing is most normal people think that's still how it works.
They don't
know what's going on.
Well,
it kind of crept up on us and it's one
of those things where it happens behind the scenes,
like
for all we know
these companies have really good A I
that are doing really good targeted advertising or
Twitter. They have some
A I that's not doing fantastically good.
Twitter has its own set of problems we'll say. But no, Google and Facebook have
crazy A is man.
And the funny thing is, I don't, can I,
-- is there somebody I can complain to that can fix it or, or
-- that cares
well, exactly. Or is there something I can do to be like,
because I actually got an ad and it's, um, uh, it's, um, uh, what's,
I can't remember the actor's name.
He's the son from, uh, Kim's Convenience. It's a really good CBC show.
Uh, very, very Canadian show.
It's, uh,
Kim's Convenience. It's a convenience store run by Koreans in uh Toronto.
And it's very funny and very good, highly recommend
anyways.
And, uh it was an ad with him in it, but honestly,
it was something that was totally more appropriate for my partner than me
in that. It was, I think it was like an old spice style commercial, right?
So, she loved it.
I was like, ah, whatever, it looks cute and clever, but I can't read this thing.
And my partner is fluent in French
and she really enjoyed the ad. I however, had no idea what it said.
But yeah, so, like a part of it I think is that
in the past when a company had some data about me, in theory,
I could get them to correct it or at least tell me what they had.
Like a great example is what is it called?
The Fair Credit Reporting Act in the United States
where you can at least challenge the stuff on your credit report and be like,
no, I don't
owe this random company 20 bajillion dollars for
some random thing that happened when I was three years old or whatever. Right.
But with this,
I don't even know if there's recourse and, and when I say that I don't even mean, like,
from a business or procedural point of view, I mean,
even from a technical point of view, I don't think Twitter has some knob in there,
they can, like, you know,
-- dial to be like stop showing Kirk French ads
-- and it's probably magic.
My guess is you somehow ended up looking at some French things and they decided,
you know, French.
And so now Twitter thinks, you know, French
and I know when you,
when you sign up for these advertising platforms,
you can pick things like only show this hand to people who know French and,
and their first name is Kurt and they live in
a house and you happen to be those things now.
So
its,
yeah, that's like, you know, you know what this reminds me of always is what was it?
We were, we were talking about something the other day and you told me
you made a comment about something I will say on the dicey side of things
and, and I didn't know what you're talking about and I was like,
I'm not going to search for this because I like, you know, Google is going to think I'm
a,
remember
-- what you're talking about
-- now,
that's what I feel like that's like with youtube,
I remember one time somebody sent me a link and I clicked it and it was like some gun,
a gun, I forget it was some gun channel showing something off.
I don't even remember what it was now.
And like youtube decided I liked guns and I had nothing but guns in my feed for months.
It's like, I like,
I don't really care if you stop showing me gun stuff.
I accidentally clicked.
Uh, I used to watch some of those, um, oh, this week in World War One
fun
and, and it's pretty cool but it's over,
stop it.
I know exactly how that goes.
Like,
just because I watched two videos doesn't mean I
want to see only these videos forever now.
But, I mean, that's the thing, right?
Is these A I algorithms are,
goodness knows what they're even doing and normal people have no idea.
And, and to tie this back to your comment about the credit reporting,
I think the difference is, that's a, that's a subject people understand
and care about because credit reporting can be understood. A is
they really aren't understood.
My, my current understanding and, and of course,
we can't prove this one way or the other.
But my current understanding is that these a,
is organizations like Google and Facebook and whoever
have no one even knows how they work
at this point because they've been kind of just off on their own for so long
and it's,
-- it's magic. I mean, for
-- real as an example,
could Twitter tell me
what data did they base this on? Is it my profile data? Is it data from a third party?
Is it,
did I exchange tweets with somebody who's fluent in French?
And so they decided even though I never
wrote in French
that somehow I speak French or can read French and which I can't
apart from some very basic words,
you know, that's, I
think that's where people are,
are gonna get especially angry and frustrated because
not only do they feel judged? Why was I judged?
And especially if they feel the judgment doesn't
match or shouldn't apply to them.
Like I, I'm, I'm more amused than annoyed that it's showing me these ads in French
because the funny thing is now, I know
I, my mental brain filter for ad blocking on Twitter is very simple.
-- If it's in French, I don't read it because it's an app because
-- I can't.
Yeah, exactly.
You know, I wish Google Mail had a filter for that. Whereas, like
I, I wish I could whitelist languages in the sense of if this email is not in English,
don't display it to me because
I don't speak
Korean or Mandarin or basically I don't speak any
language other than bad English and even worse German
-- Swabian.
-- Right. Right.
It's,
yeah, I don't know, I don't know what the answer is to any of this stuff,
there's no incentive for them to really,
-- I think, provide this because,
-- well, not yet.
-- I mean, so here's the thing and this is
-- until there's some legal or regulatory thing.
-- Right?
-- Maybe. And, and this is where I put my security hat on always. And I think about
no one really cares about security because why should they,
but I feel like this stuff
they might care about because people freak out
when something is out of their control,
granted everything is out of their control.
But this feels especially outside of your sphere of influence. And I think
this is one of those things that people might start asking questions about.
Well, like the sur
bubble stuff people are finding finally beginning to notice search bubbles
or the fact that like,
you know, when a
lot of those, what was it, those congressional hearings where those
politicians were extremely angry about,
like you type my name into Google and it says bad things about me.
And it's like,
well, yeah,
because a lot of people are saying bad things about you and that
seems to be the prevailing sentiment and that's what our A I measures and
right. Well,
and let's face it,
that's how you get change is you just need to make sure that the politicians
are affected by whatever terrible thing is happening
and now they care for some reason.
Right?
-- But if it's, if it's not them, whatever, it
-- doesn't matter well, or their family.
Yeah. Attack a politician's kids and find out how quickly they make that illegal.
Right.
I feel like we are bubbling up into something where people are noticing things
the way they are as opposed to the way they used to be.
And this always amuses me from the security perspective because it's like
we've been telling you this for ages and they're like, yeah,
but you're crazy and we don't like you.
It's like, well, that's fair. So you're finally figuring it out on your own.
I think a large part of it is security people.
We, we are often very good at telling people we should be concerned about X. Right.
Ok.
-- Why should I be concerned about
-- X
one could break into your house in the middle of night and smear peanut
butter on your door and then you could touch it in the morning and,
and it could happen.
It's like, yeah, get, get out
-- like,
-- yeah, exactly. So we're not really good at articulating.
Yeah,
these problems and their negative consequences and in fairness quite
often we don't really know the negative consequences that well,
because there usually aren't any negative consequence.
Well, exactly, like I would say,
yeah. Oh, it's a weird world
which, uh, and I think it feeds nicely into this other, uh, topic of, you know,
somebody figured out.
Oh, my goodness.
It looks like of the top 97 VPN providers.
They're run by 23 parent companies, which I always kind of assumed that they
rebranded because, you know, like price points, enterprise versus personal or
whatever. And it looks like a,
well, here's my favorite, the study shows that the top 97 VPN S are run by,
uh, just 23 parent companies.
Many of them, you're based in countries with lax privacy laws. Yeah.
I'm shocked
how
is that gonna work?
Like, where's that? You remember that spreadsheet?
That guy did and then I think it's, well,
it's an entire website now where it shows all the different VPN providers and like,
do they store data?
Do they keep data? Which jurisdiction are they in which?
Blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, like, what is it? I forget the name of it.
We'll put it in the show notes because it's been in the show notes before.
Um
Anyways,
uh researchers at VPN Pro have pieced
together ownership information through company listings,
geolocation data, the CV S of employees and other documentation,
which I gotta say that is some awesome
detective sleuthing
work.
That's, that's exact. Like this is what annoys me.
This is what journalism is supposed to be doing, investigative journalism, right?
It's not just
clever
things.
And uh in some instance,
ownership of different VPN is split among a number of different subsidiaries.
So no big surprise there.
But anyways, the point is a whole pile of these VPN providers
or something like a third of them apparently are owned by Chinese firms.
I'm shocked,
I'm
only a third. Right.
And it's funny to me because China has a, like in the last I would say 5, 10 years,
really strong history of kind of running some of the more,
I don't want to say dodgy bits but some of the more messy
bits of internet infrastructure like Bitcoin mining
like that is a heavily
Chinese thing,
right?
Like of all the miners, my understanding is a big major, you know,
double digits proportion are in China.
That seems to be the case. Yes,
there's a whole bunch of this. But
so,
and I was thinking about this and, and my first thought was like as well,
especially for an intelligence agency.
I mean, the greatest example I can think of is, you know,
-- who here remembers to R and still uses it, remembers
-- it's still there, man.
It's Tor
-- is fantastic.
-- Yeah, exactly.
Well, do you, where did to R come from?
Uh
It was, it was,
it was some sort of university project, wasn't it?
Am I remembering correctly?
-- What was it
-- not? So uh hang on a sec. Uh
it was,
-- wasn't it the US Navy?
-- Was it? I don't know, I thought, I don't know the history
of
-- that.
-- Well,
DDDD.
Yeah, here we go. The core principle of
Tor onion routing was developed in the mid 19 nineties.
So that's pretty impressive.
Actually,
it's a while by the United
States naval research Laboratory employees mathematicians,
Paul Syverson and computer scientist Michael G Reed and David Gold Schlag
with the purpose of protecting us intelligence communications online
onion routing was further developed by DARPA in 1997 blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
So the point is the US Navy came out with Tor
so that they could have secure communications online and
also
a way to gather and tell because I,
I remember working for an intelligence company that had a T one that they,
they didn't quite pay for it in cash, but basically they paid for it in cash
and it came into the office and had like no information about us associated with it
so that our virus guys could go browse the web and honestly.
Right, exactly.
You know,
without getting us nailed
the US Navy started this.
But the thing is, you know, if we know all the Tor nodes are being run by the US Navy.
Well, I, I don't think that's the case.
I mean, it sounds like the Navy created the concept of onion routing,
right?
They, they came up with Tor
and then they,
one of the big
reasons they made it open source in public is because they realized
it only is really valuable
if a whole bunch of people are doing this because,
and this is one of my favorite conversations.
Uh the are the really good intel guy had with me was he taught me about the difference
between hiding and masking and they are so very
different and I did not realize this or understanding.
-- Well,
-- then why don't you tell us what the difference is
hiding is actually hiding? So
you're doing something
uh say illegal for the sake of argument and you literally hide like you,
you need to stay out of sight.
You, you know, do it surreptitiously.
You, you travel around at night, you know, so nobody sees you doing it.
Masking is for example, if you live in a surveillance state where you cannot hide,
you can mask things.
You know, you, for example,
you go and buy a palm tree and then you go and buy nitrogen fertilizer
and then you go and buy
like an off road vehicle so that you have an excuse to go buy diesel.
And now you can,
you know, understand
a diesel fuel, nitrous, whatever bomb thing.
Sure versus hiding where you know,
you go and try and pay for it with cash from a guy who won't ask you many questions.
And so part of Tor
is Tor
doesn't work unless you can be part of a big thundering herd
of sort of quasi
anonymous stuff.
Right? Well, and, and part of the trick with Tor
also is it relies on one organization not controlling too much of it
because
-- it things
-- get otherwise
-- they can see
-- enough. You, you can, right?
Even though you may not be able to necessarily see the data itself,
you can start doing statistical
analysis on metadata. Exactly. And you can figure certain things out.
Well, I mean, that's how they got, remember the Silk Road guy,
they managed to localize his time zone
based on his activity
and then based on that they were able to monitor some, you know,
stuff and, and kind of work their way closer to him until they actually found him.
Well, he, he ended up getting caught because didn't he love
without Tor
one day? Right.
Uh, well, that was kind of, yeah, that was kind of the,
-- the break in the case as it was
-- now.
You know what, you know what I think about a lot actually.
So when they, when they caught him and they said, oh,
you logged in without Tor and we found you and I wonder if
they knew where he was because they had somehow figured it out using
-- parallel
-- discovery.
And it's like we know who this guy is now.
We just need to wait for him to make a mistake and then we can go get him,
which would not shock me in any way, you know.
But, uh, well, that's the thing,
that's one of the biggest problems with operational security is, uh, you
defenders only have to make a mistake once for an attacker to take advantage.
And
when, you know, let's, you know, if, if the local police is looking for you, yeah,
you, you may be able to get away with it.
But when the FBI
and the secret service and a bunch of other agencies are looking for you.
Well, they're gonna,
you know, I'm reminded of these investigations where it's like, ok, well,
all we need to do
is go talk to everybody with a red car
in the city
and, like, then they'll go do that totally doable.
It reminds me, like, uh,
totally tangent but the city court building in New York that
was going to collapse because they didn't weld the plates,
right?
Remember that whole debacle.
So they had to basically do an inventory of everybody that lived
in the shadow of the building if it were to fall down.
And so they did this like pseudo red cross survey thing where they basically,
like went out for a couple of months and like,
basically logged everybody that lives in the area
where they are what the building is like.
Right? I mean, that, that's a huge amount of effort,
right? Had to be done, right?
And that's the thing with law enforcement and stuff.
If you make them angry enough, they're going to get their scalp.
-- Yeah. Exactly. Exactly.
-- But I was thinking about this. So, you know,
I would, I would be almost more shocked and, and almost horrified to learn that,
for example, my country's intelligence services aren't running a bunch of tor
nodes because for one thing, they probably need to be using Tor
nodes
because it's, you know, for, for example, for, even if you're doing, like,
open source intelligence where you're just like finding public sources,
putting stuff together, you know, whatever
you still probably want to do that without exposing your IP address at
the government agency you work for.
Right. Right. Exactly.
So you're probably going to use a VPN or to R, right.
And let's face it.
Tor kind of slow VPN S kind of fast for, you know, five bucks a month
in some cases you get what you pay for.
So here's the thing, if you're going to use VPN S or Tor,
well,
how do you know that you're using it
correctly and safely unless you really understand it
because it's
hard
to do,
right?
And so I would argue that
in order to use it correctly,
you need to probably have run it or actively be running it to really understand like
the difference is between, say, you know, a VPN provider that does, um,
DNS masking versus one that doesn't, right.
That's,
you know what I'm talking about. I mean, a lot of people don't.
So if you're using a VPN? Great.
But what if your client doesn't use the VPN to make DNS lookups?
-- Well, boom, you're exposed.
-- Yeah. And that, that gets a lot of people.
This is why
actually, so I, I have a machine that I will use for a VPN for various reasons. And
I specifically set up IP filtering rules to just block literally all traffic
that doesn't
go to the VPN everything else 100% blocked.
And even then I'm like,
I probably made a mistake in these rules and it would not
shock me if there's things leaking out that I don't know about.
Exactly.
So, I, I think from an operational perspective, like I said,
I think these organizations and I don't mean just intelligence services but,
you know,
companies, right. I mean, as a company you probably
have people using VPN S. Do you kind of,
how do you intelligently shop for one? Do you know what to look for?
Well, I think part of it is
you can't have that expertise without
the operational experience of actually doing it
uh to a degree. I mean, honestly just quit using VPN S like that,
that's the answer.
Trust networking man.
Well, I mean, but sometimes you want to mask
who you are.
Like, uh remember Wikipedia, how if you're logged into Wikipedia,
it shows who edited the page
and if you're not logged in, you're being anonymous,
it shows the IP that edited the page.
And do you remember the whole, oh, the US congressional office, I think had to be
BERS still ban.
I don't know if they still are,
but they were right because the staffers kept updating Wikipedia entries of their,
the,
the people they work for, which is, which is awesome.
Yeah. And all they had to do was either VPN or log in and
those darn kids would have gotten away with it if it weren't for old man Johnson.
Yeah. But I, I bet most of them don't.
Right.
I mean,
because there's two sides to this is, first of all,
there's how much do you care and you have to care a
lot to actually turn on the VPN and then edit a Wikipedia page
and how many are competent enough to do it?
I mean, look, I'm not going to bash our, our leaders to band here, but
when it comes to technology, they're not the brightest bulbs in the pack here,
right?
And so it would not shock me at all if a nontrivial
number of their staffers don't even know what a VPN is.
Yeah, I would agree.
But so yeah, anyways, this goes back to the whole masking thing of, you know,
the VPN S are great for masking, hiding in a thundering herd of,
you know, there's, uh here's an exit note on a VPN provider with, you know,
say 5000 or 10,000 people coming through it.
Well, now it becomes much harder to correlate traffic metadata,
that kind of thing and more to the point these things make money.
-- Um
-- probably you figure you probably use a nickels worth
traffic for $5 a month because network traffic is free.
I mean, I, I, the last time I looked at,
you know, physical server when you
rack hosting with a Gigabit Ethernet, you know, 95% usage
if you really are
willing to go cheap and a bit, probably not super reliable, like,
-- like one or 200 bucks a month.
-- Yeah, probably.
But you still need staff to set it up and I bet the support is the real trick.
Right.
But, so anyway, anyway, we're, we're, we're nearing the end.
So, in summary, why don't you bring us home?
Well, I, I, why is anybody shocked by this?
This is and, and I don't mean just the VPN thing, I mean by the,
the Facebook A I photo thing.
And again, we've been, you know, if you give a company, your data,
chances are
they're going to hold on to it because it has value
now and it will have more value later when they can,
for example, interpret it and correlate it
and figure out that for example, you post family photos on Facebook. Cool.
Facebook currently identifies who's in the photo.
That's nice, right?
But at some point it's going to notice in your back
of the photo that like you have a barbecue or you have
a
swing set or a dog.
-- Oh, I'd be shocked if they don't do that already. And
-- for advertising that would be,
you know, because barbecues don't last very long.
I finally learned why.
But um
because stainless steel doesn't
resist rust at high temperature,
I'm like he's the stupidest thing I've ever heard.
That's true of most metals,
most metals struggle with high temperatures because they
start organizing and doing other scary things.
-- So,
-- Titanium barbecues, that's the answer.
Yes. That's right.
So, you know, and the thing is,
well, GDPR right, to forget aside,
generally speaking, these companies are gonna
aggregate
and store and mine and extract as much value as they can from that data because
their companies, that's
what they do.
Like, I, I don't know what else to say.
So, here's, here's what I would, I will, I will end on
people learn these things and they become
surprised and sometimes offended
-- or shocked or whatever.
-- I think offended is a really good word here.
It might be.
And we, we know this,
probably most people listening to this show are not surprised in any
way by any of the things we talk about right now.
I, I'm always reminded that normal people
are in a different place than people who do security
do you work are for example, and I'll just pick on security.
This is true of tech in general, but we'll specifically call it
plumbing
car mechanics.
-- Well,
-- and that's just it. Right.
Everyone has their own little circle of
knowledge and expertise and things like what,
how Facebook's a I might work is not in the realm of anyone's knowledge.
I still don't understand why.
If you overfill a car with too much oil that breaks the car. That makes no sense to me.
Are you serious?
-- I, why
-- it gets in the pistons?
Like then you have compression problems and you blow your head gasket.
Why can't they have like an overflow level thing? Like just poke a hole in the oil pan.
-- So if it gets too full, it's
-- a sealed system though. And
it's, the oil is self contained, it needs to be sealed and under pressure.
And so you can't have like an, I'm,
I'm sure they could add some sort of like magic release,
but it would probably add a
bunch of cost and then,
and then the problem fail,
not just fail.
Uh It, it's going to leak oil all over the freaking place when it does fail.
And now you have a hazmat situation, right?
OK. Today I learned,
there you go.
And
-- I'm sure I got some of that wrong and someone will tell
-- me,
don't let Kurt borrow your car.
That is true. I have some funny stories about changing oil.
I could tell someday but not today.
So anyway, the point is people start to learn this stuff and
it changes the worldview to a degree.
And so I feel like we are at a point with
technology where there's too few people understand what's going on.
And I know you can say, oh especially
and blah, blah, blah, blah.
But, but I mean, for real,
like there's a certain base level like you need to
know how to work a light switch in your house,
right?
Like you,
you have to understand electricity comes from a power plant travels over wires,
it goes to the light, it makes the light work.
And that's a great example because you know, hey Alexa,
turn the lights on and it happens. But
magic, I have a even I only have a cursory understanding of what's all is going on.
-- It's
-- magic all magic
but ignoring how Alexa
works, just understanding that when you give Facebook data,
they're not saying, oh wow. Thanks for the data.
You know, we'll take good care of this.
They're like, they're like this, this ravenous monster consuming your data and,
and like advertiser information comes out the other end of it.
Like they're not doing this to be nice to you.
Right.
And I,
I think there's a lot of people who don't get that yet and I think it's going
to be really hard to see meaningful change until we have a certain amount of people.
Right.
You,
you hit that tipping point eventually where people figure
it out and they become outraged and then,
then we can maybe see some change.
-- But I think we've got a long way to go still.
-- I think a big part of it too is, is
being able to explain this in terms
that average people can understand.
And I don't mean, you know, in the sense of, oh, they're dumb technically,
but in the sense of
like, why do I want to care about this?
-- Right.
-- Exactly. Exactly.
And,
and our stories are terrible because we always
concoct these ridiculous plots that never come true.
And so most people just think security people are insane and annoying and, I mean,
they're right, but like we also kind of know what we're doing.
So,
-- both are true.
-- Right.
Yeah, I mean,
fundamentally we need story or we need explanations that are
as simple as if we don't fix the sewer,
you can't flush your toilet.
Uh, that is a good explanation. And that's a huge problem.
I have 100% buy in. Now.
-- That
-- work.
Exactly. Exactly. But at the same time, technology doesn't work like that.
Like when the, ok, the internet fails that, that's bad.
And then the kids like, go crazy, but
when your toilet fails,
you have way bigger problems than compared to when the internet fails, right?
And that's just part of how it works. So, anyway, all right, I've gotten this off.
That's enough. So, thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up the show notes.
You can use the Pound Os s podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media.
-- Yeah, Kurt have a fabulous rest of your day. You too.
-- Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.