Hello and welcome to the XTH episode of
the Open Source Security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried
and my partner in crime, Josh Bresser.
Kurt, why did you call it the XTH?
Which I don't even think is a word Roman numerals, Roman numerals,
which means for those of us who are Roman numeral, we'll say um hindered.
-- This is now the 10th episode of the Open Source Security podcast. That's crazy,
-- man.
10 episodes I, I remember we started, actually,
I told myself that if we can make it to 10,
I'll feel like this is not a completely failed venture.
And
yeah, we, we made it success, right?
All
downhill from here.
Which big news do we lead with
coin
flip
last week? With,
let's lead with, with Dirty Cow because I think that subject is
smaller and more reasonable
than the other minor event that took place last week.
Yeah.
So dirty cow was a dirty copy on, right? Hence the acronym cow cow
in the Linux kernel
uh that had been there for,
what was it? Nine years,
I think nine
-- years,
-- more than nine.
But, but a long time.
Yeah. And somebody finally noticed it
and we fixed it
and as far as I'm concerned, really, that's all there is to talk about.
Um, as far as I know,
I mean,
yeah, pretty much, I mean, this attack apparently had been used a bit and there's,
you know, the proof of concept code and all that, but
I was talking with some people last night and as I pointed out, um,
this is not the last one,
-- you know, this is not the last,
-- have you seen the graph from Case Cook?
That was quite beautiful. Actually, that was a really good data visual.
He's, he's, I don't know, I haven't seen the updated one yet,
but basically case has shown that
the average Linux
privilege escalation flaw has a lifespan of five years before we find it,
which means
there's
at least
one more
that we probably won't find for five years.
Well, and you know,
and this is what I was talking about last night
was I'm I'm more curious about what is the scale,
you know, is there 10 of these left 100 1000 a million?
Like,
you know, we, we have literally
no strong idea, you know, as far as I know nobody's ever done.
Like here's what I would love to see.
For example, if somebody pick a portion of the Linux kernel, say like
100,000 lines worth of code
and just audit it like crazy.
-- But,
-- but even then man, you could have the smartest person, you know,
audit it for a month
and a
Uber could show up the next day and find a bug they missed. So
let's do this. Hold on, hold on. I want to discuss what this issue is first because
in my dealings with the nonsecurity folks,
this is not a simple issue to understand.
And so let's start there and then we'll get
into the esoteric nature of finding flaws in software
that is incredibly difficult, if not impossible,
right? So first of all, it's called dirty cow.
What is cow?
Uh So
c stands for copy
and right, and this is one of those class of security flaws.
No, no, no, not security for
what is copy.
And right,
in a modern computing system,
there's a concept of using the same bits of data
in places that need to share it,
right?
And so
in memory, you have what's called a memory page, which is kind of the,
the
how do I even describe it? It, it, it, it's like,
I mean, this is one of the problems I'm, I'm always,
I always go back to that Feynman video where
he has to describe like what is magnetism and,
and he's like, I cannot explain it to you because I, I just can't keep backing up.
So anyway,
in a modern computing system, there's what called, it's a page of memory.
It's just like a logical way to split the
memory in two sections that the computer can use,
-- right, like
-- a literal page of paper with lines.
That's exactly fair. Right. Right.
And so what happens is if two things need to use, what is fundamentally the same page,
it will
basically hand them both a reference to the same page.
And then it tells itself the kernel tells itself
that this is a copy on write page,
which means if one of these things wants to write to it,
I want you to make a copy of it and then let them write to it.
OK?
And obviously, as you can imagine,
there could be certain security considerations with
this kind of set up where you have
to make sure the copy happens before you let the other thing do the writing
right
now.
What happens when you need to,
when when the kernel decides it's time to make the copy, it marks the page as dirty,
right? And that, that's literally what we call it.
That's not like some euphemism for something
for something terrible like it's literally called, it is now a dirty page.
Dirty page means you make the copy and then neither page is dirty at that point.
And so this problem was basically an issue with the way you mark the page dirty
and then
you make the copy.
And then
basically before the copy is made,
you, there's a race condition in the kernel that lets you write to the original
dirty page.
And obviously, in the case of the exploits we've seen,
they're basically me mapping a file and disk that you
shouldn't be able to write to marking the page,
dirty, triggering the race condition and writing data into that file.
And of course,
the easiest example I've seen is just to edit Etsy password to make root do horrible,
scary things.
Yeah. No, this is
the whole concept of these uh duplicate memory pages. I understand why we did it.
Right. It's a heck of a performance bonus,
you know, especially on a server where you have say,
you know, 100 users all running http D right?
Because it's all basically identical and you have, you know, one
copy and memory doing, you know, running for 100 people,
which is a massive massive memory savings. But yeah, I mean, there's,
it introduces all these security considerations that's assuming it's not broken,
-- right? Like it was in this case, it's
-- not even just that
there's when you execute an application you do, it's called a fork
exec.
And the way this works is rather than
basically creating a whole new process,
filling all the memory with what you need to do
in making copies of everything.
It just essentially marks all of the memory pages,
copy and write and then starts the new process.
So you can imagine in that context that makes things very, very fast as well.
So there's, there's a million reasons to do this and it is it is accepted
that it's a great idea and it is, don't get me wrong. It's just, it, it's also,
it's difficult to do clever things correctly.
Yeah.
No. So, in this case, I mean, race conditions are,
in my opinion, one of the sort of the worst class of computer security flaws because
they are typically not super easy to find. You know, if you look at a buffer overflow,
you can see it in the code, right. But race conditions typically
you have to trigger them to figure out whether or not they actually trigger.
That's a good point.
Well, and so that you just brought up a really interesting aspect of this is
the reason we knew about this problem nine years ago and didn't fix it is
because the memory subsystem in the Linux kernel
wasn't as predictable as it is today.
So it was thought that this race condition cannot be triggered
so we can live with this bug for the moment.
Yeah. And then like all software bugs that are ignored,
it got ignored.
Well, and we fix the memory subsystem to make it predictable.
And all of a sudden a race condition, we didn't think we could trigger.
We can now trigger.
Yeah.
Yeah. This reminds me a lot of things like row hammer where, you know,
if you had told me five years ago that you could physically flip bits
in memory that you do not control. I would have been like, that's impossible.
It just can't be done,
you know, turns out it is possible, you know, all these attacks that like,
literally,
yeah, we, we thought were physically impossible or just like
the software does not do that. You, it just doesn't work that way. I'm sorry?
Well, yeah, I mean, so like
when I think about the Linux kernel nine years ago versus today, I mean,
it is like a totally different beast, you know,
the amount of improvements and changes,
you know, or like I remember back in the, you know,
the Linux 0.99 patch level to infinity days, you know, 20 years ago and it was,
you know, this is nothing like what it is today and,
and part of my concern there is, you know, yeah, what other bugs
have been ignored because they weren't really bugs
back then but have now grown into nice,
you know, healthy security flaws.
They're all grown up.
Yeah.
And, and, you know,
that's one of the reasons I would love to see a code audit of
a chunk of code is so we could at least maybe start to get,
you know,
say 100,000 lines of device drivers in the Linux kernel
versus 100,000 lines of sort of more co core code.
How many flaws are we talking here?
Like if we really spent some effort auditing it so we
can get a sense of the scale for the whole thing,
you know, ideally
I have a feeling it's climb under the desk and cry numbers if I had to guess.
Well, and more to the point here's the ugly truth. Right. We don't have the,
like, even if we had the money to pay people to do this,
we don't have enough people trained in the Linux kernel
core security fundamentals.
I mean, this stuff is horribly complicated.
Yeah. Yeah, it is.
Well, that, I mean, this is,
this is one of the arguments I always go back to
over and over again when I talk about this stuff is
the Linux kernel has some of the smartest developers in the
world working on it if they can't get it right?
What hope does an average developer have of getting it? Right?
And the answer is they don't have any.
Yeah. And at least the good news is with the Linux kernel.
That means, you know, people aren't reinventing the Linux kernel, right?
Nobody goes out and writes an operating system kernel nowadays pretty much.
I mean, it happens, it's rare,
you know,
the majority of these people just use a Linux kernel and a and a GNU user space,
right? And then just move on with their life.
Don't tell the BS D guys that.
Yeah.
Well, and you know, BS D two,
like I actually have a couple of BS D based devices here at home,
you know, and I quite like them.
Um part of it is I want a
somewhat diverse ecosystem, right? I actually have two firewalls.
One Linux, one bs D, you know,
the, the hope being that if there is some, like,
I don't know if you remember the ping of death back in the day,
you'd send a ping request with a, with an oversized uh request.
And then when the system tried to create this, like larger than 64 kilobyte packet,
it would just die
a
significant number of,
didn't it?
I remember because Linux got patched within a day or two. And so you logged into IRC,
you know,
and people would just enter the channel and then just ping flood the whole channel
and everybody on Windows would drop.
I do remember that and it took, it took Microsoft, I mean,
this is back before they kind of took security seriously as they do now,
but it took them a long time to fix it.
It was a couple of months.
It was embarrassingly long and I don't,
did they have automatic patching back then or did you have to do?
I think you might have had to download it
on your own
-- to install the patch. Why?
-- Honestly? Yeah, that was so long ago.
Well, this is Windows NT 4.0 days.
So I don't think it had like
software updates. Like
because
it was, I think I had Windows 95. I was, I was testing that
because I remember I would dual boot between Windows 95 and Linux
back in the day
and
man, dual boating. Thank goodness, that's not a thing.
Well, it probably is for a lot of people but I, I no longer do that.
Yeah.
Well, this,
I think this discussion of the Linux kernel and
user space and the way people use the software
leads nicely into the, uh, the second big event of last week
where I believe you need to apologize to us for something.
-- You said,
-- I'm not going to apologize.
I'm gonna say when I thought, why would someone burn a botnet on Krebs?
I think what I should have said was holy crap. Wait for the next month
because it's clear the botnet wasn't burnt.
It's much bigger
and in fact, it's still there.
The, the, the huge deal
is
actually
worse. I was talking with some people and
the Marai Bonnet is not a single bonnet,
it's actually multiple bonnets and they've actually seen cases
of one of the Marai botnets attacking like de
dossing the command and control infrastructure of a different Marai Botnet
in an effort to essentially bring that part of the botnet down.
So, yeah,
it's gotten so bad now that there are actually
multiple botnets fighting each other and occasionally then,
you know, being pointed at
places
like
d
in essence.
So
here's the question, will the botnets
have mutual assured destruction of one another or one of them emerge
after this uh selection
of, of the fittest
and, and be the the super botnet that nobody can stop.
I suspect we won't have,
I, I suspect we'll have a lot of different bonnets forever because
the reality is
nobody's going to fix these things.
All right, before we get into that,
let's for those who don't know which there's probably a couple of people is, is,
let's explain exactly what happened. There's this thing called the Mariah Botnet.
And now a couple of shows ago we talked about Brian
Krebs site having a giant distributed denial of service attack happening
where IOT devices were primarily the sources of traffic.
After that happened,
Krebs,
not just primarily IOT devices, specifically digital video recorders,
primarily from one Chinese manufacturer.
OK. Right. Right.
And so Krebs, his site comes down,
he moves it over to Google who are graciously hosting it. Now, given
this is,
I mean, this is one of those things like who wants to host that. Right.
It's,
it's constantly under attack because this is someone who
points out the seedy underbelly of the internet.
And so obviously,
there are people with,
we'll say questionable morals who would love to
do nothing more than to take Krebs down.
So obviously hosting his site is significant risk now.
So Krebs site D OS comes back up, the guys who own the botnet
that did it, published the source code to the botnet on github,
which again, I mean github is like the center of the universe now,
which is kind of hilarious you know, good guys and bad guys, everyone likes it.
It's uh
so the
source
code distribution platform,
it really is.
So, so the source code is published
and now anybody can build their own
botnet, right? It'll be, it'll be great when you have like instead of meta,
you have like botnet
spit, right? You just click a couple of boxes and now you have a bot
-- those products already exist. You just have to pay for them, but they're
-- not free.
Right?
The equivalent of me,
it used to be very expensive.
So give it time.
So, anyway, now what happens is essentially there's all these new botnets
and one of them or we, we don't know how many really
starts attacking
the, the dying company, DYN and they do DNS for a large number of organizations
and so their DNS servers get attacked, which means
you can't resolve domain names,
which means essentially a significant portion of the
internet for certain people now appears to be gone
because DNS is kind of the,
it's like the,
the circulatory system of the phone book. Yeah, that's fair. Right. Well,
what's a phone book? Right. It's a,
it's a thing they set on my porch once a year that I throw away. Right.
I
find it useful for starting fires like at the cabin. Not,
you know, let me just qualify that statement.
Oh, my goodness.
Anyway,
so, so fundamentally
we know there's all these IOT devices
they have default user credentials.
They are
worse than that.
Uh A lot of these, for example,
the 11 of the ones primarily using this is from a company,
there's this Chinese company called and I'm going to butcher this name.
HSU like X
Mai, I think,
and they're, they don't actually sell the devices. They're essentially
like an upstream provider who builds the boards with, you know, all the hardware
and
preloaded Linux
like a preloaded Linux firmware that you can easily customize, you know,
with your branding, your name, your logo, whatever.
Uh And so they then sell these to Chinese manufacturers.
I think there's about 40 or 50 of them
who then like stick it physically in a box and put like a sticker on it and like,
you know,
use the developer kit to modify the firmware a little bit
to put their logo on it and their name on it
and then, you know, sell it
on ebay or
uh whatever.
And the problem is the there is a default telnet
account for root with password. Uh What is it? XC 3511 as the password
and it's hard coded into in it dot D slash R CS.
Like you, you cannot remove this account without
uh I guess you could patch the binary if you were clever enough.
But like, let's face it, right? People buying
cheap Chinese digital vi
uh digital video uh recording systems, you know,
for surveillance systems probably aren't the kind of people, you know,
into a binary patching,
-- right?
-- It will, if I recall correctly, the source code to Maria has
like 90 or 60
credentials that it essentially checks.
Yeah,
there's, there's a couple of lists and yeah, there's,
there's a lot of these devices with these,
these hard coded, you know, root level accounts.
So this the the logical place this discussion is going
to end up with us talking about is the fact that
so there's all these IOT devices
they are currently unable.
And so now you have a device that cannot be repaired, that is being used to cause harm
to another organization
who's responsible. Is it the owner of the device? Is it the manufacturer?
Is it the ISP hosting the device?
It is,
this is not obvious and like we don't have laws to define this,
but also most importantly is the fact that
without economic incentives, nobody cares,
right? If something isn't gonna cost me time or money,
I don't care about
it.
Well, and one thing to remember too is it's not just the end devices, you know,
generating the traffic that are part of the problem.
There's a lot of uh so in the case of a of this distributed attack against D DNS,
um they attacked DN DNS using well the DNS
services that they provide, right?
And DNS typically uses uh a network protocol called UDP user
dataram protocol,
which literally it's like sending a postcard in the mail, right?
You just scribble a bit of information down
and send it off and hopefully the remote end gets it. Maybe they don't,
you know, there's no assured delivery like there is with TCP/IP.
And so because of that, you can easily spoof UDP packets.
So in the case of this attack against D DNS, there may have been only
only
100,000 or so devices attacking D DNS.
But because a lot of these devices are on I
SPS that don't do proper network filtering to prevent spoofing,
they were able to spoof IP addresses in
the amounts of apparently tens of millions of spoofed IP addresses,
which makes tracking down the device even harder because the problem is
you have to then like old time, I don't know if you've ever seen those old films.
You know, it's like why we're tracing the call and you know,
when they get to like each node of the network and
of the,
the phone system and trace them to like Canada and then to like the US and Mexico.
Well, that's what you have to do when people are spoofing this traffic.
You can't just look at the traffic and be like, oh, it's coming from over here,
you have to go up each link and be like, oh,
it's coming from level three and then you got to go talk to level three and be like,
hey,
this huge honking data flow with these characteristics where is it coming from?
And they'll be like, oh, it's coming from this, you know, peering provider.
You go to that peering provider and it's three in the morning there.
So good luck with that,
-- you know, and eventually we
-- find
-- the data is coming from inside the house.
-- Exactly.
And so even if you can trace these devices down, you know,
if I gave you a list of 100,000 IP addresses, what would you do with it?
You know,
even if I gave you a list of 100,000 phone numbers and
names of the people that actually own and control these devices,
you know, you're gonna phone them up and they're gonna think you're crazy.
They're not going to know what I'm talking about in most instances.
Yeah.
You know, so that's, that's the brutal truth is,
is this really reminds me of the whole air pollution.
Uh you know, you've got this
situation where I have a device that benefits me, you know,
in the form of it's my security system, my digital video recorder, whatever,
you know, much like uh for example, I have a car that drives me around
or that I drive around
and it creates
some pollution.
Oh, I know, I can't wait for it.
But so you know, these, these, this device has the potential
to create what we call a negative externality, right? So it's something negative
that is not my problem,
right? Like in the car in the case of my car pollution.
Unless I, like, sit in the garage with the door closed, running my car,
I'm not going to notice the pollution my car creates
by and large.
Well, same thing with, you know, if I have a device on my network, let's say,
sending out a megabit stream of traffic.
I'm actually probably
not really going to notice if I'm a normal user. Right.
Like the internet might feel a little bit slower, but really who's, you know,
they're not gonna run some traffic analysis on
their network to figure out what's going on?
I think this is a very apt analogy of pollution because you're right.
Everyone pollutes a little bit and, and nobody really cares.
And, you know, I, I even think of this in the context of
going to like a national park
and they say things like, you know, leave only footprints,
take only pictures and people are like, oh, I'm gonna pick up this rock and if like,
every 10 million people decide I'm gonna pick up one rock,
that's a lot of rocks
-- and,
-- well, that's the really ugly part of this.
You know, it's, it's death by 1000 million teeny, tiny little paper cuts.
But, you know, eventually you're bleeding out and everything's tipped over.
So let's follow the pollution analogy because I do like it.
So in this case, the other problem with po, well,
quite often pollution breaks down like,
uh, the,
the analogy breaks down a bit because
part of the problem with pollution is typically
pollution doesn't just flat out kill you.
It, but it takes like two or three years off your life.
Right.
And proving that can be very difficult because there's so many other situations.
And so it,
it kind of reminds me very similar to spam in
that we have to spend all this money spam blocking.
Otherwise email would be unusable.
Well, you know, Din D and now have to spend whatever amount
of money they have to spend,
you know, hardening their network, buying excess capacity.
You know, when I was reading some of these comments online, they're like,
why doesn't D DNS just have enough capacity to soak up the attack?
Because,
well, that costs a lot of money
and 99% of the time they don't need it.
You know, that's the real ugly truth.
Yes,
that's,
that's fair. And, and not only that,
even if they just doubled their bandwidth,
the bad guys would double the attack.
I suspect that the botnets will be able to grow faster,
then essentially most rational insane companies can afford to deal with them
for the simple fact that if you go to like your local home hardware store,
like Home Depot or Lowe's or Eagle or I don't know what they have in Europe,
they sell a lot of stuff. Now. That has an IP address.
Yeah. Yeah,
there's tons of it. Definitely.
You know,
and, and that I've, I've actually really noticed in the last six months
has become a thing, you know, back a year ago they had, I think it was just the nest, uh,
smoke alarms and thermostats.
That was it.
And now there's, I think about four or five brands.
There's like Honeywell, there's, uh, the nest stuff. There's
like
a whole pile of different manufacturers, you know,
some reasonably reputable and some I've never heard of, you know, Nest,
for example, does
remote automated updates.
You know, my smoke alarm, for example, there was a problem. Apparently.
So previously, you could wave your hand at the smoke alarm and it would like turn off
and apparently that sort of same sensor thing could be triggered during a real fire,
which obviously is bad.
You don't want a real fire
burning and then
accidentally turning the smoke alarm off because the
smoke alarm thinks you're waving your hand at
it. And so they did an over the air upgrade, right.
So, like these things are, you know,
connected to the internet and they go talk to a mother,
mother ship and unless you like firewall, it,
it's going to get updates end of story and you're not going to firewall because,
you know, for it to alert your phone and stuff, it has to go talk to the mothership.
Now,
Nest, we can all agree is doing this right. And Google owns Nest, right.
So
they're doing it right. But now next to the nest thermostat
is something made, who knows where by, who knows who
and it doesn't get any updates,
but fundamentally appears to do the same thing and it's half the price.
What are you going to do as a consumer?
Well, you know,
I've been thinking about this and one thing I would like to see is ideally, you know,
like how we have nutritional labels on food that says
how much fat and protein and carbs and you know,
whatever stuff is in there.
One thing I would love to see is some
mandatory labeling for network capable devices that says,
for example, does this device work without a connection to the internet?
Right.
Uh Nest being a great example, Nest,
you know,
there was that situation where it would lose connectivity or something to the
internet and just stop making your house hot which in winter in,
you know, Canada is a problem, right?
This is one of the reasons I won't upgrade to a nest thermostat.
I need to have heat in my house or I will die.
And so for example, I would love to see, you know,
uh what has the manufacturer committed to for updates?
You know, three years, 10 years, 20 years.
Uh are these updates free or do they cost money?
You know, is there a $5 a month to get updates?
You know, and for free? I get nothing
and just, you know, some, some data around that so I can make an informed choice. And
-- so,
-- you know, you your analogy here is quite AMT
because the nutritional labeling on food,
nobody reads or understands what any of that means.
And what you're suggesting is even more complicated than what they were trying to
simplified.
I think it would have to basically boil down to honestly,
the two main things I want to see are
what does this device do when it loses its network connection? And you know,
some of it will be somewhat obvious. For example, it maybe can't
uh send alerts to your phone, right? Because it can't connect to the network.
But some of it, you know, some of these devices might just,
-- you know, throw up in a corner and die.
-- If internet
activity is lost, it will murder your family, right?
But here's the thing man. So here's the thing
you can say this.
But what is, first of all, why, why is anybody going to care?
Because again, we come back to the fact that without
a real economic incentive here,
what is going to compel the industry or the consumer to even care a little bit?
I
think part of it is it might have to get bad enough
that somebody like the uh what is it in the US,
the FTC, the Federal Trade Commission,
you know, maybe bans the import of some of these devices until they,
you know, meet some sort of standard that they come up with
II, I don't know, like I,
I honestly think regulation and standards are the answer because,
you know, from a private perspective, I mean,
it's not like I SPS are going to shut these people down.
You know,
they've, especially in Canada, for example,
you've paid for your bandwidth and you have a data cap so they don't
care how you use your bandwidth because once you use your bandwidth up,
you start paying for it.
And I kind of,
I tend to agree
that for an ISP, they should fundamentally just hand you
the end of a wire
and then it's not their problem.
Right.
That's a sustainable model
long term.
And, you know,
that's one of my concerns because I really don't want to
see a world where my ISP controls what I see.
No, no, no, they shouldn't, they shouldn't. Right. They should hand you a wire
and
they don't care what's on that wire one way or the other. Right.
That's, that's kind of my view of that. And I,
if, if we want to think of the internet as a public utility,
that makes sense. Right?
Because there isn't like there isn't Comcast brand electricity
that comes into your like it is all electricity,
right?
See one thing that uh so I have a couple,
I have two network connections at home because I work from home
and the one of them is a DS L link and by default, the DS L modem it came with
does not. And so the DS L modem itself has an IP address of 1 92.1 68 dot
I think like 1.2 or something.
And then it obviously has a like real IP address on the internet.
But basically by default, if you, you know,
plug your network and stuff into this DS L modem, you're connected to the internet,
but you're not directly on the internet, you're, you know,
behind a network uh firewall essentially.
And I think quite,
and, and here's the nice thing is the device can be
uh configured to essentially act as like pass through and give
you the real IP address and not be the firewall.
So if you know what you're doing, you can then get your real IP address internally,
so you can run a server or whatever, right?
But by default, if you don't know what you're doing it, basically,
here's this device you plug it in and you anything you
plug into it to get internet access is protected by it.
And I think that sort of model is maybe, you know, we need to make it safe by default.
You know, like
the uh for example, like the airbag in the passenger seat is
uh well, it's a little complicated now.
They have like weight sensors and stuff, but fundamentally the, the,
the the airbag for the passenger seat and the
driver side is on unless you explicitly disable it.
Right. And you might want to, you know,
for whatever reason,
-- you know, you're like a very small person or something.
-- So you're not wrong.
Ok.
But this is,
oh,
this is such a weird and terrible problem because now
what you've described puts the onus on the device owners
or I'm sorry, the device creators.
But here's the second part of that.
So let's say we get rid of default passwords and we make sure it's not net or,
or whatever other thing
we decide is important
that takes care of part of the problem.
But there's still going to be terrible security
flaws in this stuff and it needs updates.
So now we have the situation and this is actually I,
I wrote a blog post about this over the weekend
of the law of truly large numbers is gonna start to kick
in because when we're talking about millions to billions of IOT devices,
every crazy thing you can imagine happens. So if you need to update,
say 2 million IOT devices,
which is not an unreasonable number by any sense of the word
2 million devices.
And I think it's safe to say there's gonna be a,
a number of them that just won't install the update for some reason,
which means you're gonna be talking about probably tens to
hundreds of thousands of unable or un updated devices.
Well,
and the really ugly thing to remember too
is a lot of these manufacturers are actually
have very
strong incentives and reasons to not provide updates because here's the thing,
you sell them 2 million devices in the field
and you do a software update that even bricks say one in 1000
you're gonna have 2000 very angry customers because you know,
this isn't like a PC where you can just simply stick a USB key in and reload easily.
You know,
um I have
network devices like my nest smoke alarm and my, my uh bathroom scale.
I don't know that they even have like AJ TE port.
So if I was sufficiently motivated, I could like get into it with a whole bunch of,
you know,
hardware and tooling.
And
of
course, no,
-- no reasonable human being is going to ever do that
-- if part of,
if you're expecting customers to own J tag equipment,
no,
you just failed and product design,
you know, and, and so part of my thinking is, you know, should we maybe
have SD cards on these things.
So, you know, you can at least swap out the SD card, put a new one in.
But, you know, again that introduces say 50 cents of cost, which, you know,
when you're making 2 million devices, adding 50 cents to the device cost,
that's literally a million dollars in profit. You've just burned.
Well, and not only that, most of these devices are so cheap
that 50 cents is actually
that's a real percent of the margin
and, and I think
you bring up a good point. There is, these devices are so cheap. I think
it's inevitable that we see the situation where we will have
sort of, you know, it's companies like Foxconn, right?
Nobody's ever really heard of Foxconn until the whole Apple thing.
And, and they do over, what is it? The last number I heard was over $50 billion a year
in hardware essentially
like they are just massive and you know,
like this Chinese company that makes these digital video recorders like at scale
and then sells them on to 40 or 50 companies in bulk.
You know, I'm assuming they're minimum orders.
Like how many shipping containers worth do you want?
And um
you know,
and, and so the problem is we,
we kind of get the situation where you have one device maker that, you know,
accidentally puts asbestos in all the devices and it costs us, you know,
billions of dollars to clean up.
Yeah, that's,
that's a good point. But, but additionally, so today,
I mean, let's even, let's even go as ridiculous as saying,
let's say someone is shipping an IOT device today that literally has asbestos in it,
which of course is, is ridiculous and
probably
that
famous last word.
But let's assume that's happening,
let's say that's happening
and, and let's say people find out
what would they even do next?
You know, I don't know,
-- I
-- don't, I can't think of it. I don't know.
I mean, you can, there could be some level of product recalls and whatnot,
but when you're dealing with
something that costs,
right. The Nexus seven things that keep catching fire.
And
that's the Samsung Galaxy
s
which are the Sung
and illegal to bring on an airplane.
You know?
How do you do that?
You know, like, because a lot of people are going to be like, whatever,
I'll just turn it off and stick it in my luggage,
right? Because there's
no federal offense.
Yeah. Well, and you know, so is there's,
there's a lot of things that are a federal offense that people do all the time.
But anyway, so
the problem is too,
is getting people to take this seriously when chances are realistically,
they're not going to
see their device causing the harm. You know, like
the D DNS thing is a great example because actually in taking down D DNS, like
a lot of sites and things fell over.
Like, what was really fascinating to me was to see Twitter degrade,
you know, I was, I keep Twitter open in a web page
and then at one point suddenly all the images disappeared.
That gleefully Twitter worked perfectly fine for me all day.
I couldn't have been happier.
Yeah.
So it Twitter started degrading. It didn't fail, but it degraded.
And then for example,
github, you know, just failed because their DNS went walk about and,
you know, I was trying to check in some code and it
couldn't find it.
Um But what was interesting to me is I actually had
to send out an email to some other people saying,
you know, there's,
and the email literally said there's a massive
denial of service attack against Din DNS D
DNS is a DNS provider for a whole bunch of stuff.
So basically, if you're seeing wonky network stuff and things are failing,
don't worry, it'll probably start working later
and,
and, and,
and, you know, and literally, like the one lady came back to me, he was like, oh, yeah,
our, our accounting is down, right?
They use an external, like a cloud based accounting system for, you know,
expense reports and stuff these people I deal with and, and it's like, yeah,
it's down and I'm like, ok, well, you know, hopefully it'll be back up
because that's all I have to offer. Right. I can't fix this,
you know, like I,
-- what am I supposed to do?
-- Right.
You know what terrifies me about that as well though?
Is, is you can say things like maybe it'll come back sometime today, but also,
like this botnet
is still out there.
Thet didn't get shut down, it just stopped beating up. Din.
Horrifying.
Yeah.
No, it's,
you know, and
what really gets me is imagine if they do something actually, you know,
nasty with it, like, say,
like, like
there's
some sort of major election coming up, for example,
or, or, or a holiday season where, where consumers spend vast quantities of money,
maybe even on one day,
a Friday,
for example.
Yeah.
No, it's, I mean, this is what really gets me about this whole cyber war thing is we,
we literally have
no strong idea of who did this and even if we had conclusive proof of who did this.
I mean, what are we going to do?
Well, the source code is on github,
like we can spin up a botnet by the end of the day.
-- So,
-- yeah.
No, this is, uh, it's, I mean, the good news is fundamentally with a lot of d do
stuff. It's actually not super easy to monetize.
Um, typically from what I've seen,
the best bets are like gambling sites and things like that, you know, where they,
you know,
will take you down an hour before the Super Bowl
and you're going to lose $10 million in betting.
So pay us, you know, $100,000 to go away. Kind of like the ransomware situation.
You know, we just, we'll make it way cheaper to, to not deal with us,
you know, the D DNS attack.
Yeah, it was horrendously inconvenient but fundamentally, you know,
nobody I don't think died
as far as I know.
Uh, I bet. Well, you got to think like github
is the center of a lot of organizations source code.
Now, I bet a lot of money was lost in productivity
because of the, the down day.
Yeah. Yeah.
-- No, I mean, yeah, probably a lot of people around the world lost a few
-- hours.
Conversely because Rne and Twitter were down.
I bet productivity was significantly up for another group of people.
-- Yeah.
-- So,
yeah, I mean, it's, and it's back to that death by 1000 million little paper cuts.
You know, it's like
if everybody gets one or two spams a day, it's annoying but we can all live with it.
But, you know,
you are stealing a few seconds from everybody globally and that
adds up to thousands of man years every day being,
you know, taken away
by this garbage.
Well,
so here's the other thing I keep coming back to when I think about this and I,
I don't have an answer
is
the way we do things today
essentially flawn to the point that we don't even
know where to start to ask the right questions
because this stuff, these things happening, like we, we make up analogies,
pollution cars, whatever,
but none of it really fits.
There's aspects of it that fit but the rules are changing. So fundamentally,
we don't know how to understand this problem even, which is just like my,
my head explodes.
I think we can learn a lot from food safety and
drug safety because they have similar sort of senses of scale,
right?
You have like a company making a drug
that a million or 10 million people use.
Here's the thing and you're not wrong.
And again, we, we come back to flawed analogies, but here's the thing
and this is true of safety and, and all of that is,
do you know how we got those regulations and those rules? We killed a ton of people.
And so
the thing that horrifies me is
it is quite possible we will not take this seriously until a ton of people die
because of this stuff, which is just,
-- I, I can't,
-- I think that's
human nature. Like, look at air safety,
you know, uh, what was that? The canyon craft
where
a
passenger jet was flying near the Grand Canyon?
I think it was
and it hit another plane,
right. They were both. It used to be
-- looking at the canyon.
-- Well, exactly.
It used to be common if you're flying by the Grand Canyon,
apparently for your pilot to be like, hey, let's go.
You know, I'm going to give you the scenic tour
and that led to, I believe it was, you know, the positive control where,
like everybody flying in the air has to be like talking to, you know,
traffic control.
So we know where the heck you are and what you're doing.
So you don't fly into each other
and it, you know,
there's been numerous air disasters from which
we've then investigated and learned things.
But,
ok, ok, let's,
let's go with that. Right.
We just had
a major disaster on the internet.
Right.
I don't know that it was a big enough disaster
-- for people to take notice and
-- that's the thing.
Nobody's learned anything that I can tell.
I mean,
there've been a whole bunch of clever tweets and
maybe a handful of articles and even some,
some lame podcasters may be talking about it.
But
outside of that I've yet to see any change of any sort to anything because of it,
they make some infrastructure things.
But other than those guys who's made any sort of change to what they do.
Yeah,
I mean, one thing that would help is if every single ISP on the planet blocked,
you know, spoofed packets.
So
when you do an attack, it could at least be traced back
to the actual device doing the attacking quickly,
you know, things like that.
-- But
-- it's not even that simple with UDP though Kurt, because
UDP
has the ability to send legitimate packets
that can then be used for amplification attacks.
But at least in this case, we could track more to the point,
you could track them down and block them, right.
You know, if theoretically speaking,
if every single internet service provider endpoint
blocked spoofing,
you could at least then as D DNS block stuff more upstream,
you know, you could block these attacks.
Whereas if it's being spoofed from 10 million IP S,
you can't really block 10 million IP addresses easily,
especially when they're spoofing stuff from legitimate users.
-- Right.
-- Well, and, and the funny thing there actually is, is somebody this morning
asked me, hey, is there a list of all the IP S used in the botnet that I could block?
There were 10 million IP S you can't
like no firewall on the planet can actually handle
that large of a blacklist.
And in fact, so this guy pulled up his blacklist, which is extensive.
It took two minutes
to figure out he has 5000 IP S on a blacklist.
You think about that,
once we hit 10 million,
it would probably take hours to construct that list and load it into memory.
Yeah. The only, yeah, I mean, again, back to your large numbers.
Right. Right. Exactly.
You know, there's a big difference between 1000 rules and a million rules.
You know, I look at,
uh, like I'm, you know, we're, we're talking about, um,
on another part of my job, you know, about automation around the CV process because
right now the industry sort of officially
handles around 10,000 vulnerabilities a year.
You know, it's roughly ballpark, about 10,000 issues. Get a CV.
It's actually a bit less than that, but it's about that,
you know,
what happens when we officially start recognizing the fact that we have one or
2 million vulnerabilities here that we probably should deal with to some degree.
And it's probably worth saying that at 10,000. We're basically at capacity today.
I mean, I don't know any infosec people that are like, boy,
I sure wish I had more work to do.
There is boring over here.
Yeah. No, no. Uh, nobody in infosec
is unemployed. Really.
You know, you're not, you're not allowed to be.
Right. It's crazy, man.
So, yeah, I, this, this law of large numbers,
I suspect we're going to see situations sort of analogous
to the bad drugs and the bad food situation where
hopefully nobody gets killed
because that is a really, that is a real possibility, you know.
Um and hopefully we do see attacks that are
highly inconvenient but not, you know, fatal.
And, but even if we have like, let's say, for example, tomorrow
uh the US as an example, the Republicans and Democrats, the Senate, the Congress,
the president, the executive branch, the judicial branch all
stand up and say, you know what, this is a huge problem. We are going to fix it,
do
they
sign of the end time?
-- So
-- even if we had the political will and cooper
to like
pass whatever legislation is needed,
you know, what would we actually pass?
Well, I mean,
that's a great point actually and I've asked people this question before and I mean,
this is something for,
for you and,
and everyone else listening to really ponder is if I
gave you a billion dollars right now and said,
Kurt, go fix security,
what would you do with it. And my guess is you probably couldn't do anything useful.
Granted you could, I'm certain you could spend a billion dollars. Right.
Like, actually making a difference.
I'm skeptical anything significant could be done with that.
I think one of the few approaches that might work
would be to build some tools and frameworks that are,
they would not only have to be secure obviously,
but they would have to be free and so completely awesome
that people would choose to spend the time and effort switching from what
they have to using these new frameworks and tools to write secure applications
and you just fell into the trap. I see everyone fall into all the time of.
There is no easy answer to. This
was the
only
thing that
mixed it.
Yeah, I, and I'm not saying this would fix it,
but it might make it a little bit better and at least give us a chance.
But
realistically even that I don't think you would get more than, I don't know,
five or 10% at a,
I mean,
we already have languages that are much safer.
You know, we already have techniques and tools that are much safer
and by and large
people don't use them.
Yeah,
it's,
it's crazy man.
There's the, the II I hate saying there's no hope but like there's no hope,
you know,
we,
we still live in a world where the majority
of people don't have a backup of their data.
You don't even need security situations to result in data loss. Right?
People drop their laptops or
apparently people, like
people forget them in airports and taxis,
you know,
which is unclear to me how you would do that because it shouldn't be in the bag.
-- I don't know, you know, people put their phones through the wash
-- actually don't let,
I was at an airport the other day.
This was, this was actually, was, it was New Orleans.
I was at the New Orleans Airport and I walk in
and literally there's a phone plugged in on the floor
like to charge and there is nobody anywhere near it.
And the guy walks out of the bathroom and picks up his phone.
I'm like, what the heck is wrong? Like
I couldn't.
That's true.
I, I don't, I didn't say anything but I'm like, my, my brain couldn't accept this,
that a human being would like plug in their phone,
lay it on the ground and then walk away into a place you can't even
see it for some unknown period of time and come back and take it.
-- And I was like,
-- the
-- reality is
-- the majority of people are pretty honest.
You know, if you leave your bag, well,
don't leave your bag unattended in an airport anymore.
That's a bad idea.
But, you know, by and large you can, you know,
I,
I remember one time I went out in the morning
to my garage and I'd left my garage door open overnight
and everything was still there.
You know,
-- we live in a remarkably honest society in most
-- you don't know what's in your garage.
I bet someone could steal up to 10% of the crap in there. And you'd have no idea.
You'd
have a hard time getting it out.
Throw it over the pile of stuff. Right.
But
you're not
wrong,
you're not wrong. There's a lot of honest people, but on the internet
it doesn't matter how many honest people there are because it's so global,
it's like I could be dishonest
and I cannot affect your garage in Edmonton, Canada. Right?
But on the internet I can.
Yeah,
and that's the difference.
I don't know what it's going to take. But realistically, I think,
you know, even if for example, we got the mandate uh for I SPS to filter uh you know,
the the
is there even enough networking equipment available to fulfill that demand?
-- No
-- or even the know how man, it's,
this is, this is a tough problem and there isn't an easy solution.
And if you think, you know the answer, you are certainly wrong.
-- I think
-- to some degree
it's going to take a complete shift.
Like, like looking at, for example, uh car accidents, right?
Car accident or car sorry, not accidents, collisions kill, what is it?
30,000 people a year in the USA million
I think is it a million in India. It's some ridiculous number in India
and China, right? Like just hundreds of thousands. Um
And quite honestly, the solution to this is not driver training,
it's not making safer cars, it's just take the humans out of the loop.
End of story.
I
tend to
you
and that's where I often come back to is that automation
and things like artificial intelligence
and
rather than go on and on for the next hour about how automation will save us all,
why don't we just say thank you everyone for listening.
If you have thoughts or ideas on any of this by all means,
let us know because this is a really interesting topic and unfortunately,
I don't think it's the last time
this problem is going to come up.
I'm actually curious to see when they'll use their botnet next.
I mean, and for what, because it obviously works.
It, it certainly does. I'm, I don't, I don't even want to think about it.
So I guess until next time everybody,
uh, just keep huddling under your desk, weeping softly and
we'll see what kind of fun happens this week. Right.
Yeah,
I look
forward to it.
All right. Have a good one, Kurt.
-- You
-- too. Bye bye
bye.