Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Resor.
I'm very excited. We have Seth Larson here today.
Seth is the Security Development residence at the Python Software Foundation.
Seth. Welcome to the show, man.
Thanks for having me guys. Always excited to participate in Thought Crime.
I'm, I'm really excited.
It's funny, Seth was joking before we hit record that I think on the,
the wordpress episode, we jokingly said if you, you know,
if we talk about you on the show, you probably did something terrible.
And he's like, oh, I'm coming on the show.
It's like, then we realized if you're a guest on the show, you're probably fine.
But if you're not a guest on the show and we're talking about you,
you probably done screwed something up. But, all right.
-- Anyway, anyway, happy to get the invite.
-- Yeah.
Right. Right.
So, I mean, let's just start out,
tell us who you are and tell us about the Python Software Foundation.
Seth because like, there's so much cool stuff going on right now.
Yeah. So I'm, I'm Seth Larson.
Uh I do a lot of security stuff over at the, the PSF Python Software Foundation
uh previously and still currently uh maintain just tons of
open source projects in the Python space a lot around
security and networking and HTP and the web and all of that
and the Python Software Foundation, it's a US based nonprofit that is just all about
making the Python program language and ecosystem
packages around it just better and more accessible
and more international work for more people.
I mean, that's, that's just our mission
-- so
-- well in, in the the like Python, the language is under that umbrella, right?
Yeah. So we do like the trademark, the copyright.
A lot of the community hosting of infrastructure we
employ obviously me but other people too that uh
do a lot of stuff around Python uh trying to improve it and just make it better.
We run Python us which is the largest
-- gathering of Python programmers in the world. A lot of community based stuff.
-- Nice.
All right.
I want to start out with what I think is the
latest news to come out of the work you're doing,
but it might not be.
And that is you are using Sig Store to sign the Python releases now, right?
Yeah.
So that,
that's been the Six Store stuff has been happening for a while even before I joined.
But I think the big thing
that I'm working on right now is trying to
move away from
P GP
and I know some people say
GP GP GP interchangeable, you know,
trying to move away from it because it has,
I mean, I, I don't really like to comment on the
security aspects of things which might be surprising as the security developer.
Uh, I just think that
there's a huge ergonomic benefit.
Um, Python release managers have to do this stuff for seven years minimum.
Um, and so like asking them to protect and maintain long lived secure keys
crawl that time as a volunteer, like that's a huge ask compare that to cigar
where you're just like, oh, off signing in a few times like
it's night and day. So,
yeah.
Well, this is one thing like I've been using P GP and GP G for
25 years I think, and I've given up on it straight up
and this I think really speaks to, oh, you know,
if we can just all get the developers to floss, everything will be fine.
And like flossing is easy compared to using GP G
consistently in like making a key and protecting it.
But, but also backing it up, but also protecting the backups and blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah.
And
yeah, I have to, I think at this point, we have to accept that sort of a third party.
Just magically making stuff work is the way to go because like,
that's why Python works, right?
-- Like import food. Like I'm not smart enough to write
-- pandas Six
Store. The, the interesting part of six story is that
it externalizes
the operation to parties that are already doing that work
uh in all of the right ways, right?
Like running, if you're someone who's maintaining a secret key for PTP,
it's basically like every individual person running their own C A
and it's like that doesn't scale at the volunteer level.
Um So like, let's externalize
the operations costs where they are already being paid
and then do our little part
and then make sure everything's working.
Um
You know, because like these release managers already have to maintain a
secure access to those, to those identities to those accounts already.
And so they're already doing the part of the bargain that they should be doing
and let's externalize the rest.
Well, I mean,
this is why github won because it turns out
nobody actually wants to run their own kid infrastructure.
Ok. Ok. Hold on before we go on. I want Seth to tell us
what signing releases, why do we do it? And what does that mean?
-- Yeah.
-- So signing releases, it doesn't matter at all unless you're verifying them,
you know, that's no Ashley pause.
That is a very good point because we've had
a whole bunch of signing strategies going back 30 years
where like, oh we put, you know, like, uh uh the, the external as key signatures,
like, so we have a Tar ball and externals
signature, you get the key on a CD, blah, blah, blah.
And yeah, like nobody checks those. Right. So like, what's the point?
100%? No, no.
If you're creating,
if you're creating verification material and it's not being checked by anyone,
it's basically
point
right
there. There's an XK CD comic
that says how to verify a signed email.
If it's like if it has this at the top, it's probably signed
and it's like to begin P GP text
a
regular
expression. I hear.
OK. No, I mean, that's a good point though. So,
so let's pretend
everyone is checking the signatures. So why are we doing that?
-- So
-- I don't think
like,
obviously I would love to live in a
fantasy world where everyone checks every signature.
But that's not
like that's not, that's not real
reality, right? Like it's not
um I think that a really big part of what is interesting about
this verification
is like how it fits into
these downstream ecosystems that are
like in an automated way,
pulling source and building it and all of that,
like those are the ecosystems that are likely to be the biggest targets.
And so they're also likely to be the best places to actually do the verification.
And I think that they're also like the most
able to do the verification
uh because if they're able to kind of do that one time and then after that's done,
like it just automatically works, right?
Because if you have these release manager identities, they're valid
for seven years
and you only have to update it once every two years
to add like whoever the new release manager is, like, that's not that much of a,
of an additional cost to pay as someone who's doing this downstream.
And a lot of downstream verifier for like Linux distro,
they are already doing this with P GP.
And so like part of the work that I'm doing is trying to keep
verifiers involved in the deprecation of P GP, right?
Because we don't want them to just not have anything to do.
We don't want them to be flat footed, right?
We don't want them to feel like this is a surprise that is happening.
But there's um I like to call it like a Gordian knot of signers and verifiers, right?
Where if there's this existing method
that's out there in P GP,
no one wants to do work for, for no reason, especially volunteers.
I don't want to foist more work on the volunteers,
but there's like this other need of like we wanna move
to sig store because it's just better for us too.
And so it's like, how do you, how do you make this happen? Where
from a lot of perspectives P GP is the only
verification material that's being demanded that's being asked for.
But that's just because it's existed for so much longer.
Like we're not even close to like answering some of
these questions of like how does the Linux cro use
sig store verification material in their automation tooling.
And so like someone has to be first through the wall and
I think C Python has a pretty good spot
there. And
yeah, it's, it's, it's a really tough problem.
So just a quick thing because not all our viewers might know this.
But what exactly is C Python?
No,
no, because this is something when I, when I first saw,
when I first learned what C Python was versus, say J Python, it kind of blew my mind.
-- Yeah. So C
-- Python is, it is an implementation of the Python program language.
Uh It's the reference implementation. A lot of people call it.
Um And it's primarily
implemented, it's like 5050 Python and C
and uh yeah, it's,
it's kind of the one that like the PSF
maintains the Python steering council maintains a lot of times
it's, it's like the,
the one that most people are probably talking about when they say Python
is, it's likely C
Python.
Yeah, for sure. All right. I want to ask about Sig store one last thing.
So what does signing with Sig store mean? But let's say from a, a
release manager perspective as well as the I am the person downloading this Python.
-- What does it mean if it signed with a SIG store instead of P GP?
-- Yeah.
So when it's signed with Sig Store, the,
the interesting part about Sig store is that it uses
these extremely short lived keys, right?
From like a central certificate authority. That's like the special part.
The other special part is that it uses this technology called open ID connect,
which allows
third party identity providers. So like Google and github,
it allows them to participate in part of the process where you can bind
this like human readable identity.
So like Seth at python.org, the email address, that's a human readable identity.
It's not just this like
dump of hex characters, right?
-- That's like your public key uh finger press
-- that
has worked out so well for the crypto industry.
Yeah.
And so it takes this human readable identity
and then binds that to a certificate that then can be used to sign whatever you want.
So like a file, for example,
and then that signature and certificate are totally fine to be
just kind of like dumped because they expire almost instantly.
They're not valid past a certain
like time frame. I think it's like 1015 minutes or something.
And then after those like materials are available,
you can still verify because it's like a certificate with a signature, right?
You verify it just the normal way,
but then you're usually using the identity
that is bound within the original certificate. So you can say
did this come from Seth at
python.org?
And you don't have to know like what my P GP key is ahead of time.
You just need to know that that's the
person that you're interested in and release managers.
It's this really big public ceremony of like this will be
the release manager for this Python version and here's their identity
and it's so it's a lot easier as like a downstream verifier to be like, oh yeah,
Hugo is the,
is the release manager for Python 3.14.
That's something that's already known ahead of time as opposed to like,
oh here goes the release manager.
What is their key? But how am I gonna find that? How am I gonna keep that up to date?
Um
Yeah, it's just, it's just a lot more ergonomic. And I think that the nice
thing about
SAR that is not really captured with P GP at all
is that it lends itself a lot more cleanly to like workload identities,
so not just human identities.
So things like, oh this github
action workflow execution.
So anything that I like works with open ID, connect with
github, github
actions. Does
it lets you use those identities too?
So you can actually say like this release process in
C I was the one that signed this file,
not like a human.
And I think that's like the
long term end goal,
but we're not quite there yet. So we're, we're kind of doing this analog of
identity
-- matching to a release manager instead of to the to the actual workload. Nice,
-- nice.
Sorry, just to clarify.
So,
so you're essentially because I knew obviously people can use this to sign stuff.
But you're saying essentially there'll be the ability for say AC I CD job to run.
And that specific job would generate a certificate key, blah, blah, blah,
sign it. And then obviously, like you said, it's good for 1015 minutes. It goes away.
Obviously, it can't sign, well, if it does sign anything in the future,
it will be a huge red flag, it's expired key,
but essentially that that
action, not just that like workload,
but that specific action of that workload would have a specific unique signature.
And so, well,
I'm guessing then you could essentially have like a farm to fork model
of kind of where it traverses through different systems C I CD validation,
blah blah blah
and with sig store that would all be essentially that would work and be automated.
Whereas like I know with P GP,
what we do is we just shove a key in and use it to sign everything because
what else would we do? Right.
Yeah. No, it, so the identity in that,
in that certificate, in that signature would end up being like the repo
the workflow,
like how the definition of the workflow uh in addition to like the get
commit that ran and then it also includes like the run id as well.
So it's completely tied back to
the actual steps that ran to build that artifact and
provides providence I mean, the real end goal of like, why is this important
is that it makes our infrastructure less interesting to compromise. So like
if you're an attacker,
this happens.
Well,
II I believe php also, right?
They had an issue with their infrastructure that was
hosting those artifacts got compromised and injected with,
with stuff.
And like the whole point is like if you,
if you go to python.org/downloads and you just download some files
and there's like check sums on the page and they, oh look, they match out
like,
but that doesn't tell you that the infrastructure
that's hosting those files didn't get compromised.
It's like this is what's providing build provenance.
So it makes,
it's a much higher bar to have to clear
because then you have to like compromise or build infrastructure
or the source code or some account. But all of those are risks.
Now there's this other target.
You can just compromise python.org and then, and then the host files that way.
So it removes that from the table
and makes it slightly harder for Attackers to do that sort of thing.
Well, and I'm also guessing that there would be, you know,
logs of these certificates being issued,
which obviously should match up to somebody doing something.
Yeah, six store has two certificate logs. So
one for art. Yeah, I
I'm not as well versed on the like super deep technical side,
but I believe there's one for the
artifacts and then there's another one for, uh, maybe the C A itself or something.
So,
and, and it's public, right? Their transparency log is public. So it's
anyone can go poking into it to look for the things like set that
python.org has signed,
which is,
you know, I never thought about that, but with P GP,
like one of the benefits is you control and run it and own it and do it all yourself.
But also conversely, there's obviously no transparency or logging.
No, there just isn't right because like,
yeah.
Ok. Ok.
I want to stay on the provenance conversation because that was,
it will be a marvelous segue
is you've also been involved with creating S bombs for, for Python, which is I,
I feel like Python is living in the future.
We're all trying to get to sometimes, which is very cool.
-- I take that as a huge compliment. Thank
-- you.
You should like, you've done a ton of work and it's cool.
Yeah, so S bombs, I mean, we've been,
we've been publishing S bombs uh in the SPDX format since Python 3 12.2.
Um And they're just a part of our release process because
we release all of these different artifacts.
So we release source code, we release like prebuilt stuff for windows. We release
uh like stand alone binaries for windows.
Um And so like all of those different artifacts have different,
different dependencies that get pulled in different ways
that get compiled and so trying to provide
s bomb files for all the different things. So whatever you're using,
you have a, a nice authoritative s bomb that uh
that matches with the standards. I mean, the old standards.
So like just today, new standards dropped,
um I had already looked at the draft and like know what we need to do.
But um yeah, so like
I'll be upgrading to those new standards
hopefully soon
and then
can continue being Conformant.
-- I
-- I think you're glossing over some of the immense work.
This has been because I work for a company that has an S bomb scanner
and Python isn't the sort of thing.
You can just like point an S bomb scanner at and you know,
clap your hands and say we did it everyone.
Good job like this has been a ton of manual work and I know you've,
you've been heavily involved in it.
Yeah, it's, it has been a good amount of like discovery,
especially like going through, pouring through all of our
dependencies that we vendor pulling through all the
dependencies that we actually pull in externally,
going through the dependencies
of our sub dependencies. So like PIP is vendored alongside of C Python.
So then like traversing that to see what Pips dependencies are.
So, yeah, I think it's like,
I don't know if it's like 30 or 30 some
dependencies having all the metadata and trying
to make sure that there's identifiers.
So like
in the future, we, there's another dependency that we need to request AC pe for
because we want to be able to provide identifiers for all of our,
the projects that were
that
just in the ring?
Quick question. Can you tell us what Ac pe is?
Yeah. So ac pe there,
there's a centralized database of software identifiers um that's managed by
uh I don't exactly know.
N
I was gonna say that was gonna be my guess, but I wasn't,
I want to be authoritative here.
Um Yeah, so Nist manages the CP dictionary
and it's basically this list of software identifiers
that get attached to CD E records.
And so it's kind of this like magic
in between
linkage between like an actual software project and a version and whatever to
whether that's actually affected by
a given vulnerability,
-- it's not magic. They're the worst things ever.
-- Yeah, it's I personally,
so the full acronym is common product enumeration. And
yeah, I mean, the frustrating thing for me is it was invented what,
like 25 years ago at the beginning of CV?
And it,
yes,
-- I the world has changed.
-- It has and C pe has the C pe people
stuck with it. The C pe people know it has tons of problems.
But OK, but there's another piece to this sp,
there's another piece to this s bomb story though with Python.
And that is that C Python
turns C into Binaries and
it is really hard to like,
automatically identify c things that are then built into a binary.
But how you've done it, how did you do it?
Well, we did it by just knowing, knowing the source code,
knowing the projects ahead of time, right?
Like we,
we're in this lucky position that we are by being the suppliers
of the source code also know like what goes into the,
into the, the project itself.
Well, you say that, but I like, literally,
I'm not going to name names,
but I've worked for companies where we ship software and like,
people went spelunking into what was into it and
found things like MP3 is being embedded in from
maybe and stuff and like, we actually didn't know what was in there specifically.
And like,
I think the whole log for Jay thing, the fact that the world had to spend, you know,
the better part of 12 months scrambling and panicking to see.
Like, do, do we have log for Jay in here?
Like, I don't know, you know, people have like grip
strings and like all like there was like 40 different detection methods.
Yeah, like a lot of people aren't there yet.
So I, I would not take that for granted.
That's no, like that's, that's a level of maturity that
I think everybody should have, but clearly we don't.
Yeah. And actually so the, the next thing that I kind of speaking on
eons, the next thing that I kind of want to work on
is
how do we solve the esper
problem for Python packages generally?
-- Yeah.
-- Yeah,
I was wondering about that because I just had the experience,
I didn't realize this but I, um, I have a, a mac laptop with brew installed as one does
and I, um, obviously installed Python 312 to get a specific version of something
and did, uh, you know, pip three install.
Anthropic to get the Anthropic clawed A I client
and it failed to run because I did not have rust installed. And I was like,
what the f and it turns out I need to install rust so that it can build that package.
And I'm like, oh boy, well, whatever YOLO
and like
my Python now pulls in rust so I can run my Anthropic thing.
Although it's cool that they're using rust for their Python module.
I, I don't want to think about it too much because it hurts my head.
But yeah, I mean, that's, this is not an uncommon occurrence for this to be a,
like, I have no idea where all this stuff is coming from.
Yeah, Python
Python is a, it's, it's, it's a glue language really.
I mean, like it is a huge glue language, especially in between, like,
providing a nice API or a nice way to use like low level C libraries
or A I models or like just any binary thing that you want to do.
With the Python, like it works really well.
Um But that also has like knock on effects, right?
Especially from a security perspective, you just were talking about
compiled binaries, right?
Um
So how do you create an S bomb for those things where you have tons of
code that is not Python that doesn't play by Python's
rules that's not described accurately by Python packaging metadata.
How do you describe, how do you tell a machine what that means
uh accurately and how can maintainers,
how can people that are maintaining these projects, like be a part of that process?
Because right now there's like no avenue, there's no way
even if they wanted to tell you what was in the project, there's no way for them to,
to help in that way.
Um Because a lot of the work that I actually do is like
standards work. So like
figuring out how we're going to do these things,
figuring out how these systems are gonna plug together.
Um I think that that's like the most impactful
use of my time because it's things that will
be useful for quite a long time to lots of people and it just feels like problems that
-- like full time staffing is, is especially equipped to tackle.
-- Yes. Ok.
Uh Let's, let's talk about Python packages
to accurately set the stage for the insanity here.
So Python packages can contain Python
or binaries
and sometimes the binaries were built by someone else
and sometimes they get built on your system,
right?
-- Yeah.
-- So like sometimes if you're
all,
I
was just like,
y
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. So um basically there's this format called a wheel
and a wheel essentially is just,
it's just like a zip file that you extract
on your machine and that is the installation process,
right?
-- Like I,
-- so I just, I love how everything
eventually devolves into like
uh Microsoft Word file. No, it's actually a zip file.
-- Like everything is ultimately a zip
-- file. It's all zips
and XML.
Yeah. So it's a zip file that you just extract onto your machine.
And so the implication of that. And so that's great for like
because it's not running code, it means that you can actually like audit it, right?
So you know what it's going to do.
So that is a good property.
And the other good property is that as long
as there is a wheel available for your platform,
like your CPU architecture, all that, whatever that matrix of,
of different variables.
As long as there's a wheel available,
it means that you can install it super easily, really quickly and you know,
it's going to work
and like it should work and it usually doesn't.
And so like because Python has this,
I would say user base of people that are trying to solve problems that involve code,
but like they don't really care about the code.
So like scientists,
you know, right. Like
journalists,
there's tons of people that use Python that like if they didn't need to use Python,
they totally wouldn't because they're trying to get a different problem done,
right?
And so because installation of these really,
really powerful tools is so easy through the wheel format,
they are highly demanded,
right? Like if a project
is published and there's no wheels available for common architectures.
That's a big problem
for, for that project, They're likely to get requests to, hey, can we,
can we get a wheel file available for this platform?
Whatever.
-- I'm
-- just thinking,
I don't think I've actually ever used something that I basically can't pip import.
Like I think there was one time, way back in the day,
I manually downloaded some Python source code, but we're talking like Slackware
days.
I don't think I've done that in 20 years.
Yeah.
There's lots of wheels available for these days and
the tooling around it has gotten so much better.
It's,
it's really, really good
for sure.
So I, I'll point out to you Kurt,
like I keep telling you to use poetry for your Python project.
Poetry can actually import a Git repo,
but I don't want to, I want to use Python or PP
because
there's, it's just a, you know, stuff works.
I don't wanna,
-- you know, that's it. I just Python works. That's what I wanted to do.
-- That's fair.
They'll force it on you someday. It's coming.
But
OK, I I want to kind of bring this whole conversation, you know, into home now.
Now Seth and I think you have an important story to tell in
that you are a full time employee of a foundation doing security work.
And I know there's been a ton of information.
I mean, Kurt and I have talked about it like tide lift, talks about it all the time.
You've got the open ssf talking about it
about basically just pay the freaking maintainers essentially, right? Where
there's this whole,
I feel like a couple of years ago, the attitude was like,
oh open source developers love working for free.
They don't need money,
you know, they are getting exposure
and I think that Tide is starting to turn.
But you,
like you have real experience here because you're actually doing the work and,
and I would love to just hear your kind of stories and anecdotes and, and thoughts
on
actually being full time employee to work on open source
and you have so much progress to show for it,
I think.
Yeah, I mean, one of the
one of the personal goals for this role is like
just proving that you can, how much you can do
with full time staffing, right? Especially full time staffing that is
for the most part, like pretty unrestricted, right?
Like I obviously,
I have to work on security related things where Python like I have a whole
mission to uphold,
but it wasn't like,
oh you need to do these like three things and then like then your contract is over.
It's more of like a hey,
we want security to happen. We know all these standards are happening.
We know like that open source is going to need
to change that things are going to have to happen.
And we want you to go out there and figure
out what those things are and be as useful as possible
in those places. And so it's like super
self directed and
I, I love that,
that Alpha Omega has trusted the PSF and me with all of that, right?
I
I think the really interesting thing is that
like there are just so many problems out there
that full time staffing are,
is like almost necessary to get it done in the timelines that we need, right?
Like I have a theory which is a essentially we've solved all
the easy problems and we have a lot of hard problems now that
like even just to understand the problem is probably going to take
tens of hours of constructing a mental model and finding out stuff.
And
that's not something that
you can do in your spare time easily or if you do it's going to take six months.
And I don't think Python has six months or 10 years to get this fixed.
No, that's the thing. Like we don't
like open source, took 25 years to kind of get where it is.
And, well,
except now the world depends on it and we can't take another 25 years to get it.
Right. Like, we have a couple of years. No, it's like, what is it? Like?
Those numbers are 80 to 95% of everything is open source now.
Yeah.
Right.
Like, I,
I can WSL to install and then the name of
a Linux distribution on my Windows box like it.
Yeah.
Right. Yeah, I, I think the other side of it is like
there is
so much, like, because open source has one has dominated, right? And
security is so important right now, all of these regulations happening,
I think that a
really big part of my role is like trying to make it
so that the work that needs to happen to get those regulations implemented
easy
so that all of these projects can kind of go on with their
lives or keep doing for the most part what they're doing today.
Um And be able to say that like they're complying, right? Like that
is a huge goal for me. Um
Just because like, I don't want,
I don't want all of these regulations which I think are, you know,
mostly a really good thing
to kind of crush the flame of open source. Right? And
as if it's like, it's already a hard job, it's already a hard, like thing to do.
So I don't want it to, like, just get harder and So by
having all this like full time staffing, being able to provide that time to
fix those problems ahead of time ahead of like, you know,
when everything comes into full effect,
I think providing as much help there is, is a really big part of my role as well. So
yeah, that's why I'm focusing on like
bombs and lots of policy work,
lots of people work making systems actually fit together.
So
-- and,
-- and what are the regulations? I suspect I know what you're talking about, but
we, we won't go into the details,
but at least we'll let people Google some names later.
Yeah, so it's the Cyber resilience Act,
the CR A
and also the Secure Software development framework, the SSDF from the US and,
and there's, there's a few other
regulations that are coming into effect
two that are formulating some various stages,
but those are the two big ones that are on our radar right now.
Yeah.
And yeah, there's going to be a ton more of that show up in the next couple of years.
For sure, for sure. I feel like you have set us all up
for understanding
that
paying someone to do what is functionally the we'll say boring important work.
And I think that's an important part of this is there are many things
I will not do in my free time but I will do for pay,
right?
And I think like s bombs are a really good example of that is if you go to an
art developer and you're like, oh, you should make s
bombs, they're going to be like, I don't want to because
why would they? Right. You know, as you're some SBO
weirdo
which you know, I am but
II I get it.
So I'm curious on your thoughts and suggestions for companies or,
or other foundations or kind of
anyone looking to
maybe somehow fund or hire like full time open source
developers to do the kind of things you're doing now.
Like, what, what, what went well, what maybe hasn't gone well along your path.
Yeah, I think that
the biggest thing that's gone well, has been,
I'm just gonna say getting paid is a
sorry,
I was maybe assuming that, that,
that, that was a part of the question.
-- No, the big,
-- I
mean, and feed my family everyone.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Beside besides being paid full time to do open source, I mean, like that's the dream,
right.
Um
Yeah, it's, it's been, it's been a lovely time. I mean, I, I've been enjoying it.
Uh, no, I, I think that the biggest thing that Alpha Omega got right,
uh, with this role and with a lot of the roles that they do, it's not just that the PSF is
not,
not restricting
the staffing, not making it this, like,
ok, you're going to do exactly this,
it's going because
the thing about security and the thing about
the Real World
is that things change.
Yes, priorities change.
And if we're just going to be doing the exact same thing every single day,
it's not necessarily going to end up with that result that we want,
especially if this is supposed to be like a long term engagement.
And so I think the best thing that they got right was like putting
a lot of trust in
the PSF in the foundation that's actually going to be, you know,
hiring the staffing.
And so if you're doing that, like,
if you're trying to bring on a maintainer or if you're trying to, you know,
hire someone to do open source part time
or you're trying to contribute to a foundation
to do this sort of like foundational boring work
that is really important,
trying to
make sure that it's not
like caveat
or
like we want this list of things to happen, like,
obviously come to the conversation with things that you'd
love to see because it starts the conversation,
right?
But be open to
the person that you end up hiring or the foundation that you're working with,
like, having a different set of priorities than you.
So,
yeah, that's
good.
I think, no,
I think that's important because that's one thing
I really respected at Red Hat is like,
there's one person on the Red Hat product security
team whose primary email address is at debian.org,
right? Like it's,
and well, no, like a lot of companies if you told them that they'd be like, the what?
Like, no, we can't hire what? This makes no sense. Right.
Why is he, why are we paying him to work for Debian?
And I've seen that happen with, you know, these enterprises where it's like
they, you know, oh, we'll give you 10% time. Well, no, that's not enough.
That's still kind of a hobby. It needs to be full time. And then also, well,
they'll do some of what you want but they won't, you know, they might find,
they might,
the foundation says, hey, no,
this other thing we need to do is way more important than your corporate need.
And I feel like a lot of companies
are gonna,
I think it might be difficult for them to
understand that because they're just not used to this.
Right. They're to quote Thomas PP,
I am not your supplier and they're used to dealing with suppliers who can,
you know, do this or else I don't pay
and I don't know that that's going to work very well here.
Yeah. It, it's really tough to,
I guess, I don't know how else to phrase, like, just the ego part of it, right?
Where it's like the, like owning the work, having your brand on the work. Like, I,
I think that there has to be some trust that the person that's doing the work
is going to talk about you as a sponsor in a very positive light and that,
that's going to reflect, it doesn't necessarily have to,
you know,
be this top to bottom ownership for it to
be this huge positive thing for your organization.
Well, and I think some of the organizations forget too that, like
internally at the CS A,
we end up with a developer maintaining an authentication library because
while we were using it, it had to work and it,
-- that was vastly cheaper than trying to rip and replace
-- it.
All right, I think we've come to the end Seth.
I will give you the last word, your bit of you can,
you can tell the audience whatever you like for this part,
pay the maintainers. I don't know, it works, it works. I promise like II,
I spend all day just proving that point and
it would be really, really great to see more of this happening.
I think it would make this huge improvement in the open source ecosystem.
It solves so many problems. And I think that the problem is a lot smaller
than people like to think. Like, how many staffing do we need?
I don't have the exact number, but I think it's,
I think you can do a lot with a little when it comes to staffing.
I was gonna say it's also, it's uh
in my experience,
a lot of open source projects have like a
core nucleus of one or two or maybe three people
which in the grand scheme of things is not a lot of people that's not even a bus load,
you know,
but you can put them all on a motorcycle
if they balance
and that's one thing I've consistently seen.
So I, I think maybe part of the messaging also would help with these.
I I can't help but wonder if these companies think about these open
source projects in staff in terms of what they do internally with like,
oh, we need 50 people to write this accounting subsystem
to have meetings and stuff versus you know, open source. You have
two core people and like 100 volunteers.
Yeah, open source has this like incredible multiplicative effect, right?
Like the work that happens
at these low like mid stack and in applications and everything,
it it really does have a huge impact even just having
one, you know,
one full time staff on a project can completely change the trajectory
of that project in terms of what it can get done,
for sure,
for sure. All right, I'm, I'm calling it.
Uh I'm gonna put a link in the show notes to like Seth
has a very nice website that has his blog and some contact details.
His blog is marvelous.
You've been traveling all over the place, giving talks about this stuff,
which is amazing.
They're all linked in his blog. So, so go watch him. But yeah, Seth.
-- Thank you so much, man. This has been a lovely chat
-- Thank you so much for having me.
Well, I'm sure we'll have you back at some point.
Like just keep doing awesome work, man.
Alright, so thank you Seth. Thank you.
Thank you for listening. Go to
social security podcast.com. Find all of the show notes for today.
Well, it's probably just one show note. But um
and then
he
found us this podcast,
hashtag I Mastodon Seth and Kurt have marvelous rest of your days.
-- Thanks,
-- everybody. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.