Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 145 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
So, do you have any terrible math problems for me? With 145?
Nope,
good.
Still can't do math. I actually, it was funny.
My, my son asked me for math help yesterday and I was like, super overcomplicated.
He's like dad, the answer is right here like, oh, ok.
Anyway,
it's like, yeah, so 12 year old schooling me in math now. So that's neat.
But I'll just, I'll, I'll, I'll give him a calculus challenge one of these days.
Right. And that'll be his lesson. But
anyway, anyway,
so
fire,
what do you think of when I say fire, Kurt?
Uh my first thought is, I hope my smoke alarms are all working,
that's actually related. So, here's the discussion of the day
down the street from my house,
a building burnt down the other day and like, I mean, like it burned down. Right.
This isn't like, oh, there's a charred building.
No, there is a pile of rubble where a building used to be,
which is obviously like as crazy as it gets for fire. But it,
it really got me thinking about the topic of fire
and the topic of security
and kind of, here's the broad observation I made and,
and we can discuss this and you can disagree with me all you want. But like
when, when a fire happens, fundamentally,
there are a number of things that go into motion and
people generally know what to do without too much trouble.
And I don't just mean, like the bystanders, I mean,
the fire department and there's fire inspectors and
there's insurance companies and all kinds of stuff.
And I think about security
and let's say there's some sort of security emergency.
What do you do? Does anybody know what to do? Is there anyone you can call for help?
Is there any way to clean up the mess afterwards? That makes sense.
And I think the answer is basically no to all of those things.
I'd say it's worse than that because what
even is a security disaster or security problem?
Right. There's,
you know, there's, have I been pwned? There's, um, Citrix
being compromised for six months. There's
-- that, that's a good story. You know, fire, I don't want to say fire is simple but
-- it is,
it is
when I say fire where it's relatively simple to define it as something on fire.
Yes. And, and that's fair.
And so let's, let's box this in because you're right when we talk about security,
security doesn't really mean anything.
It, it's a million things but let's think about just a, a compromise of your network.
Right. Where essentially something has happened.
Catastrophic.
What now?
Well, it doesn't even have to be catastrophic. Right.
Like, for example, you might notice,
oh, all the servers are, you know, there's,
there's people logging in from IP S in a
whatever country it is that we're not friends with today
and we don't have offices over there.
But, but I think just for the simplicity's sake, let's assume,
like you've been hacked as bad as you can get hacked.
Right. Like it's all burnt down.
There's a pile of rubble that you used to call the server room.
What do you do now?
Well, you, you start rebuilding,
you know, you try and get clean hardware or clean the hardware that you have,
you try and restore everything and
nine times out of 10, when you read about people doing that, it's,
it's a complete mess because to put it bluntly,
if they were capable of running it
reasonably well, they wouldn't have gotten into that situation. Maybe.
I mean, it's hard to say
-- part of
-- it
is Survivor bias in the sense of
the people who get kind of really hacked the worst.
You know, they probably don't have great backups.
-- It's possible
-- they probably don't have, you know,
inventories of what they actually have and need.
Oh, this is actually, you,
you've got me thinking about a new thing that I hadn't even considered before.
You're kind of. Right.
Yeah.
In terms of, if you don't have good backups and, and let's say so, in,
in the building that burnt down down the street, for me, it was a very old building.
It was over 100 years old. So obviously
it lacked some of the modern,
we'll say fire prevention measures they put in
where they build buildings in certain ways.
-- Yeah,
-- it's definitely not up to fire code.
Right.
Like now they, you know,
they section things off and there's like fire doors and they make sure like
the fire can't get in the walls and fly up into the attic,
which I'm sure happened and, and they put sprinklers in.
Right? And they have smoke alarms up the
wazoo in these places and, and thank goodness, nobody got hurt,
which is one of the reasons I'm really happy to talk about this because obviously,
if there'd been loss of life, it would be a very, very different story.
But, but the point is
when you have that kind of legacy infrastructure,
when something goes wrong,
the building is probably going to burn down,
like you're not going to burn a little bit and recover, it's probably gone.
You know what? No, actually most building fires are contained and it's
not that big a deal.
Like locally we've, there's been, you know, and we talked about this in the past,
there was that in, um,
there was one case of arson where a
framer burned down some buildings he was working on
because he did subpar work and he thought he could hide it by burning it all down.
And there's been a couple of days, remember we discussed with the,
the potted plants that aren't actually in dirt anymore.
They're in that like dry peat moss stuff that
up a cigarette out in it and it,
while your condo burns down.
But the like the majority of fires typically don't result
in a con like a complete loss of the structure.
Like a great example here is we have a,
100 plus year old hotel in the sort of historical white Ave district of Edmonton
and they're doing some renovations on it. Was it a plumber or something
or a grinder?
I think it was a grinder basically, you know, started a small fire,
they thought they put it out with a fire extinguisher.
And then like 1012 hours later, the fire department was called out because it,
you know, the building was burning down a bit.
And I feel really bad because actually I was out with my partner and we went to dinner
and, uh, she and I were walking past that place and we,
we were smelling this wonderful wood smoke smell and we were wondering,
you know,
was it Cortizon or was it like which of
the restaurants was using some really nice smelling wood to
smoke meat and this was half an hour before the
fire department showed up to put this fire out.
So,
and, and, but that's the thing. As soon as somebody noticed
smoke and flames, they call the fire department,
the fire department shows up pretty clear what you
do if you're the fire department out of fire.
Right. You go put it out. So they did.
So, there's a bit of damage to the building. But
yeah, the, the developer, it's, it's in the process of being renovated.
He's like, yeah, this sucks. But yeah, we'll just, we'll carry on, we'll fix it.
And you look at the majority of fires now, especially North America and Europe.
That's generally what happens, like, yeah,
it burns down a little bit and there's usually a ton of smoke and water damage,
but it's not like the building is gone typically.
Like, that's actually relatively rare
and, and that's fair. I admit I didn't look into that statistic, but
so here's
what I want to do
is let's go back in time
and they look at the way fire,
I guess prevention used to work because the history
here is actually fascinating in a lot of ways.
And I think there's some parallels and there's probably some lessons for us.
Now, first of all, I will say
the research I did kind of started off in Ancient Rome.
I, I didn't find anything that went back farther. I don't know.
I'm sure there's something you could go back
well past or before Rome, I guess.
But
that's where I landed. Right. And so Rome burned more than once.
And
obviously we look at a lot of the ancient world and we're like, oh,
look at all these beautiful stone buildings.
They don't build them like that anymore.
And, yeah, that's because all the wood ones burnt down or fell down. Right.
So, there were wooden structures a long time ago.
And it sounds like from pretty much ancient Roman times until like the 18
hundreds, maybe
it was basically you were on your own. There was no fire department.
There was no, like government help for the most part.
If a building lit on fire, it was your problem.
And it turns out that what happened, I guess is in a lot of these
kind of cultures and neighborhoods from way back in the day.
Like, if your neighbor's house started on fire,
people would show up and, like,
tear down your neighbor's house to keep it away from yours or if there
was a house between your neighbors and yours who that was on fire,
they tear down the house in the middle to keep your house safe.
Like it was, it was completely barbaric and, and bizarre to think about.
-- Well,
-- but what else are you going to do? Right. They didn't have water pumps.
They didn't have water supplies, like, you know,
throwing buckets of water at this thing, you know,
and I know that's still the case for a lot of rural fires. Right.
The fire department shows up,
they maybe have X hundreds or thousands of gallons of water in their, uh,
in their truck.
And so at that point, you know, it's containment
or saving the farmhouse or whatever. Right.
Because you, well, you classic, you got to pick your battles,
you know,
and there's been cases where they've let
buildings burn down locally because they're just way
too dangerous to go in and fight the fire and it's just not worth it.
Um, like there was a chemical plant fire here and the fire horns like, yep. Stay back.
-- Right. Yeah,
-- that's what we're doing.
And, and so this is, I mean,
this is one of the many things we can talk about is the fact that today
the fire departments have,
they, they have well defined procedures of what to do when there's a fire,
obviously get the people out is basically number one, right?
Save lives.
And then after that,
for example, like, I know with Notre Dame,
uh getting stuff out they could save was kind of like number two.
Right. Let's get the, the art out and the relics and all that kind of stuff.
And then let's worry about the structure itself and
it's, I mean, this old building that burnt down,
it was obviously the people all got out and then the fire department, they,
they said they wouldn't even go in because it was, they,
they knew it was coming down and they basically just started spraying water
on the next building over to make sure it didn't fall down.
Which is
like, so let's think about this in the context of security. Right?
Today, is there any procedure if you think something is going wrong? Right.
Basically.
-- No, it's kind of crazy town like
-- literally, you know,
some of the best I've seen is you turn it off and start doing forensics on it.
But that,
you know, if there's
the false alarm cost of that kind of activity is very high.
Yeah, like we just start turning servers off and calling in forensics teams.
Uh, a couple 100 bucks an hour.
Yeah, that's going to
some yelling at the board level. Probably pretty quick.
You're gonna be,
you're gonna be looking for a new job probably by the end of one or two of those,
you know, because the boy who cried wolf is not a popular person.
It's true. It's true.
But anyway, anyway, so kind of resetting back to the, the good old days of your
is, I feel like that's kind of where we're at today in a lot of security.
And
it's similar, we have the private companies, you know,
you can buy your own private insurance, your own private, you can,
you can pay security companies that will monitor your
network and your computers and if there's a problem,
supposedly, but you know, the, the, the
problem is sometimes they get hacked. You know, there was a recent one in Europe
where this high end provider got hacked.
So, you know, well, that, that's not working out so well, maybe.
And, and they're basically kind of doing the same thing, which is, you know,
if you're paying us, we'll try and take care of you.
But,
you know, if we notice somebody else's house on fire, well,
they're not a paying customer so it's their problem.
But
it's,
so that's something that happened in, in like Victorian England
is there were fire departments you could hire
and you kind of like it.
I, I would say put a sticker in your window, but goodness,
no stickers didn't exist back.
They actually would have grass plaques.
I know
in America
you would get a brass plaque that would
be on your building saying you're protected by
whichever fire company.
Yep. Yep. And then
if your building started on fire, you'd obviously call them up and say, you know,
come, come help and they, they'd show up and do something.
Only if you're a customer. If you were a customer, they just stand
-- there and watch it burn down.
-- And I know this happened in Ancient Rome.
But what would happen at a fire is
they would show up and they'd offer to buy your building
that
heavily
discounted price,
right? And you know, you either get some money or no money and you know, as
obviously as time goes on that number got small quick because they want to, you know,
get in there and knock the player down.
Um,
but then, you know,
we figured out that the negative externalities of fire are pretty bad and we,
we organized it a bit better
and I think that's part of the problem with computer security is the, the,
the negative externalities
these companies largely get away with. Like, I mean, have I been pwned?
-- Has how many records? Seven?
-- Oh, my goodness.
The number, it's, it's, it's higher than that. I guarantee it.
It's, it's ridiculous
as of this 7.8 million billion, sorry, 7.8 billion
pound accounts.
Huh? I figured it was way more than that. Which don't get me wrong. That's still a lot.
Right. I mean,
how many people are on the planet? 9 billion?
And, and granted,
I know many people have multiple entries in there,
but still we're talking about a probably double digit portion of the population.
Yeah.
So that's the problem. Right.
I'm looking at this list of companies here listed as far as I know,
none of them have actually been dinged hard for, uh, for ending up there.
Uh, no. And I don't think they will and, and that's an aspect of this.
I don't think we can necessarily correlate very well and I'm,
I'm comfortable kind of ignoring it.
So, anyway, let, let's fast forward a little bit in time. Right.
So you ended up in, in, like I said, kind of Victorian England where you had like,
fire departments you would pay and they would do their thing.
And then eventually
you got kind of government funded fire departments, right,
where they would kind of show up and, and work on people's property,
doing whatever they could
to deal with the fires.
And of course, I, I imagine part of this was the technology as well just because
kind of prior to having, you know, a pump and a hose,
what you literally couldn't do anything. Right. There was very minimal.
Well, you not only need a pump and a hose, you need a water source.
Right. Right. But you got to figure most,
most cities have a river or something
nearby to most places.
Do me a favor.
-- Go transport one cubic meter of water a kilometer without using your car.
-- No,
in that case, totally not. I mean, I'll agree with you there.
If, if there isn't a water source within a couple 100 ft, you're in trouble.
My parents' cabin doesn't have running water and hauling
up enough water just for two days of like,
you know, washcloth, washing and drinking and cooking
is such a royal pain.
Yeah, I would,
I would drive a well because I guarantee that it is totally worth whatever it costs
guaranteed.
And so, you know, we,
we not even running and drinkable water but just even running water,
like because you don't need drinkable water to put out a fire, obviously,
but just running water and putting out a fire, like you need quite a bit of water.
It's ridiculous. So, in fact, this is, this is another thing
is
the, the building down the street for me.
Uh, it started on fire in the middle of the night and they had it out by morning.
It was smoking. Right.
And they came back for three days to spray water on it
because it just like they were obviously concerned there was going to be a flare up.
And then on like the fourth day we got a huge storm.
And so I'm, I'm assuming that put everything out.
But yeah, like that was, that was crazy to think about too is just
the fact that
like, like containing this was incredibly difficult.
And again, this, this made me think of computer security again where,
how many times have you heard of instances where people
thought they had the Attackers kicked out of the network?
And then it's like, oh, no, sure, didn't.
You know,
you forgot about that workstation way over there on the other side of the room
or that printer or that wireless access point or
those accounts that still exist and have bad passwords.
And see that's, and that's part of the problem.
I think that would be actually a good parallel is that
with computer security kind of incidents,
-- there's lots of embers waiting to flare up.
-- Yep. Yep. There are,
and worse than that, there's still the sort of the fuel load,
there's still all those creaky systems that aren't well maintained and managed.
Yep. Yep.
To catch fire basically.
Right.
And now I think this again is a place where
fire is easier because you'll generally have heat and smoke.
Of course, you know, in the, in the context of, of computer security. Yeah.
Well, not always because, I mean, there's been some crazy, like, I,
I remember last summer there was,
for example, somebody,
their house almost burned down the fire started on their deck and,
you know what it was?
It was a cardboard box full of oily rigs that auto ignited
just out in the sun.
Yeah, apparently that's possible. I would not have guessed that.
Like, straight up a guy was working in his garage,
you know? And so, like,
it's similar to that and that, you know,
there's so many things where just these computer systems can be.
Well, let me put it this way. How many of us have met,
you know, good penetration testers that have never failed.
Uh, I don't, I think bad penetration testers never fail
blake,
but, I mean, good penetration testers always get in.
Yeah. Right. Guaranteed,
guaranteed.
Even bad ones usually get in, we'll say. Right.
Yeah. So,
no, I mean, and that's like, that's actually something I'm currently doing,
you know, I've been doing an, it inventory,
uh,
partly to get rid of some old systems that just don't have the capabilities we want,
but also to get rid of some old systems.
Right. Right. And that's a great idea.
I mean, that's like removing the oily rags of your network. Right.
Put them outside on the deck. It'll be fine.
Put them in the neighbor's yard. Right. It'll be ok.
That's right. That's
right.
You know, so, I'm trying to get rid of, you know,
I'm trying to get rid of problems before they become a problem.
But fundamentally,
you know, it, it's tough because it's, it's a lot of different aspects.
It's, it's kind of like forest fires. Right. You got to do forest management
and even if you do forest management, you're still going to have forest fires.
Yep. Yep. That's right.
And, and like, again,
these are things we've had thousands of years of
experience with and they're still hard to get.
Right.
And I would even argue it's,
it's probably magnitudes less difficult and complex than a lot of computing today,
which I mean,
is, it, is what it is. Right.
So, ok, so, anyway, I want to fast forward a little bit now to, we say more modern
age with fire right
now. First of all, in, in nearly every building today.
Well, I, I think in every building you're supposed to have smoke detectors. Right.
Everywhere you are
smoking.
Right. Right.
Which, in fact, I don't know if carbon monoxide, I think you only need those in
areas.
I know.
Well, I, here they generally recommend that you put a carbon monoxide detector,
you know, in your basement with your furnace and stuff
because that's the thing that's most likely to cause carbon monoxide.
Well, in your water heater, if it's gas
powered water heater. So,
so actually I have a funny story about that is I had my house wired with the, like,
smoke alarms that are all interconnected
-- and no, they're awesome. I love them.
-- Oh, no, I know. I love them too until they go off.
Yeah. Yes, that is true.
But it's, it's cool.
Uh, I tell, I tell the electrician, I said,
I want you to put one of the carbon monoxide ones right above the furnace.
He's like, well, you don't legally have to do that.
And I looked, and I'm like, I don't care
what
the attitude is that right? Like,
if there is a fire or carbon monoxide problem,
there is probably an 80% chance it's going to occur within 5 ft of this thing.
-- Like, put it there.
-- Like, I have cheap smoke alarms all over my house
and I have two high end nest smoke alarms, one by the furnace and one in the kitchen.
Right. Yeah. Exactly. Exactly.
Because like, that's where all the fire is in my house.
Yep. Yep. Although I will say the downfall.
Yeah, you said about the, the, when they're all linked together.
Yeah. When we, when we burn something in the oven.
Uh,
yeah,
the whole house is crazy and you basically just have to
exit the house for the most part because it's so loud,
you can't go anywhere in the house without hurting your ears.
Which, but again,
that's a feature in all seriousness. And that's an example of
if they go off too often,
you get your alarm fatigue and I'm going to be inclined
to disable them and that obviously completely defeats the purpose.
So,
in fairness though, smoke alarms are quite
reliable nowadays, like, yeah, they'll go off, you burn stuff in the kitchen and,
and feed smoke into them.
But that's like what they're supposed to do.
So
stop burning dinner, I guess.
I haven't done it in a while, but I,
I will also say it's generally my fault when it happens.
I won't blame anyone else. It's, it's totally me.
Um, but anyway, ok, so we got, you know, kind of that, that's part of the detection,
right, of having things like smoke alarms.
And obviously my assumption is in the fire down the street for me,
everyone probably got out because of smoke alarms.
I, I would be shocked if that isn't the reason everyone exited the building safely.
And also
what I've noticed is with, with
alarms going off, especially in sort of, if it's a place that, you know,
people tend to kind of either know that they have to
leave or know where to go check for an actual fire,
like your house or your place of work.
Right.
Or they'll leave or, you know, schools are pretty good about mandatory evacuation.
But what I've really noticed in places where
it's a transient space. So a great example is the mall.
We were at the mall one day and the,
and the fire alarms going off and we're just like, well,
nobody's running and the security guard doesn't look worried and
the, the fire alarm seems to be coming from this store over here.
So, ok, I guess we keep shopping.
Right. And same thing I've noticed in hotels,
you know where in a hotel, like,
yeah, good luck getting people to evacuate a hotel at two in the morning.
-- It's like I'm gonna just put another pillow on my ear.
-- I have no doubt.
II, I can't even imagine. All right. So, anyway, anyway, uh, right.
We've got our detection
kind of aspect.
But what I would say is once people hear somebody screaming and shouting fire,
guess what they do?
Well,
so,
so, so let's move on. This is
-- a
-- computer security. What do people do when they say we've been hacked?
-- Uh
-- Right. And that, so that's exactly the question is
if, if there's a fire,
the fire department shows up and you
have trained professionals that are basically from
a, a non
private entity. Right? These are essentially public servants,
they show up, they assess the situation and then they take whatever action they deem
is appropriate. And sometimes it's save the building next to it.
Sometimes it's saved the people in the building. Sometimes it's put out the fire.
You know,
there's a million things that can happen
and like these people are insanely trained.
My neighbor is actually one of the fire chiefs, which is, I also,
I get a lot of dirt on what's going on in the city, which is fun too.
But like this guy,
I've talked to him at length about kind of
what they do and how they train and everything.
And the,
like this guy has been in the industry for probably 40 years
and he's still constantly taking training every year all the time.
There's so much he needs to do.
And I just keep thinking, we, we don't, I mean,
even if you wanted to take yearly training, is there yearly training?
You know what I mean? It's
lack
of
professionalism.
Yeah.
Well, we, we, we definitely lack a formalized version of it.
Um And this, you know, this is obviously something the CS A is working on, you know,
like top 10 threats, for example, or,
you know,
new strategies around software defined perimeter and zero trust network,
you know, new technologies, new techniques that you can use.
Um And obviously this is,
this is actually entirely what I'm working on with the open C PE stuff is,
you know,
allowing people to measure sort of more nontraditional
training so that they can show like,
look, I, I do care.
And I,
you know, for example,
I take the Sans Holiday capture the flag challenge every year and I complete it to,
you know, keep my
like to keep
in practice and
learning new techniques. And so,
and, and that's one of the things I'm I'm trying to do is to create, you know,
it's kind of a chicken and egg problem is
a lot of places offer actually pretty decent training courses and stuff. But
as a whole industry do we have like really good stuff? Not as much as we need.
Why?
Well, because it's really hard to measure and,
and claim in a way that allows you to then leverage it and like
up your game and, you know, have a, have a better job or, or make more money at your job.
So
there's,
well, there's very few incentives to put that work in.
Um And so not a lot of people do, like, a lot of people do, like,
you look at the open source world or, you know, like,
you know, the guy running have I been ped or,
you know, Tavis Ormandy who's been worryingly quiet in the last few months.
Um,
you know, but like they,
there are clearly people who are working very hard to improve
the industry and to not only improve themselves but to make it
possible for other people to improve themselves.
Right? Ok. And and you actually just hit on the thing I was trying to go to next is
yes, we have people who are phenomenal in their own special way. But
the, the, if you look at the history of firefighting,
they have a way to transfer the knowledge into the
future where every time there is something that goes wrong,
they can learn lessons and make changes.
We can't do that today.
We have very smart people that they're,
they're an island of knowledge and transferring that knowledge out is I'm
not going to say it's even possible because it may not be,
I don't know.
But the point is we lack that ability to empower the next generation in front of us.
Right. We're all kind of mired in the same pit.
Yeah. The number of people I see making the same mistakes. It's like,
yeah, that's the thing we discovered 20 years ago.
Right. Right. Exactly.
And then we,
we forgot about it because it kind of went away for a while.
Right. And I don't,
that's one, I don't know if we can necessarily fix it. It is.
Although it's also possible, uh, you know,
200 years ago there were people fighting fires that were like, oh,
I can't teach someone how to do this.
It's too special.
I don't know about that. But it's, this is one of the problems that
we have to solve that because
if we can't look at what happened,
learn lessons and make sure we don't make the same mistakes again.
I, I, all you're gonna do is keep going around and around and around.
Well, see there's a, there's a good comment you make learning from our mistakes.
So how many places do post post mortems?
Let alone how many places do post mortems on a somewhat regular basis?
Like when they don't need to like beyond, oh, something horrible happened now,
we have to do a postmortem because the lawyers are, you know, asking us to.
And so actually one thing on my team at the CS A,
we are making it a habit of doing regular post mortems, both success,
failure and just
as a regular occurrence so that we get better at
-- it.
-- I would bet you most places do postmortems.
But I would also argue we, we aren't learning the lessons we need to.
But even more importantly
is if you do a post mortem at the CS A,
I have no idea what lessons you learned,
right? Whereas
firefighting, this is information is
on
my
team where we're actually building stuff.
And so some of it we will share externally, but some of it's internal to us, like
for example, um we discovered that we should have
essentially made um some decisions differently or more early, right?
And so we're, we're now we're a bit less afraid of making these called shots
because we are actually capable of failing fast, you know,
and actually recovering from, ok.
If we make the wrong decision, we can actually fix this.
Um as far as the post mortems and
uh letting others learn from it. One of my plans is to then
formalize this postmortem process and, you know,
write an entry about it and publish it,
you know, which forces me to make it more real and more structured, right? And,
and, you know, it's like, well,
I guess Docker currently is the one that's kind of the, the whipping boy for,
you know,
they had that incident where a quote non-financial database was breached.
And I'm like, I've never heard that phrase before. That makes me very nervous.
And Docker has been horrible
on communicating what all has happened. Whereas there's been other places with
like, yeah, we got breached and like, here's the, you know, like cloud flare,
they write up of the thing Tavis Ormandy found is really
good.
You've led me
right into where I wanted to kind of end up on this whole conversation
is so the building that burned down down the street for me, it was a total loss
and they figure it's about $8 million worth of damage.
Right. Yeah, that's, that's rough. Definitely. That's,
but anyway.
Right. Yeah, exactly.
So, anyway, because it is such a high amount, it's a high dollar amount of loss.
They,
they're bringing in the state fire inspector to kind of do the work and
write up the report and that I'm thinking also like first of all,
we don't have professionals to bring in to help deal with
the situation and then help us with a post mortem.
But more importantly is like in this case,
the professionals even have a more professional group,
they can call upon for even more help because they're like we can't do this.
We need someone bigger than us,
right? Like that, my my brain exploded. I thought this is amazing.
Like, just think about that.
If you had say three levels of people, you could ask for help for,
because the problem was so big
that you knew you couldn't deal with it.
-- Well, and
-- also so like with air crashes,
the problem is so it's really important to understand these problems
and make sure they don't happen again and again and again.
-- Same thing. Exactly. Exactly. The same
-- thing.
Yeah, I don't know. I, I
think,
and I can't help but think one of the challenges
is that the industry is constantly changing so much.
So,
for example, the CS A, as far as I know, we have three pieces of on premises equipment,
we have three offices that have a wireless access point.
And then I think also one or two of them have a printer
and that is the extent of our on premise networking,
right? So the problems I face from a security perspective are
100% different
than,
well, actually the majority of the industry, you know,
it's funny because I keep having people approach me and try and sell me stuff
-- and it's like I, I don't have a network or servers.
-- Ok. So
I thought of this too actually.
Is you, you brought up? Exactly. One of the things I was thinking about in my brain a
couple of days ago is that you could say, oh, but
my network is special or my infrastructure is special or whatever.
But here's the thing
is
when the fire department shows up,
they have no idea what they're going to be dealing with. Right.
-- What is the building made of, what is inside of it?
-- That's not true.
Uh For example, if,
if there's something especially dangerous that should be listed,
you know, there's, there's registries of places that have chemicals and have
these dangerous materials. You know, they have the warning signs up.
Well, and that's incredibly dangerous.
But I'm just saying from the perspective of you show up at a building,
how many rooms are there?
How many people are there? What's it made of? Right.
There's, there's all these unknowns the fire department already has
and like these guys are trained
to assess the situation very, very quickly.
And in fact, this is part of their training is
kind of, there's,
they show up and one of the first things they do is they'll like
go cut holes in places and they'll basically do as much as they can
to make it easier for them to understand what's happening, right?
Like that's step one,
then they figure out what's going on and then they deal with it, right?
Like that's,
that's huge, man.
For example, reading the uh to talk about like an it fire, you know,
the Equifax hack where they had that really nice 80 or 90
page congressional report on it which I read and made notes on
one thing, for example,
is they had a scanner on the system to
scan the software that should have caught the software
except they didn't, like, enable a recursive flake.
So the software was sitting in a directory
that didn't get scanned.
And so again, I,
I hate to harp on this but how many places
don't even know inventory wise what their it is.
And that's assuming just on premises. Right. That's just assuming on premises.
Exactly. The answer
is all of them.
Um,
you know,
and then there's also shadow it and there's all these other things
that can happen where you just don't know what's going on.
And so again, I think part of the challenge is,
is at least with the physical world we have some bounding and some constraints,
you know.
Um, and that's not always well, and, and, but it can,
even in a building fire situation,
it can get complicated like the fire can be
inside the walls or somewhere that's not as visible.
But,
yeah, like you said, the fire department has,
well, they've encountered this before.
So they punch holes in the walls and, like, stick their nose in and see what's there.
Exactly.
And so
with it, I think about, like, how many places
let me put it this way if I gave you
a
$10 million to go audit, like, and not audit from security point of view,
but audit from like, what exists point of view?
A fortune 100 company.
How confident would you be that you could get more than 99% of all the stuff they have?
Uh I'd be impressed if I got 50% of it. That
price.
Right.
Yeah. And that includes a generous allotment for booze at the end of every day.
Right?
For both bribes and sorrow.
That's right.
No, I mean, I don't disagree with you.
I think there's a certain amount of complexity, but I also feel like
this is part of the challenge is how do we start unpacking
a lot of this and how do we make it a science?
Because
I feel like security isn't a science. Security is like it's chicken bones and dice.
We're not even at cargo cult stages yet.
Like we don't even know what outcome we want by and large.
I, I won't disagree with that and, and so I don't know, I just,
I keep thinking about this and
here's how I'm going to end this without my not, you know,
obviously it sounds dire at the moment,
but
I feel like this is probably growing pains of every industry.
Now, I'm gonna hope it doesn't take us 2000 years
to get there because that would be bad.
But I think this is part of the challenge and now
I think the kind of call to action for everybody is our
jobs aren't really security in a lot of instances.
It's, it's, let's build the science of security. Right. How do we,
how do we make all this reproducible and how do we
make it so we can transfer knowledge to the next generation?
-- Those are the things we really need to do.
-- Well, not even reproducible.
How do we start measuring this?
How do we know what works? Doesn't work?
How do we know what skills we apply are, are valuable, you know,
and that's what I'm working on, you know, trying to figure that out.
No, I, I agree. I agree completely.
I think,
I think those are really important things and those
honestly are more important to the industry than,
than building the next new technology because even
if you build the next new technology,
if we can't transfer analogy, we don't know what we're doing it, it doesn't matter.
Well, we're just doomed,
recreate the, the mistakes of the past.
That too. Let's, let's invent another firewall. We'll call it something new.
Uh All right. Anyway, I'm calling it, man. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. You can go to open social security podcast.com.
Hit up. I don't think we have any show notes today, but we'll see.
I might, I might come up with some during the editing and you can e pound to
as podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media. Kurt.
-- Have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks.
-- Bye bye.