Hello and welcome to the open source Security podcast episode 10
9876. We have pre ignition
43210. Blast off
with myself, Kurtz Fried and my partner in thought crime, Josh Preser,
-- it was
-- inconsistent.
So obviously I would hope at this point everyone has guessed that space
is going to be on the list of things to talk about.
Now,
I want to say one interesting thing that most people don't know which surprises me.
Maybe, but maybe I'm just a weirdo
the area code for the area in Florida where NASA is located is 321.
So how cool is that
it?
Yeah, it is cool. So ok, right now when Kurt and I are recording this,
we are 50 years
into 50 years ago, I should say right now.
-- Apollo 13, I have
-- to interrupt, I have to interrupt.
There's an area code for the International Space Station phone.
It's Oh
no, it's in Houston. No, they cheated. It's just a Houston phone number.
That'd be epic.
I'm sad now,
never mind you can cut that hair.
No, I'm leaving that in.
-- That's because I
-- was
-- like,
-- because I literally Googled, like area code for space.
-- And I'm like, oh, there's one. No, there isn't.
-- It, it should be like star, star Star.
But anyway,
that's anyway,
as, as Kurt and I are speaking, if, if we were playing out Apollo 1350 years ago,
it is
currently up in space right now and I believe it just exploded a little while ago.
So it is
an extremely interesting topic and something we were talking about and I said,
you know, we should talk about just,
we'll kind of put some focus on security in space,
but just space in general is a fun topic and I'm sick of terrible topics.
-- So fun. It is a space.
-- We're finally starting to make some progress again,
you know, with Elon Musk and spacex and, um, and blue origin, like,
like they're finally because, you know what always got me was the space shuttle,
like, visually, I loved how it looked,
but once you start to learn about it,
like it was just, well, number one, it was an industrial train wreck,
like literally, like the, the failure rate was horrific.
-- You know, two of them blew up,
-- one blew up, the other one
burnt up.
Ok. Fair.
And so then,
like the thing was designed to be like a
space pickup truck with a short turnaround time,
which, like in theory, cool.
Yeah, you like, have your vehicle with the engines, you know, you fuel it up,
go to space, come back, fuel it up, go to space, come back.
The only problem is the turnaround time was like, what, two years or something
stupid. I don't know if it was two years. It was really bad though.
Well, they had to like, take every tile off, inspect it, glue them back.
Probably the easy part compared to.
So, actually,
it's funny you mentioned that the space shuttle wasn't even on
my list of things to really talk about in that context.
But
so when I was in college,
my, I think it was my senior year of college,
a
professor came in who worked at NASA prior
to coming to teach at the university I attended
and he actually, one day he was like, would anyone like to hear about NASA?
And we're all like, yeah, we want to hear about NASA.
-- Does he ever get told? No, I would
-- hope not.
But anyway,
so he held like these nighttime symposiums to talk about kind of everything.
And, and
the one thing I took away from all of
his crazy stories because there were some crazy ones.
But the one thing I didn't, I didn't I never thought about was
and this guy, he was so he was a mechanical engineer, which first of all,
I'd be like mechanical engineer at NASA.
What sense does that make?
But obviously, there's mechanical things inside the space shuttle and,
and the one thing I never realized, so
let's say you worked on a valve for the rocket engine, right?
So, obviously when you're constructing a rocket engine,
you have to test the crap out of this stuff.
Yeah, I mean, the vibrations alone
ignoring that part of it. Just like testing it. Right.
So, let's say you built a rocket, a valve designed for 1000 opens and close, right.
So you test it. How many times do you test it? Let's say you test it 100 times,
-- half a
-- million
maybe. But, but the point as you're, as you're,
as you're putting it together, right?
Because like you test the valve valve works,
you put the valve in the rocket engine test.
The valve valve still works, you know what I mean?
And so they, people never considered this with the space shuttle,
but because there were so many pieces and it was supposed to be reusable.
Well, just through testing
because you kept testing and testing and testing as you constructed this thing,
like you end up testing something like 100 times more than you expected.
And so it would literally fail before like the,
the freaking space shuttle even left the planet.
I remember reading a World War Two book. It was a like
a,
like a diary of um a tank uh
commander.
And basically the problem was they had was all the tank
maintenance schedules were designed for tanks that were being used.
So things like tightening the track bolts and stuff.
So when they
were like using the tanks for training.
They kept breaking stuff because they would over tighten things. Right.
Because you, like, tighten all the track bolts every week or two or whatever.
Which, yeah, if you're like, driving around in the tank they get loose.
But if you're not driving the tank around,
you keep tightening a bolt and eventually it goes ping.
So, yeah. No, that's, that's a good point.
Just those pictures of the space shuttle like opened up in, you know,
the bay where they're like refurbishing.
-- It basically like like how many parts did that
-- thing? The number was in the millions.
It's completely nuts and obviously part of their planning had to include failure
because humans are on this vehicle.
So you want to make sure it has, you know, a quadruple redundancy in some instances.
Well, and Cold Lake Air Force Base.
-- No, Nanaimo, the one just north of Edmonton was a return base.
-- Did it ever land there?
No, no, no, but they built, they built Nanaimo for B 52 S. Ok.
-- So the runway was very long.
-- So this is something else I learned from my professor is.
So
when the space shuttle was launched,
they had all these contingency plans about
if, if this happens, then do this, if this happens and do this.
And this is something actually in Apollo 13, the movie which is a marvelous movie,
by the way, if you haven't seen it,
like just stop listening to us right now and go watch it because you won't regret it.
But
in, in that movie they show like, oh,
we have to figure out how to do all these things to, to help the astronauts and,
and this guy was like,
NASA actually had a lot of that figured out
because they have these ridiculous number of contingency plans.
But anyway,
-- so with the space shuttle,
-- well, you don't like,
one thing that always gets me is when you actually have like a crisis with
like an airline would be the closest thing to a
space shuttle that actually is like a normal thing,
right?
The amount of time you have to deal with
the crisis before you're dead is like minutes.
-- Exactly.
-- And, and I'm assuming in rockets it's even worse, shorter.
It very well could be.
And so, right, so obviously the space shuttle,
when it's when it's launching into space and when it's going to come down,
they had all these different is it could land
in case of emergency.
And so when the Challenger space shuttle was the first space shuttle that
was lost and that was the one that had the O ring incident.
And there's, there's amazing case studies that were done on this and again,
like go educate yourself because it's phenomenal
in terms of ethics and just engineering.
It's amazing what happens is,
right,
the space shuttle Challenger goes up and there's a problem
and NASA immediately knows what's going to happen next?
It was what was going to happen next was if,
if a shuttle came out of the other end of this thing intact from the explosion,
because they knew the solid rocket boosters were obviously what exploded.
And if a shuttle with a fuel tank had come out of that,
the contingency plan was the space shuttle would fly across the ocean to Spain
while dumping fuel the whole while because obviously it's going to have a problem.
They would have set the air speed record across the Atlantic Ocean. Well,
right, I mean, unsurprisingly
and then it would have attempted to land in
like as soon as the explosion happened, like they knew what happened next.
It's phenomenal the way these people train for emergencies.
The problem is it's not just training for emergencies,
but it's having it's being given the time and the space to figure
it out in advance because how often have us security people gone?
Well, you know, I have some concerns that I'd like to talk about.
They're like, no, no, no, we've got to get this into production.
-- Yeah, I mean, that happens all the time
-- and it's like, well, but I'd like to, you know,
can we step back for a moment and like, just make sure example,
my favorite one is always, can we make sure that the data is backed up if nothing else?
So if this thing fails, we can recover it and they're like, no,
we'll deal with that later and of course,
-- that doesn't always turn out well
-- or I see us
planning for ridiculous events that are never going to happen.
-- Well,
-- or they're so improbable or so, you know,
just the return on investment for the risk profile is, yeah, that's,
that's a tough one.
Well, and this is a discussion I want to have with you on another show.
-- Is that whole Miter attack profile thing?
-- Yeah. Miter Attack is cool.
But that's another story.
So, actually return on investment, I think is a good transition.
Especially just sticking with the space theme.
Do you think Voyager One and two have any
sort of authentication on their radio communications at all?
Well, no, because they go back to the old timey computer security protocol of,
there's a mainframe with a terminal in a locked room.
-- You can't get into the locked room,
-- ignoring the
locked room.
No,
but what I'm saying is that's the same thing in the past.
Oh,
you have a radio big enough to talk to Voyager one. Well, then
either you're NASA or maybe you're the Russians.
-- I don't
-- even know if the Russians have a radio that can talk to Voyager one anymore.
I mean, yeah,
there's literally what a dozen satellite dishes on the planet
that can talk to it and NASA owns them all.
Well, yeah, exactly.
So, actually one of the fun stories I read years and years ago that,
that helps me kind of process.
All this space insecurity idea
is when the NASA astronauts
were going to the moon in the Apollo mission,
all of their radio communications were in the clear.
So Ham radio operators were able to pick this up if they knew where you're tuned to.
I remember like even today, you can still, you know,
all air traffic control is in the clear.
You know,
there's still a ton of police and fire and medical departments that are in the
clear because they can't afford fancy new encrypted radios and more of the point.
The minute you go to fancy encrypted radios,
you end up with problems like September 11th where the
departments couldn't talk to each other. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. So, yeah, you get communications security.
-- But then, oh, wait, we can't talk to anybody else.
-- It
-- definitely
-- can create a mess.
And, but anyway,
what I think is really cool is so the ham radio operators
were able to pick up the NASA astronaut communications and in fact,
there's, there's a new story,
I'll try to dig it up and put it in the show notes where this,
I think a person was in Kentucky and basically they were listening to Buzz Aldrin
and Neil Armstrong talked to each other on the moon
because he was able to pick up their radio signals.
But, but at the same time, if you were doing that, you were supposed to basically,
like, clear it with NASA saying, I'm listening to the Astro
which is like,
OK, why, like, what's the purpose of this?
-- You're literally blanketing the planet
-- some bureaucrat somewhere
probably.
And of course, you know,
the Russians were
listening in on all this as well.
And actually this is one of the things I forget I
was reading somebody discussing like all the moon landing conspiracy stuff.
And they said
the single biggest reason to believe the moon
landing happened is because if they faked it,
the Russians would have made an enormous deal about it because it
was very embarrassing to them that they didn't get there first.
I, you know, I've worked for the government and I've said in many episodes in the
asked, like, governments are terrible
seats.
Like, have you heard of this guy called Snowden?
Yeah. Right. Right.
You know, like, and I love how,
you know how Snowden got a lot of his
-- access to stuff he wasn't supposed to have
-- just the
for, was it SharePoint or something?
He asked other people for their
good
job. That's it. When I heard that I'm like, oh, yeah, that makes sense.
I don't, you know, did he hack this thing?
No, no, he just asked people for their passwords so he could get his job done.
That's it. Sorry,
I buy that. I don't know.
I, I'm kind of glad, like, because, you know,
we had the space race in the sixties because
we wanted to basically prove to the Russians,
but we could put something in orbit and land it
in a specific spot and that thing could be,
you know, full of humans or full of uranium.
It goes
bang.
Right.
You know, and then,
and then basically the space race kind of just satellites were big, you know,
weather prediction, communication satellites and all that was good.
But then it just sort of fizzled out for a long time.
-- So
-- actually, I have another funny story, I can tell you about satellites.
So I it was when the Apollo 11 astronauts were going to land in
the ocean because obviously back then the spacecraft splashed down in the ocean,
which was the US s way of solving this.
There was a top secret,
I think it was a CIA satellite that basically knew
there was a tropical storm converging on the area,
the astronauts were supposed to land and obviously back then, like,
no one even knew the United States could do this.
The idea of a spy satellite didn't exist.
Oh, I remember how, like how secret the whole keyhole satellite system was, right.
And so anyway, they basically had to, they told NASA they're like,
you need to figure out a way to move the landing
site without anyone realizing why we're moving the landing site,
right?
Because obviously they don't want the astronauts to get hurt
and you don't want the Russians to know like, oh, hey,
we can spy on everything you're doing and it was just,
I think about the madness of all of this and like
you watch these spy movies and stuff and like it was,
it was the real deal back then, man, it's just, it's madness what they did.
Well,
you know, the whole thing was like over flights so that you can verify, you know,
various military things or my favorite always is that, that USB
yard, you know, where all those planes are parked out in the desert
and then they leave them parked out in the desert for
weeks or months and some of them are like strategic stockpile
and some of them are there for destruction.
And so when,
then what they do is they like have this giant crane with like a metal sheet,
like a guillotine that they drop and like chop these big planes up into big chunks and
then they leave that out for like weeks or months so that the Russian satellites can,
you know, validate.
Yeah, there's
like there was a plane there and now there's like chunks of a plane there,
you know, and then they clean it up later so that, you know,
the Russians can validate that this stuff was destroyed, you know,
from the Salt Treaty or from whatever treaties in the past, you know,
I was also reading this.
How do you put like a seismograph in Russia that is like tamper proof?
They cannot mess with it.
And so they have these seismographs to detect, you know,
underground nuclear testing, right.
And so they like,
encase these things in concrete and they have more seismographs around them
and like radios to call for help all sorts of crazy stuff.
So the Russians can
-- out and like, do a nuclear test and like, put it back in the ground or whatever.
-- Ok.
Anyway, anyway, space, we're talking about space.
So,
so I have another
interesting kind of thing I've been thinking about
in the context of security and space.
It is not well known, but when Apollo 11 landed, Neil Armstrong had to pilot the ship.
And that wasn't technically the plan.
Initially, they obviously had a landing computer.
I wasn't aware of those, the pods, like once they were in, in return mode,
I thought it was just ballistic, like just a brick with some pa
when it was landing on the moon.
Actually, I have another story about that though too. But anyway,
he basically had to like joystick it down because things weren't working, right?
Because obviously this was all just like hodgepodge hardware that they like,
you know, had working magically amazingly.
And I mean, it was a demo test gear.
But anyway, he had to land it and it is basically assumed
that if he wasn't the quality of pilot he was, they would have crashed.
Well, have you ever played X Lander?
-- Yes, that game is so good
-- also very like,
it's funny because they actually have X Lander with like,
nice big throttle and joystick and everything at the Tell us World Museum here
locally and it is comical to me to watch people play it because they,
they, it looks because it's like vector graphics and it's like super old people,
I think, assume it's going to be, like, pretty
easy.
You know,
I have never seen anybody successfully land that
thing and I've only managed to land it,
like, safely twice.
I can land in the wide area,
but I can, I can never land
that small area. They have.
-- Yeah,
-- like the 10 multiplier or whatever. Yeah.
-- it's got, it's tons of points
or, you know, with the,
like with all the physics turned on where you're like,
-- over trying to under correct or over correct
-- and
it's really hard and obviously you're in
a different gravity which changes everything.
But I mean,
so this is one of the interesting things I
think about space is you look at these early astronauts
and they literally pick the best test pilots they could find because they knew that
the time would come when these people would have to actually fly the ships and the
they had,
would be imperative and this feels sometimes like early security where
back in the day it was all cowboys running around,
fixing problems and it was bananas.
Well, like,
literally they got stuck on the moon and the only way they
managed to fix the Lander was by poking something with a pen.
Right.
Like, I mean, yeah, it's just, it's a perfect case of, you know,
911 responders being like, well, we have to handle it.
-- Why? Because what do we do call ourselves?
-- And not only that, I think
early industries are
the heroes make the industry work,
but you eventually have to mature to the point
-- where
-- there's part of it is survivor bias,
right?
Because there's the heroes are the ones that didn't get electrocuted or, you know,
set themselves on fire or whatever.
Right.
They survived and, you know, went, ok, well, when you're doing this, do it this way,
so it's safe.
-- Right.
-- Right. Exactly.
And then eventually though,
you have to mature to the point where it becomes
boring and not that I think space is necessarily boring,
but I think it's way less exciting than it used to be.
Well, you kind of want it to be boring.
Like, like cars, I mean, reading about cars, like, like the whole crank cars,
it's like airplanes, think about airplanes. Right.
Like Charles Lindbergh flew across the ocean. Now we have what?
Hundreds of planes fly across the ocean every day and
it is completely uneventful and they all have radios,
like,
and yet they still disappear once in a while, which kind of blows my mind.
That's a Black Swan event. But you have to think, like, you think true,
I bet before Lindbergh, I don't know. The statistic on this.
But I bet a lot of people tried to cross the ocean and they crashed their death.
Because
what else do you do? Like who's going to come save you? Right.
Nobody, your plane just crashed into the ocean. You're dead.
My understanding is from the early flyers.
There were a lot of deaths, obviously, but a lot of that was like trying to take off,
crashed, died.
You got to remember too, like the, the
amount of money and expertise involved in just getting a plane off the ground,
let alone trying to cross the Atlantic.
-- So there weren't a lot of people trying. No,
-- I mean, I, I won't lie.
I'm not super familiar with that.
My understanding is, yeah,
there were a lot of early deaths but it was pretty tried to take off,
crashed after 100 ft or whatever or, you know, trying to land.
Well, here's the thing, right? You have just invented planes.
Do you know how to take off in one of these?
Right. Ok. Cool. Good news you took off.
Hey,
did we cover landing in school yet? Oh, wait, we haven't invented that.
Well,
that's the Wright brothers pretty much just crashed at the end of all their flights.
-- Yeah. Well,
-- I mean, that's why they did it on Sandy Beach
basically, you know, like it's, yeah, like, well,
we didn't have a ball pit big enough.
So go to the beach, right.
But, I mean, and that's part of it. Right. Is, is again, like, how do you do this?
So it's, it's safe when you see people testing new devices, you know, you start off,
like, well, when you watch testing of new airplanes, they like rev it up,
they take off down the runway and then they put the brakes on and turn the engines off,
you know, and then they,
and then the next time go a little bit faster and then
like eventually they take off do like a quick circle and land.
Right. Right. And, and they start pushing
literally the, the flight test envelope, they start pushing it.
And then my favorite always is when you see the Boeing tail strike tests.
-- Have you seen those?
-- I
don't know,
what
is it?
-- So
-- the idea is when you're taking off on a plane, you go fast to get air speed,
then you rotate up a bit to get airflow over the wing.
And then, you know, physics takes magic and you fly.
What happens if you rotate the plane up too fast? I have no idea.
Well, the back of the plane hits the runway. That seems bad. Right.
That's called the tail.
So, well, it's not ideal.
But so what you do if you're Boeing is you weld
a metal plate to the back of the plane and then
you have your test pilot drake it down the runway at
high speed because you have to test this that seems fair.
Yeah, exactly.
So they literally, you can,
you can youtube these videos of like the Boeing test
pilot just revs the engines all the way up,
yanks back on the stick and he's just basically like doing
a wheelie down the runway with sparks flying out the back,
you know, and then eventually takes off to see what happens.
Basically. That's pretty cool.
And, you know, but you get there, you don't start there, you get there eventually,
right?
You know, and you see these things like, well,
how do you learn how an airplane stalls, you stall it?
Yeah,
-- you start stalling it
-- and I know part of becoming a pilot is they bring
you up in the air and they're like stall it and then fix it and,
or a spin stall or all sorts of.
And so, but,
and this always the one thing I always think about with in terms of
like space and aeronautics and all this testing and even like in the automobile
industry,
there's all this testing is these are industries that
have experienced dramatic failure and they've been trying,
they try really hard to learn from their failure and test for
failure and make sure they don't make the same mistake twice.
And I always feel like in it,
we don't just make the same mistake twice.
Everyone makes the same mistake over and over and over again.
Yeah, I think part of it is that technology changes so fast that we like,
I'm seeing in the Blockchain world these people have discovered.
And this is amazing to me,
smart contracts are basically software and they have
flaws that can be exploited to steal money,
things like re entr
bugs or, you know, essentially coding errors,
or there can be errors in the interpretation, you know, in the run times.
And they're like, oh my God,
we have like these formal contracts that are formally proven correct,
the instructions are completely correct.
But the thing that compiles it and runs it has a flaw that can be exploited.
I'm like, really, you don't say
all these Blockchain security people a few months ago
after the flash loan attacks and stuff were like,
oh my God, we should start, you know,
auditing contracts for security flaws and like making sure
the runtime are secure and don't do stupid things.
And I'm like, uh huh,
can I talk to you about C or Pearl or
-- Python or Bash or
-- any turning complete language anyway.
Rock paper scissor.
Yeah.
Not even turing complete.
Even the stuff that isn't turing complete is complicated enough that right?
It doesn't matter.
And so yeah, like it just, but I'm like, where have you people been for the last 5,
10 years?
-- Like, how did you not? Why
-- would people know this?
Where would you go to learn this if you didn't know it?
Nowhere you could listen to old men complain on podcasts. But,
but I mean,
you would think it as part of software
programming disciplines or engineering and chemical engineering,
mechanical engineering.
You know, all these guys are like,
now we're going to talk about the Tacoma narrows bridge and why, you know,
-- resonant vibration is a thing
-- you just made me
realize something really interesting is so I took a bunch
of computer science courses when I was in college
and it was mostly Java and C++ back then.
Yeah. Did they ever talk about failure? No. And that's exactly what I'm thinking.
But at the same time,
all of the failures that would have been discussed back then.
You would have had what, like the Morris worm might be the big one that,
that would get discussed.
-- I don't know if many of those lessons. Well, that's an
-- attack.
-- That's not even a failure per S
-- E Well, I would,
-- I would argue it's a failure but
-- it's both.
Well, I'm thinking like failures, like where, you know,
the poor governor of New Jersey is like, we need a bunch of coal
programmers staff
because like, our unemployment system tipped over, you know,
I'm thinking more not attack failures but like a failures where it's like,
but either way, right?
Attack or not attack, you're right.
We don't ever talk about problems, but at the same time,
people generally don't advertise these things either because nobody wants to say,
oh, hey, look how bad we screwed up. Now, we want to talk about it.
Yes and no, like look at cloud Fflur every time Cloud Fflur has a whoopsie.
They are the exception to the rule though.
Google's not as good as they used to be, but Google still does post mortems.
Same with Amazon, same with, you know, a lot of these.
But again, it's the mature players do this because the mature players, well,
let's be real if you're in cloud flare or Amazon or Google,
like they could set your house on fire and you're going to be like, well,
please don't do that
because I still have to use you. Right? Like, really? Right.
It's like gasoline as much as I wish we could move off fossil fuels.
I, you know, I'm going to go, need to go gas up my car in a week
because I need to like get around the city.
I understand that like it doesn't matter.
So, yeah, I mean, and that's a maturity piece, but
I think part of the challenge is by not talking about failure.
I've met so many people that don't think failure is even an option or possible.
-- You know what I mean? It
-- is not something.
I mean, I think there are very few organizations that kind of plan for failure
and they try to do anything
to say if a bad thing.
But I guess at the same time if you're architecting failure into your designs
that costs money and that means you're working on that as a
feature instead of something that is going to sell more product.
-- But it
-- also means you understand, to some degree how the system works and how,
because to, to understand how something can fail,
you have to understand the system
well, to a degree.
I mean, so I'll actually,
I have a great example of this is I've been dealing
with Phipps 1 40-2 slash 1 40-3 a lot lately,
like more than I want to.
And
it's, it's like
honestly learning about any of these government security certifications is
a freaking curse and you will never shed your curse.
So don't learn this crap if you don't need to.
But anyway,
so it's,
it's one of those topics where if you
are in that situation where you're interacting with
an organization, like a government or a large bank or
some sort of organization that's massive, right?
They, they, they say, you know, we need to make sure you do these things for reasons
and you, of course, can argue back and forth,
but eventually they're going to win because they have all the money.
But at the same time,
it means you've reached a certain maturity level
because obviously if you're interacting with governments,
it means you have essentially a government sales
team that knows how to play the game.
And there's, there's like all these layers all the way down, right?
Well, part of it too is for one thing I just had to look this up because I'm like,
I know Phipps has been around a long time.
Like, basically as long as I've been in the industry and
pips 141 was issued on 11th of January 1990. It's really old and
my second thought would be ok.
So, like, let's hypothetically hate on pips for a moment. What's the alternative?
-- What do you mean? What's the alternative? Like,
-- what's the alternative standard?
There isn't one if I want to buy a device that
does some cryptography stuff and I want it to be like,
reasonably secure.
I can say basically,
either you have to meet pips 140.123 or four standard or what's the alternative?
There are a handful of others.
But no, I mean, fundamentally that's the only game in town.
And even now like the Phipps 143 standard just refers back to iso
documents these days.
It's nothing like it used to be where it used to spell everything out in detail.
I mean, and I understand why these,
these standards are important because if you don't,
you end up with like people making up their own crypto
and, and I get it,
I understand.
-- Well,
-- every time somebody says this thing is tamper proof, I'm like, no, it's not.
I own a sledgehammer.
-- I know, I know
-- like, you know, like, and when they say tamper resistant, I'm like,
well, maybe tamper is like tamper evident, I'll buy sure I get that.
-- But beyond tamper evident,
-- there's varying levels.
It's always cool because I know some people that
work on hardware in sensitive places and the stories
they have are amazing where like they have to
go test this stuff where they have like literally
an explosives range where they bring it and they put it out and they
open the case and like it lights on fire because that's basically its job.
And it's like, that's so crazy.
Or there's,
I forget there was one company I was talking to where they have a ballistics range
and they literally shoot their equipment with guns to see what happens.
Like, what a job,
you know, for some people that make stuff that goes to war zones. That's
seriously. Exactly. Exactly.
I remember when I found out about Mill spec gear, I'm like, ok, it's waterproof,
it's drop proof.
I get that and then they're like, but it also has to get shot because like,
if you shoot something and it just dies then we're kind of sol and I'm like, oh,
-- that
-- actually, yeah, or you think about things in space where people, like,
they're putting up 486 processors in this gear
and
why?
Because there's like all these crazy cosmic rays
and the temperature changes and it's just,
it's madness up there.
And so you can't put in a modern processor that's going to just
-- fry itself in the 1st 15 minutes
-- I remember learning about radiation hardened,
-- you know, electronics. And it's like,
-- yeah,
it's cool.
I mean, you thought you, like, I remember,
I once discovered I had a bad stick of
RA M because I couldn't compile the Linux kernel.
Everything else worked fine.
But the Linux kernel because it basically did two things that no other program
was, he used up all of my RA M
and a single bit flip resulted in
and I,
I eventually figured out I had one stick of bad Ram and I
just couldn't compile kernels on that machine
-- anymore because I've even
-- seen instances.
So there's, what is it mem mem test 86. I think it's called
where
I've seen instances where I had to leave it,
run for a day before it actually ran into the pro
like, yeah, I mean,
-- sometimes bad memory is weird and all it takes is a couple of bits and
-- oh yeah,
transient, bad memory is the worst.
It might as well be a ghost. It's like the machine's haunted. Got to burn it. Right.
But you figure when you've got, I mean, you've got a rover on Mars.
You can't be like, oh the Ram's bad. Let's go flip that out now.
Like, no, you're stuck with what you got.
I remember all those rescue missions for the Hubble Space telescope.
And I'm like, at some point,
I'm kind of like this seems like an old car and you'd just be
-- better off building
-- it except the new one still isn't in freaking space yet.
True. Yeah. Yeah. Is that
it's supposed to launch this year? I believe,
I thought it was,
I
don't know, we're talking about the James Webb Space Telescope
-- which by the way, check the technology on that bad boy. Like,
-- it's gonna be awesome.
I love the fact that they're like, oh, yeah.
You know, we just have a bunch of solar shields,
chill it down to like what is a 0.0 something of a Kelvin?
And I'm like, wait, what
if
wild is that for real? It is.
And my second thought was, wait, I thought space was cold to begin with.
-- Yeah. No, it's not cold enough. I'm like, what?
-- No, no.
So actually this is this is another thing.
So this is a cool story about Apollo 13 because we're nearly out of time.
And so end on one cool space story.
So when the Apollo spacecraft was traveling to the moon,
they didn't just like point it at the moon and go,
they actually rotated at a speed of like 1 to 3 rotations per hour.
And the reason they had to do that is because the
side of the spaceship not facing the sun gets very,
very cold and the side of the spaceship facing the sun gets very, very hot.
And so space is weirdly cold and not cold depending upon where you're at.
Well,
and it's also like the best insulator out there because there's nothing there.
-- Right.
-- And so it's very hard to shed the heat.
Now,
here's what was crazy is on Apollo 13 because
they basically went to live in the lunar module
because they had to shut everything down in the
regular spacecraft because they lost their oxygen tank,
which was also how they got their power.
What ended up happening was the lunar module didn't
have a guidance computer capable of rotating the ship.
And so Jim L
-- had to rotate the ship by hand. Wait
-- a stupid question.
But if you got the ship rotating wouldn't inertia
just take care of the problem for you.
Well, no, no, because he did it by hand,
it wasn't rotating exactly correctly and obviously
you had to constantly adjust the ship,
which normally the guidance computer would do
except the guidance computer was shut down.
Oh,
so I guess because my thinking is you start the
thing rotating and inertia would just keep it moving around.
But I guess with the astronauts moving around inside of it and stuff. Yeah. Right.
Exactly. Right. It's going, it's going to change your center of gravity.
It's going to start
in
weird ways. Right. Right. Exactly.
Or it could speed up or slow down depending upon where people are at.
And it's, this is why they had the best pilots in the world
in these ships because if they didn't,
they would have died like if you put you and me in this and they had a problem,
it'd be like, well, that's the end.
-- Kurt. You know,
-- my favorite thing was on top gear.
They put Hammond in a, like a formula, not a formula one race car,
but like one of those, the, the lower ones, like whatever.
And he could not get the thing to start and go. Like, he kept stalling it out. Right.
Because it's just those things are so perks.
Nicky, it's not like, you know, put it in first and hit the gas.
It's like, no, you got to, like, get the engine up to like 6000 R PM and like, blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah.
I'm like, because, you know,
these cars aren't meant to go below like 100 miles an hour, right.
Everything below 100 miles an hour is essentially a failure condition for them.
Plus they're going to like, get too hot and catch fire.
So watching them try to start this thing was just, oh,
-- it was comical and like you and I couldn't do it
-- right.
And this is a difference between having an industry that has heroes
running the show versus it's boring and anyone can do it.
I feel like the problem is though, to get to those heroes though.
You've got to have a lot of people who, like, died horrible deaths.
Some people have to die on the launch pad.
So maybe that's the problem with computer security is that all of our failure
are kind of bad but not bad enough that we're actually forced to learn from them.
I, I do think that's part of our problem. I really do.
I, I don't think our failures are so bad. Anyone has to care
to the point of like, because let's face it, man.
If you're like, oh get in this rocket.
And I say the last people got in this rocket died in a fire.
I'm not getting in that rocket until you fix it.
But we're like, yeah, just, just install antivirus in your computer.
You're like, oh, ok, that sounds fine. I'll do that.
And, and I mean,
I say this all the time and it sounds morbid
but like literally until computer security problems start killing people,
I don't think anyone's really going to care and
-- it's terrifying, but I think that might be the way it is.
-- Maybe to end on the note.
What always gets me about self driving car hacking is the look on the reporter's
face when they actually experience sitting in a
self driving car that's been remotely hijacked.
And you see them have that moment of realization of
what this actually means up until then it's all academic.
And it's kind of like, oh, you can hijack a car, blah, blah, blah, that's bad.
But to see the look on their face when they're like, ok, wait,
the car's accelerating and my foot's on the brake
Right.
You know, you can see that moment of, oh crap. And yeah, maybe we need more of that.
I'm going to end on one cool story back during it was the Mercury mission in, in the US.
And I know Russia has a similar story, but I don't know the details well enough.
So there was an astronaut named Gordon Cooper and again,
great test pilot, right? Like these guys were the best of the best
and Gordon Cooper was getting ready for reentry
and something went wrong with the guidance computer.
And so basically it came down to fly the spaceship or die, right?
Which is, of course, for a test pilot is like, that's normal, but for us,
it would not be normal at all.
And he obviously is doing a manual reentry where you've got, you know, there's,
there's dials and, and whatnot, but it was very,
it was very human focused right where there wasn't computers,
calculating things and he had to kind of guess where to, to do certain things.
And also you got to remember during reentry, you're shaking and rattling a lot.
So it's really hard to read dials and to even control anything.
But anyway, this guy, he pilots the,
the spacecraft into the atmosphere and he gets it to land and he was
only like one mile away from where the guidance computer would have dropped him.
And it's like, it blows my mind how good these people were at what they did.
And it's just, there's so many bizarre stories like this
that exist of these astronauts and I keep thinking
about the fact that they were the heroes and
now we're trying to make space boring and I feel like security is in the same boat.
We still have too many heroes like this needs to be accounting, not pilots.
All right. Anyway, I'm ending it.
That was fun. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you, everyone for listening.
You can go to opens sources Security podcast.com. Hit up our show notes.
I will, I'll do my best to dig up the stories,
-- but I know some of this is out of my brain and I may be misremembering, but
-- I'm sad.
I found a bunch of ex Lander games online, but they're all flash based.
Just get the original run Linux.
Anyway, open source Security podcast.com hit at the show notes.
You can use the Pound
Oss podcast. Hashtag do hit us up on social media. Kurt.
Have a fantastic rest of your day. You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks everyone.
Bye bye.