Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Digital Sovereignty.
Josh Bresser,
-- are we
-- Digital Sovereigns? I'm not sure how that works.
Uh Well, that's because we're traveling. We're not driving somewhere,
-- don't you travel when you drive?
-- Well, yeah,
it's, it's, it's a riff on that sovereign citizen.
I'm traveling, not driving thing, you know,
where they are asked for their driver's license and they're like,
but I'm not driving, I'm traveling
and then the cop is like, uh huh.
-- I still want to see your driver's license and then, you
-- know,
I've never heard of this.
I, I purposely don't pay attention to these people because
they definitely don't live in the world I live in.
And so
I'm happy to live in my bubble of ignorance or
whatever you want to call it and be like whatever.
So anyway, before we move on,
I think there's an important thing we should cover and
we're not going to talk about it today in depth.
But holy cow, the collapse of Twitter is a site to witness.
-- I,
-- I think it's not so much the co
maps of Twitter, but Ok. So it's a couple of things.
Number one, this is now my third financial crisis of the century in 20 years. Yeah.
Right. Right. Like, I'm getting a little tired of these. I've done the.com.
They're just normal now. I did the.com boom, did 2008.
The mini, I guess technically the mini in what, 2014
and now, you know, meta announced they're laying off 11,000 people.
Twitter fired half their global workforce and then realized, oops,
some of the people we fired, keep the site running
minor detail.
You know, I tried to hire them back and apparently a lot of them said no, because,
well, that's what I would have said.
Like at that point, I, I don't trust, like,
unless you give me a suitcase full of money.
No, I'm done
anyway.
Ok. Here's a, here's a fun fact. Um, Master Dawn,
the open source was started in 2016.
The company was founded in 2021 and, you know,
it's been chugging along doing whatever kind of rank.
And then for the last couple of weeks, they've been getting 4000 users an hour.
I know it's pretty wild
and, and it hasn't collapsed now,
it has definitely gotten slow and things are buggy and like, like my,
my feet on my mobile versus my feet on the website is like
hell out of sync. We'll talk about this properly someday.
But it's, it's, it's lurching along and, you know,
like people are contributing patches.
Like I wrote a web finger server, I guess it's 12 lines of javascript.
I don't know what to call it. It's not really a Damon, but
like, so now if you want, you can put up a clot floor worker and have like,
just basically serve
your, like,
name
domain. So, like your email address and redirect it to your Mastodon accounts.
Boom, done,
you know.
and so everybody's improving this stuff, you know,
and it hasn't tipped over
-- and it's
-- awesome.
It's open
-- source. That's what I love.
-- Well, it's not just open
source. Twitter runs on open source,
but Twitter isn't open.
The community is well, OK, we're going to talk about this later.
We're not going down this rat hole right now.
I just wanted to mention it because it amuses me to no end
-- anyway. Anyway.
-- But today, what's is GCHQ?
So the um the, the basically the UK, you know, Cybersecurity
Agency has basically been scanning all the web
servers hosted in the UK for vulnerabilities.
-- Did they start or are they going to start? When was this supposed to start?
-- Uh It's
already started,
-- did it?
-- OK. I don't remember a date in this story.
Yeah.
OK. So we'll assume they're doing it, which is fine.
So, well, it's, it's, it's not a date. It's not. No, no, no. To be clear.
This is not a story. This is the
NCN
CS c.gov
dot UK. Slash blah, blah, blah. It's their web page that says they're doing this.
Ok
and sorry, it's not GCHQ. It's the National Cybersecurity Center.
Why did I say G GCHQ? Oh, you know, it's just in my brain, everything. UK
securities, GCHQ,
it's fine. Whatever. Anyways. So the N CS C which does not roll off the tongue.
This is on their website,
like this is an official government web page saying we're doing this
and like what we're doing and
you know, for example, oh, here we go.
Like all activities performed on a schedule
using standard and freely available network tools.
So they're using like what N map and like,
I don't know, we're not going to guess
metas
PLO whatever
um within a dedicated cloud hosted environment.
Yeah, of course, it's cloud hosted. Like you're not going to do this on prem.
All connections are made from one of these two IP addresses.
Then they give the two IP S
note that these IP addresses are both assigned to scanner dot scanning dot service,
scanner dot scanning dot service.
Ok. I guess that's,
I guess that way if you do a reverse DNS look up like it's really clear what's going on.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
And, and they also include a header right? To tell you it's them
which I'm sure no bad people are going to use.
And like what makes me laugh is if you're online,
you're already getting scammed by like, well, showdown.
-- Oh
-- tons of stuff.
A
dozen private companies by
bad guys. Even
like to the point where that's one of the reasons I
use cloud flare is to kind of filter that junk out.
So I just don't even have to see to my logs. Not that I have logs anymore.
I just, I put seafood do or in an S3 bucket and left it there.
It's interesting because some people got really bent out of shape about this.
And it's like, yeah, but like is it, I I kind of look at this.
Now, if the, if the for example,
if the Canadian government announced a plan where they were basically going to
have police check every door to make sure it's locked at night.
For example, like uh that feels kind of creepy and weird.
I don't think that's a valid comparison. I think
the, the way I would view this almost is
the internet isn't
comparable to like your house scanning an IP address
isn't like going up and trying someone's doorknob.
It would be more comparable to the millions of cameras, especially in the UK
that are just observing public spaces. Like if you walk around the UK,
you're going to be on a CCTV camera
somewhere during uh probably
a five minute walk just because they're like freaking everywhere there.
They, they, they love CCTV.
Well, they, they use it for their policing to, to direct police services to,
you know, like there's two guys kicking off and
-- over at that bar and like, you know, send a squad over to break it up and,
-- and so, I mean,
I, I think about this one,
there's part of me that says, who cares? Right.
And because you're on the internet, if you have an IP address,
you're getting hammered with crap.
I mean, I remember
there was
an elastic search worm at one point
that, like, as, as the elastic search security team, we were like,
what does this worm do?
And I said, I'll just stand up a honey pot and we'll see what happens.
And I did and it took, I think three hours for it to be found.
And then it was really funny because there were like competing worms
constantly trying to ransom the server back and forth between each other.
And I'm like, this is great.
And the, oh I remember why
because
our
note was being put into the elastic search instance saying I've taken your data.
We were like,
did they? No, no, they did not.
They were just deleting all the data,
adding a ransom note and then demanding Bitcoin.
And then I tried to pretend to pay them Bitcoin, which they, they,
I never got very far because I'm like, I paid you what's up?
They're like, we didn't get it. I'm like I paid you what's up?
Like we didn't get it and then they stopped replying to me
and II I didn't pay them
but
but anyway,
the
like if you have something on the internet, this is just what happens.
It
is what it is.
And so I, I think getting upset over this is silly but I,
I think there's a better question is,
does this
make sense for a government agency to try to police the IP space in their country?
Pause
-- you say to police the IP space
-- for whatever I use the term loosely.
Yeah, my understanding of this is this is more of a data gathering
at this stage. It's not calling you up and saying like go patch your server.
Yes, that does seem to be the case.
And I think part of this is like
that kind of data is actually really important because
part of it is
without data, a baseline. How do you know if you're making things better or worse?
Like a perfect example of this is I have um a thermometer,
digital thermometer that I take my temperature.
My kids' temperature, my temperature is like 36.4.
That's it. That that is my temperature plus or minus 0.2 of a degree.
Now, what's interesting is my one son,
his temperature over the last year and a half has actually gone
up about 0.8 of a degree and that's his new normal.
And so what in the past would have been like, oh, he's getting pretty warm.
Maybe he has a fever is now. No, no, no, that's like his temperature has changed.
He's grown,
it's something has changed in him and his
body temperature now is consistently a bit warmer.
And my other son is like, still bang on, you know,
37.2 because I have those baselines now and I have those long term trends.
I can see.
Oh, no, it changed. Right.
And that's the thing, like,
if you make some policy change or you talk to these providers,
these hosting providers like,
ok, they say they're patching more but like
are they like at scale is anything actually better?
And also kind of does this matter?
So like we scan a whole bunch of hosts, find a bunch of vulnerable hosts that are not,
maybe not being exploited.
-- Well, why is that? That's interesting.
-- Right. They're probably all honey pots
and a lot of this, it's like public health right now, you know,
uh Edmonton public school boards, for example,
has been doing an excellent job of tracking and
publishing data with about a one day delay of like
what percentage of kids have reported COVID and what
percentage of kids are out sick for other illnesses?
And it's like 14% right now. It's really bad. Yeah. Yeah. But again, like
without that sort of longer term data,
like we know it's worse in the fall because all the kids go back to school.
But like, oh no, no. This year it's like really worse
because we have the data now from the previous two years.
Ok. Ok. So I think there's
a couple of interesting pieces in everything you just said.
First of all, they do seem to be just scanning and not doing any and, and even if you,
we could discuss for hours,
how you would even figure out who to contact
if you're just scanning IP addresses because that in itself
-- is very difficult
-- DNS register
it, it, but it's not even that simple because what if you're using,
what if you're using a cloud service and one
IP address is hosting 30 services because it's a,
a load balancer.
-- You're
-- assuming they're just scanning IP si assume that they're scanning both IP S
and host names.
Like if I was the British government, I would download the well.uk DNS file and like,
-- OK, and map, like go
-- do it.
They, they should be doing that
and, and because, well,
although that even that's funny because there's going to
be that UK things hosted outside the U.
OK. But whatever, because of I PV six, you can't scan I PV six.
There's too many, right. You can scan all of I PV four in a couple of hours.
You can't brute force scan I PV six.
Right? But that's why you need the host names. Exactly.
And, well,
the other thing to remember too is they have boxes that monitor
the traffic and they know which IP S are in use.
I mean, probably to a degree you can you can ask, they don't scan you,
they have an email address for that.
The thing is the government can do things at scale that
we can't because they have access to information that we don't
sure there was, there was actually a really good podcast motherboard did.
I'll try to dig it up and put in the show notes.
I don't, I don't know if I've talked about it here before but there is
a service.
The,
not the jig.
Um, um, it's, I think it's NCIS, it's like the, the, the lawyer,
one of the lawyer groups in the Navy or the law enforcement of the Navy.
-- I think it's NCIS. That would
-- be the NCIS as we know from the TV show.
Is there a TV show?
Dude? There, they have like six.
I don't watch TV.
NC.
Well, it was funny because I tried watching it for a little while and it was so boring.
I couldn't, and this one guy just tweeted recently that, like,
his daughter watches NCIS to fall asleep.
So she, like, doesn't know what it is but she knows about NCIS and she's like,
eight years old or something.
Yeah, there is an NCIS show.
-- There's a lot.
-- Really.
There's,
-- I think there's four,
-- 40, there are
Ncislancis, Hawaii. NCIS, New Orleans. Wow. Neat.
Anyway, whatever doesn't matter.
Ok. So
NCIS,
they were
contracting with some company that was like,
collecting enormous amounts of net flow data and selling it.
To them with the excuse of obviously metadata doesn't matter.
So, no one cares and you don't need warrants and things like that.
And then, then motherboard did a big, big thing about it. But.
Right. Right. So there's, there's definitely ways to access a lot of this data.
Now, now, the thing I think
that everyone is going to say is first of all, how do I prove something is in the UK,
which
I don't know how they're doing that or if they care,
the thing you could do is you could just do it by geographical IP space and just say,
like, look, if this is forwarding on through a VPN to somewhere else,
not our problem. Like, we're just, I suppose,
you know, we're just all the A SNS that are, like, quote unquote in Britain.
Like, ah, I just learned about the, um, the A SN IP or the IP. What was it?
Oh, dang it now, I can't remember it. The, uh, not IP info.
Anyway, there's this database, like, where you ask it an IP.
And it's like this IP is located in this and
it's probably not a VPN but it is probably this,
you know, blah, blah, blah, it's a residential service or not or whatever.
Right.
That's something I wanted to talk about. Like, what is
digital UK?
Like is it.uk, do we just say, like, look if it ends in.uk,
it's their jurisdiction because it's registered to a DNS registrar
in the UK.
Well, and even that they're not in the UK necessarily, right?
Because I think God Daddy sells them.
-- Is it the IP space?
-- So here's what they put on their website.
They say these activities cover any internet accessible
system that is hosted within the UK.
-- And
-- so I would assume they're going by IP address and routing, right?
Like, so it doesn't get out of their digital borders,
I would assume. So.
You know, but,
and let's ignore like VPN S and tunneling and redirects and stuff like that.
Well, and even like, it's funny too because think about cloud flare,
cloud flare has endpoints all over the world.
And when you connect to a cloud flare site or service,
you connect to a local IP that's very close to you.
And then magically the data arrives at your location from the cloud flare.
Magic cloud,
well, a local point of presence because they use any cast.
So they have this block of IP S that they just globally advertise from,
I think they're at like 200 points of presence now or something.
It's a lot,
I bet it's at least that.
So,
yeah, it's the, the other thing to be blunt is if they're using open source tools,
they, they're not doing anything that Attackers aren't already doing.
Right. Oh, absolutely. Like they're not like they're not using zero days.
-- So
-- here's what makes this funny as well is from the perspective of a governmental
intelligence organization.
You can't use secret tools because
you will have adversaries specifically running hosts
in your order
just to snarf the information of what you are doing.
I, there's,
I guarantee you every other country's intelligence agency has stood up
a server in the UK just to watch these scans 100%.
-- I
-- think you're giving people too much credit. But, yeah, I mean, no, I
guarantee it.
I, I would be
all right.
Maybe not every, every intelligence organization, but we'll say at least
-- the top 10. But
-- yeah, as we learned from uh what was it? The NSA eternal Blue.
Like, oops, you know,
the wanna cry ransomware ended up using it and it became a bit of an issue.
Right? Well, that's a, that's a whole other story in itself. But
regardless, I, I feel like
I read this story. Part of me says, not the dumbest idea ever.
Part of me says the dumbest idea ever.
And I have a strong suspicion. This is just the kind of crap we're gonna see
because every government on the planet is now making a huge deal about the cyber.
And so they, they, they need to do something, right?
I mean, fundamentally when you are a government organization,
someone is going to show up and say, here's a bunch of money, fix the cyber.
And now you have to say,
how am I going to spend this money? Because if I don't, I'm going to get fired.
And so,
-- yeah, and worse, we're not going to get that money next year. Right.
-- Oh. Right.
Well, exactly.
And so they're,
they're going to do things that maybe some of us geezers who've been on the
internet a long time are going to look at and shake our heads and say,
why on earth is this even happening?
And some of it will be stupid. Some of it won't be stupid.
And it's just, I, I think we're going to see more of this everywhere.
I remember back in the old days when intrusion
prevention systems were just starting to take off.
And somebody pointed out, you know what the real value of an IP S was or not, sorry,
intrusion prevention systems, intrusion detection systems,
like we weren't even doing prevention back then.
And he pointed out that the value of an I DS was
you stuck one in front of your firewall
and you stuck one behind your firewall and then
you could show your leadership the delta between the
two and say like our firewall is working.
Sure, sure. And then you could get more budget for a better firewall.
That's probably true.
This is what drives me nuts is like some things
we kind of know inherently will be better like,
you know, having passwords versus
like not having passwords at all. Ok?
Like having an account and a password that are unique and not shared, right? I
don't really need data to prove that that's better.
But then there's other things like, well, should I deploy this vendor a or vendor BW?
And maybe there are different technologies, maybe they're, you know, whatever,
like which one's better,
you know, supply chain security.
-- And, but the thing is that's where you need to gather the data.
-- OK.
No, no,
I want to pick on this though because I think what
you just brought up is interesting and you're not wrong.
But there's another angle to this when we're dealing with governments.
If the government has the ability to detect
weaknesses in a product over another product,
do you think they're going to say
vendors of this product or even product vendor who built this,
you should fix this bug or do you think they're going to
take that bug and use it to their advantage against adversaries?
We know the answer
but a lot of those weaknesses aren't really exploit.
Like think about the supply chain software that we're seeing like, oh,
like for example, as we all learned from open SSL recently,
a lot of these supply chain software things don't unpack stuff and look for it.
Like you were talking about it,
how your engineer spent the weekend writing a
thing that looks for that magic string,
like that's not a vulnerability that I can really exploit or
kind of use and but I can report it to the vendor and be like,
can you please fix this capability?
So that your product works. Right.
And that's the kind of stuff I'm talking about more like,
I'm not talking about a buffer overflow.
I'm talking about, like,
you know, this product
just like,
doesn't understand this protocol or something, you know?
Ok. All right. All right.
But
regardless you get, you get the point, we've got
the government now in the UK is going to try to do
scanning of all the UK stuff.
They're gonna no doubt go outside of the UK,
which probably will create diplomatic nightmares for somebody at some
point because it's just the nature of the beast.
And then they're going to collect all this data.
We don't know what they're going to do with it yet. And
I think you're going to see a bunch of people losing their minds,
which is obviously what the hacker news threat threat is for.
And I think at the end of the day, no one's gonna care in like, uh six months.
That's my guess.
Well, I mean,
the thing is like
showdown IO already did this. Like, and how old is Showdown Iowa?
It's pretty old now. I think
I want to say more than 10 years.
I still love, I must say from the showdown perspective.
And now I don't approve of this in any way.
But when they ran their own NTP server to start capturing I PV six addresses,
like that was so brilliant.
-- Just like holy cow.
-- Well done.
I, at 1.20 years ago,
suggested the organization I work for start running IRC servers so
we could monitor Irc.
Right. Exactly. Because when you run the server, you can access a lot of
stuff.
-- Well,
-- it's
just you see all the traffic and that's the thing we would have had to run,
like, um, one of the sort of more central distribution nodes,
not like an end node that just gets what's going through it, but like
an actual, I forget what they were called like a transit or something or,
I don't know, I mean, this is one of the,
it's suspected that the NSA runs an enormous number of Tor
exit nodes and entry nodes for this exact reason because,
well, you can't control the path the data takes through the Tor network.
If you run enough entry nodes and enough exit nodes,
you can start correlating data and figuring out who's going where, which is
good for them, I guess.
See,
this is the thing that people forget is like there's a
lot of law enforcement and criminal investigations that are like,
OK,
well, we knew it was a red truck.
So we just checked every red truck in the city,
right? That's it.
Like it's, there was no, there's no magic like no Sherlock breakthrough moment.
It's just like yesterday,
the cops announced they charged this guy with a
crime from a DNA sample collected in 1981.
-- You know, like it's in the computer So
-- I like to read,
we'll say in, uh, uh,
analysis of criminal investigations on, specifically on Twitter,
I follow a bunch of lawyers and it's fun to do.
I need to find them on Mastodon now. But
anyway,
like, yeah, I'll get there.
But
something I found out that happens in a lot of these cases is
an organization like the FBI might technically
break the law to collect some evidence.
The evidence is not admissible in court,
but they can say we know this person did this.
Now we just have to work backwards to finding evidence we can use in court.
And I think this is an example of something like that where the,
the, the UK government or any governments is going to, you know, maybe scan things,
look for things that they find something that they know is problematic,
then they might not directly use that information because like I, I guess, you know,
what else this reminds me of is, remember all the cases
where they
FBI had evidence off of someone's phone and they were like,
you have to tell us how you got that off my phone and they were like,
we're just gonna drop this case after all. Like everything's cool everybody.
It's like holy crap. Like what, what must you have done that?
You're willing to literally drop the whole case instead of admitting
in those cases. It was pretty clear like uh what was it,
is it called?
Celebrate or celebrate or whatever it's called,
celebrate is one of the companies is that I'm pretty sure their contracts say,
like if you leak this stuff, we're not selling to you ever again
and you lose that capability.
And so this is the exact same thing that,
like the allies had a problem with World War Two with where we, ok, we broke enigma
and we broke, you know, purple.
Well, how do we use this without like
them figuring out that, you know,
we broke this and we're reading this and like, you know,
the German Navy went to a four rotor design and try, uh you know,
threw them out for a while.
But like that's the thing, how do you like if I'm on your phone, reading your phone,
how do I
use that without
you then really quickly figuring out like, oh he's, he's on my phone.
And so, yeah, creating like parallel discovery like, oh
no. And, and this would actually be a good example of where they can maybe start from.
Parallel discovery was like, oh, no,
no. What happened is we actually scanned this IP. And we found this, like,
weird looking vulnerability and we investigated a bit
and that's how we found the illegal activity,
right? It wasn't, you know,
some spy stuff that's illegal,
you know. So, but regardless, it's
like you said, like the government has to spend the money, they have to do something
in all honesty, they do need this baseline data.
It's useful to have like there's companies there that just track who is data. Like
the DNS changes. Like where does this DNS point to? What is the NS server?
You know, all that stuff going back like a decade or two?
-- So, you know
-- what's really cool is when I was at Elastic,
there was a guy I worked with who he did a
lot of demos for threat detection and things like that.
And he, there,
there's a feed from let's encrypt where let's encrypt will
just like they have a fire hose of all the,
-- all the certificates being requested, their
-- certificate, transparency
logs.
Yeah. Right.
And so he was snarfing that up and he was writing it into elastic search and then
obviously he would look for certain things and
like when there would be like Bitcoin stuff,
you know, obviously scam domains and things like that.
And it was
just because obviously one of the tricks you can do in like elastic search is like,
let's say you have, you know,
cried.org,
you can say, like, show me domains that are similar to this.
-- And then you can be like, oh,
-- wow,
remember when Cloud Flower got fish and they were like part of it is,
the domain was like, what 45 minutes old?
The system didn't catch it,
you know, because they're monitoring
and that's part of the beauty is like, I can't get a DNS registrar feed like,
there's no way they're ever going to give that up.
But a certificate transparency log, especially Lutz and Crap,
who's a good citizen.
Yeah.
Yep. Yep. Absolutely.
It's, uh, it's funny because I actually,
I have a draft cwe for that kind of as a problem.
But also, like, it's interesting because
we have to do it, we have to do it in real time for it to be of value.
But for example, it does, like,
there's literally we're at a point now where if you
stand up wordpress server and it generates a certificate,
by the time you try to log in as the fresh admin thing,
somebody else might have already hijacked
-- it. Uh
-- It's certainly possible if you install an old one. Yeah.
Well, no, no, no, because when you stand up wordpress certain ways it just,
you log in as admin then set the password and everything
and
the attacker could get in and kind of.
-- Well, yeah, I mean, you'd know
-- if that happened though because you can't log in.
-- So,
-- but if they had a script to automate it and
you know, whatever.
But the point is with all this, I think this is actually a good thing.
I actually kind of wish they would provide the data set because
in my mind, if it's an open source tool
there,
like not doing anything kind of magic or special,
they're just running it from these two IP S
right? OK.
So you got to where I was hoping we would go and I love it when you do it without,
without me.
I am hopeful we will see this data
end up in something like threat intelligence feeds.
Eventually.
When we look at the way threat, intelligence and threat sharing happened today,
we're trying to get companies to do it and it's a huge
struggle because obviously no one wants to air out their dirty laundry.
No one wants to admit. Oh, I got popped and here's what happened.
I mean, there's some orgs that do it but not a lot do it. Right.
-- And there's like, well,
-- I mean, the,
the CS A participates in this and there's anonym organization of it.
And there's
what's interesting is like when,
what seems to work well is when you have
companies of roughly the same sort of size and stature
and then they sort of, they're big enough to understand that.
Like, no, this is how the game works.
Like these are the rules and we'll play by it and not
try to use this to, you know, gain an advantage that we use to hurt the opponent,
but to gain an advantage to protect ourselves.
And so I think that maturity piece is growing, but it's, it's,
it's also just really hard, technologically.
It is. And I think this is actually one of the places a government
naturally can get involved and provide some of this data because they don't have
in the game,
this is a census.
It, it, it is a census. That's a really good way to look at it, I think. And,
and it's additionally important because
if we look at, think about, I mean, census data is I, I think a great example is
there's not a lot of economic viability to census data.
Like if you had a private company with the data and they tried to sell it
like there is value, but it's probably not very high.
-- So
-- I'm gonna have to disagree with you.
Uh things like choice point and all those data
collection agencies in the US that sell marketing data.
That's true.
That's the problem is
um
the problem is they're collecting like marketing data.
And well, great example,
actually locally the city of Edmonton just halted their annual or not annual,
but they,
they've halted the census taking activities and a lot of
agencies and nonprofits are complaining because they need that data,
like they need that data to provide services to know where to go to, to function.
And it's absolutely not economical for them
to collect it themselves.
-- Right.
-- Of course, exactly.
Like that's impossible
and it's not even economical for them to, you know,
to pay somebody like choice point for it.
Like it's just not
and
like a road network, this is a public good.
The point is we need this data because nobody can collect it uh efficiently.
-- Like it's, it's being reproduced. It's expensive
-- and look, it needs to be free.
-- Right. Like your point about
-- free and unencumbered.
Right. Right. Exactly.
Because I think your point about, you know, charities or,
or services or agencies or whatever, wanting data and not,
not being willing to pay for it.
I think if you think about a lot of the threat intelligence feeds,
it's a similar situation where they're not cheap
and so a lot of people don't use them because they don't
have the budget for them and they don't understand it's important.
Whereas if it's free,
I think it changes the dynamic.
I can at least look at it because like, I'll be honest,
I've actually worked for Threat Intelligence feed companies for like
half of my career
and I've, I've never bought one, I've never said we should buy one. I've never
like,
and part of it is because I cheat and I
put everything in the cloud and it's Google's problem.
I mean, we, we had one at elastic when I was there.
It was, it was a cool service but it wasn't particularly cheap.
-- At least for the good ones.
-- Well, and more to the point.
I'm always kind of like, well, action.
What do I do with it?
-- Uh,
-- there's a lot you can do with it.
I mean, you tied into a SIM and then you use the signals from it. There's to that.
And I mean, this is also part of the challenge is
there's a narrow swath of the population that
truly understands what this state is good for.
I mean, you're, you're not dumb and you don't know what to do with it. So that says
it's not that I don't know what to do with it. I'm just like, I don't see
enough to make it worthwhile
and I've never had anybody like, demo it or show it to me in a way that makes it
-- compelling.
-- It has value.
And, and so anyway, but again, we don't, we're just speculating,
we don't even know if this is going to happen.
It's conceivable.
We've just waited the last five minutes talking about sharing data
and the UK has no intention of doing that. Which would be a shame if they, if they did.
-- I suspect
-- they
won't because the
-- Queen's copyright maybe,
-- maybe we'll see. We'll see.
But all we need to take this one home,
I guess all in all it's just your typical,
let's make a spectacle of nothing because why not?
Well, it is a new behavior and it is interesting because, you know,
people are worried about the thin end of the wedge.
Like what if the next step is we start testing for vulnerabilities?
I mean,
that's a fair question and I don't want to, that's even like crazier speculation,
obviously, but
it, it,
I think you will,
if you start testing for vulnerabilities,
you're going to crash services and crashing services creates,
-- we'll say problems.
-- Do you remember Oh, I cannot remember the guy's name.
He did all the D
DOS
work originally out of University of Washington. Uh,
David.
Oh,
what's that?
He would basically scan the University of Washington
Network and find IP S that were like,
running horrifically vulnerable software or like public, oh,
public smb writeable shares.
Are you going to tell us he crashed an MRI machine?
No. Yeah, it's like an MRI machine or something,
you know.
And yeah, like,
and, and maybe, and that's part of this I think would also be, for example,
they can take this scanning data
and they can
then go to their, for example, any energy regulator and say like
get an IP address of every energy management system
in the UK.
Let's marry them and see like what do those systems look like?
So that in future if we are like stumble across a random IP,
can we bucket it as like it's a web server or it's like controlling a power plant?
That, that,
yeah, you see that all the time where on show Dan
there's pictures of, you know,
because Shonan will take a snap a picture of like the desktop.
Yeah.
And yeah,
you get that where there's like industrial
control systems just sitting on the internet
and you can connect to them and mess with them and
it is what it is. And you know, I guess if
that would be an interesting number is seeing if,
if efforts like this take the number of publicly
available things like RDP SESSIONS and decreases them.
That would be hugely successful, I think.
But we will, we will have to see.
I mean, we,
we've seen that happen with Elastic and Mongo where you can't
put on public on password protected instance online anymore because it'll get
slacked in a couple of hours.
But that was market pressure,
not the government.
Well, no, no, no.
-- But what I mean is the attacks got so bad that the market went like,
-- well,
that's the thing though.
These other attacks aren't that bad yet.
And so this is, I think where some government
like, let's push them down the hill and, and hopefully it'll get there. So, anyway.
All right, I'm calling on this. Thank you, everyone.
I, I don't remember how to end the podcast anymore. My brain just kept working.
Thank you. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you, everyone.
Go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up the show notes. You see
Podos Podcast. Hashtag this
on social media,
Mastodon, preferably not Twitter anymore.
And yeah, Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks
-- everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the.