Hello and welcome to episode 113 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
-- How
-- you doing, man?
-- Good,
-- good. Just enjoying the smell of burning dust.
But what
it's fall. So I had to turn the furnace on.
Ah, I see. That's right. You live in the Arctic Circle
Fall comes much earlier for you
to anybody else.
Oh, yeah.
I don't, I don't look forward to, to winter but whatever it is, what it is,
you deal with it.
All right.
Cool, man. So, the topic this week is
actionable security advice.
And I,
I came across this article in the Washington Post written by
a person whose name I dare not try to pronounce.
And basically this guy was talking about trying to help
the, it specifically calls out the Democrats
because of how terribly they got whacked in the last election for security.
But basically talking about how do we teach security to these people?
And then he kind of goes through some of the things and,
and he basically lays out just a lot of the bad decisions
now just to clarify what do you mean by these people? When you say the Democrats, you,
uh, uh, I,
-- I, the, the Democratic Party
-- in the US? Ok.
So not like Democrats, but the Democratic Party,
-- which we
-- call Democrats here.
I thought Democrats were the people that belong to the party.
But whatever this is America Kurt, we make our own rules.
Exactly.
Anyway.
Yeah.
So, and, well, actually we've had the same thing come up with our,
we have a federal election coming up next year
and there, there is already talk of, you know,
-- and
-- the potential
for
meddling in this context. Are you saying we as Canada or we
having? Well, II, I
really hope the US is not having a federal election in
2019 because that means things have really gone off the rails.
It's nothing would surprise me at this point.
So, but yeah, no, so we're, we're, we're also
looking at this, you know, and there's been talk of like, what was it?
I think Facebook and whatever, having extra security for the Canadian, you know,
politicians and the people running and stuff like that.
But uh yeah, so to this email, uh yeah, because yeah,
my understanding is like there was that whole thing about the Democrats emails
and the emails being leaked and the servers being hacked and blah,
blah, blah.
And yeah, I was, I, I briefly glanced at this article and how do I put this nicely?
I, I feel for this guy. He's, he, you know,
there, there these people want to help and they want to make things better.
Uh Good luck.
All right. So I wanna, I wanna split this show into two kind of pieces because
you see more doom and gloom than, than maybe I am and, and maybe you're right.
I'm, you've convinced me of nearly everything in the past.
So I'm confident in your ability to sway my opinion now.
But then additionally,
uh we scribbled down some notes talking about like these
are actual things you can tell people to do if
they ask you for help because we're really bad at
giving actual advice that that can make a difference.
And so let's first off
and to be
clear, you're kind of doom and gloom here.
So first off, none of the advice we give is 100% sure,
which is why a lot of security people won't give this advice,
but I'm ok with it. I'm ok with 80 90% solutions because
they're better than like
100% solution that nobody can implement or use.
I'm going to point at seat belts in cars here where we all
have the crazy uncle who says those things kill more people than they save
or they come to the
corner case like what if I crash into a lake
and I'm drowning and I have to cut myself free,
blah, blah, blah, blah.
It's like no. Statistically,
yeah, statistically, wear your damn seatbelt,
you know, don't disable the airbags in your car.
Exactly. Like there are instances where it could actually make things worse.
But, but those are
substantially less common
than the,
the usual instance of you hit something and
you don't want to fly out of the windshield
or the guy behind you hits you
like the passenger behind you get, you, like, people forget about that
anyway. So, yeah, so I'm a bit more doom and gloom on email.
Security for two main reasons.
Number one in general, it's just, people don't seem to care.
I, I do think there's some of that and I, I won't disagree with you but I feel like
the stance I have is I don't try to force this on people anymore, but if
-- someone comes to me, I make sure I have something to tell them.
-- And that was
kind of my second part of that is people have
to want help before they can before they'll do it.
Exactly.
I have seen so many security projects in
security departments that showed up and they said,
oh, we're security,
we're here to help and nobody wanted their help
and like they failed because let's face it.
If, if, if somebody you
to help wants you to fail, by definition, you've already failed.
Well, or they just want to be left alone by you,
they don't want you to harass them and force them into some weird thing
mandated by security, you know. Right.
-- Right. We have, we have work to do here,
-- run this application on your laptop.
It will make it 30% slower and do nothing.
Right.
And it will occasionally fail and lock you out.
The other thing is, is email is one of those things. It's, it's like electricity.
Right.
We, there's a lot of electrical safety stuff people ignore and end up, like,
burning their house down.
Like how many people actually,
like, for example, I learned ha ha much well, after the fact that
you're actually not really supposed to do your own electrical work,
you're supposed to get a certified electrician to do it.
And technically speaking,
you're supposed to get it inspected if you make any changes,
as opposed to just say, replacing something.
-- How many people do that? Basically
-- nobody,
some people do. I don't know. It's,
I'm trying to think. I do know some people that have done
some electrical work.
I've done some myself, but I've also, I have a lot of electrical education
so it's a bit different.
Yes.
And I, I think I, although, although I guess at the same time
we have reached a point with the way electrical systems work in homes that
you have to make some pretty serious mistakes to burn your house down.
I read the code book for my local area actually. And it, it is really clear.
Two lessons, two things.
Number one, there's been a lot of deaths and burnings and whatnot.
So specifically, we have rules, like,
for example, like outdoor outlets now are actually,
like, they're hooded and they,
they really keep the rain out and there's a whole bunch of other stuff.
And then the other thing is that
these rules are clearly really designed.
So that, yeah, some dumb schmuck does come along and start doing dumb stuff.
It, it is difficult for them
to electrocute themselves or burn their house down.
But the problem being, of course,
is that dumb schmuck comes along and does some wiring and doesn't do it properly.
Then the next poor bugger who comes along,
you know, that stuff's not earthed properly or it's not shielded or, you know,
whatever.
So that's, that's part of the catch. Right is,
yeah, if every, it's kind of like in traffic,
if you're not paying attention and everyone else is paying attention,
then you're ok.
But when two people aren't paying attention and texting and they go,
both go into the traffic circle at the same time.
Guess what happened,
then they have a low speed impact because it's a traffic circle.
Yeah. Well, not the way people drive here.
But,
um, I
know there's, you know,
it's nothing pleases me more than pulling into the
traffic circle in front of someone going really,
really fast and purposely driving about five miles an hour
just to be a jerk
and, and watching the rage and their faith,
I may get shot someday, but it's gonna be worth it.
So
I can look.
So kind of how that applies to email is
like, for example,
a lot of people still think they can run their own email server securely.
Hang on. That's advice. We'll get to that. I think
your doom and gloom was less doomy than I expected. So, so do we agree that
if people don't want help, they're going to keep doing whatever it is they're doing.
But if somebody shows up and says, please help me,
-- there's some real opportunity there,
-- right?
There's at least a chance that A they will listen
to you and B that they will actually carry out
the advice.
I I think fundamentally and this will go without saying that
the long term goal is for technology to deal with all of this stuff.
But in the short term,
we do have to have some people change some of
their behaviors because the technology just isn't there today.
Well, also some of this technology is so general purpose that
sometimes like for a great example, being is I,
you know,
there are people who legitimately need to email around infected virus files,
they're, you know, malware researchers
and, and so II I know, but I'm saying like, for example, with these, you know,
with the Democratic Party,
there are people that need to send around some very,
very sensitive information that might be, you know,
password protected or encrypted.
And for example,
an antivirus scanner just can't and should not be allowed to really look into it.
And that's ok. Right. That's ok. And, and for those instances,
you can take special precautions, but we're going to try to beat. This is for
general normal advice.
Not, not, you know, I have this insane use case that no one else has help me do this.
Like that's something else.
If you have that, go find a professional and pay them money to help you.
Right. Don't, please don't use a podcast you found on the internet.
-- Hey,
-- at least it's, it's a start
-- assuming the podcast is good and reliable,
-- which of course is
actually let's just say it upfront,
it's not reliable or good because that way if someone does this and gets hacked,
-- we can be like,
-- oh
-- yeah, we're disclaiming all liability.
-- Yeah, we told you we were a bunch of idiots.
You shouldn't have listened to us.
Yeah, I don't have any errors and omissions insurance. So
it's right.
But I don't live in America. So. Right.
Right. Right. Ok. So you mentioned about don't run your own email
and I'm gonna say it's even more than that,
go out of your way to run as few of your own services as possible.
This is everything from your email to websites, to document hosting, to like
anything. And here's the reason I say this.
So I, I work at Elastic. Right?
And we have a product called Elastic Search which is
used by a lot of people for searching data.
Right now, we have a support organization.
If you need help, you can call them and ask, ask questions. Right
now.
We have a cloud offering and the thing I've really come
to realize is everyone here uses this stuff all day,
every day.
By definition, you are never going to be better than us at running
elastic search because you probably have another job, right?
-- Where that would be part of
-- actually doing something useful with elastic search
well,
and being an administrator,
right? And this is, this is true of every service
on the planet.
If you're, if you're working with, let's say Google for email,
that's literally they have a team, this is all they do.
Unless you have a team dedicated to email, you cannot do as good of a job as them.
Well, the problem is it's not just a team,
they have multiple teams, they have people doing the hardware data center designs,
they have people doing the power design for the data center,
they have the people doing the server design,
they have people doing the operating system,
they have people doing the email service, they have people doing the data storage,
they have people doing the data backups.
You do have a full time backup admin, right. We'll get to that one, you know.
Yeah, exactly. Right.
And then, and then the security team
and then the anti spam and then the anti malware and then, you know, like,
like Google bought virus total, right?
Which is a site where you can go submit a file and it gets scanned by,
I think the last I checked it was like 56 or 63 somewhere in there.
Virus scanners, right?
So for example,
I actually run all of our digital artifacts through
it before we post them to our website,
which is
to make sure.
No, no, no,
you're going to be annoyed because that's not why I do it.
I do it to make sure that we're not triggering any false positives.
No, that's a great reason.
-- I mean, that's, that's part of the reason to do such things,
-- you know,
and also to make sure that we're not shipping something with a virus out because
there's been picture frames in USB key S and God knows
what else that have gone out with viruses in them,
right.
Um So, you know, I really don't want to have the cloud security lines, you know,
distributing an Excel file with a virus in it.
That would be bad.
And that's the thing.
Like, there's no way I can replicate that even anything close to it.
No, it will.
Not only that, how many, how many small businesses don't even have an IT guy,
but rather they're paying someone two hours a week
like you have no chance.
Well,
or a managed service provider and those managed
service providers are like really lowest common denominator.
Like, they're not bad. They're definitely better than not having an IT guy.
-- Well,
-- now, would you consider Google a managed service provider or not?
Um, they're a cloud provider.
So when I say MSP, what my understanding of an MSP is, is like, ok, you know,
I'm a small business.
I need a bunch of it services MSP. You know, we're gonna pay you. What do you charge?
Ok. Well, you recommend Windows small business server or whatever it's called.
We'll have it on site
and they will like, update it and back it up and manage it and like, oh,
I need an account added.
They do that, you know.
Oh, I need like,
you know, all our workstations are locked down. No administrative level access.
So, hey, you know, uh in
accounting needs um
whatever Adobe distiller to create PDF S for invoices or whatever.
So you need to go install that on our machine and like help her you.
So it's essentially your, it department outsourced.
Ok? I mean, that's fair. All right. So anyway, running your own services don't do it.
But, but let's go even farther. I'm gonna tell you if you need email,
you, you should use Google or Microsoft Full Stop.
Right? If someone says I need help, that is, that is what I'm going to tell you to do,
right?
And this is even true of things like dealing with documents don't, don't buy office,
don't use some dodgy office thing, you download it off the internet and,
and I'm even going to say,
like, just use Google Docs
or Microsoft office 365
because like
the trouble you get into trying to maintain and deal
with local office applications as AAA non crazy tech person
is
a huge hurdle.
-- Well, just the
-- bandwidth alone now, right,
every month it's like two or three gigs of office updates for each of my, you know,
I have a five,
I have a five user, whatever license of office 365.
And yeah, so that's like
eight or 10 gigs of data transfer a month alone just for the updates.
And unless you have high speed internet,
I have no idea how you're gonna get those updates.
Uh You just don't,
that's,
that's what happens and, and
right, so, so for real, if someone comes to you and says help me with email,
just Google or Microsoft, I don't,
it's the easiest way and not only that if, if you're the tech person,
they're asking for help,
they're going to screw something up if you have them do pretty
much anything else and then they're going to come to blame you
and then you have to deal with the aftermath, which is no fun.
Yeah.
Well, and the nice thing about Google and Microsoft too is that it's,
it's not just email.
See, that's the problem, right.
This is also what makes me angry about the whole email debate.
People don't want email,
they want email and calendaring and a whole pile of other stuff.
Like ideally document management, document editing, collaboration,
you know, uh,
address book, an address book might be nice
running that because I have had to run that in house.
Yeah, it's,
it's a crazy amount of work to set up something that's kind of just
-- not great. It,
-- it, the solutions are terrible. I agree.
It's, these guys are doing it better than you could ever do.
And I'm sorry if I just made you feel bad.
Oh, I've given up,
I've been an email administrator for over 20 years now and I still run a couple
of email servers because we have one corner case list server doing its little thing.
But
for example, I don't have to back it up because it's just, it's, you know,
it's an explosion list server, right?
Yeah, I mean it's fundamentally I've,
I've been doing email for long enough that like, yeah,
I remember when MX records were kind of new
like I'm pretty old.
Yeah, it's
never again.
Alright.
We're gonna stop beating this horse, but there's one last thing I want to bring up.
Uh never suggest P GP or GP G as a solution for anybody.
So I used to be very pro P GP G
back in the day and now I'm actually kind of, I won't, I don't want to say I'm anti
P GP or GP G
but by and large,
the return on investment of it is very minimal,
assuming you do it correctly and doing it correctly. It's a real
-- pain. It's
-- almost impossible.
And so if you're like super technical, like for example,
I would be comfortable mailing you A P GP message,
P GP encrypted message. I should say
I would not feel comfortable mailing my wife.
Nor do I even want to try to explain to her how to use it.
Right. And so this is one of those, pick your audience if we're
doing. This is
a somewhat normal person,
never suggest P GP GP G Tor or any of those other crazy services because they just,
they're never going to get it.
Well.
And the other thing too is again, you know, for example, uh Google,
I believe it's Google.
Their enterprise level of product
does do
really good email encryption really
seamlessly,
whatever
it just works, you know, with. No, no, no, but within your web browser and stuff. So
it's, and people complain, oh, it's not end to end encryption.
So it's not real encryption, blah, blah, blah, to which I say,
yeah, it's good enough
-- and it is,
-- it's fine. Exactly. Exactly.
And you know what if you really have a secret, you want to tell someone,
don't email it to them,
don't email, don't instant message it.
Because even even there have been the court cases recently with
some politicians that were using signal and you know what,
they didn't clear the signal log so that the government got it anyway.
So just for
like,
talk to people with, if, if you have a secret, just call them on the phone.
But best case it's just go talk to them
in person and then write nothing down anyway. Anyway, let's, let's get to
it. All right. Now, next up I have trusted device
and when I say trusted device I'm not talking about, like,
take the old laptop and put windows on it or something.
I'm saying, buy a surface, buy a Macbook or buy a chromebook. Those are your options.
Well, yeah, I would, I would add to that in general. Um,
if you're, yeah, tablets are a bit
easier to get software updates for because they
tend not to be like carrier locked and,
you know,
the carrier doesn't tend to be between
you and the
-- update. I would,
-- I would fit like it. And even then though I would only suggest
a, a ipad or maybe one of the, the top tier tablets with Android do not run cheap
-- Android tablets, they are
-- trouble. You never get software updates. Exactly.
You know,
and, and something like, what was it?
A major percentage of them are shipping with security flaws anyways.
Like, because they're shipping with older software.
There was an article about that last week. Yeah.
Microsoft Surface, I would say is reasonably acceptable.
Uh, I actually discovered there's so Microsoft Surface comes
by default, generally speaking, running in a mode called,
what was it Windows store mode.
And I'm like, what the heck is that?
Well, as it turns out
it runs
in a way that's kind of like an ipad and that you
can only by default go and install software from the Windows Store,
which in theory is less of a cesspool than the random internet.
And that would be another thing, you know,
this trusted device don't go installing all sorts of random crap on it.
-- Yes,
-- exactly.
I think
if you can get away with it, doing as much as you can in your web browser is I,
and, and this is where I love the chromebook because
all you get is a web browser. I mean, that,
-- that's all there is. It's great.
-- Well, and
the thing is the, the main web browsers now, you know, Chrome Safari,
-- internet explorer and
-- Firefox, internet explorer.
Come on man. Ie
edge.
Yeah. Edge, sorry. Yeah, whatever they rebranded it to.
I haven't used Windows in a very long time since like Windows seven.
I haven't used it.
But yeah, I mean, those,
they basically all have security as a pretty primary concern
and Firefox is even making some changes now to make,
you know, the tracking much more difficult.
So, yeah, when, when we say use a trusted device, basically that boils down to is,
you know,
use a device that gets software updates reliably sort of from a reliable source.
-- You know, be that Microsoft, you're
-- too general for real, you're too general,
I think in all seriousness.
Macbook
surface or chromebook
and, and you could maybe put an asterisk that says, yeah,
get some nice tablets but like
-- those don't have keyboards.
-- Well, see, I, I actually would take it one further.
I would say don't buy, I would say don't, don't buy those, get, get a tablet or a,
an iphone or, uh, like
a, uh, an Android phone that comes direct from Google. That's like
gets the security updates.
I, I would actually, at this point say if you actually do care about security,
don't use a laptop
and, and that's fair. I, I would be comfortable with that advice. So,
there you go.
Sweet.
All right,
let's keep going.
-- And
-- then the password manager thing, of course, because people suck at passwords.
Uh Yes.
Now, not just saying password managers, the,
the three I know of and you might have some other, other, other ones to suggest,
but I know there's last pass, there's one password and there's Dash Lane.
-- I'll even be simpler. I would just go with last pass full
-- stop.
I would be comfortable saying use last pass. I use it,
you use it. We like it. But at the same time, uh,
you know how people are, someone's gonna complain,
someone might complain about these three.
Uh, the, the biggest thing I like about last pass is, uh,
like I used last pass personally.
And we're also deploying it are going to be deploying it hopefully at the CS A and the,
the way they handle multiple accounts actually works quite well.
And that's one challenge with some of these other password managers is if you
essentially want to have like two personas,
like your personal persona and your work persona within it, that does not work.
Uh That, that could be, I don't know, I've never done that
but, and, and I know from my perspective,
the killer for last pass for me is family mode
because that's, that's what I want.
And I,
and I guess family mode ironically is similar to business
mode where multiple people need to access the same secrets.
Yeah, it's just business mode like,
right. And
that's easy enough. And then moving on from there is two factor
-- off, right. If someone, someone asks for help, you tell them to use two
-- factor
off, I'm actually going to go one further with the two factor authentication,
I've been thinking about this a lot
if you have what I would call sort of a high security application.
So for example, my bank account, uh I don't have enough money in it to really be,
you know,
I would not consider it high security.
But if you have, you know,
a business bank account with say several million dollars in it,
I would consider that high security.
Uh, or for example, if you're some high member Muck, a
Muck policy maker with the Democratic Party or whatever,
you know, II, I would think that that counts as sort of a high security application.
And I would say in that case that you're better off
not using two factor authentication based on phone numbers.
And we've kind of gone to this weird situation
where your phone number is your like identity now because
by and large it,
it is unique and works and people tend to hang on to their phone numbers,
especially with number portability in most of the world now.
But fundamentally, your phone number is actually pretty easy
to hijack or to take over
and
it can be done temporarily like at two in the morning.
So you don't even notice that you've been hacked,
you know, and then, and there's a lot of articles where, you know,
people have their number snagged and it just basically turns their life inside out,
right?
Because
how do you prove your identity to all these companies and stuff so
long? And the short of it is
definitely use two factor authentication.
I would say generally speaking,
only use two factor authentication when it's like a hardware token,
like a UB key or the Google Titan
or it's one of the application based ones like Google authenticator or free OTP
where, you know, you basically install it on your phone or tablet.
It generates a, you know, a little shared secret or not a shared secret.
But generates a public private key, blah, blah, blah magic crypto happens
and then you can use that, you know, to authenticate yourself to the remote end.
Um But I would say at this point,
uh
if you have a high security application where
you're actually likely to be sort of targeted,
as opposed to just, you know, randomly people are trying to hack a bunch of accounts.
If you're going to be targeted, then
yeah,
if they figure out what your phone number is, which is not that hard.
Now,
I want to put an asterisk on what you just said because you're right.
However,
making normal people not use S MS could
make things worse.
-- Well, that's why I said high security versus low security.
-- Right. Exactly.
And that's, that, it's important to point that out though.
-- Yeah.
For, if you're gonna be a targeted attack victim, then they're,
they're gonna win there and, and
making basing your security on your phone number
is actually going to make things worse.
But for a normal person like you or me,
it will make things much easier because to put it bluntly, we're not being targeted,
they're just going after the lowest fruit.
And,
and here's the other important thing you said about being targeted is something
like two factor authentication isn't there to stop an attacker like that,
it's there to slow them down enough that you realize what's happening
-- that way you can do things to take actions.
-- Well, or to make it much more. No.
-- Well,
-- that's exactly it. Right. It becomes noisy.
You see something's happening and then you
can take some actions to protect yourself.
You will not stop them. If you just let them go, they will find a way and they will win
guaranteed.
And that's something we forget sometimes.
And then I guess the LA, so the last one on the list then is backups.
Find a, a thing to do backups and, and put them in the cloud and this is, you know,
Apple has time machines.
They've got their icloud, you've got Google Drive,
you've got the Microsoft Onedrive, there's
box, there's pick one, this one that the advice is slightly more squishy.
Yeah, I would say at this point also for,
for most people like doing physical backups is again, kind of
almost worse because the discipline to do it correctly is
so high that almost everybody gets it wrong.
Plus nobody ever verifies their backups when they're physical. Right?
Whereas if it's in Google Drive, it's really easy.
Like, yeah, the file appears to be there and it's not deleted.
Here's,
here's the one thing I'd say though is
Apple has the time machines and they're real easy
and, and lots of device makers, the Nas Box,
but you still have to like physically remove your drive.
Because for example, I know somebody who did it for a company,
somebody broke into the company and stole all their Macs and the
hard drives on the desk
and that's why you need it in the cloud.
Well, exactly. And so they did have off site backups,
but they were, you know,
a few weeks out of date because rotating these things is such a chore that nobody does
it.
Whereas with the cloud it's just, yeah, magically up to date. And,
and furthermore, if you really depend on this data, like I do.
So, for example, for my personal Google account in my domain,
you know, I pay the extra money for Google vault, which basically says
sure. Yeah, you deleted it. Uh huh.
It's gone except it's in Google Vault and we can pull it out for you, right?
So even if you break into my Google account short of deleting the whole thing,
it's I, I can very trivially get it back,
which is hugely important because then if
the ransomware hits or something like that,
you can get back at the data.
So it, it matters.
I
don't know. I, I feel like none of this should be controversial.
Well,
what's really frustrating to me is the honestly everything we said boils down to
go with Google or Microsoft and enable the two
of a
using
a
kind of, that's literally this whole pile boils down to and, and use the password B
that's it.
-- Those are the three pieces of advice
-- and, and I guess the,
the purpose of it is if a normal person asks you for help you.
The advice has to be that simple and that
liable and, and if you want, point them at us
and, and this is what they're going to be, be told.
So, on a side story related, I was at an airbnb, we were at breakfast,
another young couple was there and the topic of computers came
up and apparently his wife's laptop was all bucked up.
Uh, I was like, oh, you know, like what?
And she's like, oh, it's really slow and I need to replace it.
And I'm like, oh, you know, what is it? It was like a Mac from, like, 34 years ago.
And I'm like, oh, that doesn't, you know, that should probably be ok.
Like, what are you doing on this thing? Right. Like, video editing and stuff.
She's like, no, like,
email and, like docs and I'm like,
huh?
And I kind of look at the husband.
He's like, she's only got four gigs of RA M and I'm like, oh, well, yeah,
you should probably upgrade that.
And I'm, I mean, he's like, I know, I keep telling her this.
I'm like, and I look at her and I'm like, yeah, you just need to upgrade your RA M and,
and does it have a sot state drive?
And he's like, no, she needs to get one. I'm like, yeah, you, you really do.
And she's like, she's like, well, but, you know, he keeps saying this is it. Right.
And I'm like, yes.
And,
and that's something I find frustrating is people will ask
other people for advice and then be like me,
I'm not sure I trust you.
But then like some stranger comes along. He's like, yeah, I'm Kurt Herter.
I'm an itu expert. Sure, whatever.
And they like, believe it.
And I just, I don't, uh, I don't know what to do at this point with that.
I,
I have a bit of advice for people suffering from this because I have the same problem.
If you ask me what, I think I will tell you once and if you don't do it,
it's not my problem
and, and I, I deal with this, even people in my immediate family,
it's like I will tell you what to do.
You don't have to listen to me, but I'm not helping you again. Right.
And, and that's the only way to deal with it. You know what? Great? Don't believe me.
I don't care. I will still sleep at night. But like when it lights on fire,
I'm not going to go out of my way to help you because I told
you what to do six months ago and you thought I was crazy and,
and that's actually working very nicely for me because while,
while some people think I'm a bad person,
like, no, I'm not putting my life on hold for your poor choices. End of story.
Well,
fundamentally if people won't listen to the ex and I
think part of the problem too is with computer security,
you know, who are the experts?
There are no experts.
Yeah. And what I love though is the people who actually are experts.
If you ask them, are you an expert? They'll say, like, uh, no, but I'm, I'm ok at it.
-- Right.
-- I'm smart enough to say, I'm not an expert.
Anyone who thinks they're an expert. Yeah. Stay away from those people.
They're dangerous.
Yeah.
-- If they proclaim their
-- expert and, and that's actually another good bit of advice,
right?
Don't, don't,
don't be an expert,
right? Don't be an expert with the perfect advice.
-- Yeah. All right.
-- Maybe point them at the Google security blog. Seriously.
-- All right, man. Any, any parting words
-- just for the love of God people, please please
-- learn to parallel park.
-- All right. That's not exactly related.
I figure once we have parallel parking solved,
then we can maybe solve email security.
We, we will solve it with self driving cars. Humans will never learn exactly.
There we go.
Problem
solved.
When the machines take over, everything will be great.
Well,
yeah. All right. Anyway, thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes for all the crazy stuff we talked about today.
Uh hit us up on Twitter with the Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag And if nothing else, Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day. You too.
-- Thanks everybody. Thanks everyone.
-- Bye bye.