Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
and my partner in working from home for about two decades. Josh Bresser,
what were you saying?
-- I was distracted by cheese that
-- we've both been
working from home uh for about two decades,
for myself since 98.
And I think you were about the same.
I started working from home in 2000 and four.
Oh, ok. You're a latecomer to this.
Indeed.
Yeah, I love when people, you know, they're like,
essentially the work from home thing comes up.
And I'm like, yeah, I've been doing this since 1998 and they're like, what I'm like.
Yeah, like that.
Basically the people that do what I do have a choice in Canada back in the day,
which is you either move to America or you work remotely that seems fair
there just, there isn't this kind, there wasn't this kind of work in Canada.
Were you working from home? In 1998?
-- Most people had dial up internet in 1998
-- Security portal.com.
I was working, I was contracting for security portal.com
and I had high speed internet. Oh, I see. That's, ah, see, I cheated.
I lived in Edmonton, Alberta. I still live in Edmonton, Alberta.
-- And what's interesting. So, there was,
-- we'll put high speed in quotes.
So, no, no, no, no. Here's the thing. Edmonton is fascinating because we had our own
phone company, Edel,
because basically Alexander Graham Bell refused to install phones out here.
So they started a phone company out here that then became a GT tell us blah, blah,
blah.
But we had, the city is split in half by a river.
And traditionally there were two cable companies, Von
and Shaw
and Vide
on had a problem which is
they sold cable TV to everybody that would buy cable TV.
So the only time they got like a significant
number of new subscribers is if somebody built a subdivision
and so they were like,
well, ok, cool. What, what can we sell people to make more money?
Well, the answer is high speed internet and see Von had the foresight
when they built up their physical network,
they installed the bidirectional amplifiers. Most cable companies installed
the unit directional amplifiers that just
amplify the signal going down. Because why?
Well, you'll never,
you're never going to need to amplify the signal coming back
up because that's just not a thing that will happen.
That's right. We'll never do that. But Vide
on
had spent the extra money.
And of course, this is one of those things where it's like, yeah,
a bidirectional amplifier costs a few bucks
more than a unit directional amplifier.
But retrofitting it after the fact costs
like, all the money basically. Right. Like across an entire city.
Like, I can't even fathom the number.
Um, so anyways,
they had this network that was physically capable of deploying cable modems on.
So they did.
So I actually had 10 megabit down one megabit up on metered internet back in 9798.
Right.
Yeah.
And I hate to say this but like on Irc like you annoyed me,
I would just ping flood you just,
and you would disappear
because
-- I'll be blunt, one megabit versus dial up.
-- I mean, look in 1998
it would have been no 1996. It probably would have been, I went to work for an ISP
and it was, it was a big deal because we had a T one which was what, 1.5 megabits, I think
544 megabits.
-- It was 24 bonded.
-- Uh
Yeah, we had a T one to the office
-- 24 bonded
-- channels. It was amazing
because I could download a Linux distribution
in an hour.
Yeah.
No,
it's um they deployed 10 megabit down one megabit up
uh Motorola cable modems that ran hot enough that I,
that's where I get my coffee mug.
They actually had a pretty fat internet pipe but more
to the point nobody was using bandwidth back then.
Oh, yeah. Yeah. Yeah, like
there literally was nothing you could do that would actually consume that
much bandwidth unless you were somebody like me or you who's like,
I'm going to download all the Linux
and also, you know, Napster,
maybe some wares or something like Napster.
That's
honestly,
that's one of the reasons I ran Linux is because it had all the apps I wanted.
No, I know, I know
it, it was, I mean, you think back then all of the Linux software
you had to buy a UNIX Workstation, which was like 40 grand.
I mean,
no, I had a P 100 with eight megs of R AM.
-- Yeah,
-- those are the days. Anyway,
today we wanted to talk about working from home,
which I know isn't exactly a security topic and we pretend we're a security podcast.
But fundamentally,
there has been all this weird talk of working from home and Kurt
and I have literally been doing this for decades at this point.
And we thought
what a fun topic because I feel like everyone talking about it
is
a moron or at least everyone against work from home. That's what I feel like.
So let's get two quick things out of the way. The first one is,
there's a whole bunch of jobs you can't do from home,
like
brain surgery or uh, oh, good one airline pilot.
Not yet. Anyway,
maybe later.
And so I accept that there's not just accept like I get it,
there's a bunch of jobs you can't do from home.
-- Restaurants.
-- Right. Like a chef. You know what I mean? Like, yes, there are
there.
And I want,
we should also point out there are people who don't like working from home.
And that's great too.
There's nothing wrong with working from home,
-- not working from home. The
-- other thing.
Well, and this is a tangent,
but there's also a big difference between choosing to work
from home and being forced to work from home.
Which is interesting because when COVID started,
I've been working from home for over 20 years and within about two or three months,
uh, I remember it was in March, I was,
I realized something was off and I realized what it
was is I was now being forced to work from home
in the sense of I couldn't go out for a cup of coffee once every week or two where I,
you know,
go to a coffee shop and sit and do my work for
an hour or two just to be around people a bit.
That was no longer an option. Right.
And my kids were here all the time doing online school and it was, you know, so, I mean,
and, and I have a house so, I mean, especially if you're stuck in a, in a,
in an apartment with your kids trying to work from home.
God,
no.
Right. I get it. That's not ideal.
The other thing, let's get out of the way is I, I get it.
There's a whole bunch of like, locally,
the government is forcing the government to go back to work downtown because
a
downtown is going to create her out, right?
Like people have to return to the office or
the downtown economy is going to poop itself again.
Like uh and we already had that happen once in Edmonton when
they built West Edmonton Mall out here in the west end
and it, like,
literally vacuumed up like all the stores because it just
had like such a inertia and gravity to it.
But like, literally Edmonton's downtown was dead for about like 10 years.
I mean, that happened in a lot of places due to malls
and w like big box stores will just say I won't necessarily blame Walmart. But
yeah, well, and urban decay and all those other things.
Right. Right. And
it's, it's changing now. But
-- yeah, and
-- so I get that there's a big push like San Francisco is like,
pretty freaked out about,
like, if five or 10% of these tech companies leave
-- real estate rates will crater
-- out.
They won't crater out. The, the return to normal, like
by San Francisco standards is cratering out.
-- Ok. That's fair. Right. Yes,
-- it would.
You know, same with New York.
Yes. Exactly.
Although ironically now because of all the work from home,
the real estate in everywhere else is out of control, which is its own weird problem.
But
anyway, anyway.
Ok. Ok. So I, I agree with your statements.
And then a third thing is that I get that
there are business cultures that don't do work from home,
especially I,
I think basically what our conversation boils down to
is it has to come from the top down
and see. And that's why I, I was able to work from home back in 98.
Is Jim Revis the CEO then of Security portal.com.
Now the CEO of the cloud security lines, he worked from home.
Oh, I didn't realize you worked for Jim back then. That's hilarious.
I've been working, I've been contracting for Jim for, I think now, what is it?
14 or 15
out of the last 24 years?
-- Wow.
-- Like that's
that poor
guy.
I
know.
I know
it's uh
like I knew Jim when he had a blackberry.
Wow.
Wow,
that's,
that's hilarious.
So that's the thing. He worked from home and he needed flexible work time
because he also wanted to be with his family and stuff. And so
he's kind of set that culture and well, that's why I work there
and why I continue to contract for him, you know, because
that flexibility of work life balance. Like he, he not only says it like he means it,
I get that there's a lot of places like,
like those tweets from Boris Johnson were
classic because it's clear that Boris Johnson,
I, I don't know that he has a DH D but it's clear that the man cannot like,
work unsupervised.
-- No, that's, that's all I got.
-- Maybe
I, I wonder this. So,
the thing I always think of
is if you look at Boris Johnson, he appears to be a bumbling idiot,
but he's clearly not
a great person.
He went to impressive schools. He's clearly a very smart person.
I mean, I always think of the,
when he was asked about his hobbies and he said he paints
pictures of buses
and it was clearly a way to Google bomb away some bad press of his. And, and like
before or since none of us have ever seen a picture of Boris Johnson's painted buses,
which
if you do, you know, if you have a hobby like that,
you show people and you don't stop talking about it because that's just how it works,
right?
It's like,
actually, it was very funny. I'm just reminded of a little side tangent.
There is a picture on,
I think on Reddit
where
it was one of the, would you recommend windows to your friends?
And someone clicked, you know? No.
And then it was,
please explain your answer and they said you don't need to understand
like us normal people don't walk around talking about our operating systems.
And the first comment was like, have you ever talked to a Linux person?
You know,
I laughed out loud,
but
it was like, I totally get that
but, but anyway,
and so my suspicion is not that Boris Johnson can't work from home.
There's probably something else going on here because he's probably smart
enough to not actually be distracted by cheese and coffee.
Even though I will say I do
cheese and coffee
is
work from home.
Forces you to have better process because you can't paper over cracks.
So a great example of this is, this is my favorite story and I've told it before. But
long story short, I was working at, I was contracting for a place
and I was on a conference call and my
then manager was very upset because he's like her,
you don't seem to read these emails.
I have to email you myself personally and then you finally do it.
And I'm like,
I read every email from you and I do what you
tell me to because you guys pay me and like that's,
that's kind of how this works, right?
Transactional relationship.
And he's like, it's like every email to the at home list. You don't read it.
And I'm like the what now list
and he's like, you guys, can we check if Kurt's on the at home list?
And they're like, no, he's not.
And so he apologized and he's like, can we please put Kurt on the at home list?
You know, to tell people what to do. But that's the thing working from home.
Like I have a very
simple policy of if you don't put it down in writing to me, it doesn't exist.
And I don't mean Slack. Slack is too ephemeral. Like, either it's an email or a ticket
and if it's like, if it's not captured,
like if you don't tell me in a way that it gets captured doesn't exist.
And I've trained people to do this
and it works really well, but it takes a lot of discipline to do that
And a lot of places don't have that kind of
culture.
You know, they, they sort of discuss things around the water cooler, but they don't
how many places take good meeting minutes and distribute the meeting minutes
or archive them in a place that you can easily find them.
I mean, it's, it's very uncommon,
I think in the business world for that to be the case if,
if you look at organizations like the Cloud Security
Alliance or many of the Linux Foundation's working groups,
they actually do a really good job of this because they have to,
you know, because they're, they're completely virtual
well. And I think coming from the open source world too. So that's the other trick.
You and I are both open source freaks.
Open source has been work from home since ever.
And I count the people working in open source who are
in offices as work from home because they're collaborating remotely anyways,
like they may physically be at an office because it's not like the Linux kernel,
they don't have an office.
Like some of the contributors probably work together
in offices because it's big enough now.
But like back in the day, like in 19 nineties and two thousands, you know, that
it's so spread out, it has to be virtualized and distributed.
Right.
That's right. And
it used to amuse me to no end when I started working at Red Hat
and I would ask someone something who I knew was in an office
because I, I worked, I worked remote the whole hours at Red Hat.
I started there in 2004
and I'd ask someone something in the office and then I
just seen them send an Irc message and it's like,
well, I can freaking do that like, yeah, exactly.
That was the culture, right?
Even if you were in an office,
you still used IRC to communicate because that was the way you communicated.
I remember being at a P
to own
in Vancouver in a
office or in a uh in the hotel room with my then boss
and we're writing up like there's this really bad zero day the drop.
So we had to write it up and analyze it.
And we were using Irc and we were sitting 6 ft apart from each other.
-- I, I have no problem with that because that was
-- our culture.
Like we were both just silently sitting in this hotel room,
politely ignoring each other,
banging away on our laptops trying to get this thing out.
And I, like, literally at one point forced myself to turn to him.
And I was like, I need, I need to go buy a Pepsi.
He's like, don't waste your time, call room service.
And I, you know, call him and like, the minimum is a six pack.
He's like, he's like, I don't care. Just, we need to get this out in the next hour.
Like, I don't care that we're,
it was like $20 for that Pepsi.
And he's like, I don't care, we just need to get this out. Whatever.
That's money well spent. Like, it's, that's the culture, right?
It's like we used Yeah, IRC and everything was captured and text and
like, I had a deaf coworker and I'm like,
he sends out an email saying I'm deaf. So if you come to my office, you need to like,
physically get my attention because like, if like, I can't hear you, I can read lips,
but I can't read lips if I'm not looking at you.
And I, like, I remember literally contacting my RC and I'm like,
I hate to say this but like, you're really deaf.
He's like, yeah, I'm like, oh, I had no idea. Cool
because like, I work remotely with the, with him. Like, how would,
right?
And that's one thing I love about work from home is
I've, I've worked with people with, you know, various
different abilities or lifestyles.
Don't know or care they get good work done.
And I think that's part of it is, it removes that
sort of it in some ways, removes that social aspect, which can also, I think,
be very good.
Yes. Now I want to shift the conversation a little bit because
rather than
pining upon all of the benefits from work, work from home,
which clearly we are enormous fans of,
I think and,
and we won't even get into all of like the Daily commute and the grind and all that.
Let's ignore that.
So
I, I, what I find the most interesting
is you brought this up at the beginning where you're talking about,
the government is making people go to
downtown because they're worried downtown will suffer.
And I think that I think
when we hear everyone talk about work from home, that's not what they talk about.
There's always some other reason.
It, it's, we need camaraderie, we need culture, we need
-- less cheese, whatever
-- face to face communications. Right.
Right.
I feel like what we're actually witnessing is people know this is coming,
I think they know there's nothing they can do about it.
And they're actually worried about
the, the 3rd and 4th order
things that are going to
like an easy example is if I'm a big Silicon Valley company
and I just built a brand new building
and then all my workers had to go home
and we'll say this is all theoretical of course,
-- I just built this brand new, beautiful building. The windows don't
-- open.
-- Yeah, nothing to do with the fruit company,
-- right? Shaped like a rib maybe
and,
-- and everyone goes home and I'm like
-- located at one infinity wave, right?
We just built this big expensive fancy building.
Like you all need to get your asses back in here and people are like, we don't want to.
What do you do?
You just, you have this huge capital expense,
you literally cannot sell this building to anyone because
even like there's just no market for it.
-- What do you do?
-- Well, and I think there's worse things too.
So, so many companies like Red Hat
pay remote people based on where they are.
And so for example, somebody living in America,
even within different parts of America gets different pay, you know,
and vastly more pay compared to say somebody in India or
some other, you know, quote unquote cheaper country.
And so what's interesting is some companies are now,
uh like airbnb basically announced we're going to be
work from home if you want or you can,
you come into the office if you're that kind of crazy, but sure, whatever,
but we're gonna pay you based on what you're worth, not
where you live.
And I think that's one big problem for a
lot of these companies because they've historically trenched incomes
because, well, let's talk about pay a little bit.
I remember working at Red hat.
And you and I both knew that we were making quite a
bit more than some of our coworkers doing basically the exact same work
-- just in different parts of the world.
-- They lived in a different country.
I know.
-- I know.
-- And that struck me as kind of desperately unfair.
It's completely unfair, I think.
And what's funny? So, here again,
you end up with this argument where people are complaining
in small towns like where I live, I live in Green Bay, Wisconsin
where there are people coming in from
large cities that are getting paid
five times what the local rate might be
and they're just writing checks for houses because they're like,
look how cheap the property is.
-- This is great. Like I'll take that house there,
-- please.
We have that problem in Canada with, you know,
uh foreign investors coming to Toronto and
Vancouver because real estate in Canada is,
it's a real safe thing to invest in.
Like it's gonna go up
-- and Canada is a nice boring country with
-- healthcare, right? Oh, no, no, I, I get it.
And so like again, we get to that like 2nd and 3rd
a problem
that all of this creates
and
I,
I am sensitive to this problem because I think
that like there are definite housing problems in many,
many parts of, of, of the world.
But I also know that
the answer to this is not, oh, just stop working from home like that's,
that's out of the question. Right. That's like that would be like saying when
New York City in the early 19 hundreds started building subways
and the people who fed and cared for horses in
the city were going out of business being like,
oh, everyone just stop taking the subway.
Like, no, this is a change that is coming. There's nothing you can do about
it in that other industry while necessary in the past.
Like, it needs to change.
Well, see, this is one of my hopes is, I mean, right now in western Canada, you know,
small towns are bleeding out because
living there kind of sucks.
And,
you know, there's, I mean, there's been articles for a decade or two about, you know,
the entire graduating class of the
small Saskatchewan town is leaving after graduation
and the town is happy about it because their kids have a future now.
Oh,
yeah.
Right.
But the town knows that they're basically gonna
die because all the young people are moving away
but they're happy about it because what's the alternative
you live in this town with no industry.
Well, a lot of,
a lot of rural communities don't take that particular attitude towards
the change occurring around them. But
no,
but I, I
would like to hope that we have better housing policy,
things like UB I universal basic income.
And I know that's not going to be the case and I know it's going to be messy and painful.
You know,
we've already got resort towns here in Alberta where nobody can afford to live.
Same thing in the US in Colorado and stuff. There's ski towns where literally
nobody that works there can afford to live there.
And so what's interesting though is it becomes, it,
it actually seems to correct relatively.
Well, not,
I'm not going to say it corrects relatively
quickly but the pain becomes known relatively quickly
when you have a town full of rich people and nobody to work at the restaurants.
-- I mean,
-- we're, we're seeing that now. I, I don't know how this ends.
We're gonna, we're gonna find out because
-- like it's coming, well,
-- like I said,
hopefully we see some intelligent housing policy and stuff.
I'm not going to hold my breath though.
Yeah, I'm, I'm not either. I mean, but ok, anyway, I don't, I don't want to do it.
I want to get into government policy around housing because it's,
it's not only depressing but it's unsolvable by us, obviously.
Well, and I think that's what's so fascinating to me about work from home. Is it,
it's such a fundamental shift in reality. Like,
both my sons have been doing online school and it really
works for Felix and it doesn't work for Wolfgang at all.
And that's another story.
But how is somebody going to hire Felix when
he's done 2.5 or three years of online school
and tell him he has to come into the office to work, like, unless he's a, you know,
like he was a brain surgeon, he'll be like, yeah, obviously.
But,
you know, chances are statistically white collar work.
Yeah, you can do that from home.
Well, and that's what's going to happen. I think that, that, that's one of the points
that, that's on my list was
if you look at the future generations,
if you're an organization saying you have to move to,
you know, somewhere in California to work for us, they're going to be like, well,
I'm just not going to work for you then like, whatever who cares?
-- You
-- know,
I can't afford it. And B
I have to rip up.
The other thing too is
because we're at the CS A, we're hiring right now and it's, you know,
the CS A is based out of a small town called Bellingham.
There's not a lot of cloud security talent in a, you know,
and all the cloud security talent in that area has
been hoovered up by Microsoft and Amazon in Seattle,
right?
Like they're the, you know,
they have this massive gravity and they just suck in everybody, you know, I mean,
Amazon to the point where they had to open up a second headquarters
because essentially everybody that lived in Seattle that would work for them,
works for them and everybody that would move to Seattle
has already moved to Seattle and works for them.
And they literally can't get more people there.
And so they
opened up their second headquarters,
you bring this up. And here's an interesting point to think about is so
back in the early days of Silicon Valley,
the idea was we will move to this area because that's where the talent is, right?
Like we have to move to where the talent is in effect.
Microsoft specifically went to Redmond Washington
because
they wanted the people they hire to not be able to easily switch jobs.
Right?
And ironically then because they went there,
it built up this whole industry in the area with,
I mean, I remember reading a history of the company Nintendo at one point
and they were looking for someone to put their offer.
They're like, oh, Seattle Microsoft is there. It must be a cool tech place.
Like, no, actually it's the opposite.
But, you know, it was the beginning and that is true.
I mean, I remember like back in the nineties when I first started working, no,
it was the early two thousands when I got my, I got out of college and got my job,
there was this thing they called the Valley shuffle where like every six months
you'd get a new job somewhere in Silicon Valley and
you, you knew all the people because you'd work with them somewhere else before.
Right?
And everyone just kind of kept moving around
in this weird shuffling nature throughout Silicon Valley.
And
it it's very interesting because with a concept, like, work from home
you don't have to go to San Francisco anymore to find talent.
You can literally find the talent
anywhere, anywhere they are.
Yeah. No, we, we interviewed four people and they were scattered all over the US.
Yeah, that's awesome.
Like from Florida to, I want to say Colorado to somewhere in the middle ish,
you know, the Midwest, whatever. That is. That big giant blob of
-- stuff you fly over mostly
-- we, we have the Great Lakes. It's very nice.
Yeah, I've been there. I do like it.
But, um, and I think part of it is there's,
I mean, if you thought adoption of enterprise software took a long time,
adoption of new corporate culture
and as you've pointed out, like,
you can't change corporate culture without some sort of massive,
like,
call to action or existential threat that
-- they actually understand or
-- maybe a pandemic.
But even then, like, how many, like, what blows my mind is we've had
so many things have improved.
Like for one of my favorite things is, is all the medicines
here. Now, the vast majority of them do
no more walking appointments.
You have to make an appointment or better, you make an online appointment.
And I get, again,
there are certain things where you want to go into the doctor and have them like,
poke it or palpitate it or like, see, you know, that, that is a weird color, you know,
but there's a lot of things that you can do over the phone.
Like I, you know, I wanted to go get my, uh, uh, a vaccine for pneumo cocoa
and, you know, talked with my doctor quickly about it.
He's like, yeah, you know,
you should probably get that because you're prone to a lung infection.
So,
that would be good, you know, five minute phone call done. Right.
Otherwise if I go and see him, even without waiting, it's still an hour round trip.
Yeah.
You know,
and I have to sit in a waiting room with potentially sick people. So
I
know
there's a lot of places that are getting
like rid of these improvements that they made,
especially in the government.
Like the government is reopening offices so the
public can physically come back to visit.
And it's like, but wait, you managed to go two years without people visiting.
Why do we need to go back to that?
Right. Well, because we have to provide service to people. Yeah.
But you provided service to people for
two years without them physically being there.
Well, sometimes, I mean, you also have to admit that there were
many,
I guess, like,
donate whole events in government services during the
pandemic where people slipped through the cracks and,
and there were a lot of problems, I'm not going to say it was flawed
but,
but
you are, you are correct to a degree that I think
if you look at everything that happened during the pandemic,
there was a remarkable amount of society that
managed to function with everyone working from home.
And
I think it was one of those things, if you would have told people this was a case,
they would have been like no way.
That's impossible. But because we had to do it, we did it.
I know some of the numbers, but basically at this point,
there are some government offices that are open
that are seeing like two people a day.
And I'm like, why don't you just, you know,
do that thing in France where you call it and
a doctor shows up at your doorstep an hour later,
like that would be cheaper and the person was like, yes, it, it would be cheaper.
It would be much better service obviously because like,
right,
but, you know,
the government doesn't want or can't do that because it's seen as being too nice.
That is the sad truth.
Like who gets that white glove service? So
I,
I fear like
there are so many things where people are trying to, you know,
sort of shove it back to normal and especially managers with
bums and seeds because I was reading some papers about this.
And so
historically,
every measure of power at companies and organizations boils down to head count.
-- Yep.
-- Yep. Absolutely.
With a second one being budget.
But even if you have a big budget, but no head count people don't take you seriously.
Right. You need the people for sure.
Yeah. And I think that's a big part of it is that,
that
there's a lot of managers out there that aren't very good at managing.
Oh, yes.
Unquestionable. That's it. I'm going to leave it at that.
I mean, you know what, this makes me think of. So,
if you look at a lot of, I'll pick on call centers because II,
I have some examples of this.
I've heard of where
you had a very hierarchical,
hierarchical, hierarchical, that's
right
structure
in these call centers, right?
We have the people doing the work and then they have supervisors
and then the supervisors and managers and the managers have managers and,
you know, there's like 20 layers of stuff, whatever
and
when
the pandemic hit
and everyone goes home all of a sudden now it's like, wait a minute,
what is the supervisor actually doing if they're not like
walking around yelling at people to get back to work?
Right? Because now you have just, you're looking at the metrics, like
you answered four phone calls in an hour, everyone else answered 10.
You're clearly slacking off, you know what I mean?
And so I think you also see these situations
where it's that self preservation aspect where people are,
like, if I'm not in an office,
they're gonna figure out I'm not actually doing any work, you know,
because like I need to be walking around and yelling at people.
That's my job.
Yeah,
that's one thing I love is all
these places that clearly can't measure productivity.
And
again, I've read a bunch of papers on this.
We've never figured out a good way to measure white collar productivity because
like, if you look at as well, infosec is a great example.
You look at infosec, what's the value?
Well, the CS A hasn't been knowingly hacked.
OK. What's the value of that?
No, I, I agree. Actually, I've got, I've got a good one for you.
This is, this is a treat.
So
there's a, an issue in one of the open ssf repos where they're talking about
what is the right number of maintainers for a project to make it
good,
right?
Oh,
easy. Seven,
whatever.
Seven,
shut up.
So
someone asked this question and of course, everyone's like, oh,
it's a good question actually, you know, it is a good question,
but here's the thing and, and everyone's like, oh, we should pick a number
and I, I chime in of course because
II I, everything obviously and I'm like, actually I have all this N PM data
and of the 28 million N PM package releases that have happened in my data set.
Do you want to guess how many of those have one maintainer tied to them?
I'll be somewhere between 90 95%.
And I would assume a lot of those actually are tied,
like there's multiple packages tied to one maintainer.
You have to pick a number, you can't say 95 percent.
Sorry, what do you say of 28 million releases?
I'm going to go with about like 20 I'm going to say 23.
-- No,
-- it's 1616 million,
but 16 million
way
-- lower than I would guess. It
-- is kind of, I,
I
disagree with that, but it's a huge number, right? 16 million of those releases.
And
so
I point out there is a couple of issues now in, in thinking about this,
of saying number one,
we don't really have any data that says, does the number of maintainers even
directly influence the goodness or badness of an open source project?
Like we think it does, but we don't actually know,
I don't mean to be rude but have you defied good or badness?
Not yet.
No, that
that's part of the conversation.
-- Ok,
-- because I'm like, but
I, I think here's the thing is
insecurity. We have
a notoriously bad habit of just like making crap up and saying, well, more,
more maintainers feels better.
So let's say five or more. But
is it, I mean, how you making stuff up
isn't valuable
and I feel like a lot of this work from home or work in the office and everything,
like obviously, I want to say, oh, working from home is better
and for my mental health, I, I don't doubt it is but you know what I mean? Like,
we don't really have a lot of data, I think at this point,
the only reason we really got to where we were is because society shut down for a year.
And when we looked around, we're like,
actually this isn't so bad. Like we want to keep doing this, you know what I mean?
But is there data proving one thing or another? Like there really isn't?
Well,
Microsoft and some other companies have really studies showing
that productivity went up or basically stayed the same,
some have claimed that, you know,
kind of productivity was the same or better but like, you know,
like
creativity was down or whatever, that means those kind of things, you know,
and again, I get it like there's certain, like,
like if you're part of a design team that normally meets in a, you know,
in a room and brainstorms physically together on a white board,
you can't rep like I'll be blunt, you cannot replicate that with technology out.
And I've looked into it because II I looked
into like the highest end smart boards and everything
and they're flaming hot garbage compared to
a $200 white board with people physically present
-- the
-- metaverse. Sorry,
the metaverse,
-- maybe one day once we have
-- in all seriousness,
that's probably the best chance right now, but not right now.
But uh no, I, I agree.
And in fact,
you say that and a huge number of video
game companies have delayed releases by years because they,
they're creative, people were struggling to get the creative work done from home.
So I agree, there's, there's totally, in fact, I was just at an all hands last week
through the magic of podcasting. No one knows there was an absence
but like,
I was on site for a week and it was absolutely
amazing being next to people and talking to them and,
and the, the human interaction, of course, I'm like,
completely exhausted now because I haven't been anywhere in two years and it like,
drained me so much.
But yeah, I, I agree.
There is immense value in humans being together in a room but not every day.
Well, part of that is that
so I call it,
I call it the, oh by the way, effect of when you're face to face with somebody,
they will say, oh, by the way, and then a super critical thing that you need to know,
right?
Or some problem that's been bugging them for years and you can solve in 20 minutes.
And the thing is I will literally put in emails, like, is there any, oh, by the way,
kind of things like pain points, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Or when I'm on, you know, calls with people, I will ask them, I'm like,
is there anything else, like,
no matter how weird or strange or painful or unpleasant or whatever
that you want? To bring up or mention to me or email to me
and then sometimes they do, sometimes they don't.
But again, having the discipline to do that and to ask that and to kind of,
I think part of it too is people are afraid
to put things in writing that they will say to your face.
Yeah, I, I, yes, I agree with that. And
I think in all seriousness, Kurt,
that is one of our superpowers.
And I've talked to people about this at length because you and I
have no shame in looking dumb.
I mean, obviously you couldn't have a podcast if you were even because we are, I mean,
that, that's what we tell people obviously.
But you know what I mean?
Like I will just spout nonsense into slack and it's not necessarily because I'm
trying to show I'm smart or something, it's to encourage
other people to get involved in some way.
And
I find
like in the morning, I will put a stupid meme in slack or something like that. And
90% of the time it elicits responses.
Whereas if no one says anything, it's, it's crickets and I think
part of working from home
is
making interactions happen sometimes.
So you have to force it where when you're in an office you're not forcing it.
It's magically happening as you go get coffee.
But that doesn't exist.
You have to give some,
sometimes you just got to give it a little poke
with a stick and it goes a really long way.
And you also have to recognize, you have to be able to look stupid because you will.
And that's scary and hard.
Especially for new people and young people in any organization. Luckily I'm old
and I don't care.
Well, when you think about it,
humans have had thousands of years of face to face interactions of like,
one of my favorite things is most people can with
almost no effort tell where somebody else's eyes are looking,
right?
Like there's a big chunk of the brain devoted to basically figuring
that out because it's really important in face to face interactions,
to kind of read body language and stuff, not everybody can do it.
You know, I have a son with autism and
right, it's, it can be challenging for some people
but,
and the technology, especially for real time communications, like,
let's start with the phone basically being, you know, kind of the first one, right?
Because I don't think telegram, you know, and letters and stuff kind of, you know,
the,
that's not a real time thing
that's only been around real and available to
people for like really less than 100 years.
Like the majority of people
didn't have access to that stuff on the regular in a, in an affordable way.
You know, I remember when phone calls, like local,
like I've lived in countries where local calls were charged by the minute.
Oh, man. I know.
And so I think part of it too is we've only like,
even in you, you read accounts of World War Two.
You know, people were lucky to get one letter a month from home
or, you know, and people working together clearly, we're not, you know,
working together
remotely like we can now.
And so
we're, we're fighting thousands of years of,
of evolution and of cultural and social conditioning.
You know, my favorite thing is zoom fatigue and I,
I firmly believe zoom fatigue is due to the fact
that your brain is desperately trying to read body language
-- off of a potato quality video.
-- Probably
I, I, yeah, I have no doubt.
And, and so it's hard and it's exhausting because you have to do things a new way.
You have to learn things a new way and you have to be very
explicit and you have to be very declarative. You have to,
you know,
nobody's gonna see you on a Zoom call and notice that you're kind
of slumped or feeling down whereas they would notice that immediately in person.
-- Yep,
-- it's true.
It's true.
And, and I guess on that note, no one noticing we're slumped or, or feeling down
is
it's time to end the show.
So
thank you, Kurt. Thank you ever for listening. Go to over
social security podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes,
Pondo
Podcast. Hashtag just hit us up on social media.
Kurt, you have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too and remember to send out meeting agendas everybody.
Yeah, that's my number one pet peeve meetings with no agenda. What
is
that?
Alright? Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the.