Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 186
with myself Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime,
Josh Pretzer.
-- Hey,
-- Kurt. And I am so excited today. I've got a co worker of mine.
Actually,
his name is Tony Meehan and he is someone who came to Elastic as part of an acquisition
endgame, which does it end point security.
And I'm, I'm very excited for you to be here, Tony.
-- So say hello and introduce yourself.
-- I am also very excited to be here.
I've been binge listening to the podcast.
I'm so sorry. No, it's great.
I seriously like I even my daughter has been listening to it on the car at home.
-- So make a written apology. Now, y you
-- do, she actually does expect that.
Um So I'm, I'm excited to be here. So I'll give you maybe my background.
I, I came over from endgame, like you said,
I had been there for about six years from 2014 to
I guess October of last year and previous to Endgame,
I was at the National Security Agency
office called Tailored Access Operations for about 10 years there,
we were working on computer network
exploitation tools to collect foreign intelligence.
So it's kind of, it was fun to go from that job to add in game,
kind of sitting on the other side of the table.
Well, actually I think that's one of the most important things.
So I've seen so many computer security people only do either attacker
or defense
and then they don't really have a good understanding of the other side. Yeah.
So I remember my last day
in Tao, I was in Rob Joyce's office. So Rob Joyce at the time
was the chief of Tao. So kind of like the CEO of the company for, for that office.
And by the way, if you, if you don't know who that is, you should go watch his 2016 UN
talk
on uh I forget what the title was, but something about understanding Attackers.
He, he's great. So I remember sitting in his office
and telling him like, it's, this is weird for me
going from 10 years of doing this job
to now kind of being the adversary scaring the
out of myself, basically in my former job. Like that was the transition I was making
and it was tough, right?
Primarily because you're coming from a, you know, highly classified
office. And
so you have to kind of segment in your mind, certain things.
But I just remember him being very gracious and we still keep in touch.
He's always trying to get me to come back. So I, I miss that place.
I, I learned so much there.
-- It was awesome. That's
-- awesome.
Ok.
I wanna start
with Endpoint because anyone who's listened to episodes of this podcast
know that Kurt and I have railed on antivirus a lot
and I would say we, I,
I don't know if we've gone after endpoint specifically at any point in time,
but I will, I, I, I'll kind of, I'll tell you my story and we can, we can start there.
So obviously, I think antivirus is a tire fire.
And I've historically not been,
it's, it's not a secret
and
I've historically not been a huge fan
of Endpoint software because generally speaking,
it's one of those things that in most situations gets in the way
and it uses up a bunch of resources and it's just, it's a huge pain in the butt.
I would compare it to Se Linux is another one of my favorite whipping
boys where it's like this is a technology that in theory is good,
but in reality, often gets in the way more than it doesn't.
And it's actually better now.
I shouldn't say that for any Se Linux devs listening, like you guys are doing great.
Keep it up.
But anyway, so for Endpoint, we got it at elastic and I was like, oh,
this crap and we started out with crowdstrike and it
kind of sucked and it used a lot of resources.
And in fact, when I would take my laptop off the dock,
I saw a noticeable drain in the battery
and then we eventually switched over to endgame,
obviously.
And I,
I don't know, it, it, it's really impressive. It uses very little resources.
I'm on Linux obviously.
And in fact, one of the things I did was I was running this thing called Metric beat,
which just collects all this information about
like running processes on your system.
And it was struggling to graph the CPU use of the endgame agent because it was so low,
which I thought this is, this is madness, right?
So anyway, why don't you kind of let's let,
let's talk about endpoint and what it is
and why it's not antivirus and we'll say it is
not completely terrible.
Yeah. Well,
it's, it's an interesting question.
I, I think it's actually taking a step back,
maybe worth thinking about it kind of in the context of like a broader timeline,
like when I, when I joined Tao
around
2005. So I think
Windows XP service,
he had just come out
like they enabled the fireball by default. I think people probably
use zone alarm. I don't know if you guys remember that
I was a user of zone alarm.
-- Yeah,
-- I did too.
I think they started doing like weird pop ups
and stuff like scaring people into buying more.
But anyway,
so I think it's interesting to think about antivirus kind of in a broader term,
going back, at least around that time frame to now because it's evolved a lot.
I will also
with a sentiment, it's ok to think a, you know, a V as a, as a dumpster fire.
I, I actually think that a lot of security products,
if not all of them have weaknesses,
all of them can be bypassed by a determined adversary.
It doesn't matter
if someone wants to get your data,
it will happen if they care and they have resources to do it.
Kind of putting it to the broader context.
It's interesting to think about the evolution because in the beginning,
antivirus actually was effective, you know,
signatures and engines to find malware that that worked for a while.
It was enough to mitigate some of the risk.
But I also think that maybe people didn't quite understand
just how much of the cake adversaries were eating,
I guess probably the problem wasn't really well known at the time, I guess.
Maybe I would
maybe qualify my answer a little bit.
The antivirus seemed to be ok, but it actually probably wasn't.
I
think one of the big concerns I had with antivirus is
I don't care so much if it's effective or not effective.
But does it actively make my situation worse? Which a lot of antivirus products do?
Like they, they literally, they introduce worse security flaws?
That's absolutely right.
But they're also really good at mitigating sort of the targets of
opportunity where if someone's not really after you,
but instead you're sort of the 100th person targeted, like,
maybe you'd be ok because the first couple that
were attacked antivirus lab signatures for them and,
and
you'll be protected if you're not the first one to get attacked. Yeah.
I mean, yeah, it was obviously pretty easy for Attackers to bypass and get around.
So it's evolved over time, I think now,
you know, if you fast forward to the last couple of years, you know,
Gartner sort of has the, the definitions of endpoint protection platform
and endpoint detection and response. So PP and EDR,
so the idea here is we have products out there today,
some antivirus products, you know, like Kaspersky is in this group,
but you have others in game certainly was in it now elastic
of endpoint protection platforms.
The whole idea there is you just wanna stop known and unknown threats.
You want it to be as automated as possible.
You don't want to, you don't want people touching it
deployed everywhere and solve as much of the problem
as you can just sort of set and forget.
And then the EDR side of it, you almost think of it like
for an attack if, if you have something bad happening and you're not absolutely sure
it's a real threat.
You present that to someone that maybe has some experience,
they've done threat hunting or incident response before and they
can kind of look at an alert and say,
ok, what, what's going on here?
What is this?
Let's look at everything that happened before that,
everything that happened after that,
it,
it kind of gives over some of the control to a person that
has some context and some experience and the market is kind of converging.
So those most like if you say a crowd strike or if you said elastic Endpoint security,
it's sort of meant to do both of those kind of what you cited earlier.
In order to actually have any impact on an endpoint,
you need be a steward of its resources.
You can't use a whole lot of CPU or memory.
Otherwise you, the it team is not going to allow you to be deployed.
So that's sort of your job number one and then job
number two is to not only stop known and unknown threats,
but also
give some tools to
more sophisticated users to kind of do an investigation to kind of understand what,
what's happening.
If you see something that's not entirely easy to convict, but you, you,
you know, have some suspicions. So that was a rambling answer. But I
know
that's great. I guess given my background, it's just sort of security is tough.
I think you had a podcast a couple of weeks ago about
the defender is always going to be behind like you're hopeless.
It's hopeless.
That's right.
Let's all give up you had the authors of
the fifth domain that we're talking about how,
you know, the fifth domain being cyberspace,
humans have some control over when we built this domain.
So we have to have some kind of influence over it to
kind of give us some competitive advantage against an adversary as defenders.
We thought that was an interesting concept. I never thought about that before.
So I I also want to clarify a point about
endpoint detection is that these end points that run on the systems, they're not
kind of old school antivirus.
We've got a huge list of signatures and I'm just going to look for files,
they watch behaviors on systems and then that behavior can be sometimes stopped
or just logged so someone can look at it later or there's, there's kind of a,
a bunch of things that can happen here, which I think is fascinating
where
rather than like looking at, oh, there's a virus on the disk, you're saying?
Oh my goodness, you know, this process like Excel is running powershell.
That should never happen. Like let's explode. Which is, that's cool.
I mean, the classic current example is Jeff Bezos cell phone suddenly using more,
you know, cell
No,
really, right.
When you, you know,
it went from like what a couple 100 kilobytes per day or something to gigabytes,
you know, and that's what always drives me nuts when I,
when I read about these attacks, you know,
where some major company gets attacked and it's like, oh, yeah.
And then we, you know, we looked at our network logs and, yeah,
we saw a couple of gigabytes or terabytes of data
going into this weird IP in Russia or China.
-- Yeah,
-- I mean, EDR
is all about minimizing the time that passes
between getting breached and knowing about it.
Like that's, that's its primary goal. You want that to be as,
that, that window to be as small as possible.
This is a san statistic mind you, but I'll,
I'll try to dig it out and put in the show notes.
But I just saw a graph,
I think yesterday on Twitter where they were showing kind of the,
the dwell time on attacks right now is down from 200 days to 100 days, which is
like,
that's still really bad, but that's progress, right?
So there's actually kind of a cool story here
around 2015
endgame.
So this was around the time when we started
building, building our products,
we had endgames made several pivots in the course of its history.
And sort of the last pivot we made
was to build an endpoint detection response product.
But the,
the story on how we developed, it's kind of interesting, you know,
our history at endgame was sort of we made bullets before we made bulletproof vests.
So we were kind of doing some offense before we were doing defense.
And so the air force would partner with us on the
red team and they would do these massive exercises called red flag
where we would help the red team and the red
team just crushed every time they were very good.
The Air Force sort of started asking us, hey,
we want to start helping the blue team. What can you do?
I just remember sitting in a conference room with,
with some other engineers or sort of like, well,
what can we do that the product that we had built?
You know, it was really good at sort of the detection and response side,
like investigating what had happened.
But if you want to stand up against a really effective red team,
you kind of have to prevent some of the
things that they do and you can't do signatures.
Like that's not,
that's not gonna work because you have no idea what they're going to do.
You have no clue. So you kind of have to think, ok, well,
what are some common things that adversaries like to do
and how do we stop that? So the first thing we thought of
was OK. Well, they're probably going to inject some code into a legitimate process.
They're probably gonna do some process injection.
Well, how do we stop that?
So that, that's what we focus on the, how do we build a feature like that
into a product that would sort of
stop common behaviors or techniques that adversaries employ
without really knowing about
the actual tools that
they were going to use.
That's what we did. And
I just remember I was actually at the exercise kind of helping the tool,
helping the product that we built, um, get used.
And the red team was pissed. They were.
And,
but the thing was that the product was so early
that it was really hard for me and the other folks to kind of say, oh yeah,
it was definitely us.
So during the exercise,
we actually provided an update that would generate an
alert for it whenever it was in prevent mode.
And so we finally got credit for it after a couple of days. But I just,
that was sort of our evolution to this thinking
about this problem is that your signatures aren't going to work because
you have no idea what the adversary is going to do,
no clue.
But there are common techniques that people employ. And it's still true to this day,
you know, a lot of living off the land techniques that people employ where
MS build or cert util on windows like they're installed everywhere.
And so people, you know, adversaries now will instead of bringing over some
exc and dropping it to disk and having that sort of susceptible to standing by a V or
end
point. Instead
they'll drop an XML file and have MS build, you know,
do something in memory that accomplishes the same goal,
but evades most detection So, again, it's sort of,
it's kind of interesting to think about how adversaries think and, you know,
how do you kind of stay ahead?
It's pretty hard.
But one good way is to think about,
you know, what are the common techniques that,
that they'll employ once they get access to a, to an end point?
Right. Right. And there's the additional advantage
of, if you have a system that's logging everything going on,
you might lose the first
endpoint they attack.
But now you have a corpus of data you can use to, you know,
look for more instances like this, which is that's hugely powerful,
getting all of the event data, like process creation, events,
file creation events, registry creation, all that data,
getting that, collecting it and getting it off the endpoint
as fast as possible somewhere safe so that the adversary can't find it
and erase their history. That's really important.
And that's probably one of the most important things about EDR
is making sure you have that data available that flight recorder
so that when something bad happens, you can kind of go back in time,
you know, not just weeks and months, but you know,
imagine going back in time and searching
data that's years old. Like you could have a virtual desktop environment
where you know, that endpoint literally lives for eight hours when you log in.
It is created when you log out, it's destroyed.
And so like a year later if you find out about a breach,
you want data from those end points even though they no longer exist to see. Ok.
Well, how bad was it like, what was the extent
of this breach?
How long have they been around getting that data off the box is
not only important from just making it much harder for an adversary,
but
-- you need that sort of flight data recorder history.
-- Right. Right.
Except there, there's also the issue of years of data
means your product is sponsored by the hard drive manufacturers
-- world.
-- Right.
-- Yes. No,
-- I mean, that, that's a huge problem though. Right? Because there's
data retention is one of those problems that sounds easy until you have to do it.
-- And it's like this is the worst thing I've ever had to
-- do.
-- Well, especially sensitive data.
-- Oh, exactly.
Yeah. And, and that's why sort of the prevention part of it is so important.
Do your best to stop it from ever having to worry about those types of problems.
But if you do,
it'd be great if you had the data somewhere.
That's right. That's right.
Ok. Cool.
We'll,
we'll assume that we've kind of set the table at
this point for some of the history of endpoint detection.
But I guess where's the industry headed?
Because I feel like there's some unexpected
convergences going on that two years ago.
If you'd have asked, you told me this is what's happening, I would have been like,
I don't know about that.
I think elastic and end game coming together is
a big
kind of view into the future of historically.
You've had things like SIMS and you've had endpoint
applications and they haven't been the same and like in this case,
they're coming together, right?
-- So you can literally do everything in one place now, which is wild.
-- Just interrupt.
Can you define what a SIM is?
Because that's, I know I'm not and I'm still sort of vague on the whole concept of SIM,
other than like
dashboard with blinky lights.
Well,
-- Tony is a perfect person to answer that question
-- and I probably
did an absolute poor job of describing what I do now.
So now at elastic,
we have on the security team. So elastic is probably the best way to think about it
is you have the stack that everyone's familiar with Kaban and Elastic search,
but we also have a security solution.
That's, that's my team. And,
and that team, we have an endpoint
that we've been talking about and we have a SIM SI M stands for
security information and event management. The best way to think about it
is most,
you know, enterprises kind of, you know, small or large enterprises have a ton of
security products, networking devices, you know, routers,
firewalls that are all generating logs
and
A SIM pulls all of that together in one place and gives
users the ability to write new detections across all those events.
So if that, if all that data is normalized,
we do that at elastic with something called elastic common scheme.
But there are many other options out there.
So you can kind of pull all this data together and search it and write, you know,
new detections on top of all this desperate data
coming from all of your different products and security devices
so that you can kind of connect the dots across
all of the different places where you have visibility.
That's like that's the main
goal of a sub
and most, you know, like Josh alluded to most S products are Switzerland.
Um they will accept data from anywhere and, and, and we're no different at elastic.
What kind of a cool thing that we're doing with end
point is
we're looking into what are
OK. Well, what if you had
a world where si actually had a very
nice cohesive
almost security solution with S
and, and point together?
Like what are the things that you could do
that maybe others haven't been able to do before?
So one example
is you can imagine a world where
you're creating some new detection in yours
in some language like endpoint query language.
EQL is something that we usually talk about
in this scenario where you're trying to say,
OK, if this happens and this happens over this window of time,
like I want to know about it, show me
and if that ends up being malicious.
You can imagine a world where because of that cohesive integration, you could
immediately pivot and say, OK, this search, I just did,
I now want to turn this into a prevention
and push that down to all my endpoints so
that the endpoints that see the exact same data,
if they see, OK, this process,
this process over this period of time and does something,
a network or whatever the rule is,
it stops it.
So now you can kind of do some research and figure out what's going on in your SIM.
And then as you find new malicious things,
you can push that out to your end point and just
stop it and prevent it from happening in the first place.
I think it's kind of a cool thing to,
to be able to do.
So one question I have so one of the few things
I think that the antivirus industry finally got right was,
you know, automated code submission samples, right? Because
like I literally am old enough to remember when you could email a virus company,
what you thought was a virus
-- like a long time ago and
-- signatures are stupid.
Kurt, no one should be using signatures.
Well, not just signatures but for example, saying, hey, you know,
we're noticing this new pattern where so like miter attack, you know,
has a list of common patterns they've seen in the wild and you know,
no doubt there will be new patterns that we see.
I like there was a one posting on Twitter where the person was trying to hack
into a company and they got caught immediately
and the rule essentially that caught them was,
yeah, outside admins, nobody runs Powershell on their Windows machine.
So like when we see a secretary trying to use Powershell on her machine,
-- we know she got hacked.
-- This is such a hard problem too. I mean, it's,
I guess maybe it's, it's kind of interesting to think about
how
data scientists spend time coming up with
machine learning malware models
because it's all about labeled data
that come from places like virus toll, reversing labs,
other sources that you alluded to.
And the sort of very first thing that is really important to make a
an effective machine learning malware model is to have really good labeled data.
And part of labeling that data is actually reverse engineering a
binary and seeing is this actually bad and that doesn't scale.
So you have a community that works really well together where
you can have confidence if hey these 14
other companies that we really trust, think this is bad.
Then the odds are this thing being bad is probably high.
So there's, there's sort of a labeling of data problem
that I think you're kind of alluding to that again, outside of reverse engineering,
it's it's tough to scale it.
It really is. But once you get that data,
you know, knowing what data to pay attention to,
how to age off that data,
to really make an effective machine learning malware model.
It's really hard and yet you have to do it for windows
pe files, ex
cable files for Mac Os, we support and train models on macros for office documents.
That the whole world to me is fascinating and
we have some data engineers and data scientists that
do amazing work there.
That Bobby Feiler actually a couple of days ago published a new blog that he,
he gave a talk at a data science conference called CLAS
on
how to detect living off the land techniques,
kind of analyzing parent child relationships
using graphs and community detection.
Again, applying ML
to this problem like it's,
it's ripe for those types of those opportunities to use ML.
It's, it's actually kind of cool. And I, I
hate and I'm very sensitive and aware of saying this
because there are so many companies that will just throw
A I and ML at you all day long in our marketing
and it sounds so disingenuous.
And if I'm coming across like that, then I hope you delete this.
No, I think we'll keep it. But yeah, I hear you man. All right.
So we are nearing the end of our time,
but I wanted to kind of make sure we hit on one
other topic that I know is near and dear to your heart
when we first started chatting about coming on the podcast,
you sent me a link to a blog post you have about you,
you are an amputee and you had an accident.
And I think this story is fascinating and I think
it is empowering and important people tell stories like this.
I'll make sure there's a link in the show notes for everyone listening,
but tell us your story, Tony, because it's amazing.
Well, I thank you for the opportunity to share it.
Well, I certainly didn't plan for this to happen. I think 2010,
let me take a step back. So I was a nerd growing up. I wasn't good at sports.
I was terrible at all of the things like I was shocked to learn this.
Yeah, no surprise. I started snowboarding around the age of 11 and I wasn't awful.
I was not terrible.
So it became a huge passion of mine. I was, I was
doing it as often as I could.
I also grew up in a landlocked area in the States called Oklahoma,
but we would drive to Colorado or New Mexico.
So I, again, I, I loved it.
I was super passionate about it and I like to talk about this story of
why I got the amputation because there are a lot of people that deal with
ankle arthritis that it's, it's a real struggle.
It's really painful and debilitating and it's a sort of an unseen injury.
And so I, I had this accident in 2010 where I was in Breckenridge, Colorado.
It's kind of weird.
Like, if you, if you tell it from the moment the accident happened, I just remember,
like right after it happened, I'm sort of like, what's going on here?
Like someone screaming, who is that? I was like, oh, that's
me. I'm screaming.
What happened? What basically happened is I was coming down
a black diamond and the only one on the run that day and my style is kind of all gas.
No break. I was just going straight down. I was wearing a helmet. Mom.
I
hope she knows that.
I remember when, when I learned to snowboard back in the day as a kid as well, like,
yeah, we didn't wear helmets,
nobody wore helmets.
I had just bought the helmet like the day before and I've been snowboarding for like,
you know, I guess at the time I was 27 when we had the accident.
So,
you know, a long time.
So I'm coming off this run and at the bottom it marches
for the screen and there was this young skier that kind of,
she was hugging the tree line on the right,
like cool. I'll go to her left in between her and this tree.
There's this wide open space like no problem.
And, and for those of you that don't snowboard or ski,
everyone in front of you has the right of way.
Like it's your responsibility and they can't see you like, you,
you have to be in control and you kind of have
to make sure you don't cause any problems on the slope.
So
I picked a line kind of to or left
and I was, I was writing switch.
So on snowboarding kind of terms, I was writing basically in reverse.
-- I was practicing that. So,
-- do you normally ride
or? So you're riding goofy?
Yeah. Yeah.
That's right.
Yeah.
And so I lean on my left foot and I'm approaching and she,
the skier in front of me cuts to the left.
Like no problem. I'll go, I'll go around the left of this tree.
I've done it a million times. No, no different this time. But I had forgotten
that I was leading on my left foot. So I just didn't have the same control and
I was probably going about 30 miles an hour.
I realized I'm definitely hitting this tree.
I just got sat down and took the impact on my snowboard and, and,
and the whole impact took place over my right foot kind of underneath the board and
it shoved my foot up into my T BS, just smashed it into 1000 pieces,
snapped my fibula in half.
And again, I just remember like after it happened, like, ok,
so someone is screaming, why is that person screaming?
Like someone should help that person?
And I was like,
oh, that's, that's me. I'm screaming.
So I, I just kind of went through a little bit of a shock at someone that see,
like they saw the whole thing and they, they got ski patrol up there
and as soon as that kind of came out of my
shock that literally the first words out of my mouth were
my wife is going to kill me.
She's like, you know, I was alone that day. She like, just be safe.
I'm like, oh, sure, I will be safe.
And I mean, I
I
long story short, I I went through several surgeries of trying to just fix it.
I mean,
I just remember telling Brooke like I'll be walking again
soon and the doctor overheard me and she was like,
you don't understand something here like you may never walk again
and she showed me the X ray and I'm like, oh, that, that doesn't look good.
That looks bad. So, yeah, tons of surgeries, external fixators.
I even had like a piece of my pelvis
-- taken out and thrown in my ankle. So
-- they tried to, to fix the bone before
you decided to amputate.
That's right.
So uh what happened is I had so many surgeries that
it just wasn't healing and and the options are limited.
If you have ankle arthritis, you can fuse it. But that,
that may only resolve the pain for a limited amount of time.
So yeah, I decided to amputate it and it was actually I was in an airport
and I met a bilateral above the knee amputee. So he had
both of his legs amputated above the knee.
And uh he was really fit. I was like, ok, so what's going on here?
And he sees me actually in a cane.
He
actually came up to me. And so we just started talking.
I was like, yeah, I'm thinking about amputating it like, oh,
you definitely need to do that.
I mean, for an above knee amputee, a
below knee amputation, which is what I have is like a nosebleed. It's nothing
you need to do it. Like there's like no question, this is the right decision for you.
And he was absolutely right.
I think I, I got my amputation scheduled maybe six or seven months later.
And yeah, I haven't looked back.
I can now do everything I could do before I've been snowboarding again.
And it's, you know, not everyone is the same, but II, I have a blog now, a
snowboarder versus tree.
Well,
I talked to people about it and I've met other people that have had similar injuries,
felt like their options were running out.
It's really debilitating and then
they, they have an amputation and they just get their lives back.
Like I was telling you earlier that I know someone that
now he is a Paralympic snowboarder and he's doing amazing.
So
it really is a life changer.
So I, I like and thank you for the opportunity to talk about it.
I like to talk about it because,
you know, if there's anyone out there that has debilitating,
I can't walk arthritis in your ankle.
I'm not saying get an amputation tomorrow, but like, look me up, let's talk
-- because for many people, it's, it's a good option.
-- That's amazing, man.
It's, and, and in all seriousness before you sent me your blog post,
it never even occurred to me that this was a thing where people would like choose
to
amputate part of their life.
But it is,
-- it's awesome.
-- Well, thank you. My,
my orthopedic surgeon was like, no, no, no, no, I'm definitely not going to do that.
So it takes sort of the right
person, the right doctor to kind of say, oh yeah,
this is definitely a good option for you.
Well,
I think in general the human body is sort of the
ultimate extreme example of sunk cost fallacy for most people.
Yes, like really, I mean,
to voluntarily remove parts of your body that is
such a taboo thing to even talk about.
-- That
-- is every orthopedic surgeon on the I'm sorry if you're an orthopedic surgeon.
But you know,
maybe if you hear this next time you talk to a patient about an amputation,
you'll think about some cost fallacy
because that's every orthopedic surgeon wants to salvage, salvage, salvage
and that's not always the best for your quality of life.
Well,
and I can't help but think we have the same problem in Infosec
where we keep trying to salvage old systems and patch them up and,
you know, I'm seeing people just eventually get fed up,
throw stuff out and move to the clown.
It's like, wow, that's so much better.
Yep. Yep. Or, or amputate your A V, you know, like, yeah, absolutely.
And maybe that's a new marketing tagline we can use.
That's awesome.
I love it.
All right. Cool. I, I don't see a better way to end it. Tony.
That was, this has been an awesome conversation and
-- it has been an absolute pleasure to have you. So, thank
-- you.
Thank you, Kurt Josh. This podcast is awesome.
And you guys do a phenomenal job and I hope people that are listening.
If you're just now tuning in, you got to go back and listen to the other podcasts.
I'm surprised that we haven't talked about the prime number thing like that.
Me fascinates me. Like, why haven't we gotten into an argument about prime numbers?
-- I know this podcast. 186. Yeah,
-- because 186 isn't prime.
-- It might be quasi
-- prime though. Well, you know, we could still argue about it.
I feel left out that I didn't get to participate in that,
but you guys do a phenomenal job.
So I'm, I'm honored that could be a guest on it.
Well, I'll tell you what,
you come back again and we can do nothing to argue about prime numbers.
Right.
Yes, I would love
actually. So I do have a joke. I will end on before I do the outro. Is that so,
as
was reported, I think yesterday or the day before Katherine Johnson,
the mathematician
who was the kind of star of the hidden figures, book and movie passed away.
And while anyone could be sad or what, I mean, she's 100 and one years old, like,
good for you.
You've done more than I ever will. The best part I heard was that
she waited till now because she
died at the prime of her life being
100 and one is a prime number.
So
it's awesome.
Anyway,
wonderful. Thank you, Tony. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com.
I will put all of the show notes for all of the things Tony talked about in there.
You can use the
Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag You hit us up on social media and Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody and thank you Tony for being on the show. Yeah.
Thanks guys.