Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 137 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
It,
I feel like you are very thoughtful and stoic
in that opening this time versus your usual.
Yeah, let's just do the intro and get going
well. I mean,
the world continues to slowly slide towards hell in
a handbasket with respect to the IOT and stuff.
I guess
it never ends and it never will on the plus
side as people who have a security podcast to do.
We never have to worry about content.
So we have that advantage.
-- I still
-- can't believe somebody asking me.
So, what do you do when all the security bugs are fixed?
Like, what will you do for work? And I just stared at them and I,
-- I literally just didn't know what to say because
-- no, no, there,
there is an answer to that when the security bugs are fixed.
It's because the machines have taken over and I can
only hope I'm killed in the first wave of antihuman
backlash
because I, I don't want to live in that world. Like I've seen the movies.
-- It doesn't end
-- well.
You just have to watch those Boston Dynamics videos where
they're hitting the poor things with a hockey stick.
Yeah. Those are going to be used against us someday. Like,
like, look what you people did to us.
-- Yeah.
-- The archives.
Pretty much so. There you go.
-- We're, we're recording our own doom.
-- I think the beauty is this week. We just have,
we have so many ridiculous things. So I think
let's lead with maybe the most ridiculous but least dangerous one,
which is the Nike shoes kind of bricking.
Yeah. Ok. I
said
that.
Yeah.
Ok. Ok. I'm going to,
I, I'm gonna say you can't brick a shoe
because when you brick a device,
we call it bricking because it's not worth anything, right?
It's, it has the value of a brick.
Whereas if you brick your shoes using the term brick and quotes here,
there's still shoes, they still work.
If the laces or you can't tighten them up and they fall off your feet.
They're not really that useful.
I mean, we'll say they're less useful
but you could still put them on your feet, you know,
but like those knockoff Crocs that have like a bad
strap that falls off and then the Crocs fall off,
the knockoff Crocs fall off your feet all the time.
Ok.
We had that happen.
So, yeah, you know,
like the little strap on the Crocs that goes to the
back around your heels so that they stay on your feet.
Those come off sometimes. And so then
I
never use those,
the shoe falls off constantly and then while your shoes doesn't stay on your foot,
and that's kind of,
I, I think that's sort of the primary job description of a shoe is to stay on your foot.
Uh Sure.
So, and,
and the best part though was apparently this is due simply to the fact that Nike
did a lot more testing with their I OS app, but then with their Android app.
And so if you use the Android app to update your shoe firmware,
you would mess it up
and I this. Ok. And, and I'm gonna use this expression. I love this expression.
This begs the question.
Why does your shoe need a firmware update?
Why not?
Right.
We've got to put computer chips and everything,
but I'm literally trying to understand what scenario that the firm wear of a shoe
needs an update.
Like, do they have lights in them or something? And they, they put new patterns?
Well, you've got to figure it's a computer, right?
It has an operating system essentially. And so
maybe there's new drivers, maybe there's a security flaw in the wireless chip,
maybe there's a new feature they're adding.
-- I mean, there's a million things it could be,
-- but that's what I'm trying to think of.
Like what new feature, I mean, maybe better gate or running or
maybe now it can detect the Saunter as
opposed to just jogging and running and walking.
Now I want a firmware update that's going to make me 20% faster. Right.
That's, that's what I'm looking for.
Yeah,
because I just,
I'm thinking about this because I was reading another article about, um,
so this is from a few days ago, city of Winnipeg manager in charge of police radios,
arrested after two year investigation and you know what he was arrested for,
he was arrested for.
So apparently Motorola radios, they charge uh what is it for a software update?
It was
they Ch Motorola charged about $94 Canadian. So about 70 us per update per radio.
Ok.
And again,
why do these radios need so many firmware updates
because apparently they were updating these radios constantly.
Like
he basically managed to get like a um some stuff off of a ham radio operator
like a Java button and a USB key with a bunch of premade refresh keys.
Yeah, here we go.
According to the affidavit, the employee told police that in 2011,
Richardson gave him a device known as an eye button that was preloaded with more than
65,000 refresh keys and told him you don't want to know where these came from.
So I don't know if they hacked Motorola's refresh key system or he just
stole a whole bunch or whatever. But
again, why are these radios needing? So many firmware updates. Like,
shouldn't,
shouldn't you basically produce the radio, put the software on it and, and largely
be done.
Uh, no, because do you know how these radios work these days?
They're insanely complex.
-- But for
-- example, like, like, shouldn't the updates be, at least,
maybe at the most quarterly,
I think you could make that argument.
Yes.
Yeah.
I, well, and then, you know,
then the next bit of ridiculous news is this lime scooter.
Uh, so these Lime scooters apparently are throwing people off of them.
And I'm like, wait, how does that work?
Well,
the answer is the firmware has a bug where
the front wheel brake locks while you're going.
So,
for anybody who's ever driven on anything with two wheels like a
motorcycle or a scooter and you hit that front brake real hard,
you learn very quickly not to do that,
you know, because physics.
Right. Right.
And again, I'm just
ok.
So granted they need to, they, they clearly need to update that firmware because,
you know, these scooters literally are causing people
to get really hurt.
Yes. But I, I'm just looking at this and, you know, I'm, I'm really
the internet of things,
especially when they're attached to, you know,
big heavy powerful machines or machines that process chemicals is,
it's getting a little terrifying.
So the internet of things,
you know, it's, we're, we're starting to attach everything to it. And
ok, we can argue that even you know, a shoe with bad firmware.
You can assuming it has like, not those auto Titan laces like and back to the future,
you can at least still like, tie it to your foot and walk around,
you know,
something like an electric scooter where
the front brakes suddenly just engages fully
and you're, you know, going say 5, 10 miles an hour, that's, that's gonna be a bad day.
Yes.
And people can get hurt.
It's, I want to laugh at this one but real people are getting hurt. So I won't.
Actually, there's, there's a, there's a guy who's in like a coma with like,
severe brain injuries from a few years ago, from one of these electric scooters.
-- Yeah.
-- I, I believe it
because these people don't wear helmets.
No, because you're usually
just, like hanging out and you want to go somewhere. It's not right.
You just happen upon it and it's an easy way to go.
Get to a place.
And so,
and are you going to wear like a public helmet that's like tethered to the scooter?
One size fits all.
I totally would not because that's how you get some sort of parasite
like,
-- unquestionably.
-- So, you know, these are tough questions.
Like, do we,
do we need to make everybody who's traveling
faster than five miles an hour on wheels.
Wear a helmet. Yeah. Well, we do that for kids nowadays. Right.
Or at least locally anybody under 18 has to wear a bicycle helmet
if they're on a bicycle.
And the funny thing is I see parents out with their kids,
the kids are wearing helmets and the parents
aren't wearing helmets and it drives me nuts.
Interesting.
Uh, well, you know, adults get to make their own poor decisions. Apparently
that's fair. So,
I don't know what to make of this. Right.
Because the reality is, I mean, if you're, if you're writing software for I OS,
that's one thing that's only, you've got like three kind of major versions, like
1011, 12, or is it 9, 1011,
whatever you've got like probably three or four major versions
plus, you know, about two or three dozen devices to support that's manageable.
But then you look at the Android ecosystem and it's
how many versions of Android are currently out there in white, like,
say more than 2% of the market.
I would bet more than 100 if I had to guess because there's countless revisions.
Yeah.
Well,
and then the carrier specific stuff and some of them make some pretty major changes.
If you, if you count that, it's probably thousands.
Yeah. Here we go. So, uh, jelly bean and up are all more than 2% jelly bean.
That's the 4.1 and up series is down to 3%
and dropping Kit Kat at 4.4 is at 7.6 and dropping.
But then we have Oreo
or sorry, going numerically.
So lollipop at five, that's the five series is like 18% in dropping.
The uh marshmallow at number six is at like 21% dropping.
And then we finally get to Nougat version seven and that's at like 28% and dropping.
And then finally Oreo eight point whatever is at 21% rising.
So you basically would have to support five major versions
to support 90 some percent of the market.
If you're willing to drop 10% of the market, you can get down to four ma well,
four major versions of Android with multiple subversion
-- and then multiple carrier specific things. Yeah,
-- it's kind of madness
and, and not only that,
it's even more complicated because ignoring these specific versions,
there are various hardware revisions, there's different screen sizes.
-- There
-- is, well, and you were saying there's, there's like the,
the proper CP US and the new, like really
cheap arm ones or something.
I was talking with somebody and they were saying that there's
new CPU architecture that the really cheap android phones use.
-- So a lot of the apps aren't compatible at all.
-- I I don't know about that.
It wouldn't shock me if it's happening. I mean,
depending upon how it was written, obviously, there's a 32 bit arm,
there's 64 bit arm, there's some people doing MP stuff now.
Mis that was the one. Yeah. MP S
Yeah, it was mis not arm, sorry or,
or there's even risk, the new risk Risk five,
which is like the open source processor is, is kind of coming into its its place.
And the reason behind that is if you use arm, you obviously have to pay arm,
holding some amount of money to make arm chips.
Whereas the risk stuff is essentially open source so anybody can use it.
And the thing to remember too, I mean,
my understanding is a lot of these phones in developing countries, you know,
we're talking about a $10 device so even a 10 cent royalty fee is too much for them.
-- Yep.
-- Yep. Exactly.
And so here's
what I think of this and I've, I've thought about it a fair bit is
to date
security or even just quality of software
we've gotten away with,
with highway robbery essentially where you can release
a piece of software that is really,
really bad and it doesn't really matter.
Right.
It's never really mattered because what, what's the worst thing that happens?
Someone's computer stops working
and
once you start dealing with things like scooters or, I mean,
kind of less so with shoes, we'll say
people can start getting hurt. Right. Cars, cars are an easy one. Right.
Because it's just a giant death machine on wheels if it, if it goes off the rails.
And that's a weird analogy using rails. But anyway, the point is
once you start having physical things and people start getting actually hurt
now, the courts can get involved and this is something,
it took me a long time to understand.
But so
the way, at least in the United States, I don't know how this works elsewhere.
But basically in the US,
if you can't show like physical injury or like
actual physical damages or somehow you lost real money,
you struggle to have any sort of reasonable kind
of defense in court or going after somebody.
Well, a case
it's
no, you, in most jurisdictions, you have to show damages. You have to explain
how the defendant harmed or wronged you
-- in some material way. Right? Like
-- material damages, it can't be made up crap.
And this is where security has struggled in the courts because it was very,
very difficult to show real damages even with
something like heartbleed where you can say,
oh, but I had to update my fleet and it's like, well, like, explain that.
Right.
-- But you kind of have to do that anyways and blah, blah, blah. Yeah. No, I know.
-- Right.
Right. Exactly.
Because now when you have physical devices
breaking and you have people getting hurt,
now the courts are going to start paying attention, which is also going to gain the,
I guess the eye of the regulators.
And as much as I know people talk about how regulation is too slow and it can't work.
And this, that and another,
it is quite literally the only option we have at this point
and I, it kind of makes me sad to say that.
But like, for real, if anyone can fix this, it's basically the regulators,
there's saying the market will fix it,
whatever the market doesn't give two craps about security.
And I think that's been proven more times than I can count.
Well, and the good news is we already have some good legal frameworks for this.
Like in Europe they have the fit for purpose for products.
And there you can make a strong argument if you buy a product, let's say,
for the sake of argument, you buy a fridge
and the fridge has a firm firmware issue.
So it doesn't function properly, you know, within, I think, what is it? Two years?
Yeah, you get a two year legal guarantee
against faulty goods or goods that don't look or work as advertised
this.
And so this is a wonderful kind of catch all law that
really potentially solves this problem at least for the first two years,
you know,
but
I doubt we'll ever see anything like that in North America because man, oh man,
getting that passed would be uh,
yeah, I don't feel like that's gonna happen.
Right.
So,
but I guess moving along and then the next thing is
you can no longer plug anything into your USB port safely.
So I guess we have to hot glue them all shut, which
I was actually wondering about this because
all my chromebooks
and my new Macbook Air.
They don't have a charging port, they just have USB ports.
Right.
I guess you just buy a new laptop every morning at Amazon.
Yes. I think that is
the best option by far.
It.
No.
So this story is about people hiding what it was
a Wi Fi device essentially in a USB plug.
So when you plugged it in, it could do magic and we'll just put the term magic.
-- Well, it's,
-- it's, it's, it's, this has always been possible.
It's just the Wi Fi chip sets were never physically small enough to like literally,
this is a, it looks like a USB cable with that little sort of one by one or well,
I guess three quarters of an inch, whatever it is, it's small,
you know, plug on the end.
But now, yeah, you can fit a full Wi Fi chip set and everything in there.
And obviously it's powered off the USB
and it can present as a, what is it a human interface device like a keyboard, meaning
you, you plug this what looks like just
a normal USB cable into your laptop.
And all of a sudden it means somebody can connect to it via Wi Fi
and send
inject keystrokes to your laptop or mouse movement or whatever, right?
Because, well, I was thinking uh you know, those UB keys, they make those really,
really tiny ones for laptops that just stick out like two millimeters,
you know, and I was thinking of that.
Like, we already have, um,
I know one of my laptops permanently has like a little logitech mouse
sting of a jigger jacked into it. So the mouse works right.
Because the mouse is some wonky, not Bluetooth standard
that needs a little, you know, USB plug.
Have you made sure that little Dongle isn't vulnerable to the,
what do they call it? Click, jacking flaw.
Oh, it probably totally is.
But it's the windows laptop that basically I turn on to update once a month and then
-- OK, stare at it and wonder why I haven't thrown it out.
-- Right.
Uh Because that's literally all I use it for.
So,
one of the fun facts about those is a guy named Mark Newland did a bunch of research.
I forget which company he's with right now. But basically he found out that
those little dongles that you use with your mice.
They are the same dongles they use with the, the keyboards.
So you can basically connect to them
again with a keyboard. Oh, yeah. No, I know this and they have no encryption.
I know. No handshakes. Nothing.
Yeah.
No, this is probably gonna, I,
I was trying to play Minecraft on this laptop but uh with the, the new Minecraft,
it was OK.
But with the old Java Minecraft, I was getting like 12 frames per second.
So kind of unusable.
Nice.
No, it's just, it's, I think part of it is like remember when Key Ghost came out
probably one or two decades ago. And it basically looked like a PS two
uh extension cable. And for those of you that don't know what that is.
PS two is the old timey keyboard center.
It's a little round thing with like what four pins.
-- Uh I think it was and,
-- um, I'm, I'm gladly don't remember and I don't want to.
So the idea with Key Ghost was very simple.
It was powered off the PS two and it had a little bit of as, you know, memory
that would store all the keystrokes it received. So you plug it in to somebody's
desktop.
This is back when we had desktops,
not laptops and you go and collect it after a day or two and, you know,
you would have the person's passwords.
So this, this physical security has always been a problem.
And, and there are literally places that will hot, glue shut all the USB ports
and then put like a DVD burner reader in the,
in the laptop or device to move data around.
But like I said, I, I, all the modern laptops don't have a power port.
-- They just have USB. Yeah,
-- look,
gluing USB port shut is not a practical solution.
It just, it, it isn't.
I think about this one a lot and I guess here's there, there's two ways to think of it.
Number one,
this is not a, an attack that's going to practically affect most people.
That's just the honest one.
I
was just thinking, I'm going to RS A
and, you know, there's a lot of
laptops and whatnot on the show floor.
They're may be tied down or Kensington locked down or whatever that the hole in
the laptop that you jam a little lock into and tie it to something else.
Or is Kensington the brand? I forget what that name of that hole is called whatever.
I think it's maybe Kensington is the people who make the locks. I don't know,
but I was thinking for a lot of these, definitely,
there's a lot of machines that are not sort of very well physically secured.
Now, hopefully somebody would notice you plugging something into this,
but I'm thinking more of the attack of what if somebody's giving
away free lightning cables to charge your phone off your laptop?
I mean, lightning cables cost like five or 10 bucks.
-- I bet if you handed those out at a show, people would take them and
-- this is where
you have to start thinking about what does it mean?
So when I say it doesn't affect most people, I mean,
we'll say normal people who don't go to computer security trade shows, right?
It is conceivable. Some are going to get caught up in something like this.
If somebody say starts dropping cables on the ground at the park,
which is completely plausible,
but the reality is that isn't going to happen to most people.
Now, if you go to RS A, don't plug anything that has a USB port on it.
Anything, like, just full stop. Right. If you're in any sort of high risk venue,
-- don't
-- use the
-- venue. Really? Yeah,
-- that's fair.
Like, I see those phone charging stations where you, like,
lock your phone in a little cabinet to recharge it.
And it's like, well, number one don't, how good are those locks?
-- I don't want to lose my phone. Go
-- buy a $10 battery. Right.
Go buy a $10 battery and you're fine
is the reality of that.
And so here's,
here's my view on this. All right. Number one,
these aren't small enough, you're not gonna notice today.
I mean, they might get there someday,
but basically look at your stuff if you see something plugged into it, you know,
something crazy is going on and don't ever use that computer again.
Right. Give that to somebody who knows what they're doing and let them take it apart.
Well,
that's not really useful advice for somebody who
only has the one laptop or whatever.
I mean, I,
I think part of this goes to it.
-- It,
-- it has to be though, like,
well, no, no, but I think this maybe goes to the, the,
the model of like the chromebooks where you can just power wash it and re
in
and in theory that should completely wipe it
and, and this is also why I travel with a chromebook to things like this because it is
infinitely more secure and predictable
in an environment like that. Right.
A regular laptop, I don't freaking trust a regular laptop as far as I can see.
-- It just no way
-- because the other thing I was thinking is
I know you can do USB device filtering based on its,
you know, ID and everything.
But the problem is, for example, I mean, Apple is a great example of this is, you know,
there's,
there's certain USB peripherals that Apple cells that are very common that well,
you'd have to whitelist them,
you know, like I've got my little USB C to regular USB plug and I've got my USB C to HDM I
breakout thing, you know, for, for doing presentations or whatever, right?
So even if I whitelist
it,
it still wouldn't be very hard to make a hostile USB device that identifies as like,
yeah, I'm a, I'm an Apple uh
-- USB cable. Nothing to see here,
-- right? It's, it's trivial to do that.
And in fact, for those of you listening, if you ever want to have some fun.
So the Raspberry Pi Zero
has the ability to basically turn itself into
a magic USB device and pretend it's something else
which is really cool.
You can just do this in software, you can plug it into a computer in USB.
The USB power is the freaking thing
and then it pretends it's something. It's not,
which was actually used.
Somebody built, uh, I forget what they called it now,
but basically you plugged it into a computer
and it said, oh, route all internet traffic through me.
I'm the best place for your internet
traffic and obviously websites and everything started,
like,
dumping internet into the raspberry pie and it was logging all kinds of garbage.
Which was, yeah, that's a neat attack.
But it, I,
I feel like
this is something
that
you can't, you can't technically stop,
but it's also not going to be a significant problem for most people.
And I'm going, I'm, I'm always gonna come back to the story of
-- if you are being targeted by an adversary with resources, you cannot stop them.
-- But,
and physical access, physical access is the real thing. Right?
And that's a big part of it. I mean, this is part of the story is if you're
like Rs A or black hat or really any, any sort of conference even
and you leave your laptop in your hotel room even
if it's in the safe because like those safes are,
are pretty freaking worthless.
If you're concerned you're being targeted, that's when they're gonna get you.
Right. Keep that thing on your back.
If it's something you're actually worried about. Yeah.
No, I, I really do think the future of this is that kind of chromebook model of, oh,
I think I might have been compromised.
-- All right. Burn it. All down and log in again. Right.
-- Right.
And, and at the same time, this is not a useful way to spend our mental resources.
We all have a limited amount of capacity in terms
of dealing with just like the world around us and,
and being worried about getting a USB cable that has Wi Fi on it,
that some adversary is going to use to inject keystrokes.
Like I'm not, I'm not going to say you shouldn't worry about it.
But like, if that's your biggest fear.
Yeah, you're not me. Right.
And I'm just, I'm gonna say I stand corrected.
I was just checking,
I was plugging some of my Apple USB devices into my laptop and running IO
Reg
and they don't seem to be showing up like I see my podcast or I see my,
the external hard drive but I don't see the actual,
like Ethernet adapter or anything like that showing up.
So they don't seem to have a USB ID
but they should,
I don't know.
-- I have
-- no idea.
It's also a Mac. Like Apple does crazy, weird stuff.
I,
I would never trust what a Mac tells me because
I maybe rightly so think they're smarter than me.
Where is that? That's the one thing I'll say I like about Linux.
You're just holding it wrong.
Exactly. Exactly. What do I know
where, where
the Linux laptop is happy to just like, you know,
dump more information than I can possibly do anything with on
top of me and then it gives me warm fuzzies.
So everything is fine. It's all fine. It's all fine
anyway. So we're doomed again.
That's all.
Well, it really does drive home the whole physical security matters and I,
I can't help but think that's one of the reasons cloud computing
is such a wonderful thing because
generally speaking,
those Google and Amazon and Microsoft
data centers will have infinitely better physical
security than any server closet in a small and medium business ever can.
And that's assuming they even have one because like,
I've,
I've seen so many firms where they just literally have
the one server stuck in like somebody's office closet.
-- Yeah.
-- No. Lock on the door. Right.
-- It's, that happens so often
-- and, and, and I can't blame him.
-- You're not going to build a server closet for one machine. Right.
-- Right. Yep.
In fact, I remember I used to work at an ISP, like 1000
years ago, the server
was literally a machine sitting on a desk in the corner.
There was no security, there was granted that the door had a lock on it.
But yeah, it was, in fact, you could look through the front window and see it.
That's how it worked. Fantastic. And,
but here's the thing at the same time. Did it matter? No, no, it didn't. Right.
Nobody ever broke in. Nobody ever stole the stuff.
-- Oh, I'd be more concerned about somebody turning it off.
-- Uh, that, that did happen.
Yeah, that, that happened more than once
the building had redundant power.
But yeah, uh, there was a third strip,
uh, that it was, it was plugged into
and it was, uh, we'll say it didn't happen very often,
but it got turned off more than once.
And I, I, man, I have some great stories from that though because this was,
this was back when I SPS were like brand freaking new dial up was brand new
and there's just so much was just like madness and it was a miracle. Anything worked.
I mean, we ran the whole freaking ISP,
ran up one T one at the time when I started like
to give you an idea of how small we're talking about.
No, I remember that
-- back when a 1.544 megabits was the cat's meow.
-- Yeah.
And, and the thing is,
I thought it was awesome because I'd go into the office and
I had an Ethernet connection to the T one and I'm like,
look at this, I can download a Linux distribution in a couple of hours.
Right.
Seriously. That was 600 megabytes.
Mind you, this wasn't like the four gigabyte DVD s we're talking about here
and then of course, we also had a CD burner,
-- which is very convenient because I didn't own one at home because CD
-- burners,
they were expensive.
Yes.
Yeah. No, man, that was those were the days
anyway anyway.
So I feel like I'm going to make an effort to stop ending these podcasts on,
on a terrible note.
And I feel like at this point it again,
sounds like the world is on fire and nothing is ever going to get better.
And so
I guess let's, let's shift our conversation for the next couple of minutes and say,
given everything we've talked about,
are they going to lead us in a place that makes the world better
the same or worse
for?
Well, for example, the, the,
the electric scooters and I get that there's people
that hate them and people that love them.
But I think for example,
at least we're now talking about alternative forms of
transportation if nothing else potentially in some climates,
like not where I live because we have snow and ice for six months of the year.
But in a climate like San Francisco, I think those electric scooters
really do represent potentially.
Yeah,
maybe that sort of last mile problem with respect to delivery of people to a place.
You know, for example, like the city buses here all have the bike rack on the front,
which is kind of a pain in the ass because the bus stops, the guy,
you know, you better know how to work those bike racks to get your bike on and off.
Right.
And I'm thinking something like an electric scooter would be in, you know,
especially if it folds like a, like most razor scooters do.
But even if it doesn't fold,
it would still on a bus be a lot more manageable than a bicycle.
And so I feel like there's nothing else.
I personally, I would rather have a world with new and crazy stuff.
That's definitely,
probably has insecure software than a world that's like stagnant and, oh, you know,
we can't do that until we perfect the software and address every edge case.
Uh, and now having said that obviously,
I don't want electric scooters that are throwing people off of them and giving them,
you know, severe injuries or potentially killing them.
Right. Right.
But the reality is, I mean, we accept a certain level of risk in life and if you look at,
you know, human driven cars, the, the not the death toll even, but just the carnage,
you know,
that the number of people that are injured severely in car accidents.
Yeah. No, I mean, clearly we, we accept a certain level of, uh,
people mingling as we always have.
You know, you look at the industrial revolution and the stories that are
terrible.
Well, in,
in the industrial revolution is the exact parallel I would use here
is it was horrific and unfortunately just given the nature of humans,
it had to get worse before it could get better.
And I think a lot of this iot security is the same story where
it's probably going to get worse and people are going to get hurt
and they're going to get killed and they're going to get maimed.
And unfortunately I wish it didn't have to happen, but I think it's going to have to,
before people start to care.
And then I think once they start to care, things can start to get better
because just humans are, are annoying in this way. Is we?
Well, I don't know,
I guess I don't want to delve too much into like dealing with humans.
Honestly, my,
my hope is that the things like the cloud providers
with their cloud IOT integrations and their software development kits,
you know, arm has released like a software development kit for IOT devices.
And so back to the frameworks of, you know,
almost nobody can write memory management software or even file parsing software.
So that's why you use a framework and then you put your magic sauce on top of it.
And I think that's the way to go, you know, ideally, you know,
like all these IOT devices are running Linux.
Like my, I just got the lego V three Mindstorms.
I
was watching it boot up and it's running
-- Linux kernel 2.4 0.33 something that's old
-- man.
-- Well, it's, it's LEGO man, it doesn't matter,
-- you know, update, update your KGO
you should get on that like update that sucker, right? Then you could brick it.
Hey, brick. If you brick your Lego thing, that's like totally apt. Right?
Because they are lego bricks, you brick the brick. I like it.
So anyway, I, I think your points are all quite valid and I feel like
we are on the cusp of new technologies and new things and some are crazy.
Some will work, some won't work. And unfortunately
we just are going to have to go through these growing pains.
But I,
I do feel like things are going to get better because entering the realm of physical
makes certain groups that have historically not paid attention by certain groups.
I mostly mean,
like regulators and lawyers that have basically not paid
attention to this technology are going to start.
And I think, you know, things like arm providing frameworks,
ironically,
I know they're doing it because they want more people to use their stuff.
But I have a suspicion we're going to end up in a place where people are going to say,
well, if you're giving people the tools, like,
put some freaking safety guards in those tools.
Right. Stop letting people saw their arm off on accident.
Well, and you're right.
Like, I feel like end users will actually be able to show damages. Right.
And, yeah, exactly. And I think that's exactly where we're going to end up. So,
all right, I'll, I'll call that our happy note and let's,
-- let's stop now before we uncover some other horrific truth,
-- it's fine.
-- The lawyers will all sort it out.
-- That's right, lawyers.
They, they make everything better. Right.
That's
anyway.
All right. Awesome. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com,
hit up the show notes. You can use the Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag
and yeah, Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day. You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.