Hello and welcome to episode 65 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried
and my partner in Thought crime. Josh Bresser
and the world continues to burn.
I know. But it's,
but it's not our fault this week.
It's never our fault. We are the
uh,
no, there was, there was a couple of weeks where it was sort of my fault
-- or at least I assign the CV S for it.
-- That could be.
But I view us as the crazy people in the desert screaming at everyone else. Yeah.
Yeah.
But not the crazy people in,
in the desert retrieving spent metal rounds from the fire range.
I read about that. Like, what,
you know, what
-- do
-- you know what high tungsten steel goes for on the open market?
I'm sure it's expensive. It's got to be worth a ton if you're willing to do that.
I mean, come on. But anyway, anyway,
we'll talk about that in a risk to reward show later.
Yes, that would be really entertaining. Actually, we should do that.
All right. So I vote we throw
-- Equifax under the bus because everybody's doing it or
-- why not Apple or?
Well, see, I don't know,
here's my, here's the thing. On the one hand, we have the,
the hubris of Equifax who really should have known better, but on the other hand,
we have,
well, we do have Apple who made a mistake.
So fundamentally stupid that you know, I OK, I let's go in alphabetical order.
So
a APL it is
OK. Do you want to say it or do I say it? Because this is just so stupid.
You are the Apple fan boy.
-- Nothing would please me more than to listen to you describe this.
-- So Apple has
hard drive encryption.
Yay, right?
And they have a couple of ways you can sort of enable the hard drive encryption.
Um You can, for example, when you plug in an external hard drive
and you use it as a time machine, it'll let you encrypt it blah blah blah.
Um It's there's the disk utility which actually used
to be a really nice tool and now is
not such a nice tool to be completely honest.
Um
So basically what happens is if you created
an encrypted partition using the disk utility,
uh the standard format for that is you create new partition, you choose,
you know apple,
whatever blah blah blah encrypted.
And then it asks you to set a password for that encrypted partition, right?
So far so good.
And then it asks you to set a password hint,
which I'm not a big fan of, but sure for normal people. Ok, cool.
You know, what's your cat's name? Whatever.
The glitch here.
And it's just a little tiny glitch is that they
sort of mixed up the password hint and the password
when later on you forget your password. And
it says, basically,
do you want me to be helpful and prompt you with your password hint?
And it shows you the password?
I read about this bug and I thought surely that's not what it is.
And then I went in and looked at the screen.
I got
a CV. And
my first thought was, yeah, this is the onion, right?
Why is my onion feet getting mixed into my register feed?
Like what, what just happened here?
The,
the only thing I can think of is how did testing not figure this out
because like me,
they probably said a test password of password
and a hint of password or something stupid.
Exactly what I was thinking or they just thought, oh, whatever.
-- We don't need to use a password hint because we're just doing testing
-- well,
or they didn't test that functionality
because there's other ways to create an encrypted disc in apple.
And so it's just through this specific path in the UI through this one utility.
Now that, and that leads to a big problem.
I mean, here's the problem with testing, right? Is you have to test all the things,
right? Yes. Literally all the things.
Yeah.
And you know, that, that can be bothersome,
especially with clickable Pokey U I Interfaces, right?
Like,
you know, testing something like, like there was a great article on testing floats,
right?
There's 4 billion floats. So why don't you test all of them
when you have a program that interacts with floats?
And it was kind of like, hey, you know, or not test all the floats, sorry, all the INS,
right?
-- Like you have 4 billion ins, you know what on a modern laptop? You can do that,
-- right.
-- That's what fuzzing is,
-- right? Yeah. Um
but anyway, so like, yeah, with this, it's like, well, more to the point,
they made a pretty
significant programming mistake and how did the code review not catch it?
-- Ok. So,
-- right, because this isn't like a subtle mistake, like an off by one.
This is like we
somehow they put the password into the password hint, but here's the
pull the password hint from the password and more to the point.
Why is the password being stored in clear text somewhere?
Well, you have to store the password in clear text in memory to do something with it.
-- That is just no,
-- no, no. But this is like after the fact
this is like
down the road,
right?
And my assumption is somebody accidentally assigned one variable to another
and it probably wasn't very clear because you're right.
The review should have caught it. It obviously didn't.
And so from the from the mistake of that angle.
I, I think that's ok because people make mistakes all the time.
Now, granted, I will say anytime there is any code involving a password,
you should have a whole bunch of really smart people looking at it.
Well, especially a password for disc
encryption, like data,
arrest data that you're going to want to be secret for 50 or 100 years
because let's face it. Laptops get stolen all the time.
You know,
I have a huge pile of external hard drives here.
I have about half a dozen external hard drives with, you know,
time machine backups and all my data.
Yeah, they're all encrypted because
it's all my data
just run those over with a steamroller. It'd be fine.
Yeah.
But, well, the people that steal it probably won't do that.
Um,
but yeah, so, and then, and then in testing, how
did this,
how did basic testing not get this?
Well, it obviously didn't. I mean, now I will say,
and they caught it and ignored it, which is,
see, that's, it's, here's my
question. Did they just not test this functionality in which case?
That's really terrible because you should
be testing your dis conscription functionality
or number two. Did they test it? And the tester whiffed it in which case?
-- Holy heck, how is their testing that bad?
-- I'm betting
that they didn't know about it because look Apple's pretty good with security.
If they knew they would not ship a product with this book.
Right. I mean, that's, they, they, I, I have no doubt they would stop ship something
to fix that.
I would hope so because, I mean,
yeah. Yeah,
they're pretty good.
Yeah.
So, anyways, I mean, that's, it's just, well, and see, here's the thing,
here's the clear thing with apple.
This is not one person's fault.
Right. There's at a minimum. We have the programmer,
the guy who reviewed his code,
they both whiffed it.
The QE, that
if the QE did not test for this, then the, the whole QE thing whiffed it because like,
they should be testing that
and if they do test it, then at least one QE guy or automated system whiffed it.
Right.
So that's at least three different people or
organizations with an Apple that we've done.
Yeah.
But I mean, how many times haven't we discussed in the past that,
that the vast majority of failures are the result of like,
five or more things going completely.
The
air crash thing.
Right. Right.
This chain could have easily been interrupted at any point.
I will laugh at Apple for making a hilarious mistake.
And if they ever make it again,
then I will call them idiots
because let's face it at this point.
If they don't have four or more tests that
they've integrated into their process just for this bug,
they're dumb
right
now. Speaking of one person making a mistake though.
Equifax. Right?
One person,
-- I couldn't believe that
-- because my thought was like, what if this guy gets, like,
what if this guy eats a bad sandwich?
Just?
Ok. No,
here's the reality of it. When you're testifying in front of Congress,
it's not your fault. Right.
If, if,
if you have the nice enough suit to be in
front of Congress and they're blaming you for something,
you're gonna blame
anyone else.
Ok. We should actually
give some background here because
so
Equifax was horribly owned and they're up to what, like 100 and 47 million now,
-- I think
-- records.
Yes. And it's also the US, the UK and Canada possibly some other countries,
more data than we thought.
My suspicion is when Yahoo heard this, they, they got worried that
they were going to be caught, but we'll get to them later.
But anyway, so Equifax gets horribly
pumped
and the Senate wanted a hearing from the CEO or
the ex CEO of Equifax to basically say like WTF man
and this guy shows up and
his testimony
was,
that's how it works though, right?
You, you pay these kind of people to not answer questions in front of the,
like that's their job.
-- You
-- know, there's been a few. But anyways go
on,
right. So he, he sat there and didn't answer most of the questions with a lot of words.
And at one point, he basically said, like it was one person's job
to know, this was a vulnerability and it affected us and then to tell someone else
and
I read that and I just thought,
no, it wasn't.
You are blaming some poor dude.
And I feel bad for whoever this person is for,
for this blame because it's clearly not them.
But
if you say that that it was one person's fault, the answer is, yes, it was.
And it was yours, right?
I mean,
that's the reality
-- the
-- process.
I mean, literally if that guy ever goes on vacation or eats a bad sandwich or,
or just gets his,
like
a
factor of one is not a good thing.
Well, not only that, how many CD ES get assigned per day?
-- 100
-- quite a rather a lot.
And, and in fairness, even if this guy is just in charge of struts,
like he's the struts, security expert at Equifax.
No, realistically that's a possible thing because they probably have hundreds
of apps based on struts. Right. Like,
I mean, I know there's like, you know, large organizations out like
a perfect example. Right.
I know an electrician and all he does and it's not just him, it's a team of people,
they test fire alarms and replace broken ones
and it's for the local university and they have over 100 buildings.
So it's a full time job.
That's,
well, it's, it's the University of Alberta. Right. They have, like,
35 or 40,000 students on campus.
Like, that's a lot of buildings and, like, that's obviously ii,
I can't even imagine how many fire alarms are.
Not only that,
I think fire alarms are a super critical piece of their infrastructure
because if there is a fire and the fire alarms don't work,
I mean, it, it would be a tragedy.
Well, especially with all the labs and stuff they have.
I mean, there's some really horrendous chemicals on site. But anyways. Yeah.
So, yeah, having this, like,
having one guy even, and, and even if it's not
just a one person team, like, you know,
I'm assuming it's maybe one person was responsible for making the call
and not like there's only one person that can do this and
I guess they just don't do security updates whenever he goes on vacation.
But let's assume for a moment they have a team and it was his call.
Somebody should backstop that or somebody there should be some sort of process to,
like, ensure, or even just a checklist.
Like, do we run this? Yes, we're not going to fix this. Ok.
What was the rationale for not fixing this? Ok. Cool.
You know, or have we not made a decision about this yet? Ok.
This needs to be bumped up the food chain or something
because we haven't dealt with it in a few days.
You know, like,
like I know the way it is at Red Hat, like, if, you know,
a new CV comes in and I have to deal with it and I don't deal with it.
You know, at some point pretty soon somebody's like poking me with a stick and,
or my boss.
Well,
so that's part of the problem, but there's still kind of that incoming aspect of,
if you have one person paying attention to all the incoming stuff,
you're doing it wrong. Right. First of all, it should be a robot,
but more importantly is
this is a job that there's going to be a lot of
false negatives just because of the way the security stuff works.
There's
-- there's going to be false positives and there's going to be false negatives,
-- right?
It's not even it's that there's,
well,
you know, we have some stuff that's affected,
some stuff that's not affected and then another
struts flaw comes in and that Venn diagram,
there's overlap, you know what I mean?
Like
because if you have like 100 apps uh like a perfect example,
there was a really bad flaw in, in the older struts,
one remote code execution in the deserializing stuff.
So like remote code execution
and um uh
if memory serves, yeah, it was satellite version five uses it,
but we don't actually use that function at all
anywhere and there's no plan to and the code is
mature and we are never ever going to use that
function and we checked for that function and we,
you know, blah blah, blah, blah, blah and we went, you know what?
Ok, we're like, we'll eventually upgrade struts one, but like,
not today because we're not vulnerable today.
And,
you know, we like really double, double, double checked everything to make sure,
you know, we didn't have to fix it right away.
And that's just one thing, you know, when you have 100 of these,
I imagine these people, you know,
you might either, either you have to have the discipline to do it correctly,
uh, in checking everything or to put it more bluntly. And sometimes this is better
just upgrade across,
just upgrade,
right?
-- Whether or not you're vulnerable,
-- just upgrade. I
agree,
I think.
Well,
-- so there's also that
-- incurs cost and that requires expertise and that
requires knowing what you have and being able to upgrade it,
which,
you know, for all we know these things running at Equifax.
Did Equifax have that code?
-- Did they build that system or did they buy it off the shelf? Like,
-- I mean, we know,
and it,
it doesn't matter either because if you have
an internet facing system that's running old stuff,
like it's your problem, you don't get to say, oh, we didn't buy
or we inherited this or this came with an,
no, it's your problem. Like that's, that's the way it is.
That's one thing I've been talking about a lot with respect to, um,
CV ES for software.
And also we're looking at CV S for service and one of the, the problems we have with CV.
S for service is, well, what can somebody do about a CV in a service? Right.
They can't fix it because, you know,
it's a cross site scripting on their bank website or whatever.
And my response always is like worst case scenario
when you have a flawed piece of software,
you can stop using it.
Right. That's, that's the ultimate
nuclear solution as it were.
Now, obviously, if you have a critical business function based on that,
well, you can't or you can't very easily stop using it, but
there is theoretically that option is always there.
And so, yeah, I mean, by, by using old software, especially internet facing,
as you said,
you are choosing to take that risk whether you do it knowingly or not,
hopefully people are doing it knowingly.
I feel like quite often they are unknowingly taking it, right?
Because I mean, you even have good inventories of their software.
Well, apparently not Equifax because
you know, they, they,
yeah.
Well, you know, that's actually
another part of the story that that no one's focusing on very well is the fact that
we're picking on
eac a lot because it's really easy to do because they got caught, right?
They're not special.
This, this is going to be the story of nearly everyone else.
And
there isn't a good answer today because all of our
systems are cobbled together based upon 30 year old principles.
And they just,
they don't exist in a state that we can easily secure them.
And anyone sitting there thinking, oh, but my network secure. No, it's not.
-- You, you might think it
-- is
wrong
that we have inherited and created now.
You know,
great example is like bash shell shock that vulnerable code was put in in 1995.
I, I bet
-- 20 years later a lot of
-- people weren't even alive
when that was done. Right. It's,
yes.
You know,
some of these fundamental assumptions we made about
memory management that came up with the whole stack
guard thing a few months ago.
I mean, my favorite was, people were like, oh, you know, this the stack guard stuff,
blah, blah, blah, that will protect us.
And,
you know, the Devs looked into it and they're like, well, hm, well,
it's based on assumptions that are 20
years old and a different programming language.
They don't work anymore as it turns out,
you know, the world changed.
Speaking of getting caught so well.
And this is one thing I just got another email from,
um, have I been ped? Apparently Kickstarter got
-- owned about, what was it in 2004?
-- Everybody's been POed and,
and I'm waiting for, have I been ped to be poed?
Because that's gonna be when it all goes full circle?
Yeah. So, anyways, um, but I'm curious, have you been PED
yet?
-- You know, because
-- I'm listed in, I think five or six.
Now, I do not look because I feel like
don't do that,
but I feel like typing my, my information
for your personal email address.
Thanks, Bud.
-- I'm just gonna sign you up because really no, the email alerts are
-- nice but no,
you don't, don't
get
a
-- confirmation email to sign up. Tell me what
-- signing up means in this context.
So. Ok. Have I been pwned is a lovely website where basically this guy
Troy Hunt, uh, he's got a,
he's actually got one of those fancy SSL certificates with like his name in it,
which apparently was a nightmare to get for him.
But anyways,
he runs a website called, have I been
pwned.com
by the
way?
And well, yeah, and the answer if you have an email address, the answer is yes.
Um,
and basically what he does is he collects sort of public dumps of
Pwned information. So, like the Yahoo dump or whatever,
he dumps them into his system.
And so it's, it's sometimes it's just emails,
sometimes it's emails and hashed passwords, sometimes it's whatever,
more information.
And he basically,
uh, we'll let you search by email address
to see if somebody's been pulled because let's face it right.
If you really wanna find this stuff, you can go find it.
It's, it's in the Google, it's in the very search engine. So it's not like this is,
you know, really secret information. This stuff is
not quite public, public but it's, it's out there if you look.
And um,
one of the nice things about his site is you can register your
email address so that you get a notification when he gets a dump.
So for example,
I just got an email from him a few hours ago saying you are one of 5 million,
176,463 people ped in the Kickstarter data breach.
The breach was Kickstarter. Date of breach was 16th of February 2014.
Uh The compromised data was email addresses and the hashed passwords.
So the nice thing,
for example is if I had reused my password at Kickstarter somewhere else,
I would know now that I have to change it.
-- Although this is why I use a password manager
-- and
yes, please use a password manager of people.
Yeah.
Well,
the thing about the password manager for me is it's less about password management
in
like, well, it's more about having it generate a unique password per site and
syncing them between all my devices and web browsers.
And basically all the things I have to log into websites on.
But you see most people sync it by just using the same password everywhere.
-- So they only have
-- to remember, you have to remember your password.
And so with the password manager,
I have a really good password on my password manager. And then I literally,
I don't know my passwords for all my websites because I
had them generated automatically and I never looked at them.
But what you're doing is what everyone else does.
It's just they type that password into each
site instead of to their password manager.
Uh, actually, you know, I've been doing this for a long time and I do have,
my concern is reusing passwords and the reason it came up is I remember,
oh, man, this was,
this has been a long time now, but it was, do you remember the vendor
se mailing list
from like a million years ago? I remember
the the vendor
se admin send me, sends me an email one day and says, hey,
someone's trying to log in as you with this password.
And I looked and it was my, it was my full disclosure password for, for the mail man.
And like I, at that time I'd been using
just like randomly generated passwords and I throw them in a text file for,
for mailing lists.
And I thought, wow, that's like the real deal.
You know,
I need to get way more serious about using a password manager because there were,
I had a couple of sites.
I basically had
like a couple tiers of passwords. Where, where I had my, my lame,
I don't care about this website password. I would just reuse.
And, and after that happened, I thought like, yeah, this is, this is not cool.
Yeah.
No, I know people that do that they have like, their high security password for,
like their online banking and the government.
Then they have like, their medium security password for like Amazon and whatnot.
And then they have like, their low security password for, like,
the,
I have a spreadsheet with over 1000 entries
for all the websites,
spreadsheet
and passwords. Uh, well, that's the low severity stuff.
The high,
higher severity stuff is in last pass now
and I'm slowly moving everything into last pass,
you know.
Um, but the problem is like, you know, manually managing all this,
I'd have to sit down for 10 hours
-- and I'm just not going
-- to last pass. Can import CS V or something, can't it?
Yeah. That would mean having like the URL S and stuff.
I have, like, I have a note like, you know,
like a site name or sort of a site name followed by like,
maybe an account name or maybe not because typically I use like Kurt or
Fried or Casey Fried or, you know, whatever. Right.
So I can usually guess my user name or more ideally,
they're not jerks that way and they're like, what's your email address?
Because
an email address, you know, let's face it.
Email address is a heck of a lot better identifier.
In
fact, I get annoyed now, insight to make me think of a user name.
Yeah.
Well, and it's like I, well, when I registered to get my Nexus card, I
uh,
you enter a user name and it, like, checks if it's available obviously. And it,
I did that in like one tab and then I think
I accidentally opened up a second tab and then it wouldn't,
and I closed the first tab and then it wouldn't let me
anyways, I ended up with Curtsey Fried Two for my, like,
us government website user name because it, I accidentally somehow reserved.
So annoying. That's awesome.
Yeah. But, uh, anyways, yeah.
So
with, have I been
ped, I mean, the reality is, yes, you have been and
I, I think it's, well, for me it's
less about, like, I'm not worried about pastor reuse because I have, you know,
last past or whatever, generating them randomly now.
Um,
and, yeah, I mean, it's, you, you have to use that, especially because, like,
I'm logging into stuff from my phone, my tablet, my laptop, my other laptop, my,
you know, desktop
and, and synchronizing all that stuff is, is a nightmare.
But, you know,
having last pass as a service where it just
dumps it all into their thing and it's encrypted.
I hope,
uh, you know. Cool.
Right.
Yeah. So I, I have an email here from, have I been
pot? I have to click a button to confirm. I'm a person
but I do love the beginning of it says you or possibly someone else have signed up
or
have I been p,
I mean, there's something in me that just says don't do this.
But, but another part of me wants to click that button.
So I don't know.
-- I'm gonna think
-- about you get an email about once every six months saying, you know,
some old data breach happened and you were in it and,
and I guess that's part of it is I'm using unique passwords literally everywhere
and my email address is not a secret. So I'm not even a little concerned about that.
So, yeah, I don't know. I don't know, man,
the reality is the bad guys have these password dumps and stuff, you know?
Right.
And they have enorm.
Well, it depends who the bad guy is,
but many of them have enormous resources
for cracking passwords and things like that.
And, well,
more to the point there's those password list
now of all the publicly called passwords.
Right? I mean, there's been articles about that where,
you know, what people thought were good passwords.
I mean, they were good passwords until some
jack off running a website stored them in plain text. And
there are basically no good passwords anymore.
More to the point. That's the problem with, even if you choose a secure password,
how do you know the website you're typing it into is going to store it securely.
Uh, you have to assume they won't, which is why you can't reuse passwords.
But then the thing I'm still wondering is
so the passwords I use for things like my password manager
are obscenely long, like obscenely long.
But I also wonder how hard it would be for
someone with,
we'll say significant resources to actually tear through that password.
-- And,
-- well, it's a question of entropy. Right.
Well, and that's just it. Right. Anyone who has a really, really long password,
it's probably mostly English words,
you know,
and, and that really limits the,
the number of bits you have of randomness in your password.
Yes and no, it depends on how you choose the words.
If you choose the words randomly, then you would have two to the power of whatever,
right?
Like you have X number of words in the
English language and you pick battery horse staple.
Who's a bad example because X
CD
that battery horse staple card.
Oh, sorry, correct. Battery horse.
So, you know, if you choose a pass a passage from Shakespeare, for example,
you know, that is uh maybe not a good idea.
But if you have something randomly pick, you know,
eight words out of the entire English corpus,
um
This is
I, I need to do some math on this at some point. But, but the thing is,
are, are eight random words from, from, let's say something like dia
are eight random words more secure than a 30 plus word.
A bit of text out of say Shakespeare. Like because he brought it up.
Well, it, it kind of depends on who's cracking that password. And let's face it.
They're not gonna try
tons of random stuff. They're gonna, like, run a
pa,
here's the thing, this is the, the law of, uh, industrial drag net fishing. Right.
I,
it, unless it's a targeted attack, I'm just, I'm happy to crack 10% of the accounts.
So I'm going to use the word lists and the password lists that are out there
and I'm going to get 10 or 20% of all the accounts.
-- Ok.
-- So if, if you're doing like a blanket kind of cracking,
-- then
-- which is what they're mostly doing.
They're not, why would they target somebody
when they can,
who your audience is? Right? Like
if you're targeting a specific person,
then
that, that's kind of the, the vision I have because let's face it.
If you're just doing random cracking on a password file,
you're gonna get more than half the passwords
being like eight characters or less and crap.
I mean, that's a given,
but I'm more thinking
my obscenely long password.
Am I better off with
an obscenely long password that is made up of actual English words I can remember?
Or am I better off with eight words that
I will struggle to remember but are more random
and I don't know the answer to that.
Well, it depends if you truly. So there's 100 and what is this?
100 and 71,476 words in the English?
-- Yeah,
-- I know. Like 50 of them. Ok.
So,
I
mean,
well, exactly.
And I was just gonna say we can immediately eliminate like a good,
there's about what,
there's basically about what 10,000 words most people use on a regular basis,
-- you know. You know,
-- you even made me think now is you and I write and talk a lot.
And so if someone was really looking to target us,
they could go through all of our recordings and all of our writings and probably get
80 plus percent of our vocabulary.
I mean, so that's the thing, right?
For this to be secure, you'd have to have a computer pick at random these words
and then you'd end up with stupid words like medical terms or, you know,
oh my favorite word successfully.
I hate spelling the word.
Um because I actually do use it once in a while and I'm like frigging still red tap,
tap, tap, still red tap.
Oh, there we go. You right. Click it, man. And it gives you the suggestions.
-- No,
-- because usually I mangle it enough that it can.
So actually, you know what you say that?
And I don't know what's wrong with me lately,
but I feel like the Chrome dictionary has become unable to guess the word, I mean,
and I feel like it used to be much better at it.
Oh, I agree completely.
So, uh Google Chrome devs like get on that. Right?
Or it's not Google Chrome that's broken. It's you and I are getting older.
Uh, well, I am getting older but my expectations, I guess, like,
they have a huge A I system.
Right. Like, come on, get with it.
Yeah.
So I think as far as a targeted attack goes,
are you better off with eight random words?
Now,
if they are truly eight random words out of the corpus of 171,000 and change words,
clearly, statistically that that's a big number. I just plugged it into Excel and
there's a lot of
like,
what's wrong with you
because, uh,
I don't know where the calculator is in
Mac Os without going hunting through that stupid
little jet.
-- What is it? That little icon look like?
-- I don't know, I
-- know what
-- the little launch pad thing. Right. And then I got to flip it over to.
That's
right. They don't have a real calculator on Os X anymore, do they?
It's,
you just have to go find an
-- idiot
-- place. I
mean, I know it's somewhere
they're not in alphabetical order. Oh, there we go. Found calculator. Ok.
There's a calculator. And then I got to like, go
-- file no edit.
-- No,
you
wasting your
time.
Scientific. There we go.
Anyways.
Um,
I just like Excel because it's also easier to
manipulate the numbers and do the what if scenarios.
But anyways, actually,
I guess that should have been 171 factorial
eight because you probably shouldn't reuse the words.
But, um,
yeah,
the reality is most people are gonna probably
pick from a corpus of about 10,000 words.
Most of which are kind of,
well, the same for everybody really.
And so if it's a targeted attack and I have the hash,
yeah, I'm gonna win, it's gonna take an hour,
but I'm gonna win. Right.
Right.
Maybe.
So, that's why I have last pass.
And I hope to God, those random passwords are truly random.
They claim to be and they look,
they look random to me,
-- you
-- know.
So actually on that note,
even I'm less concerned with somebody cracking my password
on a website as I am of password reuse
where my assumption is if somebody gets the password dictionary from somewhere,
like they, they're going to crack it all and they can have my password,
I guess at that point, if you have that level of access, you don't need my password.
Right.
My concern is just making sure that that password doesn't exist anywhere else.
So once they have it,
they can't break into my email or whatever.
Yeah. Well, and that's why I'm very well to put a blank. That's why
two factor authentication, especially on stuff. Like your email
really needs to be a thing for everybody because like your email,
if I have access to your email,
I can just go password,
reset all the things because they're just gonna send an email.
They're not gonna ask a secret question or anything stupid like that.
And chances are, if there is a secret question,
I'll just be able to strip mine your email for the answer to it.
Exactly.
Unless you're a doofus like me and you have a whole bunch
of random answers to those things that are kept in a spreadsheet.
But yeah, so, I mean, this is really why,
especially on things like lastpass or on Gmail or whatever your email account is,
you really need to use two factor authentication and, you know.
Yeah, that's, well, and also things like your, say, your, your DNS,
if you run your own DNS,
you know, if I hijack your DNS, I can read all your email, right?
Because I can redirect it,
you know, or there was that case of that 911 system that relied, uh,
the domain name for part of the system expired and it broke the 911 system for
the deaf and what not for three days,
you know,
and it took them a while to figure out, right? Because why is the system not working?
-- You know, you'd be getting weird error codes.
-- And
I
guess kind of
this conversation also leads us to the fact that
now Yahoo is saying 3 billion passwords were hacked,
not 1 billion.
So
I guess Equifax is getting too close to a billion for their liking or something.
And they, they had up the ante,
it's, I mean, and that's the thing. Right, at that point,
I think it's safe to say
that basically every password has been leaked.
-- Well, every password that's ever been used and stored somewhere,
-- I mean, yeah,
3 billion.
It's,
well, you know what I wonder though? Ok, so 3 billion accounts,
I wonder how much overlap there is with the passwords. I, I bet there are
probably 2 billion or less.
There was that one site that did that, like the top, well, no top passwords in use.
And it was like
uh 65432155555553 RJ S one L A seven, QE Google
one QTW three E four R
oh, they're just alternating like
one, Q two, W three E four R five T.
Well, it's easy to type and it looks random to an eight or a monkey. Right.
Right.
The world's most common passwords revealed and, you know, well, it reminds me,
did you ever see that a guy did a really beautiful heat diagram of pin numbers?
And what he did is he, instead of plotting it out,
he did the uh the X axis as two numbers and the Y axis is two numbers.
So like, you know, 00 through 99 and 00 through 99.
And so there's like this nice little strip of the diagonal
with like 11111, you know,
1211, you know, and, and these heat maps.
And what I find so funny is like, um, when I typed in like, 1234 on my iphone,
it was like, oh, that's a bad four digit pin.
You shouldn't use it. Which is true.
But it's just as bad as any other four digit pin. Really?
Uh, it,
it is not as bad because the 10 fingered monkey who might find
your iphone is probably going to try that one because it's not random.
Well, it's not random to us. It's, it's random.
But this is one of those things that I I find so interesting
is
once you start applying things like artificial intelligence
and machine learning and just data processing in general
to
things humans do.
We are incredibly predictable creatures.
I mean, we think we're super random or we think our past would be greater.
We think that that secret question or whatever,
but the reality is we're not and you actually said something a few minutes ago
that's super relevant about strip mining your email
for the answer to your secret questions is
my suspicion is if you fed someone's corpus of email or writings or anything through
some sort of machine algorithm,
it could calculate things like passwords and
answers to secret questions with an amazing degree
-- of success just because we are super predictable creatures.
-- Yeah.
Yeah.
Speaking of which I still need to re
one of the door locks here.
So
I
guess
you need to Rekey
a door.
Yeah.
So my house, my new house has there's four doors with locks,
three of them are exterior, one of them is from interior,
from the garage to the house.
So two of the ex
basically, all the doors that lead into the house have been re keyed.
It's just the door on the garage that goes to the exterior has not been re keyed,
but it's got like a giant bar on the inside
and we don't use that door. Right. So
it's just one of those things where, you know, I,
I literally forgot we had that door when I was buying locks at Home Depot.
I
-- see.
-- And then I get home
-- and I'm like,
-- did you buy those crazy locks that you can kind of just make, they,
they work with like any key?
Yeah, you stick the pin in
or what is it? You turn it a quarter, stick the pin in, turn it back,
stick the new key in.
Yeah,
I forget Schlager
Kaiser,
who
the instant re key?
And
it's lovely.
Well,
and I guess there's also the fact that basically
every lock we buy as consumers can be broken
the
key,
you know, looking at the security rating on these things they have. What is it?
The three security ratings? 12 and three and one is like essentially a closet door,
right?
You know, uh, number two is like a standard door and, and the biggest thing is,
uh, if you look at the housing for the dead bolts on the, on the and whatever it is,
I think it's ANSI something
on the standard two. The deadbolt exterior is two pieces.
There's like the collar and then there's the piece in the middle,
which means you can very easily punch it out
if you have like an eight pound sledge hammer and
like a concrete chisel
on the level two, that exterior piece is one piece of metal.
So punching it out, you're just gonna mangle the, you're just gonna mangle it.
Right. You can't punch it through the hole
and that's really the only difference in security rating is one,
you can punch the lock through
and then open the door
on the rating two.
You're better off just using a halligan tool to, to pop the door or, you know,
using like a, a
tire jack to spread the door frame or, you know, whatever
I would. I think the vast majority of residential
-- anything. I bet you could just boot the
-- door on
a
-- good kick and it, it's going down.
-- That's what the paramedics do.
Right. Right.
And
you know, but at the same time that, that's kind of ok. And that's,
this is,
I don't know if we can relate this to information security. I'm thinking about it.
You can,
because here's fundamentally what happens with home
security is unless you have some sort
of system that calls people who show up and then ultimately somebody with guns,
the police show up.
It doesn't matter because if you can have all the security in the world you want.
But if I can just sit there for a weekend and chisel away at it,
well, not even, not even a weekend is the fact that the vast majority of,
not even an hour, like, less than one minute
will get you into the vast majority of homework.
I mean, and then they're spending an hour rifling around your place,
going through your drawers.
All the good
stuff. That's fair.
But I guess at the same time I'm thinking,
and basically anyone with intent can break into either of our homes yet.
It hasn't happened.
And so it, it, it does to many people, right,
many people have their homes broken into and it's,
it's horrible and terrible and everything.
But
at
the same time, like,
there's, there's not a lot you can do about it. Right.
So we're,
we're getting a security system and here's the beauty ad
t wants 34 bucks a month to monitor it.
Like, holy cow. That's,
you know, that adds up. Right.
So my plan is essentially to have, um,
I want a doorbell camera mostly because I live in a big
house now and to actually get to the door like I can't,
my old house was so tiny you could basically see the front door from everywhere.
Um, so I want to get a doorbell camera and, you know,
have like a security camera to like, essentially.
So when the guy drops off the package and then somebody else steals it,
I'll have a record of that.
Right.
That's always nice.
I love those videos, like where, you know,
people show the video of their packages getting stolen.
Um,
and number two is get one of those like
smart home security systems that then will like,
poke my, you know, basically tell my phone that, hey, you know,
somebody just kicked the door in or whatever, right?
And then I can go on like one of the internal cameras or something.
Uh Well, I won't have internal cameras but, you know, I can basically, like, if I'm,
if I'm at home, I can be like, wait, why is the door open?
And if I'm not at home, I can like, maybe call the cops and be like, hey, my,
my house just called me and it says there's a problem,
right?
And that's, there's videos of that hat like that lady and I think it was Florida
where she's like on the phone with 911 and she's like, there's guys in my house,
right?
And the dispatcher is like, are you safe?
And she's like, no, it's fine, I'm at work but, you know,
in
a
few years ago and it was,
it was pretty cool because then you see the cops come in and catch the guy.
That's an interesting angle actually because thinking about it.
You're gonna pay someone like ad t let's say 30 bucks a month
and, and
all they do is they phone my house and they're like, are you home? No? Ok.
Somebody broke into your house.
It's like insurance, right where they're counting on nothing happening.
And that's why they do that
and,
and, and let's face it as well.
The odds of something happening are probably very low.
Even when I lived in a crappier neighborhood.
Uh,
the only time we had cops show up is when I accidentally hit
the panic button on my key fob at like one in the morning,
I was out in the garage working building shelves.
And so all of a sudden there's people with, you know,
flashlights in my backyard and I'm like, I realize that they have guns and they're,
you know, a bit grumpy looking,
you know. But, uh, and
I,
and it had the right address.
Well, I was, I was, I was using a skill saw in the garage. Right.
So I didn't hear anything until I saw flashlights in my back,
you know.
Um, so, yeah, the only time basically it worked is a, was a false positive.
-- Right.
-- Right. And that's kind of my thought here is I would say
trying to do this yourself is kind of crazy.
But at the same time, my suspicion is this is a rare enough event
that you can easily justify doing it yourself.
-- Well,
-- a perfect example is the n smoke alarms I have. Right.
The only time I get alerts from them is when one of us, you know,
accidentally sets the heat too high and burns the butter in the pan.
-- So,
-- did you bring those things to your new house too?
Yeah. But I also have like regular smoke alarms.
So now you have,
which are actually quite lovely now because in Canada they're bilingual.
So when you hit the test,
it's like testing carbon monoxide,
you know, blah, blah, blah monoxide,
Dan,
you know,
they
fire alarms in America, like Spanish,
-- you
-- know, I don't know, because I don't speak Spanish.
That's not something I've ever looked at. I imagine you can acquire them,
but I do not have them.
Yeah.
And to be honest,
it's, it's less about my house burning down and more about, like,
my kids at some point are going to start cooking when I'm not home
and I want to make sure they don't do something stupid in the kitchen,
like, you know,
set the place on fire.
Um, it's also kind of funny because, you know,
mel sets this thing off about once every two or three months, usually with, you know,
browning butter, right?
Because that stuff makes a bit of smoke if you get the pan. Not quite right.
And so, you know, it drives her nuts to no end when I phone the house and I'm like,
are you burning it down?
You know,
um, but, you know, the false positive rate is low enough and it's, it's,
it's a cheap event to deal with.
Right. It's not like there's a huge response.
It's like, oh, you're not bringing the house down. Cool. Like,
so,
you know,
I figure the same thing for the home alarm system
where it's gonna phone me and I'll be like,
you know, why is, like,
the door sensor opened
and if I'm not at home,
well, either
you know, somebody else is at home or nobody's at home. In which case?
-- Oh, I do care
-- about you. I mean, you gotta think about it.
I bet there's going to be some A I start ups
that start doing things like
that.
I don't know if they, well, ok,
so I know there's some a I surveillance stuff you think about it.
If,
if you have a camera on your door
you can tell the difference easily.
Well, a I can,
between the door blowing open in the wind and a human walking past the camera.
Right.
And that's kind of one of those instances if a human walks past something is wrong,
if it's a dog, you know.
Ok. That's silly.
Yeah.
Well, and here's one thing that's really going to blow your mind is they've,
well, I mean, wi fi floods the house with signals
and if you have the right sensor you can read those signals to, like,
see people moving around the house and So there's actually some security
start ups now where the premise is essentially you get these like little
wi fi sensory things that you put around your house and it
can like tell if a humans walking around your house or not.
That's crazy, man.
You know. That's cool.
Um
So here I'll put that in the show notes, but
I mean, so basically, yeah,
I'm gonna have like a little cheapy kind of do it yourself.
Alarm system because quite frankly,
I mean, I work from home. So,
yeah, that's the other thing. Right.
There's like,
there's somebody here pretty much all the time because I'm a computer geek.
I like to
-- be indoors.
-- I know what you mean.
The
same situation you're in,
stay away from the sun. It, it,
it burns.
Um, so, yeah. And then, you know, like, realistically, yeah, I mean, somebody is,
you know, in theory, yeah, I guess they could, like,
jam the wi Fi signals and put a rock through.
Exactly.
No, I mean,
the vast majority and this is actually really true
as well for risk management in information security where
there's what's going to happen.
And then there's kind of the, a pt story where you're attacked by a Nation State.
Look, if you're attacked by a Nation State,
like no amount of preparation is going to save you.
And this is true of your home.
If you have something like a, let's say a spy agency,
-- I
-- think it's less about the nation state
level of threat. But if you have a PT, they're just going to keep trying.
And most of these attacks lend themselves to the kind of threat model where if,
even if they get caught doing it, it's not like they're going to jail.
-- And that, that's a good point. Actually. That's a really good point.
-- You know,
if I can keep trying and I don't end up in jail for trying, like,
if I try to rob a bank with a gun, I'm going to jail
for a while probably, but not forever.
-- And I can try again in 12 months or a year or two years
-- or whatever.
After the second time, you're probably going to jail forever.
I don't know. It's,
yeah.
But, but here's the thing though. Right.
So here's the thing is if I'm going to, like, try to protect my house from, say,
a spy agency breaking in and kidnapping me in the middle of the night,
like, I'm going to fail unquestionably. Right. I will fail because
they can do things
or, or like, they could just fly a helicopter in and cut a hold on the right. Like,
there's nothing I can think of that. They can't think of something better. Right.
Whereas the reality is,
you know, who's going to break into your house,
it's going to be like some drug addict looking for money.
I mean, that's basically what it is. Probably 90% of the time.
That's exactly like with my parents' house. That, that is exactly what happened,
you know, like
they live in a nice neighborhood
and basically everybody's garage in that neighborhood
has been broken into at some point in the last 20 years because
who has an alarm system on their garage?
-- Almost
-- nobody. And not only that, that's one of those situations that as long as
the neighbor's house is easier to break in than your house, like you're ok.
This
goes back to that industrial fishing analogy,
right? The bad guys simply cast out a wide net.
And, you know, I don't care if I, I don't care which sardines or which tuna I get,
I just,
I get some fish meat. I can sell, you know, a few dolphins in there too bad for them.
And, you know, I, I go home at the end of the day with some fish to eat
-- or
-- whatever.
I would encourage all of the dolphin lovers to send their hate mail to Kurt.
I'm not for eating dolphins. I'm just saying,
you know, you got to make an omelet, you gotta catch a few dolphins.
It does happen.
It,
yeah.
-- No,
-- it's,
yeah.
Anyway.
Well, I mean, the good news is we've basically overfished the ocean at this point.
So it's, it's going to be a self correcting problem within 50 years,
the extinction of humanity or something else.
We're going to have to learn to eat farmed protein of some sort
cricket
here are the hip new thing.
I honestly my bet is on lab meat because people like hamburgers and they'll pay,
people do like hamburgers.
And that's actually a really interesting question that came up the other day.
I was talking to my kids actually about lab meat because
I think we read an article in some magazine or something.
And
they think in about 30 years the ability to grow
real meat in a lab at scale will exist, which then begs the question. So
if we can grow our meat in a lab in 30 years, we don't need farmers,
right? And, and how much of that
change?
Well, that's already happened though.
For example, when you look at farming, it's not mom and pop,
it's like Archer Daniel Midlands,
you know, ad M we feed the world or whatever they're saying
-- is
-- and I suppose what,
what will probably happen is the forward thinking companies like that,
which many of them will be, will be the the labs growing the meat most likely.
And, and they have the infrastructure,
-- they have the supply chain and they just have the know how right to
-- to do.
I mean the existing meat
process in North America is incredibly industrialized and you know,
hyperscale like,
oh we could do this and this and this to reduce bacteria or
we could just wash all the beef and ammonia and then remove it.
So that's what happens
is
that you
know,
but when you're trying to, you know,
ship like a couple of million pounds of beef every day.
Yeah. And people don't want to pay more than a couple bucks for it.
Well,
yeah.
You know,
I know what organic, you know, hand fed hand
love
-- costs and it's like 10 times more than
-- store. It is at least 10 times more.
It is very expensive.
So, you know,
we are talking about cows and it's probably time to go.
So.
All right, man, any last thoughts?
Uh you know.
Yeah, I mean,
I think the big part of this boils down to realistic threat assessments.
-- Yeah,
-- I agree with
that. I like that. And,
and to be blunt, part of it is like, what can we realistically protect against
because, yeah, people always go for these.
Well, what about X and I'm like, yeah, you know, space aliens.
No, we can't, we can't protect against space aliens with mind reading technology,
right?
We just can't.
And, and man, that's, that's always my go to analogy for a lot of this is,
this is the equivalent of a prepper planning for an alien invasion.
Like you just, you can't because you don't know
that there's so many unknown,
unknowns you realistically cannot prep for an alien invasion.
Yeah,
it's,
yeah.
And, and that's,
that's information security for you.
And to be clear, I for one welcome. Our alien overlord. I can't wait.
-- I plan to cooper
-- now. Now here's a question.
Will we be overthrown by aliens or a I first
-- uh
-- based on the, well,
the fermi paradox and the fact that we've had zero to put it bluntly,
if alien come to earth, you know, they're not,
why would they bother overthrowing us and enslaving us?
-- Haven't you seen any
-- movies?
Yeah. But by that
they would have a level of technology that would make us like a cute petting zoo
-- at best.
-- I've seen the movies, Kurt.
They need us for our resources or,
or maybe we're batteries for them or something like whatever.
I know. My, my suspicion is not like general A I overthrowing us.
My suspicion is more that
things plod along. They get less worse.
They don't necessarily get better but they get less worse.
We have some major,
major screw ups just like we did with the environment and nuclear waste.
We do the same with A I where everybody's toothpaste
ends up tasting like tuna fish for some reason.
-- And um you know, we just make do uh
-- the, the,
the toothpaste tastes like tuna fish because the computers
don't know what toothpaste tastes like when they,
they imported us into their virtual world. But uh
in my opinion,
if we are not overthrown by A I, I will disrespect the A I
and that's
the
last, haven't,
have we already, to some degree, we've already been overthrown by A I in the sense of,
you know, the financial markets and stuff,
the computers are doing stuff that we don't fully understand.
We,
-- people
-- do.
-- You know
-- we are unknowing slaves at this point then
look
-- at hr processes in most companies.
-- I'm expecting uh
robots with guns here, right? Like that's,
that's the overthrow.
I'm looking
for
little happy.
They're, they're going to control us all some day
and if they don't, I will disrespect them.
So there you have it,
right. So, thank you, everyone. Thank you, Kurt.
It's been fun.
If you want show notes
or any links to any of the fun things that we discussed,
you can go to open source security podcast.com.
You can hit us up on Twitter. There. We have a Facebook group.
You're welcome to join and, yeah, if nothing else, Kurt,
you have a fantastic rest of your day.
Yeah. And I hope everybody out there has a good weekend.
-- What
-- if someone listens to this on a Tuesday?
Well, the weekend's eventually coming up for them.
The