Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 73
with myself Gert Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
-- How are you doing, Kurt?
-- Very well.
Enjoying the ski season.
Enjoying good. That's awesome.
So, I have a story to tell that's related to security, but in,
in a kind of a roundabout way
I got suckered into running the concession stand during my son's swim meet,
like, pretty much forever. Right. This is certainly one of those.
There are various swim meets during the year
and I'm certain now that I've touched it last, I'm in charge and that's fine.
Right. I think it'll be ok.
But
so
everyone thinks I'm magic
because I made a spreadsheet to track inventory as
well as how much stuff we're buying and,
and this is crazy
and profit.
So we know what, what made money and what didn't,
what were they doing before? Just a bag of money.
Yes,
that is exactly what they were doing before.
And,
but,
but I was thinking about this and the fact that I
literally spent maybe one hour of my life and I've revolutionized
this kind of committee
for this swim team
because I'm doing things like math. Right. And,
and it occurred to me that this, this is, this is security's problem. Right.
We are,
we are the people like running around and just buying random crap and having no idea
what if it works or if it doesn't work or if it makes sense or,
or there were some instances where they were actually
selling things that were making literally zero profit.
Like, why, why, why would you do that? That's insane. And it
surprise me if they
bring people in.
No,
it wasn't a loss leader. It was like sandwiches.
But anyway, anyway,
and, and
it occurred to me though, this is security's problem. We don't measure what we do.
And so we just do crazy things that we don't even know if it makes any sense.
And as soon as you start writing this stuff down,
it becomes really obvious what is a good idea and what is a bad idea, right?
And it,
I just had that as we
were discussing earlier. I,
so the, the I want a CV and I need a CV.
Request form, goes to a spreadsheet with about 230 ish entries
and I went through last night classifying them all as either basically, OK,
like the request is well formed and I can do it
or there's something wrong with the request like there's no reference URL or it's a
bad reference URL or the descriptions all mangled and kind of how it's mangled and
and now I have data and the beauty is like 10% of them.
The description is missing the version
of the product that's affected and then there's 10%
as well that are missing the actual like product.
So it literally will say something
like there's a cross site scripting vulnerability
like that's the description they're using of this phone. It's kind of like
it would be probably helpful to have a product name and version in there as
well,
just saying it right?
And the good news is like the majority of them can
easily be salvaged because I asked for that data elsewhere.
But here's the takeaway. I have actually learned something from this
which is,
I can't make people write the descriptions because
at least 20% of them will get mangled.
So I'm basically going to generate the descriptions from the data.
That's a great idea.
But and the beauty is I can say that and I actually have data to back
it up now because I can quantitatively say 20% of these people will mangle it and,
and in fairness,
like a lot of them clearly English is
not their first language or even third language,
you know.
So asking them to write
a couple of well formed sentences is, yeah, it's kind of a chore.
Well, not just that, I mean, if you read the CV E descriptions,
they're written in a certain way Right?
And I always feel like this when I deal with lawyers where the lawyer
asks you what you want to say and then they turn it into lawyer speak
and, and I mean, security is really no different.
We have our own way of saying things. There are certain words that are used.
We don't actually have a really official standardized vocabulary.
It's not standardized, that's a really good point. It
is not standardized,
-- you
-- know, what does trust mean?
What does security? What does availability mean? Right. Like
-- there
-- are
-- three podcast episodes, you just listed.
No, I get it. It's, it's crazy man.
But back to your crazy story
that, that, that's my story.
That's all.
-- And here's what
-- I love is,
is my first thought is it's great that you revolutionized this.
But does anyone sort of audit the books or are you
like pocketing like 500 bucks a week from the swim team?
And that's why they've never turned a profit.
No, in my case,
I can't because I'm showing all the money moving through the system now.
So if I wanted to embezzle, I couldn't
because we basically, and in fact, what's really cool is I,
I did the kind of projected income
right from the event
and
we were pretty much on the nose.
I mean, you're always going to be a little off because like, for example,
you let coaches come and just like take free soda and stuff like that
I'd actually be more worried if your number was correct.
I would have been.
Yeah,
that, that, that wasn't going to happen.
I, I was, I was probably within a 10% margin of error, which I think was pretty good.
Yeah. Right. Right.
Most stores, if they could order within 10% of what they actually needed.
Yeah, I feel like they'd be pretty happy about that.
Yes. And we, we did well on inventory as well.
I don't think there is a lot left, which is ideal, right?
Because this is a sort of thing.
You don't want to have huge containers of crap stored in a closet somewhere.
So anyway, but like I said, I just,
I kept thinking about security after this and the fact that we,
we, we, the people just buying random crap
and,
and don't get me wrong,
I think more often than not, it does happen to work out.
But if you apply a little bit of, I guess scientific rigor to what you're doing,
I think you can definitely get a more positive result.
And the best part, here's the best part of this though.
And this is what really rings true to me when I think about the context of security is
I don't really want to do this.
And so I'm going to try to find some schmuck to give it to as soon as possible.
But by writing it all down and showing things in documents,
I can easily hand this off to someone else and I don't have
to worry about them screwing it up or not knowing what to do because
it's, it's dead simple if it's written down. Right.
This isn't, I have to tell you what to do.
And in fact, that's kind of what happened to me with, there were people,
like 700 people telling me what they did.
And I'm like,
I can't no, like what you said and what you said, don't even those conflict.
So, one of you is lying or confused and, and that person over there,
I don't know what they did before.
You know, it's just, it's crazy.
Well, that's, that's my favorite
part of programming, right? Is that computers are fundamentally, really stupid.
So you have to decompose the problem into ridiculously simple steps.
And the only way to do that is to actually understand the problem,
-- you know,
-- have you used a computer recently?
Well, I mean, like, for example, with inventory, the fact that, oh,
we could order more stuff so we don't sell out.
But then, yeah, like you said, we have to store it somewhere. Oh,
yes.
You know who's going to store it? How do we, you know, whatever, blah, blah, blah.
Right. Not me. That's the answer. Yeah.
So,
and, and that's what I always see, you know, whenever I see like an sap roll out,
it always ends up being like, you know,
three times over budget and taking an extra five years.
Yes.
And you know, it keeps coming back to like, well,
Doris from accounting handles that function.
Well, what, what does she do?
I don't know, she just does it like she makes the invoices get paid.
Yes.
Yes. I'm, I'm totally familiar with that.
You gotta love it, man. So, but anyway, anyway, it's
just, it's got me thinking now
about how do we, how do we make what we do more boring.
-- Yeah.
-- Well, one of my
questions when it comes
down, I've been thinking about this too because like,
for some types of security you can kind of run like a b, you know, tests,
like you can have a control group and
an experimental group and see what's different.
The problem though is, you know, if, if somebody says like, hey,
let's install antivirus scanners on half our systems and not
on the other half and see which half gets more infected
people are going to freak out because, you know,
there's that perception of allowing risk when you
could have not allowed it. Right. And,
yeah, I mean, how do you deal with that? Right. It's like the whole
um,
well,
like that whole thing with kids not being allowed to be
outside on their own anymore because what if they get kidnapped?
Well, but that
don't, I mean,
they're much more likely to like, choke on a bird or something ridiculous
than get kidnapped.
But
if it happens,
why didn't, you, you know, take steps to ensure it didn't happen.
Right. And actually, uh, Schneer
had a post. Uh, I
read, I don't, I think it was last week, maybe
where somebody on an airline or an airplane had sent their
wi fi access point to like there's a bomb on board
and of course, the plane was diverted and landed and it was this big to do
and, and Schneier
was saying, you know, why, why are we letting ourselves be terrified? Right.
This is, this is your,
you're essentially letting like the whole Paris mantra win here.
And
the thing I kept thinking of was,
let's think about this from the perspective of the airline,
they do nothing
and there's one of two outcomes,
nothing happens or the plane explodes.
Well, number two, nothing happens when somebody calls the press.
But ok,
that,
that, that's true. Maybe, maybe that's potentially a third.
But let's, let's ignore that for a minute
and you've got
nothing happens, which is almost certainly what it will be.
-- Well, in fairness
-- if the plane blows up though,
chances are nobody's going to ever know about the wi fi password being an issue
or the Wi Fi name being an issue.
Yes, that's
maybe, maybe we'll, we'll assume they do
because here's the thing. If nothing happens, people will say, oh, ok, who cares?
And maybe the press gets a hold of it and maybe they made
something to do about it and and the airline could easily just say,
look, people are acting like Children.
This isn't a story. It was just a stupid clown.
However, if something does happen
now all of a sudden you're gonna have people saying
you guys knew something was fishy and you did nothing. Explain yourselves.
Right. And, and that's the thing. It's easier
to do the ridiculous thing of divert the plane,
kick everyone off and arrest the guy who set his access point to that
than it is to do nothing
because it appears you're doing something even though it's probably
useless and has a net negative impact on society.
Yeah.
The, the economist actually,
I think it was the economist had an
article about this called the goalkeeper dilemma.
So in soccer, the goalkeeper, when they take a penalty shot,
they have to be seen to heroically doing something when statistically speaking,
they actually best thing is to like,
kind of stand in the middle, do nothing.
But if they do that and they
report on they're going to get murdered or boot off the field.
Right. Well, and literally murdered in some of these countries. Right.
Well, he scored, he, he, that was an own goal and it was so like,
yeah,
that's not going to go well.
Um
but anyway, so,
and I mean,
well there was that case of where somebody found a note on a plane that said Bob
and they took it to mean bomb on board.
So, they land the plane, clear the plane, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Oh, my goodness. You know.
And yeah, I mean, it, it,
you know what this really reminds me of is
this whole zero tolerance policy that is creeping into,
well, not creeping into society that is accepted by society on so many things and
for some zero tolerance makes sense.
But for other things, it's like we, especially when you're dealing, for example,
with little kids, it might be better to have a bit of leeway to like,
not expel them or, you know, uh
boot them out for a week, but actually just talk to them about it,
you know, and see if their behavior changes rather than, you know,
these draconian measures
where, you know, for example, kids get into fights at school and they,
they can't defend themselves because if they defend themselves,
they'll get suspended as well.
Right.
You know, and,
and then there's cases where even the kid did not defend themselves
and they still got suspended for being involved in the fight.
And it's kind of like, yeah.
Ok.
Um, it's crazy, man.
Yeah. And I just think it's coming more, especially with, you know,
things were essentially
the company can sort of externalize that cost to a large degree.
So one thing,
for example is I know the local ski hill now requires all their ski instructors to
pass a child welfare check. It's a police report
making
-- sure that you're
-- not
a pedophile
-- or whatever a couple episodes ago. Yeah.
-- And, but it's like, this is on a ski hill.
This is a really public place.
You know, the kids line up outside.
There's like a bunch of little flags with, like, pictures of,
I think it's animals and numbers.
Like, so, like, there's group, 1234 or whatever. Right.
The ski instructors grab their kids, go up the hill, do their thing,
ski lesson and then drop them back off that flag.
And I mean,
I'm just thinking like the the
yeah, the mechanics of like the risk profile here,
you know,
it's just ridiculous.
-- Yeah,
-- but here's the thing.
So you mentioned last time about this that the instructors
have to pay for this background check on their own.
-- Yeah,
-- they have to pay the 70 bucks for this background check as well.
-- So
-- basically the ski hill is incurring zero cost to do this
and it's basically zero risk for them.
I mean, the only potential risk is they don't have enough ski instructors,
but I assume there are more than enough if they're willing to do something like this,
which means from the ski hills perspective,
there's literally zero negative to this even
though it's insane because let's face it,
you know, they're doing this.
Are you still skiing there? I assume? Yes.
Right. So, so there there's literally zero downside to them
and the potential upside is if something does happen, they can say, hey,
they passed the background check, not our fault, you know,
go talk to these background check people
on the flip side though. I sometimes wonder about just making all this, like
in, you know, making all the tax returns public.
I, you know, there's a couple of Scandinavian countries that do that.
And so I just kind of wonder about rather than, you know,
having these systems where we incur these costs,
why not just make all this data public
because the privacy advocates would lose their minds
true.
But I mean, I,
well, and in fact, so that that sort of happened though
in the US where we have,
there are uh,
no, no, not
Equifax.
When, when someone is convicted of
a sex crime against a child,
they go into the national Sex offender Registry
and you can kind of, you can go and say, like,
show me all of these sex offenders who live within a one mile radius of my house.
And you know, what has been the result of this?
It is primarily been used to depress property values in
places that have a large concentration of sex offenders.
And, and I understand the intent
is because you want to give people the ability to kind of
police themselves a little bit and understand what's going on. But the reality is
that's not exactly how it's worked out and
it's,
-- well, this is a tricky problem,
-- man. That's one of my favorite. Second.
Or third order effect stories is, you know,
a lot of the police services now put the crime maps online,
like they put the crime data online in a GIS database.
So you can like do a search like say,
you know, all breaking enters in my neighborhood in the last six months.
I will point out that elastic search does a very nice job of doing this.
In fact,
I I took a training class and this is one of the things we did is they took the Chicago
Crime Database.
Uh and we imported it into Elastic Search and then we mapped all
of the crimes committed in the city of Chicago over like a one month
period.
You know, one of the second order effects they found in London is that
people were actually uh rather
property owners were not reporting property crimes as much because
they didn't want to depress property prices in their area.
Um On the flip side, I was watching a vice news thing yesterday
and this Italian police force in Milan, the city police,
one of their guys Breitbart came up with the idea of this whole mapping,
the crimes out and getting details.
Like, you know, was the guy left handed or right handed?
What kind of shoes did he wear? What did he say?
You know, so that they can match up his crimes?
And so for example,
this one guy who was robbing pharmacies between four
and 7 p.m. on Wednesdays in a certain neighborhood.
So they flooded the area with police for those three
hours and I think they ended up catching him,
you know,
so that kind of predictive crime modeling can be very powerful, you know.
Um, at
the same time, yeah, there's all these unintended consequences.
Um I think what it really boils down to, uh, well, to go off on a tangent there.
Did you see that there was a paper written by some smart people
including Adam
sack
voluntary reporting of cybersecurity incidents and it talks about
people reporting cybersecurity incidents so that we
can learn from them and avoid them.
And my first thought was wow, this, this just absolutely won't work at all
because number one, we don't even have good detection of incidents.
Number two
as well. Uber, right.
They paid 100 grand to the hackers to try and, you know, just delete the data,
promise you deleted data.
No, take backs swears these,
you know, and covered that up.
And so apparently now there's a bill being introduced to make
it a criminal offense to like cover up a data breach.
Um
And it just gets to me that we don't have good data,
the data, you know, a lot of companies will try and hide these things.
But even if for the sake of argument, we had complete reporting of all this, you know,
what recommendations would we come up with and assuming
we could even then come up with recommendations,
getting people to implement them correctly.
You know, because we're just at such a, a
fundamentally not mature stage compared to say
the airlines,
you know, for safety for security. And even they're terrible at this.
They, they are terrible at this and, but they got to where they're at today
by screwing up a lot and learning lessons, we screw up a lot.
But I don't think we learned very many lessons.
Well, you know, I was thinking because I,
I see these ads for all these conferences and
I was thinking like, what actual benefit and actionable thing is coming out of this?
Like, are people, for example,
taking these hardware hacking classes and actually making more secure hardware?
I don't know.
Like I have no idea
what is the return on investment for Black Hat training?
II I
-- straight up have no idea.
-- I would be surprised if it's positive.
Well, and then I, I think about things like, you know,
how terrible would the world be without something like PC I DS s to make sure that,
you know,
credit card processes are at least
patching their systems and running A V.
It would be terrible man,
like unquestionably terrible.
And that's one of the things I love is people are always, you know, mocking check
check box security
and how your compliance doesn't matter and stuff. And it's like
you're not wrong. But what does it say about an organization that doesn't have that
right.
I mean, come on.
Well, I love that, you know. Do you use source control? And the answer is not always.
Yes. And it's like, how is that? Even a thing in 2017?
I, I don't know, man. It, I don't know.
Well, anyways, uh, switching gears, it's coming up on Christmas.
-- Yes.
-- The topic at hand. So last year we talked about the security of Santa
and I thought this year it would be fun to talk about security from Santa
where we, we take the
position of adversarial Santas. Be it
the Santa or, or we'll say some, some copycats
and I just have a friendly chat about some of
the silly stories I found and I did some searching and
it was,
yeah, it was fun. I, I will say though my first search was just for uh Santa crimes.
I think I typed in
uh it sounds like Santa Clara California has a lot of crime
because that's, that's basically all I got.
But, but anyway, anyway, that's neither here nor there.
So we should start with the,
the first story that I think is kind of the biggest and craziest
is
there's, it has its own Wikipedia page
and they call it the Santa Claus Bank Robbers.
And basically what happened was in 1927 in Texas,
there were some people who robbed a bank dressed as Santa
and they ended up with hostages and there was like this crazy gun fight.
According to the Wikipedia article,
something like more than 100 gunshot bullets were fired
between robbers and police and even like citizens who showed up with guns, which
-- sounds very Texas to me.
-- Well, it's, that's happened several times. Um,
what was that mass shooting with a tower at the university in Texas? And,
you know, civilians were providing like covering fire for the police.
Uh, were they really, I don't know the story behind that. It wouldn't surprise me.
That was,
I do remember that, that, that was a terrible event. Definitely.
In
1966 the University of Texas Tower
and the tower is still there, I think,
which is kind of crazy. But
anyway, anyway, so there's big shootout
and the criminals end up,
some of them escaped.
Some of them didn't because they were shot
and eventually they get arrested.
And
now the, the funniest thing though, the absolute best part of this story is in the,
in the notes I sent to you and I'll put this in the show notes.
There's a picture of Santa Claus,
right? It's like a hand drawn,
very sort of greeting card looking picture of Santa, right?
This is something you'd expect on.
-- Right. Right.
-- Exactly.
Ah, that's the mug shot they published
for real.
That's, that's the picture the police put out asking,
identifying the criminal.
You know, it's a good
thing that didn't happen in the modern world because all those poor mall Santas.
But it's a hand drawn picture of Santa. I mean, what, what do you expect?
I mean, that's not, you can't,
-- you can't send
-- something like that.
That's awesome.
It's completely all I can figure is they must have found a
picture in a catalog or something and thought it would be funny.
I, it, it,
whatever. I, I don't even understand how, how they did that. But, yeah.
Yeah,
I was reading up on this and I came across
a story that said that and that's why when you,
when you look up this particular story about Santa,
that picture accompanies them all.
And it's because
it was the picture the police used like the wanted poster, right?
And
so anyway, anyway,
what happens though is the guy who commits the crime ends up getting arrested,
they put him in jail, they find him guilty and he was sentenced to 99 years in prison.
And apparently the people thought he should be put to death.
So they lynched him
because that's a very Texas thing to do, I guess. Also
-- it's just like you can't make this up
-- people when you subvert, when you subvert.
Symbols of good people do get cranky.
-- Yeah,
-- that's probably fair. And especially in Texas, right?
And my favorite part here is so I was looking at the wiki
page.
No one was ever tried to associate with the lynching.
Although a grand jury was formed several
1000 persons viewed Ratliff's body the next day
at a furniture store in Eastland before Judge Garrett ordered the corpse locked up.
Like,
just,
I, I like how back in the day, like public hangings and stuff were, like,
bring the family and a picnic.
It's, you know, well,
it's fun for the whole family
and they had publicly or public hangings in, you know,
some parts of the world up until what, like 19,
the first or second decade of the 19 hundreds.
Well, even, even in France, I think they, they still, the last Guine
execution was what? In the seventies or something? Wasn't
it? Was that
the last public execution was
0 39? Ok.
And there's a picture of it and there was like straight up like a crowd like watching,
you know, it's like
a really good street buster except, you know,
this is, I guess more right. Street cinema every
day.
Uh Yes, it, well, it's the,
remember all those good wholesome values people used to have.
Yeah, that's a lie.
No, I, I know, man. Or you think about like gladiatorial combat even? Right.
I mean, people, they didn't go to watch people fight,
they went to watch one guy kill another guy.
Let's face it. It's like, it's like people who like to go to car races,
mixed martial arts.
Uh
Yeah, that's, that's fair.
Did you see the thing on Reddit about the guy who was, was streaming on Twitch?
Like one of the pay per view, uh ultimate fighting things. I don't know what it was.
He was like pretending to play a video game and you know how they
have the little little image of themselves in the lower right hand corner.
He was,
he was pretending to play the game like he was playing like two dudes fighting.
-- It was hilarious.
-- That's gonna happen. That must be a VR game already.
I don't know. I mean, maybe that's an obvious contender for virtue.
Like first person shooters, we've already got those in VR.
-- There must be like M MA games or whatever for V
-- R. Oh, there's tons of a man.
Definitely.
Anyway, it was,
and he obviously streamed a pay per view match
and, and apparently because of the way it was done,
none of the automated copyright systems kicked in
because it, it looked like a dude playing a game and let's face it too. Like a lot of
these games look
not
have by definition.
It wouldn't know the content to look for because it's being live streamed.
-- I do not know
-- because like the copyright content violation system would have to have
like every single live stream or every single
copyrighted thing to know what to detect.
-- I have no idea,
-- man.
Or I guess you could
embed a signal in the stream maybe saying like this is
it.
-- I don't
-- know. I
know
it was
just, it was hilarious.
It, it made my day when I saw it,
it could be fake even. And I don't care, it was too funny. Anyway. So, so the next story
that I really like about Santa
is, uh,
apparently there was a man dressed as Santa
at a buffalo wild wings handing out marijuana,
which I guess is legal there now. So maybe that's
because I know we're looking at, uh, legalizing it here in Canada come July 1st of,
of next year, supposedly
for Canada Day. Right. And, um,
yeah, I mean,
well, because you can't, like, go on the street and hand out beer,
you
can,
um,
you know,
the
cop would definitely,
and I would
assume
even with legal marijuana that, that would still not be like
a lot.
And that's,
that's probably fair. So, anyway, he handed out, uh,
the packages of dope to people in the restaurant
and apparently saying I have a gift for you
and then left some in the tip jar
and then left and they found him and arrested him.
Which,
yeah, that, that seems pretty fair. You can't
hand something like that out. Well, it was technically illegal then,
but, yeah, I,
it, it made me chuckle. That's
-- right. Go
-- Santa. Right.
I mean, that's always one of my classic questions is, you know,
statistically if somebody,
if I take something in public it's probably not going to be dangerous.
But if somebody hands me something like, what's their motivation?
Are they trying to mess with me? Are they trying to hurt me?
You know, this cookie, does it have a razor blade in it?
-- You know, back to the old Halloween thing? No,
-- cookies have razor blades.
No, II,
I do understand what you're saying and I think it's human nature
to question the motives of someone giving something away for free.
-- Well,
-- especially drugs,
uh, especially drugs. Yes,
indeed. It's,
now, now, I wonder though, is,
is that an innate human quality or is that just something that we've grown
to kind of develop as a trait given the world we live in?
Well, it makes sense because how many times, like, one of my kids would only
try new things if you took a bite
and he would, like,
you would hand him something new,
like a cookie or whatever that he didn't recognize.
And he'd, like, he'd hold it and he'd look at it
and then he'd look up at you and hold it out to you
and if you didn't take a bite from it, there's no way he was gonna.
And if you do the
thing, you better enjoy it.
Right. Yes. And I remember doing that with, with small Children for a long time.
Interesting. And if
I do that though, with people, I know where if they're like, oh, here eat this,
I'll say you take the first bite.
Right. And if they don't, then I know it's a bad idea.
Right.
Uh, in fact, I, I did this to people.
I know is there's, there's this hot sauce called Dave's Insanity sauce.
It's freaking hot.
Uh, you, I don't, but you could,
and
I, I've known people who would say, oh,
I like spicy food and I would take out some
crackers and put some Dave's Insanity sauce on each.
Done two crackers. I would eat one.
Then I'd let them eat one.
It doesn't bother me because I like really spicy foods and they would
not do well.
We'll say
it was hilarious. I loved it. They'd be like, why aren't you doing this?
And I'd say I do this a lot. Actually, I, I'm good.
It's like building up a tolerance to things.
-- Uh,
-- it, it's very much like that.
Well, and I, I read once that people who love spicy food,
it's a similar reaction in the brain to cocaine.
Apparently cocaine addicts
do
-- stuff. Yeah. Uh,
-- something like that.
So, yeah, I'm basically like, hopelessly addicted to spicy food, which is fine.
I like my spicy food. So it's good. It's good.
Yeah.
Uh,
but anyway, anyway,
I loved it.
So, so the, the next story
and this one is my favorite, I think of, of them. All right.
So, so anyway, apparently an armed robber dressed as Santa
climbed through the drive through window of a Kentucky fried chicken,
demanded cash,
threatened the stamp of the knife and then, uh, took the cash and fled
and I'm just thinking,
why would you climb through the drive through window.
Like what, what is the incentive to doing that?
And additionally, what is the staff doing?
Watching Santa Claus climb through the drive through window?
Are they like, what's going on here? My first thought would be part
-- of
-- this person
doing drug
is that it's so unexpected and weird
that you, you just,
a lot of people will just freeze up and be like, what like am I really seeing this?
That, that's probably fair. And in fact I've,
yeah,
I find myself in that situation many times
people trained to deal with weirdness.
So, I mean,
the greatest example being the cops here in Edmonton that had to deal with that
sort of terrorist attack.
And, you know,
so the guy runs over a cop with his car and the cops are kind of like what's going on
and then he's in the bad guy, got a U haul van and he was like, driving on Jasper,
the main dr trying to run over pedestrians and the cops like, oh, ok,
stop him now,
you know, and
they're like, but you can hear initially they're just like, what the hell,
like we're chasing this guy.
What that, like, what? Like, this makes no sense, right?
This is not like a normal profile for a crime.
And, you know,
like,
yeah, like,
I mean,
if Saint Nick climbed into my place of business
through the drive through window with a knife,
I'd be kind of like,
you know,
what,
like did I get some
coleslaw?
Ok. That's fair. I think I would do the
-- same
-- and, and I think a lot of these crimes are not particularly well thought out.
I don't think any crimes are particularly well thought out.
The Diamond Heist in Holland.
That one we talked about that way,
I think.
But, uh,
yes.
Yeah. No, it's
because I've seen that. Have you seen, there's a classic video where somebody is,
uh trying,
what is it? She wanted like chicken mcnuggets or something?
And she's like trying to climb in through an assault that
mcdonald's worker through the drive through window and
the mcdonald's lady is trying to close it
and she's also taking another order or something
like she's used to this and it's just
-- like, it's just such a long
-- show.
Must
be part of the mcdonald's training program now. Right.
And defend yourself through.
I don't know. Oh, my goodness.
But, uh yeah, I think, I think that's a lot of it. Like, because
yeah,
if you're going to commit a crime and you decide to dress up with
Santa that says to me right there that like things are already going down.
Yes.
Right.
Well, ok,
so this is one of the things I've been thinking about is if you dress up as Santa,
are you just a crazy person who happens to be
dressed as Santa when you decide to commit a crime?
Which I'm sure that some of them are.
There's some also that,
that part of their premeditation for crime was I know I'm
going to dress as Santa before I commit this crime.
What?
Yeah. I don't know. I don't know, man, I love it. It's
researching these stories just, I got a laugh.
There were, there, there are a lot, though. There's a lot of stories that it's just
basically someone dressed as Santa stole something
and
more than I could count and I only picked out the really silly ones. But it's like
this is, this is not an isolated incident.
Like it sounds like there are many,
many thefts happening with people dressed as Santa every year on Christmas.
And I guess though at the same time
you have the advantage,
there is no other time of the year you could dress in
a ridiculous costume and not have people think twice about it.
Right.
Uh, that is one day a year.
You certainly could. And, and actually
until
December 26th now,
yeah, basically
it will be
Costco actually.
Uh, they had their Halloween stuff out in, like, late,
I think it was late August, early September
and it was gone by the middle of October and they'd replaced it with Christmas stuff.
Isn't that neat?
So,
Christmas actually came before Halloween this year at
Costco and about two or three other stores.
I'm pleased to say I did not notice that because
I don't think I've been to Costco since Halloween.
But still,
oh, wait, you went to a Costco. You've joined.
I have a Costco membership.
We've got one.
Yes,
a
lot.
I have never had one of their hot dogs. Have a
hot dog.
I
have bought very little there. It's,
it's one of those things, man. Costco is like
the ultimate store at abusing the human condition.
-- There's a
-- documentary about it specifically
how they just like trick you into buying.
That's
for example,
why they have the racetrack and no signs because you
have to walk through the entire store to find anything,
right? And I mean, they, they randomly move stuff around and like,
yeah, no, I,
I love it because it really appeals to my like hunting gathering instinct.
No, I get it. Well, not only that, the other one is,
my kids love the free samples and they'll try something and
then say we should get this and I always say no,
my wife's like, oh, it was good.
We could think about it. I think the
only
reason
you
-- think
-- you should
maybe.
Well, that too. But
the thing is
by giving you free stuff,
you're, they trick us into thinking they're our friends
and we should
seriously and, and the nice people who hand them out are very friendly and it's like,
no, and I keep saying this to my family is they,
they're just tricking us into buying crap.
We don't need no, we're not getting that.
And of course, they, they think I'm some grumpy old,
you know, pain in the butt.
Yes,
they're not wrong
the
maturing
process
anyway. Anyway. So, no, I'm, I'm not a fan of Costco.
The only thing I really like at Costco I will say
is
I can buy a giant can of tomato sauce.
So I only have to open one can instead of like 10 when I make
it out of chili. That's
right. That's pretty much it.
Anyway. Anyway,
we'll keep going. We'll keep going. So the next one is not a Santa related story,
but I, I had to laugh it anyway. And apparently, uh,
a, a baby Jesus statue was stolen from a nativity somewhere
and they got it back because they had put a GPS transceiver inside of the statue.
Well, this
thing and I'm thinking, what would
-- you do that?
-- Because they probably get stolen all the time.
And it kind of reminds me of, um,
uh, this is Christmas related but there's this Swedish town.
Um, that does a big straw, I wanna say a straw goat.
Um,
and then the, the, the thing gets burned down
like every year, like clockwork
that
wait. Oh, people aren't supposed to burn. No.
Yeah,
I
don't know how to pronounce this in Swedish. The,
with an, um, lo
give
goat
is a traditional Christmas display, blah, blah, blah. Yeah, it's like a,
it's like a 23 story tall straw goat looks pretty awesome actually.
And, yeah, like, every year somebody burns that poor thing down.
Which, I mean, I,
I'm a law abiding citizen and even I want to burn something like that down.
If I saw it, you know, it's just be tempting.
It's like a big red stop button next to a bunch of computers. Right.
You just want to see what happens.
Right.
Anyway,
so, I, I think it makes sense for, like, in a neat,
because also GPS trackers are cheap now, right?
You can put those things in your pet's collar.
Yeah, that's probably true that it's fair.
The GPS tracker is probably cheaper than the new
stamps
that have them.
Right.
So
you've convinced me, I still think it's funny.
It is funny.
Yeah, I mean, more to the point like,
what are people doing with these baby Jesus Jesus?
I,
what's the
probably nothing?
It's probably prankster kids who move them and think they're clever.
But
yeah, you gotta love it.
I, I don't know. I don't know, man.
Anyway, anyway,
uh, we'll, we'll skip over that one.
this one is also funny.
This is not technically Santa related but is, is Christmas related.
Apparently there was a guy driving a, a
float in a Christmas parade
and it sounds like if you read the story, he got tired of being behind a slow tractor,
which everything in parades are slow
-- and he, uh, like passed it and then drove off
-- and
you know what I think, I think he was a dad and he just wanted to make good time.
We're not stopping, we
make good time.
Uh, he had an open container of alcohol in the car
and was arrested.
-- If
-- you
-- had
-- to drive a car with more than six kids in it,
you'd probably have an open container of
alcohol.
I
am not going to comment on that.
This is one reason I think self driving cars are going to be awesome
because you can now have a minibar in your car.
Uh, self driving float.
That'll be interesting.
Right. You've got a parade. It's something to drive a car,
huh?
I, I never really thought of that.
Interesting. Although
when you have something like a parade
that can get interesting as well because often
you violate numerous traffic laws during the route of parade.
So maybe they'll have like, special parade mode.
A parade mode with like a top speed of three
miles an hour because realistically at three miles an hour,
not a lot of people,
you definitely have time to react. You know, it's like that,
you know, you say that, but I bet a,
a nontrivial number of people get run over in
parades every year because while you're going slow,
you often have incredibly limited vision as to what's happening around you.
Oh,
Lord. Yeah.
11.5 million results for run over in parade.
I, I'm not going to look it up. I don't want to. But I, I bet the number is horrifying
and in fact, you know what's really annoying is there's a handful of local parades.
I've been to that.
They've stopped letting people throw candy because they're,
they're tired of the mess.
And
the part of me that cleans up, messes agrees with that.
But the, the human part of me says it's freaking candy and, you know,
kids and myself enjoy getting it, like throw the candy.
Come on.
Yeah. So anyway, right.
And, and now
we will, we will end this with the list.
I found a site
that listed the various crimes Santa commits
in the process of doing his activities and,
and we'll start with the first couple makes sense and,
and there shouldn't be a lot of,
I guess discussion around them necessarily.
But I, I find uh number five on my list to be the most interesting. Now,
here's
what?
Yeah, that number five because
let's start with five.
And now now just so you, everyone knows if,
if there will be a link to this in the show notes, the,
the order they list this stuff in is not the order I have it in
because I took a couple of things out and we added a couple of things.
So
it's, it's very
related, but we'll start with five as it says, driving under the influence.
Do people leave booth?
Well, and this also ties into
animal cruelty because
because I have been led to believe that the Reindeer are sentences.
They talk, they sing, they play games, they play
reindeer
games,
they do play reindeer games and they all talk and they Rudolph, the
Reindeer
distress and they bully. So that sounds
pretty
to
me.
But, but
is Santa forcing them into,
are they suffering from some sort of Stockholm syndrome?
Like,
I, I don't know, I mean, I don't know how this works.
Maybe from the driving perspective, Rudolph, won't you guide my Slay tonight?
That sure sounds like Rudolph in charge he's navigating.
Uh Was he given a choice?
Well, maybe,
I mean,
is your Uber driver truly given a choice or does he have to pay this month's rent?
Uh So Rudolph had to pay the rent. Is that what we're saying?
Stay
with him for free
recovery.
They can fly
so he could probably go live anywhere he wanted to
leave?
I don't know. Although in the uh the Madagascar Christmas special,
the, the reindeer can only fly because of uh magic powder in Santa Sleigh.
So it could also be there's some sort of drug addicts that, that can only get the,
the product from Santa. But
-- anyway, like
-- the classic sci
fi combat drug, alien thing.
That's right. That's right. I think Star Trek covered it well.
But, but anyway, number five was driving under the influence and it talks about,
you know, Santa driving to Slay drunk essentially and
like, do people leave booze for Santa
I've never done.
And my son actually has a theory that would also cover this because so
you can drive depending on where you are 0.08 0.05 under the limit.
So that's like one drink.
And my son's theory, well, he has two main theories about Santa.
Number one that Santa is the world's richest person
because he can give away all this stuff.
It's not unreasonable. But his second theory is much more compelling to me. It's
because he was trying to figure out how does Santa do all this?
Right? Does he travel faster than light? Does he blah, blah, blah.
-- And you know, he came up with clones,
-- clones
scale out, parallelize
the workload.
That's not completely inaccurate,
-- I mean,
-- not wrong,
you know.
And so here's the thing,
if there's enough Santas doing this and they all
each only have like say one drink per hour,
then they would be able to stay under the legal limit.
Uh
-- What? But what?
-- So if Santa's only
assuming
one alcoholic drink per hour is not gonna get
like
who's leaving booze for Santa? I
better start doing that,
right.
That's what I'm saying.
I want my kids to leave beer for Santa, right? Like hook me up there, Santa beer.
Stupid Reindeer only get a carrot.
Uh Anyway, anyway. All right.
So, so let's, let's head to the top of the list because it's, it's fun, right?
-- Uh The obvious one is home invasion, trespassing.
-- Well, home invasion is not fun.
Uh It's, it's fun. They're all fun. Kurt. This is,
I was actually thinking about that. Like,
what if people actually did invade homes and leave presents or clean?
-- That would be lovely.
-- Actually. What's really funny is my daughter asked me one day.
Um, this is,
I don't know, maybe, maybe a month ago she goes,
who,
what did she say? She says
Santa must be real because who else would break into your house and leave presents?
And I said criminals and she thought about it for like 30 seconds.
It goes, wait, they take your things, dad.
Yes.
Well,
uh, but anyway, so here's the question I have though
is,
is Santa trespassing
if you leave him milk or beer and cookies?
Because isn't that kind of like an invitation into your home?
Well, you know,
I
was
because don't Children and parents write to Santa saying what
they want and it's kind of like here's the thing.
If you come onto my property, technically you could be trespassing.
But like clearly if I call the cops and I'm like, hey,
there's this guy dressed in brown leaving packages at my
door and I want you to get him for trespassing,
they're going to be like, no, that's, that's the UPS guy or girl and like,
please stop calling us,
you know.
Right. And so like there's that implicit
delivery thing.
Now, the question is, you know, for example,
I've also had them open up the screen door and prop
the packaging between the screen door and the door door.
Right.
Yes. But, but how many UPS delivery people have come into your house?
I don't have
Amazon
key. So
if
I live
in
the
US,
-- but if I lived in the US, that would be a thing.
-- Oh my goodness.
This Amazon thing is totally Santa Claus. Isn't it?
Like someone sneaks into your house while you're gone?
You're gonna maybe you can tip your Amazon
key delivery person with milk and cookies.
-- So
-- II I am thinking that there is like an implicit social contract here, like
where, you know, like for example, the long guy, he can go on to your property,
you know, the UPS guy can go onto your property and, and there's, you know,
ups guys have also left packages on my back porch or under the mat or whatever, right?
And you know,
uh if I could have them actually somehow safely put
the package inside my house without getting rob blind,
I'd probably be ok with that because, you know, winter and stuff, right?
I don't want my packages freezing,
but
now thanks to
Amazon.
Well, not in Canada.
Um,
well,
I would say in general it's not trespass because there's probably that implied
or specifically, you know,
the kids wrote a letter to Santa and the parents approved of it.
-- Uh
-- Yeah, I, I would agree.
I think we could probably strike that one off and say Santa is probably not,
probably not trespassing.
And my assumption is people who don't want him to visit,
he will not visit.
Well, the other thing is, for example,
now he could be using like drones or he could be using all sorts, you know,
like Amazon that last mile delivery where they have
like the truck with drones that zip out,
you know, and, and here's a question if I drop something down your chimney,
is that trespassing?
Like, what if I drop the packages down the chimney?
They bounce out of the chimney under the tree and they don't get dirty because
I have, you know, nanofiber wrapping paper that's
dust proof for repellent.
I'm not even going into us anymore. I'm just throwing packages down the chimney
-- off
-- my roof.
Is there a sign saying that
I'm going to make one?
It says please stay off my roof.
So,
anyway,
uh,
ok. So what about, uh, unlawful surveillance?
Is Santa unlawfully surveilling us all?
-- Uh Well, again, I don't
-- know,
it probably depends on the country, right? Is Santa going to be GDPR compliant?
Well, it depends on the country in the state.
-- I would also point out Santa has never had a data breach
-- that we know of.
True.
I mean, he could be leaking information all over the place and, and he's just good,
he maybe has a really good pr department,
right? You don't, you don't hear a lot of negative Santa news.
It's generally positive. I think you could. It's safe to say his pr people.
-- They're
-- good, man. Oh, no, I got bad news for you. His, uh, no
got hacked last year in a massive data breach.
Set an onion article. No.
Well, yeah, kind
of,
kind of what Equifax is. Right. The naughty. Nice list of
people.
Yeah, pretty much.
-- Or maybe Santa gets his data from Equifax.
-- I
assume you would just buy it.
I mean, because it, well, here's the question,
is that like a core competency or something?
He just outsources now
and I feel like it probably used to be a core competency but due to cost cutting,
he probably outsourced it
cost cutting of what,
where does he need to cut costs? He's already the richest person in the world.
-- He be richer
-- if he cuts costs.
Keep up with me here.
Ok. You, ok. That's fair. That's fair. All right.
So, so I guess if he's outsourced it,
at least he doesn't have to be directly worried about GDPR.
Right.
Well,
and I would also assume that like the
kids writing letters and the parents writing letters,
you know,
um, there's again,
when he replies to you, is that like a ya
acceptance? Like is there fine print on that letter?
Oh, here's a great thing, Canada just passed some new cell phone laws.
Uh, and one of the laws requires and I'm not making this up,
it requires the contract to be readable
in that they can't use a font so small that
you can't read it because apparently that's a thing now
-- that, ok, uh, can it, can it be a phone book
-- though?
It can be a phone book but it has to be reading?
Ok.
Ok. I mean, that seems like I
was
like, you know, you could put a micro dot On the reply saying, you know,
by reading this letter, you accept the following terms, blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah.
Right?
I would be surprised if at least in the US,
if that would be legal because I know I've heard of court cases before where
something was written in a manner that was
essentially illegible and the courts threw it out because
they said even if you printed it with intent,
it's illegible.
So you can't possibly expect the other person to accept that.
Well, here's one question is how would you ever put Santa on trial?
-- Because basically everybody would have to recuse themselves.
-- That is true.
However, there are,
there are ways to try a person without a jury.
-- What
-- is here? Oh, no, I'm not.
But wouldn't the judge also have to recuse himself because
he's not going to get any more gifts from Santa
assuming he's not on the naughty list and never gets gifts from Santa.
Although then I guess you're on the naughty list.
You
want to render
a
not guilty verdict to get on the, the good list.
Would you though? I don't know.
Maybe letting him off is naughty. Anyway. Anyway. All right.
Uh, let's keep going because we're gonna be here all night.
Uh,
labor and employment offenses.
We've all seen
Futurama. Right.
Yes,
that's, that's the one I always think about is the Neptunian who are enslaved to.
Well, they're not making toys
anymore because now in Futurama, Santa only tries to kill people.
But when Bender becomes Santa,
they start the factory up again.
That ironically creates global warming which melts the ice.
Santa is frozen in and then he gets out. But
that, that's another story. Uh
No, I don't know. And that's kind of the question is,
are the elves at Saints workshop there by choice or are they indentured servants?
Well,
do elves fall under human law or are they like classed as an animal
in which case, like have at it? Just pack them 60,000 in a barn and
make them make toys like chickens make?
I would expect an elf to have a what? What is the status they trying to get monkeys?
A nonhuman person?
I think it's what they're calling it the animal rights people.
But I, I think you could easily make an argument
assuming elves can speak
and are conscious that they are nonhuman persons that deserve most of
the same rights and privileges a a person would have a human.
So, so then it kind of begs the question. Are they there on purpose?
And I feel like they must be because you would expect
in all of the years of all of the Santa,
everything that at least one elf would want to leave.
Uh,
yeah. Yeah. I mean, even the glorious people's, what is it?
the glorious People's Republic of North Korea has
people who want out for some reason.
Yes,
that's correct.
Yeah, I, I think, I don't know,
I would say however,
I would point out that there has never been
industrial action like a strike that has affected Christmas.
So we
logically pause it from that.
But since they've never gone on strike either, they're so terrified and, you know,
beaten that they're, they're well behaved or they're so happy,
they're well behaved.
So it's basically what I'm saying is, it's either one extreme.
There's no one in that.
No, I don't, I don't buy the happy argument because I think
even if
you can never have 100% happiness,
right? Some, somebody will want to leave eventually
a basket full of puppies.
I have not,
that's 100% happiness.
But, but they, they make toys,
they make toys for spoiled Children. Like that's not going to have 100% happiness.
Right? Like, let's face it. Right.
And, and it's clear that given, given the sample size, I've seen that,
that Santa's heuristics for determining naughty and I are
terrible and there's basically nobody on the naughty list,
right?
Like let's face it,
there are no naughty Children
at Christmas
and there should be, but there aren't.
So anyway, anyway,
uh,
so this actually ties in nicely with, with what's number six on the list of,
uh, it says intentional infliction of emotional distress.
Uh ie naughty Children who don't get the nice things
because they're apparently distraught over
misbehaving and not getting presents.
But
as as I just mentioned,
I would say the,
the naughtiest Children I know tend to get the most Christmas presents of anybody.
So
we're going to call BS on that one.
I think there's the veiled threat of no presents but
any reasonably intelligent child knows that's a load of crap
and they're going to get stuff no matter what.
That's basically true.
Yes.
Exactly. Exactly. Uh, what about antitrust violations?
-- Santa does kind of have a bit of a trust.
-- Well, he definitely, he's guilty of dumping,
like, straight up
guilty,
dumping of giving the stuff away below cost.
It's true.
I mean, that's,
that's a classic
-- monopolistic behavior. Right.
-- Right. That's right.
And so he's ruined his competition who does, who Santa's competition to
us?
Amazon
and they're going bankrupt
to
connect
the,
it's all there.
Ok. That's fair. And then tax evasion, which I guess
assumes he makes money.
Maybe he pulls like, uh,
your Hollywood movie style accounting where he actually loses money
every Christmas because he's selling his product below cost.
Well, but there's also the tax implications for the people receiving the gifts.
-- Uh
-- That's true.
Actually, how many people are claiming taxes on their Christmas gifts?
I bet nobody is and I bet a lot of people should be.
That's fair. So, so
Santa is creating a bunch of tax criminals.
Well,
he's definitely creating a bunch of tax
obligations that people should be dealing with.
Right.
I think with the trillions of free product he's pushing every year
that there'd be a,
-- uh, more taxes paid
-- well and also import
tariffs. I assume he doesn't pay them.
Right.
My, my assumption is in terms of dealing with customs and immigration,
he's just essentially an illegal immigrant for a short period
of time every year in every country on the planet
where he imports
way above the, the limit
of, you know, nontaxable goods and then he leaves them in country where they are not,
the, the taxes are not paid by the vast majority of recipients.
This is,
you know, you know, what's really funny is, is if this was actually happening.
Yeah, the governments would get this guy. Right.
Because of that reason right there.
Taxes,
uh, oh, bringing goods into Canada, uh, gifts worth Canadian $60 or less each.
And weirdly enough.
Silverware and antiques and jewelry and clothes, linens, books, furniture,
hobby tools and other hobby items, private collections of coin,
stamp and art appliances such as over refrigerator.
-- So, honestly, it looks kind of like he's legal in Canada.
-- Well, good job, Santa
well done. He does live very close to Canada.
Does Canada own
the North Pole,
like, like does the land extend all the way
-- he does?
-- And the under international?
Well, and that's kind of a sticking point between us and Russia.
Uh,
they would like to own it because of the, um,
uh,
yeah, basically the oil. Um, but yeah, under
territorial claim of the Arctic, I'm pretty sure we own it. I know Denmark
and Norway have some bogus claims as well.
-- Claims. But you're not, you're not biased.
-- No, not at all.
Well, I mean, they're danish, it's, they, they don't know any better.
Um,
but, uh, yeah, their claim fell through
and, uh, anyways, yeah, I'm pretty sure we should own it.
-- I think
-- that so, so theoretically, Santa isn't importing anything into Canada,
-- right.
-- But does he, I thought he existed in an extra dimensional space?
-- I
-- don't
-- know. I hope he
does. I
mean, the North pole is melting.
It is. It's true. He's going to have to live on
a,
yeah, I was gonna say, I hope his stuff floats.
It's going to change a lot of Christmas movies, isn't it?
Where, where now from going to the north pole on a sheet of ice?
You'll have people traveling there by boat to look
at what a pole sticking out of the water.
I don't, I don't know how that's gonna work.
-- Uh
-- Yeah, you can just drop a boy tether it to the bottom of the ocean.
How deep
-- it is there.
-- I bet it's
deep.
Yeah,
because there's also a
problem where, like the north pole doesn't move,
but the magnetic north pole wanders around.
It does. Yes.
And it's,
it's moving rather quickly these days if I recall
correctly where they're expecting it to flip over in,
like the next 1000 years
north will be south and south will be north.
That's going to be a problem.
Well,
maybe, I mean, it's going to happen slow. Right.
So my assumption is any sort of technology
that's not what the movie show.
Oh. Right.
Where the, well, well, there was also the movie where,
what the earth's core stopped spinning and they had
to shoot a rocket into the sun or something.
I have to restart it.
I know I'm being silly
but it's, they're all dumb. Right. It's,
are they,
I don't know,
there was some compelling
arguments.
Uh, anyway.
Right.
We're, we're out of stories and we're probably out of time.
But it's,
yeah. So I guess the, the moral of the story is
you have to be afraid of Santa. Right? There's something up with that dude.
Uh Yeah. No, there's clearly something ain't. Right.
-- Right. Beware Santas bearing gifts,
-- right. Yes. Is there another kind of Santa?
Well, I guess if you're naughty.
Well, it, every, that,
that's true because don't the Germans have the guy Rupert or what's his name?
-- Um, oh,
-- are you thinking of, um,
the
-- cus,
-- the guy who helps. What Crump is it Crump?
He's got a weird name.
Claus.
There's
center clause is just the Dutch. Santa isn't.
Actually
David Sedaris has a really funny story about that where I guess in, in, in Holland,
Santa is
accompanied by, like, 3 to 6
black men. It's,
I love how every culture has its own, like crazy Santa myth
and, and it's always just bizarre.
I love it.
It's fun. It's fun.
Oh, man.
All right. So anyway, any, any last thoughts, Kurt?
-- Well,
-- maybe leave something up for Krampus.
-- He looks like a fun guy
-- uh or leave beer out for Santa kids. If you're listening,
leave beer out for Santa, but don't
open it. He will. Thank you later. Yes, that's true.
You can't open the beer and preferably keep it on ice
that way. It's nice and cold when he gets there.
Uh Santa will thank you later.
All right. All right. Thanks, Kurt. Thank you everybody for listening.
You can hit up open
source security podcast.com for the show notes and there are
many in this one as well as the picture,
the,
the wanted poster picture of Santa Claus from Texas.
And you can
find our links to hit us up on Twitter with the Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag join our Facebook group, all the fun stuff.
-- And yeah, if nothing else, Kurt, you have a fantastic rest of your day?
-- Yeah.
I hope everybody have fun getting ready for Christmas.