Hello and welcome to episode 103 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Pressers.
So now that we have more than 100 episodes,
you keep saying like 103 and for some reason in my brain,
I want you to say 103 and I can't explain it and there's no good reason for it either.
It's just, I, I don't know.
-- It's one of those things
-- I noticed myself the other day,
somebody asked me my birthday and I gave it to them in month, day, year form,
which I despise
don't do that. That's like the worst,
it's the worst date format ever.
Yeah.
But like as a human, it makes sense, right?
Because typically the year is well now, so like,
you know,
may 5th or, you know, June 12th, right? Like that's
the 12th of June, right?
I don't know. I just, June 12th seems to like kind of
-- locate my brain faster
-- one would think. So.
So looks like Microsoft actually came up with a useful paper on IOT security.
Yeah, you sent that to me. That's really cool. Actually, what they've done.
So, why, why don't you give us the, like,
nickel tour and then it'll be in the show notes?
Of course, for anyone interested.
Yeah.
So Microsoft has released a PDF, uh,
called the Seven Properties of highly secured devices.
And, uh, one thing that actually just as a side note,
you know, I was thinking about iot but I'm also, you know,
like phones and everything, like we are carrying,
like everybody's carrying a computer around with them now that
you probably want to be secure, right?
And so this list actually applies to not just IOT but well, devices in general,
right?
Like computers or phone, whatever.
And so there's, there's seven properties that they give
some of which are pretty obvious and some of which are,
I think a little bit more subtle and
I actually wrote out a list of questions I kind of have as a result of these. Um,
but uh do we just want to start from the start at the top of the list?
So, you know what's funny is you're,
you're talking about IOT and I know they even call out IOT.
But when I read this list, the first thing I thought of was my phone.
Yeah,
not IOT.
So, but yes, we should read the list.
Uh I'll let you have the honors and then we'll comment from there.
The first one is actually, I think the biggest one and that is having
a hardware-based root of trust. So uh what they say is unforget
gray
keys generated and protected by hardware
physical countermeasures, resist side channel attacks.
Does this device have a unique un forge
identity that is inseparable from the hardware?
And that really got me thinking about iot in the sense of,
you know, let's say you have some IOT device
in theory, you know, like what happens if I like de
solder or you know,
I basically swap out the board that has the identity
of the device and put it in my device.
Now my device is your device and I have access to your stuff
or whatever that's doing, right?
In theory.
Well, I watched this documentary on car stripping, right?
And so the deal is when you steal a car, it's got a VIN number.
So you can't just like sell it on because the VIN number will show up as stolen, right?
But the VIN number is attached to essentially to like the chassis
in the car, right?
So what they do is they take, they steal a car
that they basically have like a broken or whatever chassis for.
They take that broken chassis, strip it down,
they take the stolen car and they basically like
strip the stolen car and put it back onto whatever damaged
chassis or whatever they have with a legit vin number.
So they basically severed like
and they showed it and these guys did
it over literally overnight with a pickup truck,
like they went out and stole a pickup truck at like seven o'clock.
It was one of those, it was Vice or something like that. Right? And
so they literally went out and stole like this $50,000 pickup truck.
And by like, you know, six in the morning
here is a chassis.
We bought it a junkyard, a salvage, you know, with a legit uns stolen VIN number
and hey, presto, new new truck,
that's crazy.
And it blew my mind that they could do it this quickly.
But it also, it really drove home. Like that's the thing with like
we just bought a new fridge
and we bought a dumb fridge.
I'm happy to say, but let's say for the sake of argument,
we didn't buy a dumb fridge and we bought a smart fridge.
Well, where,
where is the identity of that fridge?
And I'm assuming it would be like on a little daughter board that would, you know,
be easily plug and play out of the device.
So now does you know,
like does the rest of the fridge have to authenticate to
that daughter bar to prove that it hasn't been swapped out?
Like, you know, a
great example of this is
Apple phones with the screens, right?
That this, you know, they,
they discovered that you can make screens and
stuff that can like snarled up your passwords.
And so now Apple is making it much harder for third party, you know, swaps and, um,
hardware to take place because they're actually adding apparently
like cryptographic authentication to various kind of hardware chunks.
Wait,
you're saying you can get like a third party screen that essentially steals II,
I assume like that the taps you put on the passcode.
Interesting.
Well, uh not just that,
but because it can talk to the rest of the hardware at such an interesting level.
Right. Right. Right. That totally makes sense. Right.
So, so hardware based root of trust,
I, I dig this and I think it's important and
the thing that makes me really happy about the,
the devices we carry around now is this is kind of a thing for the most part,
right? You've got your SIM card obviously can be part of this story.
But also the phones themselves now have
security crow processors and security enclaves.
And I mean, I remember back in the day like T PM was the promise, right?
-- T PM was terrible
-- to work.
And it
part of the problem I found with T PM is the hardware guys are like, great.
We did this thing. It works
and, and all the software guys are like, oh, right, we need software for that.
-- Yeah, we didn't
-- do that.
It, it was so hard to use
well. And, but the thing is, it's happening now, like I know in um
in the Linux ecosystem and some other ecosystems there are,
there is stuff to use the T PM
to do key generation and secure key distribution.
So that for example,
you can have uh storage attached to a device that only works on that device,
right? Because the, the motherboard has the T PM with the decryption keys.
And then there was also an extension of that for network stuff. So
you plug your server into the network and
your server essentially can access the storage,
you know, and that's it.
Like even an attacker that could get another server in there can't do it. So
it's happening. But I mean, it's, it's a classic thing of, yeah, like
the the hardware existed. But
yeah, using it, I mean, oh, crypto is hard.
Yeah, it was, it was too hard to use and that's exactly it.
Whereas the phones just work, you know, tm
uh And we should actually this is also related to the next
next point in this list which I will let you read.
Yeah. So having a small trusted computing base.
So private keys are stored in a hardware protected vault,
inaccessible to software division of software into self protecting layers.
So the question is, is the, is most of the device's software outside the devices,
trusted computing base, right?
And again, we've had that in theory forever, right? Intel ring 0123.
And yeah, what happened? Well, the kernel ran in ring zero
and the Linux kernel last I checked is quite humongous.
Well, in, I think this is, this is more than that, right?
This is closer to the security enclave
concept we're talking about.
Well, that's what I'm saying.
We had sort of this, the idea of this forever and it was just
not well done and poorly used and yet we're finally starting to get there where
like my understanding is, you know, the Apple phones, for example, like,
yeah, that security enclave processor has
the actual encryption keys to decrypt the flash memory and, and
you know, that's what you're talking to when you're decrypting the, you know,
when you're putting your pin in the phone or your
uh what is it facetime or whatever your fingerprint stuff,
it's like bypassing
pretty much the rest of the phone as I understand it.
Right. Right.
Well, even the Intel chips are,
are gaining this ability today where you have the ability
to run in kind of an enclave in chip,
which is, I mean, debatably useful.
I won't get into that, but
it's this one I'm also seeing popping up everywhere, which is very exciting.
-- Well,
-- it reminds me of how we've traditionally sort of done security,
especially on servers for a lot of people in the cloud, it boils down to,
they have physical hardware upon which they run a very,
very minimal operating system
that runs virtual machines
hopefully securely and well as we learned from
Intel Specter even that doesn't always work.
And
like Amazon had to patch and reboot their fee. Right.
But essentially, you know what the, like, for example,
what all the major cloud providers do is
just have like an absolute minimal VM hosting infrastructure. Right?
Because we've had 20 years of beating up on V MS virtual machines and they're,
they're pretty secure,
you know, they're, they're pretty hard to break out of,
not impossible but, you know, like the venom and all the other.
Like if you just Google Zen CV E like,
yeah, I mean, it's not perfect. But
yeah, it's a hell of a lot closer than say, like having an, you know,
the entire Linux kernel is your attack surface.
So, you know, I like this idea of, kind of, yeah,
you have that small trusted sort of compute base,
you know, which kind of has minimal capabilities
and then inside of that inside of a VM or a container or whatever, you know, you run
the actual complicated workload that's doing weird stuff
which, which actually builds on the next point. Then it's, it's,
it's clever, these things they're all related. Right. Imagine that.
Yeah. Well, it's also part of it I think is you can't build on sand, right?
Like you, you know, when you build a house in, well, a lot of the world you,
you start with a foundation or
at a minimum, like you drop a concrete slab on the ground.
So you have, you know, something flat to sit on
that probably won't move too much but anyways, yeah, so
the third one is defense in depth, right,
multiple mitigations applied against each threat, countermeasures,
mitigate the consequence of a successful attack on any one vector.
You know, is the device still protected if the security of one layer of device so
is breached. And a great example of this actually is the chrome web browser, right?
Yes, it is. If you pay attention to the the the results of the P
to own uh which is a contest run at Cans
West, I want to say by Dragos,
you know, they've been, he's been doing this for like I think about a decade now.
Anyways,
the attacks against
the good web browsers like Chrome are now like
uh what wasn't the the one like 16 stages?
-- Oh It was insane. I know it, it was unbelievable. Yeah.
-- And, and it, and it,
it was, I mean, so for one thing, Chrome has gotten to the point now, yeah,
where to actually go from like
zero to exploit in Chrome requires like over a dozen
attacks and steps, right?
Because yeah, you can totally break this one little thing.
And now you're, you're still in a locked room,
you know, now you got to break into the safe, OK? You got the safe open.
Now there's a locked case,
OK? You get the case open and it's full of bees.
Chrome is really aggressive about breaking these attack paths,
you know, and hardening, right? Because
oh the other day, it was so funny. I was
somebody submitted a CV U request and as part of the CV request,
they actually included an example of the exploit.
It was a cross site scripting exploit.
And I'm like, oh, that's cute. I, you know, I wonder if it actually works.
So I cut and pasted it into chrome
and I get the sad little dinosaur saying, you know, oh,
it looks like you've basically tried to shoot yourself in the foot with an XSS.
I'm not going to load that page for you. Sorry.
Oh, nice. Right.
Like it and I was like, oh,
like chrome basically looked at the get request and you know,
the the the XSS string was in the get request.
So it's like even for a human, you look at this and you're like,
oh that's clearly an ex ss attack
and it was like, and chrome was like, nope,
I'm just not going to allow this to happen
because something bad will probably happen if I do.
And I was like, awesome.
And,
and you know what I'm going to call out here too
is this is a place I think security has failed historically
is we obsess over the perfect solution
and we'll say things like, oh if, if we do this, we we miss this obscure corner case.
So let's let's do it right. It's like, no, just, just do this
and then do some other things. And when you put them all together.
It's awesome.
I get the fear is you do like a 90% solution and,
and then your manager is like good enough, we're done and you move on.
Well. Right. Don't do that either.
But uh well, even that a 90% solution is better than nothing.
And that's true. Right.
So then the fourth one is again building on this compartmentalization, right?
Hardware enforced barriers between software components prevent a
breach in one from propagating to others.
So, you know,
does a failure in one component of the device require
a reboot of the entire device to return to operation?
And that, that is something that really got me thinking that question
number one,
how do you find like a fail safe mode?
Like we were discussing this and for a car you pull
over to the side of the road that's pretty safe usually.
But in a plane generally
maybe, you know, with the plane of the less options,
but like what's a fail safe mode for an oil refinery,
I think burst into flames
and, and you know, and especially with IOT stuff like
how do I reboot a light bulb
well,
or does it just reboot every time I turn it off and
turn it on or does it have a built in battery?
I honestly don't know.
It's a good question. I I can't answer that either.
You know, I would assume because, you know, part of it is I know, you can get
to boot real fast.
But at the same time when I turn a light bulb bomb, I want it to turn on, like now,
like right now now.
So, yeah, this whole hardware enforced barriers between software components
and this really again, going, for example, to android, you know, where they,
they've split out the audio system
and they've split out the video system and they've,
they've essentially kind of chunked apart the operating system
along sort of hardware lines because,
you know, when you have a web page talking to your sound system, well, you know,
on a traditional PC, that means the sound system is like, you know,
it's running with a high degree of privilege,
-- you know, because it's hardware,
-- I don't feel like that's being done in hardware
in, in many cases.
Well, it's not done in hardware yet, but it's,
it's getting there right with them chunking it apart in software at least,
and having these major subsystems so you can do permissions.
And I assume then the next step is to start, you know, actually having like,
say the sound system, talk to the rest of the system through a more well defined
kind of gateway rather than like, oh, you know, direct memory access. Go nuts,
right? Because that's, you know, that's a classic case of D MA, right?
Um With the older Macbook
with the firewire, sorry.
So firewire was amazing and fast because it had D MA direct memory access.
But what this meant is if you had access to the firewire port on any Mac,
you could just suck down the entire contents of memory,
like
in a minute.
Right.
Right. With no authentication or anything,
you know,
and, and we've seen the same thing with USB. Right.
A lot of USB stuff turns out to have pretty low
level access in the chips and you can subvert them and do bad things
and,
and so I think that's something that has to happen
because these things have to have ports and I can't
physically secure them necessarily.
Like I'm gonna put like a USB port on something the size of,
you know, a pack of cigarettes.
Well, bad example, people don't know what that is anymore.
I'm going to put a USB port on something the size of like
an SSD and like what a giant physical lock on it.
Well, not only that, something that came up,
I was joking around with somebody the other day about gluing USB ports
and it occurred to me on, I
charge my laptop then. Right on my Macbook. My USB port is my charger.
Like I can't glue that shut. Right.
-- I
-- should.
Right.
Just one a day.
Apple,
totally economical.
Yeah. No, that's, and that's a great example. Right. Like, yeah, it's,
yeah, you just, you can't do that.
Yeah, I don't know. Anyway.
So the, the, the fifth one is certificate based authentic
authentication.
So, science certificate proven by un forge
cryptographic key
proves the device identity and authenticity.
Uh So does this device use certificates instead of passwords for authentication?
And clearly
that has to happen pretty much globally. And that's actually something
I'll actually be working on with the working group with the cloud security lines.
Is this whole keys in the cloud thing,
right? We have to have encryption keys in the cloud.
Well, how do we do that securely? How do we back them up? How do we distribute them?
How do we destroy them?
And then you want to talk about, for example,
a uh like a small IOT device that needs
to connect to the mothership to report data like um
a temperature sensor or a thermostat or whatever. Right.
Again, I don't want, you know, somebody monkeying with that.
And so how do we do that? Well, it's going to have to be certificates
and more to the point, you know,
can that certificate be extracted from that device?
I hope not,
you know. So that means it can't just be on the little storage flash chip.
It has to be like in a security enclave.
The, you know,
basically you're gonna have to like scale that chip
down in a lab and do all the shenanigans,
you know, to get that certificate and even then it should be a pain in the butt.
Well, and, and look, I mean,
so what you're talking about is the end state, I think.
But I mean, we're not even at a point where certificate
communication is common.
It's, it's getting there, there's, for example, go,
um, some of the providers are using it internally and it's
with software defined perimeter.
It's, that's one of the keystones of the software defined.
Right.
So we're getting there
for that
and I'm seeing this actually become more and
more of a question where people are essentially saying
we read the Google beyond court paper
and we want to implement that for.
And there's usually, I think two main reasons for wanting to implement that.
Number one, they've realized they can't secure their infrastructure,
they just can't, who knew. And
secondly, then I think a lot of them realize, wait a minute,
if we build a system that can run securely on insecure infrastructure,
we can just dump the sucker into the cloud, be done with it.
That's right. You can.
-- So it's starting to happen. Now, the tooling is just not there.
-- It's, it's terrible.
I'm I suffer through this on a daily basis
where I'm trying to deal with certificates and it's,
I mean, let's encrypt has made,
it's so bad,
so
-- bad
-- and even the good tools still are,
-- there are no good tools.
-- Well, I'm saying
the tools that are good in our by current standards are
when let me put it this way,
could you know, a new
team member, get up and running with it? The answer is Absolutely. No.
No, it's, it's, it's so complicated.
Right. They, they would for sure do it wrong.
Even the tools that are out there get so much wrong and it's, it's just
-- the certificates and keys are so hard.
-- I know Windows with active directory
service. What's a, a active directory server
is starting to do that, like generating client certificates securely, you know,
doing the bit locker, securely sharing the bit locker decryption, you know,
master decryption key with the, the servers securely.
So it's getting there. But
what I'm kind of noticing is the only people getting this right are doing like, very,
very kind of closed inclusive systems that like they control,
we don't have it.
And so, yeah,
when you talk about certificates doing it within a system is hard enough.
But
if you want to do it have system A
talk to system B where they're totally different then,
I mean, just abandon all hope.
That's it.
Yeah, pretty much, you know, it's, it's messed up still. Yeah.
But I mean, it's gonna have to happen,
right. I mean,
actually on a side note, uh, uh, Firefox and I forget what the other thing was.
They're going to start using the, uh, the, the, um, have I been pawned, uh,
password database when you, like, enter
password? They
yell at you? Yeah. One password. Yeah, that was it.
So, no, that's awesome.
Well,
especially because that basically takes away like the
500 billion easy passwords that were to remember,
you know, and they're all gone now.
So
I don't know.
Um, so point number six kind of feeds into this is renewable security, right?
Renewal brings the device forward to a secure state and
revokes compromised assets for known vulnerabilities of security breaches.
So is the devices software updated automatically?
So, I mean, this is a perfect example where
um you have a device
with a known security flaw
and there's a patch,
how do
you, you know, get that patch installed? So that, that security flaw goes away
and how do you make sure that that patch stays put?
Right. And then I was also thinking again, like,
you know, it's, it's sure on a laptop, whatever. It's like, oh, there's an update.
Do you want to do it now or later or tonight or whatever?
And I'm like, ah, go away, bug me tonight. But, like, for a pacemaker,
like, there's pacemakers out there with Wi Fi, um,
there's the whole ST jude medical device debacle.
You know where
we found a volt it? No, you didn't. Yes, we did. No, you didn't. Yes, we did.
I'm,
I'm gonna stop you because medical devices are going to
-- be special because they're going to be regulated
-- by the,
about your car,
your plane. And,
well, so a car and a plane are also going to be regulated. But now
you talk about a phone
who is? Right. Right. Exactly.
Perfect light bulbs who is regulating the light bulbs.
Right. What about a light bulb?
Because when I turn my light bulb on, I don't want it to be, like,
not working because it's running an update.
You're getting very animated. It's a light bulb.
You're, you're absolutely right though.
Who is going to make a light bulb manufacturer update itself? And I have a suspicion.
The answer is nobody.
This, this comes back to your, your question on Twitter the other day about
why don't dryer vents just have a little sensor in
them that knows when there's a clog in the,
the exhaust.
And, and this is going to be the same deal at light bulbs.
It's because number one,
the manufacturers don't want to spend an extra $1 on this piece of hardware.
And then there's also the issue of if I have a dryer that
has a sensor on it and it still burns down my house.
Now, I'm going to sue the company for screwing up the sensor, right.
Whereas before it was my fault.
And so we're probably going to see some degree of that.
But most importantly, it's just the fact that
if you walk into Costco
and there's one light bulb is $10.01 light bulb is $1.
And the only difference is one has better security. Which one are you going to buy?
Probably the cheap one because
of course, security is a
-- relative term still, you
-- know, of course, you are. Right.
We're all going to buy the cheap one. Right.
-- And that's just the fact of life.
-- And this is,
you're, you know, one of those, uh,
my favorite story this week is that the US government is having a
hard time sourcing security cameras that don't have chips made in China.
Right.
Like, that's,
you know,
and so, especially for security cameras where they're worried, like, because,
you know, security cameras, like, even the cheap ones,
not like I have a really cheap $200 Chinese security system that included
a camera for 70 bucks that has pen and tilt microphone
and a speaker in it.
You should give me the URL and I'll put it in the shop.
It's called Skylink
net.
-- Yeah. Can't make that name up.
-- I
-- was like,
-- no, I mean,
-- give me, give me the UR
-- I don't know,
there's an app
and here's the best part,
there's an app that connects to the mothership
that then my video just magically works.
-- I bet that's super secure.
-- No, it's not. Of course not.
But,
but the point is too is that this camera is
good enough that you could probably read lips with it.
You know,
that's the thing to remember it is these even
-- cheap cameras now or a couple megapixels
-- right?
Here's what I want you to do. I want you to go buy a reloadable credit card.
Like one of those one use only. I want you to hold it up to the camera
and then, like, put like $5 on it,
never use it and see if it ever gets stolen.
I'm,
I'm totally serious. You should totally do that.
Like, that's, that's like a def con talk man,
assuming it gets stolen.
But yeah, going back to renewable security. The other big question I have
from a hardware runner's point of view.
You have to update 10 billion light bulbs with the security patch.
How do you make sure you don't break even a millionth of a percent of them?
You just don't care, don't do it and problem solved. Yeah,
like, like I'm, I'm totally serious when I say that, which is unfortunate.
Well, and see, that's what really drives me is, is, you know,
when you do an update of some device
and a human being doesn't kind of keep an eye on it.
Like, because the other day, it's funny. I actually
was in the basement and I moved a pile of boxes backwards.
Thought nothing of it went upstairs, went to sleep, woke up in the morning,
went back to the downstairs fridge to grab a pop or whatever.
And the light doesn't work. And I'm like, oh, bloody heck, the light burnt out.
And then I'm like, wait, this fridge has more than one light.
They all burned out at the same time. Huh? That seems improbable.
And then I'm like, all right, the power bar for the fridge.
Where's that?
Oh, it's buying these boxes and I, you know,
shove the boxes back and they'd hit the switch and turned it off and,
and did you have like, anything in the fridge?
That? No, because modern fridges are so sealed up that like it was still cold inside.
Right.
But the point is like,
that was a minor thing of where I just shoved a pile of boxes back and broke my fridge.
But,
you know, if I'm, if someone's installing a software update in my fridge,
like you want to baby it to make sure it doesn't die.
So, you know, is my fridge gonna start pinging me?
Like when I open it like, hey, you have an update to install and I'm gonna,
I'm gonna do it right now, like, you know,
hold on and put the milk somewhere safe if this doesn't work.
And there's a ton of IOT devices that are not going to be easily accessible, right?
There's um I was reading a project about they were talking about, you know,
building Linux
devices that will be literally buried somewhere or at the
bottom of the ocean for 50 to 100 years,
you know, pipeline stuff or communications,
right? And it's like, yeah,
I read that, you know, a great one is like the, well,
apart from the Hubble space telescope,
if your satellite breaks, you can't go fix it,
right?
-- Uh
-- No, but, but these systems have so like NASA is
maybe a good or bad example, I can't tell, but we didn't know what the,
one of the Mars Rovers had a file system problem, remember?
But they, they also had like a fail safe mode built into it.
So they basically re uploaded an operating system on
the fly in the fail-safe mode on another planet.
Which again,
a $1 iot light bulb is probably not. The
thing is
the good
news is we've already got that functionality in most motherboards, right.
Most modern motherboards have the dual bios thing where they have like essentially
two.
As I understand it,
either two flash chips or one bigger flash chip that holds two copies of the,
the uh the bios.
And when you update it, it updates one,
you reboot to it. Hopefully it works.
And if it doesn't work, there's like a lower level fail safe.
That will be like let you flip back to the known good one
and the good news is storage is cheap now. So that actually I think is a reasonable
approach to this across most devices the cost.
But here's the problem across those devices that cost more than a few dollars.
And that's again the
great and, and here's,
here's what I'm going to say about this list
is
everything up to this point
I think is doable without breaking the bank.
And if you stopped before here,
I think you would have,
you'd be 90%
you'd be, you'd be at the far, far end of the bell curve way up in the clouds,
even if you can't install security updates.
If you,
if your communications is relatively secured
and you're communicating with a known trusted
source and you have hardware-based root of trust and all this other stuff.
I think this one becomes less important and I think that's going to be the
future is rather than focus on updates for things like a $1 iot light bulb
you focus on just making sure the communications is so secure that even though
this thing can be a steaming pile of garbage from a security perspective,
it won't matter because nobody can get to it.
And that's just the way it's going to have to be,
I suspect because we have sucked at security updates forever
and I don't see us getting better anytime soon.
Well, and more to the point if somebody can physically attack the device and, like,
start
deering chips and analyzing them, they'll just, like,
-- dump a cup of water in it.
-- You've lost.
Right. It, it's like the old, the old analogy we use around denial of service.
You know, if, if I hit my computer with a hammer, I've caused a denial of service.
It's like, yes, but that's not a security issue. You're just an idiot. Right.
So that, yeah, number seven is a doozy and this is, this is like,
people who get here are going to be pretty amazing.
It's
failure report.
-- And really,
-- I would have switched seven and eight because I think the last one
is something we can do with
or six and seven, either 123457, I can't count
six and 77 is I think more important than six.
Well, no, to me,
explain it please to the audience before we continue this conversation.
Number seven is failure reporting a software failure such
as a buffer overrun induced by an attacker,
probing security is reported to cloud based failure analysis system.
So does this device report failure to its manufacturer?
So I just before we get into that,
I would say number six is more important than number seven
because number seven doesn't matter if you can't actually get an update
-- installed properly.
-- Not, not entirely.
So
number seven is super important, I think because yeah,
like are people attacking us?
How are they attacking us? What is the attack? Ok.
You know, a great example of this being is what about every I'm going to say
quarter?
It feels like there's a Adobe zero day,
an Adobe flash zero date in the wild
about what quarterly, every twice a year or something like that,
you know,
and and essentially the way from what I can tell the way
it usually kind of happens is a bunch of people get popped
their A V reports back to the A V mothership.
Hey, you know, this computer is now running a crypto miner something went wonky.
You know, they do a bit of analysis.
Oh, they're all running this version of flash or older then? Ok.
You know, go grab the content, look at it. Oh, boom. We got another zero day flash.
Go tell Adobe
they fix it and it just a couple of times a year. That's how that works.
And that needs to be automated and fast.
Yes. Yes, it does.
But when you're dealing with things that have something like,
say a hardware based root of trust and certificates and,
and proper segmentation of resources,
now we've reached a point where and this isn't even important just for security.
It's the fact that when we know the device is misbehaving in some way,
we can tell someone something is going wrong.
And I would, I would say that is far more doable than secure updates, right?
I'm not, I'm not saying it's less important or more important.
I'm just saying in, in the context of something we can accomplish,
we can accomplish this.
-- We can't accomplish consistent security updates.
-- The secure updates thing has
largely been,
how do I put, I don't want to say theoretically solved, but it's,
it's actually been like there's the tour updater, you know,
uh tough the Tor
update framework, right? Which go read the paper.
Uh it,
they, they went into like all the failure modes and address them, right?
Um
And there's some
modes you can't address, like say a freeze attack So if you have an IOT device.
Oh, a perfect example.
All the water meters in Edmonton here have been replaced by wireless ones so that,
you know, they can read your water meter wirelessly.
Right. Saves money.
And I'm assuming if I wrap it in enough tinfoil they can't read it.
And also thus by extension, it, you know,
wouldn't be able to get software updates assuming it does.
Which, well, I think we all know it doesn't. So certain types of attacks
against
updating software will always be possible, right?
-- You just wrap the device in enough tinfoil. Ok. No,
-- no, no, no,
no. II, I think we're talking about two different things.
A malicious attacker will always be able to prevent software updates.
I'm willing to say that right.
I'm not talking about malicious Attackers.
I'm just talking about the fact that when you install updates of any sort,
some percentage of devices will be bricked,
right? That is the, the honest rea not potentially guaranteed it happens. Right?
And so when you have a fleet of a trillion iot light bulbs,
if even a fraction of a fraction of a percent of them gets bricked,
that's real money.
-- So you're just never gonna do it,
-- but that's already uh you know,
light bulbs used to burn out all the time.
Remember?
And people were ok with that, like our fridge, our fridge just stopped making cold.
It still makes cold but not enough cold to freeze the freezer
and not enough cold to keep the milk cold,
except if that happens a week after you buy it,
they're going to have to give you a new one.
Right. There are certain consumer protections here that, that kick in
the rules are different for a lot of this stuff.
Right. And same thing with a $1 light bulb. Even though it costs a dollar,
-- you can't just say, oh, ha, ha, sorry. It's two hours old, tough
-- luck.
But something to keep in mind is there's certain types
of devices that where the consumer will demand updates.
So, medical devices, for example, you know, pla
-- software. No,
-- you can't talk about medical devices.
You talk about fridges and light bulbs. That's what we're talking about.
Stop going back to the things that matter.
Well, and we've already done this with cars, right.
-- We've already seen this with cars where people have had
-- cars are regulated.
You can't talk about cars, light bulbs and refrigerators.
That's all you get to talk about here.
Well, what's interesting is I know in Europe there's some, you know,
much stronger consumer protection laws where you can, like,
return stuff after I think, what is it?
One or two or up to one or two years.
And so Apple especially was,
it's a couple of years.
Um, but
yeah,
so, no, I think this list of seven things is actually
largely correct. And yeah, like if anybody were ever to actually achieve this list.
I
would be in awe of them.
It'd be great. I agree.
So, like the other problem is, well, just,
we already have that with S Os Report and other things in Linux.
But the problem I see is there's just so many false positives and,
and that's part of the
chin.
So, and that's something to keep in mind with, with some of these um,
security measures
is you have to implement it in a way where dealing with it is still economical and,
and that makes it even harder.
Yep. Yep. Definitely,
definitely,
we'll figure it out.
Let's just use A I in the Blockchain and that, that should take care of it. Right.
Problem solved.
Sweet. All right. Well, thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com to hit up the show notes.
You can use the Pound Os S podcast hashtag to
hit us up on social media and if nothing else,
Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks. Thanks everybody. Bye bye.