December 12th. This topic, I'm so excited about video game hacking.
-- How exciting, you
-- know, I like video game hacking,
especially the older school stuff because
they're generally not multiplayer games.
So it doesn't harm and stress and like make the experience for other people suck.
-- I mean,
-- OK, so let me, let me clarify when I'm talking about video game hacking.
I'm specifically in this context,
I'm talking about like the speed runners who they trigger these ridiculous bugs
cause crazy things to happen in a game.
And I will put a link in the show notes to an amazing bug in Super Mario world where
they basically place enemies on the screen in certain
places and they do certain actions and they're by,
by doing those things,
they're writing machine code into memory and then they cause an exploit to start
running their machine code to warp them to the end of the game,
which is, it's so amazing to see what they've done.
But the thing I keep thinking of is
when we love to talk about security and hacking and everything going on,
I would say probably 20 plus years ago,
there was some really cool research and amazing things.
But I would say today,
if you want to see where the most amazing research happening is it is
happening by speed runners in the world
of exploit development and abusing computer systems.
And what's always been interesting to me is
that the consoles had some of the most amazingly
and strong and time tested
copyright protection schemes, you know,
and some of them worked for over a decade or two before they were finally cracked.
I mean,
which is kind of amazing, you know,
there was a variety of explanations for that and there's tons of
videos on youtube about the copy protection and I'm not even talking about
that kind of hacking because that's,
I would say that's its own branch of like video game cracking and
dumping ROMs and running ROMs and all that kind of stuff.
And that's a whole another ball of wax and it's amazing.
But I just, I love watching speed runners.
I love watching how these people are getting arbitrary code execution in games.
And what's really funny is when I started watching
a lot of these people doing these speed runs
and kind of developing the routes they to take
and how they're going to go fast and stuff,
they have their own lingo.
And I feel like the terms they're using are starting to line up
with the words we use in security where we're talking about buffer overflows,
we're talking about arbitrary code execution and we're talking about, you know,
corrupting memory and it's,
it's so much fun and I absolutely love watching the work they're doing.
-- It's so cool.
-- Yeah.
No, I'm just looking at this list of, like, lingo and it's, it's, yeah,
it's, it's interesting. Right.
You know what it really reminds me of is sort of the, the,
the penetration testing of complex systems where, you know,
you got to get through multiple systems
and my favorite always being, you know, where
the pen tester just ignores something. And like,
it's like, yeah, we don't care about the mail server.
We'll just go for the backend database
and, and, but the security people are like, but you can't do that.
You have to, you have to go through the mail server and the attacker is like, no,
we don't.
Right.
-- Hold my
-- beer. My version of reality works for me. Sorry.
Or my favorite too is when, when you're pen testing and people are like, oh,
that servers off limits.
It's like,
right.
OK.
Yeah. Or my all time favorite was, but why would an attacker do that? Yeah.
Oh, I know. I know. But anyway, it works.
So in the speed running world though,
like in all seriousness when they're doing their
runs and trying to get their world records,
they will create rules where they'll say like in this run,
you can't use arbitrary code execution, you know,
you have to play the game like this or you
use these bugs, but you can use these bugs and so they create all these categories,
which is really cool because obviously like a great example is if
you look at a game like Super Mario World where they can,
I think the world record now is like a minute and a half or something.
It's ridiculous. It's,
-- well, it's arbitrary code execution. Right?
-- Oh, ok.
Yeah, cause I'm like, I don't even care what sequence of war pipes you use.
That seems awful fast.
It's completely ridiculous. Right?
But there's, and so obviously that run is fun to watch once, but it's never fun again.
And so by having different categories,
-- you can have like a human actually plays the game,
-- you know what?
That's a good point.
Yeah, because like, yeah, watching somebody exploit a buffer overflow.
-- Yeah, you watch it once and it's
-- like, right, I've seen this.
Yeah.
But um but then you watch the guy doing like
the bullet hopping in that one scene in Super Mario
where he gets like a perfect score, you know, with the,
the wooden battleship thing shooting the giant bullets
and he's like hopping around them like crazy and the
screen is basically full of bullets and it's just like,
wow, it's, you know, it's like watching a gymnast but it's a video game.
-- Well
-- then they practice and the tass is, are really good
tool, assisted speed run where a bot plays the game.
But anyway, anyway, I guess we're basically out of time.
But I would say the moral of the story here for everyone
is if you want to see some truly amazing security research,
go look at the speed runners and see what they're doing
to these games because it is fascinating and it's entertaining and
you'll probably get some new ideas. So, totally check it out.
Yep. Thanks everybody.