Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 178 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
-- Josh Pressers.
-- Well, welcome to actually 2020 this episode. So
-- yay, for us, we made it, the world hasn't ended yet
-- or it has.
-- And this is a simulation could be,
-- I mean, either way, whatever, it's fine.
But if it's a simulation, that means there's no real consequences.
I'm ok
with that.
Like this is, this is obviously someone let their,
their demented little brother play with the simulation.
Nothing makes sense.
-- Anyway.
-- Oh God. Like, can you imagine?
I mean, literally.
So it's, it's, we're recording this on Tuesday, January the seventh
and like literally the first
four days of the year. We just like,
like what?
-- Right.
-- Exactly. I feel like the day before was like, hold my beer
and it just got worse. It's
right.
Anyway,
I
did that linear extrapolation and we should all be dead by tomorrow.
Maybe, maybe this podcast will never be aired. Let's hope it does. But anyway, so
let's, let's talk about some friendlier things.
I've got,
I've got kind of two topics in mind and
I'll just spill the beans right away because I think
they're both really interesting and we'll do our best to
make sure we don't rat hole at either one.
But
I've noticed there's
a conversation happening on Twitter right now where people are basically saying,
do I need CV E I DS?
Like on my resume
to be?
No, I'm going to disagree with you there. It's,
there's a bunch of conversations going on
on Twitter that are an exact representation of
generally speaking. People don't know what CV is or what
for. So there's a bunch of conversations, like, do I need to get CV S?
Should I have gotten CV S? Do I have to publish them? Do I want them on my resume?
Do they matter?
Should we all burn them in a fire?
Is Kurt a bad person for having assigned 6000 of them? The answer
is yes,
but there's other reasons to. But
anyway,
that's
like,
no offense.
This is like watching people discuss
Blockchain and Cryptocurrency where it's like
you're all wrong.
But it's less funny because watching the Blockchain people argue is
one of the highlights of my week when I pull up
one of the various Blockchain forums and read the comments.
But anyway, so there's that.
And then the other topic
is
the telemarketing company that went out of business because of ransomware.
And I think there's,
ah, there's so much gold in this story. I, I can't even start.
So anyway, let's start with C
and you just rattled off
like 1000 things and let's,
let's keep it kind of narrow because I don't want to get in.
Here's the first question, what is CV? And the answer is most people don't know.
-- Look,
-- we have like 30 episodes talking about that point.
Let's assume if you're listening to us right now and you don't know what CV E is.
-- Search our back catalog and listen to one of the episodes.
-- It's like Blockchain.
There's the people that don't know what it is
and then there's the people that know a little bit about it,
but think and think they understand it.
So fundamentally
CV, common vulnerabilities and exposures, it's a barcode for
common vulnerabilities and exposures in software and as the future moves on there,
uh it's, they're looking at adding services
as well like cloud services,
but fundamentally that's it. It's a bar.
So like back in the day when there was like a new send mail vulnerability,
remember like eight little green men and whatnot, you know,
there's a new remote exploit and send mail about what, every two months
the point of something like CV is or when we're talking about the Linux kernel,
like the Linux kernel has thousands of security vulnerabilities because, well,
it's just got a giant code base going back 20 plus years now.
We can talk about these vulnerabilities and not be like, so the Apache HTP
cross site scripting resource splitting attack. OK. Which one?
There's like six of them spanning a couple of years. Well,
blah, blah, blah, no, just CV E dash a
four digit number which is the year in theory dash a four to
six or higher digit number, which is
the actual identifier. That's it. It's just a barcode. That's it. Folks,
a
vulnerability not have VA
CV has to represent a vulnerability otherwise it shouldn't exist.
It's like a barcode for a book, right? A barcode
for a book doesn't exist until there's a book to slap it on.
Or you can write a book without a barcode.
I'm sure I wrote many a comic book as a
youth that had no barcode and luckily never escaped.
You can get the CV. While the vulnerability is private,
you can get the CV, the moment it becomes public,
you can get the CV.
10 years later when you realize this, Linux commit,
fixed this horrible security flaw and nobody realized it was a security flaw,
whatever.
I'm gonna, I'm gonna put a stick in the ground and say, just
go listen to the github
episode
for all of those details because they do,
we, I guess, do a marvelous job of explaining it with github.
So here's the question though that I really want us to discuss
is do you think if you have discovered a CD E,
does that say anything
about your ability level in the world of security?
-- Again,
-- you're asking the wrong question. The question
simply is
does adding a CV to a vulnerability, add value in some way, shape or form.
For example, clearly describing the vulnerability adds value versus a
cross site scripting vulnerability in wordpress,
that's terrible.
But a cross site script of vulnerability in wordpress file food dot PHP line 172
that is adding vulnerability right there.
So does a cve add value to the vulnerability. And the answer is
sometimes, yeah, and sometimes quite a lot,
especially for the volume stuff like say Microsoft or Oracle
where Oracle comes up with 200 security flaws every quarter.
You are too meta.
I think that's
the
conception has
-- to be
-- me.
It
-- doesn't matter
-- because
we can talk about whatever we want
it.
No, no, I, I mean, so here's
where I wanted to kind of bring this and I have a feeling I'm going to be
digging you out of the meadow hall. This whole conversation, that's fine.
But is
so let's say I'm a new person
and I'm looking to get a job in the world of security and someone tells me, oh,
you need to go discover some CV E I DS.
You can put them on your resume
resume for certain types of hiring people.
Yes. OK. There we go. Because here is what I kept thinking of is
if, if someone sent me a resume was like, oh, I discovered 1000 CV E si would feel like
no, you did. Right. You either discovered 1000 garbage CV ES
or
-- you somehow are lying or you gained something because nobody
-- does that.
Conversely. Now you have the data to actually look it up easily and check.
-- Well,
-- yes, I do. But most people don't.
And a lot of people, like you said, don't even know what CV E is.
And so there's probably a subset of people that would see.
Oh, you have all these CV ES, you must be really smart.
Whereas I have a suspicion if someone sent me a resume with CV ES on it,
I would grill them like none other.
And
just because they'd be like, all right.
So let's do this if, if you're going to brag about this, like,
I'm going to hold you to task and see what's going on
-- and
-- they would either fail miserably or pass with one
colors because there's not really going to be any.
Exactly.
And, and it's one of those things that, you know what it always reminds me of.
I,
I've interviewed like a gazillion application, security people.
And my favorite was always when someone
would start talking about buffer overflows.
And I would just say,
tell me about buffer overflows
and the conversation generally goes downhill from there
because I've only talked to a handful of people
and I would,
I would consider many of them my friends now because I really enjoyed their company.
But
there are very few people who actually could answer that question
without just getting themselves into more and more trouble.
Honestly say
I am not 100% confident I could properly
-- and clearly explain a buffer overflow.
-- Yeah, you're not on my list. So,
but, but see there's, there's the trick though is I'm,
I'm smart enough to know. I don't know that.
-- Exactly.
-- That, that's a start. At least
-- that
-- that's exactly it. And I feel like
this is the same story of someone saying, oh, you need CV E I DS on your resume.
It, it feels to me
like
if you think you need that,
you don't know enough, right?
You're, that's like Dunning Kruger territory,
it really does depend what kind of job and where you're hiring because there
are absolutely places that look at those metrics.
Yeah, I mean, there probably are. No, I've, I've worked for those places.
They literally,
that was like your resume of finding flaws was directly proportional to
you getting hired and how much you were going to get paid.
Because literally, I worked at two places,
isight partners and I defense where literally
coming up with exploit code for known vulnerabilities
and proving that they worked and whatnot.
You know, if you were able to do that for Microsoft products,
you were gonna make a lot more money than if you weren't able
to or to only do it for like the Linux kernel or something.
And we had some really scary smart guys who would, like,
basically Microsoft Tuesday would roll around,
they'd lock themselves in their lab for literally 24 hours
and then come out with like a
working exploit for the worst Microsoft vulnerability.
-- I believe
-- that,
-- you know, between Vin Diff and a bunch of other shenanigans.
-- Sure. Ok.
I mean, and, and that's fair, I guess in that regard,
I,
but how many of those people had, like,
discovered the issues because I will also say that actual finding
flaws and exploiting flaws are not the same skill set.
There's some overlap,
-- they're
-- similar enough that it's a good metric but more to the point part of
their job also was not on Microsoft Tuesday was finding new and original flaws.
Like, if you go through
Microsoft
security advisories you'll see eyesight part
and I defense get credit for a bunch of some really bad stuff.
Yeah. I mean, that's true.
I, I remember dealing with reports from those folks and they were, they were good.
I mean, that's like I know the Qac
folks when I see
that's one of those ones when I see a security report with Wallace's name on it.
-- Like I go read it because I know that one's the real deal.
-- Oh,
man, when, when I was still assigning CV S and doing that stuff on the distro list and,
you know, there'd be an email and I love calls, but I also hated the head's bad.
Habit of sending the emails out at like three o'clock on a Friday.
And I was just like, oh God,
I had plans this weekend.
-- That
-- was
-- fun. Not as bad as a phone call from Tavis Horman.
You
know,
I know, I love those like memes that are talking about, you know,
when Tavis asked on Twitter for a contact on Friday afternoon and it's like, oh,
we'll make more coffee.
That's all right. It's on.
No, I know, I know that feeling. Exactly
the thing is, and that's the problem. The R CV S this be all end, all show of your
competency and sophistication and qualification.
Well,
maybe,
-- maybe not, probably not, but sometimes, yes, but sometimes, mostly, no,
-- I,
-- I would lean towards no, in most instances for the
-- majority.
That would be correct. But
I would say
what two aspects of this would be.
It shows a willingness to play well with others, especially sometimes.
Let me put it this way. If somebody comes to me with a CV,
there's going to be a couple of things that I'm going to find interesting about it.
Number one, is it like an interesting CV?
Or is it like kind of, you know, just some very simple little flaw or is it like,
you know, I found this, like, really cool flaw and like,
openness a cellar to the LS kernel.
Uh Second thing would be, which CV numbering authority did they go through to get it?
Like, did they
find something in a third party product that's not covered and, you know,
went through mir
or did they,
for example, find a flaw in an oracle product and actually get,
managed to get oracle to assign a CV and fix it?
Because if they can do that,
that's actually pretty impressive,
you know, not to pick on oracle. But let's pick,
we can pick on them.
It'll never work for them.
Those are famous last words,
but I have a relatively sophisticated understanding of CV
and what these things mean. And like, I know how the CNAs behave
and that's
not your average bear.
No. And that's the other half of this I keep thinking of is
you and I have probably one of the most skewed views of
CV E on the planet because we were heavily involved and like,
we know everything buried in the yard.
Not only were you
involved? I'm on the bloody board.
That's
right.
People on the planet right there.
No offense. You probably should have been on the board.
I think there's 100% chance you are correct.
But there's a long string of funny history.
I will tell anyone who buys me a bunch of beers sometime, but it doesn't matter. And
in hindsight, I'm kind of glad I'm not.
But because then I'd be in your position where it's like, well, crap.
I'm stuck on this thing.
-- But anyway,
-- anyway.
Right. I'm,
yes.
Anyway,
anyway,
-- so
-- Exactly. And that's so on. The one hand, part of me almost wants to say that I am not
q
I'm overqualified to talk about this because it's like
asking Einstein about his view on atomic bombs.
He, he has such a subtle and nuanced view of it that
I don't understand that.
And, and that's fair actually.
And that's actually not something I had thought of in this context
is the fact that you can sometimes be over educated to a point
that I sound like such a snob here.
But you can be like, you can know too much to have actual conversations with,
with normal people.
And I think we're even more skewed because we
talk to each other all the freaking time.
So we're like,
-- everyone knows this
-- and half the time when I talk with people about Stevie stuff,
they're like, are you sure?
And I'm like,
yes, just trust me when I say that this is correct.
You know, it's like, you know, yeah,
it's like asking Einstein about the theory of relativity.
It's like, no, no, no. I said it's true. It's true.
You know what you just reminded me of.
So there is a speed running event that will be over by the time this,
this podcast is published, it's called a GDQ.
Awesome Games Done Quick.
And they do another event called Summer Games Done Quick
and actually went to summer games done quick last year,
which was amazing.
And I loved it. But anyway,
there was, this guy was running
the Fallout
Anthology or whatever. It's basically like five Fallout games. Right.
And he, he, he ran them all in like, two hours,
which is amazing because it would take a normal person probably, like,
20 hours to beat one of the games.
-- It would
-- take me two hours to learn the basics of the.
Exactly.
And there was this one point where he's talking about, he had like,
he had a little model made of, of cardboard and plastic cups.
He constructed to explain this glitch.
He was going to do where he like, he had to jump on top of a level and then like jump
off the side and fall under like he had to loop around and go under this, this elevator
to and then get sucked up into it and go to like this, this place.
And, you know, he's explaining all this while it's loading
and
it was a very detailed explanation.
And it was surprisingly easy to understand with the model he had.
And then at the end he goes, and this saves 40 seconds. It's like,
it just, it literally took this guy two minutes
or maybe even more than two minutes to explain the flaw.
And then
it saves 40 seconds in the game by doing this trick. And it's like,
that's what I feel like here. I think we,
I mean, I mean, I that's how you win these things. Yes.
But that's what I feel like when you're saying, you know,
like asking Einstein a question.
It's like sometimes when somebody knows too much,
it can be very difficult for them to explain.
And then it seems even dumber when they're done explaining because it's like, wait,
what, 40 seconds, like, come on.
You
know, it's just,
it was awesome though. And it was actually a really fun run.
If,
if anyone's interested in speed running all the videos will be on youtube from a GDQ.
And it is an awesome event. I'd love it. But anyway, anyway. All right. So
I think
-- I want to move on and I think you, you hit the
-- nail.
This hits a fundamental problem though in tech,
which is going to a very metal level.
How do tech interviews work? Right?
Typical programming interviews now seem to largely consist
of a bunch of like programming games that don't
to the real world
or they like quiz you on essentially four
year CS
degree knowledge
to see if you paid attention in class, I guess because they don't trust your GPA.
Like write me a sorting algorithm with only four bits of memory
and the computer catches fire every 17 seconds,
right? Like, huh?
Like whatever,
that's
easy,
whatever. And so
the CV E thing is kind of, it's just a very specific technical subset of that.
It's like
ask, oh a great example, we ask a developer to, for example,
explain the differences between XML and
JSON
or even worse, ask a developer to explain why
XML stream to serialize exist.
And if they're under the age of 40 they're not going to have a clue.
Right. Because computers are just real fast now. It doesn't matter.
And that's what I'm saying,
but
fundamentally
it doesn't really matter because most of it's mature enough that it just works.
And that's kind of how the security industry is in general.
Most of it is, you know,
you report a flaw to somebody and they generally try and fix it nowadays.
They don't try and shoot the messenger as much as they used to.
And then they generally ship that fix and more to the point we live
in a world now where you get your software online every like 17 minutes,
you don't get a CD in the mail every two years.
I mean, that's fair.
I, I think that's a really good point and I, I, like,
I think that's a great way to close this conversation, I think.
Yeah,
I agree 100 percent.
Again, if you're in an industry that, like, infosec, I would say,
get what really drives me nuts is all these guy anonymous.
But he basically says I have two CV reservations that never got finalized, blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah.
And I asked,
um,
you know,
well, like, why didn't they get finalized?
And he's basically like, well, you know,
I got them reserved and just never told Miter, like,
when they got fixed and stuff and it's kind of like, well, ok,
that's why they don't really exist in the database then.
Right.
I mean, because, you know, miters not gonna,
they don't have time to go hunt down every single CV, they,
that's not miter's fault either.
-- Yeah,
-- exactly.
So,
you know, part of why CV is such a mess is like,
it would be the same thing as complaining.
Why are there so many spelling mistakes on Wikipedia?
Well, because a whole bunch of random people edited Wikipedia
and, you know,
I,
I remember reading the article for Edmonton and it said Edmonton
is dissected by the North Saskatchewan River and I'm like close,
like
we're only, it's, it's literally off by two air, right? B to D
or ad to B rather, you know, B
and I'm like,
you know, so I, I, and I was like, I stared at it and then I actually, like,
created an account and that was, I think one of the first edits I ever did, like,
I logged in and created an account and,
and corrected that one character and, you know, made me feel my brain less twitchy.
But at the same time, you know, like if I ever want to complain about Wikipedia, I
-- can't not fix things when I see them on Wikipedia.
-- That's true. That's true.
So,
you know, my take on CV is a lot of people complain about CV.
And then you ask them, well, like,
did you participate in the process and actually like, blah, blah, blah.
-- And they're like, no, it was really annoying
-- in defense
of Wikipedia. It is much easier to edit Wikipedia entries.
Not anymore, man, I've edited Wikipedia entries about factual things that again,
like the CV E page
that I'm, I think I'm an authority on
or like the, you know,
some other things where I'm involved in an authority and people have been like, no,
that's, we don't like, we don't believe you.
Your citation doesn't make sense. We're revoking your edit.
Wikipedia is, if you look at it now, it's become a really,
it's like the same thing with stack overflow, right?
You, you, you ask a really good question and somebody's like, uh no,
this is related to this other question that it totally isn't
and we're closing it as a duplicate and it's like, no, no, no,
this is something completely new and different.
-- Trust me on this one.
-- Yeah, I don't, I don't really pay attention to
ST
but fundamentally that's, you know, that's,
I would say the problem with CV is most people
don't know what CV is much like Fight Club.
We don't talk about it enough,
we talk about it all the time while normal people don't want
to hear about it and I don't blame them at all.
And I mean, normal people in the infosec industry,
I don't mean like normal people like truck drivers.
And, um,
yeah, I, again, a lot of these people I see complaining about CV,
when I asked them about kind of what, what, what happened, what was your experience?
It's kind of like,
well, that, that's kind of how that works. Like, sorry, you don't like it. But, yeah.
Yeah. Anyway. All right, let's move on ransomware.
So the story here
is,
there's a telemarketing company that went out of business shortly
before Christmas and they claim they got hit by ransomware.
They paid the ransom.
Their files didn't decrypt and they basically couldn't stay in business anymore.
And
I'm curious what your thoughts are on this one because I read that and I was like,
I don't know about this.
So going back a bit further, even,
uh there's an article here from CNET in 2017 that says basically
ransomware shuts down one in five small businesses after it hits.
Oh,
I hadn't read that but I,
-- I believe that and
-- I would absolutely believe that because think about this
just fundamentally how many companies can survive a catastrophic data loss event.
I
can't.
Yeah.
Um, but companies in general, my understanding is the number, you know,
it varies a lot but it's like 50% just are gone.
Sony made it
-- like
-- they didn't lose data.
They,
they, I'm
talking about data lost,
gone. Not like it leaked, but like,
like the building burnt down, the server got, you know,
somebody spilled Coca Cola into the server.
Ransomware, encrypted all your data, you know, whatever.
Um, so the reality is,
well, ransomware is one type of data loss event but there's others, like, you know,
hard drives fail,
like over the last 25 years, how many hard drives have you?
And I had failed, I mean, not many recently, but like in the, you know, 1st 5,
10 years of my tech career I lost probably a good half dozen drives in that.
I lose a lot.
-- I mean, I haven't in a while.
-- You're right. Smack them with hammers.
-- No,
-- just, I, well, I,
I basically, I'm notorious for buying cheap drives and powering them off.
Yeah. And then you power them off and they never power back
-- on.
-- But now granted, I mean, they're still like 10 years old.
It's not like I'm running these things for a year and then they die
like they are well past their expected lifetime when they die on me.
-- So,
-- I mean, that's a perfect example of why small businesses suffer data loss.
They, they run a bunch of hardware.
But
I mean, you,
if you want to run a hard drive for 1020 years,
there are hard drives out there that will do that and they cost a bit more.
Not much more. I don't,
but
I actually for a while was buying those, uh, what was it? Western Digital Red Nas
Drives.
And man, I mean, I went from like Seagate,
I experienced something like a 30% failure rate across a dozen drives.
So I was, I'm like,
you know, never buying Seagate again.
I went to Western Digital and I mean,
I think the worst I ever got was like two smart airs on one drive,
you know, and I had like almost 20 of these.
Um,
but back to this, I mean, the reality is, well,
Ransomware is one event that can cause data loss.
But fundamentally, like most small businesses are literally
-- a week of unpaid invoices away from insolvency.
-- Uh That's probably fair actually.
And I know I have a friend who worked at, uh,
he was like the head of it for a smallish company.
And I remember,
like he joked to me one time where his CEO showed up and basically said, you know,
what's our,
like, what's our plan? If we have catastrophic data loss? We find new jobs.
The guys like, oh ha ha. Really? He's like, no, that, that's actually it, like,
you don't want to pay for a proper backup. So that's pretty much the way it goes.
Yeah, like I recently made a policy if I don't do local backups anymore at home here,
I
only do cloud
backups.
House burns down.
Yeah, I know. I know.
I mean,
I remember working in a data center like a million
years ago where every week the bin would arrive on Monday
and you take the old tapes out and you put the new
tapes in and then they carted off on Thursday every week,
man, those were, those were dark days.
-- I mean,
-- well, the other thing too is this company that went out, somebody mentioned,
I found this quite humorous is that,
yeah, they might have, well, you were mentioning, for example, like,
did they use the key correctly or did they get the right key or, you know, whatever.
So assuming, let's assume for a moment they got encrypted by ransomware. A
got ransomware, A's key and used ransomware A's key correctly.
They, I mean, because this ransomware isn't like, it's not all of it is high quality.
Some of it actually is from what I've read surprisingly high quality software
but not all of it is.
But assuming for a moment it's decent
quality software that actually decrypted properly.
Somebody pointed out that that might not have been their first ransomware.
I mean, it's
-- sometimes it
-- could be, it could be where ransomware a encrypts everything,
then ransomware B shows up and re encrypts everything
and you might, you only know about B you decrypt B and you're like, oh crap,
there's still a here and my, my deadline has expired.
So I'm sol
which maybe, I mean, I think the odds of that are probably low.
I,
I have a strong suspicion.
This was a telemarketing firm in the midwest of the United States.
We're not going to be talking about
super tech savvy it, people in general here,
if I was going to guess,
well, and it's not like they had the kind of money that may spent
fixing their,
my suspicion
is they either got the key and couldn't figure out how to use it
or they decrypted it and the data was still in such a state.
They couldn't actually deal with
it and, and I bet you're right.
-- They were basically,
-- well, how many places, how do I put this nicely?
How many places would take more than a week to recover
if you just killed power to all the servers or let,
no, no, no, let's back up.
Not even killed power to the servers.
You shut down every single piece of
hardware gracefully turned everything off and said,
OK, bring it all back up online and make it work.
Uh
Right. Exactly.
It's gonna depend obviously. But so I remember
when my first job out of college, we had a fairly large data center.
It was like half the floor of the building we were in.
And
I remember one time we lost power where it was out for a day
and obviously UPS kicks in. We didn't have a generator.
The UPS could make it, I think six hours though because it was a big Ups.
And I remember in our four, they were like, we gotta shut it down.
We got to start turning stuff off. We don't have a choice here.
And we,
I think we left the website up because we could run basically the web
server and the router for probably a day on the remaining power we had.
And yeah, I remember that day when we started things back up.
There was that, well, the next day it was,
there was an enormous number of machines
that
-- didn't come back
-- online
-- services
-- and
it
was messed up.
I remember there's,
there's a stack overflow question where I've actually
been uploaded quite a lot where they talk about
rebooting Linux kernel.
Uh Well, Linux system or whatever, and my response was,
I actually forced myself to reboot, not just for kernel updates, but in general,
once a month
I
have
servers.
I,
that I know they would come back up and I
don't mean just the physical hardware but I mean,
the services and everything
and also that way I could do it in a controlled environment, you know, I would like,
and literally, it would happen about once or twice a year.
I would reboot and something would go wonky and I'd fix it.
But I'm doing that like
on my schedule on a Saturday morning when I'm relaxed, not
in a panic situation at three in the morning.
Um
And the reality is like,
how many places practice turning off all their systems and bringing them back up.
Does that
apart from Netflix with their chaos Gorilla?
Uh Right. Right. But they're also very cloud based.
Yeah, that doesn't, that doesn't really count. No, I hear you. So, I guess
I don't, I don't want to drag this one on too long.
But it, it, it seems to me like, so the other,
the other half of this conversation now is there's all these people that are saying,
oh, my goodness, if you're a small business,
you need like these amazingly robust backups to
make sure you don't go out of business.
And then that got me thinking as well.
I mean, honestly,
if you're in a position where ransomware could put you out of business,
you're probably not in a position to number one even know this happened.
But then number two, like
what are backups? Right? You're not,
I feel like this is such a catch 22 for everyone. I don't think there's a way out of it.
Well, the problem is,
is that this is one of those things where your return on money isn't linear.
For example, my Windows 10 machine I spend, you know,
what is it like 100 bucks a year on back blaze?
And I think the files are all pretty much backed up. Back blaze.
Doesn't back up my program files, which I would have liked.
But whatever I can probably recover that machine in the data I want on it.
Same thing with, you know, my macs and icloud, I get,
you know, my photos, my passwords, all that stuff's backed up.
Is it all fully, fully backed up? Well, last time I did a machine restore,
I think. So.
I didn't notice anything missing.
You got a new phone
and you kept messaging me about all the crap that was broken
because I had to
log
in or I had to, like, you know, poke it with a sharp stick or whatever. Yeah, exactly.
And it's, you know, it's this ongoing thing.
So, is there something probably missing from my phone still if I had to bet money?
Yeah. But nothing major. Right.
That's fair.
And so
people don't have time and money for that when they're running a small business.
-- I mean, I would agree completely. Your
-- backup solution for email,
use Gmail or
Outlook.
I agree
-- completely.
-- You know, same thing with password backups.
No, you just pay last pass or one password or somebody like that.
No. Exactly. I think, I think expecting a small business to have
anything resembling
decent. It
is ridiculous. Right. They're not in the IT business.
Oh, what I love is we've figured this out a long time ago for money.
You keep your money in the bank and the bank is in the US. It's FDIC insured
up to, what is it? 250 grand per
even the
bank isn't fully expected to keep it safe. Like they
will probably keep it safe.
But, you know, just in case the federal government will insure it.
Well, and funny enough, I would say most banks, most large banks are now it,
companies that also handle money.
Right. They're not money, companies that handle it.
But anyway, no, I, I feel like
if I was a small business owner,
I don't think there's even anything I could reasonably do here.
There is actually a great
example of this.
I've noticed all the new sort of, um,
I don't want to say the hipster run businesses but all the new sort of micro business.
Well, not micro business, but like the new businesses with one location run by,
you know, 2 to 6 kind of younger people under the age of 40. Basically,
all they are generally based on, for example,
is they have a point of sale system that's usually an Android
-- tablet or an apple tablet
-- running square or something
running square running,
you know, another application.
They usually have a website which has like, for example,
you click on the product type in your email address
and as soon as it comes back in stock,
it'll send you an email,
things like that
and they basically don't
have any it to be held to ransomware.
And what little it they do have is like tablets,
I mean, and that's fair.
And that,
-- that's the solution right there for small business.
-- Right.
You're absolutely right. Get the server out of your closet and just
sass it all
it all mobile devices, not computers.
That's probably fair too because once you have computers,
-- you start saving things
-- like,
well, not even that but, like, let's face it,
I look at my phone and the security stuff,
Apple and even Google are doing for their
phones compared to what's happening on the desktop.
-- That's very true.
-- Right.
Like Apple, face, ID, Apple, you know, um, they just, you know, how many,
how many computer,
how many desktop or laptop computers have a fingerprint scanner.
Uh, most of them do now. But I, I understand what you're saying.
Well, yeah, actually, you know, Apple actually do.
Yeah, because that's one of the reasons I got the uh, the laptop,
I don't have to keep ping in my password now.
I can just
strip my thumb on it.
But I mean, fundamentally,
I hate to say this, it kind of drives me nuts because I do love computers
and I kind of hate the walled garden that is, you know, most mo mobile devices.
But fundamentally
if I was running even a large business,
I wouldn't let people
use anything but a tablet or a mobile device effectively.
And, um, actually we should put this in the show notes,
but Laura Shin just did a really good episode on SIM swapping.
She got SIM swapped a few weeks ago.
And the reason was this phone company allowed
like people, you know, working at like the phone
kiosk or little mini store at the malls
to
essentially have a computer to access some critical
stuff and they got fished with a link,
blah, blah, blah
and they've moved that now to being tablet
only because the carrier has much more control
-- over the tablet and the security of the tablet than they do over a
-- PC.
That's probably fair.
I mean, I, I,
yeah, that makes sense to me.
So I, I hate to say it, but I think the solution is what all the kids are doing, which is
-- in the cloud on a mobile device.
-- That's probably fair.
I hadn't really thought of it in that way, but II, I do think you're right.
I like it.
I dig it.
You know what? It's the only problem is
you basically have to conform to somebody else's workflow.
I mean,
we kind of have that now.
I mean, if you're running software, even if you build it yourself,
you're not using the most efficient and ideal workflow, right?
You're kind of stuck at, at
the mercy of be it your developers or someone else's developers.
I mean,
yeah. Anyway,
cool. All right. No, that makes sense. I like it. All right.
So I'm gonna, I'm gonna call it
so wonderful. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening. Go to open
source security podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes,
use the Pound Os S Podcast hashtag to hit us up on
social media and Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye bye.