Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
-- and my partner in Thought Crime. Josh
-- Pressers.
I'm very excited. We have Tama
De
Pierre back, join the Illustrious
multi
guest club. I guess.
I guess he's the first one. No, he's, he's like the third. I think.
I think Liz Rice and uh
Dr
David Wheeler had been on it at least twice, maybe some others. I can't remember.
-- So if I forgot your name on the list, I apologize. But Tama, welcome
-- back.
Thank you. Happy to be back
to
back. And uh
I have to say that compared to tools and name you just,
you know, brought up. I am definitely not in the same kind of club I think.
Well, you are now. So
it's very exciting. No, we're, we're excited to have you.
You, we've got some what some eu government topics today,
which is going to be fantastic.
I think so. I'll just, I'll just give you the floor man. Take it away.
Oh, thanks. Uh I think uh to, to go with that. Uh
It was interesting thing. So I was
so if you remember everyone may remember from the last time I came in,
I came in mostly because of a rant.
I wrote as a blog post called I'm, I'm not a supplier.
Uh
And when I say rent,
it was literally like a midnight rent reading a
Google thing with SLC or something like that.
And it seems to have, you know,
struck a nerve and we got quite some engagement discussion around this
and this led to me talking with quite a few people this year.
And there have been quite a lot of, of, you know,
things happening around open source security and supply chain terms and
policy making in the past year, a lot of movement.
And so that led to me being
at F
them a couple of weeks ago
uh where there was a uh
a day long on the Sunday workshop with people from the EU Commission,
multiple people on multiple workshops around
how do we engage even more for free and open
software with
policy making in particular around the EU.
And so
I think that there is a few interesting to bring here uh from that
being the cr a uh how I see things after a year after.
Um the fact that I leave this discussion with some hopes but also uh
not that many. And I, a lot of interesting, always
a lot of thinking around the fact that there is a lot to build.
Yeah.
Yeah, for sure.
All right, let's start with the cr a,
because I find it to be.
Well, it's the thing I know the most about, of, of the various items you just listed.
So, what is the cr A?
Oh, I don't know if I'm the best place person to talk about that, but I can do a quick run
if you want to
do far better. You could probably have as a guest.
Malta
from NL
Net Labs that did a lot of work on this this year.
Um
But the,
the rundown is that the EU decided that
uh as nearly every product in the EU uh the
sell, sold on the EU market. If you were going to sell
a
product with software in it,
-- you
-- should have
everything at this point. A
lot of stuff
iot your, your kids toys, right? A lot of stuff
you should probably have some kind of
regulation. Now, this is relatively light.
This is uh the idea is to reuse the existing
ce marking which uh for people that may not be
from the EU is a marking you may see on
a lot of your uh electronic uh electric school stuff.
Like if you look at your charger break, it's probably have this marking on it,
which mostly say that
it
follows the rules on electrical device in the
EU and same thing for the software stuff.
Um The
reason we talk about it, a lot, a lot about it in, in, in free open source.
That's why right in open source is that um
the original text was really targeted at commercial
use, right? And the idea was that
if you,
if you sell something, you should, you know,
make sure that it follows a minimum standards. Now, on the,
this was kind of problematic because of the
definition of commercial from the EU commission,
which would mean that if you were getting like some get up sponsors, for example,
which I know a lot of people try to do
that would count as commercial.
It was kind of scary for the people in open source.
Um There was a lot of engagement during the year
and from everyone that worked on that engagement on the,
you know, false advocacy.
Um The Eu Commission and the Eu Parliament has been
quite open to uh discussion and the final text,
which is now
more or less official. I think there is maybe a last,
you know, official step to go, but that is, that's not going to change.
The text is quite more friendly for themselves.
There is like a dozen or 20 pages describing all
the situation that open source covers that are not handled.
Um So, so
the reality today is that for nearly everyone doing open source,
except if you are a for profit, big company,
right?
You are not going to be concerned,
you go on. So that's pretty good as a result.
Um
And so that's Mui
the
CR A
uh and Susie to,
to give an idea of what kind of standard regulation we are talking of things like,
hey,
you need to have a way for security researchers to
tell you when there's a vulnerability in your stuff,
which is, you know, relatively understandable, right?
It's not
feel like it's a heavy, you know, uh lie
yelling at you and regulation context, I think for open source folks, the most,
the second most important part is that
if what they call an integrator, which is a company using the open source code
find or is made aware of vulnerability,
they are, they have to, you know, disclose it to you and to the public,
but also within reasonable timeline. But they also have,
if they can
to provide a fix,
which means for us sending a patch was a fix to the uh
upstream,
which I think is quite a first in terms of legal obligation.
Well, I think for me, it boils down to that fit for purpose.
Idea of like if I sell you a hammer,
you have to be able to hit a nail with it and it doesn't break,
right? Whereas if you use the hammer as a crowbar though and it breaks.
Well, ok, sorry, that's not its purpose,
right? You can't do that
in broad terms.
Yes.
But, but the fact that not only do they have to do that but they have to upstream a fix.
Yeah,
that's kind of new, right?
For us at least in our world.
Oh,
that
-- is that, I, I'm just because I'm looking at the act and, um, oh,
-- gosh,
I don't know the way it is on the whole thing.
It's 200 pages.
-- It's
-- gigantic. Kurt, it's completely gigantic.
I'm just trying to find where it talks about pushing it because, I mean,
I did find the commercial thing and it has the car vote for open source scene,
reasonably sane and well written
as sane as you can make an open source cover out because that's a lot of cases to cover
well.
And I think in fairness too,
like I still meet people who have a hard time understanding.
So there's all these people globally, like millions of people globally,
just like writing software for kind of fun but not fun.
But because they need to do it but they don't need to do
it but they don't get paid but they do it for free.
And I mean, I admit that,
yeah, it sounds kind of confusing if you're like a traditional legislator,
business person who does things for money only.
Right. So I imagine
some of this is not so much malicious as just they don't understand the ecosystem,
right?
And,
and something that came up a lot in the
discussion on what happened is that at some point,
the parliament particularly thought that we just wanted to
not have to handle it.
Might like
we just wanted to the, the, the the point of view was that.
Well, if we put a car
out for open,
all these commercial company will just say, oh, no,
we open source it and then they will not have to deal with it.
And they did not want that and they were really seeing
it as lobbying to be able to get out of it
because that's what they are used to deal with when lobbyists come to them.
Right.
And so, so that was a lot of discussion and,
and a lot of work around that uh from what I understand, but once again,
I was not in this
discussion. So I may not be the,
-- well,
-- that type of misunderstanding makes perfect sense because yeah,
typically when a company is like, we don't want to do that because they,
they don't want to pay for it.
And I, the big difference here is the open source community in my experience.
Absolutely wants to provide security fixes and good
software.
I just don't want to, you know, be held legally liable for this,
you know, we can't.
Right.
And so I'm going to go on the other side here, which is, you said,
liable.
So that's interesting because the cr
A actually doesn't handle liability directly.
Um Because
what the cr A give all these, you know,
self assessment you need to do and all these certification and all
um
keep in mind it's, it doesn't cover,
it does not cover things that were already covered.
So like your health care device, right,
a pacemaker or something like that is not covered by the
CR A because it's already covered by far more tight regulation.
But the second aspect is another directive piece of EU law that
has not been talked as much but developed at the same time,
which is a PLD for product liability directive.
And this is the,
you know, rules that spell out how you want liability and who is liable for what
in the eu
and up until this year,
software was not part of that
officially,
there was a way to get liability for software, right?
But, but so now it has been extended with official roots
and the big thing for
software I think,
and I will start with it and then I will do a bunch
of caveat and everyone will remember me at the start of the sentence.
I'm sorry,
is that
the as is close,
does not stand anymore.
You cannot
get rid of liability
with the license of a contract on software anymore.
There is a good reason for that,
which is exactly what we were talking about before, right?
The idea of liability is to protect the weakest.
And so you cannot,
you cannot say, hey, listen, uh you all need to use my software.
But if something goes wrong, it's on you.
And let's let's clarify that because
some of us know, but I'm sure not everyone does is that that terms of service.
None of us read and just click, agree at the bottom.
Buried in that phone book of an agreement says, like if anything goes wrong,
it's not our fault.
-- It's your problem to deal with.
-- Right.
And also that we can change it at any time with maybe 30 days notification.
You don't actually have to agree to it. Which,
you know, as I understand contract law is like, that's not how contracts work,
but apparently they do
well, it's not that well tested in court.
But the, the interesting part here is more that for us in open source software,
right?
We are used to this, you know,
no warranty, etcetera, etcetera everywhere in our licenses
that doesn't stand anymore.
You cannot get out of liability by just saying, hey,
um to use this software and to sign this contract that says that it's all on you,
you cannot do that right
now.
That seems really scary, right?
Because if my software is used in a place and people get hurt, I could be liable
as an open source maintenance
that doesn't exactly work this way.
Um There is a special carve out which is that if a software
or product with software is sold and harm someone and the integrator,
the person that sold it and integrated all that code is found liable
normally, the way it works in the eu classically is that they will have to pay a fine
and then they can
go sue the upstream
their suppliers
to try to recoup some of that
is there is a special camera,
they cannot do that
for
open or software maintenance.
So we are mostly not concerned
is this for open source maintainers or non commercial open
source?
I don't remember exactly the sentence.
But if it's the same as the CR A in general, like if you're not concerned by the CR A,
you are not going to be concerned by the Plde.
OK.
So, so you are going to be good
because I'm going to assume like Red Hat, for example,
is not going to be able to wiggle out of this by saying like, oh, we're open sources
as
-- well.
-- Yes and partial is, is because they are integrators.
Right.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Hat. Open source and then uses it and get sued. They
Red Hat didn't integrate that. That
makes
sense.
So, so,
but that's not the only one.
There is a few other things but that the guest
of the idea is that you are not too concerned.
But at the same time, keep in mind that this is a real thing that's happening,
right?
And there has been a lot of discussions around this to make
sure that it fits this kind of use case for us too
because it would be really,
really problematic for everyone if like there is a vanity
girls that end up being used somewhere
and then everyone goes, Daniel see, Daniel
Sanber
says that he pays
for
losses,
right?
If everybody sued lock for Jay for the lost productivity of dealing with that issue,
that would be
dollars.
Yeah, exactly. So that the uh the outcome of this year
is this right?
And so this worked pretty well.
There was a lot of lobbying and a lot of learning by Friano
pins,
people trying to do the work on the eu to, to make sure they align well,
and yeah,
so
not too really scary.
The end result is not too scary, but it's also changes coming in our world uh slowly.
And it's also uh uh
and that's what generated this also um day at for
them
because the idea was, hey, um
we don't talk a lot
with policymakers and policymakers don't know a lot about us,
but we are kind of important and they are starting to be aware of that.
So maybe we should have this kind of, of,
of channel communication more open and try to start building this kind of advocacy
and do a bit of retrospective and moving forward from what happened this year.
Well, I mean,
what's fascinating to me is like apple
straight up in their security advisories is like
open
source, like they just list open
source after open source after open source package.
And then plus, you know, a bunch of stuff and
iMessage that we wrote and oops,
same thing, you know, Windows a bit less open source in their announcements.
But still, you know,
there is,
well, they're apparently bringing pseudo to Windows like
there
is
a
lot of stuff
and it's just II I
do. And, well,
it is kind of amazing to me that the world is literally built on
open source and I guess because it's worked so well and so quietly succeeded.
But yeah, I,
I suspect less than 1% of policymakers know about to find what open source is.
Well,
yes and no. And that goes to what I have problem with in there.
So I think there's a few things here. So the first one is
they are aware of free software far more than open source software.
And, and for one that I'm going to make the distinction, I'm going to, to do it.
Uh And part of the reason here is that the free software movement have been far more
focused on end user rights on freedoms on advocacy for this, right?
And part of that intersected a lot with digital rights movements,
right?
Which uh may not be, I don't know what the situation is in, in a around this,
outside of the eff of course.
Um but
in, in Europe, there is a lot of advocacy work on, you know, digital rights.
And that intersect a lot with,
with free software advocacy
and end user software advocacy.
So people like the EU commission, for example, will know really,
really well stuff like Linux
as a desktop,
right?
Or stuff like lib
office, right?
Or open office in the old time, all this kind of stuff because,
because they deal with that a lot,
like they literally also have mandate to try to use it on their own desktop.
They have a lot of work on that front has been done.
Gy
is also a thing that you will hear around when
you talk with people working around the EU policy.
So there is a lot of this
um
which,
and, and that's good,
right?
Like this is stuff we see in the D MA also, for example, for so Digital Market Act,
people may have heard about it in our committee due to Apple compliance, I just
quotes around
uh the name uh around that.
And there was a lot of discussion around this with
the U commission where they came to people saying,
hey, uh do you think that this is
actually useful to you and compliance the way they did it?
Let,
let's say that there was a lot of loafing
uh nervous loafing in the room at this question
and, and the,
but, but the D MA among other things say that hey, uh you should
your, your protocols for messaging, for example, need to be open,
right?
Whatsapp need to be able to interact with other things.
Facebook messenger need to be able to interact with other things.
And so there is a lot of work around that.
So, so if you look at it from a user end user perspective
and free software and open standard and stuff like that.
At this front,
there is a lot and lot of work on this and this is something policymakers know about,
at least in the eu
where you are, right is the open source spot
and, and, and that's where things differ a bit because
open sources use even malls and free software for infrastructure.
And we have some interesting data that came out this year, right? Stuff like
80% of every app
is made of open source software.
It's an average, right? But 80%
and they found that 96% of every app they scanned was using open source.
That's a synopsis data, uh data study if I remember correctly.
And so when you bring up this kind of data, there is a lot of, oh, well, um
that's a lot
that's everywhere we want, right?
Like everything is open source at this point, right?
Even your property app is by far open source.
What is interesting? And that's a question I ask in that room. So if you go on the
f website, you can find the recording of everything that was said and done here.
So you, you will hear me challenge people a bit.
Um
uh Among the thing is that
everyone in this room, nearly everyone was paid
for their work on free for free software or
on operative software or on advocacy for these things.
And my point is that this is not the people doing the 80%.
And that's not to say that, you know, it is bad that people are paid to do this.
No, that's great.
But I have not seen at any point in the discussion,
any acknowledgement or even a hint of an understanding that these people exist
that this 80% exist.
Everyone talk about free standard and then uses result and free software.
But the talks about stuff like J
or open SSL or look for jail, all that stuff is
not happening.
It's infrastructure,
it's invisible by definition.
Yeah. Yeah.
So that's why I have a bit less hope, I suppose.
Um
But it,
it has been interesting to see the the there
is an existing big free software and digital wide advocacy
but that's separated from infrastructure
and that's where we see a lot of this collision, right? Because peop when
policymakers work on this topic, they work on it based on the end user point of view
because that's what they know.
Well, I mean, it's a perfect example of this.
I actually read my local electrical code book, right?
The the abridged version, which is only 100 and 50 pages.
Most people don't do stuff like that, right?
And it's, it was clear to me in reading this book,
it was fascinating because I could read a paragraph.
I'm like, oh, what happens if and then the next paragraph is like,
and that's why we use armored cable.
So if somebody puts a nail through it, they don't die.
You know.
And I think by definition, maybe it's like a, a weird form of Survivor bias in that
all the,
all the software that's truly successful as infrastructure
by definition is so
quiet.
It just works like,
you know, you just pull in lip curl because what else would you do? Right.
You just pull in lip curl and it just works 99.9% of the time
and they'll 0.1 over a percent of the time. It doesn't work for you.
It already didn't work for somebody else who
filed the bug report and they're fixing it,
right. You know, I
think there is
multiple
aspect here. One of them is, yes, of course, it works, right.
And that's partially why it won. I think the other reason, the reason why
what I call open source one and I say open source, not face of all
things
that one
and,
and the fact that 80% like an average of 80% of every
app is open source means that we want right at this point.
The ID one proper
Sowa
is now rare.
It's
the exception.
It's the glue that holds a bunch of like essentially it's that it's like red hats.
A perfect example of this like red hat opens, shift is a very thin
of Red hat glue sitting on top of
Kernes
and, and what that means is that open source won, right?
Like open source is a default at this point for everything.
And that's not how we think about it usually, but that's right.
And, and one of the reason it won
and that's something I've brought up and I talked with a bit of
Os co si people around it and they agree with me is that
we would not be able to do software as complex if it was not open source.
And the reason for that
is because you would need too many lawyers to handle contracts and procurement
for every single piece
the infrastructure to handle all this licensing. And even if
it costs nothing, I'm not even talking of cost of the software,
but even if the cost was free
in terms of beer for
beer, uh I have to do that when we start talking about free software.
Um is you would need to
handle a contract with the supplier,
which means it has to go through procurement,
it has to go through people that don't know what it is,
how it works and you have to explain it and they have to violate
it and they have to do that every year or every two years,
you need to maintain all of this.
If you use it in a new code base, maybe you need to change your license.
How do you know that go talk to legal? Right.
The advantage of the open source stuff and that's why it won for every packages,
right on every language where you python everything you can do ping and it just work.
I mean, no, it's fighting doesn't work, but that's a different discussion.
Um It's because
you don't have to do any of that because the open source, you can,
you, you are the developers, look at him like, oh yeah, that's a license.
I know this is officially approved,
whatever I can just download it and not have to talk to anybody,
right? It's self service and that's why it won because it's easy. It's simple.
And there is not a lot of
organizational cost around it.
Like you don't need to build the whole organization.
And I think building on that too,
one thing I've noticed because I've just been through
this again where I was picking between 10 vendors
in open source.
I generally don't have a hard time choosing
because there's typically one or two clear winners.
But more interestingly, the vast majority of open source I use,
I did not pick because it's in the dependency chain.
You know, I picked
uh
Python panda and well, it,
it does a bunch of stuff and pulls in other stuff or I picked, you know, Python NLTK
or at a high level, you know, a, a PDF parser.
And I can't help but think because I just literally
spent four days evaluating 10 different vendors for a thing.
And that's that's a not inconsequential amount of time and cost.
But, yeah,
and then if I also had to on top of that
to handle all the software licensing issues and contract negotiations and,
you know, the ever classic, like, well, what does this cost?
Well,
we're gonna have to talk to you about that because we want to get as much as we can.
Yeah. I, it, it would slow things down horrifically.
Like, uh, my web des would never get anything done.
Yeah.
And, and the, so that's one aspect
in this aspect is important to keep in mind because
if that's a defining element that made it one,
it means that anything you do that go against that
is going to be a non secret.
You can't do that
even if you try, it's not going to survive.
And that's when a lot of discussion about a people need to
the, you know,
define how they decided which dependency to use on all. Like
you are bringing it back. So it's not going to work.
So question, did anybody from industry or commercial software come and say, hey,
like we need the car vote for open source so we can keep strip mining it and using it.
Otherwise it might go away
by definition, they can't do that
because if they knew how much they were using it,
they would not use like the things that make it work is
that you don't have to talk to anybody to get it.
Right. That's what we just said. Right.
What made it work is that the developer decide by
themselves and never have to talk about it to anyone,
Susie.
I'm not even thinking of it as strict mining because that's not how they got there.
Right.
That maybe the behavior we see from the outside
and we interpret it as being a conscious decision,
but that's not how it works.
Right. It's more if I want to get my job done,
I'm going to use open source. So the way I'm never going to get my job done,
they imagine behavior from that.
Well, it's so in other words, it's not a conspiracy,
it's just 1000 people happen to come up to the same conclusion.
No, seriously. And this is a thing that happens, right?
Where it's, it's not some global conspiracy of strip mining. It's just,
there's 1000 developers that all needed a lip, a library for web stuff and well,
-- they grab lip
-- curl.
All right, let me steer this conversation.
We gotta, we gotta think about kind of getting on the downhill of this podcast.
So, ok, so you have this meeting at Fos
Dem
like what are some of the outcomes that came of that?
Like you said, at the beginning, you have hope,
which you telling me you have hope fills me with joy.
So I'm curious what that is?
Oh yeah. In two or three decades we made progress
and That's
my
hope.
I'm not kidding.
Uh,
I think people forget how slow
governments and legislation moves fundamentally to keep
up with the world of change.
-- Yes.
-- But in this case, I don't think it's a government education problem.
It's a fact that we are not visible.
Like,
like, even if I talk to people that are deeply inside that domain. Right?
And that made the work all year long for this false stuff.
And I explain, you know, 80% of the software you,
you put yourselves and numbers on your slide, 80% of the software is open source.
And all right,
where does this? 80% come from?
They look at me and they never thought of that.
That doesn't even talk show into their mind
was the answer I get most of the time is, well, big companies that pay people to do it.
I'm like, ah
this is something everyone bring up to me even at for
them where people you know, should know better.
There are developers working on free on
software.
Everyone bring it to
a
no,
that's all these big companies like Google Microsoft and
all that pay people to work on these things.
And every time I have to bring example, explain
the fact that that's not how it works.
They are flabbergasted.
Well, this speaks to Josh, you know, well,
tell your one less than one developer story.
-- Well,
-- I'll tell a better story than that.
So I just pulled up the report, I will put a link to it in the show notes,
Tide lift in 2023 did a survey
about
like who are you like, are you an open source developer?
And are you being paid for this?
And,
and the numbers are 60% of open source developers are unpaid for the work they do.
13% are like professionals actually being paid to work
on this stuff and 23% are semi professional.
It says, which means they make some money from their open source work.
-- But 60% that's a lot.
-- Keep in mind this is Tide lift,
which means that
the people they dutch
by design of what they do um
-- will over represent people that get some money out of
-- probably. Yeah, for sure.
-- Yeah. Yeah.
So this is probably uh uh the, the real number is probably far bigger than 60
something percent.
Uh
OK. This floor is 60 but still that, that's a ton.
-- If you
-- think about the friction of there's
literally hundreds of thousands of widely used,
you know,
small packages that are less than one developer
and that one developer has multiple packages.
Yeah, if one or two of them quit, no big deal. But the the friction if,
if chunks of them start to go away or not maintain it,
it, it adds up. And I think
I,
I think part of the problem though is just people
don't understand the law of large numbers here where,
you know, your average package has easily 1000 dependencies
and if one of them breaks, chances are the whole thing is not going to work very well.
So suddenly I see people getting that,
they are starting to get scared about that.
We start to see a lot of people talking about that.
So I think that came in mostly because
people keep seeing these huge numbers every time
they do an update of the packages on seasons with thousands numbers on what the heck.
So I think this, this as we started sipping then
what has not seeping is where does this come from?
How does it get produced?
This is something we don't talk a lot about,
right?
Because I mean, in the, in the, in the, in the physical world,
there's no analog to this, there's no
people producing thousands and thousands of free
products and giving them out for free.
Like
that's just not a thing
on, on the scale of open source.
Well, I don't know about you but my grandma always gave me tomatoes and lettuce
and, and like,
but she's not giving them to
thousands of people and they're not
based on the restaurant offer tomatoes.
But that's because it's free to use it for more people. Right?
And that's where also there is a problem.
But I think the other aspect is how many times a year
do you go
on? You? You know, so I, I'm pretty sure everyone here does not, uh,
use the T VA lot, but let's imagine. Right.
You, you, you, you go on your news show, right? Whatever it is
and
you get an engineer talking about roads.
Ok. That's never happened
at best. You may get a politician or a local person talking about roads.
You will never get an engineer talking about roads
and, and that's the same problem we have here. right? We don't exist. And
what and the other aspect is we are,
you know, we're talking about people leaving being a problem.
They don't even need to leave,
even people keeping doing it
if they are not catching up,
if they keep being a bit, you know below and saying, oh,
there was all these things I need to do but
I will do them next month when I have time and then next month is never happen, right?
Because there is always new things,
you can get degradation even if people keep saying and doing the thing, right?
And,
and that can accumulate over time.
We're talking of at least two or three decades of this at this point,
something the US and a you know,
you are starting to get the organization that the whole infrastructure work,
right?
And in other aspects. And so the
the part where I am hopeful is that I do think first there is tourism first,
I do think that if we manage to,
to tell that story.
If you manage to explain the realities of this 80% right?
We have these numbers and we can use it, we can bring the 80% of everything is us.
And then tell the story of what us mean, who are these people? What do they do?
We can have real engagement and real discussion over the long run on this.
And the uh another aspect that making hopeful on this
is that it would not be expensive to fix.
Like
the example I give all the time rust is doing a
lot of cleaning stuff up at the lower level in this infra
level, right?
And
this is not only about the memory safety,
this is about the fact that I was talking about that with uh who was it?
Uh
Well, someone from
Tiff um Louis from Tide
Lift and, and some people as a lib as a uh lib
evg uh person
around this because they moved lip svg from C to Rust.
And the reason they did it was not because of some memory safety,
but because they could actually get tests
like you can actually test your code.
I know that's really surprising for sea people, but that's possible. I promise you
you can have documentation.
I know that's also really, really surprising for people working on sea.
You can have a compiler
with their message that when you read are useful.
I know that's really surprising for people working on sea. I worked on sea.
But that's possible. We have, we have clean water.
That's possible.
And so,
but, but we are loafing but you can have packages.
That's also something you for. See people,
you can go cow and
-- so your thing and it
-- works.
There is no
like c equivalent of pie, pie or
one for a C++ called
Conan, but it's not well used.
No. And it's a pain for a lot of reason. Part of that is the memory safety. That's
all the discussion. But, but this,
a lot of inac
work was built on sea and not only c but other things
and the thing was bring is not the memory safety stuff.
I mean, it's nice and I, I care about that too, but I care far more about the fact that
the people working on this can get the same
result in less time and losing less sanity.
Well,
it's just using more modern tools like we don't build houses with rocks anymore.
We use hammers
or nail guns or,
you know, 3d printers or whatever
we build far more stable one and faster with that.
Right.
And that's, that's, and that's the point here I'm making is that
I have hope because
rust in itself and I, I have talked with people that have been
pretty close to the rust team at the time and all at Mozilla,
it was what, 10 years
of a dozen people maximum. A lot of them turns a
total cost is probably something around 10 to 20 millions over 10 years.
That's not money I have.
But from a point of view of the impact of the infrastructure, that's a really
cheap price. Yes.
-- Oh, we,
-- my,
my city easily spent more than 10 to $20 million trying out a
new road construction technique for the ring road which let's just say,
uh it didn't work.
And so I'm going to get into a close here, right, which is on my hopes,
which is if we can tell that story
and we can get this kind of story visible,
we can engage on this and we can get work done on this kind of tooling and work to
make everything better from the ground up,
might rebuild this infrastructure and make it bolster it by making it possible for
the people that already I'm already doing the work to do it better.
And the all the reason I have hope is because we already have people doing it.
I mean, it's one
group and it's a really tiny one.
It's the stf right as a sovereign tech fund in Germany. But
we have done so many battles in the past
two decades.
And so I have hope that we can keep building on this
and engaging with policymakers and with the public and by public,
I mean, our public,
our field to make it more visible that the reality of everything you are building
is people doing this on their free time
and there is a lot of them
and you depend on them
and
they use really
educated and painful tools
and
it would be relatively cheap to do that work.
But that's the work we need to do together.
Right. Because no single company will invest in this.
So we have going to have to find ways to organize
both as maintenance and that's really hard because as maintainers,
we don't have time for this.
We already spend our free time keeping the road running.
I mean, that's, that's a sad reality, right?
Do you want, you want me to engage in advocacy? That's, that was the topic.
A lot of the topic at the first them in, in this room around this.
I'm like, great. So I can let a bridge fall. So I have time to come do my advocacy.
That's what you're asking me.
And then everyone looked at me and like,
what do you mean you are not keeping bridge up?
Well, actually, yes, I do. And that's part of the problem.
That's, that's part of the story we need to tell if we want to get progress on this.
Well,
and I mean, the challenge is people won't encounter that unless they are, you know,
like a red hat again, I would work with developers who would say straight up,
like I can fix this in three months when I have a free weekend.
And, you know, as a red hat.
We'd be like, ok, we're gonna fix it and ship it and, you know,
just can you take our patch and we'll, we'll test it and everything.
And, uh,
there's so few people that actually have done this kind of work and interact with it,
interacted with it and understand it.
And like you said, there's, there's no money, there's,
there's no company collecting money that's going to pay for lobbying.
I have a, a very interesting data point that we kind of close it out on is
the Linux
foundation's
budget is like $200 million.
There's money around for this kind of stuff.
It's just, unfortunately,
-- I don't think we have like, sorry,
-- 100 and 77 million.
No, it's, it's 100 and 77 million,
7 million this year.
Last year, last year it was 100 and 77.
I have a few questions for you
is because, um, I mean, the open ssf got how much money for
-- me?
-- I have no idea. Off the top of my head.
It's millions. I know that.
Exactly. Right. Same, same kind of stuff. Right.
I could go the CNCF the cloud native. I don't remember what foundation
got a budget, right. Which is pretty big with, if you look at the money coming in.
Um
Do any of, you know, all this is spent?
No,
that's one thing I specifically asked the Sovereign Tech Fund, uh,
when they came to me and said, you know, do you want to do some work with us?
One of my questions was kind of, what's your overhead?
Like, how much of the X dollars you get?
How many of them actually go out the door to do work versus, you know,
get eaten up internally, running the system.
And they were at a bit less than about 20% overhead,
which is actually pretty damn decent for, especially a small
organization.
Ironically, the smaller you are,
the worse it is because there's just functions you have to do.
But in theory, as they get bigger,
that number should actually maybe even drop as a percent.
But yeah, like looking at some of these other foundations, I'm just like,
yeah, we're like, it's over $100 million a year going out in expenses. Like,
so the thing to keep in mind is
it's not even overhead, right?
It's what is it, what is it invested in because it may not go into overhead, right?
It may just also be these decisions are made.
I was saying, for example, free software advocacy group
manage to have pretty good lobbying and around the same thing for digital rights.
And that's not a bad thing, right? I'm not saying we should take the money.
That's not the discussion we have here, right?
But they manage organized for this
and partially this come from all this kind of money and, and stuff. The Mozilla
Foundation spent quite a lot of money on advocacy for these kind of things too.
And that's a good thing.
Um.
Mhm.
We can't expect maintenance.
And so, so there is a discussion we may also have, which is how do we
make advocacy for maintainers a thing?
Yeah. Right.
And that's where I sit down where I have hope that if we can make that happen,
we will have results pretty fast and we can engage,
people will be interested in what we say.
And we have now the numbers on the proof that these things are here,
that we have an impact.
And if we talk with policymakers,
they have at least in the EU or I know the N A may be a bit different, but at least in the EU
infrastructure is something they understand.
Yep. Yep.
Right. For sure. And so if we can engage and talk with them, we can get results.
And the free, the free open source software is a free software movement,
got results.
There is money being spent every year into
really end user targeted free
software by the EU.
And a lot of it may never end up used for a lot of reasons because it may not be,
it's not easy to market something when you, you know,
market it mostly as, oh, it's freedom,
right? Can I use it?
No, it's fully comp
complicated and we can't pay a designer and we do not
have any users so we couldn't make it user friendly.
Well, we don't use it but it's still here. Right. It exists and it works,
we need to find a way to tell these stories
and that's what I would say is also important for, for security, almost precisely
for
safety.
Yeah.
Yeah. Right. Right.
And, and cybersecurity is a part of that
cybersecurity is part of safety, but safety is larger than that because,
like,
we don't only have cybersecurity problem here.
Right. It's also
really more simple things like, hey, um,
do we have the proper, like, you know, we're talking about, uh there is a lot of
on memory, safe channel. That's great.
But it's not only that, it's also that, oh, the pacemaker crashed,
right.
That's
Right. All
the recently there was a thing, it was a, um, a gli
um
uh
um uh
for diabetes
people, right? People who have diabetes
was and the pump, the incident pump coming for it
would
show you
the wrong number,
right?
By a decimal.
They would, they would have the decimal once once on the, right?
Um, or once on the right.
I'm not sure which one and, but there was a verification, right?
They were showing you what they understood and you could validate the tools, right?
Or not. So
they, they try to push li a bit,
but
that could happen for kind of reasons,
right?
It could be, it's a mistake that could have,
that could easily happen in the UX by just you know,
not buy one on a padding or something like that.
Right.
That's also the reality of people that
are running desperately to keep this running.
Maybe you, you don't know if it did not happen,
lays
down the stack and open the Swiss d
by someone in Nebraska. Right.
Because that's a mistake that can happen. And so when we talk about this thing,
it's not only cybersecurity, it's also the safety of you.
And that's why we end of that's why I think we
need to find a way to do more advocacy on this.
I agree completely.
All right, I'm gonna call this one because holy cow,
what a fire hose of information as always, I love it.
It's
a,
you've ruined the rest of my day because I'm just
gonna be thinking about all of this stuff now,
which is fantastic, but
I want to thank you so much, Tama.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to open source security podcast.com.
We'll put the show notes for the various things Tama talked about and use a Pounds
as podcast. Hashtag on Mastodon, Kurt and Tama
-- have marvelous rest of your day.
-- Thank you. Have a good day
too.
Thank you. Goodbye, everybody.
Thanks, everyone. Bye bye.