Hello and welcome to Episode 62 of the open source security podcast
with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime. Josh Bresser.
Happy one year, Kurt, it has been slightly more than one year since we published.
Episode one,
which I listened to the other day.
Holy cow. It's bad.
-- It's so bad.
-- I can't read anything. I wrote more than about five years ago
ever because,
yeah,
my writing from 1015 years ago is so,
so
funny.
-- But I think it's done in
-- Kruger.
I'm sure that's part of it. And you just, you, you're not the same person.
You were five years ago. Yeah, I read a blog post. I wrote about a year ago and,
uh,
it was embarrassing, I thought, and it's only been a year. I feel like
I, I don't feel like I'm that different from a year ago, but upon reading my writing,
I, I was like, that could that person read?
Like,
it's surreal and, and I guess, yeah, even this podcast, although I will say that
when we started,
we had a vastly inferior equipment
and we,
we didn't know what we were doing
and, and we learned.
And that's one thing I, I forget I was,
I was telling someone about recording a podcast and just kind of doing all the post
and
I screw something up every time and I learn a lesson, right? Like it guaranteed
and, and it's been what, 62 episodes?
And I still make mistakes every freaking time and learn something new.
So, I don't know, maybe by like episode 100
we'll figure it out.
Well,
the thing I really love is that nobody's actually
written down a good like podcasting one on one,
like go by this, you know, microphone, go by, you know, get this software.
Here's the process to edit it together. Here's, here's
you and I still haven't figured out is how to do a really good, more than
two person audio
that's very difficult to do. Well, no, we know how to do it because we did it with Dan.
But Dan, you need uh your gas test to have a certain level of,
I guess recording savviness.
Yeah, that you don't know, he's fine.
But anyway, anyway, let's, but before we get too deep in
-- here, why don't we? Uh
-- Well, I guess the big news this week would be the uh
-- has it been branded yet? I don't think so.
-- No,
no, there's no brand. This is, see, see, this is the problem.
So we're going to talk about Equifax and at the
same time there's a bunch of hurricane crazy going on
and hurricanes have names. So we know it's happening, we can easily talk about
three of them right now.
I know, man. It's crazy.
It's, it's crazy and, and this Equifax thing is just like a total disaster
and it has no name other than, although in this case,
the Equifax thing might be what it goes down as just because it's that big.
But I know it's tough man. And, and I think the other thing we should keep in mind is
this Equifax story, while it is evolving and will continue to evolve,
the fundamental privacy problems around this are eternal and will never go away.
Right.
Yeah.
Oh yeah. No, it's,
it's, it's just, yeah, it's part of how we've architected society.
It is,
it is, you're so right and we did it wrong
this,
-- well,
-- we didn't do it wrong. It's
just, it,
it reminds me of like when you look at, for example,
the way certain businesses and certain technologies worked and it had to
work that way in the past because the technology was limited,
you know, like the way phone numbers work,
right? There's
retarded in today's modern world.
But phone numbers back in the day, totally made sense because you had like a like,
well, you started with humans followed by electro
mechanical switches
and, and the numbers did things in the electro
mechanical switches as you dialed and it would,
it was like literally routing your call as you press buttons and,
and connecting wires, which is crazy to think about.
And, well, I guess humans did it before then.
Yeah.
So, so the Equifax thing, well,
I guess I'll lead off since I'm probably a
bit more annoyed about it than you are because it
might be affected
-- or it might not
-- be
affected.
-- I can't
-- even begin to find out yet.
That's, that, that's a shame. Although it's
not like I know, it's just, this is like the 10th time my identity has been stolen,
so I don't care.
Well, no, no, no, it's, no, it's easy. If you're an American,
if you are an adult in America, you're
affected.
Yeah, that's true. You're, you're affected, guaranteed,
either directly affected or you're going to be affected in secondary way,
probably by a friend or family or something.
I think it's,
it's a guarantee at this point.
I know they have some hokey website where you can sort
of find out if you may get your stuff stolen.
I will say some bad things about that later.
That website seems like like one of those magic eight balls.
No, it's even worse than that.
Good. I'm glad.
All right.
Well, let, let start
beginning and just walk through the whole,
please.
Please
do.
So.
Equifax is, uh, basically it's a credit rating bureau like Transunion or Experian.
And what they basically do is they have data on you,
your name, your social security number, your date of birth where you live,
you know, previous addresses
so that they can basically identify you and
then they also have information on you financially.
So for example, you know,
any past due bills, any outstanding debts,
um, you know how many, you know, which bank accounts where you have them.
Um, for example, lines of credit credit cards,
essentially anything that's like a financial or a debt instrument,
there's a reasonably good chance that Transunion
Experian and Equifax know about it.
And the premise of this is,
uh, so Josh, you, you know, you bought a house, right?
-- Yes.
-- Did you have a bag full of money?
I did not. Unfortunately, the bank didn't.
Yes. Exactly.
And well, then, so the question becomes, how does the bank trust Josh?
Because, you know, this bank's never seen Josh before he just moved there.
Uh Actually I've been using the same bank for like 20 years.
So
try again.
-- But
-- anyway,
but anyway, so the premise is essentially is, you know,
how if I lend X amount of money for some purpose to this person and you know,
how likely am I to be paid back?
Uh, and is that chance high enough that I will lend them the money?
And also conversely, you know, maybe I should increase that rate or not to, to
deal with the risk. So basically these,
these credit rating bureaus
have obscene amounts of information on us.
And by definition, the data they have because of how we've architected society,
this is the data that you use to authenticate
yourself to all the companies you deal with,
either with existing
relationships or ones you want to have a new relationship with,
right? Because
you know, at some point, for example, you know, when at some point,
everybody is a first time home buyer, right?
By definition,
and by definition,
-- most of us don't actually have enough money to buy a home
-- even if you did, don't,
don't,
don't do that get a loan because it
has other benefits to your functioning in society.
So
and so, you know, the the question becomes, you know, how do we,
how do we deal with this? Especially how do we deal with this efficiently?
Now, the beauty is typically the system works quite well.
You know, you phone up your bank, you ask for a credit card and they can
within a few hours typically or days, make a decision about
how
much
credit
you
get.
Now, actually,
unless,
unless you're me
because I've locked on my credit years ago
-- and we'll get to that
-- later.
We will.
So,
you know, it, it the reality is I, I love this system in that it makes
efficient capitalism possible. You know,
I can go get a credit card and go buy a bunch of stuff.
I need that I can't pay for right now,
but, you know, I could probably pay for it later.
Um
That I think that's the wrong story.
With credit cards, the value in a credit card today? I see is
I order crap online.
It gets shipped to me if it's broken or wrong
and the seller I'm dealing with sucks.
I can just call a credit card company and say don't pay that dude and they won't.
-- Yeah,
-- that's definitely part of it.
So, and you know, fundamentally even now when you're applying for a job,
chances are they're checking your credit rating because
let's face it. Right.
The job market is such that when you put out a good job posting,
you're gonna probably get more than a few people applying for it.
And does a company really want to deal with somebody who has financial problems?
The answer is, sadly, no, you know,
they're going to discriminate against those people
because it's just one more hassle.
So anyway, so these, these ratings bureaus have all this information
-- and they sell access to it,
-- right.
We, we are the product, we should also clarify that. Right.
We're, we're not the customers here.
We are literally the product like we are the cattle in, in
this giant farm.
Yeah. And, and it's surprisingly not
well regulated.
I mean, there's,
there's some attempts at it like the Fair Credit Reporting Act in the US where
like you can basically write in and get a free credit
report once a year and you can supposedly challenge what's on it
and, you know, get it sorted out.
It does work. Ok. And thats
it, it
because you've done it.
So I had the experience of I was a contractor
and the company I was working for was bought by
Verisign and
Verisign has a, just a policy that
they run a background check on all all new hires contractors. Everybody. Right.
Uh, through a company called choicepoint, that is
essentially the same thing as experience.
Trans union Equifax except Choice Point has even more data on you
because they buy
all sorts of data from all sorts of sources.
And so they basically do like a seven year background check,
kind of just looking for wonky stuff and
uh being a Canadian, I was kind of like, well, I'm not super cool with this but,
you know, I do like my paycheck.
So I'll agree to it obviously because like, what choice do I have? Right?
I don't have any power in this
uh transaction,
but I would ask that I get a copy of this so I can like,
look at it and make sure it's correct because I've, you know,
heard horror stories about, for example, this one town in Texas, the guy went and uh
accidentally got the death or sorry,
he accidentally got the birth registry when he meant to get the death registry.
And so he accidentally killed off an entire town in an afternoon.
Oh, man, that's exciting.
Yeah, it happens,
you know,
clerical
-- error.
-- What did you do today?
Um
So anyways I, I got the report back from Choice point and by and large it was correct.
It had all my credit cards and bank
accounts on it which as I understand, Canadian banking privacy laws is not
supposed to be in somebody else's hands.
And, but there was this magic weird $500 credit instrument
and it was linked to my main bank TD. So I went to TD and I'm like, what's this?
And like, we don't know, you have to ask them and I went to Choice point and I'm like,
what's this?
And like, we don't know, you have to talk to your bank,
of course you do.
So,
was never able to figure out what the heck that was.
Um, but yeah, so basically in this process, even, you know,
assuming like the Fair Credit Reporting Act works.
It's a lot of work
-- for a consumer. It is,
-- it's a pain in the neck and I'm familiar with that.
I've had to deal with some things before.
Actually when, when I bought my first house, like a million years ago and it,
it sucked getting it all cleaned up.
It took a long time.
Uh, yeah. Yeah. Anyway, anyway, this is so all we set the stage.
We kind of understand what the credit reporting bureau is
or, or these agencies. I don't, I don't even know what they're called.
They, I'm sure they have,
-- they,
-- well, the three typically, yeah, they're like credit reporting.
Bureaus, but things like choice point are even more
kind of in a gray area in the,
give them time
to do
next.
So, anyway, let's talk about Equifax first because
they had that massive breach
and,
and, and the thing
-- and
-- 43 million records,
we know,
I, right. And that's exactly it. I, my suspicion is as this story develops,
-- we're going to learn all kinds of new and terrible things because,
-- well,
we've already learned that it might have affected people outside the US,
-- like in the UK and Canada,
-- I'm not surprised
-- by
-- that.
-- Or maybe it didn't, we're not sure yet. Right.
-- Right.
And they're never going to tell you,
look, let's face it.
Unless your government, like, somehow sues them, they're never going to tell you.
Right.
That's the reality of it because they're going to do.
It's, it's kind of one of those things where
when you think of risk and liability
shut up.
Well,
not yet.
That, that's the thing.
They don't know yet.
They're going to get sued, they know they're going to get sued.
And so they're going to say as little as possible because if they
say too much it's just going to get used against them in court,
which is actually sound advice.
Anyone who may or may not be
involved in
-- court
-- cases do not talk about anything.
It doesn't matter how funny that Joe was on Twitter. Shut up. Right.
And these guys know that because
given everything we've seen, I'm pretty sure lawyers are in charge.
Well, and that, well, yeah,
that goes to part of what they've been trying to do to handle the situation,
how poorly it's been handled.
Oh, my goodness. It's like
you couldn't write comedic gold like this if you wanted to.
I mean, that's the
leave you because it's obviously so horribly poorly written
and
you know,
what else is crazy I think about is with like
all these hurricanes going on at the same time.
Plus just like general events throughout the world,
it feels like everything is literally on fire and it kind of is in some places,
imagine what kind of news and crazy would be coming out of this.
If this was the only major story in the news right now,
it would be horrifying, I bet. So. So and that's something else to think about is
this news cycle is overwhelming
and this story is still enormous just to give you an idea of the magnitude of it.
Like there's going to be less cities in Florida tomorrow than there are today.
And we're talking about
Equifax stealing, you know, someone hacking them and stealing information.
That's crazy, man. That is crazy that this story is even on the list.
So basically Equifax gets hacked, they sit on it for a while.
Uh we'll get into the stock trading stuff later because
there's a whole bunch of stuff going on there.
That's a whole separate
conversation.
Like I said,
you can't write this.
Yeah.
-- So they hired APR firm, the name of which dang it, I lost the link. It
-- doesn't matter.
Apr firm. Right. We don't want everyone to hate us by the time we're done.
And they registered a domain called
-- Equifax Security 2000 seventy.com.
-- Right? And it's nice.
-- They thought ahead because then in 2018 they can just have a new domain,
-- right? So
at
first the domain was registered, it wasn't uh SSL or TLS encrypted.
And the website,
the idea is that you plug in your name and part of your social security number,
if you're American
and it tells you if you, if you have been affected or not, now,
they forgot to disable. Uh Well, the, the, the site runs on wordpress
which not the greatest security record, but whatever, we'll,
we'll just ignore that for sure.
Um But the cute thing is wordpress by default has
a rest API so you can interact with it programmatically
and they didn't disable that. API
And so one of the calls you can make to it publicly
by default is get a list of valid users on the website,
like the accounts created
and there was one account created and it's the name of the pr firm that they've hired.
Not, not a surprise.
Uh So anyways,
the idea being that you plug your name and social security number into
this thing and you get like a part of your social security number rather
and you get whether or not you're affected,
turns out it doesn't matter what you plug in, you get the same result
and so effectively what it looks like is it's kind of a placeholder website just to,
you know, harvest the data so that they can later deal with it.
So I
can't actually, right now,
they can't right now tell you if you've been affected or not.
-- So,
-- my suspicion is they don't really know. But I also had some people tell me that
they typed in things we say
and
not necessarily
some people
-- I think
-- they were sending, I think they were using legitimate information
and
one guy said he was listed as not affected
and his wife was listed as probably affected.
Oh. Right.
-- So that's really interesting to me
-- because I was reading on crib
security that they were just typing in some random verbs and getting back
essentially hang on and find out in a
few
-- days.
-- The only thing I could potentially think of here
is if they were using some sort of very crappy hash
where they take like your name and your number and
-- they hash it and they're checking a database of
-- just,
-- they just have the raw data.
-- But I would hope that
the
pr company doesn't have all of the raw data.
Right.
Well,
anyway, the point is this website is a joke, right?
Let's just fix this website is a joke and it, did you read it?
Apparently the verbiage you waived your rights to a class action.
So they had their default terms of
stuff.
And the premise is that when you sign up for their credit monitoring, whatever
thing
you basically waive any right to sue them or do a class action lawsuit.
Now, they specifically made a statement
specifically saying that they are disclaiming that and that it doesn't apply blah,
blah blah
because, you know, part of it is the legality of that in and of itself is a whole thing.
Like I'm personally quite annoyed that, like, you know,
end user license agreements are a thing where it's like,
basically by opening the software package, you, you can't even sue us, right?
You can't even take us to court.
You have to go through arbitration and like a jurisdiction of our choosing.
Um, you know, we're not even asking you to give up rights.
We're just basically asking you to give up any and
all legal recourse ha ha sucks to be you.
Um,
so, yeah,
ignoring that for the moment because they
supposedly fixed that and they're not disclaiming it
or they're not making you disclaim that. Right.
Assuming that that's even a legal thing to do.
Apparently that's becoming a bit of a political hot potato.
Um, so we've established they were hacked. It's really bad.
Their response so far has been terrible.
They apparently hired, uh, what we call Mandiant security.
To do the audit. And the
because to put it bluntly,
it doesn't appear like they have the expertise to look through their own entire
system to
find
out.
I feel like I read somewhere that,
that Fire Eye was actually the security company
working with them and then Fire Eye hired.
Oh,
fire eye own man.
Yes, that's my understanding. Ok.
That could be uh well,
in regardless the point is for those of you who
don't know Mandy is the guys you bring in like
they are, they are the last recourse, right? Like this is the super ninja
you bring in when things are so bad. You don't know, like the A team, I guess, right?
They are the a team
of kind of doing intrusion detection and, and just figuring out what it went wrong,
um, which to put A B
does it really matter?
Like the
horse is gone, the barn door is wide open.
Their systems are probably architected in such a way that you can't really fix it.
You'd have to like burn it down and start fresh to really get something secure.
-- Well,
-- ok,
it's more than that though.
I mean, part of it is just, I mean,
I've been through these kind of forensics efforts in the past and
a big part of it is just understanding like what happened
and, and not even necessarily so you don't do it again.
-- It's just
-- so you, so apparently the hack was actually quite simple
in this case. That's, that's the really ugly part. Right.
Like, there's, you know, I, if you have like a mission impossible style hack,
I'm like, yeah, cool.
That's really hard to defend against.
It's impossible
to
defend
against.
Yeah.
You know,
if you have an adversary with like a budget
of $10 million who's willing to kidnap people,
-- you lose.
-- Right.
And what was, what was this one? Supposedly?
Although it's not been really confirmed, but apparently
-- a flaw Apache straw.
-- That's what I heard. I'm
skeptical, I don't know.
-- It's,
-- you know, the,
the Apache software foundation actually released a really nice
uh statement.
That statement is ridiculous.
It
-- is,
-- but it points out that essentially either it's a zero day in which case, like,
sorry.
Um, because there is some speculation that it's a CV.
E I forget the name of the CV, offhand. Uh, hang on a second.
-- Ok. No. Well, you're searching this, here's
-- what I
had messed it up and said that the CV was like nine years old or something. It was,
it's been a bunch of different things. Here's the, here's what I think of with this.
All right. Number one,
I don't think struts should have had any comment on
this in any way because we don't really know.
And even if it was struts, like how many,
how many organizations have been hacked because of struts.
I mean, let's face it. Struts doesn't have a very good track record here. Right.
Because it's a Behemoth monster.
And, and more importantly,
I think the most important thing in that Struts
statement though is the fact that at the bottom,
the person who signed it
is the vice president of Struts.
Why does a project need a vice president?
Like, that's not a project anyone should be using?
That's something that needs to be dismantled.
Well, it's, it's one of those,
I think Apache struck is sort of the modern equivalent of Cobalt.
Really.
Think
about it, right. It's a giant
Java monstrosity.
Oh, man, you're, you're absolutely, you're,
-- you're completely correct when you say that
-- it's, and, and the thing is though, like
coal, it,
it does let businesses build things that get stuff done,
I guess, you know, as ugly as it is, right?
Um
But going back to it,
I think they are actually kind of correct to make the statement
because the reality is even if struts was 100% at fault,
this shouldn't happen because,
and this is a question I have for you that I wanted to ask because
uh it kind of reminds me of that whole,
I think it was Lockheed Martin where somebody like ex filtrated like
10 terabytes of design data on some plane or something to China.
And Lockheed Martin was like, oops.
And here's the thing, 100 and 43 million records.
Like I get that high speed networking is a thing now, like 10 gigabit interconnect,
40 gigabit whatever,
but 100 and 43 million records
in a database. Even if they're small is still a lot of data.
They
weren't small.
Yeah. No, I would, I'm guessing tens of kilobytes each
and more to the point, the database activity.
It's like somebody's just like what, you know, where name equals like star
download.
Um You know, how is this
number one? How is the activity on the database? Not notice that? Like,
somebody was like,
accessing everything and number two,
they ex filtrated the data successfully
without like, it's not like Equifax said, like,
oh, they got like X million records but we cut them off.
Thank goodness, you know, because that, that has happened before where, you know,
companies have been like, oh yeah, they,
they started downloading stuff but we killed it.
It's
pretty
bad,
but it's
pretty rare.
Exactly.
And my question is, why is that rare?
Like, I've,
I've heard of strategies like putting in dummy records that trigger your I DS,
-- you know, records that should never be pulled.
-- I bet they
don't have,
I mean, look, if you have an I DS at all, you should notice this kind of activity.
I mean, that's the reality of it. So,
so you can probably infer they almost certainly don't have an idea if they do.
It doesn't work well,
you know, sending out alerts that are being,
that could be true. I see that a lot. That's actually that's something I,
I,
I've seen more than once is people spend all this money on an expensive
I DS and then they don't look at what it's what it's telling them.
And so why did you, I mean,
you might as well just cash that check and go on a vacation.
Well, but especially with false positives and stuff, you can't,
you can't, well,
if you do it right, you can, most people don't do it right.
There's, there's so many levels of failure that had to happen here.
I mean, for example,
the fact that someone could do this tells me
that the data was probably just sitting somewhere,
right? For almost certainly in a database
with no real protections on it.
I mean, look,
let's face it the right way to do this is to have some sort of system architected
that you can retrieve one record,
right?
Someone types in all that personal information they need or,
or what whoever is gonna make a request
and you can get back one record and that's it.
There's no way to get anything else back. And if the system can be broken,
you,
you no doubt have business cases where it's like we want all
the John Smith in Nevada who like have a good credit rating
or, you know,
because the thing to remember is they're not
just selling the stuff for like credit checks.
It's also for like advertising,
like we want a list of everybody who can probably afford a Rolex watch in America.
And, and, and
this would be a data
-- to do that.
-- I suspect
what you've just described is exactly what it is where someone
figured out a way to send a query that returned everybody.
But again, you could have it
obfuscate replies or
no, no, for example,
with the more data you get out sort of the
more coarse grained and fine or less fine it becomes,
-- I
-- will bet you, I bet you a coke
that
somebody ran this query at least once a week on the database on accident
and returned every single human in their data set.
Right?
I guarantee it wouldn't surprise me either if this was actually
stolen from a third party and not directly from Equifax itself.
That's entirely
-- possible.
-- It would not surprise me at all if that
data
and not, not only like to share data, people never get rid of their data, right?
People think data is magic and they,
you have all this super dangerous data and what do you do with it?
Right? Like, oh, we better
keep
it
-- to
-- store.
It's not.
-- Ok.
-- No, no, I'm stopping you right there. Look data.
It is, it is cheap to store crap on disk.
But pi
I is an enormous liability and having the pi I on 100 and 44 million people is crazy.
-- The risk there is enormous
-- storing data correctly and securely is expensive.
But storing it badly and cheaply is
cheap.
I love,
like I just set up some new S3 buckets for a thing and I was going through the
deletion policy and it's like now you can delete
and send it to the cornfield out in Glacier.
Right? Glacier is Amazon's
long term storage thing. And
I seem to remember reading that they like burn stuff onto optical disc
or onto hard drives that they then take off line or something crazy.
I've heard a lot of rumors and the current rumor I've
heard is that they basically have enormous banks of hard drives
and they,
they, they fill them up and when a drive is full, they just turn the power off
and then when they need it, they'll eventually,
every now and then power gets restored and then stuff happens.
That's, that's my current understanding.
I mean, that's the, that's the problem though, right? Is, is until you have
best case scenario you have an auditor come through, who's like, oh,
you can't be doing that, you need to stop doing that and then you stop doing.
Here's the better question.
Were they violating any rules?
Let's say you were someone working with, with these guys with Equifax.
Let's say you accidentally downloaded everyone's record.
Were you violating any sort of rules
tribulation,
violation of any law?
-- Because if you're authorized to do so you're,
-- I bet
they weren't authorized to do so.
And so that begs the,
are there even laws for that for banking data. Like I know with banking data,
you,
-- you have to kind of have a good reason for looking at it typically internally
-- there,
there are certain regulations that exist but they are not.
Yes, it's,
and the problem is, here's the problem I have fundamentally,
this is an American company in American jurisdiction
with data on people outside America.
And so it becomes like the border crossing problem of I try to
go into the US and I have a problem with the border crossing.
What's my recourse like? Right to my Congress.
Actually GDPR is going to fix some of this in,
in the EU because GDPR applies to EU citizens regardless of jurisdiction.
But does the eu have the wherewithal to enforce it?
Well, ok,
that is going to be the question.
However,
most of these companies have some sort of presence in the EU which means yes, yes,
they do.
Right.
Well, because I know like for example,
there's that US banking law that says basically to, you know,
for dealing with tax evasion
that if you have even a single American customer at your bank,
you have to report
like their accounts and stuff to the US
authorities. And so
in Canada that, that is a direct violation of our banking laws
or was
and the US response was, well, that's too bad.
We can cut you off and of course, we, we can't, that's like 30% of our, you know,
fiscal interactions and trade and whatnot.
So we had to roll over.
Right.
And apparently a lot of banks now in a lot of parts of the world
where if you're an American and you go to do something with your account,
they're like, oh, you're American yet your account's closed.
Here's your cash.
Right.
Because, well, no, I mean, you know, think about it,
you're like some regional bank or something.
Do you want to have to deal with us? Authorities?
I would not.
Right. I can't even imagine what the reporting costs on this are.
It's,
you know,
but the thing is the US has the financial clout to like make rules that we don't like,
but
like 80% of Canada's foreign trade is with the US. So like, quite frankly,
we, we, we can't, you know, we can't
be like, oh, embargo, we just don't
talk to you. And
this is actually what's I think going to give GDPR teeth is the eu as a whole
is big enough to have an impact here.
Whereas every individual European country people could be like, yeah,
screw you guys.
-- I don't care.
-- Right.
Is Luxembourg even a real country,
please send the hate mail.
Not me. I love Luxembourg. It's a very nice place actually, I've never been there.
-- I would like to go though. Good
-- French
fries.
Yeah,
sweet.
Ok.
Well, Lichtenstein, for example,
a friend drove me around the country one Saturday morning.
-- Like all
-- around the
country.
Well, technically not around it.
We drove from the northernmost point to the southernmost point and
I think we did the easternmost point or the westernmost point.
I forget what.
And in Europe it's tiny.
It's not like an enormous country like Canada or the United States,
which are just freakishly large.
-- So, anyway, so, ok,
-- so we've gone through 100 and 43 million people,
possibly all American. maybe not,
certainly not Americans in there without question.
Oh, for sure. But I mean,
like, is it more than a percent or whatever,
what else is actually an interesting question?
I wonder how many of the people in there are Children or
dead where they don't really have the ability to gain credit.
The dead thing is still a problem because those records can sort of still work
and the child thing is definitely a problem because, you know,
parents open up lines of credit or
I've heard
in
their
names all the time, which is especially annoying because, like,
you think they would check the date of birth on these people and be like, oh,
you're like three.
Actually, I had something happen once where
I,
my, my kids have email addresses. Right. And I, I get them, but I sign crap up for them
and
one day I get a mail from,
uh, a bank that I have a savings account with, for my kids
and it basically, it is clearly some sort of like crazy fishy spam thing
and I send it to the bank and they're like, oh yeah, we,
you know, this is probably real so that you're so,
and so must have signed up for this and I'm like, this is my kid.
They said, oh well, well, they must have signed up for it.
I said he's six like, ok, we'll take care of it right away, sir.
Yeah,
I mean, come on guys get with it.
But well, and see that's part of this whole thing is like, even if I,
I don't know what the true levels of financial fraud and credit card fraud are,
especially with respect to their cost.
But the reality is
what systems like credit cards.
So like without credit cards, we wouldn't have online shopping and like Amazon,
I,
I now get about one or two Amazon packages a week because I've just,
I've gone to Amazon first.
That's it. I'm done.
I buy this stuff like when I'm in the car with my kids
on the phone and then it shows up the next like the day,
the next day, which is like a Sunday.
I'm sorry, I want to support local businesses, but like
this is just too easy and too cheap and then other things like a great example, right?
Um You know,
going through the house buying process and we have a one week
overlap where we give up possession of this house on the 25th,
but we take possession of the new house on the 18th.
I certainly don't have enough money to cover like
the complete cost of a house for one week.
You know.
And so with bridge financing and stuff, boof, the problem goes away.
You know, the bank and the lawyers do a bunch of stuff and it's like,
I don't know exactly what happened, but like, I have a week to move now.
It's pretty sweet. You know,
the guy that bought this house stomped through
this house two hours after it was listed,
looked grumpy.
And then, you know,
we get a phone call an hour and a half later from our reels were saying like, so yeah,
he's putting an offer on this place does like leaving on the 25th work for you.
And I'm like, I guess it does,
you know,
like my, my partner literally, I was like at lunchtime like, yeah,
so we're listening to the house and then when she got home from work, it's like, uh,
so good news and bad news,
you know, good news is we don't have to work,
we don't have to clean up the place or worry about showing it.
Bad news is you have to like pack all your crap up in the next
-- couple weeks.
-- Go.
I know. I know.
So, I mean, to enable like when I, when I, because I've looked at like,
what buying a house involves in many countries
and it involves saving up all the money.
-- Yeah.
-- There's places have to basically pay for it. It's crazy.
Yeah.
Well,
or there's places like the Philippines where they
just don't have that strong identity slash credit
system.
And so, even with, you know, a modernizing economy,
-- it's just, you can't take that risk.
-- All right. So we're in the weeds
anyways.
The point is as terrible as this Equifax breaches and as
terrible as these companies are what they enable is amazing.
Yes. And that's part of the problem.
There's a whole bunch of people saying, oh, we need to like,
shut down Equifax or break them up.
I
don't know how that's going to work.
And the reality is a, that would actually make things much worse
on so many levels. And b it, it just financially can't happen.
-- I literally can't like Visa and Amex would be like,
-- nope.
Well, here's ok. So here's the better question. Ok.
We're going to ignore regulation and laws and everything around what
they did or didn't do or should or shouldn't have done.
Ok.
I think the real question is the fact
that the identification universe in the United States
is broken
the
-- world
-- too. And
-- maybe, I don't know what the rest of the world is like. I can only speak to the
-- US.
It's the
same in Canada,
but fundamentally
-- most of western Europe.
-- I, I, I'm sure it is.
I don't have a doubt but the point being like, so in the US,
you get a social security number when you're born and
that essentially just has become your national ID number,
right?
I mean, that's what it is. And anytime you do anything
that's what gets used
and we basically reached a point where if,
if someone's social security number leaks
-- you can cause immense damage to their personal.
-- The
real
problem is
how do we authenticate somebody? Well, we need some sort of
either something that they can only
themselves do.
Like essentially like if you had a cryptographic chip implanted in
your brain at birth and only you had that secret key.
Cool.
Um Unfortunately, we're not there yet.
I, I hope one day that we are because I think that'd be awesome.
But here's the problem, right?
How do you authenticate somebody without using a secret?
The
only
thing
is secret biometrics.
Well, no, no, no, we, we do have biometrics. So in theory, you know, this is like crazy
talk but
no, no, no, they don't have to be because if we have a strong
system for actually testing your biometrics that can't be easily subverted.
So for example,
um
I, you come into the bank for a mortgage and I prick your thumb and make you
uh not only sign the contract but put a little blood sample into a thing
and then I, I,
you know, sequence that DNA in real time, which we're basically there, right?
You can actually sequence an entire human genome now
in tens of minutes.
Right. The technology is actually out there, it's just kind of pricey.
And so, you know, without like, for example,
if you've ever seen the movie Gattica with the fake blood in the vein thing,
it would be very hard to fake that out. Now people do fake urine test
all sorts of
stuff. But
the
problem is biometrics is going back to biometrics.
They're way too expensive right now. And
the biometrics that kind of are affordable and work.
There's like a lot of people who don't have eyes or a face or arms and stuff.
Like there's enough people that, that would be like that poor guy.
There was a guy that went into a bank and they, like,
we need a fingerprint and he's like, I got no arms
and they're like, well, you're gonna have to go somewhere else and he's like,
seriously, like, I'm pretty sure like
some legality covers
that to get resolved. I heard about that. But, ok, so here's the first thing
that, that springs into my mind when you talk about
sequencing your DNA on site
is
why not just check to see if I have high risk for cancer and don't give me a loan if I do.
Right.
Oh, yeah. See that's the problem. That would be the other
half of that problem. Right?
Is the private,
-- there's some minor privacy concerns with sequencing everybody's
-- DNA.
And, and so here's, here's the real issue. Ok. Here's, here's the thing.
So I,
I think by talking about DNA or chips and brains or national ID cards or whatever,
you cloud the issue
because those are things that have their own set of problems.
Ok.
Well, fundamentally what happens is how, so assuming we have all these regimes,
like, let's say, for the sake of argument,
we have like an estonian national ID card with a crypto chip in it.
It's super secure, blah, blah, blah.
What happens when somebody loses them? Or somebody gets mugged and rolled
and they literally wander into a police station
with a concussion and like empty pockets.
-- Who cares,
-- just disable the old car and give them a new one?
No,
no, no. What I'm saying is how do we prove that that person is who they say they are?
Uh
Well, I would expect if you're, you, you can acquire other pieces of documentation.
I mean, like,
-- so
-- a
-- good example,
homeless with schizophrenia
-- and
-- look, I'm not gonna, I'm not saying this kind of stuff works for everybody,
right?
There's,
there's without doubt problems
and when you run into someone like say a homeless person with schizophrenia,
you have to have a system that is able to deal with one offs in one off manners, right?
So I know locally we don't have that. What we actually have.
For example, is the Boyle Street.
It's a charitable organization that runs a shelter
will for example, photograph you and basically sign an affidavit saying that,
you know, you are claiming to be this person and here's, it's not photo ID,
but it's like a picture of you with
the signed affidavit from the Boyle Street organization.
And people essentially that's quite often the best thing they can get.
They can, here's the problem.
You can't get a driver's license unless you take a driving test.
So, ok, you can get a Canadian identification card
but you need like your birth certificate or your passport
or your something else to prove it and get it.
Well, ok,
ignoring all that.
How do you get a birth certificate if you've like lost everything? Well,
ok, easy. If you have a lawyer,
right, there's paperwork and stuff to do that.
Actually,
if
you,
you can't afford a lawyer or something, you're
-- right the creek. And
-- so you're completely correct
-- in everything
-- you say.
He ignores all the people that sell their passports and ID cards.
But here's the thing is your,
this is where security fails on a consistent basis
as we obsess over the like five or 10%.
And
when in reality,
there are ways of dealing with those situations,
but the other 90% everything is going to be just
fine for and it's going to work just great.
But instead of worrying about 90% we obsess over 10%.
Well, but for me, here's the thing would,
would actually spending money to fix this
problem actually make this problem better.
Would it outweigh the cost, would there be,
would there be a return on investment?
There's, there's two parts to this and this is where we're,
we're down the wrong path here.
We're not having the right conversation, right?
This isn't about spending money to fix a problem necessarily.
What this is about is the fact that
we have an identification system in the United
States based upon a single nine digit number,
everyone has one
and they're basically not secret, right?
My, my social security number, Kurt has been stolen so many times.
I I'm sad I didn't keep them,
but I would have a stack of letters informing me my social security number
may have been stolen due to some event from a number of organizations.
And I've reached a point like,
you know what my social security number is no longer secret.
So what I did is I locked my credit
in that pin number, which is only sort of secure.
Uh
but that pin number is now essentially my secret identifier
and that is safe.
I don't fully understand the locking the credit thing.
But my understanding of it is is that
nobody can open new like debt instruments until
you kind of give that pin or whatever.
So what happens is it's, it's sort of complicated actually,
I just talked to my sister about this uh yesterday because she's like,
what do I do? You know everything's crazy. I said just lack, lack your credit.
There's nothing else you can't do, lack your credit and forget about it.
But then she also was like, uh, do I have to lock my credit with Equifax?
And I said hilariously, yes. Yes, you do.
But anyway, anyway,
so what happens is you, you basically apply to the credit agencies,
you lock your credit and then they mail you
these letters.
Well, I don't know if they, I don't know, I locked it way back when you first could.
I don't know if they still mail you paper copies, but they did back then
on purpose
and essentially the paper copy has a pin number.
And what you do then is, let's say I want to
uh get a loan or I forget why did I, I had,
I had to unlock my credit for a really crazy reason.
At,
at some point I don't remember what it even
was but like somebody needed to pull my credit
and at first they did nothing
-- and then I let them
-- pull
to pull your credit report.
Yes, for a hard
pull, soft pulls, I guess, are still
possible.
So anyway,
-- anyway,
-- so,
but they could still open a credit card in your name. Whether
it would,
-- it would depend on
-- whether or not they do a poll
I'm getting there.
So here's the deal.
Let's say I want a credit card. Ok, I'll use that as my example.
Go to my bank say I want a credit card.
They're gonna say obviously we need to pull your credit.
And so what I do is there's two things I can do.
I can either tell the credit agencies I want you to lift my credit like from this,
starting this day, ending this day.
And that's what I usually do because I've yet to find a bank that can do the other way,
which is, you can also tell the credit agencies I want you to give me a special pin
for pulling my credit.
And I also tell them who's going to pull it.
So I could say like, you know,
this blah, blah, blah bank is going to pull my credit,
give me a pin for blah, blah, blah bank
and then they give me a special pin which I everywhere I tried to do that.
They're like,
what is this? I'm like, this is the pin to pull my credit. You can unfreeze it.
They're like, what now I'm like,
you're a freaking
bank.
How
-- do you not know that
-- the whole system has these incentives to behave badly
because the bank wants to do it as cheap and easily as possible.
So
anyway, they don't want to be secure unless they have to eat liability.
And in
this
case, they can just
either you get the credit card or you don't, if you want it,
you have to play by their rules.
And so what I do now is, I just like, I,
I tell the agencies like lift my credit on this day and
then I tell the bank pull my credit on this day.
You can't pull it any other day, but this day, so pull it on this day. Ok.
They're like, what are you talking about?
I said, look, just trust me, you can't pull my credit until Tuesday. Ok.
And you can tell they look at me like this guy's on drugs but
it, it's worked.
-- Ok. I actually, that seems
-- reasonable. It's very
reasonable and it works.
And actually what's really cool is where I live.
And I know I know people are going to throw their shoe
at their, their speakers when I say this, but
I have to pay
$10 per agency
to put a lift on my credit. So it cost me $30 to lift my credit freeze for a day.
That's amazing though. No scammer is going to do that.
Right.
And, and additionally, I'm like,
I'm only lifting this if it really matters because I know, like I keep getting the,
uh, I play Delta a lot. They're like, oh, you should get the Delta credit card.
And I'm like, I don't want to pay $30 to get a Delta credit card, you know. So
in some ways it's kept me from making foolish decisions after having, you know,
maybe one, too many beers on the airplane.
Yeah,
but
I've always been amazed that people get credit cards at the airport.
That's just one of those things where it's like,
but
it's like people who buy like
-- those I've seen on TV products.
-- Some
-- of
-- those are awesome, man. I'm not gonna lie.
Some of them are great
but the ones that cost thousands of dollars and
it's like you're buying that based on an ad,
I would never pay more than $20 for anything.
But also the real,
I mean, to me, what it boils down to is that
to authenticate somebody to say who they say they are,
especially in a first time interaction, uh, name, date of birth,
uh, social security or whatever. What really gets me is none of these numbers
or data can easily be changed if at all. Like I can legally change my name,
but
can you legally change your date of birth?
No,
that's what it makes sense. Why would you, you know, you, that, that's insane.
There's no.
Exactly. Exactly.
And, you know, like I did,
it's funny I lost my wallet once in winter in a snowbank in some parking lot.
Great.
And actually a year later I got a call from a restaurant, like three blocks away from
where I'm pretty sure I lost it saying,
yeah, we've got your wallet in our safe. Do you want it back? And I'm kind of like,
uh,
yes, like that's generally how wallets work, right? You want them back,
like, you know, uh,
and but when I, when I lost my wallet, of course I had to phone a bunch of, you know,
I phoned my bank and everything and they're like, yeah, you know,
we'll have new cards for you whatever
you like. No problem. Right.
Um,
healthcare card. Oh, no, we can't change that number.
And our healthcare card here is a piece
of paper that you're not supposed to laminate.
But I always do because
it's a piece of paper
with a number on it in your name. No picture. No, nothing,
uh, driver's license, same deal, you know, got a new driver's license, but
we can't change the number.
Uh, so, like, in that case, that's,
that's probably a failing. Is it a failing?
Should you be able to change your driver's license number?
Well, I just, here's the thing, the credit card number, the bank guys,
they're all like, yeah, you're getting new
credit
card numbers are designed to be changed. And I guess at the same time,
if I lost my wallet,
the only thing I would care about is my driver's license and I
don't know if they would change the number but like my credit cards,
they get stolen all the time
and can't, as far as I know in pretty much any
North American.
Yeah.
And, well, and the thing is like, it's, again, it's supposed to be like that.
So the good news is like, my driver's license number isn't really widely used as
identification of
my driver's license itself. I use all the time, right?
But it's like they look at the picture,
they look at me, it's the same, you know, we're looking to
just made me realize is I have a passport.
And so like replacing all of my ID cards would be
trivial as long as I still have my passport because I can
just show
-- my
-- passport separate from all my other things because
yeah, I can lose my wallet or my passport if I lose both. I'm really up.
Well, no, in this case,
I have my safety deposit box with my birth certificate and you know,
I have
those as well. But
again, you know,
that
a lawyer means not too much of a problem.
Yes.
But again, what you're talking about is really corner cases for the most part.
Right?
-- People lose their crap all the time.
-- They do lose their crap all the time.
But I bet, I bet 80% of people have the ability to
get themselves bootstrapped back up to a point.
They can be functional members of society
and, and some of them can't.
It depends.
For example, like, you know, I,
I deal with a bank where there's one branch I've dealt with since I was 15.
And so they know me by face, right? Like they know me when I walk in
and that's one of the reasons I still continue to deal with this branch in the bank.
-- Because
-- even then, like,
-- they could hire new people or it would be just as easy for the bank to
-- just,
that's why I make the point of going in about once every month or not a month or two.
But every couple of months, you know,
is because, yeah, they do hire new
people
and they remember you once every couple of months, like, I,
-- I see the mailman every day and
-- the older manager type people do.
Right?
-- Ok.
-- You know, and they're, they're there for a while.
Um, but yeah, so,
but the problem is fundamentally like,
unless
you know anything, I'm going to use to authenticate to a company, by definition,
I have to give out to a whole bunch of people to get credit to get a utility
to get.
-- And this is actually where
-- the
store, this crap forever, right? They're not going to delete it, right.
-- They're gonna like, type it in and be like, ok then,
-- but here's the beauty of this,
right?
Is this is where I'm going to talk about
credit freeze as being a brilliant solution to this.
And by the way,
if you're listening and you've made it this far through a storytelling, uh,
freeze your credit, please.
Even if you don't think you need it, you will not regret it.
But anyway, the point is the numbers that identify me,
I can give it to a company.
But by the way,
the credit freeze works is there still a second layer of authentication now.
Right. And, and it's an out of band authentication
because I don't give the company, I'm dealing with my PIN.
I go straight to the agencies, give them my P I
identify myself and then tell them what I want them to do.
And that's really the way this needs to be done. I mean, let's face it.
The solution to all of this exists. It is freezing your credit.
Everyone should freeze their credit. And if everyone had to do that,
all of these problems go away.
Well, a lot of them would, but
there's still a lot of
-- other companies that store a lot of data on us.
-- But who cares? Ok. Ok.
That's a whole another topic.
-- And we can do a whole podcast just
-- like, for example, like to transfer my utilities
and I decided to combine my natural gas bill with like every other utility I have.
So I only have one provider now
and they're like, you know, Mr Siefried,
uh so blah, blah, blah, there might be like a deposit required. And I'm like,
she's like, but you know, if we can I check your billing history to see blah, blah,
blah.
And I'm like,
and
she's like, no, no, I need like you to like say that I can check your billing history.
I'm like, oh, yes, yes, you can check my billing history, right?
Because obviously this call is being recorded
and she's like, Ok. T tap, tap, tap, tap, tap. Right.
And she pulls up my, essentially my,
my billing history and credit history with that specific company and sees,
you know, yeah, I paid every bill on time since like, forever.
So. Ok, no deposit needs great.
Um,
and, you know, and conversely there's people out there I know that, like,
have to put down like $500 deposits
to get gas or, or, uh, you know, cable or whatever because they have like, terrible,
terrible track records.
And what's actually started happening in some cases
is with sort of addresses that are,
you know, typically rental properties,
they'll basically say like, yeah, we know, well,
we think you're claiming to not be this person who used to rent there.
That's cool. Good story. But like,
there's an outstanding bill of like 350 bucks at this address
and until it's cleared, tough.
-- You know,
-- that's, that's rough if, if that's the case.
But when you have like an address where consistently you have
people renting for two or three or four or five months
and not paying their utility bills at all.
It's like as a, what do you expect these companies to do?
Just eat the loss and smile.
Yeah, I mean, that's
-- II, I get it. I understand
-- that.
And that's part of the problem is we've gone to this model of like,
huge hyper efficient companies that, you know, they have statistical models.
They don't know who you are.
But their statistical model has a pretty good idea of who you are
and it says, yeah, we can, like,
sign this guy for like a credit card with all but like no limit.
Just let him go,
you know, dude owns a house, we can take his house. Awesome. You can,
-- you
-- know.
Yeah, apparently.
But, um, and that's, that's fundamentally, it's like,
even if Equifax Transunion and Experian and Choice point and
God knows how many other companies all had like,
perfect data security.
They don't, I'd still,
yeah, I'd still have to be handing out like my,
you know, sensitive information to
these places where if it were ever leaked or copied, then that person can now be me.
No, they can't. Well, ok, they can.
But this is where something like a credit freeze is super useful, right?
It's
there, there isn't a good answer to this today.
And,
well,
my cable company actually just tried to get me to
set a pin number on my account and I'm like,
why?
And he's like, so that basically nobody can like, phone us up and,
and like, pretend to be you and stuff. And I'm like, does that happen a lot?
And he's like, obviously can't, you know, talk about that.
And I'm like,
he's like, oh, if somebody were to like,
call and like order premium services in your name and I'm like, I,
I bet that actually happened
to people with teenagers every now and then
it's probably not a significant threat in all seriousness.
And the thing is with teenagers, how could I possibly defend myself against my kids?
Like, I'm gonna, like, lock up my ID
and never let them near it.
Yeah, we're not going to have that conversation either.
It's just not gonna work.
It's
-- hilarious.
-- It's like those kids who have their identities stolen by their parents.
Uh,
that's a really difficult,
so
that's another problem. And that's, well, it's illegal. Right.
I mean, it is illegal to do.
There's, there's laws against behavior such as that.
Right.
-- It is.
-- But
this is,
this is one thing where, for example, some form of biometrics, like,
even just a picture would, you know, go a long way to making a lot harder.
Um, my favorite always is when you look at some of these fake I DS
and, you know, they, like,
just cut and paste and like totally random other person's facing or whatever,
you know,
or, uh, the case where it's like, you know,
I, I am not like 6 ft seven, like, clearly I'm not 6 ft seven. Like, did you
not notice that?
I'm not 6 ft seven. I'm not even 6 ft.
Yeah.
-- Anyway,
-- anyway, no, it's, I don't know that there's a simple or easy answer,
I think credit freezing and, and by default, you know,
having like a nice little smartphone app that allows you to unlock
-- it or lock it and not have to pay 30
-- bucks.
I want to pay
$30.
Well, ok, it should be hard to do.
You have to pay 30 bucks upfront. And if, uh,
you know, and maybe the company, for example, can say, you know,
here's the password for him to collect his money.
Right. So essentially you put up a $30 bond and then the company,
you know, can verify that you wanted this and,
you know, you get your money back and that
because remember this happened with DNS, right? With the DNS, the Domain
-- and
-- there's places it's free. It just depends on what state you live in.
I, I happen to like that. I have to pay for it because
my suspicion is what's going to happen is after this,
they're just going to make it free
because
by making credit freezing free,
these guys might be able to avoid some level of regulation.
I like how we went to a point where it's like I have all this data on you.
It'd be a real shame if it leaks,
you
know,
for a few bucks
anyway.
Seriously.
-- How is that? Not extortion? Well,
-- whatever it
is.
Seriously, that sounds a lot like extortion.
-- They're gonna offer me credit monitoring if I want it like one year,
-- right?
A free year of credit,
such a good deal.
No offense.
But like as somebody pointed out on Reddit,
-- you can steal an identity and still use that like
-- 10 years
-- and
-- actually
so sort of a tangent.
But there was a thread on Reddit a few years ago I read where it was like, it was a,
it was an ask Reddit thing where,
you know, people have Reddit,
has somebody stolen your identity and kind of what happened.
And this one guy is like
my social security number name and everything was stolen by an illegal immigrant,
but they've totally improved my credit score.
That's great.
So he's like, I don't know who this guy is, but like,
he's like my credit score is like 200 points better now because
he has like a credit card and this other thing in my name
-- and he like, pays his bill religiously and I'm like,
-- that's hilarious.
That is hilarious. So actually the real person is ruining the life of the
uh identity thief.
Yeah, that's brilliant.
That's great.
You know, but, and that's the thing, right? Like, how do we? Yeah, I mean
this, this whole, I don't know, it just, the more I think about this,
the more it really does seem like extortion.
Like I'm going to keep all this data on you
and like for, you know, a few bucks I can maybe like, try not to leak it so much.
Yep.
I, I
don't know, man,
-- this is
-- ok. Well, so ignoring all this,
here's the beauty of
let's why don't we go to the really juicy saucy part of the story,
which I think will get even worse.
So, two things. Stock trading, right. We see here's one of the things, right. Like,
I think part of the problem is how do
you actually monetize 100 and 43 million records?
That's like, so much that, like,
you'd have to sell them at some.
Yeah.
How do you monetize that data? Right. Like, it's so bulk, it's like we are selling
like a million records for like $10. I don't know.
Like, I like bulk pricing on that kind of data.
You know, it's half of North America at this point.
It's
gonna be,
yeah, it's like, oh, we just,
yeah, we robbed Fort Knox but ok, now what?
And yes, I heard that, that the executives sold their stock, what,
like four days before the story hit, which is, come
on guys, it's insider trading.
Well, unless it's a
scheduled stock disbursement
thing where, you know, they do this every six months or a year or whatever.
But no, no, no, that's not the juicy part. It's not even close to the juicy part.
That's boring.
What's really interesting. Equifax stock trading is
very minimal. It's very boring. Right. There's
only, it's got, it's a very thinly traded
stock in the sense of there's not like a high volume every
date
and there's especially not a high volume of options so quick. One on one for options.
The stock market basically has sort of what most people
know about is you can buy and sell shares,
right?
Shares are selling at some market price of say $27 and you can buy, you know,
you make an offer of $27.01
and of course somebody will probably be like sweet, I just made a penny, you know,
and sell you a million shares
and conversely, you know, same for selling, right?
You're selling shares and you,
you price it up market price for a penny below and everybody's like, oh, awesome,
great.
You know,
there's also options and options are essentially a contract that either
a put or a call that allows you to either have
the option of selling or the option of buying shares
on a certain date at a certain price. So for example, I can buy an option
saying I will, I will have the option of selling, say
10,000 shares of F
Corp at a dollar.
Uh And then when that date rolls around, I can choose to exercise it or not,
I can either do it or don't do it.
Um,
the counter party to that,
uh,
has to do it. Like if I decide to sell our share, um, or, you know, uh buy, right?
That's, that's what I'm paying for, right? So
somebody bought,
uh what was it? 100 and 60,000 options
of Equifax
to sell
at, uh I forget the exact price, but it's
um, a little bit below what the stock was currently trading
before the breach.
And here's the thing. So those are what are called in the money options
in that essentially normally given normal behavior of the stock.
It, nobody would care because basically,
like the stock trades for the sake of argument between 131 $140
and somebody bought a bunch of options to sell or sorry to buy the,
or to sell the shares at 100 and 30
like no big deal, right? Like it,
chances are those options aren't going to be worth anything
on that date because that's kind of the normal trading range
and this person wouldn't be able to make any money.
And then there's what are called out of the money options where it's like,
say the stock trades between 100 and 30 100 and 40.
And you know, I, I want, I want to
buy the shares
to the
point,
somebody bought 100 and 60,000 option at 60 cents a piece. Roughly
that are now worth about $4 million
because they basically bought the option to sell these shares at this given price.
Normal trading activity on this
on Equifax for these options is like
tens of contracts per day
and somebody bought thousands of these in a single day
just around the time of the breach.
Yeah, but look, you can't buy stock,
this isn't Bitcoin. I mean, the sec knows who did that and they're going to go,
right. Like it's quite
like
this.
-- Right.
-- Well, that's what confuses me about.
This is, this is one of those cases where,
uh, if there was enough volume you could hide in the herd.
Right?
Like it was a, it was a very busy stock, I'd say Microsoft or something
here. Like
you're proving the point,
the SEC will have to investigate and somebody's going to get nail power
and that's the part I don't get is
somebody sophisticated enough to steal this data and do the stock trading.
They showed the chart and there's basically like, every other day is flat.
It's like the, it's like a one Pix
high bar
and then there's the day that this
entity brought all these
options.
Reality is it's probably just some idiot who caught wind of this and they,
they thought they were going to make a buck and the SEC is just
going to find him and throw him in jail for like five months.
And, and that's what it's going to be. I doubt this is nefarious because
let's face it. Like
the, the entire financial industry is designed to make this hard to do.
Well, the one theory is that it's insider trading based on the Equifax information,
which
-- totally illegal, they're going to get nailed.
-- Well, sure.
That's exactly what it is, right. Guaranteed.
Well, or it's the bad guys. But again,
this is the bad guys
because
it's too obvious
No, it's not the bad,
whatever, but
interesting
to see this activity regardless because it's obviously
like when you look at 30 days of graphs, this is the only activity of.
-- No, it's,
-- it's crazy town.
All right, man, we've been, we've been dragging this one out for a long time, I guess.
Here are my, my closing thoughts on this is,
I'm not surprised this happened.
I am pleased.
Normal people are starting to pay attention
and I think the reality is freezing your credit
is not only the right thing to do today.
It's probably the easiest long term solution that actually makes this,
we'll say less important, right?
I mean, now I I will say though,
here's the
question.
No, no, here's, here's the real question.
Did the attacker get my credit freeze ID number?
My P
if they have that,
I'm screwed. Right.
Well, yes and no, because you're part of such a big vulnerable herd of people,
hopefully
be safe. But you get the point,
you get the point is uh and,
and that might be that if that information comes out in the next couple of days,
that would make the story huge,
-- right?
-- So here's my thinking on this.
So from the supply side,
obviously buying somebody's identity online is like trivial,
especially now that there's 100 and 43 million more of them.
So on the demand side of the people that can actually
take this data and turn it into cold hard cash.
Does this actually give them a
-- significant benefit?
-- Probably not outside of what they already had.
I mean, let's face it
because, yeah, I can't imagine like, these people are lacking for records when you,
because, like, every single data breach,
it seems like in the last four or five years,
you know, we went from like, oh a few 1000 to a few tens of thousands to now, like,
it's just millions, every single, you know, major one is,
-- it's
-- not a story if there aren't at least
100 million breaches or 100 million records anyway.
Anyway, uh, I guess, yeah, whatever.
What, what are your, what are your closing thoughts here?
My thoughts are
nothing will significantly change.
There will be some, uh what's the English expression?
German Storm and drama, like basically Storm and drama.
But will we see good new, will we see new regulation?
No
good regulation?
-- Look,
-- let's
face
it.
The government is locked in
a stalemate of effort proportions unless basically half of the
Senate has their identity stolen and actually used an identity.
Nothing will change
even then I don't know if it would.
Yeah. So I suspect nothing of significance will change or happen.
A whole pile of people.
-- Here's what I mean, a whole pile of people will freeze
-- the
credit.
Well, screw the revenue. Just good job doing that.
Like you should be freezing your credit if you're not freezing your credit, go do it.
Go do it right now. Right.
Stop the podcast.
Go do it
apart from the hassle of dealing with this.
Has anybody really ever been out the money from identity
theft in this kind of thing by and large?
You mean out the money?
Well, you,
you talked about this in a previous
episode where it's like suing somebody for identity
theft is really hard because you would have to prove some sort of loss.
I doubt it.
And I get that it fucks to have to spend tens or hundreds of hours dealing with like,
no, I'm not debt or
no, I don't own like 17 houses. Like, can I please have a mortgage,
you know,
47 credit cards?
I don't know.
But actually being on the hook for that money,
it
-- seems like in most cases it's pretty easy to disprove.
-- It's not
easy. It's like you said at the beginning of the episode, it does take a long time.
It's doable, but it's tricky.
That's what I mean. It's, you don't need like an OJ Simpson style lawyer.
Like you can, you just need to go file paperwork
pretty much.
So, it's,
I think you're right.
I don't think, I honestly, at the end of the day it's a crazy story,
but really it's, it's not gonna matter.
I,
I imagine we're just going to be talking about
the hurricane more than this in six months.
Yeah. Well, in a financial sense, I mean, Houston being flooded and
I was gonna say Miami, but at this point, I guess we'll just go with Florida.
Um Florida being flooded.
You know, the, the,
the cost financially insurance claim wise and
everything on that is going to make this
-- not even be a rounding error and,
-- and we could talk about insurance and risk
and, and maybe the next episode because there's some fascinating overland
flood insurance. There's
a, there's
a
people
anyway, anyway, when there's some things that have been happening around
building codes that they've kind of become lax because they were like,
it's not that bad.
I like, well, guess what it is.
But anyway, anyway. All right, cool. Thanks, Kurt.
Thank you everybody for, for listening.
If you want show notes or links to the Facebook group or Twitter,
go to open source Security podcast.com.
Be sure to hit us up on Facebook or Twitter with, with comments. We love comments.
So by all means, let us know, I guess nothing else.
-- Kurt, you have a fabulous rest of your day.
-- Thanks.