Hello and welcome to the open source Security podcast.
Episode 50 with myself, Curtsey Fried and my partner in crime. Josh Bresser.
I think you mean this is episode L
I agree in principle, but nobody knows.
Oh,
speaking of, nobody knows.
I wore my reading Rainbow t-shirt to my kids' school the other day.
-- Is that a Minecraft
-- shirt?
What,
-- what does it look
-- because it's got like an eight bit.
It's, it's, uh, I did,
I participated in the Reboot Kickstarter for reading Rainbow, right,
a few years ago
and they had this really nice sort of eight bit pixel art of level of armor, like,
you know, leveling up like,
you know, anyways with reading
and, but three of the kids did know what reading Rainbow is. Thank goodness.
But the majority of them thought it was Minecraft related.
Of course
I did. It's,
-- that's the only place they would have seen pixelated graphics. I kind of get
-- it.
-- You know.
-- That's,
that's
a
good
-- point.
-- It does please
me though, that my Children call them eight bit graphics,
which brings a smile to my face.
That's right. I bet they don't know why they call it that though.
They do not.
So we don't
-- like, I still
-- use like,
do you like when you are in a youtube video and you want to go forwards or backwards?
What do you say? Do you want to go forwards or backwards? Do you want to rewind?
Do you want to fast forward?
See, fast forward still makes sense in that context,
but rewind makes absolutely no sense anymore.
-- It's
-- why is the save
icon a floppy disk,
right?
Because quite frankly, what are we going to replace it with?
And, and that's kind of how it works, right? Is the notion of rewind.
Well, obviously, it initially meant
tape
it no
longer
physically, rewind
it and, and, but there's, there's, I'm sure there's plenty of other words
that are just like this. It started out with one meaning
and just kind of evolved with society.
But anyway. All right.
So episode L uh L is Roman numeral 50 for those of you playing along at home.
Uh I also speaking of the Romans,
I looked up some interesting facts about the number 50 because why not?
And it turns out that that in the year 50 ad,
the Romans learn to use soap from the galls,
which seems like a crazy thing. Like you had to learn to use soap,
they use
olive oil. Although I know some people who need to learn to use soap so I can relate.
What's even more amazing to me is the the,
the Romans used olive oil and this curve stick that I can't remember the name of.
But essentially they would put a li like,
they would basically cover themselves in a little bit of olive oil,
get all greased up essentially.
And then use this curved stick to like, scrape it off.
And so they, they actually tried this out, like, you know,
it was a documentary on this,
they tried it out and it actually works really well for getting you clean
and it doesn't feel, apparently, feel nearly as disgusting as you would think.
And then the best part is, here's the best part.
The essentially that oil would, you know, take all your body odor with it.
So the Gladiators would sell this stuff.
I've heard that, that, that Gladiator sweat was considered magic.
That's great.
Anyway, this is disgusting.
Yeah,
-- let's, let's move.
-- The problem is we both probably watch a lot of Q
I,
I do not watch Qii, I don't know. IQ I isn't all right.
Number one, I barely watch any TV.
And Q I
locally
I don't watch a lot of youtube.
Well, when I do watch youtube it's usually video game videos.
So I'm, I'm not gonna watch Q, I, but I'm familiar with many of the topics.
It, it's a good show. Don't get me wrong.
It's just, it's, it's not convenient enough. I'm lazy.
Like if it was on Netflix, I might consider it. It might be. I've never found it.
But anyway, um,
I must say there's one other immense travesty that's
going to happen very soon is in the US.
Futurama is leaving Netflix on July 1st, which is
like, ruined my life.
I
wonder if it's leaving in Canada.
I, I,
I rumor hands that apparently Fox is trying to start their own streaming service.
That's just what I need. I need 50 streaming services. Right.
That's totally what I want.
Uh I get why they're doing this because that is their mindset, right?
We have the content
but the problem is, it's like that was the mindset of Blockbuster
how that work out.
I
granted Fox has a little bit more of
an entrenched position because they actually own content
-- that people want,
-- but they don't have enough content. Look, I love Futurama
but I'm not, I'm not going to sign up for the Fox streaming service just for Futurama.
That's like CBS is doing this with, there's a new Star Trek series coming out
and
yeah, I,
you know, I don't know, I don't think it's retro, I think it takes place in the
future of existing Star Trek
but
in the NG or
I
think I don't, whatever, I don't remember.
But anyway,
the idea was they expect people to sign up for their streaming service.
And I'm like, I, I'm just not going to, I'm going,
I don't care enough to sign up for your streaming service.
I just don't,
you know, it's funny because even if it was like,
let's say, for the sake of argument, $12 a year,
how do you get it? Like, is there an app for it?
Does my Apple TV support it if my Apple TV doesn't support it. How do I watch it?
I,
I would hope that it's supported by these TV s
but it's gonna be probably closer to $12 a month
-- and, well, but more
-- to the point if I don't have an app to watch it,
how am I gonna actually watch it?
That's what these guys seem to forget.
-- Let's,
-- we'll,
we'll assume there will be an app because I think
they're at least clued in enough to do that.
Right.
But my point being basically is like with all the stuff like Roku Apple TV,
S and all those, they basically, you know, they support a lot of things but,
you know, you better hope Apple plays more is willing to play with you otherwise.
Yeah, I mean, you don't get on that device. You're dead in the water.
See, and that would be my fear of starting a streaming service now is like,
how do you get enough device coverage to make it worthwhile compared to say Netflix?
Because these are short sighted people who don't know what they're doing.
It's, you know, you know,
it always reminds me of and this is so true even in security world where
people think something's really easy
and then it turns out, hey, those guys who told you it wasn't easy. Yeah.
Maybe they knew what they were talking about after all.
Well, yeah, there's that XK CD comic for it, you know, like,
right,
I mean, some of these,
you know, I, well, I had somebody sort of offhandedly asked, like, you know,
what is the guidelines for certificate lifetimes?
I'm like, oh,
you really want me to answer that? Like, really? You want to go,
there we
go
there. But they want you to give them a number one number
and that's all
that's
probably fair.
Probably should have said 92 days because then you don't,
you can only do it every quarter.
-- You should
-- have said 92 years and then they don't have to worry.
Well,
I've actually,
I've created a new P GP key that does not expire
and I will be rolling over to it this year.
Yeah.
My,
my old key expires in about four or five years.
So that's kind of really annoying.
Yeah.
No, I understand.
And, well,
in P GP is one of those things that
if I was doing something legitimately exciting with it,
I would be very particular about
maintaining my key and, and changing keys and all kinds of things like that.
But the reality is I do,
I basically use it to log in over ssh and to do get pulls. So, you know what I can,
I can deal with a key that doesn't expire.
Yeah.
Well, and it's not like a, you know, it's not like milk where it
actually expires.
I mean, you know,
unless you've got some absurdly short key or
something and somebody actually wants to attack it.
But, um,
yeah,
and
my thought, and my thought on the certificate, lifetime thing was,
it was actually less about sort of the act,
like I'm less concerned about the day to day security of like, oh,
somebody compromises the certificate and then uses it for like,
90 days without us finding out and some bad things happen.
And I'm more concerned about actually, you know, having
like, certificate rollover
processes that work and like having it, you know, basically,
if you have to do something quarterly, chances are, you're probably, well,
you should notice pretty quickly that it doesn't or doesn't work.
That's a really good point
actually.
And, and you're right, you're gonna
have
every month.
That's why I reboot my systems every month is to
make sure they actually come back up if the,
if they get rebooted.
Right. So when it happens,
sort of outside of my control, chances are it'll actually come back.
My file server in the basement is, has been up 700 days now.
I hope it reboots
me
too.
That's all I keep thinking is like,
thank goodness the UPS is still working because I, I don't,
I don't ever want to turn it off if I do.
Well, I actually I had one machine, I rebooted, it rebooted fine.
But one of the fans actually seized,
it was sold, you know, like
one of the fans when it stopped moving, I guess it just, it,
it didn't start again.
I, I believe that
that's, I mean, these are mechanical pieces. Well, think about it.
We're running consumer grade hardware and in some cases I,
I've looked at the dates on these machines.
I write it on the inside. I mean,
these things have like $10 fans that have been running nonstop for like seven years.
-- I think about that a lot. Yes. And it's
-- very impressive
and,
and the machine I have in the basement actually is like comically old at this point.
And the hard drives are, I've had both.
I, I've, I've got, what, four hard drives in it, I think.
And I know two of them are at least five years old
and, and I think one might be even older than that. So
the day is coming
in my defense, I have meticulous backups of this data
and I, I have little considered
the
three.
So I
have
as part of it and I keep
diss I, I have a disk I also use because I figure what I would do is sync off disk first,
an external drive.
Yeah, like an external hard drive that,
that when I remember I'd like to say once a month,
but when I remember I go plug it in and in our sync
and I figure I can probably R sync that and then pull down the last,
probably 1020 gigs of S3 to just fix it.
Yeah.
But,
yeah, that's my biggest concern is, well, you ran into that.
It took you how many weeks to upload all your data?
It took me more than a month.
Yeah, exactly.
A
hard drive.
Yeah, pretty much. I mean,
that's where I am with doing an off site backup right
now as I've gotten to the point where it's like,
uh, unless I get a new provider, like they're
supposed to be, I'm supposed to be getting fiber at some point in the next year.
They redid all the poles.
Well, no, they redid all the utility poles and moved the power lines up about 4 ft.
Right. So they actually had to replace a whole pile of infrastructure,
uh, before they can run fiber out to the, you know, houses out here.
-- So
-- they're hanging fiber in the air.
Yeah, it'll be fiber in the air.
Basically the exact same physical path as like your actual phone line.
Like your copper phone line. Right.
You know, it's a triple, it's a classic triple play from the phone company. Right.
Your, um,
uh, what is it? Your voice TV?
And internet, you know, over one line fiber fast, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Um,
and hopefully in the next year or two, I'll get it because the main thing is like,
otherwise my upload is capped unless I buy like
the biggest plan at like 15 megs per second.
Nice.
I, I don't even remember what I have. It just took a long time. All right.
Anyway, we should move on to, like, this is a security podcast effort.
So, any more
interesting facts? About 50
I know.
Well, I guess the one that,
that you'll probably like is apparently on Canadian roads with,
without posted speed limits, the speed limit is 50 kilometers per hour.
That is correct.
Which is what, like, 30
-- miles per hour.
-- It's a hair over 30 because it's 1.6 kilometers per mile.
So it's like 3132 miles an hour.
So, anyway, let's, uh, maintaining the topic of Canada as well.
Did you see the picture of the guy mowing his lawn with a tornado in the background?
Yeah, that
-- was quite
-- classic.
That's like risk management 101 right there, folks.
And I love this
was what I'm keeping an eye on it.
Well, it's funny because in Edmonton we had the tornado back in, oh,
I was actually supposed to look this up for my son Edmonton tornado.
Uh, we had a tornado in Edmonton back in a tornado.
87. Yeah. So I was 10 years old.
Um,
in, in what, that was like the last tornado you had other than this one?
No, this one was in Calgary. That's like 400 kilometers away.
So,
yeah,
but that's the thing. Right.
Tornadoes are rare enough that it actually has, like, its own Wikipedia
and it's an underscore tornado. Right.
We just generally don't get tornadoes around here.
It's, that's just it. Right.
And then, you know,
part of the problem is that's why everybody was
so freaked out about it because it was like,
it's really never happened before or since. Right.
Um, and it actually did cause, yeah, here, yeah, I killed 27 people
and destroyed 300 homes. So, you know, it was actually,
-- it, it mattered. Right. Like, it was a bad tornado.
-- This is the one when you were a kid.
Yeah.
And,
um, but like I said, like,
it's known as the Edmonton
tornado
-- singular. Like, it's that one time back in the days.
-- Oh, man. You know, it's awesome.
So, yeah, tornadoes are rare enough here that we generally don't
think about or worry about them that much.
I guess that that might be part of the problem and,
-- and I'm going to bring this back to security, a black
-- sheep or
a
swan event.
-- Right.
-- Exactly. So, like you're a dude mowing your lawn, you see a tornado and think?
Oh, that's neat because you don't understand how dangerous it is.
And this is totally, like,
when you've got security people who they see an anomaly
going on in their infrastructure or whatever and they think,
oh, that's neat because they just don't understand the gravity of the situation.
What happened with him?
There was a guy out on a farm who basically was photographing it
and then he realized all the clouds were moving around him
and that's when he realized, oh, I should go in the basement. Right.
But again, you know, like, I mean, I wouldn't,
you know, most people wouldn't pick up on that out here because,
like,
well, like in a lot of the US, you guys have tornado drills and stuff, right?
And you have, oh, I mean,
at the Denver airport they have tornado shelters in the airport,
right? They both signs
and
I've never seen that before.
You know.
So
actually, you know, it's really cool.
You bring that up and,
and to change the subject briefly is I was taking a walk in town the other day with,
with my son
and he says, dad, what's that sign?
And there was a fall shelter sign on the side of a building.
Yeah, I'm like, that's, I, I took a bunch of pictures. I said this is great.
He's like, why are you taking pictures of that?
I said, because you don't see a lot of these anymore, you know,
then he asked what's a follow up shelter and we ended up, you know,
talking about
Russia.
So
that's ancient history at this
point for them.
Uh, yes. Yes, it is. It's true. I could have just talked about the Romans and
too
much. I mean, World War One would have been the same.
Seriously.
I know I've often thought about that. Right.
Because what was taught is historically relevant and when we went to school versus,
like, what's historically relevant now,
you know?
Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah.
Well, it's like anything, I mean, and, and
every generation
for either forgets or chooses not to carry knowledge forward
and, and in some ways it's good in some ways it's bad.
We'll,
we'll see what happens in the context of
security since we barely even have tribal knowledge.
Well, we keep recreating,
you know, we keep, well, people keep rediscovering like a great example.
Multi-tenant systems are hard. Well, guess what mainframe
and then guess what the UNIX guys discovered
and then guess what the internet guys discovered and
then guess what the web browser guys discovered and then
now guess what the container guys have discovered?
Oh my God. When you let
people touch each other,
-- you know, it gets really messy really fast
-- getting PG 13,
you know,
and, and like, well,
this kind of goes to that pseudo thing like that pseudo security flaw where you could
like go monkey with another user's TT Y and see what they were doing potentially.
Well, that's a great argument to like containerize all this stuff and just like,
look here, you log in, you can pseudo you can do it within your container.
You cannot,
you have a different like dev
name space than that other guy
or whatever, you know, and you just can't monkey with each other.
So, you know, temp flaws, not our problem, you know, things like,
um,
I mean, do you remember it was what, probably 5,
10 years ago when temp flaws were just, it was awful.
They still are, they still are.
But I don't think anyone cares anymore because now they
just, like, run a VM or a container. Right. Go.
Well, a great, I mean, part of it is the whole concept of shell services has gone away.
Remember when, you know,
I remember paying five or 10 bucks a month for access to a shell server,
I remember shell and that was like the best
part about college is there were shell accounts everywhere
and I didn't have to pay anymore for shell access.
Like I just had shell access and I was,
-- that
-- was a big deal.
And now, I mean,
uh
you could get a VPC for five bucks a month
without
even trying to shop around for a deal
or just get a raspberry pie for
$5 and put it in your basement.
I mean, it's,
well, that's the other thing, right?
Everybody has always on internet connectivity because you don't have to worry
about your mom picking up the phone and interrupting your doom download,
which by the way, I'm not angry about,
but I'm just going to say that that's a memory of my
-- childhood
-- 16 hours in. Right?
-- Well, and you know, not every B BS had like reget capabilities.
-- I do remember that.
There were,
there were some that did not and it was
terrible when you were downloading your one megabyte file.
But, uh, yeah, I mean, it's just these things are, you know,
it's like worrying about not having, well, all those old timey movies.
Where does anybody have a phone?
Right.
That's true.
You know, quick call, somebody call the cops.
Oh my God. There's no phone.
Go find a pay phone or,
or like literally somebody having to go run to find a fire pole station,
which for those of you that don't know what that is.
It's literally a physical box with a physical handle,
like a fire alarm that you pull and that lets the fire department know that that fire
handle was pulled and then they would go there and then ask you where the fire is?
That totally scales.
Yeah.
Anyways. But uh
yeah. So,
yeah, I don't know the whole, yeah, people forgetting the,
the lessons of the past and I think it's even
not so much forgetting the lessons of the past,
but forgetting the problems of the past.
I, I have a great lesson of the past.
So as, as many of you are aware there was recently in an attack,
a terrorist attack in London on, on the bridge.
And what's the first thing their prime minister does blames
encryption and says we should ban encryption and put backdoors in
that
this is never going to die. I feel like someday we're going to be old men
and the politicians are still going to be talking about encryption backdoors.
I
think part of it
is, I suspect, well, it's a multifaceted issue and I think,
I think some of the big components are number one,
these politicians fundamentally don't understand it.
The reality is like my bathroom scale has strong encryption.
That's true. That would have been illegal to export like 10 years ago.
Yeah, exactly.
Uh Number two
even, you know, ignoring that you have the whole open source angle.
Like everybody has
uh how many copies of the open SSL libraries are there on the planet
a lot?
Well,
that's exactly it is. Even if
they wanted or, or let's say,
let's say these politicians convinced some of the big companies
that they need to
backdoor the encryption or they need to weaken the encryption.
Well,
heck we heck the US weakened encryption back in
the nineties and look where that got us.
But anyway,
let's say they say you need to do this stuff and let's say those companies comply.
Do you think the bad guys are going to use
that stuff or do you think they're just gonna download
or even write their own algorithms
that, that have strong encryption? Right?
One argument the politicians would make there is,
it's kind of like the whole banning VPN S like there's some of
those countries where they've successfully banned
VPN S because largely to provide,
you know,
the incumbent telephone operator with the ability to generate revenue still.
Right.
You know, so they've banned things like Skype and then obviously had to ban things
like,
well, no, no, no. But basically the, the problem is the bad guys.
Yeah,
the bad guys can make their own crypto and the politicians argument would be like,
oh, well, we'll detect that and know that these are bad guys and we'll go arrest them
or whatever, right? And that's just not gonna work.
I would argue even in the countries that have banned VPN S for whatever reason,
there are still people using them
and all you end up doing is hurting the normal people
because the people who have a reason to do that,
they will still do it. They will find a way.
And I think that's what you just said is fundamentally part of the problem is,
I think this is less about encryption and more about hurting
the normal people controlling them to some degree or making their,
you know,
being seen to be doing something that the normal
people don't really understand is kind of pointless,
you know, or, or a fool's errand, right?
It will be,
it's the goalkeeper's dilemma, right?
You have to be seen to be doing something even if it's meaningless,
you know, talking about meaningful things when Theresa May, you know,
was secretary, uh what was it?
The home secretary, which is essentially, you know, the interior ministry
that she cut back, police,
you know, funding and, uh, what was it? 20,000 policemen got cut and,
well, yeah, I mean, that's, that can't be helpful.
It, it,
it's such a weird act these politicians put on because, I mean, let's face it.
It's all just a big game. Right.
They, they're always shocked at something in reality, you know.
Yeah, you've done that before.
But it's things like encryption is bad.
You know,
we don't want that because the bad guys can use it and oh protect the Children and oh,
we need to cut the budget.
So let's get rid of these things that aren't. And it's just, it's kind of madness man.
And,
and I think this is one of the things that just irks me
and I, I even see this
outside of politics
is where you have a group of professionals that like
these are people who actually know what they're talking about
and nobody listens to them.
And it's just like the, the story of humanity is that
where nobody listens to the guy who knows what he's talking about.
Like every,
every single legend and folk story is people not listening
to the guy who knows what he's talking about.
And the lesson at the end is listen to the guy
who knows what he's talking about. Yeah, like it will never change.
Well, you know, I have that problem right now with one of my sons, he's like,
we're like, maybe you shouldn't do Xy or Z, you know,
like play with your fidget spinner right next to
your ipad because the fidget spinner has a big,
you know, has metal in it.
And if you smack your ipad screen with that, you're gonna be sad.
And it took a good 23 minutes of talking to him to kind of convince him that it
really was maybe not a good idea to play with this fidget spinner next to his ipad.
-- You know, things like
-- that,
let him break it
-- and he will learn his lesson. Then
-- I have to pay for it.
No, you don't.
You tell him to go get a job there.
It's a little tough for a six year old to get a, a,
you know,
-- job.
-- Don't you have coal mines in Canada?
We do? But they're mostly open face with, you know,
-- automation.
-- I
know
it
anyway.
Well, you know that and there's a great example, right?
We got to bring it back to the coal industry and the coal jobs.
And it's like what R B's in the US is a bigger employer than the entire coal industry.
-- Actually.
-- You know what's funny is you bring this up?
And I was listening to a podcast just the other day
and it was somebody talking about manufacturing and the fact that
exporting jobs to other countries isn't the problem
apparently back in the fifties and sixties,
there was something like 16 or 20% of jobs were in factories
today. It's 7%. And we're producing like, four times the output. We were back then.
People used to be farmers. Now.
It's like 1.5, I think
now, like one dude with the tractor can do the work of 400 people.
-- Yep. Yep. Oh, totally. It's exactly the same story.
-- Yeah.
No, we were driving out to the cabin and we saw everybody was seeing, right?
And like the size of the cedars,
like, they're 40 50 ft wide.
It's
crazy
how big this stuff is, man.
And so I, I know, I, I have some friends who do farming, like,
large farming for that matter and it's al,
it's fascinating talking to these guys because,
like,
this equipment is hundreds of thousands of dollars
but it lets them be so obscenely productive.
It's not even funny.
I mean, yeah, it's crazy. One guy can basically run a farm now
to be.
Well, I mean, it's like with cloud, right?
And, well, the whole point of it has always been automation.
Right. That's what we
define the problem and get a computer to do it.
The computer doesn't need to take naps.
Yeah, that's
it.
And this is one thing I love about the whole, you know, robotics
thing
is like, well, what, what, what do you consider to be a robot?
Like, does it have to be a physical like arm that, you know,
has four axis movement or whatever.
Like, what about, you know,
somebody writes a script to make a task 10% more efficient.
Oh, man, wouldn't it be great if all of our pearl scripts get taxed in the future?
Yeah.
Well, then how do you even measure work?
You know,
I know, I
know.
You
know,
actually this is,
you just,
I think made a point that kind of brings all of this together is the fact
that you look at these politicians talking about
banning encryption or filtering the internet or whatever,
right?
Pick some insane thing or taxing robots or
there's millions of things they can pick on about technology and
what it really comes down to is
the government or, or people in charge
they don't understand and can't keep up with technology,
which I think is extra funny because in the last episode and I still believe this,
we were saying that like the only way to fix security in iot is regulation.
But how do you,
if you have an organization that can't even figure out encryption and
now you want them to regulate a space like IOT it's,
well,
one way to regulate, well, one way to regulate it would be, for example,
to give consumers
rights and protections, which for example, in Europe,
they have some fundamental laws saying basically
if you sell something to somebody,
it has to be fit for purpose
for a certain period of time like one or two years.
So right there, boom, you,
you have to be giving security updates for one or two years.
Otherwise they can
they have the legal right to go return it and get their money back.
So for example, there would be a great way to just simply regulate it in the sense of,
you know, this thing has to work
and I think it would be reasonable to assume that, you know,
plugging a network device into a network, you know, would be a reasonable use case
and that not having security updates on that for
whatever, you know, public facing thing
means it's no longer fit for a purpose.
And if people can go return it, then all of a sudden, you know, the manufacturers, um,
would have, you know, well, the,
the people selling this stuff would have a huge
incentive because they don't want to do returns,
you know,
for a two year old device that, you know, is worth basically nothing.
And so the manufacturers would have an incentive to actually, you know,
stand behind their products.
You, you may have a point.
It's right.
It's such a weird topic.
Well, I think so
highly prescriptive regulation, like you must do exactly this, this and this,
I don't know that that's a good idea because things change so much.
I agree with that and, and, and, and sometimes it's not even that
like, but the fundamental, like
I would you know, 20 years ago,
if you told me my bathroom scale would be on the internet with a secure web server.
I would have been like, yeah. What? No, what?
-- And an idiot would do that. Yeah, exactly.
-- And now it's like, that's a normal thing.
You know, my light bulbs might be on the internet at some point.
Um,
and having the descriptive
sort of stuff,
you know, you have to put you,
you, you fall into that trap of the company saying, well, we did the best practice.
We did the, you know, we encrypted it with rat 13 standard industry wide encryption.
What could go wrong?
So I really think it boils down to is, you know,
let consumers return it and get a refund
because the other problem is a lot of these flaws don't show
up for a year or two or three or by definition,
if you're, if you know, a company might support it for a year
and then stop supporting it because a new model came out,
you know,
so I think fundamentally you put some lifespan on the device that's reasonable,
say two years, five years, whatever.
And you say essentially the consumer can return it if it's not fit for purpose. And,
you know,
you have a strong legal watchdog or arms buds.
Uh How do you pronounce that word ombudsman?
I have no idea what you're even trying to say.
The ombudsman, you know, the, the, the, the essentially the, you know,
whatever entity you can go to, to get, you know,
assistance and legal redress for whatever, you know, a specific type of problem.
I don't know
that that could be. It's,
it's outside of my vocabulary. I live in the United States. We have no rights here.
-- So, yeah,
-- the, the ombudsman. Ok. Well, we actually have one here in Alberta but
um,
the Alberta ombudsman responds to complaints of unfair treatment
by provincial government authorities
and designated professional organizations.
So it's this legal entity I can go to, to, you know, seek redress if I get like,
you know,
uh an unpleasant experience with the government or whatever.
That's not quite right.
And so you have one of these
for, you know, consumer goods, uh, they, I believe in Britain.
It's like the, uh what is it,
it's covered under the Fair Trade Act, I think anyways.
And, you know, fundamentally, if, uh, like, for example,
somebody comes and repairs your door and like, completely, you know,
makes a mess of it,
you go to the, what is it, the Office of Fair Trade or whatever in the UK.
And like, you know, there's a complaint process and
you get redress. Hopefully.
Interesting.
So, you know, you basically have that and
the reality is, you know, these large companies,
like a lot of these companies are already doing it quite well.
Like a lot of
like Microsoft, for example, they turn the ship around and Microsoft is doing,
you know, like
the fact that they actually, for example, shipped a patch for XP for that, uh,
wanna cry thing.
That was,
you know,
if they hadn't done that, I would have been like,
I don't,
I, you know, I wouldn't have been angry at them for not doing that.
I would have said they're, well, within their rights of, like we end of life,
this thing a couple of years ago, people,
well, part of me thinks they shouldn't have just because
they were without question
many other problems.
Well, well, there's been
there, there are way worse problems, I imagine in XP than that.
And so,
like, stop, stop using it.
That's just not an option though. For a lot of people.
Right. There's just budgetary constraints, like
the whole, you know, the NHS thing where they have like,
roughly a million machines running XP.
But,
you know,
the problem is they've let the technical debt
accrue to such a degree that essentially you,
you'd like,
you basically have to default on it or
something. I don't
like, I just, if you asked me, like,
what is it gonna take to upgrade a million machines from Windows XP.
I would have been like,
I would put my money on a meteorite. Like,
I, I can't even imagine this a problem at that scale.
Exactly.
You know, it's not even like you can take bite size pieces and, and make
meaningful progress. Like
you upgrade 50,000 machines. That's 5% of the fleet. That's,
-- you're still stuck with 950,000. It's
-- not even just
creating
50,000 machines. The hardware is probably terrible.
-- And so
-- you
don't
replace the hardware
apps.
Right.
It's, it's basically you have to rebuild the NHS it from ground up effectively just,
but within the existing constraints that of what you have,
which makes it even worse.
Put it in the cloud
fine.
Yeah,
actually that that's a really good point is
imagine if Aws had to backdoor
all of their crypto
in the cloud. Do you like
-- no
-- organization would use
the cloud?
-- Well, just the key management aspect of that would
-- be
two man,
-- I can't
-- even
like I am already does key management
at this scale, but now you're basically doubling it
more than doubling it because you figure every
freaking government's going to want their own key,
they're not going to share.
And then there's the other problem of like the whole hardware security modules,
the whole,
like we have an entire industry designed around exactly preventing this scenario.
Right.
Yeah, literally.
Yeah, it's,
oh, you gotta love it. You know what else I always think of too is
these politicians love to blame encryption. But the reality is this is just,
this is good intelligence is how you solve this
in putting backdoors in encryption isn't gonna help.
You need good
intelligence. You need
agencies,
three letter agencies that actually are doing good
work and not just collecting worthless data.
Right.
That it's like the Israeli airport story.
We always talk about where those are people that are
actually conducting good intelligence and it's making a difference versus a
bunch of ridiculous theater that just
inconveniences everyone and doesn't actually help.
Yeah. Well, I mean, it doesn't help the underlying problem.
It does make people feel safe to fly and they keep flying,
even though statistically it's still like, I, I'm more,
I'm honestly more afraid of, like,
when I walk my kids home four blocks and we have to
cross a major road which has a pedestrian controlled light that turns red
and like, you know, 99 times out of 100 so far the cars have stopped.
I know. No, that's not true.
No, actually two weeks ago a car did not stop,
but in fairness it was a police car with its lights on doing about 100 and 10.
Sweet.
So, you know, again, but then, you know, the system works. Right.
And he had his lights on.
Um,
did he, do you have the siren going too?
-- Uh,
-- he did not actually, which I
found
and then another c car came screaming up.
So anyways, but the point being, you know, is that, that, that's,
that's a failure scenario we've planned for
and I've been teaching my
corner case. Right. It's,
it's not every day.
Well, no, no, not every day. But
I mean, when you do, like
when you cross the street, even if the light is in your favor,
you should still look both ways because like fire trucks, ambulances, police cars,
drunk drivers, texting drivers.
Um, or my favorite that youtube video showing a cop directing traffic,
I think somewhere in eastern Europe and you're like, oh God,
I hope he doesn't get hit by a car and then out of nowhere, a cow comes running into
him.
I haven't seen that. That's awesome
because, you know, it's just all these videos is like, oh God, oh God, I hope he's ok.
And then a cow just, just runs over him and it's like
that must have hurt. But
man, it's funny.
That's fantastic.
You know. So,
yeah, you should look both ways when you cross the street.
But I mean, back to the whole security argument. Yeah, I mean,
we should plan for failure,
which, because it's gonna happen.
Yeah. No, people,
you know, it's, um, and I,
I don't know what the answer is because a lot of these companies will, you know,
make claims that like, oh, yeah,
we have security and then two years down the road they don't.
Well, then what? Right.
And if we allow people to return these devices, well,
if nothing else that'll start maybe teaching the people who sell these
things to be a lot more careful about what they say.
The only way that would work is if you had enough people returning them
and, I mean, let's look at the market today.
It's pretty terrible and,
-- and people would have
-- to have that many returning them for it to be a big
because think about how much, like, how, what is Best Buy's marginal stuff,
like 0%
like, yeah, basically it's a few percent
because they have to, like, price match Amazon Prime.
So you don't even need, like, if two or 3% of
people return their stuff, that's, that's all of Best Buy's profits gone.
But that's just Best Buy.
Although, although where would you put the, I guess,
where would the liability live with the shop?
You have to
put it on
the,
you have to put it on the end shop like they do in Europe. Otherwise it's so
it just doesn't work, right?
Because the manufacturer can go out of business or
change names or stop being a legal entity.
You know, like here in Alberta, they're, they're,
they're looking at having this database of home builders
where like you would actually have to be registered,
it would be the name.
So even if they change legal names and stuff of their company,
you could still look up and see if this guy is legit or
not because there's so many horror stories of like these builders that,
right?
Just like this one guy, you know,
paid like 28 grand or whatever to have his uh driveway resurfaced like, you know,
with uh asphalt
and he like, did all the research, he, you know, he actually interviewed previous
clients of this company, blah, blah, blah,
you know, and the whole thing turns into a disaster,
right.
And there's fundamentally not enough consumer protections and not
enough information to make a truly informed decision.
And the reality is we won't have enough information to make an informed decision.
We just won't,
we can't, these devices are new,
you know, like with VR headsets,
which VR headsets are causing people to go like cross in five years.
Well, we won't know for five years.
So a really good indication of this is that the
US military only allows their pilots 15 minutes in VR Sims
because they don't want to mess up their vision
uh studies. I've been looking at indicate pre
teens
uh with developing vision, it can permanently affect and alter their vision.
So like the Nintendo three Ds warning is real
to some degree.
I thought they made that up.
No. Well, part of its legal liability, but part of it is
we, we're not 100% certain.
Um
you know,
-- so
-- anyway, it need to be the test case, right?
-- Yeah,
-- so, so fundamentally, I mean, you,
you put that legal liability on sort of the end seller
of it and at least for the major sellers like,
you know, Amazon and best buy
that forces them to be a whole lot more careful about what they sell.
-- Now,
-- that's really interesting. Well, you look at Amazon, they sell everything.
Mhm.
I don't know.
It's, it's wild to think about.
I, I'm not opposed to it by any means just because I think things are,
things are silly the way they work today.
Well, it's definitely the consumer has very little
-- chance of redress when things do go wrong
-- regardless of redress.
You don't even know when things are going wrong in a lot of instances.
I mean, how many of those video cameras are hacked
and mining Bitcoin or something? And you don't even know,
although what is it? I read that
the whole mirror botnet mining Bitcoin can generate like, what,
three cents a day or something
like
that,
millions of devices.
Well, it's like the wanna cry thing.
They only made a couple of 100 grand and, you know,
it cost the industry
if I had to guess I would say on the order of definitely more than $10 million.
I bet it's in the billions.
Well, I was gonna say, possibly more than 100 million and
a not insignificant chance of more than a billion
when you consider all the time and
the time is a big one.
And I mean, you think like the NHS got hit in a handful of organizations got hit,
but I think just the fact that
the universe had to deal with this over the weekend.
So you're talking about overtime and ruining people's
lives and just dealing with the madness.
I bet it was in the billions easily.
Yeah. Oh, I could believe that.
Oh, the battery in this thing died. Sorry,
I just bought some new tablets and the battery
life is apparently when you buy $100 tablet,
the battery life is kind of terrible.
I'm shocked
who could have known.
Yeah.
So, no, I'm actually quite happy that it lasted
-- five hours or so.
-- Five hours seems ok.
And actually some of these as well,
if you run the battery down and up a couple of times it, it will get better
where, like, charge it, drain it, charge it, drain it.
I thought that was bad for lithium
-- ion batteries to completely drain them.
-- It is not good
is my understanding, but from what I've seen, my suspicion is the,
there's an internal,
uh, computer that measures battery level
and apparently to calibrate it,
you charge it and drain it and charge it and drain it and once it figures out what it is,
then it can give you the proper amount of battery life because my,
I suspect they said it very conservative out of the
box and let it teach itself what to do.
Right.
I mean, quite honestly,
I don't care because all these things will be thrown away in 2 to 3 weeks.
-- Right.
-- Well, I mean, you know, it's 100 it literally cost 100 and $20 Canadian,
which is, yeah, it's basically 100 bucks us
-- actually a bit less.
-- Is it running Android? 4.2?
No, Windows 10?
Oh, nice actually. So that,
that crappy Windows 10 tablet. I have
it. Uh
it got the update to like Windows 10 creator or whatever the heck the new version was.
And I'm thinking, I, I literally paid
Windows 10, got some big new update. Uh maybe two months ago.
I think it's Windows 10 Creators edition or something they called it. But anyway,
this tablet, I literally paid $50 for got the update. And I'm thinking
this is madness like Android, the Samsung tablet,
my parents own hasn't gotten Android updates.
I won't buy an Android tablet is I want to buy an Android
tablet that will get at least one or two years of updates.
Does Google make a pixel tablet again yet?
I
don't
know
the other.
Well, and the other catch me because I want to pay 100 bucks for this tablet.
Yes, you are
that
there,
there is that minor
detail
tablet.
Um Yeah, so I mean, as a consumer, right? Like I,
you know, should a tablet, for example, have like a guaranteed two year lifespan,
you know, and I can return it to Best Buy if it's
not getting security updates or something.
I I would love to see that, but I, at least in the U si doubt that will ever happen.
Uh Anyway, speaking of the US, speaking of the US,
have you heard about the hack back bill
that's been proposed.
I
know
a
few
times.
I
know
just what gets me is,
I can't imagine any real hacker actually hacking from their own system.
Of
course
not.
It's
not only
if there's someone you're mad at break into their system right
now,
all
of a sudden
vigilante justice
is by and large, you know, these, these people that are being,
being used as a platform to hack, other people are unaware of it.
Obviously,
you know, I would hope they're unaware of it because if, you know, by definition,
they are aware of it and letting it happen.
Well, that, that's terrible.
Um,
so my concern would be is you get two organizations that are like,
you know,
one thinks the other one hacked them so they attack back and the other one is like,
oh my God,
we're being attacked and then they start actively
hacking back or hire somebody to do it.
This seems like a really fast way to cripple the US economy,
the world.
It's just, it, it's so comically ridiculous. I mean, it,
this is like saying if, if you think your neighbor stole something from you,
you can go take something of theirs, right?
You don't need proof, like whatever, just you think they took your lawn mower,
go take this.
It's fine,
you know. Right. Right.
It's just, yeah,
and that's the other thing is the level of proof required is going to be.
Well, you know, the IP address.
Well, as we all learned from the whole file sharing, you know, suing debacle,
like uh those are quite often wrong or those records aren't quite,
the whole thing is comical on so many.
Again, though, this comes back to politicians have no freaking clue.
And
I assume they're coming from a like stand your ground kind of Castle Doctrine law
perspective of like their thinking being that like
this is like standing in your house,
somebody's breaking in and you shoot them with a shotgun.
You know,
and even that quite often doesn't go very well.
Like in Canada it's just, it's illegal.
-- It should be illegal. Duty to retreat.
-- Right. Don't,
don't shoot people. All right, folks,
there's one thing you take away from the lesson of this podcast is,
is don't shoot anyone.
Ok.
It's just,
-- they
-- probably need
these guys
unless it's what,
unless it's really needed. And legal and
in some cases
just don't shoot people. All right, don't shoot people that should be the default.
You know what? It probably is. These people probably watch the Matrix
and they're like that, that's how computer hacking works.
Right. And it's just,
oh, my goodness.
I have no words to describe the stupidity.
Well, see,
I think the fundamental issue is the physical world
doesn't really translate to the virtual world very well,
especially now with the internet being everywhere all the time.
What about cloud? Actually, that's a good point.
Think about, like, what you're going to hack back into Aws. Yeah.
Good luck with that guys. Right.
Well, and then Aws sees you doing it, do they just, like, flatten your link?
-- Like, I don't know if again, going back in the
-- day,
that's my point. Right. Aws is going to put up with that crap.
-- They're gonna shut you down.
-- They already put up with that crap. Right.
They already ignore it.
Like, my understanding is for a lot of these major providers, like Aws,
that background noise is so loud that they just ignore it because what, you know,
it's like,
given, you know, here's a list of machines we know sending out spam.
Do you want to do something about it? No, just blacklist them.
I'm not gonna get them.
Are you kidding me? I'm not going to waste my time,
you know, like with the Marai Botnet, like,
here's a list of all the 100,000 system owners.
Yeah. Who cares? What am I gonna do with this? Tell them
right.
Here's the NHS with a million machines that are not just out of date but, like,
off life support.
Like, they're not supported by the vendor anymore.
Everybody knows this. What are we gonna do?
You know? I, I think the problem is we're back into that.
The problem of large numbers.
Oh, yeah, that's very true.
I mean,
it's, uh, yeah, it's just,
I think the fundamental reality is the whole security posture we've had
for the last 3040 years has been around a manageable number of systems
but they aren't anymore. Right. We're talking, you know,
a
w says how many
I'm gonna say hundreds of millions of computers.
Oh,
at least,
at
least
more than 10 million,
you know.
-- Yeah,
-- I, my brain hurts thinking about it.
Yeah. So,
and then within that how many containers and how many,
you know, virtual servers are running?
Right.
Right. Watts.
Anyway. Anyway, hacking back doesn't work
well. It, it's just,
-- I'm not really clear on what it's supposed to accomplish.
-- I, I have no idea.
-- I, I can't, it's
-- not gonna be a deterrent because as a deterrent it's like, great.
I will actually go to somebody I don't like and use
their systems to hack the other guy I don't like.
And so like, when,
uh,
it's certainly not going to work as like
an actual physical kind of protection because,
yeah,
people will just buy a shell host and that poor shell hosting provider will get,
you know, slammed.
And, um,
yeah,
anyway,
I,
part of me hopes it happens sometimes just
to see how horrifically terrible it would be.
I,
no, I'm gonna say no, I,
part of me thinks you have a point and then part of me thinks this is,
this is like you were saying about your, your son with his fidget spinner in the ipad.
There are,
there are things I'll let my kids do
that
I know there will be a valuable lesson to come out of the other side of it.
And there's some things I won't
because it's, they're probably going to die or they're going to ruin my life. Right.
-- And, and
-- there's a, there's a high probability of maiming. Right. Right.
You have to draw a line somewhere for things like this.
And I think hacking back is well across the line of,
let's just let them learn a lesson by doing this.
Right. It's,
well, this ignores the whole international aspect of it too.
-- Yeah. Right. I'm like, you're right,
-- all of a sudden. Right.
Like everybody else in the world is, like, wait, what now? Right.
Then they can all pass their hacking back laws and then,
then everybody can stop getting along.
Yeah.
Well, the reality is you can already do this.
It's just questionably legal but I,
I've never heard of anybody being successfully prosecuted
for this.
Like, as a company, you know,
there's been a few individual hackers that have been prosecuted but by and large
even that is pretty few in pharmacy
has an actual company ever done this before though.
I
mean, I don't know of any, I know of people who've done stuff like this before.
Well, I mean, there's, I don't,
I don't think there's any companies that have publicly admitted to this,
but clearly
somebody somewhere has, had, had to have done it at some point.
Um,
and there's companies that have engaged in
behavior like that where it's like borderline,
you know, like the Sony rootkit debacle,
you know, they basically hacked a whole bunch of, you know, customers machines.
Right.
That, that's stupidity though. Right.
That's not, I guess that's the other part of it.
This, this whole idea is malicious intent.
Right. It's not stupidity. If you're hacking back, it's malicious intent.
-- Well, mens rea, it's intentional. It's not like, oops.
-- Right. Right. Yeah.
Sorry for hacking you. You know,
I didn't mean it,
which I'm sure would stand up in court.
Uh Which one?
All of them?
Oh my goodness. It's, we need to end this.
This is no, no, no more good will come to this conversation.
We ramble on about nonsense for far too long. So,
thank you for listening. Everybody. If you've made it this far. Congratulations.
You have far more fortitude than I think I would have.
If you want any of the links to any of these crazy stories,
you can go to open source security podcast.com.
We have links there to show notes. We've got a Twitter link, we've got Facebook
and you can use the Pound Os S Podcast. Hashtag if you want to get a hold of us.
Uh Yeah, I guess until next time,
Kurt episode 50. Congratulations, man.
It's a long time.
Kurt, you have, you have a great day.
I
-- hope everybody has a good week. Thanks
-- everybody. Bye bye.