Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
and my partner in disclosing stuff.
I'm not sure what word to use, responsibly coordinative.
We
don't like the word responsible anymore,
but
disclosure
disclosure,
I like that actually.
Is it.
Are we functional? I'm skeptical.
Uh This unit is functional,
says you
all right. So anyway,
we're going to discuss a very unique
disclosure topic
that
if you, if you've been listening to us for a while,
Kurt and I have discussed coordinate disclosure or, or pick a term,
we don't like responsible for some historical reasons we can discuss later.
-- But
-- it also defend, I mean, who's defining the word responsible in that case?
Right.
Microsoft is,
and, and anyone who doesn't do exactly what they want you to do is irresponsible.
And in fact, funny enough back in the day in their advisories,
they would discredit people for not acting responsibly,
which I thought I always thought that was hilarious.
-- I was always
-- sad. I
that was a big deal because when I worked for eyesight and eye defense, right?
We, you know, bought vulnerable like we were the first,
it was the first company to buy vulnerabilities and report them to vendors quickly.
And
Microsoft Tuesday would roll around and we wouldn't know
until it went public if they were fixing our issue or not, like,
even an hour beforehand, they wouldn't be able to tell us.
And there were times where they were like, oh, yeah.
Yeah, it's going to get fixed and then it, it didn't
that month or, you know,
or we totally didn't expect our issue to get fixed that quickly.
So
my understanding of it, it was Microsoft was kind of doing the best they could, but
they were papering over a lot of holes.
Well, I mean, I'm sure they still do.
We all there,
there's some, there's some demons
beneath the surface
no matter who you are anyway.
So
there is a story, I will put a link in the show notes where basically this,
this researcher and now the story.
-- No,
-- no, no, not a researcher, a company, a
company, whatever.
Well, no,
that's different because companies have lawyers and
money and stuff and most researchers don't.
That's a good point.
So
basically
this company and now the blog post is like no legitimate details in it.
So don't think like there's anything exciting in this.
But basically they talk about, they found a,
it sounds like they found like an open database
or something from a company that writes stalker Warre.
And
then the question becomes, what do we do with this?
It sounds like they alerted the company
and the company did nothing.
And now the question becomes, what do we do with this information we have?
Because obviously
the the situation sounds like it is a victim database.
And I use the word victim in the context
of you have the stalker installing the stalker wear on
the victim's device. And I don't want to get into the argument of whether
stalker wear is ok or bad or you're a parent with Children or whatever,
-- like
-- very simple thing because I'm actually in the position now of I will be
having to use a product like this for my one son who has autism,
so I can keep an eye on what he's doing and make sure he's safe online.
But there will be full disclosure, I will tell him he may not understand it fully.
But there's also the legal aspect of, for example, I'm his legal guardian.
And there, there's a big difference, for example,
there between then the uh the situation say between two adults,
right?
When somebody has a child
and is that child's legal guardian?
For example, this is a whole different ball game.
So there are some pretty, I would say pretty legitimate cases for this. Now, do I?
And here's the difference though, do I want to use the software on his phone?
No, I don't, but I don't have an alternative
and that's fair. And I think that's the difference. I'm doing this as a last resort.
Not as
a,
you know, this is easier than parenting him.
OK? That's fair.
So,
but in this case, this is a piece of stalker wear that's like,
well, and that's the other thing is
the nso group.
I,
I was thinking about the other day and I
realized they're just the ultimate in stalker wear.
I mean, basically
right now, now it should also go that we don't know which Stalker Wear company.
This is, it sounds like they're a little seedy from the blog post. But like we, we have
-- one that isn't see d,
-- well, that's probably fair.
It's,
-- it's definitely one of those areas.
-- Well, the best quote here.
Stock War operates in a legal gray zone,
which I find funny because it doesn't have to. Right.
There's corporate software that monitors end points that, you know,
people are fully informed and it's disclosed and it's not a legal gray area.
It's actually completely legal to do that.
And so that's what I really dislike about the Stock war software is it's,
it's something that could be done properly, but they choose not to.
Well, yeah, because their markets probably 10 times bigger.
Right. So, I, I wouldn't say it's a gray area. I would say it's probably illegal.
-- Yeah.
And, and there's actually I'll,
the eff has some really good info on stalker wear and everything going on.
There's a, they have a lawyer.
Her name is Eva Side on Twitter. I don't, I don't, I don't know what her real name is.
It's funny how I know so many people by their hacker names or Twitter handles and,
like, no other information.
But anyway,
I'll put a link to her in the show notes and she's
done a ton of amazing work around stalker Warre and getting it.
I mean,
just getting it classified as malware in many instances has been a huge challenge.
-- Yeah. the Avida texts. That's, that's a huge win for people.
-- Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah, absolutely.
And, and it's like you say, it's one of those situations if you know it exists
and your A V picks it up like, OK, great.
Like I understand this is here but if you don't know it exists and your A V picks it up,
it's like holy crap, what is going on, right?
Ok. So anyway, anyway,
there is a company,
they report this and now they just write a weird
blog post instead of doing any sort of actual disclosure.
So I would say from the concept
of responsible disclosure or even coordinate disclosure,
-- there has been none of that.
-- Well, there's been no disclosure,
disclosure in general. You can't call it anything disclosure
-- when there's no disclosure,
-- there's no disclosure.
So anyway, it brings up a really interesting point though that I, I think gives us,
well, actually I got to walk that statement back.
Sorry, because they did disclose it to the company and the company then ignored it.
And
this, the reporter is like, well,
ok, and gave up basically.
-- And,
-- and that's part of the story is what, like what happens if you report something.
But we'll, we'll get to that topic.
I just, I, I want to put our stake in the ground and say, ok,
so
we're going to
talk about disclosing security vulnerabilities and there's a
couple different hypotheticals we can go with.
But let's kind of start with where the stalker we story begins
where you find an issue that is potentially dangerous. And this is where you've got,
you know, P I
I, well, let's actually, let's, let's define that a little bit because
so to be clear, I think there's sort of three groups here,
there's the stalker work company,
there's the stalker aware companies,
customers who are using the stalk aware to generally do bad things.
And then there's the stalker aware victims,
right? And these are three very different groups, obviously.
And I would say in this
and you can define harm against these three groups.
You know, for example, that the company has to spend money fixing a vulnerably.
Well, that's too bad.
Um
The customers of the company that are using the stalker, we can maybe are, you know,
going to be exposed or their victims will find out and remove the stalker wear again.
I would say that's,
that's a,
that's what we want, not a bad outcome.
Uh And then finally, there's the damage to the victims
of the stalker warre and,
and those are the people I care about in this scenario or any scenario.
Really?
And so for example, like you said,
it sounds like there might be a database of data being exposed
and
yeah, that would
suck for them to have all their private photos
and all their S MS discussions and everything leaked.
-- Well,
-- and we don't know. Right. It could be photos, it could be just names.
-- I mean, whatever it
-- doesn't matter.
P
I
has been most likely in most jurisdictions illegally obtained. Right.
-- So,
-- well, that's really interesting actually.
So not, not to go on a weird tangent but like from the perspective of GDPR,
if you're a stalker war company and you're holding someone's data
like that, that's a strange
claim, the business requirement to hold that data, right?
Like you can't, you can't go to the tax man and say, hey, you know,
delete all my records.
I mean, can they, I don't know. I'm not, I'm not a lawyer
but, well, no, no, there's a business need exemption, right?
-- So, like the tax authority has,
-- but this isn't a tax authority.
This is a company operating in a legally gray area.
So the problem then is you need to lodge
a GDPR complaint and go through that whole process.
-- That's probably
-- true.
And the other thing is I'm assuming this company is not based in Europe,
but I mean, it could be.
Well,
probably not anyway. Anyway. Ok.
So,
so, so let's, let's think about this.
Here's,
here's where I think it gets interesting is from the perspective of a company.
Right?
You are a company, you tell another company you have a security vulnerability,
the company ignores you.
Ok.
They know it's you.
-- So there's no, like, let's just,
-- let's call it the reporting company.
Ok. Yes. The reporting company. Exactly.
So, if you're the reporting company,
you can't like, post this to the full disclosure mailing list now because
there's,
well,
and they're going to make legal threats.
But what are they actually going to like apart from slander and libel,
especially in, say,
a jurisdiction like the UK where it's really like
truth is not even a defense over there.
But as a company again, you know, companies have lawyers,
companies deal with this kind of stuff all the time.
I guess
the real problem though is,
is what's the incentive to actually disclose this publicly?
Well, I mean, that's probably part of it too.
Right? Because
you run the risk of the company suing you,
you have the potential of, ok,
I've just essentially told the world where to go to find
a bunch of victim pi I which is of course,
insanely dangerous for the victims.
And, and you look like the bad guy here,
you could potentially have an instance where
you, you talk about this and now
the world's, I'm skeptical the world's going to see you as some sort of hero here.
-- It's, I mean, this is a weird, weird disclosure problem.
-- Stupid question.
So, for example, there's,
there's certain classes of problem where to give a horrible example,
child pornography, you can counter child pornography.
There's well documented avenues to report it
and they will go deal with it.
Now in Europe with PI, I, there's GDPR and the, um,
oh,
I forget what the data is it called a data authority or whatever it is in the country,
you know, the enforcement thing in the country.
And my thought is if assuming, well, for sure, there's gonna be,
there's 100% chance that at least one of those records is a European
person covered under GDP.
And so my one thought is you could go to the GDPR authority with this,
but is there some authority you can go to for data breaches?
Now, my understanding is that the FBI and stuff are starting, you know,
Biden has made noise about that and saying that this is actually OK, we get it.
It's a problem now
and that the US government is going to start dealing with this a bit more.
But I don't think there's any well sort
of documented and actually responsive place to go
saying, you know, I found a pile of pi I
like, can you law enforcement people go deal with this properly?
Right. And, and they mentioned that in the post, I, I think it was in the post.
I, I read this somewhere but basically, like,
if you bring this to someone like the FBI,
there's,
there's nothing they're going to do about it
because it's not technically a crime in many instances.
And, I mean,
that creates a whole another weird problem
from their perspective of reporting vulnerabilities.
Yeah.
I, it's tough because on the one hand I generally prefer disclosure, like,
let's document all the bugs, let it out in public.
On the flip side.
I, I really don't want to hurt the victims of the stalker wear
and, and I think that's just it.
So, like, historically, if we go back in time, let's say 2030 years of,
of vulnerability to sculptures, it was usually,
I found a bug in windows. I took Microsoft Microsoft laughed at me.
So now I'm sending my exploit to the full disclosure
mailing list or the bug track mailing list or whatever.
And then Microsoft gets embarrassed and they're like, oh ha ha.
We were just kidding.
Actually going to fix it after all. Wink. Wink.
And like,
that's completely different because that's
basically researcher versus Microsoft.
Right.
There's no, like, third party of pi I of some victims that's getting leaked here and
that's what makes it so much different and so difficult to just wrap my head around.
Well, I think part of the thing is there, there wasn't,
there was like,
there were no
ba barely any malicious software or services on this level.
No, no, no, there was, there was nothing
they were, they existed but they were like, they were unicorn rare.
-- I,
-- I can't think of anything historically. That was anything like the stalker wear.
I mean,
potentially some, like zero day brokers but even that's super questionable.
Yeah.
So, I mean,
I think that's part of the problem is
also the scale of these things typically nowadays,
you know, these stock,
our products and these pi I breaches are
thousands and tens of thousands and millions of people.
It's in the millions quite often.
I mean, there have been some that have been billions of records and
I
mean,
it's
ignoring that though, right?
Like, let's not talk about the breaches because I think that's another,
another topic.
I'm just thinking from the perspective of disclosure.
I feel like I feel like there's a couple of different levels where if
I'm just disclosing to a company and it's just a bug in their product,
I'm gonna have no remorse just going public because they're being jerks to me.
Right.
But if it's, if it's like pi I is available, I mean, like there,
there have been these instances, there's this,
this researcher that I
um goes by Bob, I think it's the,
I can't pronounce his last name, so I won't even try. Um,
I'll put a link to his Twitter account but he,
he does all this research where he looks for like
open databases on the internet and when he finds them,
he contacts the company and then he usually does a little write up because, like,
that's
shtick is a consulting company and
like, this guy is super awesome.
And I've talked to him before about some things and like, I, a great guy and like,
this is an instance where I don't think he's
found a situation where he's reported the problem
to a company and the company's been like,
screw you go away.
Right.
And like even, let's say he did, like,
I just, I can't, this is such a hard problem to talk about.
Like, what do you do? What do you do if the company tells you to go away?
Well, I, I was thinking so there's not a lot of authorities you can go to,
but there are organizations like the eff who have lawyers and again,
they can offer if nothing else,
they'd probably be able to give you some reasonable advice.
-- You
-- know what you just made me think of.
So there, there is something you could probably do,
but you're going to need lawyers.
There is a very high probability that this data that was found is hosted
in a cloud
and so you could go to the cloud provider
and potentially give them enough. We'll say documentation
that compels them to disable access, be it shut down the machines,
turn off the internet access, whatever
and that could potentially work because you're dealing with a potentially illegal
-- situation. Yeah.
-- But then they just go stand it up on some other instance.
It is very probable. Yes.
You know,
the NSO group apparently is using a combination of Amazon web services
and OVH and digital Lotion and essentially a list of hosting providers.
-- I mean.
-- Right. If,
well, ok, so, but the NSO is also special because they're like literally
the best of the best when it comes to this sort of thing.
I assume we're talking about a company that probably has crap architecture,
crap software and it's probably barely functional.
Yeah. If nothing else shutting down their access temporarily,
I, I think that the problem becomes this.
Here's a good question. What does remediating the situation look like?
Because the company has the strongest possible incentive to not be like, oh, oops,
we, we didn't mean to disclose that data.
We're going to do the right thing and get rid of it. No, of course, they're not.
Their whole business model is predicated on being jerks.
Well, no, no, I would say from the simplest level,
just turn off public access. Assuming we're dealing with like an open data set.
What about warning all the users or the victims of the stalker
-- Warre? It's,
-- it's stalker
Warre. Their victims don't even know you're part of it.
They're not going to warn them
because I'm looking at this and assuming, let's say hypothetically speaking,
I'm doing a bunch of research into Stalk Warre and I run
across a stalk work company and I scan their network and I
find an open Mongo DB instance or whatever with a whole pile
of records with obviously stuff that's been snarled off people's phones.
Do I maybe send them an email?
And I'm saying I, you know, doing this anonymously,
obviously not as myself because I don't want to get sued.
But
would I would, would that be something that would be helpful or harmful?
This is not a territory I'm in a position
to talk about because I think when you're dealing with
abuse
and victims of abuse,
it's often not the things we think makes sense often don't.
And I'm not an expert in this space.
So I would by no means attempt to contact any
victims or do anything involving victims of this sort of
thing because I think virtually anything I would do would
probably put these people in danger is my suspicion.
Well, yeah, I mean, and that's, and that's what I come back to is.
So number one, what does remediation look like? And number two, how do we,
how do we do no harm?
Right. Let's not make things worse.
Well, I I would say from the perspective of disclosure and what,
what we're talking about here,
remediation is closing the data set off to the public, right?
Plain that that's the simplest lamest possible answer to this.
I think if you want to go levels deep,
that's where you need to start involving people,
like the eff and lawyers and someone who understands, like,
how to interact with this universe in a way that doesn't,
like, literally get people killed.
The thing I just keep coming back to is I really wish
the A V vendors would do a better job of this.
And also, and actually that's a cop up because most phones don't run A V
and I've looked at A V on phones and it's a disaster. Like it makes things worse.
Like, I love what Apple's doing with, you know, on my phone now.
I get that annoying orange dot When my camera's on,
you know, I have that,
that feedback of no, this is actually like you, my device is recording me now.
But, oh, I meant to do that because I'm on a Zoom call or whatever.
And I think that's part of the answer is to make things like stalker.
We really, really obvious.
I love, you know, they've added the hardware cut off
effectively for the microphones and stuff if you have
a case with a little magnet in it,
right?
For your new ipads.
So your ipad can't be passively recording you anymore,
which was possible in the past.
Um And I don't even want to think about the Android ecosystem.
Yeah, exactly.
Yeah.
I mean,
if the company says we're not going to do anything
about it and going public would likely make things worse,
I feel like eff or possibly some investigative reporter is the way to go.
Because apart from that, I just,
I think what,
you know, what I think, what we basically are both in
is we on the Dunning Kruger curve.
We actually know that we're at the far left of the curve and we know nothing.
And I think the trick now is,
is you've got to go find somebody who knows something about this.
So honestly, now that I say this out loud, I would,
I would Google for a journalist who reports on stalker wear.
I mean, that's probably fair.
I think,
I think you're hitting on an important point is the world of vulnerabilities and
disclosure is changing drastically from the world we know because back in the day,
it was basically just throwing Microsoft or
Adobe or someone under the bus oracle oracle
oracle
or
they were. So
let's pick on Sun because they're dead now.
-- You
-- know, I never had a lot of trouble with sun
time. I interacted with them. They were pretty good.
-- Some
-- of their timelines though in their advisor,
like the the researchers released advisors,
right?
I remember man, there'd be like six years
anyway. Anyway,
the point is all of this as a service I think
creates unique problems because it's not as simple as just saying,
oh, I'm going to full disclosure this because
you're potentially affecting
people who aren't the company you're disclosing against.
You might be destroying small companies.
I mean, it's very possible you could be,
you could be making someone a victim of identity theft by by saying, oh look,
look at this data set like here it is or whatever.
-- And like this is a super crazy, super hard problem.
-- Here's a thought,
for example, and I'm not advocating this because it's illegal.
But remember when there was that
Mongol
DB thing where
they would go around and I'm not talking about the encrypting the Mongol DB to force,
you know, uh for ransomware.
But there was a period where somebody was going around and it was either Mongo
D BS or mem
Cash D BS or something like that
and just
wiping it.
Yeah.
So I,
I set up an elastic search honey pot to look
for this because it was happening at one point.
It was called meow bot.
And,
and the really funny thing that happened
was
I had my bogus data
and
it got ransomed, which of course,
it was funny because I was recording everything people were doing on
this honey pot and the ransom words didn't actually download anything.
So it's a
lot of
work man. So it was not ransomed.
They just deleted everything and added a, a little text that said, oh,
we're ransoming you ha ha.
And then it, and in fact, I'm,
I, I tried to contact the ransomers.
I'm like, oh I sent you the Bitcoin and they're like, we don't have it.
And I it was a little bit of back and forth and they,
it was,
I got bored of it.
But anyway, anyway, they,
then it got meowed, then it got ransomed.
Then it would just kept going back and forth between the not ransomers and the meow
-- bot deleting everything and it was a bit
-- hilarious,
but there's an example of wood wiping the database because that would also have the,
the effect of forcing the company to then deal with
it because they need that thing to be operational.
And I would argue that
you that
the potential for harm is minimized
because
you know, that there's less of a potential for data disclosure.
And as far as the victims of the stock aware, you know,
essentially being punished for this company's
issue by the, you know, by the stalkers
II, I would think that that is minimized.
Well, but here's the problem you get is so I report it to the company,
then everything gets deleted, right?
I'm probably getting sued
and I think that's the challenge and,
and this is really where it comes from is when you're dealing with a company that is
of shady origins.
We'll say the, the real, I think the real ethical question becomes,
if you contact them
at all,
you've now put a great deal of responsibility on yourself.
Because now you, now the next steps you take,
you have to be very careful because if you report something and
they tell you to sod off and then their database gets deleted.
They're probably gonna come after you. Right.
Or it ends up on with a reporter at a newspaper or, you know what I mean?
Like, you become the target at that point.
And this is why when I've noticed issues in my banking or stuff, I've just
ignored it.
Just Kurt pay no attention.
You know, my money's insured, try not to think about it because I don't want to,
I don't want to deal with my bank possibly getting grouchy at me.
Well, and look, there's like, so something to think about is like,
there's a book I'm reading right now.
It's by Nicole
Plot. Who is, she's, I think, I don't know if she's still at the New York Times.
She's at the New York Times doing cybersecurity reporting.
She wrote a book called, this is how they tell me the world ends.
And
there's, I, I'm at the point of they're talking about like the whole,
like underground Zero Day exploit market and stuff.
And there's one point where a guy literally tells someone, like, if you,
if you leak this, you're going to get gutted and by gutted.
I mean, like someone's going to literally come and murder you
and like, you have to think about that, like,
some of these companies you're dealing with,
they're of the sort that you might have some legitimate
safety concerns if you're on the bad side of them.
Right.
Well,
and I think this speaks to maybe going to the eff or a journalist first because the,
to put it bluntly,
journalists who write about this stuff probably have better
operational security than most militaries because they have to,
they need it
like kidding.
I, you know, I mean,
in the last five years how many news outlets now use
some form of secure dropbox to receive anonymous whistleblower submission?
Right.
And I mean, let's face it,
like murdering journalists usually is highly frowned
upon and gets you loads of trouble.
Depends on the,
because recently there's been a lot of that in certain countries.
I know it's,
but, but you get the point right is,
I mean,
I think this is where as we venture into this universe
of everything is a service and all this information being available.
I, I kind of agree with you that
in many situations, like now look, if I found an issue with Microsoft,
I would have no reservations contacting them.
Right. But if I found something with like a company of questionable background,
I,
I do think maybe the eff or reporter might be a best
first stop because then you have a bit of a buffer,
a cut
out cut.
And
also,
well, the eff is going to be and here's the other thing,
the eff and a journalist are probably going to be able to do
an actual risk assessment of who are we dealing with versus you.
Well, now, at the same time though, I guess, like, this isn't the eff's job.
You know what I mean?
Like the eff if they suddenly get inundated with people reporting, like, you know,
stalker we data leaks.
Well, and they can say no.
Right.
Just, you know, like when you report bugs upstream they can say no,
we're not dealing with this.
Yeah. Yeah.
But then you can just dump it on full disclosure or some public
mailing list or something and walk away like you can't do that here.
Oh, no, no.
But what I'm saying is it's up to the eff whether they say yes or no,
you have to treat them as an adult essentially
and give them the choice right to say that.
Oh, they might get overwhelmed by this.
Yeah, they might, but they're also the eff they're professionals.
I mean, they are, this isn't exactly what they do,
you know you and I have been in the same situation where
somebody literally emailed me.
He's like, I want 100 cvs for these fuzz cases and you're going to have to like,
figure them out and assign the cvs properly.
And my response was no,
I need you to do a root cause analysis and show me the vulnerable code
and then they come back like three days later and it's like, oh,
-- it's just one doss and one function and
-- that's right.
OK.
Sorry. No. Right. And
it's, it's always one function.
There's literally, it's the, it's, I would say it's the effs job
to talk to people about weird problems and then
decide if they're going to help out or not.
That's kind of their stick.
-- I
-- don't,
I don't know, man.
I, I feel like we're putting,
we're putting a lot of responsibility on the eff here.
If you look at the eff and journalists, historically,
a lot of them like this new weird stuff because
this is where their industry and their life is headed.
Like, look at you and me what we're doing with security, right?
Where you and I have completely changed how we look at vulnerability,
identification
and management from say 10 or 20 years ago.
I mean, it, it's true, it's completely different and,
and I think disclosure is completely different now.
I, I really,
so it's funny we came into this and I thought we just have a bit of a chat about, oh,
this is how disclosure works and, and look, this is a weird one.
But like,
I do think the whole,
like, like the whole universe of disclosure is completely different and,
and I feel like this is a different problem.
-- I would not,
-- it's an ecosystem now of different things.
I mean, to a degree, I agree with that.
Like if I think of historical disclosure in software,
like let's say we're working with a product from a company or a project on github
or whatever,
I think the disclosure there even if you go public
is drastically different from the sort of disclosure of,
I found a data set full of stuff.
What do I do now? Like, those are really different problems.
Traditionally, the closest thing we had was like, oh,
I found billing data for a company
and that's easy. The company goes and closes it up.
There's no
victims, there's no
malicious stuff involved.
But what I mean is there's no, like,
it's just legitimately a company made a technical error
and had a problem.
These,
I think part of the problem with disclosure now
is these are no longer just technical errors.
There's ethics and morality involved,
I mean, yeah.
Yeah, I, I agree.
And there's nothing saying that a company,
you could report their billing data and they could just be like, go away nerd.
We don't care.
And I, I would not shock me if that happens where people report something to
somebody
and they either ignore them or they threaten them or
the Australian who discovered that the bank was just using sequential numbers
and
he went through a whole legal thing with the bank trying to basically
destroy it,
you know?
Right. Well, and that's just it. I mean, you could,
this feels so much like the early days of old disclosure where
you could report an issue to a company and they were like,
we're suing you.
I mean,
what, what, what would stop a company? You saying? I found all your billing data.
What would stop them from being like we're suing you? Right,
man, this is, this is so
hopefully the, the bank would have a slightly mature enough process to,
to know that that's not the way to handle this.
-- I mean,
-- a bank is slightly different than
some other company. You know what I mean?
There's a huge spectrum
we're dealing with.
Well,
it's interesting because I've been looking for
some information around bug bounties and disclosure policies
that both protect the company and the reporter.
You know,
remember years ago when a couple of big auto industry players came out
and said we will accept security reports and we promise to not sue
you. And we were like, oh, that's stupid.
Follow by, oh no, no, no, that's actually really good.
You needed that. Well, because they were suing people like,
and I think this will be part of that maturity process of
companies will have disclosure policies that not just
define how the researcher deals with the company,
but define how the company will deal with the researcher
and they may or may not hold to that agreement, but at least it's a good signal.
You know, if,
if a company explicitly says here are the circumstances
how you report to us and how we don't,
we won't sue you.
But, and maybe for example, they do list if you do this,
we will involve law enforcement fairly, right?
Like if you break into our systems and go,
you know, touch stuff that you're not supposed to touch.
Yeah, we're going to involve law enforcement, so, don't do that.
And now the expectations and the rules are understood,
I guess the one takeaway I think I'd give to anyone listening to.
This is, this is kind of where the bug bounty framework excels is by having,
if you're a company and you have a bug bounty, you are creating a skeleton.
I mean, you need more than just a bug bunny.
You actually need security people and you internal policies and stuff.
-- But like, I think that they have a
-- complaints box, you put the paper in the box.
Exactly. It's full.
-- No one can fit anymore in it
-- and it, well, no,
it feeds the incinerator to warm the building.
Oh, there you go.
But you, you get the idea, like when you have a bug bounty,
I feel like you at least have a skeletal framework
that sets you up to
make improvements in this space. You have to care. Obviously,
it's like the C I CD pipeline thing.
You, you can't do this without that infrastructure, right?
Any improvements you make will be ad hoc.
You need to actually formalize it and put it in a framework and document it and
-- well,
-- and that's where like this is a place if you're like,
I'll use hacker one because I work with them is
they do this all the time. So you can say, like, please give me advice.
What do we do in this situation?
And they generally have seen it because goodness knows you're not the first.
And so they can help guide you through some things. And like an easy example is
you could have infrastructure where you say like,
please do not denial of service us, right?
We don't, that's, that's out of scope
and you can have other infrastructure that it's like, yes,
we know this thing over here sucks
where we know like just please don't tell us about it, you know, so it,
it kind of creates some opportunities in that regard and
I mean,
I don't see dodgy companies ever wanting to do that,
but I guess it's the sort of thing that if you don't have this framework,
you don't have a bug.
B you don't have a disclosure policy listed
that is a signal to the people doing the research that
you are going to be a dangerous entity to interact with.
-- And so then they can look at alternative routes instead of trying to contact
-- you.
Yeah, talking about signaling, I think that's very important and
I would say by definition somebody making stock war is probably a software pariah.
Yeah. And
you know,
unless their stalker aware is a very explicitly
like warns the person that's being installed,
like some of the child control stuff actually pops up warning screens so that,
you know,
like every login you are being monitored blah, blah, blah, blah, blah. Right.
Which it totally should do.
Yeah.
But in this case, obviously that's, you know,
this sounds like proper stalker aware.
So that's not the case.
And I think you're right, it's, it's, and again, going back to those signals and
I'm still wondering though, again, what does remediation look like?
I mean, it's, it's good to get the victims
information off of the internet.
But I feel like in a way that's almost helping the company.
-- I mean,
-- well, it is obviously, I mean, this is such a weird one
and in a way you're helping the victims avoid some harm, potentially,
I guess maybe that's, you know, I think that's my concern is, is you have the definite
helping the company offset by the potential for offsetting harm.
And is that potential for offsetting harm with these stock
were victims enough to warrant being nice to the company?
I would say maybe because as you said, these, these, these victims are, you know,
not having the, the easiest of lives and days.
Well, here's, here's how I think we should end. This.
One is as happens more often than not.
I have more questions after discussing this for half an hour than I did coming in.
But I think that's good because obviously having
questions is how any knowledge journey begins.
And
I think
we have to start thinking about disclosure of this
sort of problem in a new way because trying
to apply the old rules of disclosure just doesn't
work because this is a completely different problem.
And so I think framing this as a disclosure
discussion is probably incorrect in the old way.
So we almost need like a new way to talk
about this and we don't even have the vocabulary today.
So in summary,
I have no idea.
However, I will say if you are a company, please, please, please,
please please have a disclosure policy and have a bug bounty program.
It is hugely important
that
you get on this train and you start setting this stuff up.
I'm just,
I'm going to actually disagree with the have a bug bounty
program because a lot of companies can't afford that or it's,
it's too much having a place to
report the vulnerabilities that is actually monitored.
Yeah. Absolutely. Absolutely.
When I'm not going to argue with you there, absolutely.
Disclosure is more important than
Bag Bni they are related, but one does not replace the other necessarily.
I think part of it is, I would say for commercial products that you sell,
you should probably pay for a bug bounty.
That's like you have coffee and toilet paper in the office.
That's just the thing you need to do.
But for example, nonprofits,
nonprofits shouldn't have to spend money on a bug bounty
so that people can report vulnerabilities on their website.
They don't always have to though, I mean, you can,
you can utilize like the hacker one platform as
a nonprofit for free or very little money,
right?
But you get what I'm saying, right?
Like, or some, you know, some small and medium business that has a website, you know.
Right. Well, I mean, that's a whole another story, but ok, I'm calling this one. It's
on.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you all for listening. Go to opens sociality
podcast.com. Hit up the show note
Podos
says podcast hat.
hit us up on social media. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the.