Hello and welcome to episode 88 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
Hello, Kurt, we have a guest today.
We have Chris Rosen from IBM, who's going to talk to us about container security.
-- Can you say hi, Chris?
-- Hello, everyone. And thanks for having me on Josh and Kurt.
Real excited to be here.
Yeah. Awesome. No, thank you.
I guess I'll give you a few minutes to just kind of explain
what you do and why you're here and then we'll jump right in.
-- How about
-- sounds good.
So,
I'm a program director of offering management within IBM cloud and focused
on our container service and container registry and our microservices fabric.
So everything related to containers is near and dear to my heart.
So I'm here to talk about some of the things that we're doing within IBM cloud,
as well as some of the things that we're doing out
in the open community on a number of various projects.
Awesome. That's very exciting.
Kurt and I have done many shows
about containers and especially container security,
which, which I will say these days.
Is becoming much less exciting than it used to be, which I think is a very good thing.
Right.
Absolutely. And I think it's really
mainly around education and as users start to understand what
these new technologies are and how they actually work,
they're becoming more comfortable with it.
And like you said, therefore less exciting than in the past.
Yes. Yes, indeed. So, I guess let's start at the beginning. Right? Is
what do we consider container security these days?
Because I know this has kind of been evolving a little bit over the last
probably year to two years since we first really started paying attention to this.
So security is really
a multifaceted approach that
and what's important is that security is not just some rubber stamp
at the end of your delivery pipeline or your new project,
your new future enhancement where you say, OK, yes, you're secure.
Move on
security is really everyone's responsibility and the term devs
ops, some people like it, some don't.
But to me, the reason I like it is because security is everyone's responsibility.
Whether
you're a developer or an operator at the end, security is important to us.
So that being said, you know,
I think there's kind of the Linux side of security which
gave us things like name spaces and C groups and set
camp and
user name spaces that give that isolation
to containers and then the processes within them.
And that's,
I think that's pretty foundational and that's been around for quite some time
then as we move up the stack, we think of security as far as you know,
how do I ensure isolation of my cluster, my resources running in the cloud?
How do I minimize the attack surface?
How do I store my Docker images in a secure manner?
So it's really the end to end of how we're thinking about container security today.
-- So
-- I love the end to end approach because this is something that
Kurt and I have been kind of railing on for years now is
in, in the good old days, it was very much
security was a step in a long process.
And of course, nobody liked the security people because they ruined everything.
And,
and I kind of love your attitude of security is everyone's job because I feel like
it is insane to expect
one group
at the very end to maybe hold the keys to
the kingdom as to whether your project leaves the door.
Right.
Exactly. And
when I talk to users,
it's not that they hate security and they don't
want to comply with their csos regulations and rules,
but
it's hard.
So a lot of times they just kind of push
it on the back burner because of the challenges.
So what we're trying to do
is make it easy and intuitive inherent to the platform to make
it easier for our developers to comply with our security rules.
And regulations.
So, one thing I'm wondering about is I've seen a general movement towards this.
Yeah, this Dev
Sec ops, if you will, what would you define Dev
Ops as?
So the way that we do it?
And I'm guessing we'll get two different answers
at least. Right.
We may, yeah. Yeah, I was going to say we may get more
from my point of view. It's really about when we look at our ownership within IBM.
So we break down our offerings to different teams that will own
a microservice through the entire life cycle of that given component.
So we sit down together with offering management development and design and we
go through design thinking and think about
how we're going to actually build something
and then that team owns it all the way through rolling it into production.
So they are the ones that will get paged out at
2 a.m. on a weekend if something breaks for their component.
So it's,
it's about life cycle ownership.
And then also of course, most important here is the security of that
and building that in all the way from step one at the design
thinking workshop to running it in production
and going through obviously within IBM,
we've got a number of regulations that we have
to adhere to before any component can go live,
which is running out in public cloud.
So they are responsible for that end to end.
Yeah,
because one thing I've I'm really noticing is that security in general is getting
much easier as the software teams mature,
you know,
because I literally remember time when people using source code control was like,
that was magic,
you know. No, like seriously, like, remember what was it?
Uh Joel Spolsky on software.
One of his, I think it was he that wrote, you know,
essentially when you're interviewing for a job,
ask them if they use source control and if they don't run away,
you know, and of course,
nowadays that would be unthinkable to not use source control.
Although there are apparently projects that still don't use source control.
And I'm, I'm just wondering how much of this security is becoming
just more possible due to the maturity model,
you know, being able to do change management when you have.
I mean, I'm curious, how big of, of projects are we talking here? Because I've seen,
you know,
some that are two or three containers and I've seen
some products now that are 20 or 30 different containers.
Exactly. So I think the key point that you made is that it's really about
automating everything and defining everything as code.
So that way we've got repeatable
um auditable processes when we're going through this delivery
of some new capability or some new component.
And even though we may be using different tools, we've got,
I don't even know how many number of different source code tools or build tools,
but ultimately, they are all driven by a common CIC
D pipeline
to build at the end.
So giving that automation, that insight, I think is extremely important.
And then as far as the scale, like you said,
there is really a broad range today that we are seeing from,
I've got some capability that I'm enhancing and it's one or two containers
up to some very large and complex microservice
architectures that could have 75 different microservice components.
And then each of those of course are scaled out.
So we are talking hundreds of containers within this architecture.
That is awesome. I I think back to the days when containers started
and the the idea of being able to
run and manage hundreds of containers simultaneously was
probably crazy.
So I I guess you mentioned C I CD and this is something that is,
is always near and dear to my heart, especially when it comes to security is
explain to me how you guys are tackling the issue of needing to kind
of continuously refresh and update your containers in a manner that also doesn't,
you know, overburden your poor ops team who has to keep the lights on,
right.
So again, back to automation when what we have in IBM cloud,
we have a component called vulnerability advisor
which will introspect every layer and every
image for not only known vulnerabilities but
then also policy violations based on ISO
27,000.
So do you have remote logins enabled and weak passwords and things like that.
There's other tools out there that we partner with,
whether it's twist lock or Aqua or SISIG or probably, you know, 20 others.
So the point is there's a lot of ways that you can
build in this kind of security and this checking into that CIC
pipeline.
So in our process, we actually do a vulnerability scan.
So before we instantiate a live container,
we introspect that image for these vulnerabilities.
And if it fails, then we manually stop, well,
we automatically stop that production train.
So that way something can
get deployed. Now, if
it passes, then it continues to progress through
in the way our pipeline works internally is
that we can automatically deploy to different environments
once it goes out to production, which again is our public cloud.
There is a manual gate and it has to go through and then be
approved to ensure that we've got the right things in place like automated,
run books and things like that.
OK. So, so you keep mentioning your public cloud and I'm curious
what is,
what are you talking about here?
Is this IB M's cloud and what is the,
are the other containers you're deploying running the cloud
or are they projects running in the cloud?
All of the above? So IBM cloud is our,
it's,
it's really the umbrella for our platform running
from formally known as IBM blue mix,
which was a platform as a service cloud foundry only offering.
Since then, it's evolved,
we also acquired softlayer a number of years ago to provide our
infrastructure as a service and networks and storage and net layer.
So now bloom mix and soft layer
are combined to one under IBM cloud.
In IBM cloud,
we've got 170 services IBM provided as well as third party and open source tools.
So things like Watson or weatherdata or IOT
and when our customers come to IBM cloud,
they can use what we call the IBM cloud container service
to create single tenant Kubernetes
clusters to deploy and run containerized workloads.
We also the other side of that
is that a number of our internal teams are reformatting to
run as containers and microservices and run at the IBM cloud.
So our largest is really
Watson. So hopefully everyone has heard about Watson.
It started out as a way to compete on Jeopardy, but now it's actually doing real work.
So we've got Watson helping education and government
and users in business on how to solve things and create chat bots.
They're all running on containers via our Kernes
container service.
And I guess you also spiked my interest by mentioning Kubernetes. So
Kubernetes is obviously a very open source project
and
it it's kind of become the container orchestration standard. Now, I I guess and
I would you mind speaking for a moment on kind of
how Kubernetes fits into all this and and what what it does
as well as you know, let,
let's give it kind of that security angle
of why is this level of orchestration important,
especially for security?
Certainly.
So when you think about kind of the
container ecosystem and we've got the foundation building blocks
that everyone thinks and hears Docker,
but we really mean open container initiative standards.
So if you're building on that engine, that image format, that registry format,
that's what I consider the foundational level.
And as you get started with containers,
Docker has made it very easy to install on your laptop,
whether you're running Mac Linux or Windows and get started very quickly.
The reality is you start to increase that complexity.
You need some way to kind of orchestrate not
only that day one deployment of your workloads,
but ongoing management and maintenance and scalability and all these things.
So then comes in kind of this container orchestration layer. And you're right
before there were several options. You had Dockers Swarm, you had
Kernes,
you had
marathon and several others.
Kubernetes
seems to have won the day from a popularity perspective.
IBM invested 100% in Kubernetes.
We contribute not only upstream in the communities,
but we also build our offerings using that upstream version of Kubernetes.
Now,
when you as a user in IBM cloud, you deploy that cluster, like I said,
they're all single tenant and dedicated to you.
So you've got your own isolated compute network and storage to run kubernetes
and
all of the communication
in our case from the master node,
which is essentially the brains of your cluster to
your worker nodes where your containerized apps are running.
It's all done via encrypted VPN tunnel.
So we're really ensuring that security, like I said, is baked in end to end.
So we secure that communication,
we secure the isolation users control which
microservices have outbound connectivity because the reality is
the majority will ever only need to communicate
via some private non routed IP space,
not out over the public internet.
That's, that's huge. I mean, and there was just like the mem
cash D stuff where there was essentially a huge dos
attack
ddos
because people had services available to the
internet that had no business being there.
And so this is that, that, that's really exciting and,
and I applaud you guys for kind of taking that approach
because I think less is more in, in this case, right? Sorry.
The thing that just gets me is we're
finally practicing what we've been preaching for.
What is it now? 60 years of, you know, minimized privilege,
like straight up. Right. And,
but the thing is until now there's been no real way to do this at scale.
You know, it's all been manually tweaked conf figs and hopefully everybody got it.
Right.
Exactly. And so you bring up a great point in that
we've been preaching this, but the reality was,
it wasn't easy to do before container technology came to the forefront because now
it includes all of these kind of security capabilities out of the box.
So I as an end user don't need to learn
100 new things.
I'm just using some new container technology because it allows me to package my
app and all my dependencies and move it from my environment to yours.
It will eliminate the whole problem of, you know, it works here.
I don't know, doesn't work in your environment clearly. That's your problem. So
we get that benefit.
But then we're also pulling along all of these inherent security benefits as well.
Yeah, totally. Totally. And
the story,
I'll tell you just because you're from IBM is
I was an ax administrator like 10,000 years ago
and I remember the attitude was how much crap can we run in this one machine? Right?
Which was,
which is totally the way it was done in hindsight.
Thank goodness,
everything was much smaller and you didn't worry as much about security,
but like it was a total train wreck, right where there were,
there were like 20 plus services running and,
and, and I look at this kind of the attitude now with microservices and,
oh my goodness, it's so much nicer.
Yeah.
And what's great is, you know,
obviously we still have a huge customer base that are running on
the P Linux servers and Z. Linux
mainframes are not dead.
So we've got those customers that are modernizing
their applications are developing new cloud native applications
using Docker Tech
on those existing platforms.
-- So
-- how does that work if you're kind of trying
to use a container on say a non standard Linux?
So some some of those packages will actually run
the same consistently on X or P or Z.
However,
there are others that have dependencies down kind of the architecture level.
If you're thinking about P and Z, there's Indian ness that may be associated with A,
we should,
we should actually clarify because my suspicion is much of the audience
has no idea what you're talking about when you say P and Z
I have thankfully never had to deal with these.
All right. So let's back up and give a quick intro.
So IBM has been a long time hardware manufacturer.
So we've got different architecture types,
we're familiar with kind of the X or the intel A
T based hardware.
Um But we also have these things that are called power. So we shorten it to P
which used to run A
and now it runs P Linux or power Linux or open power.
And then we've got formerly the mainframes which are now
Zlin
and they run just a Z architecture base.
And the premise being that, you know,
they're building in security and scalability and things to their
texture.
And at a time,
we really ran a majority of private data centers and large financial institutions
-- and that hardware is still around despite a lot of movement to the
-- cloud.
Yeah, I mean,
my understanding of the Z series is that
you have hot swappable ram and hot swappable CPU
-- It was crazy.
-- Like
-- I can't even imagine what that requires from an engineering point of
-- view.
Yeah, there was definitely a lot of, you know,
engineering feats accomplished with that hardware and it still runs, like I said,
in a lot of data centers for a lot of our customers and now they're
with that investment that they already have,
they're looking to enhance and modernize and
build new with containers and microservices,
-- which is,
-- which is really cool.
And I applaud IBM for kind of thinking ahead versus taking the attitude of, you know,
we got you, now you'll do what we tell you to do.
Well, I'm curious, do you find customers,
do they really want to switch to containers or are they switching to containers?
Because essentially like,
you know,
that's where the talent in the market is going and that's becoming the new normal.
It's probably a combination of both because
you're right, a lot of the new developers,
that's what they're focusing on in some new modern languages.
They are not, you know, programming and Cobalt and all these other things anymore.
So
there's that part of it,
but then there's also the part of the inherent
benefits that you get from a microservices architecture.
So I can
scale out different components based on
their utilization and their workload requirements
or I can roll out new versions of a given component
of my architecture without adversely affecting the rest of the architecture.
So gone are the days of ok.
Well, we've got this upgrade, I need to shut the entire application down.
I hope that it upgrades successfully and then I
hope that it comes back online and actually works.
So now we're kind of breaking down the architecture and making
those upgrades and those scaling points much more fine grained.
Well,
the other big capability I've seen especially with
containers is the ability to roll back,
you know, to a known good version and state,
which is not always so easy with a monolithic app.
Absolutely, because we are just dealing with new versions of Docker images.
So as we build some new capability or add some fix, we have the new version,
but we also have the existing known good version.
So we can set a policy to roll out
at any rate and pace that we define.
And if it works great, let's pull out and roll out the rest of it.
But if something fails, then we just roll back to that
known good because
not only are we adding new capabilities in this manner, but we're also
that's how we roll out our security fixes and updates
in a container in microservices world.
We're not patching live containers anymore.
We're remediating the base images that they
were deployed from and redeploying that workload.
So it really changes kind of the paradigm
around how we maintain security in this architecture.
So can I ask when you're deploying, say a security fix in this manner,
do you guys just deploy, say like 10% of the fleet and then
wait and see for a little while to make sure it doesn't explode or do you just go all in?
We definitely go in a staged approach
because we want to minimize
that blast radius.
If something goes wrong and we get a patch that at scale does not perform or operate,
then we want to ensure that again, we are kind of minimizing
our
effect that could be felt by our user. So
Kubernetes has some of this capability baked into it already
to allow you these kind of roll out plans.
But one of the areas where we are contributing
to the open source is a project called is
O
and this was announced jointly with IBM Google and Lyft back in April of 2017.
And what Isio does, it basically sits on top of her orchestrator.
So in this case, Kubernetes
and gives you more control over,
rolling out new versions and new updates to your microservice architecture
and giving you that in depth telemetry and reporting and
what's failing where
latencies giving you insight to what is
really a very complex microservice architecture.
Well, and that's one thing you, you mentioned earlier was this whole concept.
And I've heard this term quite a few times is this microservices fabric?
And can you maybe unpack that for us a bit?
Because I've, I've heard it used a couple of different ways now.
Certainly. So
when you think about container use cases,
it doesn't have to be some new cloud native microservices based architecture.
Obviously, that's great.
It's a great use case for containers,
but we're also seeing a lot of kind of lift and modernize your existing apps.
So there's
those two main use cases.
If you are going down the path of a microservices by either
refactoring some existing monolithic app or developing some new cloud native app.
Then you need this microservices mesh,
which basically gives you the insight to a complex world.
So when you think about is
and there's a number of things out there,
the Netflix
Oss
stack
in others that provide similar things,
but we thought there were some capabilities
missing and that's why we jointly went into
Isdo here with Google and Lyft. And so what is
will do
is provide.
So there's four main tenants.
The first is around intelligent routing and load balancing. So that's what allows
to roll out new versions in a controlled manner and say either,
you know, 30% of this component gets rolled out to a new version or you know,
Josh is my guinea pig when you log in, you're going to see the new version.
So it gives you a lot of control in that
manner and roll out or roll back if something fails.
The second thing is around resiliency across languages and platforms.
So it's really meant to be infrastructure and language and platform agnostic.
So you can take
SDO, we'd love you to run it
in IBM cloud,
but you can run it on Prem, you can run it
in Aws Microsoft Google. It really doesn't matter.
You can use it consistently and your
developers don't need to change their language.
So if they're developing in go or you know, whatever they develop in
that doesn't change with ST
the third thing is around fleet wide policy enforcement.
So this is important, you can install a certificate, authority
and control and determine which components can talk to each other because
maybe A can talk to B but A can't talk to C so is
gives you that enforcement. And then the fourth thing which I mentioned was
that in depth telemetry and reporting because
as the complexity increases, you need to figure out where latencies,
what's actually causing the issue.
Um If I have different time outs from one microservice to another,
where is the breakdown actually happening?
-- So
-- you, you piqued my interest when you said
you can set policies so say A can't talk to C but it can talk to B
and that sounds
immensely powerful.
And, and I'm curious,
is sto controlling that on the on the network
layer or is there something else going on here?
Exactly. So it's at the network layer, you can define
who can actually communicate it
similar to a containerized firewall. Essentially, you can think of it like that.
So the way
envoy deploys, which is a via sidecar, then you can define that policy from the ISTE
pilot, which is essentially the brains of
iso
and define who can communicate with each other.
So again, it just minimizes the attack surface within your architecture.
That's amazing.
I mean, look anyone
done any security work before knows that lateral movement is where it's at, right?
You just got to get in and then you're good to go.
But obviously this,
this sounds like it totally negates the concept of lateral movement.
Absolutely.
So I mean,
you're spot on because you think a lot of North South traffic and we have rules there
to limit who can get in and out and ports and ips and things like that.
But that East West traffic
is very important as well because we see a lot of attacks where you come in and then
you jump from one container to another or you
kill the first container that you came in on to try and hide your track.
So it's very important to limit
the connectivity inside the architecture as well.
There was a really good CCC talk about exploiting containers and using things,
for example, like
generating logs or generating like events and activities
within Amazon web services that would then,
you know, sort of leak out publicly, you know, even though that specific container,
for example, couldn't talk to the internet,
it could talk to other systems that ultimately were attached to the internet.
Exactly.
And so there's a lot of,
there's a lot of vendors out there providing that kind of real time assessment
and, you know, I don't want to use machine learning because it's very overused,
but basically building these real time policies
and detecting anomalies in your architecture.
So if something like that is happening, that is not how you expect it,
it will flag you and then you'll either be able to block it or say yes, yes,
that's fine and allow it.
So let me ask,
then you mentioned machine learning and like you guys literally have an A I, right?
You're one of the few companies that can claim to actually have an A I.
No. Are you, are you leveraging Watson in any way to do any of this clever stuff?
Yeah, definitely.
So we're like you said, we're very fortunate to have our friends at Watson, you know,
right down the hall from us.
So we work with them to build in
these cognitive solutions. So it's
not only at kind of the container live container running perspective of, you know,
who is speaking to whom and is that allowed?
And is there,
you know, some,
some spike in resources or something that we're not really expecting to happen.
So we've got that built in.
We also use Watson in a lot of other ways in our platform from, you know,
cognitive chat bots or extending your applications
using the breadth of Watson capabilities.
So we're definitely fortunate to have them with us.
-- So
-- you're saying we should welcome our new A I overlords in the cloud.
They're, they're very powerful and it can be very helpful to us.
-- So, yeah, and we know
-- they can beat us at Jeopardy. Right.
Absolutely. And chess,
-- one
-- last thing you'd mentioned and I just saw on the
website while looking at it,
you'd mentioned about,
you know, faults and fault management. And I'm actually looking at this page about
Isio and it mentions
it has the capability of fault injection. And
I'm just, I'm curious what drove you guys to, to include that like,
is this like the chaos gorilla and chaos monkey that Netflix uses?
Yes, you are exactly right by injecting
some fault or some chaos or some failure?
It forces you to think about your
architecture and where potential breaking points are
when I talk to customers.
And I tell them that, you know, containers are very powerful,
but they can also allow you to make poor decisions
by using injecting fault and issues into your architecture.
You will be able to identify and create more highly available applications
for
all the way at the data center level,
all the way down to the actual application components.
So I'm curious,
is this something you can actually like build into your sort of live system?
Saying, for example, you know,
I want 1% of my systems to fail daily.
Yes.
So you can define kind of how granular or how
chaotic you want a particular fault injection to be.
And we actually do this, we call it fire drill Friday internally where
a particular microservice team
will go through this.
And it's basically a way to test how resilient their component is for failure.
And so that the SRE team,
the site reliable engineering team will inject failure and figure
out what the breaking point is for their component.
Wow, nice.
Because one thing I'm seeing increasingly is, you know,
the teams that do do this also end up at a state where, you know,
they're just having such a high baseline of
failure when there's an actual real failure.
They're like, yeah, that's like barely a statistical blip now.
Exactly.
And it's important because of that ownership from the
end to end for those teams to see that.
So it's no longer I as a developer, I write something. It's, it's awesome.
I throw it over the fence. Good luck.
-- So now I need to think about that entire breadth of that
-- man.
Those were the good old days. Right.
Exactly.
I do not miss them at all.
No, no, I know. I know.
I do remember that when or my favorite was you'd give the operations,
people instructions that were wrong
and they
beat their heads on their desk for days because
they didn't want to ask you too many questions.
It was. Oh, man, it's a miracle. Anything worked. Right.
Yeah, I just,
I remember like literally all the time we
spent getting standing PHP applications up with dependencies.
-- Like seriously, how many tens of hundreds of hours did we spend doing that?
-- Too many?
Too many?
Only to find out the developer was running some other version of
Linux with a different version of the package that you could get
seriously.
Alright. Alright. So I I think it's probably time to start taking this one home.
So I guess
Chris, do you have any any thoughts for us around?
Just kind of general advice for container security in in
the the new and exciting world we live in.
-- So
-- my perspective would be that to build on and leverage open
source tools where you can to give you kind of that consistent user experience.
I've talked about how we're using open source at kind of the
engine level and then as we go up the stack to Kubernetes
and I've talked about
Isdo,
I encourage all of your listeners to go out, use it, contribute,
we're taking pull requests.
So that's, you know, we're excited about that.
There are other open source projects that I will briefly mention as well because
in line with open source, we announced a project called Graphia,
which is an open source project with IBM and Google.
And it's basically
the goal is to provide this centralized structured
knowledge base of vulnerability data.
So that way instead of everyone maintaining their
own graffias will allow this as kind of the
source of truth to govern your entire software supply chain.
And then within Graffias, there is a component called CRIS
which allows you again as an organization to set that Kubernetes governance policy
on data that's stored in the Graphia project. So
I think it's really important for all of us as consumers and whether you are running
it on IBM cloud or any other cloud
to build on consistent open source tools and projects
and then build on top of that. So
to me,
that's really our point of view from IBM
is to invest in these open source projects where
we are not only
using them and building offerings on top of it,
but we also have core contributors that are out in each of these various projects,
helping them, helping steer the direction of these various projects.
Wow, that, that sounds amazing. You just hit us with a bunch of stuff.
We'll put in the show notes
for, for the listeners and in fact, you, you spiked my interest as well.
So I can't, I can't wait to look this up. So
wonderful. Well, thank you so much Chris.
We really appreciate the time and we look forward
to having you back again in the near future.
So I guess thank you, Kurt. Thank you, Chris. Thank you listeners.
If anyone wants to see the show notes for the various things discussed today,
you can help
source security podcast.com.
You can use the Pound Os S podcast hashtag to get our attention on social media.
And if nothing else, you two gentlemen have a fabulous rest of your day.
Thank you, sir.
Thanks
the