Hello and welcome to episode 98 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Pressers.
It has just been one of those weeks. You know that?
Oh, yeah.
And everything from the horrible security news to the fact that this is
uh episode 98 take two because I screwed up the first one.
But,
-- um, and
-- I love that when you finally got your real microphone working.
I'm like, wait, what happened to your voice?
Yes, that's right. I sound exciting now.
Oh, my goodness. Anyway, anyway,
I guess the good news is we haven't killed anybody this week
not to make
light.
But
I, I just, ok, we have to lead with this because this,
do you want to read the quote or shall I?
I'll let you do it.
Ok. So this is from the N TSB crash, uh preliminary crash report.
So the N TSB, the National Transport
should
-- clarify.
-- This is the Uber crash. That was
as far as we know the, the first self driving car to like hit in and kill a human.
Well, I,
I would say that it's, well, we'll get into that.
So
according to Uber, the agency said, quote,
emergency braking maneuvers are not enabled while the vehicle is under
computer control to reduce the potential for erratic vehicle behavior.
The vehicle operator is relied on to intervene and take action.
The system is not designed to alert the operator. End quote.
I don't even know what to say about that.
-- Well, they designed a system that will kill somebody is what they did.
-- Seriously.
I mean, I read that three times when you sent it to me and thought this,
this has got to be a typo.
It's crazy.
Yeah.
Well, and what's even worse though is if you read the full uh preliminary report,
um,
they have a system in the console that the, like, so the human operator is,
is responsible for sort of reading output on this console
system because when you see the video of the guy,
he's like looking down and I'm like, is he on his phone,
like going on reddit or something while he's, you know,
supposed to be monitoring the system?
No, he's actually doing his job, which is
looking down at the console and interacting with it in the sense of
he's supposed to flag interesting events for later review and stuff.
So not only so, so you have a system that can fail
and if it fails, it doesn't warn the human
and the human is expected to take over and the human already has a high cognitive load
in that they're supposed to be doing other stuff like
interacting with this console that they have to look down at
like this is crazy.
So like the the human beings, situational awareness cannot be sufficient.
Well, and and and it clearly wasn't right?
Because the poor guy, you see him look up and just the horror on his face, right?
You know, he just doesn't have time
to react.
Oh
my goodness.
And
I, so yeah, this is a, this is a perfect example of like,
literally I read this and I'm like, this has to end in death.
There's, there's statistically there's no other outcome,
but you just can't get lucky enough for the system not to fail at some point.
Yeah. It, I,
I guess this is one of the,
the problems with
putting like real things, interacting with societies, historically speaking,
most of our computer systems have kind of been off in
a server room and they didn't make a huge difference and,
and, you know, putting in my security hat,
if you get hacked,
nobody dies, it doesn't really matter. Right?
But now that we have like things in the world,
it does matter and it is a big deal.
I think Schneier
put it best. These aren't computers
with stuff, this is stuff with a computer. This is a car,
this is a fridge with a computer. This is a chemical plant with a computer,
right?
This isn't a computer just hooked up to some, you know,
fridge doing something cutesy.
No, this is legitimately like, uh, how much does this vehicle weigh?
Um,
yeah, it's, it's a 2017 Volvo XC 90 which is a pretty damn big heavy car.
And, I mean, when you think about the kinetic energy of that thing doing, like,
uh, what was it doing?
47 miles an hour or something?
I, I have no idea.
I, I purposely not looked into this too much just because it's, it's,
it's horrifying to me and, and I don't want to watch any of the videos or,
or learn too much, I guess.
Yeah.
Um, yeah, the speed limit there was 45
MPH.
So, yeah, I mean,
you do the math and the kinetic energy of this thing is considerable.
Right? As well. You look at, well, the, the Toronto uh truck attack,
right?
This guy drove a truck down the sidewalk trying to drive over women and killed,
you know, about a dozen people.
Right.
Um, but looking at this, I mean, this is literally,
you know,
so classical engineers like mechanical engineers and chemical engineers,
you know, they,
there's a reason it's hard to become one of them and there's
a reason you have designations like professional engineer that can then,
you know, sign off on plans that are then built
like bridges and chemical plants, right? Because if those things are built wrong,
they collapse and people die.
Yep. Yep.
This is a perfect example of something where, I don't know what's worse.
Did somebody know that this is like,
did somebody at Uber consciously make this decision
or, you know, was it kind of like the original, uh,
remember the iphone with the external antenna that
had a problem with how you hold it?
Right. No. So was this a case of where, like two different groups?
Like one group is like, oh, let's disable emergency braking.
So we don't keep getting rear ended, right? Because every time like
the computer sees something funny, like a shopping bag,
it's gonna like come to a screeching halt and then you're gonna get rear ended.
Like,
because Google has discovered right now that they're recording
how often they get rear ended at red lights.
Um,
you know,
and conversely then the other group was like, oh, you know,
the operator will take action uh, when something bad happens and, um,
you know,
whoever's working on the U I will probably make
sure that they know that they should be doing something
and, and it just didn't happen.
So I like, I don't know what's worse that they, that they built this system
and consciously made this choice that resulted in a death
or
they
didn't have enough, you know,
control an insight over what they were building to
realize that this was going to be a problem.
It's almost certainly the case of multiple groups
not understanding what the other groups are doing
because let's face it, nobody is going to make a conscious decision
to do this.
This is just, well,
-- they
-- might if they didn't understand it because remember the Challenger disaster,
they made a conscious decision to launch
when the old rings had been subjected to a temperature
that was colder than they were rated for blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah.
And, yeah, they, they made a conscious decision.
You know, there's that one infamous powerpoint slide, you know, oh,
what's the guy's name?
The uh, information display guy Tufty,
right. Edward Tufty. I've got all these books. They're beautiful
and, you know,
like literally one bad powerpoint slide and a decision by
some managers to keep to the schedule and voila.
Right?
And, and it, it, it can happen. But again, that was, that was a mistake,
right? And that was,
this is almost certainly a mistake. I guarantee. Nobody said we need to do this.
This is the result
of poor communication and let's face it.
The vast majority of accidents in the world are the result of poor communication.
Right.
Yeah.
Well, that's, yeah, when I was binge watching all of those airline disaster things,
it, it seems to really boil down to a couple of core things.
Number one, not doing maintenance correctly and,
and quite often the root cause of not doing maintenance correctly is, you know,
people don't know how to do it correctly or they,
in one case they, yeah, they didn't communicate the day shift and the night shift,
the night shift took out a bunch of bolts
and the day shift, like,
literally didn't put them back in because they weren't told that they were taken out
and like the, the, the, the, the rear
Aron of the plane fell off funnily enough because, you know, if it's not bolted on,
it will fall off.
Imagine that.
And so,
you know, and then the next big one seems to be losing situational awareness, right?
Where something happens and they,
they focus on the wrong things like that plane that crashed into the Everglades,
you know, about 60 years ago, because they were fiddling with a broken fuse.
Wow.
Right.
And they spent so much time and effort,
mentally fiddling with this broken fuse and trying to deal with it.
But yeah, they crashed into the Everglades.
Um
Yeah, so, yeah, fundamentally a lot of this is,
is bad communication and lack of situational awareness.
And
yeah, I just
ii I literally don't know what to say at this point because this is a,
a really great example of how not to build
a system because like the system has a failed deadly condition.
You know, it encounters an emergency
and
trusts a human to react to it. But doesn't tell the human,
nobody's going to disagree with you.
That that's a huge problem.
But unfortunately, in many instances like this,
this is what happens is something fails,
it gets studied and you make sure it never happens again.
Well, and to that point, for example,
I'm going to be proposing ac we identifier for this where,
because this is an increasing thing
where we have these human computer interactions
and we don't fully understand them yet
because this is all new.
Yeah, I mean, it's, it's totally accurate, I think, and,
and historically speaking,
most security issues
were, were caused by a computer just sitting there doing nothing specifically.
There's some right.
There's like some cross site scripting and things, but generally speaking,
we still blame the machine,
right? We don't blame the interaction in many instances.
There have been some things with what like URL S showing
the wrong.
Well, I shouldn't say wrong but we'll say confusing
domain names for example. But,
but even then we tend to blame the machine more than the interaction, right?
Yeah.
Well, it's uh there was that recent video,
remember of that ski lift just destroying itself.
And apparently what happened is the uh there was a power outage and
then they didn't kind of bring the ski lift back online correctly.
Like they basically hit the wrong buttons
and somebody pointed out that,
I mean, this is a modern computerized ski lift.
This isn't some like 50 year old piece of garbage.
But if you build a computer system that can experience
a, a reasonably typical fault condition of, you know, the power is lost
because
that is a pretty common fault condition that and if you,
you don't do the exact right steps to bring it back online, it like,
basically destroys itself.
You, you can't really blame the humans for that.
Like somebody built a system that was going to fail at some point,
you know.
Yeah,
totally, man.
Right. And that's why we have,
you know, and, and I get that some systems are so complex.
It's really hard to define a fail safe condition like an oil refinery or, you know,
like things that are just massive, like do you want that valve open or shut?
Right? If you suddenly shut the valve,
the, the, the,
the fluid or whatever flowing towards it might burst
the pipe if it's at a certain speed,
right?
Because it hits that closed valve and you know what, right physics
and so, you know, like things like, for example, self driving cars, yeah, I mean,
it's screeching to a stop, a fail safe condition.
Well,
yet not if you're on the highway that can actually be really bad in daylight,
you know, maybe,
maybe it's better to run over that rabbit, like sucks to be the rabbit, but,
you know, better than
slamming on your brakes and heavy traffic.
So, yeah, defining a fail safe condition can be difficult.
And that maybe that's part of what happened here, right? Is they,
they, you know,
decided that the slamming on your brakes and getting
rear ended constantly was not the way to go.
Well.
No, you know, you know what,
this is actually the first thing I thought of is it was what one or two episodes ago,
we were discussing automation
and
automation basically either has to be all or none.
And expecting humans to be involved in any way is, is failure is the only option.
And this is exactly that
if, if the car had been able to make all of the decisions on its own,
we wouldn't be having this conversation right now.
But because
they decided to let a human interact and
then there was a breakdown in communication.
Now we're having this horrible conversation.
Well, and here's the brutal truth. Right.
They could have Uber could in theory create like a,
you know, create a range for them to test on like a closed circuit
and have, you know, like those, those cardboard things on tracks, you know,
that get pulled out, like, you know, in the old
movies where the kids are doing drivers. Right.
And the little like girl on a bicycle,
cardboard thing pops out and they run over it and they're like,
uh,
but, you know, they could have done that. They could have built a closed range that's
like with no humans on it.
I did. They though, it
wouldn't
surprise
me. They did.
Well, if they did, they certainly didn't test
enough because somebody walking with a bicycle at night
or, I mean, look, I'm, I'm not going to make an assumption here.
II, I agree with you that it seems common
and it's completely possible they,
they tested this and it's also completely possible that this,
this particular change that resulted in disaster was made,
you know, shortly before it happened.
Right.
There's, there's so many unknowns here and I guess fundamentally what,
what I think I'm going to call it as is just
humans can't be involved. It has to be 100% automated.
I, I think that and more than that though,
we really have to look at how we define computer human
interaction because the next topic we're going to bring up,
-- we don't define it. The computer
-- doesn't
trust me.
No, no, no, because, well, no,
because some things you have to have computer human interaction because
so the next topic we're going to talk about was Alexa,
right?
Alexa
email all my information to somebody else
and that's a perfect example. So,
-- so what happened here is somebody got a call
-- from,
I
apologize in advance of what I just said, messed with anyone's Alexa.
But that is
Alexa.
Buy me a dollhouse.
But here's the thing, right?
So what happened is somebody basically got an email or a phone? I forget a phone call.
I forget which from a client saying basically, like, uh you know,
you just emailed me like a recording of a conversation,
uh like that you didn't seem to be aware of.
And what fundamentally happened is this couple was talking in their
domicile
and they triggered their Alexa
accidentally and then Alexa recorded a bit and then,
um essentially they said some words that Alexa interpreted as, you know,
uh send this message to a contact and then it, you know,
waited some more to listen to them and then
chose a contact from what they said.
And see, here's the thing, right?
Typically, when we interact with a computer or a machine,
we are very explicitly interacting with it, right?
Like I'm sitting on my computer and I'm banging away at the keyboard, right?
I'm not going to accidentally do that,
you know, I'm not going to accidentally move my mouse and click stuff, all of them.
Actually, I have accidentally put stuff on the space bar and been like,
why is this video not working
-- or,
-- you know,
the cat,
it just walks
until recently. We've never had machines that opportunistically
wait and watch and watch or listen to us and then take action based on that without
us maybe explicitly being aware that that is happening.
And so what I'm realizing is these aren't like an Alexa
isn't really a computer anymore. It's kind of more like a dog
that's just like sitting there waiting for you to be like, OK, let's go for a walk,
right? And then the dog jumps up and goes and runs to the door and
you're like, oh, no, no, sorry. I was on the phone talking to somebody,
you know,
I'm familiar with that problem.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, because you have a dog, right.
Um, and so that's,
I think that's the thing. Right.
Is,
is up until now machines have effectively been dumb
and they've only done what we tell them to do
and
the way we tell them to do things has
keyboard and mouse or buttons and switches.
Or I'm sitting in my car and I'm smashing the gas pedal and steering
the, you know,
I explicitly know that I'm dealing with the machine and telling it what to do versus,
you know, if my Alexa
is turned on, right it II I was actually thinking of leaving it on for this episode,
but I decided it would get too annoying
right
with it.
Uh Jumping on and off.
Um
But uh
what, what are you doing? Are you, are you getting your,
I'm actually plugging, I'm just plugging it in because why not?
-- Let's see how bad this
-- is. Oh man.
Uh
Is there an on off one? Oh, there we go.
Ok. It's got a blue ring. It's happy.
Um So yeah, I mean, traditionally
we don't have machine and, and the other thing is, you know,
machines didn't have computer vision systems
or hearing systems that could actually,
you know, with the compute power available. Actually
listen and understand us
like that's fundamentally pretty damn amazing in my mind,
you know.
-- No, it is. It's, it's very impressive.
-- I'm afraid to say a word.
Oh,
it just made its ding dong.
It's a shame you have headphones on because then I could converse with your Alexa.
But
so here's, you know what this made me think of actually is,
have you ever seen those, those kind of examples where someone will, will, like,
teach a machine learning algorithm how to identify numbers, right?
And, and it'll get it right.
It starts doing a really good job and then you show it like
a picture of a dog and it'll say that's a number four.
No, that's a dog.
Well, and that's a good, we now have ac we classification for essentially
giving malicious data while training an A I or ML to like subvert it,
it
doesn't,
it doesn't need malicious data even. I mean, this Alexa
example, like there was nothing malicious going on. It was just Alexa
got confused
and, and it was a
picture of a
dog.
No, Alexa
did what it was supposed to do, which is it listened for its name and then it didn't,
it listened for voice commands.
But the thing is it, see when it does this, it puts the blue ring on
but it doesn't make noise or anything.
So if you're not physically in the room with it,
you wouldn't know as a human being, right?
Um This is what came up with the, with the, so we recently on the CV E board,
there was that issue with Alexa
where
uh there's a repro feature where basically
uh
Alexa
will listen for a command
and if it doesn't hear a command after eight seconds, it can rep prompt,
it can be like, excuse me, I didn't hear you or whatever
and it will listen and wait for you to give it a command
and it turns out that,
that, oh, it just made a funny noise.
Um And so it turns out bad guys could, you know, set up an Alexa skill,
which would hit the rep prompt feature endlessly.
And essentially, thus put Alexa into permanently recording mode.
That's exciting
the device has. So the one I have,
it's the little, it's about the size of a large pop can,
it has seven very sensitive microphones,
right?
So it can not only tell, it can not only listen,
but it can do directional sound and stuff.
And so
I don't have to be in the room for this thing to hear me.
And again, that goes back to that thing of like, typically when we like when I'm
hitting the remote control for my TV, I'm poking away at it,
you know, I'm not accidentally being like, hey, you know, did you see that,
you know, ludicrous show on channel four last night?
And then all of a sudden your TV turns on to channel four, right?
That's the future man, it's coming.
So
I think fundamentally, like I said, it boils down to machines. Used to be dumb.
But now they're about as smart as a dog in
some ways when it comes to paying attention to us.
And so,
you know, they're like, yeah, I mean,
I would love to see what would happen if you yell, you know, treats or, uh,
I know with my, uh, my parents cat, if you, um,
if you crack open a tin,
like, you know, the noise the can opener makes,
yeah, that cat's there in like three seconds and she's old and lazy.
But you know, she hears that noise
and boom, she's in the kitchen.
They know
they know.
But, but so far the Alexa
is unable to run to the kitchen. So we have that going for us.
That's what we need, we need like like the Sony Io with an Alexa
tape to it.
Well, no, the problem is like for example, your Alexa skills could do that.
They could interact with your vacuuming system or whatever, right?
Alexa
vacuum the floor.
Yeah. And it would, yeah,
that, that stuff is, that's the whole point of it
probably works. I'm sure it does it today
Alexa kill, right? Like it's coming.
Yeah.
So I'm I'm really think because for example,
I've disabled Siri on all of my Apple devices.
You remember that one show we did where I was like,
I've disabled Siri on all of my devices and my phone's like,
how can I help you? And I'm like,
because yeah,
because what happened is I did a
software update which reset that setting apparently.
And now that I say that
what is my phone doing?
Right.
And, and, you know, you know what that reminds me of is when, like,
you go into Twitter and Twitter used to be the worst of this.
We'd go into Twitter and, like,
turn off all the stupid alerting functionality and then the Twitter
app would update itself and it would turn everything back on.
I was like, whoa.
And they don't anymore. But like, that was, ah, that was so annoying.
I, I think fundamentally what this really boils down to is
we as in, like,
we as an industry don't have a lot of
experience with this kind of computer human interaction.
Like we just don't
think it's safe to say like humanity doesn't
have
this kind of interaction.
Yeah. And I mean, a great example of this is cellphones, right? Like when cell,
when smartphones came out,
I wouldn't have guessed now that on a regular basis,
I would see people texting and driving while making left hand turns.
I think that was inevitable.
I mean, there was texting and driving was a problem long before smartphones,
right? It's,
and this is why the solution to that.
But, but ok, here's so, here's something to think about though, is
the solution to texting and driving
isn't to find people or to put up signs that say don't text and drive.
The solution is to build self driving cars. Right.
And, and the solution to something like Alexa,
where you have a device listening to you all the time
is
-- this one gets trickier because its job is to listen.
-- Right.
Well, how do
you, for example, do you maybe make it,
you know, see the problem is you watch things like Star Trek, you know,
the computer human interaction by a voice is horrific.
-- It is so bad and
-- painful. What do you
mean? It's
painful that computer does everything it's told to do
well and,
but you have to like explicitly talk to it,
you have to make sure it's paying attention, things like that, right?
Whereas with the Alexa, it just, you know, does its thing.
Um
So I, I think two things will happen.
Number one, you know,
how do we need to be maybe more formal in our interactions with Alexa?
And number two though is things like Alexa and other machines too in general need to,
you know,
I need to know what their state.
I need to know what's going on more intuitively, right? Because
like right now I know fundamentally my car is going to do only
what I tell it to do because I drive a dumb car.
I look at this Uber car and there's no, like you could not,
you literally could not pay me enough money to get in one
of these Uber cars where it's designed to like not emergency brake,
not tell the operator, there's an emergency and hope that,
that human has enough situational awareness to go deal with the problem,
which they don't,
I mean, let's face it.
But I feel like that's still not,
that's not the Alexa
problem though. Right. I mean, this is, this is
a
part
of, but this is going to be. What about your, um,
I mean, some, some devices are so like those IKEA light bulbs
fundamentally, you know what a light bulb is doing
because it's doing its thing, it's either on or off or making a certain color, right?
You know, so in theory it's quote unquote air quotes here, simple,
but something like an Alexa,
which is like very much a, a general purpose, you know,
um Alexa
drop me a beat.
I'm super impressed,
kick it.
There we go. Right. Like,
ok, Alexa stop,
Alexa stop.
So, I mean, that's a great example, right?
Alexa can do something where when it does it, it's,
it's really obvious that it's doing it,
but like Alexa
record everything I'm saying and email it to Josh,
I'm, I'm gonna be super impressed if this works.
Oh, I hope not. I haven't hooked up any email accounts to it.
Well, no wait, it would be attached to my Amazon account
anyways point being right is
the Alexa machine can do things some of which are really obvious,
like dropping a beat
and it can also do things that are like,
really not obvious like unlocking all the doors in my house.
And I just realized,
as I say that I'm really glad I don't have Alexa hooked up to all my doors locks.
Like I don't have smart locks because
again,
there's way too many failure scenarios that I don't understand.
But for example, having
said this,
do you remember the story about Siri where like some guy's neighbor yelled,
Siri unlocked the front door from outside and it did it.
Yeah,
like it.
I, I guess I, I did all this and I believe it all and I don't know,
I,
I feel like
the answer to this isn't something
-- we yet grasp because this is a new paradigm for everybody
-- in theory,
if the device was smart, like for example,
your dog knows uh let me put it this way.
If I walk up to your dog and I say, let's go for a walk,
your dog's probably gonna look at me and
not get super excited.
He'd be totally
-- all right.
-- Well,
but fundamentally, I mean, ideally we need these, the,
the problem is it's kind of like the self driving car situation
where we need the device to be able to handle it all,
but we're not there yet.
And how do we get there?
And that's part of the problem, right? We have to build these intermediary steps,
what we really need.
Basically, here's what I want.
I want a device that's roughly about as smart as a dog and
that it can tell who I am and who is not me.
Right.
But that's only half the problem.
I mean,
like in the case of these people getting their conversation email to a friend,
Alexa
thought
it was doing the right thing.
And
now, now here's, here's the trick though, is
in order for Alexa
to have known they were having a conversation
that was not involving Alexa,
you would have to send literally all of the audio somewhere else.
Have it processed and then have that central place.
Say, OK, situationally, this is a conversation not involving me. Don't respond.
That opens up like a whole another.
That's how
works by the way
you do
-- that.
-- Well,
no, no, I I, yes, but it's supposed to only send things after you say Alexa,
right? In theory, it's not like sending everything you're telling me right now.
Well,
depending on
that's
supposed to do that or whatever
it might be because you just said record everything I say.
But um
so and, and that's an even tougher case because for example,
maybe somebody only wants to have one Alexa in their house
and they do want to yell at it from other rooms versus
maybe like see,
that's what I was thinking is I was going to keep the Alexa in the workroom.
So and it only kind of explicitly use it in here.
But yeah, no, that thing can hear me from like the kitchen. No problem.
Yeah. Right, man. I mean, it's amazing what some of these microphones can pick up.
Oh Yeah.
Um So it becomes,
yeah, it's just how, you know, how does Alexa,
for example, cue
or tell me like, hey, I think you're trying to tell me something, right?
Like your dog, if you say let's go for a walk, your dog's gonna like perk up,
his ears are up, he's looking at you,
you know, because it's a,
it's a thing in the house that that's reacting to the environment where Alexa
is like
it does react to the environment
because it has that color ring on top and it can talk to me,
you know.
Um for example, it,
well, that's what I'm saying, right?
I clearly it isn't because if you're not in the room with it, you don't see the lights,
right?
So for example,
do we need machines to be more explicit like hot? You know,
in some cases it would be good for the machine to be like, hi. I think you want me to do X.
I'm I'm gonna do X. Is that what you really want me to do?
Like you really want me to cook this turkey at 450 degrees for 12 hours?
That sounds super annoying,
right? It would be hellishly annoying,
you know, and again, this is where it boils down to.
I want something smart enough to be like
uh you're telling me to put a turkey in the oven and to heat it for, you know,
12 hours at 450 degrees.
I don't think that's a good idea.
Um, you know, you're telling me to unlock all the doors in the house and
you're not in the house.
Like,
is that what you really want?
Echo, received an important update and must restart.
I'll be ready
again shortly.
Apparently it auto updates and then tells me it's updated
and it's a good thing
and it's a good thing.
I'm not depending on this thing for, you know,
health and safety because apparently, hello, Alexa.
Alexa.
Hello, wake up.
It's up to the
Alexa.
Oh, no, the ring is blue again.
But again, I don't know if this thing is dead or is it doing something?
Maybe it's listening to everything
you
-- say.
-- Does this update take 10 seconds or 10 minutes?
Alexa,
can you hear me?
Alexa? Drop me a beat?
Nope. It's thinking the little blue light is pulsing.
So it's, it's thinking, I guess.
Right. But this is a perfect example,
Alexa
help. I've fallen and I can't get up.
No, I died
now, if
you will
like call 911 for you.
No. And actually in Canada it's illegal to have automated phone systems called 911.
Only
humans are allowed to call 911. Yeah, part of it is that, well, false alarms.
And number two is, you know, a lot of jurisdictions, 911 is not allowed to hang up.
Ah, sure. Right. Right. Right.
Because, I mean,
while there was that case in the US of
that 911 operator hanging up on hundreds of people,
uh, and being told, like, telling people to, like,
deal with it and hanging up on them and she's apparently been sued and fired now.
Um,
Alexa.
Oh, this thing is still updating.
No,
no, we're not, we're not doing this. You're not going to keep talking to your Alexa.
-- I
-- think
-- the challenge.
So I think the challenge fundamentally is we have
machines that are smart enough to basically be dangerous
and not smart enough to like, you know, sit boo boo, sit,
you know what I mean?
And
I agree with you and I guess the thing I keep thinking of is however, this gets fixed
is almost certainly going to be something that doesn't
exist today because I can't think of any existing
methodology or knowledge
that can actually solve this problem without just being super annoying.
And, and I do think it's going to get fixed because I have Alexa
is, is very useful and, and don't get me wrong like I would love to have one. But, but
this nightmare scenario is exactly why I don't,
I
don't.
And I think one thing I think of is I think of trains right back in the day trains,
there was a ton of train disasters and collisions
because we had very poor signaling systems.
So like trains would literally just run into each other,
right?
And
we invented processes and then we invented technology, you know,
where like we segment the track into segments.
You know, the track is green, you can go on the track. Nope.
Now the track is red because there's another train entering that track,
you know, whatever things like that.
We, we invented all these processes and procedures
and then technology and relays.
And like right now here in Edmonton, we have a big problem where
we paid tails some insane amount of money to
build the signaling system for our light rapid transit.
And uh they stuffed it up and the thing can only run
at like half or one third speed of what it's supposed to run
because like to do it safely, you, you, you can't run it at full speed, right?
Um
You know, but,
but we, we know how to deal with that like, oh, the system doesn't work properly,
but we know how to compensate for that even though it sucks,
you know,
and, and there have been actually several cases now,
two or three cases of where trains entered
red track,
right where they, you know, they should, right?
But nothing bad happened because there was other systems that caught that,
you know, resulting in a shutdown, right?
-- The, the system fails close
-- and, and I guess
that's,
that's the lesson here, right? Of, of both Uber and Alexa
is that failure is inevitable.
But as long as we
take the failure and we learn from it
instead of using failure as a reason to give up,
which I there are people obviously decrying
-- failure as don't even try
-- well. And part of it is also is defining what is failure,
right? So for example, is it a failure?
If the Uber car sees something,
it doesn't understand and slams on the brakes to be on the safe side
because I've seen people do that in traffic,
you know, the infamous people,
rubber necking the accident on the other side of the road causing
a
pile up.
Like that's, that's happened where literally, you know,
there's a minor fender bender on one side of the
highway and on the other side of the highway,
there's like a 15 car crash because some
jackass decided it was more important to watch
the show than to pay attention.
Yy.
You know.
So, yeah, these are, these are difficult things, you know,
like a highway speed just slamming on the brakes may not, you know,
when I think about this, I think about self, you know, um, uh, plane autopilots,
you know, because you can't just pull over to the side of the road,
right? You got to deal with it.
And I think that's maybe to the advantage for airplanes is number one,
they're hideously expensive.
And number two,
you,
you have to really think about and define what
the failure scenarios are because otherwise you're losing,
you know,
multi $100 million,
$100 million piece of machinery with people on board.
Right. And
-- II, I feel like we're gonna get there. Right. I, I
-- think we have to,
this is
the genie is out of the bottle.
Like we,
we can't get rid of smartphones and we can't get rid of these home assistants.
We, I think about being 30 or 40 years older from now and having this thing
and having it be able to remind me of things and have it, be able to, you know,
help me with my daily life and you know what?
It sounds awesome.
-- That's like
-- it does, it does.
And, and I guess that's, that's how we're going to close. It is just the point that
complaining about this stuff doesn't help, it's not going to go away.
And so
it's going to fail, it's going to have problems
and, you know, it's very much like if you're not part of the solution,
you're part of the problem.
And, and I think a lot of a lot of,
especially security people and the way they're mocking all this
are definitely part of the problem and they aren't helping.
I was gonna say, yeah, they're definitely not helping.
And I mean, so like I know for myself personally, I'm looking at trying to help,
we're going to look at defining cwes for
this because the common uh weakness enumeration system.
So we can define these problems.
So people are then more aware that, oh, that is one way to feel spectacularly.
Let's maybe try to avoid that,
right? It's, it's like the old saying, right? Once you give something a name,
then you can defeat it essentially.
So awesome. No, I like it, man. That, that's great. So, all right. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. You can go to open source security podcast.com
to grab the show notes of which there are many this time and you can
use the Pound Os S podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media.
And yeah, Kurt, you have a fabulous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.