Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in thinking about supply chains.
-- Josh browsers.
-- We do think about supply chains.
And it's funny because we've been thinking about them
-- for probably 20 years
-- before they had a name.
Yeah, because you know what,
my favorite thing about open source used to be was trying to find it.
-- Uh
-- That's true. It could be difficult
-- like
-- legit, right?
And in some cases it was easy because it's like, oh, I need a DNS server.
Well, there's bind.
That's it.
Like, uh,
yeah, pretty much.
-- That's true. That was the only game in town in
-- the late nineties.
You had Bind and DH PD. That was it, you know, to get your network up and running
-- and, and, or a web server. Well, there's Apache.
-- Was there more? Yeah.
-- No, that was really the only open source web server, wasn't it? Yeah,
-- that was it.
-- And then,
-- and then because the other ones were what?
-- Iis and the Sun web server and
-- there was a couple of like Zeus and stuff that,
that was the
commercial explosion, but quickly like glass fish and all those that
went away eventually because
it turns out building web service is quite expensive.
It's funny because now, you know, it's so easy.
Like I, I need a random library to do something in my.
Well, first of all, which language do I want? I have a plethora of choice
and then I go to pi pie or rust crates or whatever.
And I find like the top five results, let's say, look at, you know,
make sure they've been updated in the last six months
or a month or year or day or whatever.
And then I pick one or two, try them out and they
always work
-- to some degree. I
-- don't think that's how most developers work.
No, it's not.
-- No, they just most go to
-- stack overflow
and they copy and paste the solution for the particular problem they have and,
and I do that all the time.
Well, I just had that experience where I was looking for something and the answers.
Uh oh, it was, how do II I have now, I built a backup True
Naz Box. And so I want to synchronize the first True
Nas Box, some of the data pools to the second True Naz Box. So if the first True Nas Box
craps out,
I can just stand up the second box with
pluck and the other things because they're fully synced at
the, at the volume level
and like it's actually it's built into the interface but
the documentation is a bit out of date and of course, if you google it,
all the answers are from like 2016 and stuff and they're like,
hilariously out of date
or they mentioned our
sync, which has actually been taken out of true
as now as a service.
Oh, nice. Yeah.
And also it's the wrong way to do it right.
You want to do it at the volume level, not manually,
synchronizing a bunch of random files.
Sure. Sure. I mean, that seems fair.
Yeah. So it's,
but, yeah, you know, you're right. Like most people don't.
Yeah, they,
you know, it always reminds me of, it's like shopping for cars.
We all, a lot of us have a car but we're never taught how to shop for a car.
We're never taught what to look for in a car and then everybody's like,
kind of at the point now where I'm going to go buy a
used car and it's just a question of how badly I get gouged.
-- Not whether or not it happens because,
-- but we do it like, what,
10 times over the course of our lives.
Yeah, exactly. And they do it 10 times a day.
-- So,
-- obviously,
well, that reminds me of this whole black hat thing.
Like, so I wanna, I wanna to set the stage
before we go on. So there is a security boulevard. Is it a blog post or an article?
-- I don't know what it counts as it
-- has a date in the title. So I would say blog,
OK, it's titled Black Hat USA 2024.
Key takeaways from the premier cybersecurity event. I thought that was Defcon.
Defcon is the premier cybersecurity event. I thought so,
I don't know.
-- Isn't
-- that the one everybody
likes?
I mean, it depends who you're talking to. Are you in sales then?
No, no, you don't like that.
Well, that's the thing. Blackhead is the corporate one.
Defcon is the more technical one, let's say.
-- So
-- when I was at besides,
I went to besides Las Vegas and only besides
Las Vegas because everything else is a zoo and
I was talking to someone at lunch one day about just everything going on.
And this guy had a marvelous insight. He said, Defcon isn't a conference.
Defcon is a festival
and I think when you think of it that way, it makes perfect.
-- It makes sense because it's like a, well, the
-- hackers village,
it's tons of people.
Yeah,
there's all the little villages and there's all this weird stuff
going on and you have no idea what's happening and,
and then it's, it's utter chaos.
Well, my understanding is I always felt like
Defcon was more participatory. Whereas blacks,
you go, you listen, you walk the sales floor.
Uh what do you call that floor, the conference hall thing.
-- I
-- don't know
the show hall,
-- whatever it's called and you're like the place that
-- used to have swag
-- and then you try and pack the swag or throw it out
-- but there's no swag anymore.
It's all garbage now.
Like, it's terrible. None of the conferences have swag worth even getting anymore.
That's why I don't. Yeah,
the thing, I never, they always used to give away laptop bags and stuff and I'm like,
doesn't, by definition every, you know, it's like buying luggage at the airport.
-- Most people have luggage when they get to the airport.
-- Yeah.
But if you, so actually you say that
my suitcase broke
and I get the trip
corner cases, but like giving everybody a free suitcase seems kind of silly.
I have received many laptop bags and
backpacks that have gotten use from conferences.
I bring them home. I give them to people, my kids use them whatever. Like do I use it?
Absolutely not. I have a very nice backpack.
But, but anyway, ok, so inside of this blog post,
there is a section titled The Supply Chain Security Crisis,
which is such a marvelous type.
-- I applaud you.
-- I know because it just happened. Finally. It's never,
-- it's not been a crisis before. I
-- mean,
I,
I know what it's not a crisis.
It's, this is like it's not, this is like the pothole crisis or the
trying to get people to wash their hands after using the toilet crisis.
I think it's I like Clickbait titles and so
I'm almost definitely going to use that title for this podcast episode
because I know we're going to get lots of
clicks because it's a marvelously click bait title.
Sorry, I just read it. Oh my God. Sorry.
Crowds strikes, prompt,
an effective resolution of the outage was met
with praise as they minimize the disruption,
reinforced community trust and their
capability to manage unexpected challenges.
-- A what does that have to do with supply chains?
-- No, no, it does.
I think it does and I think it's good that crowd strike,
-- but
-- that's not how I remember that event going.
I was at an airport on the Wednesday after that and we were very delayed
on a Wednesday because I was flying Delta.
I'm just glad the plane got to where it was supposed to go.
Like
that was pretty much.
-- My concern is like, I don't want to spend the weekend in Atlanta.
-- No.
-- But
-- anyway, good food though.
-- Those have good food.
-- Every, every large city has good food now
they got crawfish.
I do love crawfish.
-- Ok. Before. Ok. No, no, not right now.
-- I can't get that up here. You can't get,
well, they're growing in the river now but they're not safe to eat.
You have, you don't have crawfish in your rivers and stuff.
Well,
we do now in the North Saskatchewan River because
somebody released God knows what into the river.
We also have a goldfish problem.
We've always had them in Wisconsin like I used to eat tons of them. When I was a kid.
We do go catch them and then eat them. It's nice. Winter.
We have winter.
It's not quite your winter. But, ok. Anyway. All right, we're, we're
ok.
Here's the thing. I think the fact that
there are people willing to call,
we'll say crowd strike incident and we'll put incident in quotes,
a supply chain attack or not attack but a supply chain event.
Right. Not an attack. It was not an attack, it was an event.
Yes, crowd strike is part of the supply chain for numerous organizations.
A lot of organizations that we found out
and this is the sort of thing you absolutely need to think about.
Like when we talk about supply chain, I think it is
almost exclusively a conversation about open source these days.
And there is a lot more in your supply chain
than just open source you need to think about.
In fact, I would argue
the not open source is often a bigger problem than the open source as crowd strike.
So kindly pointed out for us.
Well,
we have direct proof of that and I
have industry experience with that Microsoft Tuesday.
Like how much time and effort do companies spend checking these
updates to make sure they don't break anything for sure.
Right.
-- Thousands, if not tens of thousands of hours at large companies,
-- you know, I mean,
I remember working for a company
that ran a lot of Microsoft stuff and, yeah, we would have, like,
a test lab just for installing updates in and be like, does everything still work?
Oh, this thing quit working? 00, it quit working because the dis went bad.
Like, it's fine. It's not the update. Yeah. No, for sure.
And I think a lot of places probably still do that.
Well,
and I think part of it is the traditional view of the supply chain
is from the manufacturing world where it's
stuff that goes into building something.
And
most manufacturing companies, well, see the difference is when you buy a hammer,
it generally doesn't randomly break or get a software update that breaks it.
And this is true of like a lot of manufacturing equipment from back in the day.
It's like, yes machines can fail, but it's not like modern machinery where,
you know,
they're getting software updates constantly and just
constantly glitching or having problems or,
you know, this other thing got updated,
sends a slightly different data packet now and this
other machine fails because of that or whatever,
right?
And I think that's part of the challenges we they're used
to like this was all part of your historical supply chain.
You know, we get titanium from X, we get steel from Y,
we get paper clips from whatever, but
they were easy to sort of change out. They were more fungible, right?
Like steel is steel. If you get the right grade, who cares who it comes from right
paper clips. Staples. Who cares?
Just go to, like, I don't care if you get it from Office Depot or Staples. The,
the office supply company called Staples.
But, like, with software being such a core part of all this,
anything complicated nowadays, like a refrigerator or up.
Yeah.
All of a sudden it's a lot more complicated and I think we,
the supply chain is a lot more fragile because it's a lot more complicated.
There's more potential for disruption.
I think your your explanation is wrong for a lot of reasons.
And I just want to read this description
from the middle of this article, the section of the article because I think it's,
it's the topic and it says I'm just going to read, I think it's a,
it is the last sentence.
It says
he emphasized the urgent need for organizations to adopt
more stringent security practices such as continuous monitoring,
supply chain audits to mitigate the risk posed by third party software components.
Here's what I'm gonna say.
If you look at the way society,
especially in the world of it has been functioning to date.
We have been, I would say
pretty successful by ignoring most of these problems.
And I think the reality is
and this is even true of your very long explanation. Just now
in the world of it, we only fix what is literally broken and on fire.
And most of the supply chain problems aren't broken and on fire.
Now, when Crowdstrike crashed, like all of Delta's computers
that was broken and on fire. So there was no plan B,
well, it was also all at once.
I actually have a very good analogy for this, which is my Kia,
the engine seized.
Yeah, you
saw that
and it turns out, uh,
let me just find the link,
uh, Kia Engine recall lawsuit site.
-- So, um, it's Kia Engine class settlement.com.
-- That's the website.
Yeah.
And so here's the thing. So my, my Kia engine seizes. So I, like I had it towed to
tire and they
seized it's dead. And I'm like, well, great. Now what,
like he's like, well, we phoned the Kia dealership and this is a known issue,
but these engines can seize and fail.
And I'm like, oh, ok, because I've never heard this before. Right.
And he's like,
and I'm like, like,
do you know what the timeline on getting this fixed or whatever it is?
He's like, well, they're kind of backed up right now.
He says they have seven cars and for the, with this problem in right now.
Oh, my goodness.
And at a different Canadian tire, I was at a, for a different reason.
I, I mentioned this and they're like, oh, yeah, the key engine recall thing.
Yeah, we, we're seeing a lot of those and I'm like, they're recalling an engine.
No, no. But that's the problem is it's not a recall. It's once it fully breaks,
if you can prove that you did oil changes and
took care of it for about four or 500 bucks,
they'll rebuild your engine or replace it, which is obviously, you know, to get it,
the full
price is about 5 to $7000.
So hopefully they'll cover it.
But obviously they're going to fight me on that because they don't want to pay for it.
But the fact is that like this covers like
eight years of engines put in Kia Optimus and sports
and a couple other models.
So literally like locally, like the Kia dealership, 1213 blocks from my house has
like half a dozen or more of these cars in for this type of repair.
My car blew up
like this is,
this is exactly it like, is this a huge problem? Yes.
Is it a problem enough that there was AAA lawsuit
with a settlement where Kia does not admit fault?
Yada, yada, yada.
Yes. Are they replacing the engines for 400 bucks a pop?
Well, yeah, and that's,
that's expensive for them.
And
this is,
this is
a,
but this is just how this works because like
you can't go back in time and fix the problem. Like we already shipped.
Lord knows how many of those engines.
Oh, and also these are engines that were built by Hyundai
used in Kias,
right? So Kia didn't build the engine Hyundai built the engine, the GD I engines.
They, they're now infamous for like, not, yeah, for being unreliable, long term.
And so, yeah, this is, and what, what blows my mind is like, I literally had
the car towed.
So, and because we were waiting so long for the tow, I literally put the key under the,
the floor mat because like, what somebody you gonna do steal my car.
That doesn't work.
That's true, actually. Yeah, because I had that thought.
I'm like, what if somebody steals my car? Wait, it doesn't work.
Like, ok,
so if you ever see a car bending on the road under the door under
the floor mat or in the gas cap is probably where the key is,
which will probably be of no value to you at all.
Everybody knows this.
Like now I've been,
I've been told this like five times in the last week with all the people I was
with. They're like, oh, did you leave it in the gas cap thing? And I'm like, no lock.
I had to leave it under the thing. They're like, oh, ok, cool.
So I had the car towed to can tire and like, basically
the tow truck driver fired the key into the drop
slot and then the next day I talked to him.
So I've basically done this thing mostly hands off.
So I have this asset my car which is broken. So it's worth a lot less money.
Now, it's kind of hard to steal because it doesn't move.
But I've literally had it like, towed cane tire.
They did some stuff to, it looked at it said it's broken.
Then I had it towed from the cane tire to the key dealership again.
Dropped off, you know, II I wasn't physically there.
I did go the next day to drop off the paperwork
and, you know, and then they gave it back to me. But
like this, with this huge asset, it's basically been,
I've been trusting third parties
and like the tow truck driver, I don't know who that that is.
Like, I, I, you know, scheduled him through the A MA app and hey,
your tow truck driver, Bob will show up and do it at some point.
Yes. And it, it's not ideal
but it's generally working and yeah,
my car will take Lord knows how long a month or two or three to get fixed,
you know, because they're gonna fight me on it and I want to fix it.
Well, rebuilding an engine is not an
thing
and I'm guessing if I pay for it myself, they'll be like, oh yeah,
we can have it done in a week, right?
Because then they'll make money doing it
-- for
-- sure. 100%.
They're going to let the intern rebuild all of these engines.
Like this is exactly what happened with crowd strike.
It's like we,
we shipped an engine that blew up a bunch of stuff and you had
to pull over the side of the road and get its tow and get fixed
and it was, you know, you could fix it but it was a lot of work and, yeah, I mean,
thousands of flights were canceled or late but, like,
the world didn't come to an end.
Like, I bet you a dollar if you ask 100 people
-- on the street about this, like, maybe 1% will know.
-- Oh, yeah, for sure.
And, and look, even in the IT world it's been what, like a month now,
-- the
-- fact that you can't remember how long it's been.
Exactly
the,
the Friday before I went on vacation. That's what I know.
And I'll never forget,
like I sat my wife and kids down on
Tuesday night because we left on Wednesday morning.
I'm like, look, we might not get to where we're going.
We might end up stranded somewhere like Atlanta halfway there. Like
we have to be for prepared for this trip to not go very well for a couple of days.
It was the 19th of July. So it was over a month ago.
-- Oh, it's over a month now.
-- See, like we can't even.
So, it doesn't matter because we kind of recovered everything and life goes on.
Well,
it's gonna matter if you're Delta because they're threatening to sue crowd strike.
But that's a whole another story.
Well, they kind of have to because their insurance is not going to pay out.
-- That's probably true.
-- And they want to recover some money.
-- That's
-- fair. And I'm sure they'll get something from somebody,
some there, someone's going to settle somewhere like it's not going to court.
Well, and again, Crowdstrike will settle
and this specific settlement has no impact on any other settlement or lawsuit.
And this is very,
of course. Exactly.
You know,
it's like when Air Canada got dinged for their A I giving
bad refund advice and they specifically went to the BC tribunal which is
explicitly the act covering it says this is not for lawsuits for setting
precedent if it's important to go to court and do it there.
This is not like this is a lower, this is a step down from arbitration almost.
Ok.
Anyway, we are like all over the place I want to bring us back to specifically,
but this crisis is new.
It's all of a sudden it's not existed for 20 years.
Yes. And, and I think,
I think the thing
that I find the most interesting and this is even true when I, when I talk to,
especially like Toma de Pierre
is the lovely human.
He is,
is sending me really interesting like blog posts and
books and things like that on a regular basis.
And as like
in it, security people as infosec people, as
aec people as whatever we are
MLA I
ops
whatever
I
love looking at these problems and being like, oh, we have to worry about, like,
updating these packages.
We have to worry about this backdoor package.
We have to worry about this and this and this and this, but everything exists in this,
like, much larger system
and the reality is
even as bad as we like to think things are.
And it's, it's funny because actually I was chatting with a coworker this morning
and he was like a lot of your podcast and with you saying we're
all doomed because I think the last one I did that and it's like,
yeah, they kind of do except we're not really doomed.
I mean, society functions for the most part,
it's more like we're just doomed to
the sort of mediocrity zombie shuffle when things
that could be better. But
putting the effort into things being better would be like,
like that daycare that served or not, sorry, a daycare,
there's several set of daycares in Calgary use a central
food prep kitchen that made hundreds of kids really sick.
Right. So they were, they wh it on food safety big time. And so, like,
we have all these food safety rules.
Like, I, I actually know a person who is a food safety inspector,
health code enforcer person
and like,
we not eat at certain restaurants and tells us not
to shop at certain places or eat at certain places.
I believe it.
And, you know, yeah, like legit, I look up the, the,
the records are public and I'm like, oh, yeah.
No, I don't want to go there.
There's so many things we could do to vast, like,
here in Edmonton we've had a lot of
recent people in crosswalks getting run over by cars
in March crosswalks because drivers aren't paying attention.
-- Yeah,
-- they're, they're probably totally not looking at their phones. Right.
Yeah. Well, or they're driving these trucks where you can barely see over the hood.
Those two, you have to be at least 4 ft six or so to even be seen
for sure. You know. So they're running over little kids like, yeah, I mean,
these,
these are impactful things we actually did lower the residential speed
limit from 50 kilometers an hour to 40 which increases pedestrian survivability
off the charts. Right. The difference in impact is massive.
But of course, you know, it's,
it's not like they're really enforcing that speed limit widely because like,
how would we?
Right.
So actually you bring this up and there is a youtube video I just watched,
I'll dig it up and throw it in the show
notes, but it talks about
the train safety
and, and there's some, some train exploded one day
and it was like the horrific pictures and it looks
like some love crafty and monster that it turned into
-- all the
-- steam tubes.
Right? And,
but the thing is like 38 people died, I think
from that crazy explosion. And I'm like,
there's a lot of things that happen where 38 people die and no one cares.
And
-- it's interesting
-- how many 7, 37 max has crashed? Well, two.
Yeah.
-- Yeah.
-- Like
who, you know, a door fell out of one because they forgot to put the bolts back in.
I mean, Boeing has had some
incidents as of late, we'll say.
But even then,
like Boeing airplanes are still in the air.
Right. And
they do get a lot of attention, but at the same time
-- how many people die every day in auto accidents
-- per passenger mile.
-- It's, it's insane. Like cars are utterly insane.
-- We don't care
or, or the other one.
Actually,
I also watched a video talking about like the extreme
heat in the American Southwest right now where it's,
it's really bad and like people are literally
dying because like if their air condition,
if you're old and your air conditioner breaks in your house,
you're probably going to die is what's happening.
We had that happen
last year with Vancouver and the heat dome. And there was talk
of like, for example,
for renters making it a right for them to have air conditioning because otherwise,
you know, these places are literally unlivable and that you can die in them.
-- And
-- I, I did that happen.
You
-- making landlords pay money for stuff.
-- Well,
ignoring that, we forget, right? We forget almost immediately crowd strike,
we forgot
almost it's a month
and I think this is like
part of the human condition.
And this is where we start talking about
like organizations need to fix their supply chain.
They need to monitor things, they need to patch things,
they need to do all this stuff, they need to audit whatever the reality is,
they're not going to because there might be a supply chain incident.
And we might say like, oh my goodness log for Jay,
like this is the worst thing that's ever happened.
We need to get on board and everyone needs to pay
attention and we have to upgrade all of our stuff.
And then a couple of months later, everyone kind of forgets and you,
you can look at sonatype published a graph
that shows like 30% of log for J downloads
from Maven Central are still vulnerable to log for
shell.
They have to be because you've got a package that depends
on a package that depends on a package that downloads log for
shell. I mean, maybe
or log
for J Sorry.
Yeah, whatever.
Like
that's like we have this at Red Hat where we started
going down the Java rabbit hole and it's like we,
if we touch this, will it break or not?
It might.
-- Yeah. Might
-- as
that's well and more to the point in some
cases there was nothing to upgrade to like the,
you know what I mean?
-- Like the original project that kind of faded out or whatever,
-- right.
That, yeah, and that still happens now.
With like Python and N PM and everybody for sure.
-- But
-- especially with the complexity, like when you have 10 packages,
chances are they're still all alive. But when you have 1000 packages,
like, statistically one of them,
the developed before it died last Thursday for sure.
And I think that's part two is
the scale and complexity.
But
like I remember,
like I used to know all the configuration
options for Apache back in the late nineties.
I'm skeptical this is true.
Well,
all the important ones and now I wouldn't even pretend to know what they all are
-- and
-- you don't have to just go to stack overflow and copy and paste on.
-- It's fine.
-- Well, yeah, but that's the thing, right? Is like
you and I used to run Linux
and
I could do a psxau
and tell you what every single thing was.
Probably, haven't been able to do that for over a decade. Exactly.
Right.
Like you, you asked me how um system D works and my answer is, it's a binary blob.
-- It
-- is not
a binary blob. You know what I'm saying?
Like it's, it's no, it's like II, I know it's open source,
but in the sense of it's this giant love, crafty and horror of code.
That
kind of does a bit of everything which we need.
-- They,
-- they have lots of little components built into it.
You could tell me that
system D will make toast and I'd be like, I believe you.
-- Right. Like, I have no idea what its capabilities are
-- a
plug
in to do that.
Exactly. And so that's the thing. Ok.
-- But
-- here's my point. Ok,
I'm not, we're not,
we're not ending this conversation like this
because we're off in the Doom territory.
No, what I'm saying is quite the opposite. Is, this is ok.
Everything's working fine. Is it perfect?
It's not fine.
There's a lot we need to do better.
But I, I think the important thing,
I wouldn't say it's fine. I would say it's not a crisis. So even though
the title of this section is the supply chain Security Crisis and the
title of this podcast is almost definitely the supply chain security crisis.
It's not a crisis.
It could be
maybe if, if certain things would happen. But I think generally speaking,
because we're dealing with complex systems,
we're not dealing with individual things.
So when you focus on one thing, it can look very bad.
But when you focus on like the larger systems,
it's definitely not as bad as we might be led to believe.
I think one of the fundamental problems is this is everything now.
This is the whole world, every aspect of the whole world. Basically,
it's the telecommunications networks, it's all the infrastructure, it's all the
like, for example, here in Canada, we might have a train strike slash walkout.
There's two main companies,
one is going to go on strike and one is going to be locked out.
So we might lose all of our trains in Canada and like to put it bluntly,
they, you know,
they're talking about how the truck industry can pick up a little bit of the slack,
but single digits at best.
-- And
-- I'm sure there's not a bunch of trucks just like sitting there doing nothing.
-- Oh, yeah,
-- exactly.
Well,
and there's certain things you cannot transport by
truck safely long distance like pot ash and sulfuric
acid and oil.
-- That could be I I honestly know very little
-- like no,
you cannot transport this safely.
There's a reason we do it in trains.
This feels like the last episode where you complaining
about the browser cas and me being like,
I don't want to care about this problem.
But the thing is like I would say this could we do better?
-- Yes, but do we need to do better
-- also? Yes.
I actually don't know. I think things are pretty.
No. No,
I'm not sure there is always room to do better.
What would be the actual benefit of it versus the cost of it though?
Is there other things we could invest in? Like for example,
instead of making the the the physical di uh
landline like making dial up better and faster?
No, the answer was high speed internet, right?
And now I would say in the open source world,
our supply chain problems I think are less about observing what we're doing
and auditing what we're using and all of this,
I think the more valuable and useful thing is to go down a level.
I don't know if a down or up how to define this. But
the people working on the open source
are really what we need to focus on versus we obsess
over this like consumption aspect of open source of like,
oh I'm downloading a package from github.
I need to audit the package. I need to do that.
Instead of saying, let's make sure the person working on the software
has the resources they need and is taking care of. And you know what I mean?
-- And it is not like working themselves to death.
-- So like the Sovereign Tech Fund Fund
open
source projects.
Exactly like them.
Yes, I think exactly what they're doing and,
and funding that is of course difficult and I do
-- think the government should be heavily involved
-- for sure.
Well, it is a, if there's any public good,
if there's anything that meets the definition of a public good,
it has to be open source.
Yes.
Like
curl, for example, like to quote Daniel, does this run curl? Like
do, do things use coral. The answer is yes. Pretty much.
-- It's
-- everywhere on and off planet
I think.
Well, maybe that's part of it is we need to stop focusing on the product
and focus on the process
-- that builds the product.
-- II, I think that's part of it. Yes.
Now the other side of this though is so while I was
in Las Vegas and I put a thing on Mastodon about this,
I had a conversation where
the end result of it was me realizing that
a shocking amount of our supply chain security
actually sits on the shoulders of like github
and pie, pie and cargo and N PM.
Because we expect that if N PM, if A, if a maintainer backdoors a package,
we expect N PM
to pull it.
If someone publishes a malicious repo on github,
we expect
github to pull it
-- and like, I don't want, it's not OK though.
-- This is how the internet's always worked.
It is. But that's scary as can be, man.
Remember Irc and all the forums, look, look at Reddit,
Reddit rests on the shoulders of a couple of mods to
keep the place from turning into a talk success pool.
Well, everything is like this because
fundamentally there's a lot of economic incentives for
things to centralize and be more efficient,
right?
I don't want to run my own. Sure.
Get infrastructure and especially when my options are run my build and run my own,
get infrastructure or use github.
-- But
-- OK. No, no, no, you're not going down this hole.
I'm going to stop you right now and you're going to pull the Oh,
but what choice do you have?
-- Which is where you always end on this?
-- No, I'm saying, but the incentives align
to have this outcome.
A is that even a problem?
-- Because I would argue Microsoft has a strong vested interest in
-- not github.
Ignore github.
And let's talk about pi pie.
OK. Pi Pie is a foundation
-- and they have a strong incentive to run pipe pie.
-- That's
they are holding up
the world right now
and I guarantee they are underfunded.
We are counting on a volunteer run
underfunded foundation
to keep our supply chain secure.
And we know this and there are people who say that's fine. I don't think it's fine.
Well, unless we start taxing companies, they're like, remember the episode,
you know, this, the the the the security of the market demands.
Well, this is, this is literally what the market wants. Then the corporations,
some of them step up and commit to the foundation and donate, you know,
a nice chunk of money
and obviously the vast majority don't
-- because everybody uses Python, right? Like
-- that's,
I think this is like sovereign tech fund territory is my point.
I
think a lot of this stuff is sovereign
tech fund territory where we need the world's governments
to care and understand. And my, this here's the thing at the end of the day.
And I want to end the show on this point. I don't think
most people
understand like the importance of something like the Python Foundation,
the PSF the Python Sulfur Foundation
on just like
all of our software, right? Like we love talking about A I,
it's all Python
the PSF is driving the A I revolution.
And I don't think that lawmakers,
I don't think our governments and I don't think a
lot of leadership understand the utter importance this thing has.
And I think
that
is probably more valuable to try to raise some of that up than it is to say, oh,
we have to audit all of our open source because I think the reality is
if we properly fund and staff, the PSF,
that's probably going to have drastically more benefit to supply chain security
than anything you're going to do as a company.
Well, that's the difference between solving a problem,
like putting a band aid on something and fixing one boo boo
and systemically looking at all the incentives and how the system works
and getting some people with actual resources and
-- power to help fix the system
-- for sure.
And that, but that's not where we've been directing our gaze.
I think we've seen things like
the open ssf get a bunch of attention and money when the reality is
the Python Software foundation should probably be
getting that attention and money instead.
Well, to put it simply, Red Hat has a lobby office in DC.
All the tech companies have lobby offices in DC.
I'm guessing very few open source projects do
I would be shocked if any of them do
Mozilla
-- might,
-- maybe,
maybe Mo
that's the thing like Google, you know,
all these companies have massive lobby efforts to help, to help air quotes,
write legislation and educate lawmakers.
Yeah. And so how else would they like?
-- They're not going to go looking to learn about open source on their own?
-- That's true.
This is the, however we have an army of open source people.
And so maybe one of the things to think about is how can,
and, and we need someone behind this, like,
how could someone like the maybe not the sovereign tech fund?
Because I know they can't lobby but like,
there's got to be maybe the Python Software foundation can, can say, like,
please write letter, talk to your lawmakers, write them letters.
I bet it would take shockingly few
open source developers to actually change something.
I suspect that's right
because from what I've looked at and read about lobbying, it's,
-- it's time consuming and expensive and complicated.
-- We're not lobbying,
-- we're constituents writing letters
-- that's lobbying.
-- Maybe, I don't know,
-- that's literally lobbying.
I don't know,
I, I don't know that what the term, I don't know what the definition of lobbying is.
I just assumed it was like rich people with money.
-- Well, they're the most effective at it. That could be
-- anyway,
because they can,
well, they can afford to hire the people to tell them how to do it.
Well, that's probably fair. We don't know what to do.
And that's a big part of what I'm seeing.
Historically, in open sources,
we've always ignored sort of the soft people skills, squishy side of everything
of
like,
well, that episode where he talked about how open source is getting gray.
What's the best we can tell? And like, how do we bring the new people in?
-- Not
-- the best we can tell. Like there's actual data. I think it's time to call this one.
But I, I think at the end of the day, you are correct.
We have ignored things like politics
and governments and all of that. And I think to our detriment to this point
and so I don't, I don't know what comes next.
I don't think it's doom and gloom, but I also think the,
the things we need to talk about and we need to educate people about is not,
you should vet all your dependencies.
Don't get me wrong.
I'm not saying you should go get I'm not giving
anyone like a get out of jail freak out here.
Like you still have to have proper hygiene internally.
But I think
if we want to see true change, we have to go to the sources more than anything else.
-- Yeah,
-- two comments. One, you should know what you're putting in your mouth.
And two
like, remember the hacker manifesto specifically says things like, you know,
we are free of borders, we are free of blah, blah, blah.
No, no, you're not.
I
know. Right.
And that's the thing like historically, a lot of these,
his hackers really do believe that they can be free of all these things.
It's like,
no,
no, like you, you live in a culture.
I used to think that, but yes, we have to function in society unfortunately.
-- Well,
-- especially if you want society to give you some of that sweet, sweet tax money.
That's true too.
-- To fix stuff.
-- All right, let's call it, man. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening.
I hope this was a happier ending. Go to open source security podcast.com.
Head of the show to
Susie Pando says podcast hashtag on Mastodon. Kurt.
Have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too.
-- Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.