Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 130 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Pressers.
Hey, Kurt.
And today I am pleased to say we're talking to Danny Grander, the co-founder of SNCC.
Say hello, Danny.
Hello. And thank you so much for having me.
No, thank you, man. We've been trying to get you on this show.
I feel like for, for years at this point.
So I'm, I'm ecstatic that we finally got things to work out. So,
yeah. Awesome, man.
So I, I guess why don't, why don't you give us a little rundown of kind of who you are,
what you do, what Snick and, and that and then we can go from there.
All right. So, um I'm Danny. I'm, I'm, I live in Israel in Tel Aviv.
And as you said, I'm the co-founder and responsible for security at
SNC. So, um
the security be is I'm kind of wearing two hats first would be the
product security and
building our vulnerability database doing all that research as well.
And, and the other part, uh would be also responsible for
SNCC and Home security, keeping, sneak, secure and compliant.
I'm also a member of a AC TF capture the flag team called Pastan.
So
we're an active team and just came back from the CCC event uh in Germany
also played the CTF there.
And uh yeah, so in the past five years where we were actively playing,
we had the honor to win uh uh three Google CTFS and three first play and three cccctfs.
Um Yeah.
and in my past, I was, I was doing uh quite a lot of development in
different start ups.
But I'd say for the last 10 years before founding SNC,
I was focusing on security research, uh vulnerability research in particular
and that was mostly around to low
level stuff like embedded systems and crypto
analysis analysis as well. So
that's, yeah, that's a kind of high level overview.
Nice. That's awesome. Well, in, in SNC,
I think is,
is a bit close to our hearts as obviously this being an open source security podcast.
And, and you guys are,
I feel like every time I'm reading some sort of news about open source security,
like there you guys are, right?
You've been doing some crazy work, which is awesome.
Yeah.
So, so um so it's sneak, you know, like when we found it snake, uh our,
our mission was to
help developers and use open source code and stay secure.
And so
that's uh the major thing for us was to, you know, to
solve that problem for developers and it's different
than solving that problem for security people.
So still we are a security product and we are a security expert experts and you know,
we have uh what we, we need to, to, to help, to solve this problem.
But
the product we're building is
addressed for developers. And that's, you know, we believe that this is,
you know,
open source dependency like the dependency management and the security part of,
of managing your dependencies is something that
should be owned
by the developers as you know, as part of the quality that uh
they, they own.
And uh and that's why we,
we believe that we should build a product that is usable by them, you know,
something that they find useful for them and,
and integrating all their work flows for them to, you know, to,
to be able to reduce that risk.
And of course, this is
something that, you know, the security faults in any organizations want.
But uh ultimately, this is something that we believe is the best place to solve is,
you know, by developers.
So that's why
from day one, we build it as we, we build it, you know, the company as a depth to
company, it comes down
to many aspects, you know, how we build the product,
how we do the product or how we develop it, how we market it.
And um
yeah, so, and of course, like where we also present, you know, like even giving talks
and uh and content we write
it also from day one was very different, you know, from the typical I'd say
uh security cybersecurity company
at least. Well,
but generally nice.
So I was curious, you're talking about open source.
Um And obviously the,
the one most recent one that comes to mind is the zip slip vulnerabilities.
One thing I have to say is I was looking through your advisory on it
and something you've done that not very many people do is you
not only talked about who is vulnerable and how they're vulnerable,
but you actually
gave the example of Ruby and Python where you,
you actually looked through their libraries and source code and
apparently found no vulnerabilities uh specific to zip slip.
And I, and I have to say I really appreciate that because one thing I've noticed is
um with these sort of broad vulnerabilities.
So one of the first ones I remember that I had to deal with was the XML hash dos
like eight years ago.
And we, we definitely knew like a few things that were vulnerable
and then the rest of it was just this giant unknown, right?
And I spent the better part of I think two months digging through
stuff looking for, you know, is this vulnerable or not? So
I have to say I really appreciate
when the security V
I mean, I really appreciate people telling me what is vulnerable.
Like that's, you know, G I Joe now, you know, half the battle,
but telling me what isn't vulnerable is also hugely helpful because,
you know, if I'm running Ruby and Python now,
I know I don't have to spend two months
digging through my source code looking for this.
I just want to say I appreciate that and I wish more vendors would do that.
-- But I know it's a ton of work.
-- Super happy to hear that.
And I think there's an interesting story story behind this.
So,
you know, um
when we
basically the zip slip story started with uh us finding the
the vulnerability.
And so maybe I'll briefly explain what's uh what this, what is this ability is about.
So basically, uh it's, it's um
ultimately, it's a simple directory traversal vulnerability.
But one that happens when we extract archives, not necessarily zips but any kind of
archive.
So what typically a typical code that uh
that extracts a vulnerable code that extracts an archive
into destination folder
would
just iterate over the entries over the files that inside that archive
and and extract them into the destination folder by attending
the name of the entry, the name of the file inside the zip to the to the path,
the target directory.
So if the name inside the zip file contains, you know
dot dot slash dot dot slash,
then the the the final path that we are extracting the file
into and the final path for the folder would uh you know,
might end up being a different path than the one we intended
to extract to.
So
this vulnerability vulnerability is not something new,
like first time mentioned in Frack magazine
in 1991.
So,
you know, when, when, when the internet was, you know, created.
So, so, so that's how long this type of vulnerability was not.
But uh and so when, when we found, you know, when, when, when, when,
when we found the issue
in several open
source projects, it was
uh we've seen it in Jenkins code and several of its plains including one from Amazon
and uh several Apache products.
So it, it just, you know, it was just surprising to see
that kind of, you know, well known, all kind of vulnerability
in, in, in such popular uh projects.
And so we, what we did next is, is and these, all of those were were Java projects.
So what we did next is kind of searched all the
github,
all the open source called on
github
to see whether there are any other vulnerable projects that have, you know,
projects that have code.
And we found plenty, we found a lot of projects, we actually had to kind of filter
to, to look at uh uh analyze only projects that have certain amount of stars.
Uh because, you know,
otherwise there are so many projects that had the vulnerable code.
But one thing that was
obvious
to us quickly is that
we see the same kind of pattern, we see the same kind of code that is vulnerable
in those Java projects.
And it would always be
a
full implementation.
You know, you would see that 60 lines of code that would, you know,
read the create a zip object and then enumerate over the entries and then create,
you know, output streams and write those
instead of this one single line that you would expect to see,
right when you extract a zip archive.
And and so
that's where we actually realize that there is something special about Java.
Something happens in Java because all those projects
and I'm talking about hundreds of projects
uh had uh had that same snippet of code sort of, you know, different variations,
but you know, pretty much the same snippet of code that was vulnerable.
And so actually the documentation for in different uh
uh archive libraries was vulnerable.
And 19 out of 20 questions on stack
overflow had vulnerable implementation, only one had, you know,
good.
So,
so what what happened is that
because and this is very specific to Java
because um
in, in Java, you didn't have the standard library there, the Java standard library
and one of the most popular or the
most popular java and archiving library from Apache Apache
commons compressed didn't give you the simple method
you can call to extract an archive file,
a zip file,
you kind of had to either implement it yourself.
-- Sorry,
-- wait, Java didn't have a built in on zip.
No
downstairs. No,
a single
call. You cannot do a single call for. Yeah. And,
and
so obviously what would happen is that either you
went and did the hard thing which is like,
you know, understand how to do all this zip streams and like, you know, all the
all the enumeration and, and you know,
write your own code and probably still as a developer, not a security person,
you had good chances to implement it, you know,
wrongly, right?
Not to take into account the fact that entries inside the
zip can contain dot dot slashes and all of that,
right?
Or you do the simple thing that is Google
and actually you, this is something you can try.
Now if you write, you go now to Google and you write
Java and zip file, OK?
And click on five, you know, you'll see like several block posts giving you
giving you the implementation, you'll see several stacker
flow answers
and you'll see that all of them are still vulnerable. And so
this is funny to me because I we actually had a discussion
a couple of years ago on the CV E board list about
can we assign CV E documentation? Because there's a couple,
there was a well known case of it was like a my SQL
code snippet in like a textbook of all things or something where,
yeah, it just, it was something horribly, horribly wrong
and people keep using it because, well, it works right.
But it's just insecure but it works.
And, and honestly I've been thinking about this because,
yeah, like, essentially we've got this, well, it's not code per se.
It's code examples
but people consume it as if it was like a library.
They just cut and paste it into their application, which is, well,
much worse because then it can never be updated unless they do.
-- Exactly.
-- And that's, and in zip
slip, you actually see that, you know, you see that vulnerable code that appears in
apache's website. Well, it appeared back then
and, and, and, and you can just see how it was copy pasted.
It's amazing how every Java project that had something like, you know,
had some functionality dealing with archives would have their own zip ut class
that would include and zip, you know, and, and,
and just being copy pasted from stuck overflow other open source projects.
So
the, the, the, the amazing thing is that, you know, when you,
when you compare it to Python, for example, so in Python, in order to
extract the zip archive, you need to do two things. First is do import zip file.
And the second one is called zip file dot extract all.
And you provide a zip file, right? And you provide the destination folder.
And the interesting thing that the implementation of
that function was vulnerable up until 2014.
But
as soon as it was fixed, you know, all the projects that utilize this functional,
this this method
were not vulnerable anymore.
Unlike
the situation we're having right now with Java, right
is that
it's like, so we know about the issue,
we know how widespread it is but and we went and reached out to all those projects.
But the in many of them,
the code is still there and this thing being copy pasted and it's still, you know,
the issue is still there.
So it's like statically linking,
you know,
statically linking a library that is vulnerable and then you don't even know,
have a way to know that you have this right
and vulnerability in your code base unless you know,
somebody knocks on your door or you listen to this podcast,
right?
Yeah. No, I've noticed that with sort of these, these very low level
and I'm making big air quotes here, simple things.
I mean, because this is what frustrates me is a lot of people, you know,
think that unpacking a file is simple and well as you know,
it's not,
it's actually quite horrifically complicated in many cases because there's
was this something I I, well,
when we were working on Tar and looking at tars vulnerabilities, you know,
or just all of these things.
And
I mean, the good news is at least people don't cut and paste tar code.
But I mean,
things like zip and uh XML parsing and I've seen a couple other cases where, yeah,
people
for, yeah, whatever reason, I guess the there's no well known library.
So people do it themselves.
Here's a fun question. Do you think there's an actual solution to this?
Realistically?
Yeah.
So, so, so you know, like we, we actually seen it, seen, it,
seen all kind of different issues.
So one is the one I mentioned is that, you know,
vulnerable code being just copy pasted.
So snippets just, you know, they, they
float around and people take like developers take them from, you know, stacker
for other open source projects.
And so
they are, this is one kind of issue that the solution, you know,
on our side would be to, you know, go and reach out to all of those developers,
notify them
and try to, you know, fix the issue and just get rid of this.
So even when the project was, the vulnerability was not exploitable,
it was it just had the vulnerable code,
but the vulnerable code wasn't reached could not be reached by, you know, by
militia by an attacker.
It just, you know, some internal logic,
we would still inform the project and ask them, you know,
to just to, to add the extra two lines of code that would validate, right?
And, and just to prevent future kind of, you know, misuse of, of that code.
But the other thing we did is looked at, we focused on archiving library.
So we we went to all those ecosystems
and looked at the the libraries that their only
purpose is to help you deal with archives.
And sadly in Java, all of those were vulnerable.
So in Java, not only you didn't have, you know,
like standard library uh that you know,
give you this one function you can call to extract the zip.
But also those libraries that actually
uh were less popular, but still they gave
you this functionality, all of them were just vulnerable,
three or four of them were vulnerable.
And so, and, and, but the good news there is that as soon as those folks fix the issue,
you know, just all the, all the consumers of the library just needed to upgrade.
So that's
an easier thing to do, you know, especially if you're, you know,
using uh if you're managing your dependency with SNCC or with any other tool,
it is something that you can, you know,
you can get notified about immediately and you can fix.
But with the, when compared to, you know, the first case where it's just, you know,
copy pasted snippets in your code base, this is much harder issue to, to fix.
And, and so yeah, and lastly,
you know, there is this the solution also on the ecosystem level.
So, you know, we compared Java and um you know, and Python.
So I think Java and
the one thing that should happen is that developers should have an easy way,
you know, to to to use
to open an archive, right? Sadly, Apache chose not to implement such function.
I'm not sure why it was like, it sounded to me in the beginning like a very you know,
theoretical discussion whether the library the
Apache commons compressed library should do
with compression compressor like is it
the compression library or archiving library?
They are a compression library,
they deal with compression algorithms which is different than
archiving, right, combining files together.
But I think while maybe theoretically you know the definition,
it's the compression library, I still think that such an API is something
really important to have regardless of you know definitions
because otherwise just developers get it wrong.
And as an example, 16 Apache projects and I talk about Apache projects,
not like other open source projects, got it wrong.
Six of them were actually vulnerable. So with their own you know library.
So this is just a good example of you know how how important
is to have secure like good API that is like you know,
secured by default, right?
And so I think that that's a big step for Java to to do. And so oracle actually are
working on, on introducing such a thing.
And yeah, I think that's just, you know, will make the problem go away at some point
like it, you know, like it did in, in in other places,
one thing to note is that so.net actually have a
really good implementation so that the implementation was secure,
was safe,
but the documentation was wrong. So they actually fixed it immediately there.
They had uh they responded really quickly
and uh one thing they did is is add another extra kind of protection
that
no other language,
no other uh ecosystem uh did is to add another protection to actually, you know,
disallow dot dot slashes in,
in, in entry names
uh by default.
So you had to kind of, you know, ask for it if you, if you, if you, you are that, you know,
having that special case, so which is really brave thing to do it,
it's probably breaks some applications.
But I think that's,
that's an interesting and brave choice on their part kind of
quick story about how we went about to disclose this because,
you know, like we find
hundreds
of affected projects.
And so, you know, we have like we have Oracle and Microsoft, like, you know,
big players to, to, to uh to dispose to we have other popular open source projects.
And then we have like a long long list of just open
source projects that all we have of them on them is,
you know, like that in email address, we can actually pull out of
the G,
right?
So what we, we did, we, we chose the Google Project zero disclosure,
the responsible Disclosure model.
We we chose to go for a shorter period of 60 days just
because there are so many projects and all of them are open source.
So, you know,
when they are being fixed, it's visible to everybody.
So we kind of uh chose to make the disclosure window shorter
and we started with uh disclosing to, you know, all the major companies,
the ecosystem like we were calling and, and Microsoft
and, and big companies. Uh and
so, and, and the foundation Apache Foundation
and uh people
also so amazing was like, actually the cooper
with Apache was great.
They immediately created the group of people that, you know, triaged the whole
all the projects on Apache and um
managed the fixes on their part.
People
was, were amazing. We found the issue was found in, in, in the,
in, in spring uh
zip code and, and they just fixed it in within one day.
This was amazing to see it just like one day
including assigning a CV, which is like an amazing feed in itself.
And so many, many big companies just, you know, surprisingly reacted to it quickly.
But, but, but what I didn't
is that we actually started with fixing the library.
So all the libraries, the archiving libraries
that were vulnerable, we, we reached out to them first.
So when we, you know, they would,
we made, we just wanted to make sure that
the actual libraries that are popular that are used
by developers would have a fixed version as,
as soon as we go public.
And I have to say that it, it created some challenges.
Of course, there is quite a lot of work involved with, you know,
managing the disclosure correspondence, you know,
helping fix the issue and all that.
But also some projects are, you know, just, you know,
unmaintained. So some developers just, you know,
they don't see the email, they just busy to, to, to, to actually to attend to it.
And some
developers didn't even know their project is the most popular archiving project,
for example, in go
ecosystem. So
we reached out to a guy, we told them that there is an issue with his code and he's like,
hey, like I wrote this code for myself several years ago.
It shouldn't be, you know, production.
And they're like, hey,
this code is like the most popular goal archiving library now with like 1000 stars or
so, we actually also helped fix the, you know,
opening full request to some project just to make sure that uh when we go public,
the libraries themselves are, are fixed.
So we did that for Z four J
and for archive and several others. So,
so there was like about,
I'd say 15 different archiving libraries among different ecosystems,
most of them in Java, I'd say, but
there were few in.net as well that, that we disclosed to first and help fix.
And then as a last step, I'd say about 30 days before going public,
we just automatically disclosed,
send automatic emails with all the information pointing out to the, you know,
to the github
project with the,
to the exact line having the vulnerability to hundreds of projects.
This is something we did attic,
it backfired a bit because
we use mail gun and, you know,
you know, it was paint like made then in
MI
five like shorten
the URL. So a lot of folks thought we like, you know, we're,
we're,
we're sending this phishing emails and you know,
there was like some, some some challenges about it,
but we learned a lot of lessons from that.
Well, I mean, my, my two thoughts, one on your short disclosure timeline is,
as you said, this has been first publicly written about in Frack in 91 at least.
Uh I quickly checked the CV database for
directory traversal
zip and there's like 100 and three entries going back to 2001.
So, you know, at this point,
yeah, it
people don't know about this obviously or they would have fixed it, but
they should have known about this.
I would say, you know, like, well, and the second thing I find really interesting,
I never really gave this as much thought as maybe I should have.
But the lack of a standard library means obviously,
people need that functionality.
So they're going to implement it themselves.
And if you have one person implement something,
at least if it's wrong you have one place to fix it.
But if 1000 people implement it now you have 1000 places to fix it,
you know, and going to the Java example that, that's,
I never really thought of this as a risk before, but it actually does seem
like a very legitimate risk, you know,
a, a missing sort of commonly needed standard library.
Yeah.
Yeah, exactly.
And, and the thing is that like all of those implementation are exactly the same, not
by a bit, but it's like, functionally, they all do the same thing. Exactly.
You know, like the variable names are slightly different. You know,
there is some slight differences in formatting,
but essentially you're opening a zip file, you're traversing the, you know,
the entries and then you're like writing the files
and to your first point.
So again, there is like,
like the distinction between the type of vulnerability which was, you know, like
it, the first mention of it was like really long ago in the frat magazine.
And then, you know, we had so many CV S and there,
there is like much more products are vulnerable
to this issue than, you know, what's mentioned in CV.
And, and so essentially for us, the disclosure meant, you know,
making public the fact that a specific product is vulnerable, right?
And that's the sensitive bit, that's what wasn't known before our research. So,
so the type of one
was definitely no,
by the way, we chose to kind of we thought about it and it was like, OK,
part of the reason is OK.
So Java missed this part like Java kind of, you know,
missed this bit about having this high level api for constructing archives.
So so
this is like somehow they manage like one of the oldest languages ever, right,
somehow managed to miss it.
But there is also lack of awareness to this kind of issue. So there's like
security folks do know like they do know they
like when they see the step of vulnerability,
they immediately know
but developers not so much. And
and so we we we thought that
we would want to kind of like increase increase awareness to this issue.
And and
one thing that
jumped to mind is what we have with zip bomb, right?
Like this kind of vulnerability that is denial of service vulnerability
like in any kind of compression algorithm. When you know, like you, you compress,
you take a huge chunk of data that is
well compressed like the same character repeated over and over
and then it is being compressed to a small chunk of data.
But when it's being extracted in the server or in the destination, it just explodes,
right?
So this
zip
-- zip bomb like this is something that is, you know, this is a well known cons
-- yeah,
the billion labs attack.
Exactly. So the same thing with, you know, exactly the XML
and, and, and, and so,
and, but this time vulnerability, we felt like it's so prevalent. It's so, you know,
like we see it in so many places.
So it kind of, you know, deserved its own name.
Also, we, like we had to find them, you know, to call this project,
the name to call this project internally.
So
it started with
zip sleep, but we also chose to kind of,
you know, keep it up and just have it. And then the good thing that we already see,
like, uh you know, it's being, it's, it's, it's a much more
uh like, you know, understandable concept than
arbitrary file right through, you know, directory traversal or whatever, like,
and, and there is, if, if we actually looked at those 170 CBS you mentioned
and the descriptions are very, very different, you know, in some cases,
-- it would be like because
-- they're all written by different humans.
That's the dirty secret to CV. It's all, it's all manually. Sorry about that folks.
Exactly.
And, and, and, and,
and, and that, that's actually, you know, that's made us think about
uh also like, how should we, you know, name those issues?
And
by the way, I have to say that. So
thanks to you guys, we became AC N A, the CV numbering authority.
And so
the zip sleep vulnerabilities were the first one we assigned CV S to as
yes, it's part of like being CN A. So that was also exciting for us.
Well, and,
and this is something I think important for people to realize like CV ES are great.
Don't get me wrong. I love CV S
but they're really more for computers than people, right?
People don't talk about CV E dash here, dash whatever,
you know,
and with respect to zip slip, there is CWE the common, you know,
weakness enumeration database, which is the idea is to
classify all the different types of vulnerabilities.
You know what is a buffer overflow versus a buffer underflow?
And I'm just looking through it quickly,
I can't tell which one I'm supposed to use for
this vulnerability because there's CWE 23 35 36 3726 maybe.
And so I,
I think in a way this branding of these
vulnerabilities really helps because the other thing is discoverability,
right?
If you plug zip slip into Google,
you get, well, you get your, your research page,
your FA Q essentially that covers it beautifully
and it, you know,
to put it bluntly, it's really easy to say to a developer.
Please go Google Zip slip and read the first result.
I can prove the point here,
Kurt even what's the CV E for heart bleed
like the most famous security issue of all time.
The only CV I know off by heart is CV E 2016 9 triple five, also known as El Diablo,
it was one of the first protocol vulnerability
and TLS and it's because it broke our reporting
system because we updated the report over 100 times
and it turns out we had a counter for that.
So some poor
schmuck had to re enter all the data manually and then we
updated it like another 60 times.
-- But,
-- but that's
exactly
the reason to know that. Right. Like, no, I agree.
I think naming things is, is good for humans and,
and like this is a crazy issue that like what you say 100 and 70 CV es for this one,
Danny.
So, so these are the historic,
I think you guys mentioned that like looking back at
the C DS from the previous series from this one,
we had about 30 CV S but they are still coming, right? Because
some of those, for example, uh Microsoft just in the last patch,
Tuesday then assigned to
zip slip CV S one in powershell
and another in.in dot net core.
And so it took, it took half a year since the disclosure
and just uh because they uh this is something
actually like the thanks, like they, they found the issue,
but because we kind of alerted them to, to the to the general issue of zip
and several vulnerable projects, but they went and,
and did some internal uh research and found a
few other products that we weren't aware to.
Uh And so they were nice enough to actually accredit us with the CV S. So this is uh
so, so the CV S are still coming. I think we're now at about 30.
But when it comes to number of vulnerable projects
that already kind of
uh you know, confirmed and fixed,
they are much more and it's still kind of, you know, process of assigning those.
So some are CNAs themselves like
apaches. So we have
and seek exploitable projects there. But I think so far, only four CV CV s
but expecting to, to get that gather to assign as well.
And the cool part is that we also created this skid
hub uh page that
basically a collaborative document for anyone to be able to
add new,
affected uh libraries affected the compression libraries
or projects to the list there.
And
we're so happy to see
several requests.
So people found this issue in pearl in the pearl library,
which we didn't actually had even the time to check.
So in D code and D libraries
and several others. So, so this was also a good
sign for us that you know, like we raised raised awareness.
So people actually you know,
looked and see like how prevalent it is and actually did a simple thing like,
you know, just checked the first li
we
stumbled upon that wasn't listed on our
document and just found the
bunch that were vulnerable. So
also kind of some some good collaboration with the community and,
and, and, and one other thing is that we see much more reports since we, you know,
internally we track all those open source
vulnerabilities and add them to our database.
So we also see the zip slips that are, you know, coming not from us. And
there is definitely an increase in in in the zip slips that are reported and fixed and
in other product projects that
unfortunately not code to directly to this github page that I mentioned.
But still, you know, go through the disclosure channels and you know, being fixed.
-- So that's, that's also great.
-- Fantastic. Oh
man, that is so cool.
So I, I guess we're, we're nearly out of time,
but I wanted to ask you one more question and we'll make this one quick is so
the, the other thing I love that SNCC
does is the kind of state of open source security report,
which the the current ones from 2017,
you tell me you're working in your 2018 report and
-- that thing is awesome. I love it.
-- Thank you. Thank you.
And yeah, we are working on, on the next one, the 2018 and the plan is to, to uh
publish it in mid February.
We
have to
keep an eye
out for that
and I guess I want to talk about uh
just, I guess, praise you guys for two important things is first of all,
a lot of what we do in security is kind of voodoo and,
and you guys are giving us some numbers to really look at, you know, which is,
which is fantastic and, and I love that,
but then most importantly is at the bottom of your report,
you have action items people can take
which like
none of the reports I ever see that.
Talk about the state of security, tell people what to do
and, and I applaud you guys for that because it's like, OK, great.
Everything's on fire. What now? Right? Like the end
-- and, and that's awesome. So well
-- done. Thank you. Wow, that's so great to hear.
I'm, I'm definitely passing this message to, to the folks work.
I'm going to say I'm, I'm sure they, they, we're planning to keep it,
but this is so good to hear that, that feedback.
-- Thank you.
-- I love that. Awesome. Awesome. So, I guess,
yeah, let's say any, any clothing
first, Dan, before we, we head out.
Um Wow, this was first of all, like, I really, really enjoyed the conversation.
It took us, indeed.
It took us so long to get to talk, but I definitely hope that's not,
that wouldn't be our last conversation.
So, so uh would be really happy to, to keep on talking,
collaborating on all the, you know, open source security stuff.
Yeah, I think I really had fun. So
uh
-- thank you. Thank you so much.
-- Thank you. It's been fantastic.
I can't wait to have you back, man. So, all right, cool. So, I guess thank you, Danny.
Thank you everyone for listening. You can go to open source security podcast.com.
I'll have show notes for all this stuff. Danny talked about.
I'll have links to things like his Twitter and linkedin and
all the usual suspects and then you can use the pound
to podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media and you have nothing else, I guess.
-- Uh, gentlemen, have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too.
-- Thank you.
Goodbye.