Hello and welcome to the
security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime. Josh Bresser.
-- Back
-- to Crime. How exciting
to be clear. We had nothing to do with what we're about to discuss. Did we?
I personally,
I'll be blunt, I don't see a good path to monetization with this attack,
so I'm not interested.
Ok. So we're gonna PHP. Got back
door and
-- that's neat.
-- Well, the thing is if that had actually made it
-- into a release, yeah, that would be news.
-- I agree.
Well, sort of, I mean,
-- but
-- I'm pretty sure nobody's using PHP current or head or whatever it's called.
I would hope not.
I mean,
I would suspect most people running PHP are running comically old versions of it.
Well, I've installed PP by hand.
So the answer is everybody's running whatever they were given by default.
No, I'm serious. Right. We've, we've, we've been, we've been there.
It's, I don't install anything manually anymore.
Like I, I consider even installing like a snap to be like that's a little bit,
maybe too much work.
But, ok, I'll do it this one time. So, yeah.
-- So PHP they put in the back door and, well, like you said, it was, it
-- was ok.
Let's, let's explain this a little more in depth for anyone who doesn't know.
So PHP is a web
development language from,
it's a blast from the past.
I mean, I haven't written PHP code in well over a decade,
I think at this point and I don't think I've even seen any in over a decade
-- says the guy who runs a wordpress site, I
-- do not run wordpress. I pay automatic to run.
Word is wordpress written in PHP. I don't even know.
-- Is it
-- cool? It's a PHP. It's a class. It's
wordpress is the ubiquitous lamp stack, right? Linux Apache, mysql PHP.
Oh, that's right. Lamp. I forgot about lamp.
-- Yeah, that's funny. You know what?
-- We're going so old.
-- We're starting to forget stuff then and
-- the world moves on. Right.
-- I mean, no Js is the PP of today.
-- Well, also Holy PHP is up to version eight.
I just looked at the website and I'm like, is it? That's what the website says.
-- It
-- doesn't matter. Right.
Remember it used to be Pearl and then it was PP and then I don't know it was
in the middle and now it's no Js and it'll be something else in a decade and whatever.
Well, the nice thing about PHP is, you know,
you could actually just jam some code into a page and poof instant.
-- It just worked.
-- It definitely had a uniqueness to it. I will agree with that.
So, anyway, anyway, anyway, PHP had
two commits that have been pointed out where it was
clearly a malicious actor inserting bad code into PHP.
And here's the really wild part about all of this.
They believe the credentials were stolen from the user and from, I,
I don't have confirmation of this,
but supposedly two factor authentication was enabled.
So
something that, that adds a whole, like what's going on here aspect of this.
-- Well,
-- if they proxi it, right?
Just because the thing is, it depends on how you're doing two factor if you're doing,
you know, a six digit
code S MS to your phone,
you can either intercept that by intercepting S MS
or somebody's at,
you know, a bad web page and they enter in their six
digit
code. Now it's, it's when you start talking things like, well UB keys,
then you're actually like, even if you go to the attacker website,
plug your key and your key is gonna be like, no, bro, don't do that.
Yep. Yep.
OK. So anyway, we find out about all of this, everything's kind of reverted.
And I think the one thing the PHP developers did that it is very clever
is they were running their own source code management system and they were like,
we have to stop doing this immediately and they moved everything to
-- github like overnight.
-- It was easier than that because
I
moved to github but github was not the canonical source. It was a
copy. OK.
I'm less impressed now with how quickly they did it well,
-- but
-- more to the point they have the foresight to do that.
Lots of projects do that. I think like a lot of the Apache stuff does that.
-- Well, the Linux kernel even is the
-- Linux kernel.
Yeah, it's in github.
I know it's in github. But is that not the canonical copy?
-- I don't,
-- I don't know anymore.
I don't pay attention to any of this stuff anymore.
-- The other thing is it was actually two developers that got hacked. Was it
-- two of them?
Yeah,
it says yesterday 2 2021 3 28 2 malicious commits were
pushed to the PHP source repo from the names of Rasmus
Erdf and myself.
So
two accounts got hacked, which is even more impressive.
Well, maybe it, well, it's, here's what I don't get about.
This whole attack is the attacker is sophisticated enough to pop to developers who
are hopefully somewhat technologically sophisticated and, you know,
somewhat security savvy
and they have that level of sophistication,
but then they totally screw up on the back door.
-- The back door is so comically obvious.
-- I know that's
what I mean.
They didn't try to hide it at all.
It was clearly a backdoor which I and I think this is where
the whole story veers off into the weeds is no attacker who's
legitimately trying to attack something.
Does this,
this feels like there's some meta layer
that we don't understand of someone trying to
prove a point or someone trying to send a message to someone else or something?
It's, it's stupid.
Yeah.
Remember those massive D
OS attacks where everybody's like, oh, it's the Russians and Chinese.
Why would they burn zero days to blah, blah, blah.
And it turned out a couple of teenagers doing Minecraft D
os extortion. I mean,
right.
-- So
-- your story is more boring.
-- It's I will, it's like the Twitter hack. It was a 17 year old.
-- I remember that one too
like this. I'm sorry to say.
But when I say somebody who's technologically sophisticated and security savvy
like me, I can still get hacked by a 17 year old.
I just have to be tired one day and make a mistake once
or just live with a 17 year old. And,
-- well,
-- for example, at the CS A, we keep getting these, uh, you know, word documents,
mostly Excel files that have Macro viruses, that
one or two of the detection engines, mostly the Chinese ones on virus,
total.com detect and the rest don't.
And so, you know, Gmail happily passes these through and they're,
they're really obviously viruses or, you know,
macro viruses because it's like a short little Excel
file from somebody we've never heard of from some,
you know, random AOL account or whatever saying, you know, blah, blah,
please open this and it detects in a couple of antivirus engines.
This actually speaks to some stuff I've been
looking at where you're going to get hacked.
The question is how fast can you get rid of
the attacker and return to a normal good baseline?
And
git is lovely for that because to get rid of two git
commits is, well, it's really easy. It's one commands
and for example, to move to github, the
thing I love about github
is
I also have a copy of it.
So even if github were to get hacked and somebody were to monkey with my G
repo in github,
my workstation would be like, whoa what, you know what happened here, right?
Like all the commits are wonky. You know, I would throw up a huge air
and if you also do signed commits, which are a pain in the butt, but not impossible.
You know, now you also have to
compromise cryptographic material on the workstation.
The difference here is,
I don't think they actually broke into the developers workstations.
It sounds like they got fished.
And that's a big difference.
Like I absolutely guarantee you at some point in the future, I will get fished.
It's gonna,
-- you're a human, all humans are going to get fish.
-- That's why he's a password manager.
But anyway,
but the chances of somebody actually breaking into
and getting persistence on my workstation are much,
much, much lower.
I mean, that's true.
I do rail on signed commits a lot because they don't exactly do what
people think they do and the vast majority of people have unprotected keys.
Dude, it's such a pain in the, to have to type in your passwords every time.
-- So
-- it is, it's, it's a huge pain.
I literally have unprotected signing keys because, but it does raise the bar.
This is what got fedora in trouble is people had unprotected SSH
keys on shared systems that are also used to manage like infrastructure.
Well, but here's the challenge, right?
Even if I protect my SSH key or my P GP GP G, whatever key,
if the attacker gets local persistence
with my privilege level right now, it's just a waiting game.
-- Yeah, you've got huge problems. I mean,
-- even,
well, it's just a waiting game.
I will eventually unlock my key and they will, they will see that.
I mean, brutal simplicity.
They could just alias the command to something that logs it and runs the command.
Probably.
I mean, this is where you can make the argument like UB key can store your GP G key
on the, on the hardware token. And like I have that it's a huge pain in the butt to use.
But
even then if someone has persistence on my machine,
they can just wait for me to plug the key and unlock the key and then it's over.
But well,
but then there's a subtle difference is that they can
use your key but they can't copy your key.
That's true.
And so that means you can have an incident,
but you can also,
you can close the barn door. Most likely.
That's a good point. I mean, not that it matters.
I would still obviously recycle that key immediately if it was used incorrectly,
even once
that I know of because who knows how many times it got used, you know,
and that's part of the problem, right?
Is, is with like with availability and integrity, it's really obvious,
like kind of what happened.
Well, let me rephrase with availability.
It's pretty obvious what happened because it's either broken,
missing or gone with integrity.
If you have backups or something to ref to reference against, it's pretty easy,
but not always.
And then with confidentiality though, your stuff could be out there on the dark web.
-- Who knows?
-- That's true. Yeah, you can't, you don't know.
Yeah. And you can't prove a negative of saying like this is gone.
We wiped it off the internet anyway.
So here's the real thing I want to talk about with,
with all this whole PHP nonsense is the fact that
there's going to be naysayers that are like, oh open source. It's so insecure.
Look at all this, look at all this.
But I think the reality is this is kind of how it works where
something happens, lots of people notice
and then there are reactions to it immediately
and the exact opposite is ubiquity is in the
news right now for basically just trying to brush
everything under the rug for a terrible incident.
It works.
They did manage to brush it under the rug until you know,
there was an uh a reputable article about it.
And so long story short, it sounds like because when it initially came out,
I was like, OK,
saying
third party hosted data,
that's weasel words now because everything is third party hosted because
you're unless you have your own hardware in a colo location,
somebody else is hosting it,
right? Infrastructure as a service platform is a service, whatever.
And
there's obviously like pretty much everybody uses
Amazon S3 buckets at this point to
store data because it's just so cheap and it just works so well.
And so the classic thing is, you know,
people don't protect their S3 buckets properly and they get popped and
voila,
you know, data exfiltration from us, they use real fast and easy.
So I was, I was betting that that's what had happened originally.
And it turns out I was right.
Uh What I wasn't right about though was about how bad
it was like the type of data that was exposed.
And
here's the thing, if, if it was just this one thing, I could sort of forgive ubiquity.
But I've actually noticed in the last six months
because we actually bought a bunch of ubiquity gear.
And so, you know, because they're, they're good. Right. They're ok.
But because we've bought it, I've been paying a little more attention to them than
well I ever did before.
And there's some threads on hacker news that are,
especially in the last week or two that
are actually kind of concerning talking about,
you know,
the amount of engineering talent that has left the company and how
it's just sort of in a race to the bottom with cheap developers
and worse things like advertising in the interface in some cases.
Uh
That's terrible.
It just to be blunt, it sounds like the company peaked and is in decline.
And, and look, even if that's true, the fact is
they are
hiding behind a curtain
and they pulled the pay no attention to the man behind the
curtain and they got away with it for a little while.
But I think the lesson here is
anyone who complains about open source being insecure
is either they have an agenda or they're
comically ill informed because like these are two
opposite instances where the open source example,
things happen the way they should have happened to make everything better.
And in the ubiquity sense, it's like
this is a comedy of errors.
It's not a comedy of errors. It's, it's, it looks to be actively malice.
-- OK? Comedy is stupidity then maybe.
-- No, no, no.
It, it looks to be,
it looks like they actually made a conscious decision to hide this.
I I have no doubt they did. I have no doubt. Someone with a fancy title
made this happen.
Yeah. No, it's,
and
I will absolutely forgive PHP.
Like, in my opinion,
all major open source projects should be in github because if nothing else,
like
spending that time and effort running that infrastructure
is unless you're building tools that do that,
you know, like, get labs. If GIT labs is in github,
I would say that's a problem. But get labs, you know, they're on their own dogs
-- or for example,
-- well, there's like Ed Lass
and has
lab has its own
github.
There's, there's a handful of services that do this and you're right,
this is their service.
This is their bread and butter.
By definition, you will never be better at this than they are.
Nobody builds their own
data center anymore. We leave that up to the experts.
You know, you, you go and rent rack space because getting reliable power,
reliable internet, physical security, all that stuff.
It's a nightmare.
But having said that so
somebody like ubiquity doing this, it's, it's,
it kind of reminds me of the whole back door versus bug thing where
there's malice, there's intent. Yes.
And,
and I want to focus on that for a second because here's the thing
you need to understand is if an open source project has a security incident,
they have no choice but to
lay it all out.
-- There's no choice
-- one where they've tried to hide it, but
it doesn't work. What happens is, I mean, I've been a part of this more than once.
Is the conversation starts.
You talk about how do we make this seem less bad?
And you come to the inevitable conclusion,
we just have to tell the complete truth. There's nothing else we can do.
That is how this goes down.
There might be a hiccup in some projects where they're like, oh,
we'll try to make it sound this bad.
But at the end of the day,
you're gonna be telling the truth.
Now, when you are a private company,
you can have this conversation and you can come to the conclusion.
We're going to lie
and it is conceivable. No one will know and I promise you 100% every single company
that gets punk
has this conversation
and some of them decide to lie.
Part of it too is I would say it goes back to the intent.
My, my experience with open source is that when it comes to the intent of hiding,
it's more about personal ego or things like that.
There's, there's generally not a lot of money involved.
No,
no, it's just about looking stupid.
Like I don't want to look dumb and well, you look dumb because you got PED
-- like that's just how it is.
-- Yeah. And everybody gets ped at some point,
you know, I actually got pulled through a PHP vulnerability once
there used to be so many.
And, well, no, the funny thing is that it, it was on a f,
it was on a Friday and there was a, like I knew there was a Linux kernel issue.
I should remediate and I was like, I'll put it off till Monday
while the attacker didn't.
Whoops. Like it, it happens. It's just, it's
what's always funny to me is there's, if somebody breaks into a person's house,
you don't blame the person who owns the house, you don't call them stupid.
But yet with software and networks we do that all the time.
It's, it's interesting to me how there's that,
I mean, it's sort of a different dynamic. If somebody left their door hanging open,
you would call them stupid if someone ran in and installed their stuff,
like they opened the door and left,
right.
And in some instances
in it, that is kind of what happens.
So I think it's more complicated but I do agree that generally speaking,
we shouldn't be blaming the victim in most cases.
Yeah. But on the flip side, what some of these victims are doing is so egregious that
right.
You know, like with what ubiquity did,
number one to leave all that customer data exposed
or allow access to it. You know,
because the thing is, if you're in Amazon, you can lock that stuff down,
you can have multi factor authentication, hardware tokens,
like you can do a good job easily.
In theory,
ok. But the problem is ubiquity isn't just some random company.
UBIQUITY is a company
that is like solar winds and that if you hack into
ubiquity you can now hack into a lot of corporate networks.
That's fair.
So I would say that they have a special, you know, it's, it's the difference between,
uh,
somebody who makes consumer grade locks and somebody
like Schlag who makes commercial grade locks if Schlag
has,
you know, a flaw in their lock.
Yeah, that's, it's bad. But
now you, you know, you're talking about, like, breaking into banks and stuff.
I mean, I, I agree with that, I think because, well,
not only that the industrial equipment costs more and it comes with
the impression that it is better than the consumer grade equipment.
Right.
-- Oh, yeah.
-- No, I have a Schlag lock on the door here and it's, it was not a cheap lock.
I, I
do not. Um,
my locks are terrible but that's ok.
It's, the locks only exist in my house.
So when I get broken into I can tell the insurance company I had locks pretty
much,
you know, it's funny to me because, like,
my front door lock is biometric so that my kids can get
in without me having to worry about them losing their key.
I mean, that's fair. I, I'm, I'm ok with that.
Well, I also have a security system. So,
but is it hooked up to the internet?
Yes, of course it is. It's ring.
No, not the security system. I mean, is the door lock hooked up to the internet?
Sweet.
So, if the, if your wi Fi goes out, can you knock it in your house?
Uh, well, no, no, no, you can get in with a biometric or a key.
-- No,
-- even without internet.
Yeah.
Well, the bi
is local. Right. It's a thumbprint scanner or it's a fingerprint scanner.
-- Well,
-- right. But I don't know, does it send that off to the cloud or something
locally? Which means it's comically terrible.
No. No.
Like, seriously the, the experience of, you know, like on a, on an ipad,
you can just mash your finger down basically anywhere and it just works
this thing. You got to put your finger on just right. Or it's, it just kind of goes
beep, beep, beep.
I
mean, that's probably better than letting, like a hot dog open your door, you know?
Well, if you really want to open my door, bring an eight pound sledgehammer,
you can't be giving out information like that.
I'm pretty sure most doors can be opened with an eight pound sledgehammer.
I bet most doors could be opened with a kick.
-- Well, but you might hurt your ankle.
-- Probably. I would, I'm old.
I can't, I can't be doing that kind of stuff.
-- I know.
-- Seriously. It's my osteoporosis.
Which, well, that actually leads to another interesting topic.
So, we decided a long time ago.
That keys had to be secret, which meant, you know,
with the rise of high quality cameras,
people need to keep their keys in their pockets.
-- Yeah.
-- Right.
Well, you know, one of my favorite examples is remember when the whole, like,
you have to buy a TS, a approved lock for your life
became a thing.
Someone took a picture of the TS A keys.
This was like AAA press thing where the TS A like the media group took a
picture of the keys and then someone took the pictures and they 3D printed TS a keys
and
well, right. But like
that's hilarious, right?
Well, the same thing happened with uh when it was like a New York,
either a fire department or an elevator key.
It was like posted online and it's,
it's actually known as like the 8684 key or
something because that's the bidding on the key.
One of the magic keys
that opens up like half the doors in New York
anyways. Um So the deal is keys have cuts,
um
cheap keys basically just have depth of cut.
Uh for example, a more expensive lo like a slog.
They also have a direction of cut, right? They have like a slope to it.
Yeah. And, and you know what, we'll just put a link to the lock picking lawyer.
He talks about all this stuff and shows it off and he takes it up hard and it's amazing.
And uh and I love that anyways.
And so the majority of consumer grade cheap keys are just cut to a certain depth,
you know, uh it's uh between a one and a five depth of cut.
So there's
five positions.
And so the deal is
if you can take a picture of the key, obviously, you can copy the key.
But what if you can listen to the key being inserted into the lock?
-- I
-- mean, it's a side channel attack on, on keys. I love it. It's awesome.
And, but here's the thing, right?
So traditionally, I would have said, oh, that's gonna be tricky.
But here's one of my friends recently did an IOT project where he took a really tiny,
single form uh single uh system on a chip, small form factor board.
We're talking something the size of like basically two jelly beans glued together.
That's a computer running Linux,
right?
I've seen them. They're awesome. And he attached it to a lithium ion 16, 850 battery,
which means it'll run for like months.
Right?
Well, and that's, I think that's the thing that has changed is
I can now build a surveillance device with a camera and, or microphone
-- that is number one, very high quality. I
-- mean, I carry one in my pocket man.
Yeah.
Well, I'm talking small though, not big, like a phone. I'm talking small.
Like it looks like a piece. Like it just, it looks like a small piece of gravel,
right?
And that's part of the difference is,
you know,
you could easily hide something like this near the lock as a rock or a,
a piece of dog turd
and not, and collect time over da or data over time, right?
So you collect multiple key insertions because
that was one of the challenges they were
saying is like look a single key insertion that's gonna be really hard and yeah,
it probably will be.
But I'm guessing with some machine learning algorithms and you know, 10 or 20
instances of the data,
I'm guessing that problem becomes much easier.
Yeah,
probably there's so I'll put a link in the show notes but the lock picking
lawyer actually has a video I watched some
time ago where there's this like little camera
you,
yeah, you insert into
the the keyhole
and then
it, it you look at the picture and then they have like this little card and based upon
it's just a borescope,
I mean, right? But based upon what you see then
that you, you could decode the key,
get the code and then basically go to like a one of those
lock creating machines type the code in you decode it from the camera key
and it will print a functioning key like it's
and
here's the difference that technology used to be horrendously expensive,
but now it's,
you know, 3050 bucks.
-- Well, no,
-- I mean that that particular camera, I think was like $300 which is still not
-- ok. $300 is still pretty cheap.
-- It's still pretty cheap. I agree.
Like, and you're right,
cause a technology like that even a decade ago would have been thousands of dollars.
I bought a bore scope. It's eight millimeters in diameter.
It has led lights on the end. It's basically just a, it's a fancy USB camera
on the end of a 10
m
stall.
-- It's amazing
-- to inspect my plumbing and it was,
it was under $30.
They're super cheap. I don't have one.
-- I keep meaning to get one
-- and it came with a USB battery that has a Wi Fi transmitter.
So it connect as a Wi Fi camera,
right? It's got like this really terrible app but
you basically just plug this battery and shove
the camera down a thing and then you can
pull the image up on your iphone or ipad or if you have like a laptop,
you just plug it straight into the USB
and it was like 25 or
-- it was under 30 bucks.
-- Yeah, they're dirt cheap. I, I looked into one at one point.
I,
I don't remember why I didn't get it but they are
-- ridiculously inexpensive
-- and they used to be thousands of dollars.
-- Yeah.
-- Yeah. I mean, I, yeah,
I remember that.
I remember when it was a huge deal. If you do someone with a Bar Scco camera
and, and I remember actually using them on C RT s
because that's the only way you could look at the picture.
Oh, yeah.
And they didn't work in the sun because it's AC RT.
So you had to, like, construct this weird little, like, shaded area to, to use it.
Oh, man, those are the days. Anyway. Anyway, we, we're in the weeds.
So, I, I think that, see, and this is part of my
sort of risk assessment of my house is, I'm not,
I know fundamentally that the whole point of a key
is that it relies on obscurity of the bidding and
quote unquote, air quotes, difficulty in copying the key, which it's not,
you can go buy blank keys and a key punch for 20 bucks on ebay.
-- Well,
-- you can use a bump key and get into any lock in like three seconds.
Just locks on houses suck and are from the perspective of keeping people out,
they fail 100%.
And so my security posture for my house doesn't rely on that.
Right. It's just
like most things, the, uh, physical security, uh, the,
the premise is I want to slow the attacker down enough that the police can show up.
I mean, that's fair.
Well, because no offense. But if somebody doesn't show up to enforce
and through, I mean, physical force to enforce the law,
why would the attacker stop?
I mean, they wouldn't. Right.
And this is one of the problems in like rural communities,
right where the cops take half an hour to an
hour to show up the Attackers know that they can
go through your barn and grab your A TV and stuff.
Yep. Yep. Yeah, there's infinite time for sure, for sure.
And, I mean, ok, so let's, let's bring it all back to the beginning and,
and tie this all together.
I think it really, I think we're going to see a shift from
traditional sort of barrier security
to more monitoring and active response security.
And I don't mean just physically, but,
you know, on your phone, on your computer,
the,
the reality is we know the Attackers are gonna get a zero
day or gonna get a well known issue that you forgot to patch
and they're going to get in.
And for example, I love that apparently on Apple iphones now,
a
99.9% certain way to get an attacker off your phone is to turn it off and on.
Right. Because they to get actual hardware-based persistence
-- is apparently really difficult on an iphone
-- now.
I mean, so look, I like what you said at the beginning, but I wanna,
I wanna relate something to that.
So I, I do think you are correct that prevention is generally a red herring
and I don't think it works very often,
but I will say in light of many of the supply
chain attacks that are now becoming like a hot topic.
I'm seeing more and more people becoming more
and more obsessed with prevention instead of detection
and the real, like, here's, here's one of my favorite examples.
You know, I work at elastic and our products contain a,
a large number of open source dependencies
because obviously every product does today.
Right. That's just, that's how it works.
And I track these things meticulously and there are,
for example, you will have, uh, I mean,
we've talked about this at length where there will be a
security issue in a bit of code we're not using.
And it's like, OK, I acknowledge this is there,
but this is obviously vastly less important than the security
issue in the bit of code we are using.
And I've, I've had more people than I'm comfortable with basically show up and say,
uh because of all the supply chain attacks,
you have to fix all of these issues immediately and we can't,
they can't be in the product.
And of course, in my perspective, I have the ability to talk to these people.
Like here's what is going on. This is why we're not doing it
because me fixing this thing, you're obsessing about means I'm not fixing,
fixing that thing over there that actually matters.
And you're like, oh, ok, well, you do that. I mean, not everyone.
So people are like, no, there's no other way.
-- And I'm like, well, whatever,
-- well,
some people I think fundamentally don't trust their vendors and
they want like a completely clean scan report because they,
yeah,
I mean,
I, I get that but I think this is also a place where like in the,
in the instance of elastic,
all of our source code is wide open on the internet. You don't have to believe me.
Go freaking look yourself. Now, granted, 99% of the people arguing with me.
I'm,
-- I'm quite certain can't do this
-- to have the expertise and go make your own decision.
If they did that, why are they using you as a vendor?
-- I mean,
-- you could,
you could definitely say that and I sort of agree to a certain amount,
but I think at the same time, like
this is a delicate balance of, I don't believe you fix it all of
no.
And here's the source code.
If you don't believe me, go hire someone to look at it and prove me wrong.
I think the problem more basically probably boils down to a
liability argument of the vendor said they fixed all the flaws
and they clearly didn't versus if the vendor says they fixed
some of the flaws and didn't fix all of the flaws.
I feel like, you know, you're gonna have a hard time proving something in court
to throw that company under the bus.
I mean, that's probably fair and I know there's, I know of more than one we'll say,
I know instances where tricking the scanner was the solution
versus actually fixing problems.
But here's the thing, if you get, if you get a clean scan back,
that's a busted scanner, right?
Somehow someone, either the scanner is broken or someone found a way to trick it.
And, and additionally, here's the other part of that, that really just,
the more I think of it,
the more it becomes obvious like this PHP thing is a great example,
blindly upgrading to the latest version of something automatically,
I think is probably dangerous unless you have a really good reason to do it.
Well, you would need such a mature C I CD testing pipeline.
Well, and,
and not just that and people don't like three
-- people have backdoors
-- generally don't get found immediately.
There's a little bit of a lag.
And so I think if you're, if you're upgrading too fast,
I think that also carries a certain risk to it
versus
making sure.
Ok, let's give this new thing a little time to cook and then we will upgrade to it.
You know what I mean? I it's, it's all everything matters in this equation.
And I think
we've swung the pendulum in a direction where there's just this like
there's this group of people running around screaming upgrade, upgrade, upgrade
and
they're missing all of this other stuff that comes with that, right?
It's like if you do this, there are going to be other consequences to your actions.
In theory, I would say, ok, because there's, here's the problem though,
there's a difference between upgrade, upgrade,
upgrade and I can actually upgrade everything and
know if it works or not because I have
a
C I CD pipeline. I, I agree.
And that's the first big part of the problem is everybody kind of
seems to blindly assume that everybody will be able
to upgrade and things just won't go horrifically sideways.
Like I saw my devs talking yesterday about, uh some rails module from, you know,
they, they would like to use version 3.0 0.0.
They're on version two point something right now,
obviously two point something to 3.0 0.0.
-- You and I both have an immediate reaction of uh like whoa
-- something's broke.
I mean, that that's the whole point, right?
That was the point of versioning as saying 2 to 3 is going to have breaking changes.
That makes sense. I like that.
And so, but on the flip side,
I know my Devs are mature enough to basically to do this and,
and see if it kind of breaks or not and if it breaks,
then I trust them to either fix it or roll back
and if it doesn't break cool full steam ahead.
And that's the difference though, is,
is having that ability to test and be able to roll back and do all that.
But most places don't have that,
you know,
to put it bluntly if you're shipping your software
or your service or whatever, you're updating it less than once or twice a week.
You're not there yet.
Like,
when you get to the point where you're doing, you know, once or twice a week updates,
now you can talk about kind of safely running current because you've, I would hope,
you know, matured the process and automated enough such that it's, it's a non event.
Yeah. I mean, I think this is how we should end it. I,
yeah, I think like everything, the issue is complicated
and I think it is just human nature to try to trivialize what we're doing
in a way that is probably silly and dangerous because we're humans.
Well, and we want these simple solutions like, oh,
you fixed all the potholes in the road,
we fixed the big ones, the little ones are still there.
-- So
-- we'll get to those eventually and they might turn
into big potholes and then we'll fix them right away.
You know, that's just, that's life, that's how it is. All right.
Anyway, thank you, everyone for listening.
Go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up our
show. It's Susie Pound To Us Podcast. Hashtag You hit us up on social media, Kurt.
You have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye.
That.