Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
All right, I'm going to put a link in the show notes that I want everyone to go see.
But yet last night,
I witnessed one of the most epic examples of hacking I have seen in a long time
and I'll explain this a little bit first and then we'll get to the,
the real topic we're going to talk about today.
But this is too cool not to at least explain.
So summer games done quick is going on right now, which is a speed running event.
I absolutely love. And by the time this podcast goes out it is going to be over.
So you have missed it, go watch
all the, the speed runs are on youtube and they're amazing.
But there's one specifically I want to call out. So there was
a speed run for a game called Paper Mario, which is a Nintendo 64 game. OK.
This speed run they did.
It's also on the Wii actually, they've got all, all different,
all different consoles,
but specifically the Nintendo 64 matters in this
instance because what happens is the speed runners.
Basically, they set up the memory of the Nintendo 64
and then they
execute some commands that jumps program execution into their,
you know, machine written code
that then jumps to the end credits. OK.
Here's the bananas part about this
is in order to see the memory correctly in the way they need it.
You have to have a Nintendo 64 with what's called the expansion
pack in which doubles a ram from four megs to eight megs.
Then
you have to play the legend of Zelda Ocarina of time
to write the machine code into the expansion memory.
Oh, so it doesn't white memory before it uses it.
-- That's right.
-- Well, some games do, some games don't.
Well, I mean, back in the day that actually mattered for performance. Right. Right.
Like that. And it's, it's bananas
given that we're talking about a system with four meg of ra M right here.
Like, yeah, people took shortcuts.
Right. Right. And it's, it's completely insane because they play ocarina of time.
They set everything up.
Ocarina of time crashes and it brings up the equivalent
of the blue screen of death where it shows,
you know, a bunch of registers and,
and scary other information and that's how they know
that they wrote everything correctly. Then they quickly switch cartridges,
they play paper Mario up to a point where they can basically
make the program jump to another place now in Paper Mario,
they have no way to write
the machine instructions they need into memory,
but they're already there from the legend of Zelda.
And then all of a sudden the game ends and credits start and it's just,
it is absolutely amazing.
-- It is so cool.
-- I'm just always amazed that
people have the spare time to do this.
Right. No, because this is a nontrivial amount of work and effort.
It's completely nuts and there's, I'll, I'll put another link,
there's an explanation of how this was done and it is
an incredible amount of knowledge and effort that these people did.
And it is, I think
endearing
that there are people who care so much about speed
running and these games that they're willing to invest,
you know, I mean, I mean, essentially think of it like a hobby, right?
Like, some people will play golf every day of the week.
These people are understanding the inner workings of
video games and the consoles they run on.
It's fantastic.
Well,
what always kills me is that they have such a
deep understanding of this platform and how to abuse it
and we somehow pretend like security flaws are hard to find
like this.
Like, what they're doing is objectively as hard,
if not harder than most security flaws.
-- Right.
-- Absolutely.
-- 100%. And they're doing it for fun and
-- they have no source code.
Yeah.
And those like consoles are actually as
Well, there's, you know, the thing where, like, if you want a game and just game,
you get a console because it doesn't crash and do stupid stuff like a PC.
Like my PC.
Literally, I finally made it stop crashing and I made Google chrome stop crashing.
And it was memory speed. It, my, my four sticks of ra M
they're all identical, you know, same brand, same everything.
So they're hopefully the same, but
they will not run it through 600 megahertz
reliably. I, I suspect one of the sticks is, you know, just not quite right because
running at 3400 megahertz and it's rock solid
and it took me like a week and a half of pain to finally go.
Oh, maybe if I turn down my memory speeds,
my computer will stop. You know,
like if I, if you asked me to break into a windows system versus like a nez
I would pick the windows machine every time
anyway. Anyway,
it made me smile as I watched this happen.
And it's,
it's funny too because one of the things that I think sometimes we take
for granted is a lot of people in the security and hacking space,
we understand a lot of this stuff.
So when you talk about arbitrary code execution, that makes sense.
-- Well, even jumping, what is a jump in code? Right.
-- Right. Exactly.
And so they're trying to explain to an audience that
has no idea what any of this stuff is,
and
I won't say they did a great job,
but I think they did a pretty good job of all things considered.
And it, it was just,
it is amazing. It is absolutely amazing.
And I love the fact that this guy played two different games and swapped him
and, and executed his, his instructions. It's, ah,
I love it. It was so cool. All right.
Anyway, anyway, we have an actual topic to discuss today.
-- Why don't you tell us what it is?
-- So, typically open source software
is one of two things.
It's either, you know,
a person or a project that's kind of just a
bunch of people hacking away and working on it.
No real corporate backing or anything or the other model that's quite common is,
but there's, there's like a company wrapped around it,
you know. So a perfect example being like Red Hat Linux or
Ubuntu or Elastic or, you know, Google Chrome, right?
I, I,
they simply put, there's a company that has a need either directly for the product,
like we want to sell this thing and support it or sort of an indirect need.
Like we need,
we need people to have web browsers that don't suck and it protects our ad revenue.
So we need a good web browser out there.
You know, like back in the day when Java V eight,
you know, Chrome came along and just beat Firefox like a rented mule. It was ugly,
how much faster chrome was than Firefox.
And, you know,
because Google needed java or a javascript based
apps to not be so terrible anyways sometimes.
And this is sort of the, this to me is the really interesting one is when
something is sort of small project or single person open source
and then it gets acquired by a company
and I think a
big problem here is, is most and it's probably Survivor bias by definition,
a company that starts doing open source probably kind of understands open source.
But a company that goes into open source by Quasi, I want to say,
I don't want to say buying a project, but it's,
I don't know what other word to use. Acquiring, that's the word, acquiring a project
typically, like, screws it up horrifically, like, uh, well,
look in the show notes for maybe a link to the free note debacle.
Oh, my goodness. Yeah. Exactly.
And we even,
we did a show about this and it got even worse after we recorded the episode.
-- Oh, exactly. And it keeps getting worse. Right. So,
-- it's true. It's not done yet.
-- But wait, there's more.
-- Exactly.
And well, blunt, why do you think audacity is going to be any? Not as terrible?
Audacity has a slightly different,
we'll say set of circumstances
and for anyone who hasn't figured it out yet, we're going to talk about audacity.
Yeah. So Audacity's new parent company, Muse Group. Is pretty new itself, having
only opened its doors last week on April 26th, 2021. This Muse Group owns some brands
related to music software. How do I put it nicely? It looks like they wanted a good
music editor,
which is fair. Right.
Like I writing something like garage band or audacity is, uh,
I believe the word nontrivial would be an understatement.
Yeah, I mean, you're talking multi
years of effort to decades. I mean,
-- maybe whatever, a long time, decades
-- of hidden sound engineering knowledge,
you know, anyways,
they've done some things that are stupid sounding but sort of make sense.
Like
they have app analytics now to improve the app and, and in fairness,
like Linux has done this kind of stuff with S
OS report for jeez a while one or two decades.
-- I
-- mean, Fedora does this actually where when, if you're running Fedora and I,
I assume I, I, my, my guess is
ubuntu and some other distributions,
-- it's,
-- it's on, I've seen it on ubuntu.
-- It's, it's installed by default on a lot of stuff.
-- Right.
Where if your program crashes, it brings up a crash reporter.
Now it doesn't do this automatically. It brings up a crash reporter.
You know, you can fill in some details and then submit it to Bugzilla.
And I remember back in the day,
there were a handful of,
we'll say personal information filled bugs where there was stuff in crash reports
actually. Debian kind of does this too.
I know they have a, they call a popularity contest,
I think where basically your machine phones home all
the packages you have installed on a regular basis,
which would make it pretty trivial to fingerprint a machine if
you know anybody's done any tweaking to their packages at all.
-- Right.
-- And now mind you, this is all opt in, right. None of this is disabled by default
or enabled by whatever words are hard.
Well, we might as well hit that one while we're here.
Yes, if this is opt in
that is a totally different thing than an opt out system,
which is what audacity is doing.
Right. And it's actually not even clear to me that
audacity will allow you to opt out.
I don't know, I haven't looked.
But what's interesting is they've done a couple of things in the license.
Well, it's not the license, it's the desktop privacy notice.
So it's not the license but,
and they talk about here for legal enforcement data necessary for law enforce
litigation and authorities requests if any.
Pretty sure none of my open source software is,
has a direct compliance with law enforcement clause.
What it really looks like here is a bunch of lawyers got involved
and just did some really bad stuff that essentially has poisoned this.
-- I think it's
-- stupid. I don't, I wouldn't say bad, I think stupid and bad.
-- Well,
-- things like you're not allowed to use the app if you're under 13,
which is hilarious because actually the GP L forbids a restriction such as that.
So by saying you can't use this, if you're under 13,
they're violating the GP L which the Audacity code base is licensed under the GP L.
Exactly.
Well, but again,
it's interesting because it's a privacy notice and they say the app
we provide is not intended for individuals below the age of 13.
If you are under 13 years old, please do not use the app.
So they're sort of asking they're not
telling.
Well,
so the issue with that and the reason they do this
for anyone who doesn't know is in the United States,
there's some idiotic think of the Children on
-- the internet law copa
-- Child Online Protection Act.
Yeah.
And it basically says anyone under 13, you have to treat different than
in kids over 13. And so
if audacity is collecting metrics and information from a person under the age of 13,
the rules are vastly different than if they were
collecting information from like the general pop population.
Well,
and it gets worse because they say things like we may disclose the personal
data listed above your hashed IP address
to the following categories of recipients.
I'm sorry, hashing an IP address just doesn't work anymore.
There's only 4 billion IP S
right.
Like,
yeah,
you know,
and what's interesting is they talk about the usual stuff like staff members. Sure.
Competent law enforcement body. Ok.
You know, our auditors, advisors, legal representatives and similar agents. Ok.
To a potential buyer, huh?
Wait, what now?
-- Yeah, we all know what that really is. They want to sell our info.
-- Exactly.
The thing
-- I think that they forget is very few people download audacity and install it.
-- I
disagree.
Well, no, no, no, in the sense of on the,
in the windows and Mac Os world people download it and install it.
But in the Linux world, the system
takes care of that.
So, so they're going to lose the Linux market by probably next Tuesday.
They're gonna, they've already lost everyone.
And what's gonna happen is there will still be
people who Google audacity download and end up at
the audacity
download site
at some point.
Somebody's going to get, you know, somebody's got a friend is going to tell them,
hey, you're using audacity.
Did you hear about X? And they're gonna go? Whoa, that's messed up. Oh, but it's ok.
You go over here to get the one that doesn't do all this crazy stuff. Oh, ok. Done.
And they'll switch and that's it.
-- And,
-- and for anyone listening,
I will put a link in the show notes but there is a fork in the works already which I mean,
should shock nobody.
And it's funny because they're actually, they're trying to pick a new name for it
and like it there, they had a vote and it,
the voting link made it to four chan
and
yeah, they deleted that
-- github
-- issue
boat.
No, no, they had anyway.
It doesn't matter.
But yes, it,
it's everything you can imagine the issue's been
deleted and they're trying to do it again.
Which, I mean, it's part of the hilarity of open source, I think.
But
anyway, Audacity is being forked. So, like, for example,
I do all of the podcast editing and audacity. I spend
many hours a week using this tool and I was super annoyed. Now there's a fork.
I'm like, whatever I don't care anymore.
And, and honestly,
I'm going to do whatever I can to help the fork along just
because like this is a big deal and this is important to me.
And
it's one of those situations of like I was lazy before and now I recognize
the importance of being involved in caring more well.
-- And
-- what's interesting is looking at the audacity github.
It's actually a lot more active than I would have guessed.
There's over 100 contributors, which is a pretty good, healthy sign.
But when you actually go look at the contributors data, the graphs,
there's the top person with 4800 commits.
The next one is 1700 then it's 203 100
288 5550. And it just, it's a long tail.
These top four or five people are like 99.9% of the code in the last couple of years.
And it's not clear to me
that they have any legal obligation to stick with the audacity.
And it's a classic case, if you lose, you lose literally one or two key devs
like this top dev is half the work. The next Dev is like a quarter of the work,
right? Like you lose one or two of those people. Well, yeah, you own audacity good.
-- Have fun with that. Right.
-- Right. I mean, this is kind of what happened
when open office in Liber
office split is basically all the developers
who were doing the work, went to Liber office and open office just languished. Yeah.
Well, yeah, I remember that and the whole arguments with the
licensing, the whole blah blah blah and I'm just like I want to open word documents.
-- I
-- mean, honestly,
the the open office debacle is very similar to this and how it went down now.
Now, why are we talking about this on a security podcast?
Well, I think this has a security implication if to put it bluntly, OK.
Getting a little bit worrisome.
Anybody who runs software on your system that you regularly update,
especially if you pull updates sort of directly, you know,
from them and not say through a vendor.
Well, they basically can execute arbitrary code in your system real trivially.
And something like audacity is, I, I forget how big it is, but it's, you know,
it's over 100 megabytes binary
for
sure.
Like there's a lot of stuff to it.
And
what's interesting to me is we've, is, we've said traditionally, OK,
you found a buffer overflow.
Great. You get a, you know, vulnerability identifier and we should fix it,
but
it's less clear.
Oh, we, you know, we've identified a, a malicious software developer.
Well, OK, he's, you know,
they're putting back doors in the code, they need to stop that, you know, OK,
but when a company acquires something,
especially when a company has no track record of being well behaved.
I mean, that it's literally was a week old when it acquired this thing,
right?
That's, that's worrisome to me, that's like a very material change to the software
that brings a lot of risk and uncertainty and unknowns.
I mean, a simplistic example would be, you know, some product says, hey,
we're going to write our own home built web server and use that instead of, you know,
engine X
hatch.
Well,
that right there to me screams security vulnerabilities because
it's just hard.
So I think we need to be more aware of these material changes to projects
that bring a lot of risk with them
because the reality is a security vulnerability doesn't
necessarily get exploited, right?
There's tons of people running old software with security vulnerabilities,
they're doing just fine.
It really is that simple.
I mean, there's how many out of date Android phones on the planet.
Well,
basically,
so I think as the security community,
we need to start paying a bit more attention to
stuff like this because like the free note example,
with the IRC acquisition thing,
they
went evil and malicious, like they,
they took over support channels and channels that project
to coordinate security work, for example.
Yeah, that's a, that's a problem.
I mean, I think there's another side to this and I, I mean,
I hadn't even really put consideration into
what you're talking about with the vulnerabilities.
But I think just the fact that this,
this is a huge just bait and switch essentially where you have
some sort of project that spends years building this goodwill in community.
And then all of a sudden
somehow an organization appears acquires it
and then basically decides we can do whatever we want.
Look at the power of this brand.
And I mean,
we've seen this even in the private
sector where you have some trusted organization,
it gets bought by a big company and the
big company just runs it into the freaking ground.
Well, and some of that,
that's the thing. Remember with these companies acquiring, there's a
lot of people as a technical person, I was guilty of this back in the day where
like, oh you acquired this company, this great technology.
Obviously, you want to roll that technology into your products. No,
they might want to acquire that company as an acquire, right?
We we don't care about what they do.
We just, hey, we can hire 100 competent engineers in one week.
Remember, Google Wave. Exactly.
Uh Number two is a client acquisition.
I've seen this a lot in certain niche.
Well, not even niche industry in the skater industry. Honeywell, for example.
And all the other big players,
the only way to significantly grow their customer base is to
go buy other skated companies and basically buy their customers.
You know, because stuff like Ska
is on such a long lead time, like five or 10 years for these projects that
you can't just sell it to somebody, right? It's a whole long painful process.
And I assume those systems stay in operation for like
-- decades once they're deployed
-- the life of the plant.
So there's acquire, acquiring clients,
then there's actually maybe acquiring technology patents in IP
there's acquiring brand and goodwill,
right?
There's, and then finally we have the,
they actually bought the company because that company is
a good fit and they're missing that piece,
right? And then,
and I love, we're not going to link to it.
But the economist years ago did an article about like,
where's the synergy where they basically pointed out
that all these deals that like list,
you know,
A plus B equals better than both?
Like never happens.
Yeah, I believe that.
And well,
there's even been instances recently where I
think Facebook just did this where they,
they acquired some companies just to murder
them because they didn't want the competition.
So, yeah, the acquisition to kill it,
uh, is, you know, that's another ugly truth of,
uh, we have a product that's doing quite well.
Uh, this thing might come up and eat our lunch.
Yeah, let's, let's make sure that doesn't happen.
Right.
You, you, you basically terminate it before it becomes a big thing.
And the real sad part there is,
I always wonder like how many cool technologies are missing because
of that or how many technologies got delayed or public transit.
Right.
Car companies bought all the public transit companies, they couldn't kill them
to sell more cars. Exactly.
So,
yeah, in this case,
it looks like the company owns a bunch of software for doing music related stuff,
making musical scores.
They kind of want to flesh out their portfolio and,
and have like a complete portfolio but the way they've done it is uh
awkward.
They, they've really annoyed the community.
Yeah. Well, the community obviously is, is striking back and
I, I
would be shocked
-- if this fork doesn't catch on quickly.
-- I suspect
what will happen is the fork will catch up, catch on and grow, especially with the,
the people that package the stuff and ship it because do
you want to package and ship something from this unknown,
possibly evil entity that has a bunch of weird legales
or do you just want to deal with the open source version?
That's right. Right. That's that's a no brainer. I mean. Right. Exactly.
And the company will
bundle up and sell off a bit,
a package of software that people like and
use who kind of want something that just works
and, and the reality is it's conceivable. This company doesn't even care
because they're like, yeah, whatever we got what we want, go away nerds.
And,
I mean, that's part of what makes, I think
this whole situation so confusing.
It's like no one knows what's actually going on and we're all assuming the worst.
And I mean, maybe it is, maybe it isn't,
I don't really care because we have a solution.
But, you know, it's,
it's mind
boggling.
Well, and I think it's sort of safe to assume the worst because if we have we ever had
a company acquire a project like this, that's new.
You know,
it's one thing when a company like Red Hat or Ubuntu or
Souza acquires an open source company because it's kind of like,
you know,
like they have a track record of decades of behavior in the
open source world and they're just going to keep doing that.
Whereas this company that's only existed for a week.
I, but like I said, I think these, these kind of material changes to the project
need to be taken into account with risk because
what if they decide to do something crazy? Like start
injecting ads into the thing,
did it that happened with was it N PM packages. Remember a couple of years back,
someone
put ads in their N PM packages.
I think we did a show on that where we talked, you know, how do these people make money?
And this is one way to make money.
Uh Now N PM has a thing where they basically
show you which projects would like sponsorship and kind of,
you can go and actually click a link and just
plug in your credit card number and sponsor them.
It's, it's actually pretty slick and I think it's way less offensive and annoying
now, I guess there's a funny other side to this
that
I
don't think anyone's really talking about.
But it is true is, I think even a couple of years ago,
this would have been unthinkable where the concept
of like using open source in this way,
it just didn't exist.
But I think if you want proof that open source is one like this is it.
But what terrifies me is, I think we're at the beginning
of this
journey, I think we're going to see more and more instances of this happening where,
I mean,
if you have an open source project that's controlled by one or a couple of people
and someone shows up with a bag of money and it's like give us your project,
a lot of people are going to take that payout and I,
I honestly would not blame them one bit for doing it.
Well, and what's fascinating to me is there's,
there's a lot of historical projects with a lot of
IP and a lot of knowledge locked up in them,
well, not locked up, but you know what I mean? Embedded in them.
So like Engine X or Apache.
But they, they all kind of have a parent entity like a,
literally a company or a foundation.
And then there's things like audacity which have huge
amounts of engineering knowledge and talent baked into them,
but they don't have that protective mechanism,
right? There's, there's no larger entity.
And now, so you bring up an interesting example, Apache and Engine
X. So like these are good examples, you've got Engine
X which is a company which actually F five just acquired
and you have Apache which is a foundation, right? When you have a foundation,
I don't think you can acquire a foundation.
I mean, I don't know exactly how that all works,
but I have a strong suspicion it's not going to happen.
Well,
there are foundations that spin off their stuff and sell it off to other entities.
So that's a possibility and you can acquire a foundation in the sense of
you can hijack control of it by getting control of the board or whatever.
That's probably true too.
But it's, you know, it's generally kind of a pain.
Whereas audacity is I'm guessing a handful of
people because looking at this contributor list,
it's clear that, you know, if you take out those top two or three people.
Audacity languishes.
Right. Right.
Exactly.
Um, so
-- I guess now,
-- but, ok, so here's my point though, of all this is if you look at,
I would say the vast majority of open source and this is especially
true in like the N PM world where there's lots of smaller things.
These aren't foundations that hold this stuff,
these aren't companies that hold this stuff, these are
people on github,
but they're also, I think there's a fundamental difference.
Audacity is a big honking desktop app for which there is really no easy replacement.
I mean, literally, if somebody says I can't use audacity, what can I use?
And I'd be like, I guess garageband.
Well, you don't know because you don't work with it.
There's a ton of stuff you could use,
but fundamentally audacity is probably the best open
source audio editor on the planet today.
Yes. And it's in your face and you have to learn it.
But whereas an N PM package typically is I'm not going to say, always easy to replace,
but I'm going to say it's probably easy to replace them.
-- Something like audacity.
-- No, not at all. It, I mean, it depends.
Some are,
some aren't like I'll give you a great example is there's a package called low dash.
Low dash is used by I bet 80 plus percent
of N PM packages,
-- low dash is irreplaceable.
-- Well, I don't mean irre
like, I don't mean it's hard to replace in this.
Basically,
what I'm trying to get at is it's really easy to fork an N PM
and have something equivalent that will keep working for you for a long time.
Whereas a desktop app
typically, you know, you can see,
I think there's a bit of a fundamental difference in the way
desktop apps are used and sort of those back end libraries.
I would argue
that it is less work to fork audacity than it would be to fork low dash.
And I'm pretty sure I'm right
because if you needed to replace low dash,
you're talking about like 10 layers of dependencies scattered all over
your N PM
modules.
It would be disastrous.
Well, I guess the fundamental thing though is there's no path to monetizing low dash
now without doing something basically evil. Whereas audacity, it is self evident.
It, you know, ads, it's a desktop app collecting data upselling people stuff.
I can't imagine trying to like, sell somebody something through grip or set or a
right. Well, in like low dash is another example.
I, I, because of what you said, I suspect no one's going to buy it because
like, how would you even monetize that? And other than maybe like for injecting ads?
-- I mean, I don't know, it would be a disaster for sure,
-- but I suspect there's,
this is the one thing that always,
I find interesting is this idea of sort of money filters.
Right. Where you have these sieves that collect money
in the software world, especially,
you know, you have the classic cases like Oracle where it's, or sales force.
Why, why do we use sales force? Because we have to.
Right, because they, they're sales force. Right. Exactly.
Everybody out there who deals with sales force is groaning. But
these companies that are looking for these sort of,
you know, fat
juicy, ripe software applications that they can then acquire probably cheaply.
Like I'm guessing this was not a million dollar deal. Probably not,
you know.
And so I,
I worry that there's going to be more of this because if you only
like for a lot of companies to spend a couple of $100,000 acquiring something,
there are a lot of ways you can very easily make more than that back.
And it might be something as simple as like we acquired
open source project X and our stock price went up and our
-- CEO sold a bunch of shares and made money
-- and look,
I, I
guarantee you this is the beginning.
I
-- mean, if I was gonna, it's
-- like ransomware, we know it works now.
It Right.
Yes, I agree completely.
And I think we are going to see more examples
of weird things like this happening in the open source
world because like open source is one open source is
normalized and there's going to be companies that view this as
an easy button to get ahead.
-- Well,
-- there's a pile of value sitting there that I can acquire for a couple 100 grand.
Duh.
Yeah. Right. Right. I mean, what would it cost to actually write an audio editor for
-- millions? Millions of dollars?
-- Tens,
-- probably a good one. At least.
-- How would you even hire?
So, where would you even find the programmers?
I don't know
if anyone knows where to find programmers. Like, let me know, I'm
looking
you and everybody else.
-- I
-- know, man, it's horrible. Anyway, anyway, we're,
I, I feel like this has been a marvelously wandering conversation but I,
I guess at the end of the day,
the my, my big takeaway from all of this is just that
this is, this is not going to be a singular event. I think this is the beginning
of something we're going. If we don't pay attention to as an open source universe,
I think
it is going to end very badly and a lot of people are going to get burnt.
-- I
-- think the real ugly truth is there's all these
piles of magical value sitting around but
the people working on them have not been able to monetize
or even remotely make back what they've put into it.
You know, I, I always love these people when they're like, I quit doing this project.
And, you know,
and by the way I had, uh you know, a sponsor link and it made me like $87 in like a decade.
Yeah. Yes, that, that's how this works. Nobody will pony up a nickel, let alone $10.
I mean, well, not today. I'm, I'm hopeful that some of these things like github
has sponsors, NP MS sponsors. You got Tide Lift doing work. I'm hopeful it catches on
because I think the work these people do
is virtually invaluable to the world and it is
terrible that there are so many organizations just like
strip mining the crap out of their work.
-- Perfect
-- wording because I was about to say
the real thing I worry about is the externalities of
when they poop all over these projects and destroy them,
like strip mining a mountain and you know,
-- the watershed is contaminated from and I'm going
-- to leave because it's over.
It's not my problem anymore. And it's, yeah, it's, it's terrible.
I don't
it, man, it's so funny because I mean, I just, I remember a couple of decades ago
it was like, oh, I don't know about this open source thing. Is it gonna work?
Is it not gonna work? And now
like, look at what's happening. This is wild.
So anyway, anyway, I'll give you the last word on this one. Take it home.
Don't pollute the environment, be it software environment or the real environment
because
I love it. No, it's, it's, you make like,
II I hate it when these companies make life objectively worse for everybody.
You know, like setting the ocean on fire,
right? Which definitely isn't happening right now.
Uh
Anyway.
All right.
Thank you. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening. Go to social
security podcast.com. Head up the show notes
here, a pound
oss
podcast hashtag hit, hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the.