Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
and my partner in Hating but loving printers. Josh
-- Reser,
-- nobody loves printers. Kurt. Literally nobody.
Well, this is true, but we do love printed material. No,
no, I don't. Ebooks, ebooks all the way.
-- I hate paper.
-- So
I, I tried going paperless
and I have a Kindle and all those things.
And for example, I just took out the New York Times recipe book from the library and a
day after having taken out from the library ordered a copy on Amazon.
Um, it's exactly 1000 pages long
and it's a lovely thick book with tons of recipes in history and it's
a wonderful read and I want to be able to write in it.
And that's fair
and see.
And that's the use case I keep coming back to is so I have had an ipad Pro, an ipad
A
uh I have a Microsoft Surface Pro, beautiful touchscreen and pen, by the way,
like amazing hardware.
I have a remarkable, I
do
-- have a
-- remarkable,
wonderful hardware.
Most God, awful, terrible software.
I found I don't enjoy writing like with a pen on any device ever.
-- It just, it, it doesn't
-- remarkable is about the closest it's the,
the feel the texture is
damn
pretty
paper.
But
I
still
don't like it.
It's,
it's as close as you're going to get to using a good roller ball on 20 pound paper.
That's
right.
You
know,
and I've tried all of these things with the correct software
to read and annotate and make notes on PDF S and,
well, as you can see, there's,
there's a bunch of printed material behind me and some red pens.
-- Can
-- I see printed material
-- and those in the boxes,
-- which way does my finger move?
There we go.
-- Sorry. The whole mirror thing is very confusing.
-- It is, it's lovely because
it's me
and
-- oh, it's me.
-- Everyone can see what you're doing. It's fine.
-- Yeah. So,
-- but that's the thing, right? Like people like
coloring pages,
like you want a coloring page for a little kid to color in it. Just papers
that's a valid use of paper. But from my personal perspective,
I have done everything I can to rid my life of paper.
Now. Now, actually I have a project I'm working on.
I'm doing some cowboy engineering and we'll talk
about it at some point in the future.
Engineering. Yeah.
It's where you just go off and do something on your own without
telling anyone and then you show up one day and you're like,
didn't I do a good job, everyone
I wasn't sure if it was like a cowboy
related.
It's
not a
cowboy. I don't like cowboys either. But that's another story. Anyway.
I actually took out paper
at one point because I was trying to figure out some,
I was wiring some things up and I needed a schematic
and I took out a sheet of paper
and I wrote it down
and it ii, I could have done it on a computer,
but I'm completely confident I cut my time in half by using a sheet of paper
because I could look at it and touch it and poke at it with a pen.
So it has value. But from my perspective, I detest paper
and I do whatever I can to rid myself of it.
I bought a ton of devices. I bought software.
I forced myself to use them and yet here I am.
And now the good news is
there are still,
you know what, this totally reminds me of is the whole,
whenever people start discussing TV.
S
and what is the solution to TV.
S nowadays, the solution is you buy the dumbest TV,
you can and don't plug it into the network.
Yeah.
-- That's right.
-- Right. And,
and if you want like, fancy stuff, you plug an Apple TV into it, which is
the, it's
the least worst
experience.
It's a pretty good experience. I'm happy with my decision to do that.
I have an LG TV.
And it's funny because I bought the LG TV and they had like, the LG operating system,
whatever they web OS or whatever they call it.
And I was like, I'm gonna give this a go
and I made it less than one day.
Well, my favorite thing is I have, I actually,
oh, it's high sense. I bought it from Costco.
The Apple TV. Turns on the TV.
That's normal.
-- Now, that's called CE C and
-- then, so the TV pops up the Roku interface saying,
oh,
I can't see anything input wise. You should try out the Roku experience
and then wait, forces me to wait like five seconds and it's like, oh,
I can see the apple TV.
Let me
go to that.
That's miserable.
And I'm like, so every time I turn on the TV, through the apple TV, I'm just like,
I hate you.
I hate you. I hate you. I hate you. OK? And I, and
like,
I just wish I could disable that and just be like,
just be a dumb TV with an HDM I input and
a audio out to the sound bar. That's all I want.
I'm pretty sure this is a glitch,
you know what I mean? Making air quotes and, but that's how I feel about printers now.
So like with printers, my rules are OK.
It has to support printing from the network,
especially wireless because I want my mobile devices to be able to print to it,
right?
Uh number two. It has to do duplex both sides.
I do like that feature because you waste a lot less paper. Uh
Yeah.
Uh number three and this is an absolute deal breaker.
-- Laser jet or GTFO,
-- I agree with that. I will never buy ink jet.
-- Well,
-- and see what I love about inkjet is there's three use cases for inkjets.
You either print a lot in which case you're paying a horrific per page
cost and you should buy a
laser jet, right?
You print a medium amount, in which case you pay a horrific amount
and you should buy a laser jet.
And then my favorite use case is you print very little.
So the ink cartridges dry up and you have to throw them out and buy new ones
every 12 months. That's
right. Exactly. In which case, you should buy a laser jet
like. And the upfront cost of a laser jet is horrifying, especially for color.
It is, it's terrible. Even buying toner is terrible. It's very expensive.
The toner won't dry out well. Right. I know that,
you know, it's the, it's the Terry Pratchett boot story, right.
Where
if you can buy the expensive boots,
they last for 10 years and the cheap boots only last for one year.
So you have to buy 10 pairs over 10 years
or you buy the expensive boots that also fall apart.
That's how the
pictures work now anyway. Ok. So the, the actual topic
that we've not even touched on yet is the question of, can you own
anything anymore?
And I think printers are a good way to frame
this because it's clear none of us own our printers
and also our TV. S
because the TV is such a horrific experience.
We all hate it and yet we have to deal with
it because I don't have the option to disable this.
I don't have control of my TV.
I, I was, I forget what I was on something, maybe, maybe le me or something.
But anyway,
there is a display type. I think they're called commercial displays.
That's just a T VA dumb TV, basically. But they're, they're like four times the price
they are made to be on for like 24 7,
which I do feel like is a use case my Children have given the TV,
by just never turned it off.
But
so, but this, this actually is the same thing. It's
do I actually
own my printer? Well, my printer, I have to plug into the network.
Although to be fair, I've actually, I
don't think I've actually ever upgraded the firmware on that thing
in the probably half decade I've owned it.
So, could somebody break into it? Well, if they get through my
-- nap device? Sure. Probably.
-- I think my printer auto updated itself.
But I'm certain it hasn't, it's been EOL for like,
literally five or more years at this point.
So,
yeah. Anyway,
but look, it's not just printers, right? You've got like TV. S are a good example.
My phone is one of my favorites.
Like, do I own my, my phone or does Apple technically own my phone?
I think Apple probably owns it.
Well, you legally own your phone but Apple has control of it. That's true. They do.
And I think that's an important distinction. Is this the legal distinction of
ownership versus control. Like and
traditionally, that line has been very clear like I am renting a car.
So or a better example, I am renting an apartment.
So I do not own the apartment.
But legally,
I have rights like you can't just come in as
a landlord with unless it's an emergency or something.
But there's been traditionally very clear lines between ownership and control,
right? Rental cars, apartments, all these things.
But now those lines are completely gone with things like your printer, your phone,
your like I have a dumb washer dryer behind me here.
So I own them
straight up. But there's no questions because there's no networking.
There's no like the the software on that thing is very rudimentary.
You know, it just plays a little tune when it's finished,
which I managed to finally disable.
It was like,
and I'm like, oh my God, I hate this.
But now a modern washer dryer are going to be like, hey,
I need to access the Wi Fi so I can get like software updates and,
and show you how close your laundry is being done to,
you know, on your phone, on the app. That's terrible.
Right. So, you want to know? It's funny when I bought my last washer and dryer,
the brand in all the laundromats is called Speed Queen.
And it's, it's very high end machinery. It's, it's like double the price of normal.
-- It's industrial commercial. But
-- they, yeah, but they last, like, forever.
And there's basically like zero computers in this thing. It's lovely.
This is an interesting example of the difference between commercial grade,
industrial grade versus consumer grade, which is commercial,
industrial grade equipment typically makes money.
Like a laundromat dryer is making money.
My dryer is just drying my clothes,
-- not making me money.
-- Well, it's sitting unused most of the time.
But so the interesting is because the commercial
stuff and industrial stuff is making money.
It has a higher duty cycle obviously
because like if a machine can literally print money for you, then
you want to run it 24 7, right?
Without interruption and without, and so if it breaks,
you want to be able to fix it very quickly and
easily.
And again, that's a major difference between a lot of commercial grade equipment
and consumer grade equipment. Consumer grade equipment is glued together
with like those plastic catches and everything. And
commercial grade equipment. You got a bunch of torque bolts,
torques,
bolts that like pop out in like 30 seconds and the whole thing just blows apart.
Well, and not only that,
so this is an interesting point you bring up and
this kind of comes to what I'm thinking about,
like, can you see
or something you don't own
in the commercial space? And even to, I'm sorry, in the, in the
not commercial, in the, what is the non commercial residential?
Would that be the right word? Consumer? Space,
consumer? Ok. Consumer.
-- Because
-- you're just consuming it and it's a dead end like it just, that's fair.
That's true.
It's very much. I feel like a race to the bottom, right?
Where price is often the driver behind all of this
and you look at commercial and there's return on investment is what's looked at.
Right? So when you're talking about
racing to the bottom,
it's all about how do we make it as cheap
as possible and somehow make money on it later.
-- And this is where like ads and TV s and all that kind of crap comes up. That's where
-- TV.
S make their money.
Like TV. S are a solved problem.
If you build TV, S
and screens and software,
you have 1020 50 competitors
and it's the margins are like 1 to 3%.
So the only way to make any extra money is to like load bloatware on it. Right.
-- Same thing with Android phones.
-- Oh, my goodness, you're right. It's bloatware.
I never even thought of it. Like that. But you're right. It's bloatware.
Yes. What else is it?
I don't know.
It's bloatware that somebody somewhere hopes that some
schmuck is gonna accidentally subscribe and forget to unsubscribe
-- and pay 20 bucks a month. I mean,
-- you're right. That's,
I mean, remember when all the computers, when you buy a computer in, like the 2000
and it would just come with the dumbest stuff on it, like, obnoxious, horrible,
ridiculous things.
That's a TV now. Oh, my goodness.
I ran NT four on my desktop and it was glorious
because it came on a bunch of floppy or a CD
3.51. But I would install NT four and be like,
ok.
Yeah, I remember that.
I, I did the same thing because it, it was, well, it was for businesses. Right.
So it was more expensive. Why did I even have a, I
don't remember how I got a copy. I had a legal copy of NT four. I know that I remember.
I acquired it somewhere but, and I got it really cheap. But anyway, anyway. Ok. Ok.
So that's, oh, man, this is a good point.
Oh, you know what?
I, sorry, I was just digging through my print interface.
It's been updating itself because it's running firmware from, uh,
two months ago.
Oh, that's pretty good. I know.
Mine, mine,
-- mine had auto updates on and I know they haven't been updated in forever
-- and the
thing is I did a ton of research and I bought an HP Laser Jet,
but
I don't need to run software on my devices to print to
because I am not installing that 400 megabyte monstrosity of crap.
I did the same thing because my printer has it,
it literally runs cups in the background
and so I can just connect to the IP P port
and send it PDF S and it just prints stuff.
And so I either I either have the postscript or the PDF driver on all my gear
and it just works
and this is why I will probably never upgrade this printer either.
And I'm sure it's very secure.
And that leads me to the second thing, which is this printer, the toner cartridge,
the chip is really easy to get out and put into a new one.
So the toner cartridge with the chip is like 100 and 50 bucks and without it,
it's like 70 bucks.
And so I, I've got a permanent low toner warning now because it's printed
-- three toner cartridges worth
-- of 7000 pages of toner,
like more like 20. And that's the other thing is, is the consumables, right?
Commercial grade stuff.
They understand that they have to sell the consumables at a
fair price because they're gonna consume a lot of them.
Right. Like, if you, yeah, that's probably true.
As a, as a, as a consumer.
I, I'm, I'm dumb and I can't, I don't do a spreadsheet to compare
all of these things, but businesses absolutely do. That's true.
They know what's up. Right.
A business is not going to be like, well, they might be dumb enough to be like, oh, hey,
this printer is really cheap.
Yeah. Sure.
We'll buy that one and then, you know, they get stiffed on the,
on the consumable cost.
Right. Because, like,
I actually almost bought one of those wax printers. Have you seen those?
I'm, we, I'm familiar with them.
We had one of those when I, one of the companies I worked for,
basically, it would be hideously expensive upfront,
but
it would be a beautiful color printer that would do like commercial grade stuff.
And I would literally buy it once.
Oh, yeah. The images are amazing.
I would buy it once and I might buy some new wax in like 30 years
and that would be it.
I don't know if the wax goes bad. I actually, I don't remember.
So, the funny thing was the company I worked for,
they had like an ink service for the printer where we got a new box of wax,
like once a month.
And so they would, at one point they were like,
we have like 10 boxes of wax in the closet.
Like, if anyone needs to print a lot of something, go for it.
And I remember I was getting married at the time.
I was like, oh, I had some things I could print.
So
I, I took advantage of that.
But man, that was a long time ago anyway. Ok.
So here's the question I would like to ask.
Let's put this in the context of
let's pick on Windows, Microsoft Windows or let's say Mac Os, either one
if you do you own your computer, running Mac Os or Windows.
And I think the question is, do you, so legal ownership? Sure.
But do I want and have control?
And I would also extend this, not just to Mac Os and Windows,
but what about Ubuntu or Debian or Red Hat?
Linux?
How are they any different?
-- They're open source,
-- but they're probably not different.
I, I don't think you're wrong there.
Like I run FG
update and kind of hope for the best. Like, I don't
-- examine what's happening. I just,
-- so it's funny, I upgraded my computer
that I run Fedora on the machine I record on and, and, well, I didn't edit on all, all,
all podcast stuff.
So, you're on 39 now,
-- I guess I don't
-- even know what version it is and I don't care anymore.
I just upgraded constantly. I literally ran DNF dash Y upgrade.
Walked away to get a cup of coffee, came back,
rebooted and then we started recording this podcast.
So, like,
yeah,
a decade ago that would have been a bold move.
But now, like, it just works and yeah, I, I couldn't tell you what's been upgraded.
I have no idea.
No idea.
I didn't even look at the list of stuff
-- like
-- I have to upgrade a couple of V MS from open
to LTs to whatever 23 or something the current one is.
And I'm like, I have no idea what the difference is.
The only thing I care about is I need a newer version of PDF to text.
That's why I'm doing this. Sure, sure. I need some updated stuff like that. And so
I guess the question is, do I have control of these devices?
And the answer is like, no, like, uh
I just noticed on my phone a few weeks ago
that there's a new button in the control panel,
do like locally generated subtitles.
Beta, turn it on or off
on your phone.
Yeah,
that's a new feature in Mac Os.
Yeah. And you wait, I OS, you mean on phone?
-- Yeah,
-- on your Yeah, dude. Right.
But the point is like, I don't even have a clue about all these cool new features.
-- That's how out of control it is.
-- That's true.
That's a good point.
Here we go. And I guess then that, so here's, here's the next question that I have is so
if we obviously, ok, we'll, we'll ignore ownership maybe control.
-- I mean, I'm pretty technical too and I'm
-- like, yeah. Oh, no, no, I get that.
-- But how can we possibly even pretend we're securing any of this stuff?
-- Well,
I think it's a bit like
food safety in that.
I don't necessarily understand why I'm applying all these rules.
Like some, I do like washing my hands. I get why I wash my hands. Right. Right.
And I understand, for example, certain internal food temperatures. Ok.
Like pork to, what is it, 165 or 15 or whatever
-- temps for various foods.
-- It's on the magnet on my fridge
and I've double checked what's interesting.
Internal,
um,
internal meat temperatures are one of the few
things that multiple governments actually agree upon.
If you check the FDA
and the Canada Food Health Agency and Europe and a bunch of others,
-- they all agree. Which I find kind of interesting,
-- interesting.
-- I wonder if they have like good research behind that because
-- science,
because science, because there's certain parasites and bacterium and that's it.
They,
it's one of the few things where it's actually consistent globally.
Let's hope it's because of science because that's not always the case.
-- Like,
-- true.
It might just be like somebody wrote this down and, hey, that's a good number.
Let's use that number.
Then that does happen. Sometimes
I would say though it has to be
reasonably accurate because otherwise you'd hear way
more about outbreaks of terrible disease.
Right.
Well, it's, it's rare enough that they,
like locally right now we have a massive outbreak
of a really nasty strain of E coli that hit apparently a, a series of daycares
had a central food facility.
So they're pretty sure that's what did it,
because it's like 10 different daycares that are part of a chain
and there's like, over 100 kids sick, you know, over 20 in the hospital.
Like, it's a, it's bad and it's rare enough that it, like,
made the news and more importantly, like, we don't have good systems to deal with it.
Like, there's still parents who are like, oh, I,
I hadn't like my kid got sick and I didn't know that this was going on and
in my mind, I'm kind of like,
I feel like they should have phoned everybody,
like,
as a public health agency.
Yes. Like
you shouldn't do this for everything.
But once in a while you, you gotta work the phones and just call everybody.
-- I
-- mean, I don't know how that works. I,
-- I feel like
-- you get a list of people from the daycare and
you call all of them and you say if your kid is sick,
take him to the hospital.
-- No, no.
-- That, that part I get,
I'm trying to think if anything like that's ever. No.
You know what I know that like the school has called me
when there was a head lice outbreak when my
old
head lice,
I love that. They have to call for head lice but not for like an infectious disease.
Right?
There's old laws. No, because there's old laws. It's the same problem here.
I see, there's old laws that say you ha, like you have to call for head lice because
it used to be a really endemic nasty problem and funnily enough.
The shampoos used to work and they don't anymore.
-- Well, yeah, the current strain of head lice. I don't
-- know.
But thank goodness I escaped head lice.
No, the current strain of head lice that's
popular is, it just doesn't care about the, the shampoos anymore.
-- It, it out evolved it, I
-- mean that happens.
Yeah.
Better shampoos now.
Anyway. Ok. Ok. So,
oh man.
So how do we, how do we? Ok. But back to my question, how do we secure something?
-- We
-- don't, there's compensating controls there.
Hold on, hold on first.
I want to clarify that the,
the title of this episode is going to be something about
you can't secure what you don't own or something like that
or do we own anything? I don't know yet. I'll figure that out,
but
I think ownership is no longer the important point
about anything, right? Because I think the definition of ownership is so fuzzy now
that it, it muddles the conversation.
Yeah, we'll let, we'll let Cory doctorow answer this question.
But I think from our perspective it's really about,
can you secure a device
-- you don't control?
-- Yeah.
-- And I would say maybe even active control,
-- whatever I'm not worried about,
but like I don't control my operating system at the end of the day. Right.
I'm getting updates from Fedora. Fedora is driving the bus.
Ok?
So let me give an ex like I think this active versus passive
control might be more important than we think it is because for example,
I have locks on my doors
and I very explicitly have a biometric lock on my front door.
Not because I want to keep people out of my house,
but because I want to make sure I can let people in
and it can get over the air updates that I have to trigger. But
I don't know that that's the case. Like it might phone home once a month,
right? Versus the mechanical lock on the back door that I
control passively and actively,
I just can't go out and decide to do stuff the front door,
I am led to believe through the interface that only
I can trigger it to get a firmware update.
But for all I know it
like my HP printer here that I completely forgot was automatically uploaded,
-- right? Like,
-- yeah,
so no, I I think, I think what you're defining as active and passive,
I would just define as control or not control.
I would say you control the back door, you don't necessarily control the front door.
Well,
it's more that I have to take active measures to ensure
I continue to sort of control or do stuff with the device
because
like my front door lock, I have to check in, I have to update it.
-- I have to, I
-- assume it has a battery. Right.
Has batteries that have to be replaced every once in a while. Yeah.
But what I'm getting at basically is like,
there are certain things I can sort of ignore and certain
things where I have to actively stay up to date.
-- Like my phone. I, this is
-- needlessly pedantic.
Well, but there's like new zero days running around so I have to update my phone
or else I might get popped.
Right. Like there's that whole new pile of zero days in I OS.
And that leads to a second part of it where I have control,
but I have to do certain things in certain ways.
-- Or else I let's
-- rewind this whole conversation
because I think it's gone off the rails.
Here's the way I want you to think about this.
And here's a question I have for you ignoring that whole,
like there's IO a zero days or whatever,
you're running a computer sitting on a network
on that network or other devices that you have.
Absolutely no say over what they are doing,
your computer is running an operating system you've acquired from
somewhere and it's running software you've also acquired from somewhere.
How do we reasonably say we are
securing that computer against adversaries when we basically
have zero control over the software or the hardware that is sitting on a network,
we also have no control over.
So I think that comes to the best practices that we generally have that work,
which are things like doing software updates, reducing exposure where possible.
So for example, having firewalls or network address translation devices so that,
you know, I'm not like my desktop is not
on the internet. It is
that
-- 1 92.68 dot blah, blah, blah.
-- Oh
no.
-- Now we know Kurt's IP address but for
-- example,
like like this Google home device here,
they have actually changed the fundamental operating system.
I remember, didn't they go from Fuchsia
to Android or Android to Fuchsia?
I forget which
I
have no say in that or I,
I don't even know what type of operating system this thing is running.
And so for example, this device here, it just sits there and I hope it updates.
-- That's it. That's all I can do
-- to.
-- Yeah, for sure.
-- My windows machine, I very religiously keep up to date.
And like, actually this morning,
I'm annoyed because I had to log back in
and restart everything because it updated overnight and rebooted.
That's the right way to do it, you know.
And so fundamentally it just, it's kind of like having a house.
There's certain best practices like put locks on your doors
even though somebody can kick them in pretty easily.
You know,
I was just watching some Halligan Bar videos with my son last night
and you know, firemen take,
it's on average a minute seven to a minute and
30 seconds to get through a good dead bolt,
you know, on a commercial steel door.
No,
I was gonna say commercial doors. Right.
Whereas, like, on my door it's like they're, they're not even,
I don't think they're even gonna bother getting the Helian Bar out.
They're just gonna kick it hard.
Yeah, for sure.
You know, and I have like, the cameras and some lights and, you know,
motion sensors and crap.
But right
part of it is like your risk profile.
Like there's a big difference between a bank and me or
uh let's say a hypothetical casino that owns a resort
and, you know,
it has all sorts of things like room access controls
and like ATM S and like feeding thousands of people,
you know, in theory,
they would have a much better level of cybersecurity than myself.
Well, they might, I mean, it turns out they probably don't
for those of you not. It's still, what is it? MGM Grand got like, just completely
gutted,
like
-- everything broke.
-- They even had to turn the slot machines off. I, I read,
yeah, you know, it's bad when they turn off a revenue generating
device
-- and that's the Colonial pipeline.
-- It's amazing to me
the colonial pipelines hack.
They turned off the pipeline because they couldn't effectively bill,
they couldn't track what was being shipped and
produced and sold well and given away basically.
And so they turned off the pipeline. It wasn't a technical
issue. It was with
money
and I imagine is probably similar with the casinos because all the,
all that stuff is network now.
It's all magic.
Oh, yeah.
Wild.
And there again, like,
you don't, you don't own it.
-- Ok. Ok.
-- So,
and that's a perfect example. MGM Casino, you think?
Number one,
they've clearly spent a lot of money on this stuff and even they got totally pantsed,
like, not just like the slot machines got shut down or the door access got shut down,
but like the whole thing got messed up.
Yeah, like people can't even check into the rooms. It's, it's bad.
So, ok,
so,
I mean, that's probably an example of
you've, they've had to
basically outsource trust and I think that's the whole story here
is in the modern society just given the way everything works.
We have to outsource our trust to a degree we've never had to do before.
Right? Because like you put a lock on your door
and yeah, you can buy the expensive lock,
you can buy the cheap lock and there's definitely some things to talk about there.
But fundamentally now, like if you have a computer running an operating system,
you have to say, like, I basically have to trust Microsoft 100%
because I have absolutely no choice.
Well, and so this goes back to that control versus ownership of perfect example,
I'm going to go get my winter tires put on my car in a week or two
because at some point it's going to snow and
my summer tires on snow are comically slippery.
Like we're talking Bambi on ice.
Yeah, because you live in Canada
in the US,
we don't have winter tires because we have all
season radios and they suck in the winter.
I look,
here's, but here's the thing. Right.
Tires are a great example.
Imagine if you put tires on your car
and they were like, now you have to pay us $15 a month to use these tires.
And I think that's what some of this feels like sometimes.
And then you end up like you, you have no, you have, there's no concept of control
and if you don't feel like you're in control,
there's no concept of security either.
Oh, man, this is so messed up.
It's hard to secure something you don't control for sure.
I think it's impossible to secure something you don't control.
I think a lot of, a lot of what we call security
is definitely smoke and mirrors in that regard.
-- It's
-- like a great example is people who talk about putting the best lock on their door
and I'm like, ok, go on youtube and search fireman breach wall.
It's basically a two minute job.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
-- Like that's it, it's a two minute job to get through any wall and,
-- and I mean,
that's part of it.
Right. Right.
The,
the quality of your lock is generally
inconsequential for someone trying to enter your
-- home
-- when the side of your house is three eights plywood with
aluminum or plastic siding.
Well, even, even without that, there's watch a lock picking lawyer, there's,
these locks are all terrible.
Or get a 20 pound sledge hammer at Home Depot. Seriously.
A 20 pound sledge hammer and a couple of good whack.
Yeah. Right. Well, and that's just it,
or get a, get a hali
-- bar because they're pretty
-- sweet. No, don't do that. We're, we're,
that's enabling, that's enabling the bad guys.
Oh, no, we've, we've told them how to break into a house.
Uh The fdny forced entry guide,
I'll put it in the show
-- notes.
-- Ok?
I wanna, I wanna clean this one up and I guess here's, here's the where I'm,
I'm sitting at in my brain right now.
All of this like securing what we don't control ends up coming down to like,
we have to make trust decisions and we have to draw lines. And this is an example of
I'm gonna say I trust Microsoft and I trust Fedora.
And so I'm going to draw a line on the, like, like the,
the chart of things under my control.
Like the hardware is beneath Fedora as well
and everything above this line,
I feel like I can affect, this is things like installing updates,
setting the firewall, right?
Like making sure it's not plugged into the internet.
Those are things I have control over and everything below my line.
I can't pretend I have any sort of control over what's going on there.
Well, and here's a question
why
you trust them.
And the answer is actually really simple.
-- I
-- have to, I don't have a choice because
your incentives align.
Well, and that's true too.
And a perfect example of that is why the Apple
TV is such a better experience than the Amazon firestick.
Because Apple's incentives are to keep me as a consumer in their lifestyle cult
and keep paying them a couple like 1 to $2000 a year in
to buy new hardware.
And I'm happy and they're happy versus the Amazon.
And Amazon is a, their DNA culture is uh being a marketplace.
-- They're, they're basically a market maker, buy a
-- bunch of crap you don't need.
And so their culture is to,
is to flog my
attention to advertisers.
And so I remember when the fire stick, I,
I literally ran an update and then the content
that it shows me actually went from like this to
and it got squished like a 29.
And, and that was literally a day where I was like,
I literally went online and bought two Apple TV. S
-- and I was like, I'm done here.
-- I, I didn't do that.
I literally, when they, when my fire TV S updated,
I drove to Costco that day and bought two Apple TV.
-- S
-- Exactly.
And we're privileged and we can do this,
you know,
not everybody can just go for a couple of
100 bucks because they're annoyed by the advertising.
Ok. Ok. Now I wanna, I wanna bring this one home. No.
So, printers back to printers, we're gonna go back to printers as the end.
When you have a printer.
Do you know what's above the line on your printer?
Nothing. Exactly.
Basically. Nothing.
And I think that's one of the challenges and that's what,
-- yeah,
-- because it has to be plugged into the print network.
It, it, and, and it's, yeah, you basically have no control.
You can think you do but you really don't.
-- And I think there are devices
-- build a print server,
plugged into the print server and have like a
Linux print server running to media access and stuff.
-- But nobody does that.
-- That's a different use case, I think. No, well, not anymore.
You could with the Raspberry Pi or whatever.
I
think the point is
that when we talk about can you secure things you don't own?
It's not really that it's really about that like line of control.
And in the case of certain things like a printer or a fire TV stick or whatever,
like there's nothing above the line,
there's nothing you can secure, there's nothing you can do.
And so you basically have to just say either I trust completely
the manufacture of this device.
In which case everything's fine
or I don't trust them at all. In which case, you probably shouldn't be using it.
I think that's right. But there's a subtle twist to it, which is
you can reasonably secure up to the line that they provide you.
And this is goes to something I've been calling shared capabilities.
So we have an idea of shared responsibilities and cloud security
and I've been thinking that we need to expand
that to be shared capabilities because for example,
Amazon, like, I, I can't monitor the network.
It's their network unless they give me that capability,
which they do with certain VPC products.
So I think it's even more. So is
the,
the provider has a line and you can sort of
conventionally secure up to that line using their stuff,
their updates, their config
options, whatever. But anything above that line
now means you need to go do some weird compensating control which
may or may not be possible.
Like for a printer, for example, I can't not plug my printer to the network because
how am I going to print to it? It has to be plugged into the network.
Like that's not an option.
And,
and I think that's one of the fundamental problems for almost everything nowadays
is that
it's basically useless unless it's plugged into a network. For sure.
Yeah. Oh, my goodness. Yes.
And I think that's part of the problem is for things to be useful in the modern world.
They have to be connected to the network. That's true.
That's true. All right, I'm gonna,
I've got one thing I want to say before we close this one out.
So there is, I'll put a link in the show notes.
There is a,
a government request for information in the United States from the White House.
They're asking for best practices for securing open source.
It's actually the,
the title is technically request for information on
open source security areas of long term focus.
And I want to call this out because anyone listening, like go go submit
uh
RF I response, I don't know what they're called.
It probably is some fancy name in the government. RF I response.
But anyway, I was reminded that we should, we should plug this
because I was in a meeting with uh Alan Friedman who's like the, the,
the godfather of SBA
and, and I know he listened to the show every now and then.
And so Alan was like, you should, you should tell people to do this.
And I was like, you know what? We should, it's a good idea.
So anyway, that's how I'm ending it. All right. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you for listening. Go to start security podcast.com.
Hit up the show note, Susy Pound do says podcast. Hashtag
on Mastodon.
-- Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day. You
-- too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone.
Bye bye.