Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in arguing Josh Bresser.
We do argue a lot. Most people don't have a view behind the curtain.
But Kurt and I argue about literally everything
and we really mean to each other sometimes.
But in the classic sense,
I guess from the, we'll say the learned man sense, I'd call it where.
Well, it's respectful. We do. We're friends at the end of the day.
We never end our arguments with like I hate you,
which is good
even though I make fun of you sometimes for being an A I fan boy.
Yeah, I am.
But I think part of it too is even when we disagree,
I still in the back of the mind have the and it's not even that you might be right.
It's also that I might be wrong. And those are two
things
-- because quite often we're both wrong.
-- Oh, absolutely.
And I,
I'm also happy to change my mind
when you provide me with compelling evidence.
I am happy to change my position and I've done that
many times
anyways. So what does mail channels allowing spoofing of email domains by default.
Uh Google marking, a web page is serving malware
and has
a
corps license change. All have in common. I mean,
but you said you, you wrote it down and I've already forgotten it.
-- Um
-- I told
-- you
-- what the answer was it,
is it responsibility? Was it? Yeah.
Some version of responsibility or accountability. OK.
I want to set some context before we keep going.
So it's Sunday at approximately 1 p.m. For me,
I woke up like two hours ago
and it was the, the Sunday after a B sides and, and black hat and Defcon.
I flew home on Friday night.
And so I basically had Saturday to rest,
but I'm still like insanely tired and I slept for like 12 hours last night.
I'm totally old. I'm not even gonna pretend that's not the case,
but I do want, I do want to call out Bides because this year, all I did was B sides.
I didn't go to black hat. I didn't go to Defcon. I decided they're too busy
and it was super chill. Besides, besides Las Vegas is very chill.
I really like the hotel they do it at and I
stuck around on Thursday to just hang out and go,
you know, have lunch and drinks with friends and stuff and it was marvelous, but
I need to call up B sides for their
amazing attention to detail.
So I gave a talk this year called next generation Enterprise Security.
And it's where I watched All Star Trek
next generation and talk about their terrible security.
Now, I've done this before and I know we've talked about it,
but B sides has a box when you submit a talk that says,
please submit your most ridiculous speaker request you can think of.
And I asked for a person dressed in a Starfleet uniform in the front row to heckle me. I
think it's amazing.
And I walk into the talk and there's no one
in the front row dressed in a Starfleet uniform.
And I'm like, oh man, they didn't do it.
So I start talking
and like maybe three or four minutes into the talk.
A dude barges through the door with a Star fet uniform on, carrying a trombone.
And I was like, this is gonna be so good and it was, it's,
I'll put a link in the show notes.
It's, it's, it's on youtube, but it's like the, the guy was amazing.
-- It was so much fun.
-- Did, did
-- he ever
-- do the Picard Tuck while he was in there?
-- No, no,
-- they
pull
-- out the uniform because they kept writing up,
-- right? He did not do that.
I don't, he sat in a chair much of the time in the front
and heckled, but he was very good.
-- It was good. Heckling
-- is hard.
Like,
that's my favorite thing about a stand up comedian is when
a stand up comedian gets heckled and heckling is bad.
Like, my favorite one,
there was just a recent one where somebody said you're not funny.
And the stand up comedians, like, oh, what now? Like, ok, let's, let's go with that.
Like, ok, you're German, you're not funny.
You made fun of the German person, blah, blah, blah.
And he's like, ok, let's try again. Like, something, tell me what's wrong.
And the German guy went, you're not funny. And the Canadian comedians, like,
like, you're not even trying. Yeah. Right.
So, but, but then you see good heckling and it's like,
-- that's funny. It is.
-- It is. And
generally speaking don't heckle comedians because they're like professional
-- things on the spot and you're not,
-- and they're sober and you're probably not
sober.
That is a good point actually. Yes, that's,
I remember I was at a comedy club once and some
drunk guys from Red Deer started heckling the comedian and he,
uh,
-- yeah, he was not nice.
-- They, they take, they take you down. It's amazing. I know.
-- But they were so drunk, they didn't even realize.
-- Well, that could be too.
And that's sad. But anyway. Ok. Ok.
So, uh, Bide.
So
super fun. Well done
Bides. It's, it's an amazing show. All right, back to your topic.
Sorry, I had to interrupt that way when people understand why I'm not.
-- Well, ok, so
-- basically
mail channels is a mail delivery provider. You
have a web api
api, you give it some data and
an email goes out, it's free. Mostly. Um there's also you can buy services.
And so by default,
most people that want to send mail just want to send
mail and they don't want to do so like hyper securely.
And it's funny because I actually mail channels did a thing with cloud flare
and where you can use them very easily from your cloud flare workers.
And I had a cloud flare worker for the web finger dot io thing where I should
send email.
And honestly I tried uh mail gun and Sendgrid which we
have accounts with and pay for
and like, oh man, there are web API S and stuff for a bit.
Anyway, the
point is it did not work well from cloud Flair's worker.
I tried mail channel the demo example
and it just worked immediately and I'm like, oh, ok.
And then I immediately had the thought of wait a minute.
There's no authentication. There's just like I'm sending email as
clouds
carolines.org. Oh, I can't have them.
I like I can't add them to our SPF record center protective framework
because then anybody can use male channels to spoof a cloud crew line.
And then I checked, oh, they support DKIM uh domain. He's identified male. I know
it
-- before
-- encrypted mail
signed email, not encrypted mail. Sorry.
And so I'm like, ok, cool.
I look at their tutorial. It's terrible. It's disjointed. So
I set it up. I document it because I'm gonna have to rotate my de
keys or set it up again in the future.
And I actually emailed the mail channels people and
they actually replied and actually added it to their official
augmentation and put a link to ours saying thank you for this
because,
well, yeah, I mean,
I had it like from literally just cut and paste.
Here's the open SSL commands, here's the, this the, this the, this done
because future me is gonna have to fix this and it's gonna be tired and just
have to figure it out.
And so
now somebody figured out, wait a minute,
mail channels has become quite successful and
there's like 2 million domains using it,
then they can all be spoofed because none of them bothered setting up DC.
Yeah.
The second one is that
somebody complained on hack
news that Google marked their website as hosting
malware and it turns out they actually had
a
zip file on it that contained malware that
they were intentionally distributing for like testing or whatever
and like, yeah, and hacker news is kind of like, yeah.
So you're saying you distributed malware and Google discovered it and I mean,
your site is malware and now there's not a real good process to get rid of that because
weirdly people who actually are malicious
and distribute malware often claim like,
oops,
yeah. Should you please
unlist us? Like we're,
-- we're good now
-- we promise we won't do it again
-- and
-- then again,
so Hashy Corp just came up with a license change for, um, uh, what was it called? The
Hashy
Corp Business License.
And I think it's like all their stuff basically is it?
I haven't looked at exactly what it is,
but Vault and Terraform are the two big ones that they
-- have.
-- That's all their stuff. Like
that's fair. I know they have other things but
-- that's basically all their stuff.
-- Those two things are what matters
for sure. For sure.
Yeah.
And so
I'm looking at this and it's all sort of this,
people seem to have this expectation of
responsibility or quasi
ethical or moral behavior, but
like the world has changed. So a perfect example is email, email used to like
you and I were running email servers before SPF even existed.
There was like no security on anything
-- you
-- would get Joe jobbed. Somebody would spoof your address in
-- return for spam and you'd get like hammered,
-- you could tell that
-- to almost any email server and just send like crap email. I am
-- Bob.
I
don't remember how to do it, but I, I remember doing that a lot.
It's ok. You tell it blah, blah port 25
and then you hello or you?
That's
-- right.
-- And then it's, it's mail from
and receipt two, right?
-- Receipt
-- two
and then,
and then enter your data including subject focal
and blah, blah, blah and then hit
twice blank line or no sorry dot Enter
to. Um,
and then, like, accept it for delivery or not, then you're done.
I mean,
the,
the reality is a company like mail channels or any mail delivery company forcing,
I'm doing a thing with my hands here that Josh can see
the scales forcing people to set it up securely or getting a lot of customers.
I mean, look, that is the perpetual argument in the business world.
There are times where security goes against the features
-- that business
-- needs ease of use and set up.
Sure. And, and security always loses because the reality is
if you don't have customers, you don't have a business.
So security is irrelevant in that context.
Yeah, I mean, we're at a point now where I've,
I've interacted with companies that don't even validate my email address
and I actually logged into an old Aws test account and
it's like you haven't validated your email and I'm like,
how did this account even get set up?
And like
it's been billed and like it's paid for stuff and like we used it for testing.
-- How did that even happen?
-- So this reminds me of a conversation I actually had
while in Las Vegas. I don't remember with who.
So I apologize if, if whoever I, I talked about this with is listening, like,
-- let me know and I'll give you
-- a shut up, just claim we're being GDPR compliant.
Right. Right. There you go. That's Right.
They, they made a comment like something has to change.
And I said, I don't know if it does because this is the security, the market demands,
right? If you look at the world, the world functions
yet we as security people are talking about how everything's on fire and terror.
Right? Like
-- is it,
-- it's coming, I mean,
-- it just, it'll probably just after the Linux desktop. Right.
-- Yes, that's fair.
That's fair. But it's at the same time, like society functions.
This is the amount of security, the market demands
and like,
I wish it was better but
-- it obviously isn't that bad.
-- Yeah. Like, and I think part of it is
there's not just sort of what is responsible
but what is sort of necessary and needed.
Like
the reality is we've had email spoofing since email began.
That's it. That's, that's, that's the extent of my argument.
Like I would say it was mostly harmless jokes in the past where, like,
you send your friends an email from God or something.
Well,
and then it's started to kind of escalate
because especially for spam delivery or fishing,
like, obviously for fishing, if I can spoof you know,
your CEO S name at your company.com,
that's going to look a lot more believable than like
we get stuff from like, blah, blah. Oh, what was the last one we got was um,
some vet clinic or something got popped and so was
sending out email pretending to be Zendesk or something or
uh
oh
Sendgrid. So we are getting,
somebody is going through all the DNS records on
the planet looking for SPF records for Sendgrid,
I think
and sending fake like your Sendgrid account has been suspended.
Click here, blah, blah.
And of course you click there and it's like some totally nasty fishing site, but
I only get them for sen
grid, not for male gun or the other ones because it's kind of weird.
And so I'm kind of wondering if maybe the average SD
user is not as savvy
that could be because
it's really easy to tell
who uses what email systems because YSPF records
like
otherwise your email doesn't get through or
in the case of Google it gets through,
but it gets that horrific nasty yellow warning banner saying this might not be blah,
blah,
blah.
So anyways like, yeah, I mean,
I wish mail channels require dkim set up for every customer.
Then there would be like way less spoofing, but
obviously
the people using it are not being affected enough
to go set up deacon because well, they're, they're not going and setting up Dean,
like, like you said, the market is spoken
and
I,
I wish people wouldn't smoke cigarettes. But that's the thing.
I mean, the market speaks on many things. That's,
and that's the challenge too is it becomes a boil of the ocean problem.
Like I pointed out like there's a guide on how to click, click, click, do this thing.
And you know, somebody pointed out that that's not easy
because it's a scale issue of like 2 million domains have to do this.
And that's the second part I wanted to think about here is
like,
oh perfect example.
All everybody's losing their minds because all the A I bots are scraping the web to,
we scrape the web and have training data
and they're all like, oh, but we, you know, we support robots dot TX.
And if you put in like, don't crawl, blah, blah, blah, we'll respect that.
But it's like
asking everybody to opt in to secure their data.
They're not like half the people don't even know it exists.
So that's funny you say this because I got in,
I was in a discussion
at one point where there is a, a lawyer doing privacy leg
like legislation fundamentally and some other people and these people are talking
about all of the interesting technologies you can secure your data with.
And finally, I just said, I'm like, look, I looked at the lawyer, I said,
tell me if you think I'm wrong,
technology doesn't matter. We have to solve this through legislation.
And he was like, you are absolutely correct
because the problem is even with technology,
anytime there's a problem and the data leaks out
like the horses left the barn is over.
Versus if you have legislation that protects your data.
Cambridge
analytics,
people will try to do bad things with it.
But at least there's legal ramifications then.
Whereas today there's nothing, once your data is out, it's out and that's the end
or you get that like, $2 settlement with, uh,
or
whatever.
Yes.
You know what my favorite was, was there was some point,
like in the nineties or early two thousands where there
was like a settlement with one of the music companies
and I got like, I think a 70 cent
credit to buy
-- music.
-- That's my
favorite thing. It's like you get 70 cents off your next purchase. It's like
this is ridiculous.
Like why even send this to me? This was the postage was half of the cost of this.
Did. Well,
oh, here we go.
If you are a class member, the deadline to file initial claims,
perry claims for free or free for free credit monitoring or up to 100
and $25 cash payment and other cash reimbursement passed on January 22nd 2020.
So
Equifax data breach is long done. I
don't
sign
up
for that. I feel like I don't think I did
to get
making people sign up to get it. Like at most a few percent will, like
in North America, we can't even get half of people to vote in a federal election
for sure.
For
sure. Is the heck not going to get them to set up deacon records on their email?
Do
exactly.
And,
and on the flip side, somebody was pointing out that this,
they said emails becoming the walled garden. And
I sort of agree and disagree in that in that some of the, well,
Twitter only Google and Microsoft outlook are
Google gmail is 30% or something.
And I don't know what outlook is, but on the corporate side, it's massive.
And for example, if Google says, like do SPF or we don't,
we don't accept your email, then
people would deploy SPF D
D.
But there's an incentive at that point,
it's like when they switched over to the HTTP S or else
for web searches, it,
it
improves your search engine rankings and everybody's like I would like to.
-- But
-- again, that's, that's a market incentive that's effective versus art today,
-- we have no market incentives.
-- Well, but what's interesting though,
we go from a boiling the ocean and trying to
get 2 million people to agree to one company being
potentially able to make a decision. But
I mean,
it incentivizes those 2 million people sufficiently to actually go do something.
-- Now,
-- at the same time,
I think you could create an antitrust argument about the power.
This company has to do such things because I mean,
Google could also say if you don't put a uh
like a dancing bear at the top of your website,
we won't index it.
Everyone would have a, I think they're at the top of their website and
that's kind of scary, you know.
Well, I mean, like,
people forget this is kind of how barcodes happened
is Walmart and the Department of Defense said like,
no barcode, no buy.
And everybody's like, ok, barcodes are awesome.
And so I like,
I guess what I'm saying is,
I don't think the answer to this sort of market
speaks thing is to have a company like Google,
hopefully do the right thing and ask for more security.
I think
as much as I
am nervous by
specific technical legislation,
I think that
maybe is the better way to go,
but
-- it's so far behind that. Does it even matter?
-- Well, and that's one of the questions.
I mean
that this, but this,
I don't want to get into that today. I want you to tell me how has
a
Corp fits into this still which we haven't gotten to yet has
Corp is
just the latest example. But a lot of other companies have done this where
well, like Facebook with their Lama open source license, that
is open source
unless you have more than 700 million users,
which would be a problem I would like to have.
But so is there these companies want to make money because
that's kind of the whole point of companies in general
and
they have a thing. That was true. I let's go with true O SI,
what was the phrase O SI approved open
source? That's right.
An O SI approved license is what we currently think
-- of as open source
-- and they go to something that is
not just
like a minor tweak or change, but is it goes against the spirit,
many would say of what open source is meant to be on the flip side though, like
Hashi
Corp is getting essentially
clear cut by people using their stuff and not contributing back even a bug report.
Right? And we've seen this happen with a lot of products like
-- Nessus, you know, like, I
-- mean, that's open source. That's how it works.
So I can't help but wonder is like,
should there be an expectation if you're a company doing open
source that somebody can come in and eat your lunch and?
-- Well, there's no recourse.
-- Yes, that, that's absolutely an expectation.
And what I was going to say, argument wise is whether or not you like it,
that's the reality.
It's like, should I look both ways when I cross the street?
Well, I have the right of way as a pedestrian in a marked crosswalk,
but I'm still going to look both ways
-- because the world we live in, I might get run over.
-- Right. Right. Ok.
I want,
I want to start at the beginning and this is related to that
email we got that I said I didn't read but I did skim
and I, and I like an episode or two ago,
I made a comment like if it's not on the O SI S list.
It's not open source and it turns out it's technically
open source approved is what the O SI calls it.
-- It's, it's kind of complicated.
-- They, there's trademarks and stuff going on.
They
fundamentally the definition of open source is squishy.
But so far the O SI has managed to, I think, hold the line
on we own like we control this term. Go away.
-- Everyone else I would
-- say more convincingly.
their list is in the spirit of open source
and that they accept.
So here's the thing
I would start with Red Hat
like Red hat,
Red hat Enterprise Linux
is technically
covered by open source licenses,
but it is definitely not within the spirit of open
source because if you distribute the source RP MS,
they,
they remove your license to access Red hit Enterprise Linux.
So you could definitely say like that is open source but not in the spirit.
And then you look at things like Mango or elastic or Hashy Corp or whatever
where they basically
-- they like to claim open source. But it is not technically in the open
-- source
or the open core. This part's open
source,
-- but like,
-- well, open core is different.
Open core is open source because you have actual open source components,
-- but
-- it's useless with all, all the other stuff.
-- Uh
-- Some of it is and that's a different problem. Yes.
But then what I think these like Hashy
Corp is doing uh I best heard it described as business source
where it's basically, if you're a person, you can use this.
But if you're a company and you're creating a competing product,
-- you can't. Well, that's
-- the llama thing. 700 million.
I'm assuming that's the number for like 10 cent Baidu, Google
-- Microsoft,
-- probably. Right.
And that's almost certainly their target for that particular,
the number of companies with more than 700 million users is I'm hoping last thing
I want to
pick this up where you made a comment about, you know, companies make money.
And is it ok if someone takes their open
source and like eats their lunch with it basically.
And
I think the danger we see happening here is the,
if you look at almost every start up on the planet today,
they brag about having open source because open source is a good marketing tool.
Like I'll give you an example
if I work for Anor
Anchor has two tools called sift and gripe that get used a lot.
We don't have AC L A contributor license agreement.
I'll explain what that means in a little bit.
I would not have gone to Anchor if they did because
I just come off the heels of elastic pulling the shenanigans.
But anyway,
they had right, they had one too.
so like
we have these tools that are open source and they're open projects,
we accept lots of patches from people.
And if now, if I go to a conference and I say I wanna talk about Anchor Enterprise,
the product my company creates, that's close source.
Like
no,
that's not getting in under any circuit. We don't do vendor pitches. Yeah, exactly.
But I can show up and say, oh, hey,
I'm gonna talk about gripe this open source tool that does vulnerability scans
and that gets accepted a lot, right? Because it's an open source tool and it's cool.
And so most start ups treat open source
as their marketing department because you can say
I have this thing that's open source. Let me come talk about
-- it at whatever venue you have
-- even more simply, it allows me to get a taste test and go,
oh, this actually does kind of do what I want
and to a degree
and more importantly, 99 times out of 100 as a company or a corporation or a,
if I'm using this for work stuff, my response is, oh, and you'll like,
sell it to me with all this other stuff that makes it really easy to use.
And I
like,
like I have a vendor right now where I'm paying 99 we upgraded from
$49 a month to $99 a month for something I could totally build.
But it would take me like 100 hours to build and run
-- and then
-- you have to run it and running things is expensive
and, and or we can pay 12 hun
like 1200 bucks a year.
It's no
brainer.
But now here's what happens, right?
So like
in the context of
Acor, we have sift and Gripe and they are like the foundation of our enterprise tool.
OK.
So anyone could take sift and gripe and build a tool on top.
In fact, there are many companies have, we know of many comp competitors to
Acor that have literally taken sift and gripe
and built competing products on top of it.
And that's how open source works like those are, that's the deal.
That's it. We deal with it too bad.
Like we hope what they contribute back,
-- but they don't have to. Well, and
-- I think the big thing is though,
ideas are easy, execution is hard
and sustained execution of like an open source
project.
-- It's tough for sure.
-- Absolutely.
-- That's super
-- hard
for sure, for sure.
And if a company can do that and actually keep
that piece of open source alive and going well.
Yeah, then like, I'll look at the vendors and a lot or the,
the sort of the secondary market,
let's call it where they kind of take the open
source from the original company and repackage or rebrand it.
-- And in my experience, most of them don't do a great job.
-- No, of course.
And that, that's my excuse. Always, as I tell people, look, if, if a competitive,
taking one of our things and they're doing a better job than us. We suck. Like that's,
that's how, that's like my other argument is sometimes people would be like, oh,
but if this feature goes into open source
and then people won't pay us for enterprise,
I'm like, look, if, if an open
source project can damage your enterprise product, like you suck.
That's the lesson here
keeps moving forward.
Exactly. Well, they all do anyway. Ok. Ok. So here's the important part of this.
I think
so. Hashy
Corp,
they had this open source and I think we can easily agree. This is true of Mango DB.
This is true of elastic search
without an open source product.
These things would not have gained the popularity. They had,
-- they would have never launched for sure. They'd have like six users.
-- Absolutely.
So the open source was very much
a, an important component of their success.
And now what they had is they had something called a contributor license agreement.
What happens when you have AC L A
is you are signing over your copyright rights
to the company or organization because like
the free software foundation has clas also.
But their, their purpose isn't to relic
it as a business someday. Well, yet.
But they could though,
that's the
thing we never know.
This is what I love is, people are like, oh, but they would never do that.
I'm like, cool, put that in writing in the contract and they're like, oh, but,
-- yeah.
-- Exactly. Exactly.
And and they claim it so they can switch to other licenses and whatever,
like a proprietary business
just saying.
-- Right.
-- Well, and so that's the thing.
See, that's what gets me is, for example, do they ever say,
do they ever put in that thing?
I guess you could put this in ac a, uh, contributor license agreement where
we will only go for example,
-- to O SI approved licenses and then you'd also have to subvert the O SI
-- I believe the um
I, I think Liber Office has such a clause,
I think don't quote me on that, but II,
I know they exist and I think Liber Office has one.
But anyway,
so you got the CL A right?
If you want to contribute source code to a project like
Hashy Corp in the past or Elastic Search or Mango DB,
you had to sign a contributor license agreement
that said I'm giving you all my rights
and a lot of people did it.
And most of these companies said, oh,
we will never change our license under any circumstances, you know,
super double cross pinky swear. And then eventually
they did.
And because of that cl a,
there's nothing anyone could do about it
because what happens if well, they can fork it,
well, you can fork it and that will happen.
And that happened with elastic search because like uh open search was forked off.
Elastic search.
Nessus was forked. I'm, I'm, I know hashy corp will be forked.
I don't know if the fork will live.
Well, of course, well, anyone can fork it, but I don't,
is it going to survive as a question?
Like, talk to me in a year?
Yeah.
More than
commits.
Right. Exactly. And that's, that's always the thing.
People are always like, oh, we'll just fork it.
It's like forking things is really hard.
Yeah.
Like when that whole rel thing came out and people were like, oh, we'll just like,
do it ourselves.
And it's like, oh
right.
That's like saying, oh, just walk the Cascadia trail with a 400 pound backpack.
It's fine. It's very easy. Everyone.
Yeah, I know. I know.
So anyway, now here's where, here's where not having AC L A is important, right?
So today there is a, a blog post by uh Pamela Chaste
I will try to find and
it basically talks about how we don't actually know
who owns open source license code if there's multiple contributors
because the way traditional copyright law works, like, for example,
let's say you draw a picture of a cat
and then you give me the picture of the cat and say, Josh,
you have my permission to change my picture of a cat
and then I draw a tree in the background
who owns the copyright to that picture.
Uh If memory serves, if you do enough transformative work to the thing,
then you own that copy.
It doesn't even have to be transformative if you give me permission and I do it.
Yeah, I forgot the permission thing.
Well, yeah, obviously I can license you the copyright. Yeah.
-- And then you have, yeah,
-- the last person to touch it has copyright over that work then
and open source is different though because you have multiple contributors.
So if I contribute a one line patch,
do I now does the last person have the copyright over the code?
And no one's ever answered this legally?
So, but the intention is with, if you don't have a contributor license agreement,
everyone involved in the project would have to agree to change their license.
And obviously, if you're trying to go from Apache two to business source,
that is not going to happen, right?
-- 100%.
-- I mean, in theory, you
could,
but you'd have to also probably gut a whole bunch of code for people that don't.
But even that's not obvious, like
because
we don't know the copyright ownership is just,
is going back in time and removing some code.
But, but what, well, I should say is removing code in the current iteration
that was added in the past. Does that count as removing their contribution?
Like it doesn't, this is not obvious at all. This is very murky
and traditionally in the open source world, we've ignored it because we could
because no one's ever said like, oh, hey,
I'm the last contributor to this project and I own it now.
And if someone did it would be a heck of a court case to say the least.
Well, it sort of has happened but it's never been.
Most of these people don't have the money to properly fund
a court fight for it or it just doesn't really matter.
Like somebody claims ownership of something. It's kind of like, ok,
cool. Who cares? Like life goes on
because,
and this is something that's been coming up a lot
because obviously I'm doing a lot of stuff with a IA
I generated content cannot hold a copyright unless the
human does a whole bunch of transformation to it.
We have no idea what level that is. 1% 10% 99%. Who knows? Right.
But one thing I've been coming across is
why do I care about copyright?
And the best answer I have is I care about
copyright because traditionally we use copyright to control the thing,
especially if somebody
abuses the thing.
Like if they post it to their website,
I can use copyright to issue ad MC a takedown notice for example.
But,
but, but
there are cases where I don't care that much like
well to put it simply the the Cloud Security Alliance,
we we want you to read our papers.
So like if you want to take our papers and distribute them,
we're not super happy about that.
But at the same time, like we're kind of giving them away for free to begin with.
So it's not that big a deal like we're not charging, you know, 50 bucks.
It's not like an iso standard where they watermark each one with
your email address because they cost some godly amount of money,
you know,
uh we're, you know, we're just handing these things out.
And so I was thinking about this and I was kind
of asking people this kind of awkward question of like,
well, why do we care about copyright?
Assuming it's not like a music CD where we're trying to sell the darn thing, you know,
and prevent piracy.
I mean, fundamentally, if you don't care about piracy, why would you really,
that's the open source way, right?
Is generally speaking as long, like,
so GP L is a little different because GP L you have to,
you have to release the source code, but with like Apache two,
-- no one really cares what happens.
-- And, and so that's the flip side of it is
again, they're sort of using copyright to enforce something they want.
And in this case, it's sort of the,
I don't want to say it's the opposite of control because it is still controlled,
but it's controlled to contribute
and gain access to those contributions
as opposed to locking it up.
But again,
well, for example, all the service companies just
ingest open source and like, maybe never give anything back
to the point where companies change their licenses. So that they can't do that,
right.
But fundamentally, I've been thinking about this, like,
do I really care all that much about copyright?
Like if we have an A I uh
support bot
generate a answer to how do I reset my password ticket?
-- Yeah, we don't care about the copyright on that answer.
-- Ok.
Look, there's two sides to this argument. OK.
There's the data going in
and today there are multiple court cases where you have creators
who are upset that their content was used without permission in an A I system.
And I totally relate to this.
I don't,
I go back and forth whether it should or shouldn't be legal, but it's not up to me.
-- So it doesn't matter.
-- It's also kind of, it's a done deal.
-- No,
-- it's, it's not, it's not at all. Don't talk like that.
The reality is until this goes through the courts. It's not a done deal.
Court and law is the functioning foundation of society.
You can't say it's a done deal. It's a, it looks like it's a done deal.
But if the courts tell an A I company,
you have to remove all of the art from this particular artist from your model,
they're completely screwed
and that's, they know it.
-- We
-- thought GDPR might make a difference,
but a lot of these tech companies engineered around it.
-- GDPR
-- has made a difference. Kurt GDPR has made a huge difference.
I'm pretty sure Facebook still has all our data and is selling it.
-- Facebook has
-- our data but there's definitely more
power you can exert over not Facebook.
We'll say Facebook is special because they're extra sleazy and extra huge.
But the challenges some of these large A I companies are
-- well like Google saying basically extra
-- sleazy and extra huge.
Google is like, you know, if it's on the public web,
-- we're feeding it into an A I
-- because today they can,
but if copyright says you can't do that,
they will change because they have to because
they're going to get sued by literally everyone.
It's not a done deal, but now
-- they're going to fight it to the death because they have to, I get
-- that
and they, and the thing to remember too is they don't have to win,
they just have to stop
and they will, they'll try.
But now on the other side as well, you have the issue of copyright on the output
of this stuff.
You and I don't care a lot about copyright because it doesn't pay our bills.
But if I was an author
and I was creating copyrighted works that I was then selling as my job.
You know how I was living,
I would care a lot.
The online romance book novel industry has already
been just stomped by A I generated stuff.
I
am not surprised at all.
I mean, I
-- think
-- that's
-- already formulaic,
-- right? I've heard a lot of the children's books are coming
under the same sort of attack with a lot of low quality,
like generating a board book with like
50 or 60 lines of text in total. And some images is
that's a really easy thing to set up and,
well, no,
no, no,
I, I think it's easy to turn out.
But I think making a good story because, like, when I was,
when I had young Children
there were a handful of books that were
clearly just heads and tails above the others.
Yeah. And those stories do very well.
The others my guess is they probably don't make any
money because you look at them and you're like,
this is obviously crap and maybe someone will buy it and give it to your kid
in a
-- present and then you throw it out.
-- Fun fact there was, um was it
who's the guy, uh is it Neil Gaiman? Who's the guy that wrote The Fool?
Uh Not The Fool series, the one
they're based in San Francisco kind of magical
devils and stuff. Anyways,
somebody set their name as the author's name
and released a new book with a similar title
by similar title.
I mean, I think it was the same title of an upcoming book of the author and I
was like, oh, it released finally. Hallelujah. And I bought it and this
thing comes to me in the mail that was like an on demand print.
And I'm like, no, and I did a return and filled out the form and
Amazon, you know, like, whatever, they don't care as long as you do, like,
less than 1% returns that are just like we don't care.
But it was pretty clearly this person had set up
a, they were trying to,
yeah,
that's horrible.
Yeah.
And I mean, we're going to see more of that because
yes,
it's easy. Ok.
But
I think
how does this tie into responsibility and hashy Corp,
I'm still not putting all these pieces in.
So, for example,
like
in the past companies behaved in ways that were
usually reasonably ok when it came to making money.
And what's interesting is they would sometimes do things that
we said that is not an acceptable way to,
to make money or to defend your moat,
you know, like suddenly
like suing competitors to drive them out of business, you know, like you,
and what's interesting now is it's becoming kind
of a trope where these companies become successful.
And
in my experience it seems to be driven a lot by
service companies using their open source and offering a service now
and, and this is driving them to modify their open source licenses to this, you know,
hashy court business license or like the totally free but business friendly,
open source license or whatever.
Ok.
-- Well, is this good or bad? Is it
-- ok. It's bad.
I'm gonna, I'm gonna unwind everything you just said. Ok, I wanna unwind all this.
So if you can't say companies like, somehow had this
moment of, of like Zen and realism where they were good and decent and they,
what happened was,
that was
-- not my
-- in.
-- Ok.
-- That's kind of what it sounded like.
Ok.
Well, no, I meant more that they didn't do reprehensible things
yet.
-- They, they wanted to but they couldn't or they didn't
-- feel it was necessary.
But no, no, they did. So this is where, ok.
So you did kind of say what I thought you said,
this is where if you look at
the way companies acted and they'll say in the late 18 hundreds, early 19 hundreds,
like they were literally throwing human beings
into machines because it was cheaper than,
than building a railing.
And like you had these huge companies that were just
awful and they literally killed people and no one cared.
And then the government, it got,
well, I'm talking more
-- the last 2030 years of tech companies. I mean, and
-- that's just it, right?
So it got so bad. Governments had to step in and be like, hold on.
We have to fix some of this.
And now we're back there again where these companies,
like if a company could like remove all their hand rails at their, at their plant,
they would, right?
They would love to if it saved them five dollars,
there was that meatpacking thing where a 17 year
old lost his hand and the company was fined,
-- it was just over 1000 bucks,
-- which they don't care, they're going to keep doing it.
You know.
And that's why we had these, like,
we had labor unions and we had government regulation that was
basically telling the companies you can't throw people into machines.
It's not, it's not ok.
And we're back because a lot of these protections are gone and
in many ways the world has changed and it took it away.
Now on the topic of like,
like saying hashy Corp is,
is getting their lunch eaten by another company or whatever.
I think this is your classic commodity
problem where if I create a product and I can,
let's say patented and I get my 20 years of patent
and at the end, if I haven't done anything to really innovate,
people are gonna copy what I do
and they're gonna steal my stuff. And you could argue, well, that's not fair.
Hashi Corp did all this work and they built this thing and like you're not wrong,
they did a lot of work, they did a lot of good work.
But at the same time, I think you could argue that
the fundamental functionality of terraform and vault,
it's not going to change drastically because
it's basically a commodity function now like
it's expected and we need that functionality and it's not novel anymore.
So, and this, for example,
is a perfect example of where worldly mapping gets it right where
it talks about things go from Genesis to custom to products,
to utility
and
to put it bluntly
-- in most of the utility space, your margins are 1 to 3%. Right.
-- Exactly.
And that's what's happening.
-- Like
-- grocery stores 3% margins to,
if you're lucky, it is horrifying to find out. You know, I
don't, when you like, I remember a chef at large did an episode with Earl's.
It's a chain of restaurants, Canada where they went over like,
here's this dish of food for like 28 bucks and like, ok, like,
you know, like, uh, about a third in food costs.
Here's the labor cost, here's the like,
cutlery or plates getting broken is like 10 cents and
like this and that and that and then it's like,
literally you're left with this handful.
This is like, this is so old. We still had pennies
and like,
it's literally a handful of like a couple of nickels and a couple of pennies.
And that's
amazing. It's absolutely amazing.
So anyway, I think that's the difference when we have this discussion.
It's easy to say, oh, big be Amazon.
Big mean Google are stealing from poor little hashy
carp
and it was the same with elastic where big mean Amazon was stealing from elastic.
But I think what you end up with is like, your product has become a commodity.
It's time to do something else.
-- This is not going to make a difference
-- and
the smart companies keep moving up the food chain.
So like Microsoft and Red Hat went from like we have an operating system
to
that. We have everything
had 100 and 20 products.
Like,
and, and I mean, so here's what's funny is so like elastic, did that change?
Elastic doesn't sell elastic search anymore.
They're selling solutions built on top of elastic search. So
elastic search
fundamentally,
fundamentally, I don't think they had to change their license.
I think they were just really mad at Amazon or something. But
like,
I
sometimes
wonder if it's one of those interim steps that a lot of these companies have to take
because to put it bluntly, if they could make the leap from software to services
they would have.
And maybe, and that's true, maybe, maybe that's what they needed to,
to change their internal mindset.
-- I don't know,
-- we talk about culture and that company's culture is software.
Like a great example of this is Microsoft's company culture
is not software, it's business solutions,
right? Everything they ship
is a business solution.
So like Windows 11 still has PR N and calm one and com
two as reserve device names because people are still using them for that.
Like
somebody discovered you can't make a Microsoft team's
name of like LPT or PR N because
that like then we have to make a directory call that and you can't do that on Windows.
So those are magic forbidden words.
And I was toying with the idea of like making
a major open source project called LPT One or something.
That would be really funny,
-- you know,
-- walk out all the windows people.
But
like
talking about this corporate DNA, like,
that's the thing is if your culture and DNA is making software,
which a lot of these start ups,
they are technically
minded, founded entities.
And so they have that, like, we make software, not, we make a solution or we make,
you know, they don't have to step up until
they maybe let business people come in and redefine the company, which
that's, that's rare for it to work.
One of the few examples I can think of for success for that is Apple.
They were from a technical company to a lifestyle company
and that's what people don't get.
It drives me nuts when they're like, oh my God, that Mac is so overpriced.
I'm like, yeah, none of us care.
I,
I do, I hate my Mac. But anyway.
Right. But like, fundamentally my math watch with all my other stuff
don't care.
They fuel my lifestyle of hatred, Kurt, they fuel my lifestyle of hatred.
And I, I think that's the thing is what is this,
I guess
what is the new behaviors and the new things?
But we want from companies, but also
what is sustainable and what will actually work because
we can want company like greenwashing, right?
All these companies are like, oh, we're going to be socially environmentally,
blah, blah.
You know,
and then every time one of these companies is
investigated for what they're actually doing with the environment.
It's like,
oh, yeah, we took all the plastic and burned it.
Right. Like
we dump
it in the
o,
-- we
-- planted
-- a pine tree. It's ok.
Right.
Look, I, I think here's how I'm gonna end this one.
I don't think open source is gonna stop being a
feature used by small companies to get attention because it works
right until it stops.
I think what we're going to see
is
the community is becoming wise to what's going on.
And like, for example, if I saw AC L A on a project, there's absolutely no way
I'm going to participate in that community because I know how that story ends.
And so I, I'm hopeful that the,
the what's going to come of this is start ups will keep using open source,
but they're gonna have to stop using CLAS.
That's my hope because I think no cl A
I won't say it solves the problem, but I think it makes it better.
That's a thought for like maybe for the um what is it? The open
OS sf what does that mean? Again? Open source, open
-- source
-- security foundation.
Yeah, like maybe
do they have a badge around cl A
not having AC L A?
I don't know if their members would be appreciative of that
and then we're back to incentives and doing things that the people
don't like.
This is why we don't have sponsors.
All right, I'm going to call this one. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you for listening. Go
open source security podcast.com. Head up the show notes. He's a
Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
Excuse me? You too.
I love it. All right. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.