Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner and wondering what it's all about Josh Presser.
-- Yeah.
-- Anyway, Douglas Adams figured this out years ago.
All right, I have a story of epic proportions to start this episode with.
Right before
I got on with you,
I recorded a webinar
for Clouds Smith, right?
Which is a, a company in like the supply chain security space.
They're really good people. I, I like them a lot
and
I have a Mac I use for work and I hate Macs.
This is not a secret to anyone who's listened to the show for any period of time,
right?
I could not get this Mac to work with the webinar. It's just a web browser, right?
Just a web browser.
It would not work like the video was messed up.
The audio is messed up like it just would not work for me.
And finally,
I was like f this and I pulled out the computer
we use right here to record this podcast all the time.
And I fire up the web browser site on Linux
Flawless which browser
chrome it was chrome I tried Firefox.
Firefox was unhappy, which is not surprising in any way.
I find almost everything that has to be chrome.
I
-- just, it,
-- it does happen. I, I hate that too, but that's another story.
But anyway, like, worked flawlessly on Linux and I was like, this is the first time,
like, I think in the history of ever, Linux
has actually had audio and video working correctly while Mac Os did not do it.
It was like,
blew my mind. I didn't even know what to say.
It's, I just, I feel like it's 2023 and we've computers have had sound for like, what,
-- 40 years
-- more than that they had sound in the sixties.
-- Like,
-- I know the original analog since and stuff and like,
yeah, but I mean, like proper digital sound,
you know, with like delivery over the internet since the late nineties easily.
Like,
and I just, I'm kind of like, it's been 30 years.
-- How come we can't get this right reliably across all the platforms.
-- It's hard to do.
Well, I get it. I totally get it as a person who's worked with sound for a long time.
I've written applications that do sound things like, I totally understand
why this is so hard.
-- But
-- I also feel like, like I get like using some wonky little browser,
maybe not working.
But like if you're using Chrome Safari or edge,
it should
-- just work.
-- One would think. But it didn't, I blame,
I
blame Mac Os because it hates me and I hate it. And that's fine.
It's funny because I, I have a pretty good relationship with all my computers.
Be they Linux
Mac or Windows and we just all seem to get along.
So I, I hate them all and they all hate me. But the beauty of Linux is, it has
the ability to figure out at least what's going on
so I can go like, stomp something
to the ground if I need to and solve my problems.
Whereas on Windows and Mac Os, they're basically like, ha ha, no, go f yourself,
loser.
Well, and that kind of leads into this thing,
this opaqueness of systems where like you bought it, you own it.
Well, you own a license to the software,
but do you kind of own it? And so here's the thing. What do, ok.
So what do the Polish trains GM, car dealership,
service departments and like G capital kind of all have in common?
They're out to screw us all.
Well, no, there's a very fundamental fact about selling large equipment, which is
the vast majority of money you make when you
sell large equipment is off the financing of it like
a
few,
like a decade or whatever ago, GE split into GE capital and the GE that makes stuff,
the G capital, finances, same thing with all the big three automakers.
-- Well, or big four auto, I forget how many it is now, whatever
-- the big
automakers,
they make all their money on financing.
And it's getting to the point now where
car dealerships are refusing to sell people cars.
If they want to pay for them,
they will only sell it if they finance it,
which is sort of, kind of illegal depending on your jurisdiction.
Like, it's happening locally and there's been some kerfuffle about
it. Like, what are you gonna do? Sue them? Like good luck.
-- There's,
-- I'm sure there's nothing you can do.
And then the second part of large equipment is you make a lot of money servicing it.
OEM. Parts. Right? Like I watched that cutting it.
Engineering, you know Australian Curtis guy
and you know, like he quotes these jobs and he's like, ok, like
they asked me to fix this part that like,
and it's got like a giant crack and it's like broken in half.
It's like, it'll take like a couple of days,
but the original OEM part is like $30,000 and I quoted them like 10 grand to fix it.
So they're like, please please try.
Um, also
the OEM part isn't available for six months.
So, you know. Wow.
I mean, it's just
a million dollar piece of capital equipment sitting there for six months.
That's very,
that's
fine.
And that's what gets me is like, people
always seem to forget that it's all about the financing and the servicing, like,
like the selling you, of the thing,
I'll sell it to you for a dollar. I don't care.
As long as you let me service it for 50 years and finance it.
That's fair.
Well, that's
kind of coming home to us now with that Polish train company that apparently
went so far as to put like Geolock
software so that the train undergoes like a level one.
I forget the levels,
but basically there's several levels of service and like a level,
like a lower level of service, like an oil change kind of thing.
Sure, whatever that,
that's allowed anywhere but like the deeper levels of
service where you're like swapping out engines or,
you know, doing like really
massive things.
Yeah, apparently that's geo lo
and if you do it,
not at their service locations,
they, they break the train and,
well, it wasn't even just that just if the train sat for, what, 10 days,
I think it would basically
because you don't know if they're touching it or not. Right. So just,
you know, no, no, no.
Because unless the parts have like electronics in them,
that kind of know what's going on.
You, you don't know if the train was serviced or not.
Like, you can't tell if the pistons in
a,
you know, in an engine were
swapped out or whatever. It's not an iphone with serialized parts
electronically communicating to each other.
-- I think
-- here's the story to the train thing because like John
Deere does this as well and they're not apologetic about it.
Right.
But I think the train story is interesting
because
they said none of this was happening and it was actually a group of hackers.
-- Oh,
-- they're still denying it. Yes.
-- That,
-- that's true.
They are, they're still denying it now threatening to sue the hackers.
And I love that. Well, number one, the hackers made the train work
and I'm pretty sure as good as a software engineer
is if there's something actually physically wrong with the train,
no amount of turning it off and on again and like,
tweaking the software is actually going to fix it.
So I'm pretty sure they actually fix it.
But what really blows my mind is this poor
train company literally like stumbled into this because they,
they were servicing trains and they kept breaking them and they're like,
like what's going on, right?
We're like,
we're not idiots like what's going on
and they literally googled like Polish hackers.
That's
Dennett said,
-- I love that you
-- maybe want to make sure you get the
right one and not an ad from some Chinese company or something.
But so they straight up contacted these Polish hackers and the hackers like, hey,
yeah, that's totally a thing we can help you with and,
and you know, there'll be links in the show and it's the articles.
If you haven't seen it, it's all over Mastodon and everything.
But it just
the fact that the company is shamelessly both denying that it happened
and now
trying to essentially get the trains pulled from service
by saying that it's not safe because the software
has been monkeyed with. It's been modified. We don't know what happened.
So therefore it's not safe.
And of course, the Polish Tracking group is like, yeah, no, we,
we didn't mess with the train control
software because we're not like idiots like,
right,
like anybody who has ever dealt with industrial control systems
even a tiny bit knows like if this control something that
weighs like 50 tons and moves at 100 kilometers an hour.
-- Right?
-- No, no, no, no, no, no, no,
I want to interject one other part to this story.
Oh, it's juicy. Huh? No, no,
no. It was just related. It's the Blender
presentation that was,
it was sent to us actually from a listener uh like a couple of weeks ago now, I think,
but
there's a marvelous presentation from Blender Con
where the, the head of the Blender Foundation, uh the
best
name ever.
It, it's, I know. Right.
But anyway,
he, he talks about the license of Blender and how it's a GP L and
I've never seen someone focus on
the,
the A he take the angle he takes of it
where obviously and this is something you've talked about before.
When we think about things like the VSD license,
the end user is a developer.
But when we think about the GP L, the end user is actually the end user
and he focuses on how like the first
items afforded to you from the GP L are, are a hugely important part of lender.
On a quick note on the BS D thing. It's not the developer so much. That's the end user.
It's the distributor of the software which
is in open
-- source, that's the developer. But
-- in a
company, it's not the company who has developed whatever.
But the point is like, I think about all this stuff kind of mixed up together
and we live in this just like Bizarro universe
where like, what, what do, what do we even own anymore?
Nothing. Well,
it's worse. It's, it's not even that I don't own it.
It's that I don't have meaningful control over it.
And
even if I do have meaningful like, OK,
I have meaningful control over that Linux box sitting over there
and
I can download all the source packages. I can recompile them.
I and I actually can do this. I have done this. I did it for a living. Like I've made
-- like, I work for red. We'll say
-- you used to be able to do this.
But the point is
I don't want to,
I don't want to
like,
I own a car. I
don't want to rebuild the engine. That does not sound like fun.
Like I just recently swapped out the side mirror on it
because a lady hit me and broke my side mirror.
But the point is, I don't want to, I just want a car that works. I want a solution.
And so I'm also at the point now where
most a lot of what I own is so complicated and would be so like fixing a TV.
No, you're just gonna go to Costco, spend 500 bucks on a new one, right?
Like the thought of even just trying to take a
TV apart without breaking those little clips in the back,
you know,
like it would have to be like, I love watching those people repair,
do component level repair of phones and switches
and it always boils down to,
they didn't pack their data up and they need
their data because the guy literally is like,
this is a Samsung 20.
Like, why is the person paying me $400 to fix it
because their photos are on it,
please back up your data and then he's like
-- taking it apart and swapping out a
-- capacitor.
Yeah, I mean, but, and, and there's people who can't, most people can't do that.
Right. Yeah.
Well, and more to the point though, but there is,
I own a lot of stuff that is so complicated.
Now,
even if I technically
both own and control it,
I don't have the time and expertise to actually fix it.
And even if I can find somebody who does,
it's barely worth it anymore.
And that's obviously like a train is different because the train is a giant capital
investment.
You know, that makes
sense
to
keep.
And that's happening locally too now where
I sent you that article. But so here in Alberta,
the average used car is about $42,000 Canadian
and the average new car is $71,000 Canadian,
which is like,
that's more than I've ever spent on buying these
cars and fixing them in my entire life.
And
so the article was talking about people who are like,
my Subaru broke and it was going to be $9000 to fix it. So we did
and I'm like, you know, like five years ago, if somebody said,
like they spent $9000 fixing their car, you'd be like,
-- you're insane. Buy,
-- buy
-- like
-- a used
one for sure.
100%.
I know that's not an option.
-- Right?
-- I mean, that's a,
that's a weird, it's such a weird problem and I think,
but on the one hand,
I'm kind of glad people are fixing things and not throwing it out
because the amount of energy that goes into building a car significant.
But
at the same time, like, you know, am I gonna have my 2015 car until 2035?
Yeah,
like it
maybe looks that way.
-- I
-- mean, and cars, cars do better now,
I feel like they last longer than they did when I was a kid.
I felt like once a car had about 10 years old, like, it was a heap of trash
and I have a 10 year old car now. That works remarkably well.
But anyway, all right, I wanna, I wanna pile this together
because
I think the concept of ownership is, has been overdone and,
and if anyone listening doesn't know who Cory Doctorow is, he's spoken extensively
to
podcast.
-- The one in 10,000 that, that, um, do
-- not assume people know
ever because it is extremely common
for the things we think are obvious, aren't necessarily obvious. Right?
So anyway, Cory Doctorow
writes extensively on all of these sort of topics and he's been on a real kick,
especially with the train story,
kind of about this whole concept of ownership, right?
And I think this extends
all over the universe now, right?
Everything from like the video games we play to the music, we listen to
you heard all the Sony story.
Uh Yeah, the the losing the rights to their
like,
oh, I even have a better story.
My one child
loves
the Crayola apps on the ipad and the Crayola
apps on the ipad are actually quite well executed
and they made one back in the day that actually had like
like a,
a pen and a brush and a thing that you would actually touch on the ipad surface to,
to brush and draw and it would like do different effects and stuff
and
they stopped maintaining the software. So at some point I OS was like, you,
sorry, it doesn't work anymore,
you know.
But the good news is now is I can pay
Apple Arcade $9 a month and get access to the Creole app again.
So I get to pay for it again.
Oh, wow. This is so exciting. Well, it sucks because now I get to pay.
Actually, it's, I'm paying the yearly fee, which is like 60 bucks a year.
But I basically,
I get access to the software I previously bought and was taken away from me.
What a good deal.
Yeah.
And the best part is it can go away at any time again
because now it's an Apple Arcade
and I'm like,
I don't know how the Apple Arcade stuff works.
Like, if I stop paying for Apple Arcade, do I still have access to all the apps? I,
-- oh,
-- you know, it's gone.
-- I
-- mean,
-- I get to pay forever and it might just go away randomly.
-- How exciting for you.
-- This is the best of
-- both
-- worlds.
-- I mean, this is like, I, I've got,
what are they, what is Microsoft game pass, I think for the Xbox
-- game pass? Extreme
-- Pro.
Yeah, whatever.
But it's like
for
two
-- bucks
-- a month and you,
and you get access to tons of games and,
like, it
is a reasonable deal because there's a lot of games I've played on
game pass that would have been 60 bucks if I paid for them.
-- They also
-- don't tend to break or disappear stuff as much.
They
do.
do, they
do
-- so on, like on game pass. Wait
-- between versions.
No, no, no. There's a section of game pass called Leaving Game Pass Soon
where they've run out of their license or whatever and they,
the games are disappearing
like a five
year license or something.
And there's,
there have been a handful of things. I've been,
ironically,
there have been a number of things that have disappeared and
then come back a couple of months later I've liked,
but
this is, I mean, it's this Bizarro. Well,
we
own things,
right?
-- What they want.
-- There
-- is
-- no, see in the old world,
I would sell you something. You would give me a pile of money for it.
And we were basically done.
That's right because
I didn't have the infrastructure and the services in place to like,
do recurring billing easily and actually get my
money out of you and more importantly,
enforce it.
Like, if you don't pay
while you still have it, what do I do now? Right. Oops.
And of course, with digital stuff, there is an inherent
DRM is pretty much baked into everything at this point.
-- Like
-- I want to say one thing that I think is
important to this conversation is yesterday while making my lunch.
I was thinking about this and I thought,
why, like,
why didn't, like, why were companies,
why did companies feel better in the past in this context and then I realized
every company 50 years ago that could have
screwed us over like this totally would have.
It's just, they couldn't.
Exactly.
And I, I think it, it's easy to think about the past to some amazing,
awesome place and it kind of was, but it was because they couldn't,
not because they didn't want to.
Right.
Well, oh, I, what was I watching? Oh, I was watching, uh I'm not gonna name this
because it's embarrassingly terrible on Amazon Prime video
and
there was ads in it and I'm like the ok.
First of all, I thought I paid for prime so I didn't have to watch ads,
but there was an HP ad that
was essentially a guy buying sushi. So os H I at a gas station
and
then getting violently ill and puking into a toilet and
it was an HP printer ink ad basically saying like,
you shouldn't buy off brand ink you
to buy like the HP stuff because according to the risk of, and I'm like,
my takeaway was like buying HP printers results
in like violent vomiting in a toilet and
disagree with that hot.
Right?
And like they were just positioning themselves as the,
like they straight up were trying to position themselves as the less evil,
terrible printer ink company,
right?
And again, a perfect example, HP and HP Enterprise, right? They basically
the HP printers were making something like
80 plus percent of the operating profits.
And so they split the company in two into like the printer
ink division that also happens to make printers that you put the printer ink in
and
oscilloscopes and servers and everything else.
And what was also fascinating is that I got a second hp commercial for a printer that
it said like ink trays and they're good for up to two years.
So you don't have to worry about your investment in the ink.
Oh, interesting.
And I'm like, that's exactly why I buy a laser jet.
Well, yeah, I mean, we know that, but laser jets are really expensive to buy.
This one was like
-- 3, 400 bucks,
-- which you can buy the
crappy
in chat for like
100 bucks.
But speaking of which I just remembered,
I need to turn off automatic updates on my printer
because my printer still allows me. I'm still using that same chip.
It's now been through three cartridges.
It's really on a low toner setting now.
Like, it's very, it,
every time I print it's like low toner, I'm like, I know it's fine.
But no, but they might push out an update that breaks it and says, let's
printed
like this ink cartridge chip says it did 50,000 pages or
whatever.
I'm not gonna talk to them anymore.
I mean, I guess my
-- date,
-- what
would be the downside to them doing that for them.
Uh, people would get mad.
It would probably look bad from apr perspective, which they might,
-- or might not like HP is
-- such a popular, good company.
They're not totally terrible, but it could tarnish
what little goodwill they have left.
-- I mean, there is some,
-- I'm buying a brother printer next time.
Like I've been reading and everybody says brother printers are just,
they manage to, like, not mess it up.
Right. Right. Which is ironic that,
but it's probably more expensive than an HP is my suspicion
the
last 10 or 20 years and I will spend not the amount
of just the, the cost of the toner like the cost of the HP toner versus the,
the non chipped toner.
-- It's $100 difference. I want to
-- tie it all up and I want to bring blender back in now
because I think
we have this like universe we exist in now.
That's all about trying to extract value, let's say from everything going on.
And a lot of companies look at things this way and it's
how they're paying their bills and whatever it is what it is.
And then
we look at something like blender,
which is, and I, I, you know, we should hold on, let me, let me reset for one moment
and explain what Blender is. Right? Blender is a GP L
3D rendering software
that was started by a company, it was sold as a product until the company couldn't
basically fund it. It, it, it didn't make it, which happens to companies.
And then the guy who runs the Blender Foundation now to,
he created like AAA crowdsourced effort to say if we raise,
I think it was a million bucks,
we can buy the source code to Blender and make it free
and make it, everyone can use it.
-- Well,
-- make it open source, which is even better than free, to be honest
-- because it could be free in commer like closed license.
-- Well, Blender was free.
I put free, it was like
shareware but
right, and it worked and people
for it and now it's considered uh an amazing piece of software
that anyone can use.
But one of the things he talks about in this
presentation is how people say like, oh,
I don't want to use Blender because it has this
license and I can't add my plugins to it.
I can't, you know, change it and, and make a product out of it.
And he's like, yes, that's the point. Like that's literally the whole point
you shouldn't get to.
-- When you say people you meant companies are complaining
-- that's
-- it's, it's companies for sure
-- because I'm like,
no actual person would complain about it.
-- No, no,
-- for sure.
And one of the things he says that that was just like,
blew my mind is how if you're a developer working for a company on some Blender code,
like that code goes into the Blender community and if you change jobs,
you can keep using the code, you wrote somewhere else,
which is like
it. That's very cool and very amazing.
And there's,
but it's the GP L license which I know tons of
companies consider viral and lots of people don't like it.
But from like
from the perspective of I am a human trying to do a thing
like it is,
-- I know it can't go away.
-- Let's take a step back 30 years.
Why did Linux beat Bs D?
Linux was objectively
crap compared to BS D in the beginning, like
-- Bs D and free Bs D were far far superior.
-- They were forked from UNIX, right?
So they had a huge head start.
And my personal theory is is that while Linux
had a rough start and a pretty rough childhood,
the GP L
meant stuff got folded back in because remember back in the late nineties,
there was a
ton of companies shipping stuff based on BS D like F five
F five load bouncers, man,
those things were like 50 grand a pop and it
was basically glorified free Bs D box for sure.
And the thing I think that happened is is Linux got
that small but incremental compound interest
of developer contributions over time.
Whereas in the BS D world,
the companies
vastly improved free BS D
in their product
and then very rarely if ever
went upstream with it because honestly also back then
the velocity in the delta was a lot less.
And so keeping your own up, like your own kernel patches and changes was uh easier
air quotes easier, but still
a pain.
But like,
you know, keeping a Linux kernel 23 years out of date now is basically impossible.
Like I, I feel so bad for all the people that have to do this, like, holy cow.
Like it was bad seven years ago. I can't imagine what it's like now. For sure.
For sure. That's the thing is like with BS D, the license is
what led to it. Not it, it, the growth was slower than Linux
and Linux compound interest works.
-- That's all I'm gonna say.
-- Not just that if I am cooperating in
an environment like this, I don't want to think
I'm going to contribute some changes that my competitor is then going to take modify
and then beat me over the head with later. Yeah,
which I think is a very real concern in many of these instances.
Oh, it happens all the time. Sure, sure, sure. And now I want to
tie this into like trains, let's say right
where if I am a train manufacturer,
I build a train, someone buys my train
and that might be that could be the end of
it right where I never touch that train again.
I never get another dime
off that train
-- and
-- your board is gonna scream at you because the shareholders are gonna have a like
a legal case against you to make sure
that doesn't happen because they want that sweet money
for.
That's the modern world.
That's the,
but I think it is,
it creates such a weird
incentive for some of these organizations.
I think when that is your, I mean, because the focus isn't building a good train,
the focus is making sure the train comes back to me for maintenance
-- and
-- financing it.
So it, it turns into this weird incentive now
versus,
and then the extreme example of this is, is I don't sell you the train,
I lease you the train and I not
lease you the train, but I lease you the train and the, the service and parts.
And this is even happening with like military vehicles.
Like I was, I remember watching a thing where
I think it's Ryan Mattel makes the dingo
and they will not only like lease you the dingo,
but they will send people to very strange parts of the world to fix the damn thing.
And I don't mean like send them to fix it on spec but like,
like we'll set up like a base camp motor pool
to fix these things and maintain them.
And the argument, it's like what the US did with
all of their uh food used to be kind of done in house.
Like if you went somewhere and invaded it, you,
you brought a bunch of people in green uniforms who did all your cooking.
Well, and then that was, remember in the famous thing, it was sold to, um,
Kellogg Halliburton or whatever it's called.
Right.
You know, and that's all those sorts of cheap contractors coming in from, you know,
other parts of the world that pay a lot less money.
And the argument being is that, you know,
the military should be doing military stuff, not making breakfast.
-- I
-- mean,
-- you can make that argument
-- and there's this kind of core competency focus where,
you know, you're seeing it now with public private partnerships. Like,
do we really want the city to like employ 5000 people to fix the road system
or do we just want to do like a PPP to build the Anthony Hende portly?
Well, that's what we ended up doing,
right?
Because it allows you to, to shift costs into the future, present value of money,
future value of money.
And I think the problem is everything is boiling down to
a spreadsheet with what can we maximally extract money?
And I don't mean maximally over like 10 or 50 years, but like, you know,
my, my incentive or my view might be this quarter or this year to get my bonus.
There's a lot of that in
-- industry,
-- we were just talking with a software vendor and they're like, oh,
if you sign by this date, like uh January 31st,
you don't even have to pay until like May or whatever but if we can get you signed by,
like January 31st, I'm like, oh, is that your year end?
He's like, yeah, how, how'd you know? And I'm like,
-- everyone
-- does that.
-- I'm like, this is not a secret. Like, come
-- on,
that's just, that's meeting a quota and, and whatnot.
But now, II I think the incentive structure of all of this is, is a good topic
and this is also where we can kind of
tie security into the larger conversation as well,
right?
Because we,
everything that happens, you've got basically you have upfront costs,
you have long term like total cost of ownership, we say, right?
Like that's what
unknown risks and
there's
all kinds of stuff like that, right? And, and you can
shovel some of that onto other parties if you're like leasing or you're,
you're saying like we're going to pay you
-- a flat fee for yearly maintenance and fundamentally
-- no
company is gonna eat that cost.
Like it always drives me nuts when people talk about renting a house, they're like,
oh, I want to rent a house because what if the roof breaks?
I don't have to pay for a new roof. And I'm like,
if you think your landlord is simply eating that cost and be like, oh silly me,
I have to pay $10,000 for a new roof.
I guess my tenants, you know, get off free.
-- No, no, it's baked into the cost of renting like,
-- for sure,
but it's not a cost you have to pay immediately.
Right?
No,
-- it's like the free phones from your cell phone company.
-- Yes.
The phones are a great example of that right where they're always like, oh,
you get a free phone.
It's like, no, you don't.
That's why your phone plan costs $20 more than this other phone plan
where I bring my own phone
and, and anyway, anyway,
I feel like
there is
a definite art
and understanding to this whole like figuring out the spreadsheet,
the magic spreadsheet that explains how all of this works.
And there's actually a really good video I will put in the show notes
that Matt Parker who does stand up maths
did an episode with Climate Time
where they talk about the city of Chicago leased
the parking meters
to AAA banker. I forget what company it was. But anyway,
and Matt Parker basically breaks down the math and
the city of Chicago screwed this up pretty big.
Like
there's, if you look at the graph,
they basically start getting screwed at like 35 years.
And prior to that, you can make the argument that this wasn't a terrible,
the top Google result is parking meter deal gets
even worse for Chicago taxpayers annual audit shows.
-- I gotta read this because these numbers are amazing. It,
-- it's bananas for sure.
Parking meter revenues are nearly back to pre pandemic levels.
Levels with 61 years to go on the 675 year lease.
Chicago parking parking meters,
LLC has now recruited its entire $1.16 billion investment plus 502.5 million more.
They're making
profit in 14 years and with
-- 61 to go
-- and it's a 75 year lease, I think. Right.
It's, it's bananas. The, the whole video is bananas.
But anyway,
anyway,
this is a challenge and I feel like, especially in security,
total cost of ownership is one of the favorite things
people love to talk about in the world of security.
Right.
We're like, oh, if you use this tool,
your total cost of ownership is half of what that tool is and,
and this and that and another.
-- And I feel like
-- they've never shown me the spreadsheet for that though.
Like, I've never seen this,
-- of course not.
-- Right. Because I'm like, I'm like, what are the assumptions here?
And like the assumptions are,
you'll buy, like, the cheapest version of our product,
you'll buy the most expensive version of their product,
then you set it on fire and buy it again.
Exactly. That's right. Exactly.
And it's run by monkeys who don't know how computers work
and for sure
it's,
it's bananas and
when you put all of this together, sometimes it feels like we're living in this,
like, bizarro dystopian universe.
-- Right.
-- No, it doesn't feel like,
ok, we kind of are.
No, no, we kind of are
printer, ink cars,
like, like
something like in some US cities now, 10% of house sales last year were to
-- hedge funds and other large entities. Yeah,
-- that's true.
I did hear about that and lots of cities are trying to fix that
well, past it feels like dystopia.
That's fair. That's fair.
And now, like, look,
we're running out of time and we basically dug ourselves into a giant hole of manure
of incentives.
And the thing is as long as these incentives exist,
like a perfect example is locally,
there's a bunch of efforts to
essentially privatize profits and socialize the losses
for everything from like the Calgary, the new arena that they want.
Like the province is kicking in over $300 million. Ok?
So like they're supposed to put money aside so that when the Well is closed,
that it's remediated and you know,
shut down properly and there's an orphaned Well Fund because, you know,
some of these companies go bankrupt.
And,
but what happens now is they sell the non producing or
less producing wells to these companies for like literally a dollar.
And then that company weirdly has no assets and goes bankrupt. And so
we're now looking at potentially tens of billions of dollars
in orphan well, remediation here in Alberta like that the taxpayers will pay for
and there's 4 million of us. So that's a lot of money.
Your story is sad. We need to, we need to end this. On a, on a positive note,
I'm not going to let us go out like this.
Maybe the A is, will solve this for us by whipping us
out.
If we're lucky,
if
we're lucky the computers, the machines will take over. But
no, ok. Look, I, I want to,
I want, I want to send us out on this in a kind of reasonable way. Right. Because
it's easy to look at everything going on and be like everything is terrible
and it's all doom and gloom and nothing works and I hate it all.
And I think Blender is the thing to look at
to give us hope. Right? And there are other examples similar to Blender,
but
there,
when we work together and we try to make things
better and like there's lots of open source projects that,
that I would say right now,
my focus would be very open source because I think that
is a space that has figured some of this out.
We can do things together that do amazing things, right.
There are plenty of, of software products, security, not security, like whatever
that
I won't say we own them necessarily.
But I would say it's closer to this concept of ownership
that we're used to.
Well, see my concept of ownership now is
can I maintain it? Can I fix it? Can I change it? Can I sell it? Can I share it?
That's
right. And what blows my mind is like, I have physical books here and sharing it,
like, here, hand it over to you and
give me the book and I can,
you know,
and I have Pirated media content. Where can I share it? Absolutely super easy.
And then I have stuff I paid for
and like, holy hell, you can't share that for sure.
Or even worse, like the Netflix thing with the whole I'm divorced.
My kids have two households. They have a,
you know, they, they travel back and forth between the houses with their phones,
but not, you know, like there are some devices that they're logged in
on their Netflix accounts that stay, they, they'll never come over here to my house
and apparently they might get locked out at some point.
Yeah. That's right. That's right. You know, and I'm just like,
this is why
it's what the, the funny, I'm just going to leave this.
My, one of my sons, the one that has autism
now seems to understand
he wants all his important stuff on the pluck server.
Like there's stuff like he actually got upset the other day.
There's a movie on youtube, uh, the police, a little police car movie from Sweden
and it wasn't on Plex and he wanted it on Plex because I think he,
I don't think he can verbalize it, but I think he understands,
I want to watch this in the future
and it's on youtube and it may not be on youtube in the future. But
daddy's plex server magic, it's always there
for sure, for
sure.
So I think part of it is as a, as a culture in a society,
we need to start pushing back and working around this and like hiring
hackers to fuss with our trains to make them work if need be.
Yeah. Yeah. Hackers like man, I love hackers. They fix everything. It's so good.
Yeah. Yeah. I mean, I think that's one way to look at it.
So I'll kind of end it on this quote from Cory Doctorow. Right. He says
if buying isn't owning piracy isn't stealing slow
clap, clap.
I kind of agree.
Like
-- that's well done, sir. I love it. All
-- I know is I, I paid for games
that don't work and I cannot down
-- and install.
-- You should look on the internet archive.
Actually,
-- they've done a marvelous job of making a lot of this weird old stuff work
-- ipad stuff.
No.
Absolutely.
100%. You can maybe get an A PK and kind of get it working. And I,
I've tried with that and it's just been so
temperamental and problematic that it's not worth it.
That's fair.
That's fair. Like it sucks because man, that kid misses some of his games.
No, I'm serious.
Like he just really wants to get that poor little Lego Duplo bunny,
his ice cream and help him with his friends.
That's it. He just wants to help the bunny
anyway. All right. And, and I'll end up one last note, please. Everyone run Firefox.
-- It's important. That's all.
-- I'm sure a tri troppo
of edge
safari for Mobile and Chrome is fine
run. Firefox. Kurt start running Firefox.
I'm, I'm specifically
the
manager
makes me want to go
-- run
-- it,
do it.
I've tried and do it.
You suffer through it.
I
am.
I,
I just don't understand why they can't fix the persona manager
-- because that makes it unusable for me.
-- All right, I'm ending it. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you all for listening. Go to social security podcast.com.
Find the show notes.
You can use the pound dos as podcast hashtag
on Mastodon to tell Kurt he should run Firefox.
Kurt.
-- Have a marvelous rest of
-- your day. You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks
everyone.
Bye bye.