All right. Did you want to lead this one or me?
-- I, I don't know. It's December 20
-- first,
21st.
Bug
-- bounties.
-- All right.
Uh, I like them. I love bug
for two big reasons. One,
it's, it, it strongly signals,
not only that you can report a bug but where to report it and how to report it.
Right. Because not, not all projects are clear on that. You know, I,
I remember one project they wanted you to log into their IRC server
to get,
to ask for an account in their bug tracker so you could file the security bug.
And the rationale was, they had a lot of spam in their, yeah,
I remember we talked about it was a Fedora project because
they were getting a lot of spam in their bug trackers.
So they locked it down and this was how they handled account creation.
I'm like, well, you're never going to get a bug report. It's just too much work.
-- You know?
-- Actually that's interesting because if you work with a bug bounty.
All right. For, I guess one thing too, like we had, don't roll your own crypto.
Don't roll your own off. Don't run your own bug bounty.
-- Well,
-- what's the difference between having, like,
security at bob.com versus security at bob.com?
-- And we'll pay you 20 bucks for security
-- at Bob. Well, ok, so here's the problem is
-- in most countries there are legal implications to paying people.
-- Oh, good point.
Yeah. And
-- for example, if we have a bug money at Elastic, we use hacker one.
-- Yeah.
Do you fill out the W eight ban or the W eight Ben?
-- Right.
-- And like it is hacker one's problem
to figure out if we can or can't pay that person money.
Yeah, because, like, for example,
the United States isn't allowed to give money to people in a couple of countries.
Well, and there's also the, well, the restricted people's list,
there's also people on this list from
-- the Department of State that you're not allowed to do stuff with.
-- Yeah.
Right. Right.
Because imagine if a,
if a terrorist organization started claiming bug
bounties and if you gave them money,
like, you're going to get a visit from a guy in a black suit, you know,
probably more than one.
Uh, yeah. No, I, I apologize.
I, I, every time this topic comes up I forget that,
that the whole payment thing is such a nightmare,
which you think I would realize because I get,
I do most of my contracts for American companies and I go through this constantly,
you know, and, well,
and then the second thing too is bug bounties are an ongoing security thing.
Right.
I, for example, I hate
code audits
because
you do a code audit,
you find some flaws and I guarantee you if you pay a different group of code auditors
the same or more money, they will find a separate set,
like they will find a bunch more flaws.
And so a bug bounty doesn't pretend
that we found all the bugs and it's good.
It's a bug bounty is part of the process of making this thing less of a tire fire.
Well, and look, I'm going, I've been through many code audits.
I,
I don't run it anymore but I ran a bug bunny and I will tell you now that the quality of
bugs you get out of a bug bounty are significantly
higher than what you get out of a code audit.
I would assume that that would depend on who you hire.
But the reality is code auditors.
The good ones are super, not cheap and more to the point. There's
-- 1000 of them globally made
-- and they only have,
usually you get a code audit for like two weeks or something.
Right. There's that time box around it where a bug hunter can spend infinite time
-- on your stuff if they want to.
-- That's a good point.
They can take that like slow approach of, for example, a run through a fuzz,
then look at the results then,
you know, coordinate with this other person. Yeah. No, I suspect you're right.
-- Yeah, time constraint would matter.
-- And they don't find anything.
I don't have to pay them if my code auditor doesn't find anything.
I still have to cut him a big fat check.
Yeah. Somehow I feel like there's no code auditors that, you know, work on a win.
-- No, no win. No pay fee structure.
-- No.
And look, the other thing too is when you get a code audit,
you get a fancy letter that says you got a code audit and
then there's certain customers that you hand the letter to and they say,
oh, good job, you got a code audit.
And that's the really the real reason behind it more so than what you,
what you get found.
-- Oh, yeah, I've seen that checkbox. Do you have third party code audit?
-- Right.
-- Because if you don't, then
-- why not? Here's the question.
-- Do bug bunnings count as a third party code audit?
-- No,
I've been,
I've been very interested in this topic for a
long time and I've talked to many customers.
I've talked to many bug bounty people about the fact that it
would be lovely to be able to say a bug bounty is,
you know, we have a bug bounty in place.
We have people looking at this and we're finding
these kind of bug and basically giving statistics on what's
of what it looks like versus necessarily saying because we,
I've been involved with code audits.
I pay a lot of money for code audits and I think the letter has value
but the results of the code audits,
-- I think has been less than the bug bounties
-- for sure.
And objectively, depending on what your bug bounty pays.
Obviously, if your bug bounty pays a dollar,
you're probably not going to get good stuff.
But there are bug bounties out there that pay in the hundreds of thousands.
We do not pay that much.
But we, let's say there, we, at one point our numbers were very low and yes,
the amount you're paying dictates what you're going to get.
Because yes, if you have a bug money not paying a lot,
you're just not going to get a lot of results.
Well, I'm going to go somewhere where the money is. Yeah.
It's definitely a very money driven environment.
-- Well,
-- it's, these people are doing work for money.
That's
-- right.
-- And they're money driven. Like,
who knew, who knew anyway. Anyway.
Also, we still need an unpaid intern.
No,
-- I'll see you on December 22nd
-- car. Thanks everybody.