Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt
Siefried and my partner in
managing S
Josh.
Yeah, we'll get there, we'll get there. So II I need to preface this podcast with.
There is a thunderstorm happening outside
and there may be thunder
and other ridiculous noises
that, that come with me. And I also have a funny, a hilarious
anecdote to add to that. So I took my bike ride this morning. Right.
As I always do, I check my phone, check the weather and it's like,
basically I have an hour to take a ride before the
rain comes and I think no problem I can do this.
Right.
So I'm, I'm riding. I get about halfway done and I look into the sky
and it looks like one of those paintings where half the painting is
sunshine and flowers are happy and the other half is like the apocalypse.
And that is what I see in the sky and there's like lightning
and it's black and I'm like,
I need to ride and I rode faster than I think I've ever ridden in my life.
I did not get wet, but holy cow. My legs are sore.
I've, yeah, our weather here is also broken.
Yeah. Oh, you're right. Right. It's,
and honestly,
I can't ever remember seeing a sky that looked like this because it was just like,
literally half of it was awesome.
And the other half was like, there is death in this sky.
It was wild.
Well,
and that actually is pretty much exactly what's happening
here with the Linux kernel in this code.
No, it's not.
Well, no, you've got like all the code that builds properly
with, you know, even W air.
So every error becomes a warning and like forces you to deal with it.
And then you've got this pile of code coming into the kernel that's like
a
-- bit of a train wreck.
-- OK? Well, there's, there's two things that happen.
There's, there's a, a story we found on the register
that focuses on the Linux kernel.
And there were two really cool things in this story
that I think are worth discussing on this podcast,
obviously open source.
So first of all,
Linus basically complained that he doesn't like the way github does merges.
And I agree with him
every time I look at github merges, I'm kind of like
-- we'll get
-- to that, we'll get a hand.
And the second thing is that the kernel is going
to now enable an error flag called dash w error.
And what that means is historically, when you compile code,
the compiler can issue warnings
and it could be warnings like, oh, you're using this unsigned integer
in a way that it expects to be signed. For example, that's an easy one.
There's like millions of errors you can get. Right.
And historically, we've been like, oh,
our warnings are fine. Right. We don't care, ignore warnings. It's fine.
And in fact, there's a switch to ignore warnings.
Now,
the colonel has said we are not ignoring warnings.
Now, if there is any warning at all, the build fails, which now it is a,
it is a kernel compile options.
You can basically say I accept warnings because obviously
when you're reporting to a new architecture or something,
this can be a part. But anyway,
I think this is a huge deal because an enormous number
of security problems we have seen have been ignored warnings.
-- So this is cool.
-- Well, see, and here's what drives me nuts.
The whole premise of warnings
is,
in my opinion, here's a warning.
That's so that's fine.
Like if you're a developer and you write code that doesn't have warnings,
I'd actually be kind of freaked out and worried because you're
either perfect or you're doing something so banal it doesn't matter.
But so I expect developers to write code with warnings, right.
That's yeah, please do that.
But for production, like when red hat compiles the kernel to ship it to customers,
-- it better not be compiling with warnings.
-- I mean,
I, I have a perfect example to describe this situation
is I remember a long time ago I was working with an,
with an open source project and it was a Ruby project.
And there's this Ruby two called Brakeman
and
we, I ran it through brakeman and brakeman came back empty and I'm like,
Brakeman must be broken.
So I go to the project and I'm like, hey, I think Brakeman's broken
and I, I think it was a brakeman developer was like, no dude,
Brakeman is fine like this project comes back empty.
And I'm like, what?
So anyway,
they're talking to the devs and one day they got so mad at Brakeman reports
that they went through and were just purposely
doing whatever it took to shut up Brakeman
and they actually added some security vulnerabilities by doing this,
which is why I was talking to them.
But I'm like,
what?
Yeah,
I mean, because there's that famous Openness Cell Law in Debian where
the guy who first name Kurt just like me
basically got tired of a warning and he made the warning go away.
Well, so, so this one is, is also unique though.
So it's really fun to pick on Debian for this because
it was kind of their mistake. But behind
the person.
No, no, no, only kind of for real.
So what happened was the, the Debian developer didn't like this warning,
basically put together a patch that said this makes the warning go away,
sent it to open SSL,
open SSL ignored the mail said nothing either way.
And then he was like, well, no one said anything.
-- I'm going to include this patch and then someone looked at it and was like, uh,
-- oh,
well, my
understand is that that person was also on the open SSL development team,
they might have been,
but that just kind of makes it like here's my thing,
random person sends me a patch,
whatever I might ignore it.
But like one of the developers on the team, I'm on sends a patch
like
you,
you know, to quote, to quote the fifth element,
you know, you might want to read that could be important.
Alright.
So anyway,
I think the air conversation is going to be the more interesting of the team,
but I want to start with
github.
I just, sorry, I have, they actually
did whatever it takes in the project to make
Brakeman not warn or find any errors at all.
I'm just,
I'm trying to think of what it would take to
do that in a ruby project because Brakeman looks for
a lot of different things. It's clearly possible.
I
would not trust that code anymore because it's been so weirdly optimized for.
I mean, maybe,
maybe it's complicated.
I mean,
this is always one of my concerns when you
have any sort of automated scanner that's overly noisy,
is eventually developers get angry
and they start making poor decisions.
And so it's like scanner vendors.
If you're listening, please, please, please don't be overly noisy.
Well, or better yet have maybe confidence levels like I am sure this is a problem or
I think this might be a problem.
No
one does that, you know, and it drives me nuts that
like there's a reason every single government and military
has specific words around.
I am highly confident, you know,
like is it going to rain today
maybe or yes or you know.
-- Yeah. Anyways.
-- Anyway, anyway, anyway. All right.
So I want to talk about the merge thing first because I think, I think it'll be quick.
So what happens in the github
universe that a lot of people don't always realize is when, when you submit a github
pull request, it basically takes a whole bunch of commits on your branch,
it squishes them into one commit and then you write one message
kind of and that's what ends up getting sent to the project.
So you could have say 30 commits
to add a feature.
But what the project sees is one commit from you.
-- And
-- it's almost worse than that because Git itself has a merged command
that does this
and
use
that
well, but it sort of does it somewhat
more.
I'm sorry,
you shouldn't squash merge because there's merge
squash don't and github basically squashes emerges.
But when you use Git by itself,
you can have it merge all of the individual commits, which is the right way to do this.
I will say
it strikes me as one of those classic things where some kind of,
I hate to say like a pointy haired boss was basically like, can we make this simpler?
And the Devs went well.
Yeah, but we shouldn't. And the point to your boss went,
-- I like simpler. Let's do simpler. I
-- mean,
it's complicated.
I think, I think from a purely usability perspective, this obviously wins.
But from the kernel's perspective, I think the kernel is special and unique
and the developers have certain expectations. Many other projects don't.
And let's face it too. I mean,
how many pr s have I submitted?
That is basically one commit on my branch.
You know,
it's the number is not zero.
And and additionally, you also run into the situations where
I submitted pr the developers like change.
This is this,
this and this II I add my patch and now the PR
is basically magically updated and now it looks how they want it to
look and then they can merge it and it doesn't have an
extra commit that's like fix the
stupid complaints from those annoying developers.
So anyway, anyway, it's I
the I think the funny observation of this is
get and the kernel were both created by Linus
and like
and now github
is tormenting him. I love it.
It's, it's
I always love how software
gets published and then used in ways that,
you know, various people feel is wrong
and depending on kind of who they are, we,
we either care or don't care about their opinion.
And then obviously, you know, maybe the person who created this,
their opinion has a little more weight
on the flip side. Obviously, this is what the majority of github
customer base probably wants because
I
literally
the number of people complaining about this is like not many
and look at the same time,
all the other advantages of github
drastically
-- always annoyed me, but I'm like, whatever, whatever, I'm
-- fine with it.
I remember the before time.
I do not like the before time.
Oh my God. I remember doing
merges
with,
with the CV S
and it was just like,
-- it is indescribably painful and stupid is all I
-- can remember. Just diff like
-- source code we had, I had a bunch of tar balls and, well,
-- look, I mean,
that's your fault for not knowing how to use CV S or something.
Then like any time I had source code, dude, it got dumped into CV S like guaranteed.
-- No, no,
-- no, I was using projects that didn't have CV S.
I was, I was using projects that didn't have CV S.
It doesn't matter.
Then you make your own repo and put them in it so you can deal with it,
-- I guess.
-- Yeah,
that was the, I'm not sure my 46 could have run that.
You'd be surprised. It was CV S sucks. So hard.
It works surprisingly well in old hardware. Anyway.
Anyway, the, the other cool thing Lina said as part of this complaint about github
is he's expecting signed tags
to be the source of the
pull requests coming in, which is also really cool. Like I know using GP G sucks.
No one's going to,
to
argue
-- that honestly
-- I had GP G signing set up on my
desktop for so long that I forgot I had it enabled.
And then so I got tired of GP G for win or something. Oh, sorry. It's on my laptop.
Yeah, GP G
on Mac O complaining about some update.
So I removed it and then I noticed my sign commits broke and I was like, oh yeah,
I set that up like five years ago and forgot about
-- it.
-- Yeah, I mean, that's a, that's a different problem.
Like you don't use five year old keys but like it, it is,
I like that he's asking for this because I feel like it is
hopefully going to create some good discussions.
Well, two things I would say one,
it provides sort of a minimal extra level
of security that isn't that hard to implement.
And I say that in the sense of if you're a kernel developer and you cannot get,
get signing to work,
you should probably not be a kernel developer.
Well, no, no, there is one other huge advantage here is if you have a signed tag
you can't change a tag once you sign it
and you send it.
So now
if you update it or change it,
you're going to have to kind of delete it and recreate it, which is going to mess up.
Yep.
No back seats.
Right. Right. And so that's part of the magic of all this.
So you end up in a situation where
like with the current pull request model,
you could submit a pull request, add a patch to it
and you know, the poll request gets updated.
Whereas if you're doing sign tags, that should not happen,
it blows my mind that the whole it industry is
yet again,
rediscovering how awesome it is to have data
that doesn't just magically or weirdly get modified
-- when you're not expecting it to. So things like,
-- yeah, we call it Blockchain now.
It's
exactly right. And,
and I love talking with Blockchain people where I'm like
just the simple use case of now, I know that I have all the data correctly.
That's it. That's, that's all I like.
I don't care about the other properties of Blockchain nearly as much as just
I have all the data I need to have.
And I know that it's correct and I know
that it's the agreed upon world view of that data
-- and that's such a huge step forward. Yeah. Yeah.
-- Yeah. Well, funny enough.
So no one ever seems to talk about this.
I feel like, but the underlying technology of GIT
is fundamentally a Blockchain.
Yeah.
Well, the only difference between Blockchain and actually before git,
remember Cislo
NG Cislo
next generation Cis Lng still exists. Yeah.
And it did the signed,
it did the block signing in the commit or in the log.
So that if somebody were to modify your log file, it would stand out like a sore thumb
and that came before it
and
it just, it gets me that.
Yeah, this we just we know that the data has not been mangled.
That's a, that's kind of a useful property who knew.
Oh yeah, it's a big deal. Definitely. Alright. Alright.
I'm I'm happy with this part of the conversation.
We should talk about warnings and errors.
Well, and so I did a quick search in Google and I love it.
So if you search something like Linux compile W air kernel,
the top results are all basically stack overflow or related sites saying how do I,
how do I compile my kernel when you know it's throwing an error and it
won't compile and I want to make the error go away or suppress it or whatever
and half of them are answered, half of them aren't even answered.
And yeah, so there is that you can add that minus W flag
to build flags to suppress that.
But
again, yeah, if you're
like,
how do I put this nicely?
If you're compiling a kernel, a Linux kernel
as a developer,
you should know how to handle this
because if you don't know how to handle this,
how on earth are you developing for the kernel?
Well, no, I don't think that's a reasonable expectation at all.
I think there are people who have
a job which might be to build a kernel for a specific piece of hardware.
They might be a kernel expert. They might not.
My suspicion is often they're not going to be
a kernel experts because they probably inherited this somehow
and their job is to get a running kernel. Their job isn't to ensure correctness.
-- So
-- they should understand their tools and know how to use them.
I mean, that's easy to say though. You're taking some sort of ridiculous stance.
I think claiming that someone should have knowledge. They might not,
I mean, people might not have it and let's face it at the end of the day, Kurt,
if your job is to get a running kernel, you need a running kernel.
-- None of the other stuff matters.
-- Ok.
So would you let me replace the brakes on your car?
I wouldn't let you because you don't know what I'm
-- doing just
-- because I don't have some knowledge.
That's a ridiculous comparison.
If your boss comes to you and says, Kurt, you have to do this thing
and you know, if you don't do it, you, you potentially could get fired,
you're going to get it done no matter what.
I'm
disagree a bit. In that. If my boss gives me an impossible task,
I'm going to tell him he's given me an impossible task
where I need some other resourcing to do it properly.
I,
I think it's important for people to push back if they're given
an impossible task by their boss because part of it is,
you know, I, I don't know how to design an airplane. Right.
If my boss were to tell me to design an airplane, I'd be like, no, I,
I should not be doing that now, but I get on the flip side,
there's people who are in a situation with a boss where they, the boss doesn't care.
But also by definition,
when you're being asked to do something that you don't know how to do.
Dunning Kruger kicks in and
maybe you think it's not that hard, like
a perfect example. Oh, yeah, these are warnings, right? I just make them go away.
How bad could it be?
And realistically there's a whole pile of kernel warnings
that aren't that bad.
But yeah, you, you can compile a kernel with all those warnings and it'll work fine
like that. There'll never be a problem.
I mean, maybe I still think this is a,
a position you're taking that lacks empathy for
people who might be doing something different.
-- I think it's a
-- bit,
I don't think I've explained it very well, but I think the concern I have is that
these are complex tools
and
could they be made more user friendly?
Always, everything could be more user friendly. Right.
Like doorknobs are, can be more user friendly in the form of lever knobs. Right.
Something as simple as a doorknob that we've had for millions or thousands of years.
Um,
but I worry in this case, you know,
if a hardware vendor is shipping a kernel
and doesn't really understand what they're doing.
You know, we have standards for brake pads,
we have standards for plumbing supply so that, you know,
if something normal happens, they don't flood your house.
Right.
And I think part of the challenge is we've kind of ended up
with it being allowed to kind of be terrible and I get it,
we're moving forwards really fast, you know, break stuff fast, fix it fast,
move forwards.
And
I think I would prefer that over like a waterfall design methodology
where we would still be inventing web servers today if we did that
right, sir,
Tim Berners Lee would not have gotten this thing out the door in like six months.
Right. Right.
So,
but I also worry because the thing is software used to be the kind of
thing like right now I have software in my house and if it fails,
my light bulb stopped working, it's annoying but not the end of the world,
but like a self driving car
that is a big chunk of metal traveling at high speed.
So I don't think that's necessarily a reasonable comparison.
So for example, when you're working in a regulated industry, which for example, I,
I have experience with, I've worked with the FAA
and
some, some contractors who built
airplane parts and, and computers and things like that. And
there, there are very strict rules and regulations about how the software works.
Like, for example, one of the rules they have
is in aviation,
every commit that is made to
the software running on an airplane has to have a purpose behind it.
You have to be able to explain that purpose. Right? Like
now your light bulbs, which you've did, you bought decent light bulbs, right?
You're not running.
I went with Phillips Hugh after I got tired
of the light bulbs getting reset through normal use,
starting to blink.
-- I mean,
-- this is a great example, right? When you're buying like $10 light bulbs,
they're not good.
The,
I guarantee you the kernel running on those things,
it had a lot of warnings. Right.
But now at the same time,
like,
who cares? You know what I mean?
It's not an airplane, an airplane is regulated your light bulbs.
Well, they probably should be underwriters, lab tested.
They're not going to test the kernel running on the light bulb,
they're going to do some tests to make sure
it doesn't burn your house down when it fails.
Right. Like those are very different things.
Well, there's, there's iot ovens now that have apparently
tried to cause fires. I mean,
but, but now we're entering, I think where it's borderline,
there should be a regulated space where there should be
a higher standard where I think saying your software should be
compiling without errors or warnings and if there are errors
or warnings you should be justifying these not being like,
oh, if I just
the flag of the make vile, everything goes away, you know?
And, and so I think there's, there's all different levels in this and I,
I think taking a stance of you, there should never be warnings.
Well, well, admirable
is not realistic.
-- Well,
-- no, I never said that and, and honestly,
I think they're actually a real problem because
alarm fatigue and trying to separate out the,
the errors and warnings that matter from the ones that don't.
Right. This is, I mean, perfect example, I've got the CS A email, uh, all the SPF and D
and everything dialed in real tight.
So now I've got the noise low enough that I can actually spot real problems like, oh,
you know,
we had a payment processor where we'd set the from field
incorrectly and it actually showed up because it was like,
you know, about 10 emails a day and it, it's,
that's big enough now to actually show up, right.
Whereas before when it was, you know, 20% of the email mangled, it was like, well,
here's a huge pile of mangled email, like what do I, where do I even begin?
-- So,
-- I, I have a funny counter example,
I can give you Open SSL Three just came out a
couple of days ago from the time of our recording.
And if you read
-- the instructions for migrating your wait, open
-- SSL three,
yeah, they skip too
because I was like,
what?
That's right. You fell asleep.
Tell me 2021 is over.
That's right. It just, it's, it's normal. Everything's fine.
You know, my guess is they did it because
I bet going from open there were probably a lot of people who confused Open
open SSL version 1.1 with TLS version 1.1 and they were probably freaking out.
And so my guess is they just,
and, and
I,
I've dealt with similar problems in the past
where like one of my favorites always was
II, I forget I was talking to someone that was, that was explaining
how the ubuntu
release model, how,
how this version is not stable and this version
is because the number means this and that.
I'm like, the number is a date.
They were like, what, like, look at the numbers. It's years,
-- day, year, month. Were
-- they confusing?
-- You know, the Linux kernel odd even thing
-- maybe. Yeah, that's what they thought.
They thought they thought everything was odd even like in the whole software world.
I'm like, no, that is not what's happening here anyway. It doesn't matter.
So anyway, in the onsl instructions for migrating because they made some changes.
It sounds, it sounds good. I'm, I'm quite pleased with what I see mind you.
I'm not, I'm just going to bash them because I can't.
But they basically have,
they're saying disable warnings because you're going to get a lot of them when you,
when you start migrating.
And part of me is like, this is hilarious
and the other part of me is like,
I feel like telling people disabled warnings is dangerous
because as soon as you turn off the warnings,
they're never going to be turned back on.
-- Yeah.
-- No, it's,
it's quiet. It's nice.
That is a one way switch.
Like,
and, and I mean, this is where I think
what, what Linux kernel is doing is, is awesome because they're,
they're turning the switch the wrong way and there's going to
be a lot of people who freak out I think.
But like, I love it.
-- It's
-- in the official documentation,
-- the
-- open SSL thing.
Oh my goodness. Upgrading to open SSL 3.04 moments,
all 1.1 0.1 should be relatively straightforward in most cases,
uh The most likely area where you will encounter problems is if you
have used low level API S in your code as discussed above.
Fair. Yeah. Don't do that.
Which they've removed them, which is epic.
-- Don't do that. That crap is where everyone made mistakes.
-- It's like,
well, and in fairness,
openness still did some bad things like not checking host names by default.
So everybody assumed that they checked host names
because I made that assumption everyone did.
Anyways, in that case,
you are likely to start seeing
deprecation warnings when compiling your application.
Ok. Fair. If this happens, you have three options, ignore the warnings.
They are just warnings. The
functions are still present and you may still use them. Ah,
however, you aware that they may be removed from a future version of openness,
a cell?
Ok. So you're basically going to paint yourself into a corner there.
I mean,
unfortunate and then you're going to run the same
version of open SSL for the rest of time,
which is another problem.
But I like how number two suppress the warnings.
I would pause it that suppressing the warnings and
ignoring the warnings are effectively the same thing.
No, I don't think so.
I,
I think you can have a warning in your bill
blog and say we choose not to address this versus,
I'm going to make them go away and never see them.
-- I'm
-- going to plug my ears and
then
you end up with out of sight, out of mind, which is hugely dangerous.
-- Especially
-- insecure, remove your usage of the low level API S.
Yeah,
but this,
they otherwise they don't recommend disabling the warnings or anything anywhere.
So, is it just for that or, or in fairness?
Is there are tons of people using these low level API S because, like, I don't know,
I don't know either. It just amused me when I read it.
Yeah,
I would assume based on the fact
that there's actual specific documentation for this,
it's a pretty common case probably.
I mean,
how many, how, how many times have you built software with no warnings?
Like,
-- never, no.
-- Uh, the Hello World example in the bash cow
book, whatever.
And that doesn't count.
But it is
actually, you know what's funny is I,
I built something not long ago and I don't even remember what it was now,
but there were no warnings when I built it.
I was like, well, that's weird. I assumed I screwed something up because
there were no warnings.
Well, and see, yeah, that's a perfect example of we,
we're at the point now where we're so paranoid.
If something is actually correct that it must not be correct.
Well, it,
I mean,
we were anyone who has compiled software,
you're used to warnings because there's a lot of them.
Yeah. I, I don't know. I think
I just,
one of the things that really kind of
drives me nuts, especially around the Linux kernel is I wish
that there were just some good places and I get that pay,
there are literally places that would rather pay an intern to compile the kernel for
their project than spend even like a
dollar getting a professionally built kernel with support
that's because it, it cost, it cost a lot to do it, right?
And it's really cheap to do it mostly, right.
So I,
but again, this, this comes back to regulation, right?
If you are regulated and a regulator says, show me your build blog,
you're gonna care.
But if you're not regulated and no one's looking at your BUILD blog doing it right.
And I'm putting right in air quotes which no one can see right now doing it right.
-- Is it costs money for literally no benefit, worse
-- than money though,
because people have money,
companies have money. It costs experts, teas,
which they
quite often do not have and cannot hire.
Right.
Well, for example, something as simple as just knowing we all like you and I,
and probably most of our listeners know about github and know that github
made private repos free. So the argument of like put it in github.
Well, but it has to be public or we have to pay. No, it's free now.
So these people aren't even like there are still tons
of organizations not using github even though it's completely free.
Yeah.
So for example, this, this hypothetical IOT company, you know,
compiling their own Linus kernel.
Well, at least keep that stuff in github,
you know,
so that you have logs and change logs and when
you do suppress some warnings by tweaking a config file,
it's in Git
and I'll bet you there's a lot of places out there where no, it's, you know,
it's on a developer's workstation.
It's just, it's in the tar ball. It's fun.
So, I, I
will say that the software industry hasn't, you know,
blown up too many things or destroyed the world yet,
but I do worry with software eating the world that we are,
especially with things like ransomware that we
are setting ourselves up for a really,
you know, there, there's always that infamous like, oh,
if we have all this terrible software, you know,
we're setting ourselves up for a Cyber Pearl Harbor where, you know,
country X will come in and take over all of our lawn mowers and dishwashers.
-- And
-- I was just gonna say that
I, I don't, I,
the problem is
when do you nay say in this manner where you talk about Cyber
Pearl Harbor or I'm worried the world is going to light on fire.
We're going to end up in some futurama esque
incident where all the robots try to overthrow humanity.
It, it, I don't think
that's what's going to happen and I don't think it'll ever happen. I think
this is where we need
smart decisions and, and good understanding because like an easy example is
there are pieces of software like a car that I expect to perform
very differently than say the video game I'm playing on my switch.
If that crashes, if that's got a security motor ability,
I really don't care. And I probably don't have to, you know, versus
my car. Holy crap. That thing, better not crash while I'm going,
you know, some ridiculous speed on the highway. That would be catastrophic
or an airplane. I mean,
crashing
either, you know,
in Fairness Boeing 78 sevens must be turned off and on every 51 days.
I mean, look that is,
they found a workaround for their obviously stupid problem
but it, it, it works and you're dealing with professionals
that
there's lots of checklists, there's lots of standardization.
You can give that request and say you have like now
if you told people to do this with their cars,
no way, no one's gonna remember to do that.
But the airplane industry is very different.
Well, it's, yeah,
I mean, a perfect example of this.
My son on his computer, the web camera stopped working for Chrome,
like it worked in Skype and stuff and of course,
what's the solution reboot it and it goes away.
So now I'm teaching my son that we're just
going to reboot his computer like once a week.
That's my, that's my kids all the time. Hey dad, this broke. Do you reboot?
No, go reboot it. See if it still works and then come back to me if it's broke
and they never come back. I know
again,
like is anything truly bad happening because webcam isn't working honestly?
No, it's not. It's a minor inconvenience, whatever, you know,
and, and I think that's just it is,
is in the security world
we always try to try to put everything together in the same bucket and,
like the crap running on your home computer is
not comparable to the stuff running on an airplane
and pretending it is, I think damages a conversation.
Yeah, that's one thing.
I mean,
I love the idea of the CV SS temporal scores of how important is this thing because,
you know, a, a DNS vulnerability is a perfect example.
A DNS vulnerability running on my, you know, Google Wifi home mesh stuff.
Yeah, whatever.
But you know that same vulnerability running on
root servers that might be a problem.
You know,
those are two totally different use cases
and we generally don't make that distinction.
We're just like,
right. Right. It's, it's bananas
how that works.
And I think, I think that's part of the reason no one listens.
Well,
this
was it Atlassian Confluence or something has a bug in
that
code execution.
-- Oh
-- It's doom and gloom. And apparently it's just being exploited for crypto miners.
Well, I mean, that's bad but
I don't know but you just remove the crypto minor like it's not being used.
Like my first thought was
this would make really good ransomware because holy cow man,
like fixing like
the, if our ticketing system breaks, that makes my life not fun.
Like a lot of work flows de depend on that ticketing system.
And I don't want that data being infiltrated either
because there's some pretty sensitive stuff in ticketing systems.
Right.
Maybe,
you know, so, and it's just, but I'm like, oh, I literally read that and I'm like,
oh RCU, that's terrible.
And then I'm like, oh, it's just crypto miners using it. Oh, who cares?
Well, actually, I think there's a more unique approach to that is
my guess
is a huge number of these vulnerable instances occur.
-- Confluence are probably like abandon wear on the internet,
-- right?
-- I would not be shocked. So
-- when you,
when you own it,
you put your crypto miner on there, now you're generating some revenue.
Whereas if it's abandoned
and you try to ransom it,
no one even knows it's there.
How are they going to find out you've ransomed it, you know.
Well, yeah, it's like, oh you, you've taken my, you know, a bag of my garbage ransom.
Cool.
-- I don't even, who are
-- you
-- turn that off?
-- Like what are we doing?
But people don't even know because when you ransom something like that,
what generally happens is you ransom it and you put a message on the screen that says,
hey, I've ransomed your thing
because like I actually, I remember when I had my elastic search honey pot set up,
it got ransomed and they're like, oh, we have all your
data,
you know, pay us at this Bitcoin.
I mean, of course, I,
I was doing a bunch of monitoring what everyone was up to and
I know they didn't have my data because they just deleted it all.
But,
like,
you know, it's the same thing of,
if I'm not paying attention to an elastic search instance on the internet,
if someone deletes all my data and I don't even know it's there.
It really doesn't matter. I'm never going to see it.
Yeah.
It's
a,
again,
it's, it comes back to this whole what matters and what doesn't.
And we often don't even know.
I've been doing a lot of thinking about this,
about these confidence intervals over the last year or two.
And I think the real problem is there's a lot of fear of getting the
confidence interval wrong because if I just say
this is terrible and it's not terrible,
I probably don't get in that much trouble.
But if I say this is like a 0.6 on a scale of 0 to 1 and it's a 0.8
like,
you know, my boss might yell at me about that.
Whereas if I just say, oh, it's terrible, I probably won't get in trouble.
And the,
the second problem there also is actually figuring out
kind of how bad it is likely to be
is
difficult at best, impossible at worst because of the
really, like,
I,
I always come back to remember when we worked
at Red Hat and we'd have these horrifying vulnerabilities
that were like, oh God, this is going to be on the news we're going, oh, and,
and literally nothing would happen
and then some stupid vulnerability where we're like, oh, yeah, it's like a four,
you know, on CV SS, it's like, whatever, we'll fix it when we fix it.
And it's like on the nightly news and people are, you know,
holding senate hearings about it and we're like, why?
No, like,
you know, we're like, literally, like, stop, just stop.
Let me tell you about this other thing. No one cared about. Yeah.
And so I just, I,
I
guess what I'm saying is as much as we would
like for there to be confidence intervals and like,
oh,
these are the errors that matter and these are the ones that
don't actually categorizing them and classifying them would be so much work.
And I don't,
I can't really imagine what the benefit would be like, the maturity to consume,
it would be so high that most people couldn't.
Well, ok, I, I'm going to end it on. I, I've been thinking about this a lot and I think
it, it's,
we don't have the capabilities to do this yet
because we obsess over humans and incomplete data.
But I think the reality is
so something you're describing where let's say DNS is a problem, right?
You need to understand, am I using this library? How am I using this library?
Where in my infrastructure? Am I using this library?
And so there's, there's all this data we often don't have.
And so we like to just say, oh,
let's imagine the worst possible scenario when the
reality is that might not matter at all.
And we just lack the tooling and the data to make some of these decisions.
Because for example, if you're going to worry about a DNS library, you need
like a tax surface, you need threat models, you need to know where it is.
And this is all, this is all really complicated stuff.
This is already all into 1% territory of what?
Right. And the reality is
we humans aren't going to fix this because first of all,
there just aren't enough who understand the problems.
But more importantly is when you're taking in all this data and doing all this stuff,
it becomes the sort of thing like it's perfect for, for robots to do
and the tooling. I mean, it is coming.
If you look at a lot of there,
there's a number of scanner vendors starting to do some of this work.
I think we are on the path,
but I think we're probably still five or 10 years away from
having like the true ability to say this is my infrastructure,
this is a vulnerability,
what does it mean?
But it's going to happen
and I would pause it that
my strategy for dealing with this has been to outsource it all to cloud providers.
-- Yeah,
-- but it's just, you know, it's like,
like maggots and rats underneath the surface.
Oh, absolutely. But
as long as you know, that thin veneer of civilization and beauty is on top,
right. I mean,
you tell yourself whatever lie you need to, to sleep at night. And
that's, that's fine. I'm not, I'm not knocking that in any way.
-- I'm completely serious about it
-- more to the
point, like I'm going to be able to do any better than Amazon or Google
way,
way worse guaranteed. But the point is that
like,
this is all coming and I think it is
going to start getting better and the answer isn't like
hiring a bunch of security people or training a bunch
of security people because the problem isn't the people.
The problem is just we have all this data
or we don't have the data we need,
you know what I mean?
And it's like you have to just dump all the ingredients in the pot and,
and see what comes out
and we're not, we're just, we're not there, we're getting there,
we're getting there, but we're not there.
All right. All right. I'm calling it. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you, everyone for listening. Go to open source security, podcast.com.
Head up our show notes, use the Pound Do Ss podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye bye.