Hello and welcome to episode 36 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime.
Josh Bresser.
-- How are you doing,
-- Kurt?
I'm doing well. I'm enjoying some coffee.
Lucky you. I've caught some terrible plague probably for my Children and
yeah, for me,
-- everything tastes like potatoes.
-- Uh No, not yet, but I suspect that's coming.
Uh So speaking of crime,
which particular crime,
why are we speaking of crime? No, no one even mentioned crime.
We talked about potatoes and being sick.
Uh So
those children's toys.
Ok. So this is the iot teddy bear story, which is,
it should warm our hearts to know that there is a company
who cares enough to record everything you say around their toy.
Oh, it's actually worse than that.
Um Apparently their actual security on the teddy bear.
This is the one where the guy had it like
lighting up its eyes red saying kill all humans.
That is
awesome.
And also the mobile app is apparently a complete train wreck.
I would expect nothing less.
Yeah. And so then of course, for our listeners to top it off.
Um,
apparently they were they not only record all the conversations
and whatnot that the kid says to this teddy bear.
Um they store it on a Mongo DB instance with the default no authentication
and it was publicly accessible on the internet.
-- It's like
-- feature on top of future, man. It doesn't get any more exciting than that.
Well, and then my favorite part is not only did it get held to ransom,
but it had been held to ransom multiple times,
right? Because they never cleaned it up.
And so also multiple researchers had apparently tried to tell them. So,
yeah, this really underscores to me why we need the uh like cloud
and service based, you know, vulnerability identifier.
So we can talk about these things and, you know,
record them in a central database and, and essentially at least name and shame.
Do you honestly think
this company would have cared if they?
No, but hopefully, what can happen is, you know,
something along these lines and we can start maybe seeing class action lawsuits.
That could be. That's an interesting thing.
-- Well,
-- ok, but here's actually, so here's the trick is
I have talked to lawyers more than I would like about class action lawsuits and,
and things like this and the way the law currently works
is you have to show
generally physical harm, even just losing money isn't enough.
And so like in this case, nobody was actually hurt. So there's no lawsuit here.
I mean, I'll tell you that now
even your personal data being stolen
doesn't count.
-- Well,
-- one thing I've always wondered is, um, especially if these, I,
I don't remember if these things have a video camera or not,
I don't think they do but there are toys that do have video cameras
and if you start recording video of kids in their bedroom and stuff, I mean,
so that's a different law actually at that point
and it is conceivable
that recording audio from Children could fall
under some crazy child protection act.
But I'm, I'm not completely sure.
But, I mean, I'm more concerned about the fact that I just, as a consumer,
I want to be able to look these things up and, you know,
find out what the history of this company is and,
you know, have they been good and stand,
you know,
-- stood behind their products or have they just shipped garbage and then whatever,
-- I,
I think when it comes to toys,
it's generally ship it
right.
I mean, they're toys, this, this thing probably costs what, 100 bucks
and, and kids love this stuff.
It's again, but the problem is, you know, it's,
we're rapidly, I, I think this really harkens back to what Schneier
was talking about with the IOT security thing. It's, it's not a car anymore,
it's a computer but,
you know, with this huge machine it controls, you know,
part of it
and some of these kids toys, for example, can move around
or can,
you know, interact with their environment in various ways.
Right. Right. Some of them can,
it's,
you know, and the FTC,
I believe the FTC slapped a bunch of
those baby monitor makers that were totally insecure.
Oh,
yeah.
I
don't remember.
So, I'm wondering if that would maybe set a precedent.
It, it's conceivable. Well, it depends what kind of
rules they try to enforce with that, which always makes it interesting.
But I guess so, regardless of
the legal aspect,
you, you sound overjoyed.
Uh, yeah, because, uh, this is from January the fifth F DC.
Sus maker of routers baby monitors over security.
-- Uh,
-- yes,
but those were because the manufacturers were
claiming security as one of their features.
And so that was kind of false advertising.
And if I was gonna guess nobody touts security
is one of the features of their teddy bears.
Although maybe, maybe there's a huge market for this.
Maybe we need to create the security bear.
Yeah,
-- the security bear. That cares.
-- The
-- security
-- bear. That cares.
Oh, man, I can see it now. We'll, we'll make millions.
Yeah, I'm not sure because I know like in the US,
at least there's a lot of places where, for example,
you can record video as much as you want,
but the minute you record audio it gets you into a whole different legal.
I
do not know anything about that.
I know the laws are bizarre and crazy and they differ greatly by jurisdiction.
Um I know Canada is a one party, consent state federally. So, you know, as long as
one party of the conversation consents,
but here's a question is the bear party to the conversation.
If I had to guess there was probably some phone book.
Eu L A you had to click, I accept the conditions of this. Eu L A
and it probably acknowledges that you accept,
it's going to record everything you say.
Yeah, like those TV. S
-- Yes, that's right. So
-- that was,
and that got, I think slapped down too. So maybe there is some hope,
I don't know. We'll see. I mean,
here's, here's the problem though,
let's say there are laws that say you can't do this,
you know, all seriousness.
By the time you figure out it's a problem the horse has left the barn,
right?
Well,
the other problem too is there's devices that legitimately need to do
this to function like the um the one should we call it?
That Amazon Alexa
thing?
Like it needs to be listening to
like,
you know, you don't want to have to tap a button and then talk to it.
Well, and there's a court case going on right now actually because
the there, there was a murder, I guess, and they believe that the Alexa
recorded evidence and Amazon is
not willing to turn it over without basically a, a good reason.
-- And
-- so
aren't they asking for a warrant,
like which I mean,
I,
that was my understanding of the
case. Amazon is simply saying you need a warrant to get at this data which
right,
and, and obviously law enforcement wants it when they want it for any reason.
And, and so I kind of understand both sides of this, but even if you need a warrant,
that's borderline terrifying
that you have a device recording everything going on in your home.
Well, that's one of the reasons I will not get one of those devices or a smart TV.
Right.
These smart TV s just have a
horrendously terrible track record for security updates for
-- listening to everything you
-- say
they're so convenient.
-- I
-- I'd rather just stick a Mac mini or an Apple TV on it. It
has youtube
right there.
-- Yeah,
-- but I mean, so does
you know, and, and I get it because like the, you know,
the video conferencing features I've seen on some of them are quite nice,
you know, like the integrated Skype, it's done well is actually
-- it's kind of nice.
-- Yeah, I don't know if mine does that.
I don't think it has a microphone on it,
but I'll also admit I haven't put a ton of effort into finding out.
Oh, well, so anyway, anyway, here's
this, this bear is, is a crazy story.
So they're recording all of this data and they're dumping it in a mango DB
that was totally unprotected
and you said it was ransom multiple times.
And I guess here's the question,
is it an unreasonable expectation that a toy manufacturer
has security knowledge to ensure this doesn't happen?
And I know how we're gonna answer this. But I think it's an interesting question.
Well,
I would say there's an even a question that comes before that
is why were they recording all these conversations to a central database?
Because they can, I mean, that's usually how these things work is there.
-- Yeah,
-- see, that's more my concern is because from there then you start, like,
if you don't do that, you don't have security as many security issues.
I mean, that's
-- part of,
-- you know, it's
like,
well, it's like that we were just before the show we were talking about, there was
a, there's a local charity that sells lottery tickets for a house or whatever
and they got hacked twice, right?
And you know, the second time around they got hacked,
it was like all the credit card data as well.
And I'm like, aren't you not supposed to store that on your web server?
Like pretty sure that's like under PC I compliance somewhere.
It's pretty specifically states
thou shall not store this data on a web server,
right? The the rules are crazy to say the least.
And so I, I think with this, that's see,
this kind of comes back to that sort of nutritional label I want for my devices is like
you know, I know for a fact my ipad and my iphone o obviously they have a microphone,
they can record my voice, they can,
you know, I know um
Siri, for example, you know,
ships the data back to Apple sometimes for voice recognition,
right? It doesn't do it on my phone directly.
And uh my understanding is obviously they keep all of that stuff forever.
I would expect they
do,
you know, but, and so, but that's well understood,
like when I use Siri and so I have Siri set up to, you know,
I have to press the button for it.
I don't just say, hey Siri and then start talking, you know.
Um So in theory, I have that bit of control
and
as I say that
my
phone just
turn that off,
Siri
order
a,
ok, I'm gonna have to go reset my phone in a second here. I thought I'd turn that off.
You just proved
the whole point of this conversation. Kurt.
-- I thought I'd
-- turn that off
here,
but here's the thing I keep thinking of here.
I think people will make the argument that a toy manufacturer, it's just a toy
-- and we don't need to worry about security. What's, what's the big deal?
-- But
it's just kids talking to it, right? Like nothing that's not real data.
I suspect there were similar conversations about safety
at one point where it was like,
it's just a toy, it's fine, you know.
And then we found out that, like, you know,
child's first uranium kit is like a bad thing
and, and maybe we shouldn't be selling those,
which actually is a thing. I don't know if you knew that.
Oh, yeah.
No, I, I, I'm envious that I can't buy those, you know, make your own cloud chamber,
make your own cloud chamber
for uranium. Uh, so, you know what a cloud chamber, right?
You, it's basically a box filled with gas and you can see
as the uranium or whatever radioactive source decays
and sends particles through this chamber full of,
I forget which gas
-- it leaves like a little incandescent trail or whatever.
-- Ah, ok.
So you can actually see,
you can, like, see in real time radioactive decay.
Right. I'm, I'll be comfortable watching videos of that on youtube.
Yeah,
it's pretty, mostly harmless. I mean, if it's an
alpha
source, you
know,
mostly harmless then
that could be the motto of our security bear.
Oh, my goodness. I think you're proving the point here, Kurt.
Is that
so anyway, back to the conversation topic is the fact that
I think a lot of these toy manufacturers are going to try to blow this stuff off. But
at the end of the day
and this is true of safety,
you need regulation to make this happen
because let's face it if we just told
people
that here are a bunch of toys and
consumer reports released a safety rating of all the toys released this year.
Would anyone read that?
No. Yeah, exactly. And even what they understand it. Right.
-- And
-- they couldn't, there's probably what, 2000 toys released every year.
Well, even something simple, like,
what's the difference between a four star and a five star crash rating?
I know five is supposedly better.
But if you ask me, like, objectively, what does that mean? I, I have no idea.
I, I,
yeah, now that you say that, I'm wondering what that does mean, but I,
I couldn't tell you.
Yeah. Is it a statistical thing? Like,
is it,
I assume,
uh, five star is better?
-- Yes,
-- five star is the best. But, like, on what, like, are you less? I don't know.
Right. I literally don't know.
-- I'd have to look it up
-- and this is the exact same problem is,
let's say we have security ratings for products and let's say
your product has an 87 in mine has a 92.
What does that mean?
You know?
Who knows?
Yeah.
No, the thing that really reminds me of is, you know,
a lot of cities have tried to make
their health inspector reports more understandable to people.
Right. Because for example,
you know, you might have 10 infractions but maybe they're all really minor or,
versus a place with one infraction.
And it's like, yeah,
you know, the guy, like, did something terrible. Right.
In fact, I remember I was, I don't remember where I was now,
I was in a restaurant and they had their,
their health inspection report hanging on the wall and they had like a seat
and this was a fairly nice restaurant. And so I went to read it
and it was,
it was something absurd.
Like they had some improperly stored towels or something,
got them a seat and I'm thinking
that seems so minor. It shouldn't even be called out. Right.
But it apparently brought him from an A to ac and that got me thinking
like, what,
why do, why do I care? And how does that matter? And, you know, there's places doing
well,
there's probably some good reason for that though.
Where and, and, you know, maybe it doesn't matter or maybe it does matter. But,
I mean, I,
I was eating at that restaurant in San Francisco repeatedly
and I read they had their health inspector report,
you know, on the wall and it, it had two major failings.
One was, they were storing raw meat above the vegetables, you know,
so the drippings and whatnot could be a problem,
uh, for the salads and stuff especially.
And then number two is they were using raid
in the kitchen right around food prep areas.
And it's like, yeah, I don't want raid on my food.
That's
-- not good for me.
-- I bet bugs are safer than raid.
I don't know.
To be honest, I'd have to look into that,
but either way I don't want bugs or raid in my phone.
Ok. That's fair. Ok. We'll call it there right.
You know?
But fundamentally at the same time, I mean, I get that, you know,
food prep and the food industry is not gonna be always 100%
you know,
can't be super sanitary and clean. Well, it sort of can be, I mean, I've seen
you look at some fast food places and some of them,
the better ones are like really quite clean and well run or
more to the point. The automated ones.
Well, OK. Automation is special and I think this is
when security becomes more automated,
which I think is just a totally expected future point.
Yeah,
it will,
you won't have to worry about things like
this because the automation will do what's right,
you have like a sealed
system essentially that has known inputs and outputs and, you know,
hopefully doesn't have bugs crawling around it, both physical or virtual,
right? And I think
this is where it's going to end up is the fact that if you need
a, a database,
you know,
having the intern install something he downloaded off the internet
is less ideal than having some sort of system.
You click the I need a database button
and then it magically gets set up well, securely
and, and we will do what you need.
The problem though is you would,
you need integration between the end point device and the database like
do you, you know with, so
Mongo DB is a simple example, right?
You just have like a reader or a right only gateway
and you know, these devices can connect to it and just shove data.
I wonder if the devices had any sort of authentication back to the database or if
they talked to some other end point and that was shoveling data into the Mango DV.
I mean,
the right way is obviously to have some sort of other
end point that can do something like some sort of authentication.
And now we get into the crazy
of security of like, you know, each device, what you just have like a,
a certificate on each device.
But then somebody could like hack their device,
get the certificate off and use it to,
you know,
to shove in bad data and you can't revoke it because they're all the same.
So now you have to have each device with its own separate certificate,
which means that the manufacturing process, you have to, you know, just blah, blah,
blah.
Right?
And we just quickly go down that rabbit hole of like, well,
we've just reinvented online banking so that this kids toy can like
shove audio data into a database somewhere.
Right?
Oh, it makes me sad that everything you said is completely correct.
And so the reality is if they want to do this,
they're gonna do it poorly because here's the sad reality is Right.
There's no downside risk to this.
They already sold all the toys.
I,
I really would love to see what would happen if you went back to like Toys R Us
or something and tried to return this thing based
on the fact that it has like this horrendous,
-- you know, privacy breach.
-- Right.
So, I would bet you Toys R Us would take it because the large
big box, right.
They, they, they will take literally anything just to make you go away because
like refunding money
is less work than dealing with crazy people.
Exactly
with the online retailers and stuff.
So that's one of the reasons I buy from Amazon is their,
their return process is so painless if you don't return too much stuff,
you know, I've only ever returned
one thing to Amazon ever.
And it's because I accidentally ordered two of them instead of one
and they charged me for them by the time I
didn't even realize it till two things showed up.
And I'm like, oh, Amazon screwed up. And then I looked at my credit card statement.
I said no, I screwed up.
So,
ok. But so here's what I want to go back to though is you just rattled off
an insane laundry list of steps that need to be taken to
basically secure a system like this from an end device standpoint.
Well, not even secure, but just to make it more robust.
Well, I, I wouldn't even say it was secure.
At that point, there's still a lot more you need to do.
You're not wrong. But I guess here's the point is
how many people
can legitimately do this.
Right?
Like when you're talking about architecting a system for that level of security,
it's, it's not a skill, you're just gonna find, you know,
you're not gonna put an ad on a job site and have
a dude who knows how to do this kind of show up.
This is crazy, hard, insane stuff. And
if I was gonna guess
a toy manufacturer probably has a margin as close to zero as you can get.
And so over architecting something
adds cost, which means they're not gonna do it.
Yeah,
I mean, honestly, my only hope here is that we have a lot of major vendors,
Amazon Red Hat to name a few that are working on just kind of a vertical,
I like IOT stack,
you know,
in the sense of like these IOT devices that generate messages or need to get data,
you know, and then boom, you, you talk to the Aws or Red Hat system gateway thing,
you know,
that has back in data storage and back in data
mangling and back in data processing and you know,
all the, you know, integration with all the other shining dancing parts
and you know, you basically
just write the app,
right? You don't have to worry about the back end at all, right.
Kind of like, you know, app developers have,
you know, access to these back end services where it's just you like,
if you want to write a multi user game,
you don't have to write a multi user game server,
you just plug into one of the existing ones.
Well, right, but there's the back end,
which I think you could argue is easier because you only need to do it once.
But there's still all of the end points which
have huge problems.
Well, these guys now provide some development kit stuff for the end points to like,
you know, here's the library that you used to talk to it, right?
You want to send a message. Boom, here you go. You know,
your device will generate a certificate at boot time,
you know. Right.
Whatever
you iii I don't think you're wrong and I think
this is an interesting way to think about this.
But,
but here's so, here's where
my first thought is, is again, we're back to the concept of there's zero margin.
And so
you would need this to be so low cost, it's basically free because let's face it.
The alternative is these guys are just gonna roll
their own stuff that they download off the internet.
Yeah.
Well, and I think that's where something like, you know, like a busy box equivalent,
you know, the busy box, Linux that runs on like every single router on the, you know,
-- every single low end router on the planet,
-- it runs on almost everything.
And in most instances,
though these guys have basically downloaded it off the
internet and made it work on their device.
Right. They're not working with.
In fact, I don't even know, I,
I'm sure there is but I don't know of organizations that, like, sell
iot style development kits
-- that would solve some of these problems.
-- So there are, there are several.
Um, but yeah, again, it goes back to, you know, well,
do we do it properly and pay money for this or do we just have, you know, the intern,
go download Busy Box,
the intern is gonna go download Busy Box.
And there's, there's, well, there's two, there's two sides to that because I,
I, I've done this more times than I, I'm proud of. But
like when you're young, especially you wanna show you can do something.
And so I would, I would never buy things.
I would always, like, put it together using piles of random open source.
And of course,
the minute I left those companies, they were like,
what is this stuff? We don't even, you know, they didn't have, they had no clue.
-- They never
-- lost. See.
And that's one of my hopes is that as those companies,
the reality is virtually every company on the planet now is becoming to some degree,
a software company,
right? That's
everything that ships,
I was gonna say beyond a light bulb, but even light bulbs have software now, you know,
everything has software
spoons, spoon.
Well, no, there's those self leveling spoons that have like the anti
vibration stuff. So people with Parkinson's can eat cereal.
And
not only
that,
I mean, these chips are getting so
cheap.
I mean, like, let me give you an example is I took a ferry ride on a boat, uh,
about six months ago
and the tickets turned out to be RF ID.
They were little paper tickets that have an RF ID chip inside of them.
And there was like, there was literally no extra cost for this ticket
and it, the machine,
Raspberry
Pi Zero,
the new Raspberry Pi Zero just came out and
-- it's got wifi Bluetooth and it's $10
-- 10 bucks.
Right. Exactly. And that's the thing is the,
the cost of all this hardware is so close to zero now
that
like software is gonna be the difference, right?
And software is in some instances is zero.
So
security costs money. How do we get security into any of this stuff?
Well, my hope is like I said,
these companies start to mature their security process of it.
And,
you know, for example, at a minimum,
I would hope realized quickly that,
you know, it's better to
uh sort of outsource this, for example,
and get like uh an SDK from a major vendor than it is to like, you know,
make a random pile of stuff internally that sort of works.
But, I mean, in all seriousness,
I think without government regulation and I'm sure we're gonna have
plenty of people who totally disagree with this and that,
that's fine.
I'd love to hear what you think. But,
I mean, fundamentally if, if someone isn't telling them you have to do it this way,
they're always gonna pick the cheap, easy route
every time
and, and, I mean, I always think about
the, the self regulation,
like around environmental controls and things like that.
Right. I mean,
outside of APR disaster.
Yeah. Screw that stuff. That's pretty much
the
APR disaster. Like look at uh, I mean,
deep horizons like what are people gonna do? Stop buying gasoline?
Yeah, I mean, that,
that definitely had some issues but they also, they,
they took steps to mitigate some of the pr nightmare.
They were in the middle of
it as part of that
and
it's
right. I mean, and I guess here's, here's one of the questions is,
was it cheaper
to deal with the fallout of that accident than it was to do it? Right.
And that like, I don't know the answer to it. I suspect it wasn't.
But fundamentally that's what it has to come down to is
doing it wrong has to cost more than doing it.
Right. And today that is totally not the case.
Part of the challenge too is, I mean,
Deepwater horizons is an extreme example because you lost
that drilling platform that was worth several $100 million
if not over a billion.
And, but the problem is I'm guessing, you know,
the insurance company had a really bad day
probably. And
-- that's part of the challenge is
-- ignoring the oil
platform is let's shift it back to a toy
is
two
days
with the toy is there's no significant,
there's not going to be like a loss equivalent to that for the manufacturer.
Right. Exactly.
There's, you know, there almost a bunch of data, worst case scenario with this M
-- DB being encrypted and ransomed.
-- It's not their data. What do they care?
Right.
I mean, that's the reality of it.
Yeah. So,
no, it's, there has to be, yeah,
there has to be economic incentives to behave properly.
And I don't think,
you know, as much as I would love to see like CV E, you know,
common vulnerabilities and exposures database help with this and give,
you know, I would love to see a world of informed consumers, you know, like,
well, like consumer reports is done for cars to some degree, you know,
they've definitely made it a lot better but still people, you know,
there's lemon cars and, you know, brands and
cars with, you know, major defects and I mean, you know,
every time I hear of a safety recall, like what was
actually,
-- you know,
-- what you just reminded me of is,
so there's a company called JD Power and Associates that does
various, um,
Well, we'll say surveys of people who acquire automobiles
and they said that the,
the ratings of these cars and car manufacturers has
been going down for the last couple of years.
And so they did,
they did some research into being like, what's going on
and it turns out it's the entertainment systems. It's a software. Yeah.
Where people can't, they can't figure out their entertainment system.
So they're giving lower ratings on these cars.
Well, I've, I own a car that's old enough that it doesn't have that.
And honestly every time I interact with
one of these in vehicle entertainment slash,
well, especially better than navigation systems,
I never
use the
vehicle negotiation.
Yeah.
Well, and more to the point, like,
doesn't everybody have a cell phone now?
-- No, like, seriously.
-- Right.
I, I agree.
And I love every time I go to rent a car and they try to get me to take a GPS and I just,
right, like who gets those
people who forgot to buy a data travel package?
-- Maybe. I don't know. But that's
-- the only thing I can think of is,
or,
or you're going somewhere so bizarrely out of the
way that they don't have cell phone service.
But there's offline maps, man.
Well, I was gonna say in that case, you're probably, you know, GPS, you,
you'd be packing a GPS in a rifle most likely.
-- Right. Right.
-- You know,
because I can't think of anywhere on the planet.
Really that I've been to, that doesn't have cell phone service
with the exception of like, oh, there's like a three mile stretch of road, uh,
a couple of miles away from my parents' cabin where it goes through a little valley
and there's real, like, there's no cell phone service for like a mile or two.
And that's it.
There is no cell phone service in the basement of the Marriott in San Francisco.
probably due to seismic reinforcing.
Actually, that, that could be,
-- that could be
-- because I noticed cell phone reception inside
a lot of the older San Francisco buildings
is terrible.
But then you look around you and you see all those like massive eye beams and all that,
they've added a whole bunch of steel and stuff to,
you know, prevent this thing from falling down during the next big one. Right.
Right.
You know, I gotta say I was really impressed actually with how well cell phone and,
um Wi Fi worked in the Moscone, you know, and it was packed
and there were people just, you know,
hammering on, you know, using data for demos
and
cell service that I couldn't get the Wi Fi in the Mosconi to work at all.
It worked for me, but like, my VPN would drop every two minutes,
but I could like surf the web and do youtube and stuff, no problem.
So as long as it was like something that didn't
mind its connection being thumped on the head every,
like 10 seconds.
Yeah. No, I, I agree. That's like 40,000 people. That's amazing.
Yeah.
And 40,000, like heavy data users. I'm guessing. You know,
I would assume so.
So.
All right. Anyway, we should, we should move on. We're kind of,
let's,
let's go on to more,
let's say interesting topics. Google's e to email.
Yeah. So,
email encryption. Oh boy.
Yeah. Where do you even start?
This is something that makes me sad because this is something I, I was,
I was a true believer for many years of email.
End to end encryption.
And I'm pleased to say that I was one of the straws that broke the camel's back.
The
GP G.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
No, it's, um,
it's sad because I mean,
fundamentally nobody cares about end to end email security really
outside of like people with H IP A requirements.
That's it.
Here's,
here's the deal and this kind of goes back to what we were talking
about just now is what's the incentive to encrypt your email end to end?
And what's the disincentive for not doing it?
Yeah.
Well, and, and what gets me is part of the challenge too now is I consume email
on sort of three, well, basically there's three ways to consume email in my opinion.
And that's number one is through like a classical email app, like,
say Outlook or Thunderbird or something, you know, like a big,
full heavy like 100 megabit client.
Second way is a mobile client like whatever,
basically the default mail client on your phone or tablet is sure.
And then the third way,
the web interface. Right. Right.
And,
and I access my email primarily through either my mobile or my web app and I only
use a full fat email client like Thunderbird when
I have to send and receive encrypted email.
And my solution to that is just to never send or see encrypted
email.
Yeah, I, I'm, unfortunately, I'm in a position where I have to do that once in a while.
And, uh, but otherwise, yeah, I mean,
and that's the problem, right? Is
most of these web interfaces and mobile clients don't
have a really good system for end to end encrypted email.
Like, for example, you can use, um, X 509 certificates
on your mobile client pretty easily, especially on an iphone.
But, um, that
I, that doesn't really work all that well with the web interface ones,
you know. So essentially,
you know, I don't want to be, well,
we have these three different classes of email clients
with like three widely varying abilities to support encrypted
and signed email.
Right. There's no like plug in I can download for all three to just make it work.
That is true. And I suspect that's a huge part of the problem
in, in making encrypted email a thing.
Well, and then the other problem is, for example,
I know people who work at offices where they hot desk,
you know.
So uh hopefully they have something like maybe Microsoft
Windows with uh what is it active profiles?
I think is the name for it, you know, where your profile follows you around and stuff.
So. Ok, great. Now you can have your encryption keys but like how do we,
you know, now we need to set it up for the, bring your own device and now we, well,
but wait, now you can't check email remotely on a, on a web terminal.
Right?
Well,
and not only that if you don't have the key on some sort of like a card or a little UE
fob,
now you, if you have the key on your desktop and on your phone,
you've doubled
your attack surface against that key.
Yeah. Although realistically, I don't think anybody's gonna bother
unless you're like some crazy targeted attack like a bank or something.
Well, but here's the thing is nobody bothers because nobody does this.
If encrypted email was widely deployed and used,
I think you'd see a lot of attacks against it because those keys would have value.
Yeah.
And I think part of the problem too is encrypted email doesn't
really solve a lot of problems because in my experience,
the bigger problem with email
is validating the sender,
right.
Especially, you know, when you get business email,
like uh go pay this $20,000 wire transfer bill
-- to this weird account
-- in Russia and no questions.
Yeah. You know,
um, and, you know, make sure, like, and because, you know,
we see that kind of stuff all the time.
I mean, there's all those, what were they calling it,
spear fishing attacks against these, you know, companies?
I think that one company lost, like, $16 million or something ridiculous.
It was on the register.
I mean, that's, that's real money. Like,
no, it's true. But at the same time,
encrypted email won't solve that problem. That's my point. Right. That is all about
the sender validation
-- email problem, right?
-- You can sign the email. But even then is,
is this like e two email solution?
Google has,
is it actually gonna help with that because we still have
like key management is going to become the primary issue then?
And that's
honestly, key management is harder to solve than plugins for various apps.
Well, and, and that's sort of, I think why they basically, so there is a, um,
that Google, where the heck is it? What are they called?
They announced it like a month ago, right?
So it's,
it's encrypted email and it's, but it's all done on Google's end.
So they do all the key management, they do all of that
and they just display the email to you, right. And
so it's not
technically encrypted end to end,
it's encrypted like almost all the way to the end you know,
and just that final display
-- is clear texted,
-- we need to clarify this.
So the way it works and we'll find a link for the
show notes that that talk about kind of what Google has said.
But so fundamentally, the idea behind end to end encryption is I have a key.
Kurt has a key,
I send something to Kurt and only Kurt can view it
or verify it or whatever it is we're trying to do.
Ok.
Now what Google is doing is they're using something called S
Mime, which is a way to encrypt and validate emails.
-- But basically I
-- have some bad news for you.
They just,
-- they just abandoned it yesterday.
-- The S
-- mime thing did they really Google
-- abandons end to
end email encryption projects invites community to take over
that. No, no, that's e to email. That's not the S mime
thing.
-- Oh, no. Ok. Yeah, that's the end to end one.
-- Right. Right. It's so obvious. Right.
So, so we'll, we'll get the differences.
But so fundamentally and so Kurt having key, Josh hang
key, that's the e
email.
Well, to be more specific,
having a key on the end device that
you're actually reading and sending the email from.
Right. Ok.
So that in theory the only place that email is
encrypted is like on your device on the screen.
Right. Yes. Yes, exactly. And so what Google is doing though with their S mime
support and I suspect this is why they open source. The E email is because
they gave up and they,
yeah. Well, it's open P GP based,
giving it to the community and we'll see if the community can do anything with this.
But in all seriousness, I, I suspect they can't just because
we've known about this problem. For what, like 30 years,
how do I get the keys on everything?
Right. So, anyway, anyway,
uh, so Google service with S
Mime is basically you give Google the keys
and then Google does all the operations on their server.
Oh, I thought they actually generated the keys themselves.
So you just like clicked a button and turned it on.
That's what I
want.
I
don't
do.
OK. So let me, let me back that up even more. So S Mime
use certificates. So you have to hand Google
some sort of uh certificate in the chain
-- that they can use to. You can either I, my understanding and I
-- can go
has trusted roots now.
-- Uh
-- they have theirs but you still need and you can't just trust them.
You should have your own root in your organization for the S mi
See. And my take on this is I would just outsource the whole dang thing to Google.
-- So,
-- so OK, so regardless, OK, the point is Google has the keys.
And so that means
from Google's server to where it's going,
there could be some level of trust that you wouldn't necessarily have
in other instances.
And like, so for example, a reason you might want this is people talk about
there's uh H TT not H TT
SMTP, you know, SSL SMTP,
SMTPS.
And
is it SSMTP? I forget it doesn't matter whatever.
So
SMTP.
And the thing is though, your email doesn't have to go to just one place.
It can hop around between multiple servers on its trip.
And so
if your email isn't encrypted for the trip, every server that touches it
can view what it is. And in some cases you could send
or you could have an encrypted SMTP session to one
server and then that server could relay over plaintext.
And so you can't guarantee
any sort of authenticity
or even just secrecy
as email traverses the internet. And so if you're using s
mime to encrypt, everything
that changes the rules because now the email can
be encrypted as it's traveling across the internet.
Right?
Well,
and this actually now creates a big pile of security problems because
you have an encrypted email and you can't scan it for viruses.
You can't scan it for content
outgoing or incoming, right? That's something to remember too is
a lot of places, for example, have a legal requirement to scan outgoing email.
Like there's those appliances that look for like social
security numbers and credit card numbers and you know,
-- personally identifiable information being accidentally included
-- in
the point of
mime though is
because you can have infrastructure in your organization that can
still look at this stuff and figure it out.
Well, just everything I've seen of end to end encrypted email, it doesn't,
outside of a very few specific, like, high security requirements.
It doesn't, most people don't have that problem.
And secondly, the downside of losing, like, no offense.
But if you don't scan your email for viruses,
I guarantee you somebody's going to get down to
-- hamster dot Dxe and click on it
-- without a doubt
without a doubt.
That's a given, right?
And, and so the tinfoil hat in me says giving Google the keys is a terrible idea.
But the realist in me says this makes way more sense.
-- What,
-- you know, it reminds me of cloud flare, like as bad as that cloud flare,
cloud bleed breach was
cloud flare has now done SSL TLS encryption for 4.3 million websites.
The majority of which wouldn't have had TLS or SSL encryption otherwise.
Right?
And, and it's kind of,
I guess this is all of security is there's always some sort of trade off and
the problem is, and I, I keep saying this over and over again is if there's,
if you have to choose between usability and security, security loses every time,
unquestionably,
well, you know, outside of, again, very limited things. I mean,
the system has to be usable or what's the point? I mean, a great example is the, uh
you want to talk an extreme example,
remember nuclear weapon safety in the US and nuclear weapon security, right?
And so they, they had the requirement back in the, you know,
fifties that we need to make these weapons.
So like the bad guys can't use them.
So they had this idea of a permissive action link which was essentially like,
uh, it was an eight digit code,
um,
you know,
on the nuclear weapon and if you entered it wrong
too many times the nuclear weapon would disable itself.
So you can, you know, just sit there trying codes and, you know,
then set the thing off.
Um, but, you know,
again,
key management is hard so they set all
the pal codes to 000000 for like several decades
and they probably still are.
Well, they've actually changed now.
But, but fundamentally, there's a great example of, I don't care,
like from their perspective, security of the system.
Yeah, it would suck to have a nuclear weapon stolen
but to not have retaliate,
you know, retaliatory capability
and lose mad, like mutually assured destruction
-- would be far worse.
-- And
additionally, people
change jobs, paperwork gets lost.
Who's holding the codes and how do you ensure you
can get them quickly and easily if you need them?
Yeah,
I assume at that point you'd end up just stenciling them on the side of the weapon.
Right. And in this, I mean, this is basically the encrypted email problem of
when you have to maintain your own key.
It's terrible and hard to do. And so most people just,
they don't,
-- they, they take the easy.
-- I've outsourced as much all my tls and SSL. I mean,
I still buy certificates for my end systems just
in case I have to switch off cloud flare.
But fundamentally, I've, I've outsourced as much of it as I can.
-- Whatever, man, that's what let's encrypt is for
-- now.
They don't do wild cards.
And I use,
I
use
cards because that way I only have one certificate to manage.
Let's encrypt. Just get 37,000 certificates. It's fine.
It's, uh,
there's some use case issues in situations where
let's encrypt is actually kind of painful and
honestly, 70 bucks per year for a wild card is like, and we're done.
Yeah, that, that's fair. That's fair.
And you don't have the management nightmare of 37,000 certificates sitting
around
-- the
-- configuration issue. It's just,
it's a, you know, blank dot whatever website use the blank.
Right.
I
wonder if they have limits.
Like, if I had a server set up that was requesting, you know,
thousands of certificates a day.
I wonder if they would not do that.
I
would, I would hope they have some sort of limiting
something built in.
But, I mean, the thing is, you can legitimately have a web,
a single IP web server hosting thousands of websites,
you know, some of those hosting providers really pack them in.
Oh, they do. They do. I remember the days of running a web server with,
well, it was hundreds back then but it was very crappy sun gear and, yeah. Yeah.
Yeah, you just kept smashing them in there, man.
-- Yeah, I mean, most of those websites aren't seeing any traffic.
-- Right. Exactly.
Yeah. The vast majority of them did nothing in effect. I even remember back then.
You needed a separate IP per virtual host in Apache.
We had a machine with 300 IP addresses.
It looks awesome.
Oh, I remember talking to my ISP and telling them that, you know, with, uh the um
virtual hosting coming in, you know, being able to do
more than one site off of a single IP,
a major part of their business was selling extra IP S to people.
Sure.
Right. Because you want to host more than one website. Well,
IP S are five bucks a month.
Yeah, back when there were plenty.
-- Yeah.
-- And I mean, that, that is a heck of a cash stream.
Oh, I believe it, man. I believe it.
So encrypted email.
Yeah, I think, and honestly, I think
the thing to remember too is, is it is still quasi
end to end encrypted. It's just unencrypted at various stages of it.
So, for example, it's unencrypted on Google's end,
but then it's still encrypted from Google to you over like a TLS encrypted channel.
Well, right.
But I mean, I think the, the issue becomes,
you have to put a significant amount of trust in Google, which I think
at this point in time I'm relatively comfortable doing,
but it's, it's always one of those things of
when you put a ton of trust in one organization,
something is going to happen someday,
that will be problematic.
I don't know.
I mean, we've, we've been outsourcing high trust to doctors,
lawyers and accountants for literally centuries now.
I mean,
I'm always reminded, I was at my accountant,
we had to phone revenue Canada to renew my agreement that basically
my lawyer could like talk to revenue Canada on my behalf.
And it's funny because revenue, the revenue Canada call center, you know, he,
he like, he knows that the revenue Canada call center number by heart.
He's like dip, dip, dip,
dip
and then he's like traversing the phone tree in like three seconds, you know,
and it actually gets it to ring to a human quickly.
And you know, it's like, hi Ron
again, blah, blah, blah. And he's like,
yeah, this is so and so accounting agency, I have my client here.
We need to blah, blah, blah. And she's like, ok,
uh I'll need to verify his identity.
He's like, OK, the client's here and she's like, what's your uh full name?
And I'm like, you know, Kurt say,
and what's your social security number? And I'm like, uh
and
my s my
slides some paperwork over to me with my social security number on it.
Right. And I'm like, what's the point of this? Like this guy has all my data?
It's, it's a big show,
-- you know, it's
-- a big show.
But ok, but here's the thing is your analogy is perfect because
lawyers and doctors and accountants
have certain professional requirements they must meet
to be part of the profession,
right?
They are professionals, not because we just call them that,
but because there are actually things they have to do to prove they are competent.
What is Google proving
that says they are trustworthy and competent?
They are,
well,
trust
us.
Wink. Wink.
Right. But here's the thing,
they're like socks, you know, I know Amazon, for example,
has a web page basically listing like every single security control
they've passed and it's basically all of them at this point.
-- I know. Same for
-- Google. Right.
I, I think that might be a start.
I would also point out that, you know, even in the U with H
A and stuff, Google, you know, health data breach
and, you know, there's lots
but, but here's the thing is
all of those are specific in their own unique way,
but fundamentally
none of them really have hard requirements on say,
customer privacy or in the case of Google,
like we're not their customers if you're using a free Gmail account.
And so
there's a lot of squishy area here that
you don't necessarily have in the other professions.
And so II, I don't disagree with you that I think you can easily make an argument.
Google is trustworthy.
But I, I also wish there was more meat on these bones
that said
this is the way it has to be. These are the protections we have as consumers
-- as
-- people
with PC. I, and I mean, it's still less than I do,
-- but here's the thing
-- PC isn't about protecting consumers though.
PC I is about protecting banks.
Oh, true. And I wish there was more of it because I
trust the bank implicitly. It also helps.
-- Well, it lowers the cost to me because there would be less incidents
-- in theory.
Yes, that, that is the basic idea. However, even then, even with PC I compliance,
I get a new credit card at least once a year.
I mean.
Right.
I'm looking at getting a new credit card just for some online stuff I need to do.
No, no, I mean, I have to get one because it was stolen, you know.
So it's, it's crazy man.
There aren't good answers to a lot of this today and
my feeling on this and we can talk about this another day
because I don't want to go down this rat hole too deep.
But like security is a very immature industry still.
We don't have a lot of this stuff figured out and we have a long way to go
see part of my concern is,
is I think the technical side of security will
always be immature because it's always moving so fast.
And that could be
the business management side could definitely mature a bit with, you know,
actually doing risk analysis or actually,
you know, figuring out what, what are the risks,
what risks are we willing to take and accept, you know,
and pass on and then also maybe informing people of those risks, you know,
appropriately, like in English,
that is understandable.
Yeah.
No, I agree completely. You know, because like this, this
end to end thing, well,
sort of quasi
technically speaking that that Google email is encrypted, end to end, just
not
completely end to end. You know what I mean?
Like it's subtle but it's, it's from, uh, honestly, from my personal opinion,
-- it's good enough to qualify as end to end and
-- that's the key.
It's good enough, right. It's because here's the thing,
-- a
-- lot more usable.
Perfect is impossible
and perfectly nothing are basically the same functionally
and so good enough
is good enough,
right?
And I can think of no better way to end this.
So,
with a good enough podcast.
That's right. The good enough podcast.
-- The security bear.
-- That's probably mostly safe.
Oh, my goodness.
Yes.
Oh, it's time to go. All right.
All right, everybody. Thank you for listening.
I'm sorry,
I
can't stop thinking about that.
All right. So,
thank you for listening.
If you want our show notes or any of the other silly things we've,
we've cooked up today is go to open source security podcast.com.
You can find links there to contacting Kurt and I on Twitter.
We have a Facebook group. You're welcome to join, to interact
and
Kurt, you, you have a great day.
Yeah.
And I guess the moral of the story is everybody with an iphone should say, hey Siri
and, and make sure that their phone does the appropriate thing.