Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in analyzing how I say hello, Josh Pressers,
-- but I don't
-- analyze it.
You said it weird. And so I asked you to do it again.
What do you think would happen if you took the
like the last seven years of shows and stack the waveforms?
Like it would it be like my signature where it's pretty close or would it be like
my actual signature which is just all over the
-- place
-- your intro or like the show itself?
-- Yeah. The
-- Hello, like stack just the first word. Hello. And what like,
I kind of want to see it now.
There is a song where one of the recording artists,
I forget the name of it because I'm bad at song names and lyrics.
But
there's a spot where it sounds like this like
huge chorus of people is singing part of the,
the refrain.
And what the, the
the studio people did is they took like every take this
guy did because he did like some absurd number of tapes
and they put all the takes together and it created this amazing effect.
And it was really cool. It, it's a very popular song.
I'm certain you've heard it, but I don't remember the name of it because I,
I know four songs.
So
I'm pretty useless like that.
Basically, if the Beatles or Queen didn't sing it, I probably don't know what it is.
Right. Exactly.
So, that's, that's actually directly related to the whole pipe thing.
-- The Beatles and Queens or
-- no, the, the, the taking the cuts and stacking. Because
so, and, and the other topic too, like,
there used to be a lot of things that were possible but really hard, you know.
And the one thing I love the most satellite imagery
because I remember 30 years ago, like,
my mom worked for our art environment and she'd be,
she specialized in rivers and river related stuff
and she's going off maps that were made like
100 and 50 years ago by, you know, three guys,
-- a mule and a sack full of like food
-- with a compass and some twine.
Yeah, pretty much. Right. And they did some pretty good jobs.
But part of the reality is, is like river banks and rivers move over
well, 20 or 30 years, let alone 100 and 50.
And so she'd actually have to check if
like, is the river still there? Because it's been 100 and 50 years.
And so she would have to pay some, you know,
or rather she'd have to get the government to pay
some ungodly amount of money to have somebody in a plane
go, fly up there with a camera and, like, take pictures of stuff
and then they'd have to try and you'd use landmarks, like,
say a mountain or a hill that don't generally move that much
to line up with the stuff that might move or like,
hey, there's a forest there.
Now, there wasn't a forest there before.
Right.
Yeah.
Well, and you know,
now it's like Google Maps does it for free with like super high resolution, right?
And there's, and I was reading, there's actually a company now
that is
using satellite imagery because it's high enough quality now,
like the commercial stuff
to
index every tree.
Like, so it's not just like AAA mathematical model of like,
there's roughly this many trees over here.
It's like, no, there's like 2479 trees,
like
-- we counted them. Well, we had the computer
-- count it 10 years ago.
I would have been like, no effing way. And now it's like,
and you're like, I, I could probably do that on my laptop given a
-- couple of weeks.
-- Well, I couldn't but someone smart could,
well, you just need a good GP U and some ra M.
That's the thing, right? It's gone from like,
OK, in theory, we could maybe consider like,
I always love the human genome project because remember
the human genome project when we were kids.
It was like, oh, maybe in our lifetime
and then the technology got better and they're like, oh,
maybe in 20 years and then technology got better and they're like, oh,
and then the technology got much, much better and it was like, yeah,
it was done last Thursday.
So, you know what I love about the human genome project for anyone not listening,
who's not, like, very old.
Basically, there was a time when
all of the human DNA was viewed as a monumental task.
It was something we might do one day.
It was like a moon landing
in the sixties of we think it like it's possible if we spend enough money,
we think we can do this, but we're not 100% certain.
That's right. That's right. And, and
when we did that, when we sequenced it all
it was, I remember knowing some people looking to hire parole programmers and,
and I was, I talked to some of them
and I was just, I think I was just out of high school or
in like my late stage of high school. I forget exactly where it lined up. But anyway,
it was basically text files piped into pearl
scripts that were piped into other pearl scripts.
And because there was too much data, you couldn't hold it in memory.
So you had to pipe it across and all these pearl scripts.
It was, oh man, it was so it was bananas
and now, I actually have, I have a copy somewhere in my back clips of my genome.
That's why I just, well, you know, because II I spent like, what was it?
And this is a while ago. So it was expensive back then. It was like 250 bucks.
It's probably like 10 bucks now. Well, I think it's still like, over 100 bucks. But
the point is, yeah, you basically spit in a cup aggressively to get some cheek cells.
Mail it off to 23 me or whoever and then, like, a couple of weeks later
and, and then they send it to your insurance company. So they know when you'll die
that's illegal in the US, but
not in Canada
in the US. They passed a specific law
banning
the use of genetic testing like that to approve or disprove coverage in
Canada though. Yeah.
But in Canada insurance companies are less freaked out because that
the really expensive stuff tends to be covered by the government.
That's
right.
Well, and, and by Canada, I mean, the rest of the western world outside of the U.
I know. I
know.
It's like, why I know, I know it's so difficult.
-- Only one western country configure it.
-- But that's the thing.
Like the same thing like this, this 60 minutes thing where it's like,
-- ok,
-- hold on, hold on. We can't, no one knows what you're talking about.
So we have two news stories that piqued our interest
and I think they're the,
they're the same problem, but they don't seem like it.
So the first story is on May 20th
Pi Pie suspended new accounts and packages from
being published because they were under attack essentially.
Now it only last
package indexes.
Yes. Yes.
Thank you.
-- It only lasted a day and then they opened
-- it back three
days.
Uh, I thought when I looked at the,
-- I'll put a link.
-- It was like one or three days. Basically,
it was short.
But yeah, no, it's, it's um,
ok, but hold on before we go on.
And then the second story is a
comment
from Mastodon
where basically it,
it, a 60 minutes reporter
had their voice cloned
and then tricked a colleague into handing over their passport number.
This to like anyone who's been paying attention is not surprised in any way.
But they were. But anyway, then this,
this comment talks about how scammers are going to use this stuff.
And we should all have a like a second factor with our family for knowing
if we're actually the person on the phone or whatever.
I have that because I went through the eighties.
You and I are Children of the eighties.
Remember, stranger danger and having your family passwords.
I
had
one,
I
never had one
because you know,
somebody might offer you kittens
to get in their car. And so they would have to have the password.
But actually it's even worse than that because there's,
there's the V FX artists react crew, corridor crew.
Sorry,
that's such a good show. And they do have like some of their defects stuff.
We'll link it in the show notes.
Um But some of the deep fakes they do are,
oh, it's fantastic, like terrifying, basically, like real time deep fakes,
especially like let's be real voice is actually really easy to deep fake.
-- Oh
-- my
-- goodness. Yes.
Like I'm completely confident that I could replace Kurt with
GP T at this point.
-- And
-- there are there are deep fake systems that only
need 10 or 20 seconds of voice to clone it
and
hundreds of hours of you,
right?
And
yeah, so I mean, well,
and even the thing like the caller id is still up like people still
are shocked about caller id, spoofing. And it's like,
yeah, that's
just, I mean, caller, caller id is literally,
you know what it is.
Caller ID is literally as secure as the return
address on an envelope you get in the mail.
I mean, basically,
whatever somebody decides to write on the outside of the letter essentially.
Ok. But anyway, here I think is the fundamental underlying issue in all this
is
we are living in a time of unprecedented change
and it only looks like it's going to increase in
speed if you look at like all of the
-- signs
-- and not just increase in speed but availability.
See, that's the thing.
It's not just like human genome sequencing when it first came out. It's like, cool.
It's faster. Great. But I can't sequence my genome. Are you insane?
It's still tens of millions of dollars. But then 10 years later it's like
$200.
And I think that's the difference.
Right. And it'll be literally free in 10 years.
This A I stuff went from maybe someday one day to in November.
Open a releases chat GP T and then six months later
it
just nuclear bomb explodes and it's 20 bucks a month
now. And, and here's,
I think the interesting part of this
is humans
evolved
in a world that basically would rarely change the world
you were born into in the world you died in,
uh, in,
was functionally the same,
basically more than 50 years ago,
I'd say 50 years, maybe 60. And now, I mean, one of my favorite data points of this is
the time between the Wright Brothers first flight and a
person landing on the moon was less than 50 years.
That is
bananas to think about how much progress had to happen for
those two events to occur within a single person's lifetime.
-- Think about tech in the last 30 years,
-- like tech in the last
-- 10 years
-- when I try to think about how many computers
do we have in this house if we count all the
I,
you know, all the phones, all the tablets,
-- all the iot devices.
-- It's like
infinite,
infinite.
I'd have to guess at this 0.100 in my house.
So, you know what I was talking to my kids about this a couple week ago
when I was in college. So I graduated from college in 2001.
So this would have been about 2000 give or take.
I had to do a senior project and my senior project we needed a microprocessor for
and it was really hard to get one.
The only one we could basically get our hands on was a Motorola 65 02.
And it was not cheap and it was very, very hard to use.
And now like you can buy a freaking ESP 32 for like five bucks off the internet and it's
more compute than existed 30 years.
-- But the tool chains are free to use
-- it.
Right.
-- Yeah, that too
-- because when I think people forget like, oh you got ac pu 20 years ago.
Ep No,
-- let's talk about how much compilers cost. And we have talked about
-- a compiler.
I laugh at you.
We had to program it in assembler because that's all we had.
And now granted the 65
to
the instruction set for the particular chip we had like it did on one printed page.
So it wasn't like completely ridiculous. But still
there was no compiler.
There was no Python, there was no C we were writing assembly for our like one K of Ram
that was
hooked up to the chip. But it was
so weird and that was in 2000 and now it's 2023 at the time we're recording and
-- compute is so cheap and it's so available.
-- Well, I just got some Arduino
chips that have like only a quarter megabyte of
like flash storage on them.
And I was like,
wow, like,
that's actually a lot for something that's being a temperature pro basically,
-- they
-- run at what, like 12 or 32 megahertz probably.
You don't even know that they run.
And now, now I'll be back 20 years ago. Well, 2023 years ago,
I mean, if we ran that chip more than a megahertz it like, self-destructed because
nothing ran that.
It,
it's so, anyway, humans,
we exist in this world and it's so hard for us to apply
the rules of the past into the present because they don't work.
Right.
And I mean, I think about this when it comes to security all the time,
it's worse, I'm gonna interrupt because it's also, it's,
there's this fundamental attribute of reality of what's real and what is not real.
And the ways we have of recording reality in the past were things like stories.
And so we know people lying,
whatever,
then we had written down and written down is a
little bit more real because you can't change it.
You know, you can't just alter it without it being kind of obvious on the page
and then we had photography. Oh, ok. Well, like, chemical based photography is
very real.
Unless back in the original days you do some sort of practical special effect.
Like, you know, have somebody holding a bloody knife and
put the knife in half and, like, put it on his chest.
So it looks like you're stabbing them or something. Right.
But that's the, the nature of what is recorded and what is real and what is not real
is out the window. Now
it's just straight up anything that can be recorded now could be fake,
deep faked in real time, basically, you know,
and I think that's another thing I think about where like if I'm watching the news,
I know for certainty that, well, this could be like
an A I generated news feed on the fly from
a script from somebody typing in real time and not
like the traditional evening news that you and I would watch 1020 years ago.
And that's even happened where there were politicians saying, oh,
that's a deep fake of me.
And it's like,
-- I'm pretty sure it's not,
-- but it's happened locally.
-- Yeah, where somebody got recorded. But
-- anyway, anyway, so Pie Pie, right?
I wanna,
I wanna talk about this in the context of
pi pie because I think that's the most interesting like
pipe pie is a great example of this is a
packaging repository that it's what like a decade old.
Probably more than that at this point.
And
the world they created into back in the day where it's like, you know,
there's no name spacing.
It's global name space.
Anyone can sign up. Anyone can publish that. Made total sense. Because if you were
only eight years old,
that's it.
Creation date. 2015 07.
Awesome. I mean, good job to them.
-- Wait,
-- what do we
stupid question. I, I honestly have been using PP for song. What did we do before?
Oh yeah, we,
we cried a lot
and
manual oh
user local.
That too.
I mean,
I remember downloading random Python crap and just installing
it wherever I could to make it work.
It was terrible.
I mean, N PM suffers from this.
I'm picking on PP just because they're in the news but like they're not special.
All, most of the package repository suffer from this,
but they were created in a time
when, if you could publish a Python package
you were in like the top 10% of tech users probably
like the ability for anyone to do this was 0%.
Like there's no way scammers could do it because they
didn't even have a clue what was going on.
So, like these systems were designed
with this inherent level of trust in it.
That doesn't, it, it doesn't work anymore.
There also wasn't really a lot of value for Attackers.
That's true. That's very true.
-- Right.
-- And that's the thing. See, here's the problem is
it doesn't matter how hard you make something intentionally or
otherwise because let's face it pipe wasn't hard intentionally.
It was just, that's the nature of the lot of the technology we bought.
It's terrible and hard.
You know, it's like R PM packages. They're still insanely terrible.
Like, because I've,
I've been a package maintainer and like, it's,
it's ridiculous. It's so ridiculous. But anyways,
once there is value there for Attackers,
unless you make it
the cost to an attacker to get set up much more than the value they can grab.
They're, they're going to do it and,
and the reality is you can't make that cost so high
that it
dissuades an attacker because then you're going to dissuade
all the normal people,
you know,
and,
you know, there was the hacker news thread talking about, oh, you know, add a capcha.
And literally the response was like,
that's probably not going to keep the bad people out because capa
can, you just have a human, solve them.
That's right.
That's
right.
That's it. Like, I'm sorry, you know. Oh, what about a phone number? Well, again,
you can get phone numbers like,
it'll be tough to do this at scale of setting up millions of accounts now.
But for high value, tens or hundreds,
easy,
for sure, 100%.
And so there's,
that's what gets me is because I've looked at these systems and I'm like,
is there any way to really secure them.
And the answer is no,
there's no way to say that we only have good people in here. No bad people.
That problem,
identity is the issue there, right?
But also intent because
-- well
-- ignoring intent, ignoring intent, right?
The if you had a way on the internet to strongly tie identity
to something
which we don't really have, we kind of do with like
log sso login and stuff, but we don't really,
I'm, I'm gonna have to
disagree with you strongly because for example, I have an account with login.gov,
ok.
They do pretty strong identity
but that costs and again, it costs a horrendous amount of money,
you know, like, but, and again, that's the thing like,
even if you are willing to pay for this, which the US government is because, hey,
taxpayer money, not
a problem.
And more to the point, they kind of do need strong identity controls.
But even if you're willing to do like login.gov
levels of like,
Kurt had to go to the international airport here in Edmonton where there is
a US customs office and I had to talk to a US customs agent,
get my, you know, fingers and eyes scanned,
you know, they took my passport, driver's license,
blah, blah, blah.
And now I have a nexus card,
which I love because I don't have to get in the line
with the people who don't know how to take their shoes off
I know, like even if you're willing to do that, there are still cases where
the value of that,
of subverting that system is high enough that people do.
Yeah, for sure. And so
fundamentally, can we have a system where we keep all the bad people out? Well, no.
So can we maybe have a system where we keep
the most of the bad people out? So it doesn't become a complete cesspit
and more importantly,
and this is the thing I keep coming back to with things like pipe pie and N PM.
I think what's really needed is to have a steering committee
or a security committee or whatever you want to call it.
Who's like, oh,
this package is evil now kill it or replace it or
put up a good version or roll it back or,
you know, they take some corrective action right away
-- and advertise it.
-- They don't advertise it very well,
but they do a pretty good job of pulling stuff.
Yeah.
And that's exactly what I'm saying is, and that works.
I, I think we have to focus less on keeping the bad people out because
I think prevention is almost always a lost cause
because if you look at the history of prevention versus detection,
especially in the world of computers,
prevention almost always makes a mess.
I mean, this is everything from like antivirus
to, you know, locking people out of accounts
to trying to make sure that the bad.
People never do anything in these ecosystems like pi pie and N PM
and it's difficult but,
but detecting something on the other end and dealing with it quickly,
that tends to be effective.
Yeah, for example, I it just reminds me,
I actually need to go squat a pi pie package name.
No, like I need to, I just need to set up a stub package and grab the name
to protect one of our projects so that somebody doesn't
file a pi pi package with our project name.
Right?
-- Well, is, is what I'm doing, malicious or evil.
-- And now now it should be said too like
Docker Hub
doesn't suffer from this quite as much because they have name spaces,
right? You can't squat
a in a global package name in the Docker Universe because that's not how it works.
And actually it's funny because that's one thing uh if you
read the API discussion uh on the GSD tools thing,
one thing I realize now is anything we build at the GSD has to have name sway
because
there's two possibilities.
One,
we don't need name spacing in which case. OK, we wasted a few characters or two.
We need name spacing. That's it. There's, there's nothing following that.
-- We need name spacing. We have to support it.
-- It solves a lot of problem.
I think in the context of name spacing,
you don't worry about the identity problem because the name space is the identity
and like random weirdos
they can create their thing and the odds of you installing it accidentally,
-- I'm not saying it's zero, but it is much lower
-- for sure.
Well, and that's the thing. Like, for example, there's a typo squatting. Right.
And that's happened in the real world with them all the time,
like Bitcoin and whatever wallets, you know, where so many
typos
or the spell check, corrects
domain name or something or there's,
there's bit flips like we have confirmed bit flips now
in the form of remember those uh those certificate,
uh uh
logs
that were wrong and somebody's like straight up like looking at the certificate,
log, it fails and if you flip this one bit now it's back to being correct.
-- Yep,
-- for sure.
And I, you sent that to me, I'll try to dig it up and put it in the show notes.
But yeah, like it's fascinating.
Yeah.
So we, we have like confirmed in the wild affecting a real world system a bit flip.
Ok. Ok.
Before we keep going down this path of just talking about random weird stuff
like let's put this now in the context of a 60 minutes report,
right where we deep fake someone.
-- And they're saying, ok, you need your,
-- well, it's not just deep
and so on, but it's also getting the information, getting the right names,
getting the phone number
again. That used to be really hard and complicated.
But then like social media happens.
All that crap.
We all have pictures and voice and everything all over the place now.
-- And
-- who's your boss? And who's your direct reports and
your dog's name? And,
yeah,
-- that's right. Yeah,
-- I just realized, I don't know your dog's name.
I think you've told me, but I've forgotten it.
My dog's name is Atlas.
Atlas.
Oh, ok. At
Atlas? He's a very large dog and so we named him Atlas and
he is, he just had surgery. Actually, he tore his AC L which dogs can do.
Yes, for real. And they have this fascinating surgery
where they,
the dog's knee is like this weird monstrosity the way it works and
they literally cut the bone and rotate the bone a little bit.
Yeah, for real. Like, it's wild what they do. But, like,
it's been a couple of weeks and he's already walking better than he was before
he had the surgery.
-- Put your dog's leg on backwards to fix
-- it. Not on, not on backwards.
They just rotate it. Like, like what?
I don't know, like 10 degrees or 15 degrees or something.
So, the way, yeah, it's wild. It's wild. It's tplo, I think they call it.
It's completely nuts, but it,
it works and I'm very pleased because he's a large dog and
he likes to run and so he'll be able to run again.
So I'm happy about that. But, but anyway, anyway,
but I just, I just docked my dog's name.
So I better now I have to go change all my secret questions. Answer
my dog's name. Anyway,
-- I think, or
-- rename the dog to QX 4719362.
That's right.
You know what else to survive?
There's a, there's a, I love, I love Penny Arcade, right? As a web comic.
And there's one where
they're talking about secret questions and the one guy's like,
what is delicious?
And the other guy is like, oh my goodness, this question is so deep.
Like, how do I possibly answer this? You know, what is the what is delicious?
Even mean the other guy is like candy, candy is delicious.
It's like
it's so good. But anyway, anyway, I, I feel like there's a second side to this
and
the 60 minute story covers it well in the wrong way where this, this comment says, oh,
you need to set up like a second authentication factor or whatever
-- and, but actually use it but
-- you won't, you won't. That's the thing you're not gonna.
And that's the second part to that is
even if you say had some convoluted process with your family saying, you know,
I'm going to give you a secret code word or whatever.
We're going to say this or that or we're gonna talk about something
when you are under duress and if someone calls up and says, oh,
so and so was in a car accident and they're
at the hospital and we need this information or whatever.
When you put a person under duress, all of that stuff goes out the window
because
you are suddenly the world changes, you don't know what to do.
Your brain doesn't work, right?
And this reminds me a lot of when there are security events that happen, like,
especially at work or with people I know or something
like you and I have lived in the security world for decades at this point.
And so security events to us are normal, like we deal with them all the time,
not a big deal.
And it's always funny because like something will happen
and people come to me super freaked out and I'm like, oh, it'll be fine.
We're gonna do this and this and this and they're like, what?
Blah, blah, blah, I'm like, no, no, it's fine. Don't worry about it.
I got it like, go away and it's funny because
they're freaking out because they're under duress
and I'm like, whatever, just leave me alone, I'll fix this in an hour, like come,
come talk to me in an hour, everything will be fine.
Well, especially if somebody's never experienced that thing before.
They've never game planned.
They don't even have a basic, you know, what was that,
that famous NFL coach where he's like, if you're trying to make a plan on the field,
you're
screwed
like you're done.
You know, that is the worst time to try and plan and
-- come up with a decision like
-- sports and military training
and all that stuff is like that where the reason you
run plays 1000 times in a row is so when you get pounded in the head by some giant dude,
you're not like, oh no, what do I do now?
Like, you just know what to do because you've done it 700 times
and the 701st time, you know what's going on.
And this is where trying to put this kind of structure in place
on the fly.
Just it, it, it doesn't work. You can't do it as normal people.
And this again comes back to like
Pipi
has professionals working on this stuff
and I give them credit for doing something like saying no, no new packages.
We're just shutting, we're shutting it down
-- like that's bold
-- revenue.
Canada has now done that twice, once for heart bleed and once flog for Jay
where they're just like, hey, you want fire your tax on them.
-- Nope, we turned it off until we fix this.
-- And that's, that's ok. And here's the thing,
that's how you can tell
there are seasoned professionals behind this
because a normal person would not do that.
Well, especially the first time around it was like two weeks before tax deadlines.
I
remember
like it made the national news like it was a big deal here.
-- And
-- that's the thing like
this is where I think it's, again, we come back to that conversation,
I think of prevention versus detection
when you're on the other side of an attack
and response. Well, yeah. Yeah.
Same, same, I consider detection and response in the same bucket.
But when you're on the other side of this stuff having the ability to just be, like,
shut it down, like, shut it all down right now,
that's hard to do.
It sounds obvious.
-- But it's not,
-- it's actually more subtle than that because this is something I've,
I've been trying to teach my son is when you're rushing,
you don't give yourself time to think.
So, if something goes wrong,
you panic and it just all goes to hell in a handbasket
and so you can just slow it down
to give yourself time to think
and not just react but actually think
about what to do next.
And the, the case I keep coming back to, I'm like,
have you ever seen a firefighter run?
No, I'm
dead
serious.
No.
If you, if you do, you should probably run too as well.
And same thing in hospitals go to a hospital.
I have seen nurses run in a hospital, but it was for a good reason.
They were obviously going to an emergency,
-- but that's the only time they
-- weren't running from it. That's for sure.
-- That's
-- the,
and that's part of the playbook though. The one time we run.
Yeah. No, it, it is.
But again, these are people who do this every day like that is second nature to them,
dealing with catastrophe and emergency is their job, right?
They know what to do.
So, and then the challenge becomes though,
is most of us have the red queen problem where we have to run just to stay in place.
So how do we find time to train and to practice for what ifs that may or may not happen?
Like at the cloud security lines, we have general plans around
uh you know, disaster recovery which mostly boil down to.
Well, if Amazon's broken, then you know, Kurt has canned food in the basement.
I mean that II I, yeah, I agree with that.
You know, like I like to put it bluntly if Google fails spectacularly, it's like,
well, Kurt will try and move us to office 365.
It's more likely
-- Western civilization has collapsed
-- or Google
did something egregiously stupid again,
like
like the Google analytics for thing where I'm,
I'm explaining to my people like this is why I was trying to get us to fix it because
all of the old data goes away and they're like, can we export, I'm like,
you can export the reports
and not the data. And they're like what now I'm like, this is what Google like
if I could export the data, trust me, I would because I'm not a maniac,
you know, I would.
And then the default being that they only keep
data for two months now instead of 14 months.
And I'm like, oh,
I was, yeah,
because I was flipping through the interface
and I'm like data retention two months.
That doesn't seem like a lot like two months.
And I clicked on the pull down to see what my options were.
It was two months or 14 months.
And I'm like, I think 14 months should be the default, but
I guess they're being driven by cost cutting measures now
anyway.
But, yeah, so this is the thing, like, we have general ideas of, you know,
how we're going to respond to stuff at the CS A
but,
like, I haven't
had the time and space to actually run like, a fire drill every six months.
Like, I love it when we get these, um,
questionnaires from these companies that are like, you know, do you have backups?
Yeah. How do you handle your backup tapes?
And I'm like, we don't, you know, do you do this,
that and the other thing for security?
And I'm like, yeah,
it's like,
do you actually, like a couple of them now have said basically,
do you have disaster recovery plans?
Yeah.
Do you, like, actually test them once a year? And it's like, who does that?
No, lots of people do, lots of people. Do.
They have tabletop exercises to do that kind
-- of stuff,
-- tabletop exercise? But I'm talking
like, yeah, you can't really test it
-- but
-- chaos gorilla like Netflix where it's like
no one does that. Now, now, here's the thing though,
tabletop exercises have value
and
it's not the same.
And even if you practice a lot with the tabletop,
everything's gonna go out the window when it comes to real life.
But I think
you will find egregious problems in your process if you tabletop something.
-- Well,
-- and if you make somebody sit down and not talk
seriously,
when you do a tabletop exercise,
pick one person at random and make them sit down and not talk
and you will probably find. Oh, oops.
Yeah.
Interesting.
You never thought about that.
Another great table top exercise is
ok. So slack goes away. How do we talk to each other?
I mean, that's a great question because that's happened to multiple companies.
And so, for example,
we have a signal group chat with myself and some of the principal that I,
I bump a message to every six months just
to make sure everybody's phone number hasn't changed.
-- I mean,
-- that's actually a good idea. I hadn't, I don't do that. We keep phone numbers
in a
-- location we'll say,
-- but how are you going to talk to them, like on the phone?
Like some old timey person, text
-- message,
-- man,
you
-- know,
-- text,
maybe get them all to install signal or whatever because
then you actually know who it is and so on and
what not.
But this is the exact same so, so like, well,
I don't have the time to do these massive exercises.
I know enough, I've seen enough houses burned down
to, so to speak that. I know that like, ok, I need
all the phone numbers of everybody in advance.
I need all, you know, this,
that and the other thing in advance and we all have signal installed and we all,
you know,
these preventative measures that will make life so
much easier when something bad does happen.
It's funny because these are new problems. Like, historically,
if you needed to get a hold of people, like everyone worked in the same basic area,
you probably knew where people lived, we went to work together, go to their house.
You know, it's,
doesn't work like that. Now,
if you show up at the office and if the office burns down,
you just hang out in the parking lot until everybody shows up.
-- I mean,
-- that's true. You could have done that.
I've, I don't think I've ever had that problem.
Well, you have the, you know, the muster point sign out in the parking lot.
Right.
But, yeah.
So, and I think that's, that's a big thing is,
is that I hate to say the nature of reality has changed,
but some of the big parts of, like,
the nature of recording reality is straight up out the window in the last six months,
it interests me
because
if we try to solve the problems of today, by the time we come up with even ideas,
there are new problems that we didn't even foresee.
And this, I think I, I don't have an answer for this. I don't even have an idea
and we haven't even identified all the problems of today yet.
No, we have. Exactly. And things are changing faster than we can comprehend.
And so like the question becomes, how do human beings as basically glorified apes
deal with a world that is changing faster than we can possibly comprehend?
And I have no idea. I have no answers. II, I legitimately don't know.
I don't know how we, what happens here.
See one interesting thing is there, there are some, there's like,
see these sort of very generic pieces of advice.
I think that will always work like maybe
slow down and, and take a moment to think,
right? Get like actually have an A
-- loop and not just a panic loop. I mean,
-- but that's easy to say.
-- Well,
-- no, no, I understand. But,
or for example, when I mentioned this to my CFO, he was like, oh, that's easy. You just
when you get like that weird email from the, you know,
the CEO who's trapped in a Mexican jail,
you email them back at their address and you type it out, you don't cut and paste,
you don't hit reply, you actually like
manually punch in their phone number or email
address or whatever good way of contacting them,
you have to reach out to them.
Right. You don't hit reply on the email because the email might be spooked.
And I'm like, oh, that's really simple.
He's like, yeah, that's what we do in the accounting world and
when people don't do it, they get ripped off and when they do do it, you know,
they actually get a hold of Agnes in accounting.
Who's like, yeah, we didn't send you that invoice. That's weird.
No, because we get like, for example,
we get fake invoices all the time from those like internet search companies.
You know,
that's like a new thing.
-- We
-- have to
pay this curtain. I'm like,
no,
that's a great scam. People send like lots of companies just pay invoices because
I don't know, I've got 7000 vendors. I guess this is a vendor.
They're like, Kurt, did you sign us up for this? I'm like, no, I would no
like RSE on Google is pretty good. We're not, we're not paying somebody for this.
Obviously,
it works because we keep seeing them and
I've been seeing these things for over 20 years
and they're gonna keep happening man. And there's going to be new scams and
I don't know, I don't have any answer.
They're going to be phoning my
-- CFO with my voice saying, hey, you know, we need to pay this invoice.
-- That's true.
That's true. That is probably going to happen at some point.
Well, that's exciting.
I I feel like we're leaving this one on a terrible note.
I don't know what to say.
Well, even better. Like TD Bank uses voice based authentication. Right.
We've talked about this before where it's like that,
that's great.
And that probably works for most normal people again,
up until a few months ago where all these deep takes.
Now there's like, again,
quarter crew used the service where you literally
feed it like a minute or two of audio
and you get the voice.
Oh,
I
get, I don't know, buy canned food and get a bunker.
That, that seems like the best solution.
Yeah, I don't know.
Part of me wants to say like,
oh facetime and turn your head side to side
really quickly to prove that you're not a deep
fake, but
-- like that'll be solved in a month or two.
-- Probably.
Well, no, you know, ok, here's how we end this one.
That doesn't make it sound like doom and gloom.
Human beings
have an amazing ability to solve ridiculous problems when we want to
right to date
many of the most ridiculous problems we have,
we have been ignoring because human beings are also
exceptional at ignoring problems until they can't anymore.
If it's not chewing on, you
can
be ignored.
That is generally what happens. And so some of these problems
we will ignore forever because they will never be serious enough to really matter.
And, and
the ones that matter,
we will solve because that is what people do and people are good at it. So
it is interesting to me
to see what is actually going to come of all this because I think
humans will solve the problems we need to and we will ignore
some problems. We shouldn't. But many of them, we also should.
-- Global warming might have been good to solve 2030 years ago. That
-- one is,
yes. But right,
here's the thing this comes back to that humans will ignore things until they can't.
And we're getting pretty close to we and when we can't,
but then
I am
optimistic
that humans will solve the problem in ways we can't fathom today.
-- Sun
-- Shield
using technology and process and things that don't exist and, and look, I'm not,
I'm not gonna laugh at Sun Shield because that might be part of the solution.
I don't know,
but
I, I am comfortable
in saying humans can solve any problem. They want to,
the,
the asterisk is we have to want to do it.
And we have been ignoring an awful lot of stuff for an awful long
time and I think the bill is coming due on some pretty big problems
and all of this is part of that story.
So
I guess that that's probably less optimistic than I'd like,
but I feel like it's not a total.
Well, we're all boned.
Well, when you look at the challenges humanity has faced like we're here like,
it's not pretty and it's not always
tidy but we're here and
to put it simply, if you look at something like global poverty rates,
it's, it's getting better
a lot better compared to 30 years ago, 20 years ago. Like.
Yeah.
Wow.
Most statistics, crime, poverty,
-- like hunger
-- leaded gasoline. Like, jeez.
You look at that, those charts of crime in the US gasoline
-- and it's just like,
-- holy cow
do.
Right. Yeah, for sure. All right. All right.
I'm gonna call this one before we end up
in the weeds again on some other unrelated topic.
So,
thank you, Kurt. Thank you all for listening. Go to
our Security podcast.com. Head up the show note, Suzie Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag to hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye.