Hello and welcome to episode 89 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime and definitely not financial crime.
Josh Bresser,
you say that like we're in some sort of collusion
def
definitely not financial crime. My financial crime is the best, right? Like
so,
although these days, it's probably not as funny to joke about
just because
man, this whole A MD debacle has been.
It is a story to say the least.
-- I like
-- it.
I'm amused.
I like it because like most stories, there's
all these kernels of truth that
you can look at and it either is a giant mess or you can look at it.
And personally I'm going to take devil's advocate.
I think this is actually a really good thing.
I think the good guys won.
That's the way I'm looking at this, right?
The bad guys lost the good guys won.
I'm not sure I would agree.
Uh No, I, well, so let me, let me
may maybe, you know, something I don't.
And so fundamentally what happened was there was a research group
-- that published some flaws in a MD processors and and there can I
-- interrupt you?
I'm not sure I would call them a research group because number one,
they only existed for a few months.
And number two, they,
they really do look and smell and quack like a, a financial, like
we'll get
to,
let's call them a research group for the moment.
They published some, a MD flaws that we say are bad but not terrible.
And at
the,
and at the same time, coincidentally,
someone had done some major shorting of a MD stock.
And the beautiful part is the flaws that were released
did nothing to the share price of a MD stock.
So the, the attempt to short this was we'll say an abject failure
and,
and I guess it's also worth noting that this
was done to what Saint Jude maybe a year ago
and, but it was successful then because it was medical device shorting
and, and that one did work
and
the flaw
-- it could
-- kill people
well and more to the point though,
not so much that the flaws are more serious than they could kill people.
And heaven forbid that that actually happens.
And please forgive me for saying this,
but more to the point that those flaws would have a
financial impact on Saint Jude in the form of lawsuits.
That's really what mattered there. That's why their stock price tanked.
Right.
Let's face it.
The majority of these hardware flaws that we're dealing with in the computer world,
you have a very hard time suing these large
companies and proving damages and actually getting in the
car with them,
right? With medical devices,
those lawsuits become very expensive, very rapidly. So even if you don't lose them,
you just still lose because trying to get FDA approval on devices when they're,
you know, involved in a lawsuit and stuff that, that can basically kill a company.
-- Right.
-- So, so
anyway,
do you think the good guys lost?
I view this as the, the bad guys tried to short the stock, it failed
and I have a suspicion they just lost a bunch of money.
That, that, that makes me happy.
That would be the case. Um
So I
was doing some research because at first I thought these guys were bad guys too.
But you know what,
I
think they're not great guys. But if you put it in the lens of activist investors,
which is a well known, well established thing,
so much so that there's a nice link on the SEC page.
Um
uh
So essentially the concept is here is how
do we hold large companies accountable nowadays?
-- I'm asking you, how do we hold large companies accountable now
-- in my PC,
like,
fundamentally we don't,
I mean, that's just the reality of it.
Yeah. And, and in past we had
journalism and investigative reporting,
which is very expensive.
I mean, you know, the cost to do one article can be hundreds of thousands of dollars,
if you're paying a staff of a few people to work on it for six months, you know,
and all you get out of it is like 5000 words of dense
text that, you know,
10 people care about.
Right?
And,
and then someone's gonna point out and scream fake
news and then your story was for nothing.
Yeah.
So one thing that's happened
and, and this has been going on for decades is that
it seems that the e takes the position, but
we want to keep the market honest,
right? Because if the market's not honest, if the market's not fair,
uh the market won't work,
right? And that, that would be a significant problem.
So how do we keep the market honest and well, you know,
we could have investigative journalism and whistleblower laws
and things like that and that's good.
But more fundamentally
how do we economically
compensate or reward people for doing all this work?
And sort of one, an one answer is, is to essentially have activist investors,
which, you know, they invest in a company
and then they,
they take activity.
So in some cases, um activist investors have taken, you know,
large positions in a company
and then, you know, encouraged or even forced the company to go green, for example,
or to, you know, pull out of
really uh unsavory labor markets in like Southeast Asia, you know,
where you have like little Children making clothes or whatever.
Um,
and the flip side of this is too. Well, for example, if you
have caught a company doing something naughty,
how essentially do you make money from that knowledge legally?
Right. So not insider trading, let's be clear.
And one of the things you can do and that has
been done in the past is this short selling of a company
and then releasing the news. That is
hopefully true.
I mean, if it's not true, then we're into a whole other legal pile of worms.
-- And actually,
-- if it's not true, it's illegal.
And I, I did some research because when, when this happened, I was like,
this can't be legal.
This has got to count as insider trading and it doesn't,
right. It's totally legal what these guys did with a MD. And
I understand what you're saying.
And I think,
-- well, and
-- here's what I would say, I would say the market reacted correctly
because
although let me put it this way, if they had come to me,
if these guys had come to me in advance.
Uh And this is assuming my, my scope of CV coverage were to include a MD,
which it does not, I would send them to Miter.
But for the sake of argument,
let's say I was able to assign them or I was in the position to assign CV S yes or no.
For this,
my response would be,
these are kind of stupid flaws,
but they are technically security vulnerabilities, right?
These are trust boundary issues. Now, granted, you
already have to have a high level of trust and access to the system.
But fundamentally what they described are actually
valid security vulnerabilities with the proviso,
you need a really high level of access you need like, you know,
there's a whole bunch of, of pre existing conditions to exploit this
and essentially,
um it's not something that allows you to like gain access and to, you know, like
remotely take over a system.
It's more something that once you're in, you can then hide very effectively,
you know, which we don't want, right.
So
I would have basically what I'm
saying is these were legitimate security vulnerabilities
for the purposes of CV E counting.
They should get CV S unless there's some details missing where, you know,
this is just not exploitable.
And in that respect, I would say the market reacted correctly and that yes,
these are vulnerabilities and
no, they're really not going to impact am D's bottom line,
right? Nobody's going to really be able to sue
nobody.
I mean, will, will people be affected by this flaw potentially? Yes,
but it would only be part of a really specific targeted attack.
You know,
this is not some widespread like flash zero day drive
-- by web attack that takes over 10 million
-- PC.
And the thing is you need to be route essentially to exploit these and
let's face it if your system has an attacker running around his route.
You've
got,
you've got some other problem.
The challenge is how do you get that hardware back to a known good state?
And with these attacks you may not be able to
see that. That's where these become a problem.
I agree. I agree.
Like, every time somebody gets rude on the system,
I don't have to throw the hardware away.
That would get
expensive
and troublesome.
That's why you just use the cloud.
Not my problem.
Yeah. Well, yeah, and
that's one of the reasons I do is it's someone else's problem. Right. You know.
But, uh, so in this case, I wouldn't say that the good guys won or lost.
I would say that,
um,
I, I would definitely say to some degree this is sort of, how do I put it?
I don't want to say unsavory because that's sort of a moral judgment almost.
This is not something I'm a huge fan of because I wish we had better ways
to express this information and to, you know, reward people for this information,
but the reality is we don't.
Right. I mean, let's face it. Journalism is dying.
I'm, I'm comfortable calling this unsavory.
I, I think
trying to short someone's stock
-- for
-- stupid
question. Why didn't A MD document these flaws somewhere?
-- Saying, oh, by the way,
-- if,
what do you mean, why didn't they document them
-- in their
-- documentation?
They could have said, oh, by the way, if somebody gets rude, they can, like,
go monkey with the bio
-- in this way that makes it very hard
-- to
know
about
prior
to this report.
-- I would say they should,
-- I mean,
the
argument that yes, if, if an attacker breaks in, they can potentially
modify the bios or something like that.
I mean, in theory they shouldn't be able to, I, I have a suspicion.
A MD didn't know this was a plausible attack.
I mean, outside of the realm of crazy research. Right.
Um, I, you know,
part of me would say that's kind of as we're learning from specter and meltdown.
I,
I think it is maybe time for hardware vendors to do a
little bit more security than they have been doing in the past.
Um, I don't know if you saw,
but Microsoft has just offered a rather significant set of bounties for meltdown
or was it specter or both type related flaws in their, in their products?
Uh, like if you,
yeah, if you can show valid side channel attacks, I think the,
the maximum reward was like a quarter million or something.
Like it's,
it's a decent amount of money.
Well, I mean, they're,
they're already there for hyper V flaws also where
if you can break out of hyper V guests,
you can make a ton of cash.
But at the same time, like, let's face it, these are the kind of bugs
that are,
they're very, I mean, I I think even calling them very difficult is,
is drastically downplaying what's going on here.
I mean, the work that has to be done and the knowledge required
to figure this stuff out is crazy.
Well, it's not just that they're hard to exploit.
It's that
the, even if you do achieve exploitation,
the,
the information you're getting may or may not be terribly useful,
you know,
it's one thing to get remote code execution in a remote
server that's clearly easy to then leverage for something else.
But
yeah, some of these side channel attacks, you know, you have to,
you have to be on a system that's also processing
someone else's sensitive data and you have to know,
have some context for that data.
Like,
you know, if somebody gave me a pile of patient records,
it's not like I'm a bad guy and I don't know how to monetize that,
you know, I don't know what to do with somebody's uh cancer report or whatever,
like how to make money off that.
Um
So, yeah, no, I would say in this case,
I'm not sure the bad guys won or lost necessarily.
I think this was a valid
uh sort of investor activist activity.
Uh Again, not super awesome.
No, man. No, I'm gonna call no.
And here's my reasoning behind it is in the security world, there's kind of a, a set of
acceptable behavior we'll say,
can we qualify that as the information
security world because there's that overlap here.
Right.
Yes. Yes. We'll say kind of in the world of CV S. How does that sound?
There are certain,
I guess, expectations and behaviors that have become the norm
and telling a company giving them 24 hours to respond and then shorting their stock
that is in no way
or they shorted the stock in advance.
Well, ok. Right. But you, you, you get the point.
Well, ok, They were probably hoping to sell quickly, right. Like
that is not acceptable behavior. If someone did that to us, we would be livid
and we would probably go on our podcast
and complain incessantly about what they did.
Let me play devil's advocate.
Why is this behavior unacceptable?
Because let me just further playing devil's advocate.
If you'd given a MD 90 days to deal with it.
-- Could they have,
-- I don't know the answer to that.
-- What
-- about a year?
What about a week?
Look? Look?
I mean, we, well, we can agree that being that it's CPU hardware,
-- it's not like they can pivot on a diamond and release a patch
-- to.
No, it's not about the patch.
Even though it's about just understanding what the heck is going on.
As a MD.
I would have simply replied that, yeah, these are technically true,
but here's why you don't need to worry about it.
But no,
-- you and
-- we may or may not
make that determination in 24 hours though.
This is incredibly complicated stuff going on here
and, and I think it took even some of the smartest people,
I've paid attention to more than 24 hours to come up with
their stances on this, of not a huge deal.
And so I look, I,
if, if they would have told a MD
and said, we'll give you say 30 days even
and if a MD had done nothing
then great, right. Make a big deal
and, and do your thing.
But if you report something to an organization, I think there's a certain amount of
just reasonable time you need to give them
and if they're co-operative and they're interested in working with you,
that's the right way to do it.
What, what these people did I don't think is ok.
Well, see, part of the problem is
we're looking at this from the lens of information security.
But if you look at this from the lens of, you know, investment,
right?
I, I, I'm sorry, but as I understand the rules of investing,
if it's not blatantly illegal, you and you can make money doing it, you do it.
And that's the accepted norm over there.
And realistically, if you look at the, um,
what was interesting to me over the CTS? Was it, is there called CTS Labs?
Right. I think that was the name of the, uh,
of the company that did this,
the, um, the CFO is, uh, this guy who, you know,
clearly has a background in finance and apparently, you know,
related to this kind of activity.
I mean,
so he's coming from, I'm, I'm assuming he's coming from a finance background where,
yeah, like if it's not blatantly illegal then cool. You know, and
from his perspective he's saying, ok, so we have some legitimate flaw. Ok.
Granted, it's very hard to exploit and not super impactful but,
you know, maybe the market decides it is a problem. Maybe they don't.
In this case, the market decided. Yeah, it's not really a problem. And,
well, so it didn't work out for them this time.
My question is, do you think they're going to do this again?
These guys might not just because they probably got burnt pretty good here.
My guess is they had investors and they were,
they were playing up how much money they were
going to make and they probably made zero dollars.
Well, they lost money because it costs money to short
stocks. Right. You, you have to pay to borrow the stock from somebody.
The longer you borrow it, the more you pay
-- it's complicated. I know we'll say, ok, we'll say they lost money
-- probably
when you consider also their time and effort.
Yeah. All right. Right. They, they paid people no doubt.
But here's the thing I keep coming up with is
it is not illegal,
but just because something isn't illegal
doesn't mean it's ok to do.
I mean,
could you imagine what the security world would look like if
everybody was just like popping zero days and shorting stock,
it would be insane.
I'm in the open
source world where that's not really a problem
because
the majority of the open source code we have,
you know what I mean? Like, yeah, so to be brutally honest,
I'm not so sure this would be a terrible thing,
especially for some of those commercial vendors
that are very hard to hold accountable.
But more to the point like a Nintendo is a
great example because remember Nintendo had their forums and their whole
systems hacked like what was it like four or five times
in a row over a period of like 23 years,
they got denial of service. They, you remember that whole saga a few years ago?
And like as far as I remember, it did nothing to their stock price of meaning,
you know.
-- No,
-- no, because it, it didn't affect their what they do.
And so I suspect
like this one is interesting because this is kind of to the best of my knowledge.
This is the first time this has happened
now. It happened a year ago.
Well, no, no, no, I'm talking about a pure where it was.
It's um ST Jude is a medical company and I would say again,
the rules for medical devices
are different, but especially the legal landscape for medical devices
because here's the thing as a medical company.
Like if you get tied up in lawsuits and you can get your products approved,
then you're, you're
like, you're basically being held hostage in a very effective way.
Right.
-- I
-- mean,
but that doesn't apply to
argument
with any, I
mean,
a MD.
Well, ok, let me put it this way.
There's like, what, 30 some odd lawsuits up against Intel. Currently,
Intel is still shipping fresh silicon.
Right. There's no,
-- there's no like FDA approval. They have to go through
-- to see
what
I see what you're saying. They can still sell even if they have a lawsuit.
Yeah.
Or many lawsuits.
See, and, and with a medical company that becomes much more of a problem. So
I would say,
uh I'm going to ignore the medical industry and devices for now because a,
they're a flaming train wreck and b
there's that whole other set of considerations legally, right?
So I'm just going to go with like the pure, like the,
you know, the AM DS Intels, the, the traditional software,
I think what's interesting to me is this is as
far as I know the first time that this has happened
in sort of the normal software world, hardware world.
And apparently the market,
I don't know if the market necessarily reacted
correctly or simply didn't react at all.
Right, because that's the other option, right?
Most people read this like, I don't get it, whatever, who cares?
A and BS fundamentals are great, you know,
Bitcoin is making their GP us fly off the shelf.
So like like straight up, right? Who cares?
So, my thinking is,
are we going to see more of this and how are the markets going to react?
And I suspect
uh
if you can make money doing this, people will definitely try
that. That's just a fundamental thing, right?
If people see a new scam, somebody will try.
That is probably true.
-- Now,
-- the question is, will that actually work? And
I'm guessing
probably not because we have this huge history of
just for a whole pile of reasons.
It's basically impossible to actually sue a software company for damages.
It, it is. And, and I also want to clarify one thing at this point is
I don't think either of us believe this behavior should be illegal.
I do think it is unethical, but I think it needs to be legal and before we die, I,
I think that that's a really important point we should, we should discuss as well is
here's the thing.
If, if,
if behavior like this was considered insider
trading and you couldn't trade in securities
that would put people like security researchers at a
major disadvantage just in terms of living their life
because all of a sudden,
you would have tons of insider knowledge
about any product or company you were investigating
-- and that would be awful.
-- Well, and this is the whole point, right?
People are supposed to be allowed to use expert knowledge and expert,
you know, methodology to divine the future performance and price of a company.
That's the whole point of the stock market.
Right.
You know, is we have all these different actors
pricing the market and, you know, coming to a consensus
and, and
to be clear, it doesn't always work.
Uh, there's been some epic failures
but by and large, I mean, it's the least worst system we've found so far.
Right. Kind of like democracy.
Um, well, it's certainly better than a command and control economy,
like a variety of, sort of communist states tried,
you know, the, the,
the quality of life index over in those places wasn't so awesome.
Um,
what's so, and see what's interesting to me is
because I was also poking on the SEC website.
So there's definitely ways to file complaints and report fraud.
Well, security flaws don't fall under that.
Right. This isn't fraud. This isn't, you know,
so the question becomes, like I said, how do we,
if a vendor doesn't behave in a way, like, say Microsoft where they, like,
run a big bug bounty with like real cash, like real cash amounts.
I'm not talking like five grand because let's face it. Right. For a skilled hacker
to spend a month working on something or two months,
working on something and have a possibility, not the guarantee,
but the possibility of maybe only earning upwards of
like one or two grand or five grand.
It's just not worth it.
Right.
You know,
uh, to put it bluntly, you can sell something like that to the bad guys for more money.
Right. And
that's what I really am impressed with a lot of these, you know,
new bug boundaries is the amount of money involved is enough
that you can actually make a living doing this and,
you know,
do the right thing but not all vendors
do these bug bounties and we, and I don't think we can or should expect them to
because I would say there's also that, like you said, that ethical component of,
you know, like
if I spot a flaw
in a crane,
you know, I'm going to report it because I don't want the crane to fall down.
I'm not going to report it because I want to make some money
on the flip side. If I'm a crane inspector, you know,
then I'm incentivized
to make a living at this.
So I, I think really what it boils down to is, yeah, this is,
I don't know that I would call this behavior unethical.
-- It would, I would, like I said, it's
-- no, II, I think it's unethical.
It's distasteful in a way.
But I don't know that there's a better way. I don't know that there's a better way.
There is a better way. Look.
So here's the thing, if you're a security research company,
which they're clearly not because they spun themselves
up just for the sake of doing this.
Ok?
When you create yourself
just for the purpose of shorting someone else's stock
that is unethical,
right? Because
their goal was to make a mess for a MD, right?
Their goal wasn't to make the world a better place.
Their goal was to make a mess for a MD and profit off of it.
Arguing devil's advocate from an investor perception.
Their goal was to get the market to price the
stock correctly and in doing so make money from it.
Look, I'm, if,
if, if I have to argue that investors are ethical,
we're in trouble.
Ok? Because they're not.
So I just,
I, I definitely don't like it because it's very messy. But here's the problem.
Fundamentally,
people need
to pay the rent and their bills.
How do we
allow them to monetize this information?
Right?
So a great example is we've got companies that make like network appliances that
block attacks and they buy zero days so they can block those attacks.
And then at some point, another vendor can, you know, maybe actually fix the flaw,
-- you know,
-- let, let's, let's pick on specter and meltdown.
Where did they come from? Right.
Was it, did,
did someone attempt to shorten heck you could
have shorted intel stock after that one,
couldn't you?
But,
but here's the thing like
how, how are those paid for?
And, and
I'm asking you,
I don't know who uh I don't know if
the original researchers were recompensed in any meaningful way.
Well, they, they were because they, they had jobs. Right.
It was essentially Google Project Zero. And then there were some, some other,
well, there was a university involved, I think if I remember.
But anyway, the point is these people had jobs.
So, what's the incentive for project zero?
Well, they're essentially trying to reduce their costs, I assume, by, you know,
having less incidents and less problems to deal with,
by proactively dealing with it.
Well, and, and
they have a name for themselves. Right.
There's a certain amount of credibility they've gained by being good,
honest researchers that act in an ethical manner.
Right.
And now this company, this is what CTS, you said
they will never be able to interact with anyone
in the context of information security again,
because their reputation is now completely worthless.
It's worth what their shorted stock is. Right. I mean,
in all seriousness
and, and I think that's the thing is there are what, what Kac
has done? A bunch of cool work, didn't they do? Uh,
well,
Kac has, they did
stack
-- was last year.
-- Right. Right.
Right. And, and again, why did they do that?
Did they do it so they could short a bunch of stock?
No, they did it because it gave them brand recognition that is worth far more than
anything else they could have done.
They have a business model that allows them to leverage this information
and that's part of the problem is you have to have a
business model that allows you to leverage this information and monetize it.
And that takes a lot of time and effort short selling a stock is, you know,
if you're in the financial world and know how to do it, it's quick,
you know, you need a brokerage account and some cash
-- and you're ready to go
-- except when your plan backfires and you lose all your money.
Yeah.
Well,
and how many security firms have, you know, cratered out?
Right. I mean, nothing is risk free.
You know, I, I just, like I said, I'm not,
I cannot,
I, you know, 20 year old me would be horrified by this.
I cannot bring myself to condemn this.
I do not like it. Let me be clear. I am not a big fan of this because I wish we had
more efficient and effective ways
of incentivizing people
to do things that I think are ultimately good. Like reporting security flaws,
at least somewhat responsibility, giving the company, you know,
some amount of time to digest it or deal with it
more than 24 hours.
Yeah. But at the flip side, I'm not sure I have
any be good answers.
You know, like what I've done in the CV world is, I've, I've tried to reduce the cost.
So,
you know, we still,
it's still a cost to get a CV E but hopefully
now it's only a few minutes versus like hours of effort,
you know,
so I can at least bring the cost down.
And, and ideally also improve the benefit by making, you know,
the data is now machine readable.
So more people can consume it and
you know, leverage it.
But
fundamentally, as I said,
OK,
we've got people who do the right thing for the sake
of doing the right thing because they're good people and that,
you know, that will always be some percentage.
We've got people who do the right thing
because it aligns with their company's interest.
A great example being, you know, project zero, right? They want,
for example, Tavis, Tavis
Rindy is looking at
um update or software for stuff that's used on hundreds of millions of computers,
like, you know, uh what is it, um uh
Starcraft with the Starcraft updater, right?
You know,
somebody pops that thing that's like 100 million gaming computers taken all,
you know, taken over.
Then we've got companies with a direct business model of, you know, we,
we use the security vulnerability information
to, for example,
uh create
filtering rules for our product that you then
subscribe to so that this attack is blocked
and it's blocked.
Well,
in advance of the vendor being able to actually update
it and ship an update and more to the point,
maybe you don't have to spend money applying that update as much, right?
So that's cool.
Um
So we've got those sort of three models with the bug bounties.
I wouldn't say the bug bounties are
they,
they essentially the bug bounties are an expression of
companies that want to do the right thing.
Or
the bug bounty is cheaper than, like,
dealing with these catastrophes going public all the time.
Right.
Like,
if a MD offered a bug bounty of half a
million dollars and they'd gone to a MD privately,
I'm guessing that that would have been even just
for all the amount of stress and hair pulling.
A MD went through would probably be cheaper.
This would not have gotten half a million dollars.
No, but I, that's, that's my point too with this. Right, is that,
you know, again,
the good flaws aren't even guaranteed to be monetized through a bug bounty.
So bug bounties are very,
they're, they're good and I think they should exist, but I don't think they're the,
the, the be all end, all answer.
And so then the question becomes apart from those kind of four models I've gone over.
Well, how else do we get people to incentivize these flaws?
And I mean,
one thing I'm running into a lot right now with CV and CV numbering
authorities is a lot of researchers who want to become a CV numbering authority.
I'm assuming either A to put that directly on their resume or B to
just pad their resume out with a pile of BS CV ES because,
you know, I've had some people who, their rejection rate for CV request is like,
basically 90 some percent, like,
they've had like one or two good ones and the rest are garbage.
Right.
Right. And this is actually where some of the bug bounty
companies get it. Right. Because they, they give you a score and if you have too many,
uh, false, false negatives or false positives, I guess it would be
you,
you get docked.
And so obviously researchers have an incentive.
Of course, there's,
there's some hilarious Gamification that happens around that and
we should talk about that some other day.
But
fundamentally,
it does make researchers more careful to not just like send garbage,
which
I appreciate as being someone on the other end to that fire hose.
Yes. Oh, I know.
Yeah, I mean, I'll be blunt, that's why I went to the, the, the web form,
but I want to see you that asked a whole bunch of
questions and you better fill all of it out correctly or I'm
going to send you an email saying I need more details and
then I'm going to it until you reply with more details because
I don't have time to track all this crap down.
And even when they fill out all the details correctly,
I'm still finding like about a 25% to 40% rejection rate overall.
-- That's a lot.
-- Right. Right. But again,
why are people doing this
in, in the case if I want a CV E for free
because the way, the way you're talking about everything needs an incentive.
Uh, the resume padding is a clear incentive for a lot of them,
for the vendors requesting CV S, they want the CV because, you know, it just,
it actually does make their life a bit simpler.
Well, and not only that, I mean, one of the things I tell people all the time is look,
if, if you're working with a vendor who has zero CV E I DS in their product like that,
someone who doesn't care or isn't paying attention, right?
That, that you need to be careful with them.
CV E is one of those things that's like
-- I wash my hands after I use the toilet,
-- right? What's an indicator?
How do I know that?
-- Because I publish CV.
-- Si mean, yeah, somebody with or sorry, a vendor
or a project with no CV. Si would wonder. Yeah.
Do they have any security response going on?
So, yeah. No, like I said, overall, I'm not
a big fan of what happened, but at the same time, I think
this,
I don't know, II
I am curious to see if this happens again.
I assume it will happen again because it does
have the potential to make a ton of money.
I mean, if you can move a share price one or 2%
you can potentially make a lot of money if you know what you're doing.
With short selling or put, uh,
you know, with options.
And here's, here's my point is I still don't like this because if,
if someone did this to me, I would be livid with them
24 hours is not an acceptable amount of time.
Now, now, I will say
if you report a flaw to a vendor
and the vendor ignores you for some predetermined amount of time
game on.
Right.
That's when full disclosure is totally reasonable.
In my opinion,
if the vendor isn't playing nice and they're
trying to strong arm you or they're ignoring you
go public because that is the easiest way to just make it all happen.
And in fact, funny enough, I mean,
that's how people used to have to deal with some of the large vendors back in the day.
I mean, it was very common.
Yeah. Oh,
I remember those, those bugs being released with timelines in the years.
Yeah. Right. It was, it was terrible.
And this is where, like, some people harp on project zero for 90 days. I get it
90 days for some, some people is not a long time, but at the end of the day
it, it matters and you don't want this stuff dragging on forever.
And so I'm, I'm ok with 90 days, I'm not ok with 24 hours
whether you want to short the stock or not,
I guess let's put it that way.
I can ignore the shorting aspect of this.
I don't like the 24 hour aspect of this. Right.
If you give a vendor 90 days and then short their stock. Great. I'm on board.
Good for you.
But if you give them 24 hours, whether you short the stock or not,
-- I'm going to say not
-- cool.
What's most interesting to me is I suspect they picked
the wrong target because when you think about the security,
the information security world,
there's sort of three kind of large groups. There's like the hardware vendors,
you know, which is actually a relatively small group, like there's Intel,
there's a MD
and arm,
then there's the software vendors which is a
larger group and then there's the service providers.
And I suspect actually
the kind of company that would be most
impacted by this would be the service providers,
especially with things like GDPR coming in.
I mean, imagine if you found a major something as a service
and you found a way to disclose like people's names and email addresses,
well, under GDPR,
that has the potential for some really huge fines
and that is a clear and immediate consequence that the market does understand,
you know.
So
I'm curious, I, if I had to guess I would say that the next target,
um
because let's face it intel and a MD of whether the, you know, quite a bit and clearly,
you know, investors aren't going to panic.
I suspect the next target is either going to be software vendors, which again,
I suspect won't really work because
-- like, how many CV S a year does Microsoft Fix or like Red Hat or you guys like a lot?
-- Oh,
yeah, it's, it's quite a bit and, and I know that actually this is something that
more than one person
I've assisted
in doing some research to do CV ES affect share price.
And we have never been able to correlate that ever even for terrible things.
So I suspect it'll be the services will be the next target for
this because also the services don't really have a good track record of like
saying, oh, we have this flaw that we fixed, right?
Most of that stuff just happens behind closed doors.
No, it, it does. I know. Uh
I don't know, man.
May maybe, maybe, why don't we, why don't we end it there and just say
when, when it happens,
we'll be here, right?
And we'll be happy to talk about it and, and maybe
we, we, that we will of all the things in the world that that is more true than any.
All right, sweet. So, thanks, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
If you want links to any of the things we talked about today,
hit up the show notes at open source security podcast.com,
use the Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag
and yeah, Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks Josh