Hello and welcome to the open source podcast
with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner in the millennial Paz Josh Pressers.
You got it wrong. We're the open source security podcast. What did I say?
You said the open source podcast.
I'm not going to let you redo it like that.
It's
too late, it's too
-- late.
-- There still
be that pause there.
-- What's the
-- millennial pause? I don't know what that is.
I just learned about it yesterday from LT,
but the millennial pause is a barely perceptible pause that
is present at the start of some recorded videos.
And so basically they what
and uh Luke talked about was a combination of technology.
We come from an era where when you start recording
it doesn't start recording it.
It like the takes a second or two for the
computer to think about it and stuff to happen in the
-- little light
-- for the tape to move or
the light to go on or the app to start or whatever.
So we basically start recording and wait for some sort of
signal or feedback from the device that it is indeed recording.
Then we start talking.
Whereas younger people just hit record and start talking.
Well, yeah, that's because they live in the magic world.
Well, and also time constraints like tiktok videos.
You don't have time for a one or two second pause,
like like Vine, remember Vine 15 2nd videos.
If you pause for one or two seconds, that's 10% of your content right there.
-- I suppose that's fair.
-- So,
I am utterly guilty of this because I'm old and so is Josh,
I'm fine with that. I look, I'm comfortable with it.
So I, I have a funny old person story to tell you actually.
So I was surrounded by youth.
Yes, last night.
And there was an IP four networking problem. We had a Raspberry Pi with
the wifi was connected to the internet and
the Ethernet was connected to a local network
and the thing they plugged the Ethernet into
claimed it had a default route and you could, you could exit the network on it, right?
Obviously didn't go anywhere. That was a lie.
And the, the Raspberry Pi by default,
sets the metric on the Ethernet to a lower number than the metric on the Wi Fi.
Which means for anyone who doesn't know I PV four networking,
it means it will try the Ethernet first. But what happens?
It tried to get on to the internet. There was no internet and then it just,
there was never a response to packets. So nothing ever worked.
And I'm like, oh, we just have to change the metric and they're like, what? No.
And it's like, ah,
I know how to fix this. I will teach you all.
And then I started explaining, they're like, whatever. Just make it work old man.
-- It's like, fine, I'll make it work
-- well.
But every network device they own has, oh, I,
I was having network problems and I finally realized what it was
is around 11 o'clock. That's when the firmware updates for my wi fi happened.
And so basically my Wi
Fi network would like just poop the bed for 5 to 10 minutes
randomly once every couple of weeks.
And I wouldn't notice it always because sometimes I'm in bed by then,
but sometimes I'm up working.
So I turned off auto updates because it just gets too annoying.
Like, because when it does happen, it's horrendously annoying.
Don't turn off auto updates,
don't do that. Turn those back on.
Well, no,
what I'm doing is and now I have a calendar reminder to just do it on the weekends,
-- turn those back on Kurt, turn them
-- back on
because
change your time zone, change the router time zone to something
annoying
-- because it doesn't matter
-- why would they pick 11 o'clock at night? Because
-- like three in the morning I get,
-- I, I agree. I think 11 o'clock is too early.
In fact, the, I recently recorded the cybersecurity awareness training for,
for work because I hated all of the existing training.
So I made my own because I was just like it was a fit of rage
and basically II, I hand out a couple of pieces of advice.
One is use a password manager. The other one is auto updates
everything you own.
Like
I agree. But
the thing is I lose about half an hour of work every
2 to 3 weeks at 11 o'clock because I'm like fighting this thing
change the time zone. So it updates at 2 a.m.
or is your time zone set to something stupid?
Does it think you're like in eastern time?
No, it's set to my actual time zone.
Ok. I don't know. I don't know about this
time
zone,
whatever. Put that away, put your phone away. We're recording a podcast right now.
Not,
not doing network maintenance on Kurt's wifi system.
We have a topic today and it is not your wi fi system.
So, what's the topic today?
So this was your idea?
And I'm going to explain it apparently. No, it's too late. It's too late.
You lost your chance.
So Kurt had an interesting suggestion.
He sent me in saying, stop looking at your phone. Kurt. I see you doing that.
We,
so
God bless the video. I wouldn't have known this in the olden days.
So Kurt sends me a signal and basically says we should talk about
the just scale of packages today when you're a consumer because
like back when Kurt and I started at Red Hat.
Red Hat had probably thousands of packages,
I would guess over the span of all of the various operating systems and products.
And that was like a huge deal.
I was about 5 to 8000 packages depending on what, like,
I actually have unpacked all of rel and looked through it and stuff and it was about
5 to 8000 sort of sources plus other products. So,
but it's in the scale of the 10 to 50,000 over the whole ecosystem for Rel and,
and, and that was a big deal, right? That was a huge deal back then.
But now if you're using
a, a node application,
you have thousands of packages. And why is it different? And what does it mean?
And I think there's some interesting things we can talk about.
I think part of this boils down to what prompted this was I
was talking to somebody and I realized I was saying things like,
you know, back at Red Hat, we use statistical,
we could use statistical models basically because we had enough stuff,
you know, we're not managing trees,
we were managing multiple forests and I realized that's,
but that's now the common case, right?
And part of it is a matter of scale, like I can take care of one cat. Sure, no problem.
I've done that. That's easy.
Two cats a little bit trickier but sure, three cats, I've done four cats even.
We had four cats at one point. And that was, that's a lot of litter boxes to,
but like 40 cats or 400 cats, like going from 4 to 40 cats to 400 cats, like,
like most things in life now it becomes matters of like you have to have strategy,
you have to have logistics, you have to have supply chain management.
And that I think is the thing is there's this threshold
where you go from making dinner for your family to being a restaurant effectively.
I think it's different than that even because I think you
can argue that making dinner for your family is doable.
And then
running a restaurant is one thing. But now, I
mean, imagine the next leap when you go from feeding,
say hundreds of people a night to feeding thousands of people in an hour.
Well, and that's what I mean is there's these.
So I think there's a couple of jumps in scale where there's
like essentially where you can manage your vulnerabilities sort of manually.
One at a time when you have
like maybe one or two a month.
But I think the cut off is we're gonna go logarithmic because it's just simpler.
But like 10 to 100 very different and 100 to 1000
very different and 1000 and up
very different.
And at some point,
I think there's a cut off where it just
doesn't matter anymore because like once you're handling,
say 5000 vulnerabilities a year.
Sure. 5000, 10,000, whatever.
It's, it's mostly going to be heavily automated and you're gonna have process. And
like I said, statistical models,
it just doesn't really matter all that much.
But that's the thing is, I think a lot of people are make, they've,
they've made the jump into using
hundreds or even thousands of dependencies and packages.
But mentally they're still stuck in the model of, like,
I have a server that I maintain.
I agree with that.
And I think this, I don't remember if we talked about this on here or not,
but I wrote a piece on, on the blog called, what did I name it?
Like, perverse vulnerability, incentives or something like that.
And it was basically, I, I've been dealing with this for more than a decade now,
but I talked to people that are obsessed with having zero vulnerability
and this is where they'll, they'll send in a report and be like, hey,
I scanned your product and it has all these findings and I'm like,
I know it has those findings,
but like we've literally went through them and they don't matter.
I sent you the justification for these findings explaining why they don't matter.
And you're insisting I have zero vulnerabilities which is
not a target you want
because you'll get to zero if you want to.
But it isn't going to be the way it's, it's the cobra thing from,
from the cobra effect.
-- Right.
-- Well, here's the fascinating thing.
Number one that they're basically trying to do zero defects,
meaningful or otherwise.
But here's the other fascinating thing that, that whole argument bases itself on.
That isn't always true, which is the vendor had
a
vulnerability.
The vendor shipped an update that they claim fixes the vulnerability,
updating, fixes the vulnerability.
And that is not always true.
For example, like, remember the cluster that was shell shock.
Like there's been lots of these where, you know,
one of my favorite is always was the I want to say was it
was the qual stack guard stuff where they did some really good research.
And they're like, you know,
they came out the nice like couple of page emails to the distro list and like,
you know, so we'll need like one megabyte stack
pages which well, it's not great but it, it'll work.
And then, you know, Florian looks at this and he's like,
I'm gonna go check and he comes back like a week later.
He's like, so good news, bad news stack guard pages will fix the problem.
But they need to be a gigabyte in size,
which means you can now have three processes running on a 32 bit system.
I think that might count as a regression.
Uh I
-- think we would frown on that.
-- Yes.
And you know, it, luckily it actually got proper fixed before like
we released it.
So we didn't like release the fix and then find out it was broken and redo it.
But this, this idea that you get to zero defects by just upgrading your software.
And,
well,
here's the thing that I see everybody ignore and it,
I don't understand is
you upgraded all your software so you have zero defects. Correct? Sure.
Let's pretend we can do that.
But all those defects that were lurking in the software,
we're looking in upgraded software,
there's more defects lurking that you just don't know about.
Well, but we'll fix those obviously when they're discovered.
-- Well, it's
-- now zero known defects and by known, I mean, publicly known to them.
And so this whole thing,
basically what it boils down to is you can never have zero defects.
It's, it's a fool's errand for sure.
But people pretend that you can achieve that somehow by just upgrading.
Well, because it makes sense.
Look, I think this is related to your topic of kind of just packages at scale
is
we are humans which are squishy bags of meat.
And we make bad choices, generally speaking. And I think we look at a lot of problems
and we try to simplify them into one
easy thing we can do to solve it. It's,
I mean, if you look at human history,
we're riddled with this where if we do this one thing,
it'll be fine.
And I think when we look at
all the packages we use, we'll say things like
we shouldn't have any vulnerabilities in our packages that will reduce our risk.
It probably won't, it will probably actually make your risk go up.
But to ex I mean, it takes a half hour podcast to explain why that is versus saying
zero vulnerabilities equal zero risk. Like have you got a sound bite?
Now, let's go with that.
And I think that you see this as well in package use where
remember a decade ago when all the source composition analysis
vendors came out like your Black ducks and so forth.
And they were saying we will find open source in your stuff.
And people would be like, oh, we don't have open source and they're like,
let's scan your product and see
because what happened was these companies were telling,
you know,
you, you know,
I know, but
companies would tell them
developers you're not allowed to use open source.
And so the developers instead of like
properly installing and using open source packages,
they were copying and pasting open source and things like that.
-- And so it was hiding
-- every single windows app I've ever seen that implements
any web service
cuts and pastes G zip because G
encoding
or compression
in the web
is special. But I'm saying like, but also XML hash do
s same thing.
They cut and paste that one little bit of XML parson code
and now boom, you can parse XML.
So there's a lot of these little things floating around that are widely widely used.
Plus then of course, you know, I need to library to do acts.
Do I write one or do I cut and paste one in,
-- I cut and paste one in,
-- you're going to cut and paste it,
you're gonna go to stack overflow and look at what they
say you should do and then you're gonna do that.
The challenge is, is to even just have a mature view of the problem.
You need to have a very sophisticated
understanding of the components and the problem.
And
I think one of the challenges, for example, is most people have never built software
and I don't actually, and what I say and that's
a
and for example, the word build has a very specific context here which is,
I don't mean write software, I mean build it like download bind
and do the dot slash dance to get it up and running
manually. Like not using a package manager.
It's funny you say this because this is a conversation I had a couple of weeks ago.
The word build to people like us is not what build means to most people today.
Because when we think of build, we think of compiling code into something
and build for a lot of people
means running some amorphous thing that puts another thing and
then I can use the other thing and they're,
they're technically the same thing.
But in our minds that is not the same thing.
-- So,
-- and even just to understand, well, like, for example,
every time I have to explain the difference
between a compiled and an interpreted language,
I'm just like, uh,
you know,
it's different.
Some of it matters. Some of it doesn't, there's trade offs, blah, blah, blah.
Anyways point is it's hard to understand this stuff, especially if you don't
-- do it at least once or twice. I
-- mean, I think that's part of it.
Look, I think there's a bunch of pieces.
Well, I would challenge anybody here to measure something,
measure a gap in your house and then cut a piece of wood
to fill that gap and get it right on the first try.
Less than 1% of the of humanity can do that.
Why, why would they need to,
I mean, that's why you hire professionals to do that, but this is why.
OK. No, no, you've, you've actually hit on an important point.
I think that open source is like any other resource, right?
And
you need people to manage that resource for you who understand what it is like?
You can't take a bunch of developers that don't know
anything about open source and say I want you to use
these packages
to make the application work better
and then expect them to understand what the like deep
implications are of that on your overall business risk.
They don't, they only know I'm doing an N PM install of this stuff.
And that's all I know. And that's, that, that's ok.
Why would they know more than that? Right.
-- Well,
-- and it's, it's thinking of, are they thinking a
perfect example? Are they thinking about scalability?
Well, no, the question first is,
do we need to think about scalability? Right.
And you and I again have the maturity to, to know to back up a step and say,
do we even need to think about mature like scalability as an issue here?
-- And if we do, then how do we do scalability?
-- What do you mean by scalability?
-- I think that's a meaningless term.
-- Well, so for example, I'm building something
and for example, there are things.
Oh perfect example, when I worked at Isight partners, we had data
that would be used to generate a web page and it made all the calls sequentially.
So if you're on the local area network and
100 calls happen with one or two millisecond latency,
that is fine
when you're up in Canada working remotely with 50 to 100 millisecond latency times,
100 round trips.
It takes 5 to 10 seconds for the web page to load.
And for example,
the developer kept arguing with me that it worked and it was
fine and it was not slow and it was my fault.
And then he tried it
and then he tried it from his house and he was like, he apologized to me the next day,
-- which was nice
-- Well, it was your fault because you live in Canada,
it was, it was like literally a simple tweak to make the sequential stuff parallel.
And it so it actually sped it up on the land for everybody.
But the thing is like,
he never thought about the performance aspects of what he was doing,
which a lot of developers don't like does performance really matter?
Like I know a lot of people work for
the government and everything happens on local area networks,
which was super great until COVID hit and then they all had to go home.
And for example, the government discovered a lot of their
data center sites didn't have enough upload
bandwidth to support people working from home.
You know, they had to move to the cloud. So
what I'm saying is it takes a huge degree of maturity,
not just to answer the questions
-- but to know which questions to ask. So
-- it's, it's not maturity, it's just
being old.
So what you're talking about is there's, there's what, what is the old saying?
There's the known unknowns and the unknown unknowns sort of thing.
Well, there's no knowns, known, unknowns, unknown, knowns and unknown unknowns.
I forgot that already. But you get the idea,
the the point is
there are things you don't know, you don't know.
And I think especially in the context of like using a, a lot of open source,
how would you even know
that there's dependencies of dependencies and
that there's different communities for every package
because you've built the software by hand 30 years ago and you,
and you experienced manually importing dependencies and tweaking LD
-- big and doing horrible things.
-- You can't expect people to know this automatically.
They have to, they don't even know, they don't know this.
And this is where if you know a couple of geezers like us, then yeah,
you can ask questions and we won't shut up about whatever it is.
You've asked us to tell you, everyone can't do that.
They can.
Because for example, my cousin in Germany is a carpenter and a carpenter in Germany,
that's like a protected term like doctor.
So he did an apprenticeship,
local carpenter workshop
using, you know, traditional tools. Then he had to do his one year v
where he travels for a year and works and he's only allowed to carry
what he can in the naps and he's not allowed to pay for transit.
So he has to like hitchhike and big rides.
And the stonemasons also do this.
And it's like a 500 year old tradition and it's kind of hard core and they're like,
well, we've been doing it for 500 years and it works.
But the point is
if you hire a carpenter in Germany, so a guy shows up wearing a black suede pants,
the white,
you know,
white dress shirt and the black kind of matador style
jacket with the mother of pearl button sewn with a Z
and the big floppy black hat.
Like basically, if you hand him a rock and a chisel, he can build you a house
that was part of his apprenticeship and his training and his von
-- and
-- understand the point of this. So
the point is
a carpenter in Germany. They are,
they are taught the old methods, they are taught from the ground up.
They're not like a modern computer programmer. It's like I do uiux development.
I have no idea what ac pu is now.
That kind of works maybe a bit better for
carpentry because certain things like wood is wood,
there's been advancements in engineered products, but, you know,
fundamentally we have the same techniques.
Whereas in computers, like we've,
everything that's more than 10 years old is
considered garbage and thrown out the challenge is,
is how do you find that balance of we need smart people to make the power tools
and what is the appropriate level of training
to use the power tools correctly and safely?
-- Ok.
-- So this is teetering on the old man, yells at cloud territory right now, but
let me ask you a different question. Ok.
So I have a guy who comes out to fix my refrigerator.
Do you think he can tell me how the motor works?
No,
but does he need to know how the motor works
-- or does he just have to need to know
-- exactly?
-- He does. It's a modular component that he replaces it
-- is. Yes.
In fact, this actually just happened to me.
I had a problem with my air conditioner and
the person came out and they had to fix it.
And my son's power supply in his computer died a few months ago. Remember?
And Felix was like, oh, should we find it figure out why it broke?
And I'm like, no, we just replaced the module.
But OK, but here's the point, there's two sides to your argument.
There's the, you should know everything about everything,
which is apparently what carpenters in Germany do.
-- If
-- you want to be a no, no.
If you want to be a master carpenter, if you want to be a master carpenter,
you need to know from the ground up.
If you want to be a day laborer and just frame walls, you don't need to know much.
But the thing is
what happens is the framer is working under
somebody that actually does know what they're doing.
I would agree with that. And I think
that is the crux of it is when you look at
any, I should say any many
software houses,
they do not have scary deep knowledge because, well, quite frankly,
there just isn't a lot of it out there and it's really expensive if you want it.
So, but what do they need it?
I mean,
things are working like I can go to my
bank's website and transfer money like it it works.
What's more interesting to me is that virtually every single one
of them is structured to pretend like they have it.
Oh, we have senior developers and junior developers.
We have code reviews.
Yeah, those code reviews are like, yeah, whatever.
Yes,
I love, I wish I could find it.
There's a comic I saw one time that talked about code reviews
and it was like, if a code review is like like 10 lines or less,
it will have pages and pages of like questions and descriptions.
And if the, if the code is like 50 lines or more in the diff, it just looks good to me.
So the thing is traditional, but here's the part of the problem is,
is kind of like building a house,
you can make fundamental mistakes in software or in building
a house that may not show up for a long time
or and are very expensive to fix.
And that's true that does happen like asbestos remediation.
Like
that's expensive.
I'm familiar with that because the house I own
my house was built 100 years ago
and
all of the pipes in the basement had asbestos on them,
which they don't anymore and their basements are placed as well.
But that's another story.
But
I
like just we replaced the basement.
I did, I have a funny story about that. So January is Radon
Awareness Month.
I found out and I thought, well,
I haven't ever tested my basement for Radon and I had it redone like a year ago.
So I thought I should check my basement for Radon.
Now that we're actually down there,
I tested it for Radon. It's a little bit, a little high, like nothing crazy.
And so I called the Radon guy
and he's like, ok, what year was your house built in? I'm like, 1919.
I could hear him go. Oh, no. Wait, wait, wait, oh, hang on, hang on.
I was like, I had the, I had the foundation replaced. He's like, you what?
Like, yeah, the foundation is only 10 years old. He's like, wait, what?
I'm like, it's fine. Just come to my house and I'll show you
and yeah, it was like, it was dirt cheap because he's like,
this is like a new house.
It, it's very easy for me to abate your radon and you installed all this stuff and,
and it's great now.
But I'm like, yeah, it's fine because usually I, I asked him,
I said when you have 100 year old house, what's it usually like?
He's like, honestly, I just don't do them.
-- It's so much work
-- well. And, and that's a perfect example of expertise in mastery.
He knows which job
to walk away from.
Right.
-- That's an important skill, especially if you're a contractor.
-- Really.
It really is saying no to things is hard to do. But holy cow, I get it.
And that's a perfect example. In the software world saying no to things.
How many times do developers actually get to say no to things,
feature requests or adding this thing or whatever?
You know? And I've seen it phrased differently.
Like I think Squarespace had a really big blog entry about this
of they don't say no,
they say it was some version of like what would be required to achieve this.
Ah
interesting.
And so then you can have a real and honest conversation like a perfect example,
CS A I was like, oh,
we should do like end to end sort of email testing
and monitoring to make sure our email providers aren't pooping out
funnily enough.
Cloud FFL just published a blog entry on this like today or yesterday about how they
use cloud FFL workers to balance their outgoing email and stuff like that and blah,
blah, blah,
and I realize
what the CS A does.
It's just too much. It's, it's not worth it to even do it.
So it's just on the back burner. It'll maybe happen someday. Maybe not
until then, you know,
if mail gunner Sendgrid go down email breaks for a little while.
Ok. So in the, in the time we have left, then I want you to
answer me. This
is having like a,
a disturbingly deep understanding of your open source dependency tree.
-- Is that worth it?
-- It depends on the use case.
If you're building a web front end that does something
like
I built web finger dot IO.
I don't need to worry too much about the dependency tree. But if I'm building a bank,
I would like to know what's
in there. I would agree with that.
You know, if I'm building a mission critical system
that affects people,
if I'm building something that runs a chemical power
plant or a chemical plant or a power plant.
Sure. So, actually good example.
So the FDA in the United States, the Food and Drug Administration in the latest,
I forget which bill it is.
One of the bills I've read so many lately.
One of the bills tells the FDA that medical devices need to produce S bombs now.
Like that's a great example. Right?
Like if I have a thing inside of me that's keeping me alive,
I want someone to know what's going on and, and the thing is like,
there's nothing you can do with the S bombs.
Technically right now, it's more a matter of, if you can make one of these,
you're showing you have a certain level of expertise versus someone who can't.
And I think that's part of the story is just being able
to do a thing shows you have a certain level of maturity.
Yeah, I mean,
one of the houses I bought,
we had it inspected and literally the house inspector was like, oh,
did you know the garage burned down a little bit at some point? I'm like, what?
He's like, yeah, just a little bit. Like, not much. I'm like,
ok. Pause. What, what exactly does it burnt down? A little bit mean?
He's like, oh, well,
there's obviously a fire in there because there's
like alligator charring on all the rafters.
But they're mostly
solid and it seems good.
And I'm like, oh, ok then, and I,
I asked the neighbor I'm like, did this garage ever catch on fire?
And she's like, oh, yeah. Yeah.
Like he used to do, I have a workshop in there and he did a lot of woodworking and, yeah,
one time, apparently he smoked as well.
And so, you know, yeah, it burned down a little bit one time.
-- Those
-- oily rags in the corner, right.
So you just,
and,
and it's one of those things where I like and then
I poked my head through the inspection part and I'm like,
oh, like, like you can see all the wood is charred, but it's
generally like 80% there.
It's probably, I mean, it hasn't fallen down with snow load in over a decade. So,
ok, like,
it's a defect probably.
I think you would classify the garage, burning down a little bit as a defect, but
it actually didn't matter. And it's still standing there, like, 20 years later.
I mean, but you can,
you can make the same claim against open source packages in your product
because you could have like, a very old package.
-- But if it's not doing anything interesting. Who cares?
-- Exactly.
And that's part of knowing which defects matter.
And don't, so remember when, um, when Red Hat bought, manage
Iqem, I looked the ruby rail, uh, the ruby Gems dependencies
and I found a bunch that hadn't been updated,
like one had not been updated in four years.
And I'm like, oh my God,
-- what,
-- four years? That's it. That's nothing.
And it was called American Date and it just converted
dates into month, day year, the American format
and I took
a quick look through it and it was reasonably sane. I'm like, ok, cool, who cares?
And I did the like a quick audit of
basically by age of lack of update to see if they mattered and
none of them were front face and none of them were like really touching
user controlled data.
So I'm like, yeah, ok, like it should be updated,
but I'm confident to put my engineers, you know,
approval stamp on it saying these building plans are ok.
It probably won't catch fire and fall over right away.
And maybe that's part of what we need is
sort of that high level
approval by somebody who
is then liable
and thus carries insurance.
So then then that enters into the whole aspect of the insurance industry,
make sure that these people are qualified, hopefully and they do good work,
you know,
accepting where you have identity theft and
buildings falling down like that Italian guy who
-- pretended to be an engineer or
-- I don't know if this will ever happen.
I mean, so like
for, for anyone who doesn't know, like, for example,
in the world of civil engineering, you have to have a licensed civil engineer,
like stamp your plans and things to show that like the building
you're going to build is sound and it won't fall down.
There was that building in Las Vegas that they had to tear down, they built like
two or three stories and then had to take it down like oops.
Yeah. But I mean,
I don't know if software is ever going to be there.
You can make the argument that things like critical systems.
You could potentially say like
you should have some sort of
software engineer and I don't, I use the word engineer like biggie engineer,
-- proper engineer, not sanitation engineer
-- like well,
and we all call ourselves engineer but an engineer like there are professional
engineers where you have to take this horrible test and you have to
prove you're competent and then they give you a license and you have
to do things to keep the license and it's all very complicated.
I think part of it
is
-- you're using the
-- word,
you know,
OK, hold on. I want, I want to reframe this because you know what I just realized
last week, I think it was on Thursday or Friday, the United States released the,
the Biden administration, whether they're like cybersecurity,
whatever, I forget the full name of it. But I think one of the things
in that policy document
is it has become clear that the free ride software has
had from liability and accountability is coming to a close.
And so while part of me says Kurt is a lunatic for
suggesting like there's a licensed software engineer signing off on projects.
It might not be that ridiculous. Just given the current situation,
we must hold the stewards of our
data accountable for the protection of personal data
drive.
The development of more secure connected devices and reshape laws that
govern liability for data losses and harm caused by cybersecurity,
errors,
software vulnerabilities and other risks created
by software and digital technologies.
That's from the
the cybersecurity strategy.
-- Yeah,
-- it's got some good stuff in it.
But the thing to remember is you're using the word software to
encompass everything and there's a huge difference between a nuclear power plant,
a
hospital.
You know, my my American date
-- that converts dates into that stupid
-- American.
One of my favorites is, is like video games, right?
When I'm playing Mario 64 in my switch,
I would say I'm much less concerned about the licensure
of software developers on that versus the person who built,
you know, the implanted pacemaker or whatever, you know, something like that.
Those are very different situations.
And the flip side too is a great example like the whole
Tarkoff
controversy right now. TV
is really apparently terrible for not having any anti cheat system,
no replay system.
-- And so
-- no one knows what Tko
-- is. You have to explain this better
-- TV
is a video game. It's a multiplayer video game.
And long story short,
you can spend hundreds of dollars buying in game items to have a good loadout to,
you know, have a better chance of winning and stuff.
So there's real money involved for these things.
And when you die, whoever killed you typically gets all your gear.
So, like if you have $100 loadout and you die
well, too bad. And cheating is rampant in Tarko,
there's no anti cheat system really.
That's, uh, well, there is an anti cheat system but it's not great.
Uh, they just banned a whole bunch of people recently on last weekend, but
there's no replay system. They, they lack a lot of fundamentals. And so
even video games now have Real World Financial,
like financially measurable consequences for having these security problems.
And I think that's
sort of what's changed is
we've gone from
software is not like software
is no longer a nice to have or an optional thing. It's,
it's life
and this free ride, you know, it's like, look at the mining industry,
we used to just dig holes, send people down the holes.
Hopefully they came out with rocks that were valuable and shiny. That's true
to the point where it got so bad that every American company in their sec.
10-K has to make a statement about their mine safety,
like red hats.
10-K has a thing. We don't own any mines. We don't plant on any mines.
Blah, blah, blah. You know, same thing with building houses.
Now we have building codes out the wazoo
because people used to just slap houses together
and then horrible things would happen. They would burn down, fall down,
whatever.
Yeah. Well, that's like, I mean, my house is 100 years old
and it's funny because
I was talking to a contractor one time at the house
and I pointed out like this insane beam we have.
And he's like, yeah,
they just did that because they figured it was probably good enough.
Like they had no math,
they just put a giant beam in because they're like this, they should hold it all,
-- all
-- that stuff in Germany, like 16 inch,
I've seen 16 inch oak beams in a house and it's like
that
will like, it's 500 years old.
There's your proof.
You know, it's funny because the,
but so what I think will happen is we'll see a sort of a
top down approach, like with more
like
get the real safety critical stuff first, like the power grid, ho
you know, all this kind of stuff.
And one thing,
the cybersecurity strategy talks about is
further these and other critical sectors
rely on,
upon the cybersecurity and resilience of their third party service providers,
cloud based services enable better and
more economical cybersecurity practices at scale.
But they are also essential to operational
resilience across many critical infrastructure sectors.
And I think that's the next thing that's gonna happen is we've already
seen the industrialization of it through cloud in the last 10 years.
But I think we're going to see like the six sigma like like
99.4 nines reliability approach to cloud computing now
because we have to like again, it's not nice to have. It's
like if Amazon goes down,
I'm going immediately to the nearest food store to buy all the canned food.
Because if Amazon goes down and stays down,
there's gonna be hell to pay,
that'll never stay down. I'm, I'm comfortable with their ability.
But if look, here's the thing, if Amazon goes down, it doesn't come back up,
society collapses, it's fine.
Like you don't need canned food, just hope you're killed first. That's
anyway. All right, I'm gonna,
I'm gonna tie this one up because I, I love that. We started out talking about
managing lots of open source dependencies and we land ourselves into the
-- fact that I think regulation is coming for the entire industry
-- because
everybody is managing open source dependencies.
-- Now at scale, whether you like it or not look well,
-- but here's OK.
Here's the one thing I want to end with is if you read
all of the, the document, the Biden administration published,
they're very clear that like, this is not open sources problem.
This is the problem of the vendors. And I love that.
Well, I think they're smart enough to realize, to quote like Thomas De
Pierre,
what is actually
possible.
-- Right.
-- And, and we could write like
we could, well, we do write laws that saying you can't run red lights,
right?
Whatever. I'm a sovereign citizen. I don't have to follow your laws. Kurt?
All right.
I'm gonna call this one before we get too silly and probably get in trouble.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you all for listening.
Go to open source security podcast.com. Head up the shout out to
Zondo
Podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks, everyone. Bye bye
the