Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crimes against scale.
-- Josh
-- Pressers. I mean, what is, come on? That's lame.
That doesn't even mean anything.
Ok. I'll redo it. No, no, it's too late.
I'm not going to let you like it's done, it's done. It's etched in stone, it stays.
That's the beauty of being the editor is I wield the ultimate control.
I could make you sound like an idiot if I wanted to.
-- I was surprised
-- you've never made me chipmunk voice.
I, I don't, I don't, I'm too lazy to do any of that sort of thing.
I just, I, I wield my power
anyway. Anyway.
So scale because one thing I've been noticing,
what do you, what do we mean by scale?
Well, security at scale and what I mean by that is I,
I've been noticing a lot of people who say, oh, I can do that
and the answer is yes, yes,
you can absolutely cook a hamburger or find a security vulnerability,
you know,
but the problem becomes
well because I mean,
I just had the experience right of I updated 30,806 GSD entries with the Souza Ulg
did not like that.
Well,
I love the one tweet comment where it's like basically he got
like blocked by the API for abuse by just trying to look at
it. So
yeah, II I get this a lot. I I went, you asked me to approve that full request.
I'm not gonna link to it because just don't, don't, your browser doesn't like it.
Anyway,
I went to the files change tab just to see what it would say.
And it just showed an infinity symbol. I said there are too many files to show.
Yeah. So anyway, anyway,
well,
and the funny thing is like on my local machine when I was flipping between branches,
it was
actually, it only took about 30 to 60 seconds to,
to like essentially rewrite every single one of those 30,000 files,
which is pretty impressive.
IG is pretty fast.
I'm, I'm always amazed by how just fast git does literally everything you need
do. I mean, it's shocking at times.
Well, again, the Linux chrome is working on scale. It's probably one of the biggest
I would say active code bases in the sense of there are definitely bigger code bases,
but they aren't nearly as active as with respect
to change velocity as the Linux kernel is.
-- Yeah.
-- And they work in some really wild ways the way they use branches and they do.
I mean,
I remember back in the day
when
the dominant source management system was CVS.
And like,
there's just no way the Linux kernel could have even existed in that ecosystem.
It was just too slow and too clunky and it could, I mean,
I remember trying to do like branches and merges in CVS and it was like,
you needed some sort of advanced degree in mathematics to actually make it work.
It was madness.
I actually remember somebody with a degree in math,
wrote a paper about that stuff and how
essentially, well, no,
the problem is that a lot of these tools were designed by academics because, well,
if you design one of these tools commercially, you sold it,
you didn't open source it, right?
Like bit Keeper tried and
do they still even exist.
They must
-- nothing ever dies. Yeah. So bit Keeper is the reason we have it
-- because wasn't it?
Andrew Tannenbaum
-- type to help?
-- Yeah, basically.
Yeah.
So what happened is Bit Keeper gave the Linux kernel like a license for using bit.
-- OK. Hold
-- on, hold on.
Let's, let's start at the, if we're going to tell this story, we're going to tell it,
right.
So in the early days,
the Linux kernel had no source management.
Linus used an FTP site and people would mail him patches
like that was it that
-- they did. And it, well, it worked. We'll say I won't say pretty good at that
-- scale.
It works when you have like 10 patches a day that can work.
And there is the Linux kernel mailing list was basically the change log, right.
Well,
anyway,
and then
Linus decided they needed source code management and they
ended up with a closed source product called Bit Keeper
-- because
-- it was the only choice.
It was the only one that could probably do what they needed at the time.
The Bit Keeper developers basically said we will let you use this for free.
But here's a bunch of terms you must agree with.
And one of them was like, basically no reverse engineering what we're doing
because I think they,
they knew what would happen if someone reverse engineered it,
which is exactly what happened.
And then I believe it was Andrew Tanenbaum
who is in charge of Samba
basically one day,
like just typed,
like connected to the Bit Keeper server and typed help, right?
And it listed some information and then like there was some, you know,
a little bit of chatting and stuff and the Bit Keeper people got really angry
and they booted him
and then there was a bunch of weird politics and a bunch of madness.
And basically Linus was like, we're done
and he took what, like a month off of working on the kernel and literally wrote Git,
you know, I mean, it's,
it's hilarious to me that one person is probably responsible
for like 80% of everything we touch every day.
Be git and Linux,
I mean,
-- it's madness
-- and one of the reasons it works so well is he
has worked at all these different scales and is aware of them.
So
like he's one of the few people that's not doing premature optimization.
I think there's something even more important than that is
this is something I run into all the time.
And I'm going to specifically call out like the current SB
formats where there's SPDX and there's cycling DX, right?
These are formats that were built by committees
and you can, you can do as much work as you want in a committee.
But when the rubber hits the road, when you have to actually start doing things,
that's when the real change happens.
And in the case of Linus, he's always been solving real problems versus
going to a committee
and defining problems and then trying to solve them.
It's very different how that works.
Well, actually, I think it's, it's more subtle than that.
It's um and I, I want to say Joel Spolsky writes about this,
-- he writes about everything. Well,
-- he writes about having taste, good taste.
The thing is you can have an artist or an expert or a skilled machinist or in this case,
a very skilled software developer like Lyne
Torvalds
who has excellent taste,
but then you run that through a committee process and it destroys it.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah.
And so I think that's part of the subtlety here is is that there's a lot
of situations where a person or one or
two people create something actually quite good,
beautiful and then the committee just destroys it.
It happens anyway, we're supposed to be talking about insecurity at scale.
Well, but this feeds it.
This is the whole problem with security at scale is
security at scale is no longer a technical problem.
It's a policy, strategic logistics problem, is it? Ok.
Josh, I just found 10,000 vulnerabilities in your software product.
And here's a list, they're all perfectly scoped out. There's no patches.
So good luck with that.
I've gotten reports like that.
I remember there were people who used to run Fuzzs
and send stuff like that and it was ridiculous.
Ok.
Here's the thing with the actual 10,000 exploit
codes that actually get remote root on,
you know what I mean?
Like, it doesn't,
basically the point is no matter how high quality you still have to, like,
go through it,
understand each vulnerability and patch it and doing one or two of those.
Sure. 10, maybe 100. Ok.
We can work on this for a few weeks but if somebody comes to you with 10,000 of them.
Well, what do you do?
Yeah.
My, my
overly dramatic pause.
I'll leave in but no, you, you're not, you're not kind of wrong in that instance.
I, I'll tell you what would happen in most cases.
If, if I showed up to an organization.
And I said here are 10,000 security findings. Do you know what they do?
They, they ban me and tell me they're gonna sue me if I publish any of them.
Like it, it's, this is why like
I'm going to call this episode insecurity at scale because I think
when we talk about security after we reach a certain point,
if the organization isn't prepared,
it turns into a legal mess and it's really insecurity at scale.
-- It's not security at scale.
-- One thing that gets me.
Uh so, you know, COVID rolled around and a whole bunch of organizations were like,
holy cow, we need to enable work from home at scale.
Like they maybe had a few people working from home before, but, you know,
not everybody.
And so like,
literally a lot of organizations didn't even have enough upload
bandwidth from their data centers to support everybody working from home
or the more recent, you know, the, the, the conflicts between, well,
the Russian invasion of Ukraine, it's not a conflict, it's an invasion
and all of a sudden a lot of Western companies are freaking out and going, oh my,
you know, we're on some sort of heightened cyber alert status and it's like,
so now you're worried about cybersecurity.
It's always been this bad. It's just we were kind of ignoring it.
And I think that's part of the problem with scale is that it's like global warming,
we've just been ignoring how bad it is
and the scale of it is horrifying. Like, do I start recycling? Will that fix it?
-- Probably not.
-- I think you're conflating two different problems here. There's the
kind of long term structural issues I'll call them
that exist in meet space.
But when we're talking about this, the technology scale,
I think there's kind of a different thing because
we have technology to let us do huge things.
I mean,
do you remember a decade or two decades ago when a
database with 1000 records in it would have been a lot
and now I can run tens of millions of records in an elastic search instance,
my laptop and it handles it like it's nothing.
But that's what I'm saying is those at scale,
no matter how good your technology is at scale,
it outstrips the technology and everything
becomes that logistics strategy policy problem,
right?
Because at some point you outstrip your scale of software and hardware.
I mean, but this is we're supposed to be talking about security at scale right here.
Well, and that's what I mean is so for example, I can give you AC ID build pipeline
but makes it really easy to fix bugs. And that's great if you have 10 or 20 bugs. OK?
But it falls like, what do you do at 10,000 bugs,
right?
And that's one of the things that's amazing to me about the Linux kernel is that
I love how they just take, the tact of a bug is a bug.
We fix bugs because bugs needs to be fixed and
they just fix the bugs as fast as they can.
And then they tell people, look, if you want to
have all the bug fixes, you have to run current,
like you can't be back part of this stuff.
-- You can't be selective because this thing is too big.
-- Well, that's not true.
That's not true.
Ok,
I'm going to reframe this a little bit because
I think we're often kind of the weeds tad.
So
the Linux kernel has the mainline kernel,
but then it also has long term support releases.
And this is something that
we have been working with them a little bit on
with GSD where they send us basically a big,
great big long list of things that might be security bugs, we don't know for sure.
And the way they do that is,
uh uh there's a developer named Sasha Levin that we talked to.
I I, he uh I'm going to try to find it. There's a talk he gave
several years ago where basically what they're doing is they're using
machine learning to look at kernel commit messages
and ascertain like this one could be security.
And I think the problem you get at scale,
especially when you talk about something like security
is we like to think about security as black and white, like vulnerability,
not vulnerability.
But the reality is, it's this big squishy space and there's,
yes, for sure.
And there's maybe sort of, and there's, uh, probably not, but we don't know.
And then there's absolutely not, you know what I mean?
Well, and part of the challenge to make it even worse, there is
to say something is not a vulnerability.
You, you kind of have to prove a negative,
which sometimes is easy and sometimes it is
not so easy to prove something is vulnerable
is also
can be very easy or can be very difficult.
Like uh my favorite, you know, ping of death, I send you a large pink packet,
your machine crashes.
OK. We're all agreed that should not happen
easy.
But oh,
here's this like possible subtle logic flaw in some
of the control flow of this other thing.
Like can it actually be reached and exploited in a meaningful way? You know what?
Let's just fix the logic and move on, right.
And a
lot of people are like, no, no, I want to know if it's vulnerable,
like if it's actually exploitable or not.
And sure, sure again, sure.
Ok, we can do that for a few bucks but we can't, you know,
intensely research and document every single bug because like,
I mean,
how we did, I think what 2000 G sds for the links kernel last year?
Oh, at least that probably more.
We don't research them at all. We take their word for it.
Well, even if you had a group of smart people,
assuming each one of these is going to take at least a few hours.
-- Well, OK,
-- look like scale.
I,
I think here's a different way to look at this
and this is something I deal with on a regular basis
because I work at
Anor and one of the things Anor
does is we build S bombs from stuff and then we can vulnerability, scan those right
where you're taking say a container image, you scan it. And I, I have a great example.
Actually, I'm giving a talk,
I will be after it'll be after this actually gets published for the with the CNCF.
I'm doing a live stream.
I've taken all of the docker official container images.
I scan them for S
palm and then I vulnerability scan them and I put all
the data in elastic search and you can dig it out right
there is the rails official image which was deprecated five years ago,
still available has 7000 vulnerabilities in it.
Now,
when you get results like that,
it's easy to just like pull your hair out and say, oh my goodness, what's going on.
But the reality is once you surpass, we'll say double digit vulnerabilities,
you now have to start making assumptions and making some policies
of just saying like something with 7000 vulnerabilities just no,
just hard.
No, right?
But let's do something as
100 vulnerabilities. What does that mean?
And you can't individually go through all 200.
You have to start writing policy that can make some
intelligent decisions based upon some of the data you have.
And I think this is where security at scale starts to
get hard for a lot of us to wrap our heads around
because we've obsessed over perfect or nothing
for so long that we don't understand.
There's this squishy in between where we have to make, I won't say guesses,
but we have to use the data available to us to make the best
decision decision we can make with that data.
Well,
and part of my concern there is people are making decisions that are
framed in the sense of I have a container with 7000 vulnerabilities.
I need to fix these.
Well, maybe no, maybe the answer is you need to do a different technology stack
or something, right? Like there's there's other options. And so
I mean, that's one thing like at the, at the CS A
for example, my response to patching servers is like, no,
let's just use platform as a service
like let's just
do that.
-- I mean,
-- yeah, you talk about this all the time.
I'm looking at, you know,
all these companies that are worried about fishing and it's like,
and they're talking about fishing training and it's like,
-- no, I think the better answer is go by a bunch of hardware tokens
-- that's easy to say.
But now we also have the scale problem of distributing 10,000 hardware tokens.
But you also have the scale problem of trying to teach
a whole bunch of people not to fall for fishing,
which
-- as we've seen does not work
-- well, depends who you ask.
You don't solve world hunger by growing more food.
You solve world hunger through many things like food distribution, food,
accessibility, food safety, security.
Right? Like it's, it's, it's, it's a lot harder than just like grow more crops.
-- They have to get to the people that need to eat them. Right.
-- Right.
And this is kind of where some of that scale comes, comes back into play, right? Is
-- scale is weird and hard and humans are really bad
-- at it
and you get emergent behaviors that nobody expected.
Yeah,
that's always one of the other really funny
things when you start doing something on a,
on a wider scale,
-- things can get weird. Well,
-- or you get incentives and people start doing things that
don't. Oh, ok. It kind of makes sense now in a context of, you know,
1% of people are going to do this to eke out some perceived advantage.
But the problem is 1% at scale is a problem.
-- You know, I mean,
-- that's always one of the things I laugh at is when
you're talking about really big numbers
and people they say, oh, it's only 1% 1% of a billion is a lot
like
you know that, that's 1% of a billion is what? A million
million, no, 10% would be 10 million.
-- Is it, is it,
-- there's 1000 millions in a billion. Math
is hard.
Like that's the answer.
But you know what I mean?
It's hard.
It's very hard.
Yeah, I always come back to,
if 1% of people consistently decide to ignore red lights,
what happens to our traffic situation?
And the answer is it falls apart real fast.
The other problem is most people have never dealt with.
-- I'm going to say medium scale, let alone large scale.
-- No, I agree.
And I think this is especially in security. One of the traps.
I always see, I used to get this actually, when I was at elastic is
the elastic stack is a,
we'll say large piece of software is the polite way. I'll describe it.
It has a lot of dependencies and we would do our
best to keep track of them and understand what's going on.
But it was, it was um, it was scale right where we were dealing with
hundreds of findings on a regular basis.
And so one of the challenges being we have to keep
track of them, we have to understand what are the important ones.
What are the less important ones? How do we prioritize this work?
Because
you can't just like start randomly upgrading everything.
I mean, it, it explodes, it's just not, it's not practical
and it was funny because
I would talk to certain people and they'd say, oh, you have to fix all of these.
And it's like,
no, I don't, I, I can't,
but even if, even if I had the resources to fix it all, I wouldn't
because fixing everything would create more risk than the issues have themselves.
And there were so many people who just like,
they could not wrap their head around it at the end.
It's like it is what it is. It's in your court now.
It's actually worse than that because in, in,
even if you took on the task of fixing all this,
imagine if you'd taken half those resources and made the product better.
Right.
That's the thing.
It's not if I have the resources to actually like, fix every security problem.
Like, basically, if I have the resources to patch every pothole in Edmonton,
I would rather not patch every pothole in Edmonton.
-- There's like we could use a new bridge or two and some new roads.
-- Exactly that.
Exactly that. And this is where again, issues of scale start to change.
If you have to fix one security vulnerability, great.
That's no big deal. Fix one thing.
Yeah. Log for j heroic effort. It can be made.
But now what happens when you have to do that?
-- Log
-- for Jay is a very bad example.
It's a great example because
you can do one log for J a year
emergency response and probably not burn your people out.
But what happens when that's a quarterly issue?
Yeah, more than one of those a year would be terrible.
But I mean, so, actually no, in all seriousness,
I think log for J is a good example because
I talked to many people that were not having to scan
tens of machines or hundreds of machines or even thousands of machines,
they had tens or hundreds of thousands of instances where they had to
figure out do I have log for J on this system somewhere?
And that becomes an enormous challenge.
Like if I said, Kurt scan your system for log for J
in like five minutes, you'd probably come back and say I didn't find it or, oh,
I found it over here, right?
But if I said Kurt here are 10,000 computers,
-- scan them for log for J
-- and half of them are not
really well maintained.
We just had that like there's a CS a member that literally is like
we started scanning all of our infrastructure more aggressively
and
like RCM,
like basically poop the bed with all the reports and alerts.
I have no doubt
because again, they're working at a, you know,
they're working in that 100,000 plus scale.
And it's like,
and that probably generated
thousands of events per system
times. Well, no, thousands of events per system times, thousands of systems.
Now it's a big number
and it's literally what do you do with that it's
-- well.
-- Ok. No, I mean, this is actually this is a good example.
Let, let's dive into this space.
This is where I think SIMS are a great example is in the old days
and old days being like five years ago, you know,
in the old days back when I was young, you would deploy
a SIM system is security, what is it? Security information, event monitoring
and the intent is you collect all this information
and then you can detect when there's maybe an attack
or you can look for a strange behavior or whatever,
you can kind of build these rules.
But basically the way it had to work is you would deploy your SIM,
you deploy all these agents, information would come back,
-- alerts would fire and humans would go look at the alerts,
-- right,
and investigate and deal with it.
And even when even at the beginning,
humans couldn't really do this because you were gener
probably 100 alerts per person working on your security team.
I would say it's probably an a, an optimistic estimate now,
in most infrastructures just because of their scale, you know,
I'm gonna say the word scale as much as I can, I guess.
But in most infrastructures because of their scale,
these si environments are actually generating millions
of events per day
and no one has a security team of 100,000 people.
I mean, even if you had the budget, you couldn't find them.
And so we reached this point where now we, you, you kind of have two choices.
You can either just turn off a whole bunch of alerts, which
maybe that's probably not a good idea. I mean, why do you have this
or now we have to start thinking bigger where we can say,
how can we let the robots do the easy work?
And how can we go from a million alerts to here are 30 alerts.
A human needs to look at every day.
I would slightly disagree and say again, it goes back to you,
look at even higher level strategic and policy of,
you know, do we have to be even doing this
or is there other ways to accomplish this or are there other technologies or other,
you know, methods?
-- You
-- need to do it? You're talking out of your backside on that one.
It definitely needs to be done.
No, no, no.
What I mean is, well, for example,
do we need to run on premises email or can we just outsource it to Google?
That has nothing to do with the SIM generating a million alerts per day?
Well, but at some point, you can start to get rid of,
-- you know, some
-- of it. But even even when you offload this stuff, Kurt,
you have connectors because you need events from your email system.
You have to know where is the email coming from?
When do I see logins coming from Moscow, Russia. You know what I mean?
Like you need this information
but I mean, ii I
think part of the challenge is a lot of security people
see something and then they try and solve that exact same thing.
They don't ever do sort of a root cause it's human
nature and I don't mean a root cause analysis and like,
you know,
exactly how did this feel but more of a root cause analysis of like
kind of how did we get here and do we need to be here?
I mean, some of it,
I think you oversimplify this matter all the time
and I'm not going to entertain it right now.
Well,
I'm going to point out that the COVID is a forcing function to move
people to the cloud has resulted in a lot of old it getting binned.
Oh, sure. And that's a good thing. I think, I think it was going to happen anyway.
It's just, it got accelerated, which is 15 years. But now we have a new problem.
We had a bunch of stuff on prem,
we had a certain amount of insight into that gear and infrastructure.
Now it's somewhere else.
I still need some of that insight because like one of my favorite examples is,
let's say you have a user that logs in from San Francisco,
California in the US and then four minutes later logs in
from ST Petersburg, Russia.
Well, yeah, and that's,
that's one of the classic things when I look at single sign ons
and why a lot of companies kind of don't want to outsource the accounts to say Twitter
or linkedin or Facebook or Google because they
lose that insight and they lose that control.
It's sort of, well, I don't know if your account's been popped or not because I have,
I just see you coming in.
Well, it, and here's the funny thing so you can rely on something like Octa, right?
Where Octa logs a bunch of this stuff. But with the way
some of the new single sign on mechanisms work
is you really just need
a cookie
and it contains all the information and you don't necessarily have
to ask the the single sign on instance for authentication,
right?
And this is where having some of that insight being pulled into like your SIM
can make all the difference and this,
but it creates new challenges because now you have to figure
out how do I get this information from the web mail
and from
-- github? And then how do I correlate
-- it? The Conditional
Act
access control, which is kind of the hot thing now, right?
Like for example, it works great within the Azure ecosystem.
But the minute you want to talk to a server outside of Azure, it's kind of like, well,
-- how do you get the data to and from
-- it?
All right, you need to explain what
-- ABAC is because I bet a lot of people don't know.
-- Ok. So
ABAC is essentially, well, like you said, Bob,
the salesman always logs in from an iphone and an apple air from, you know,
the Western US.
So if he suddenly logs in from China,
did he travel there or is that an attack, you know,
or things like looking at access patterns time of day, the devices being used,
the software being used, basically looking at as much data as possible
to create sort of a risk assessment of that event.
Well, and,
and then you can trigger kind of behaviors based on that
where you could say if Bob logs in from China,
just no
deny. Or you could say if Bob logs in from the east coast of the United States,
then I want you to make him give a second factor, right?
Or, or you could even set things up. Like I want,
I want you to have to log in with user name and
password and they give me a second factor and then I'm gonna,
you know, ping your phone and you need to, you know what I mean?
And you can start
looking at the data,
looking at the various events and attributes and
everything and you can start making in intelligence
decisions. But again,
this is a problem at scale where if I tell you this,
you could think about, OK, maybe I could do this for one or two people.
But now imagine you have an environment where you
have a million logins an hour coming in.
How do you possibly correlate all of these
things together and deal with them appropriately?
So the data like within Azure, you can do this within Azure.
But the minute you have a system outside of Azure,
how do you get the data to and from it?
And
the answer is it's complicated, which is a classic way of saying is like, yeah,
we can build a custom solution that will do that,
which is
like the ultimate, in my opinion,
the ultimate software kind of useless answer because it's completely true.
Like yes, we can build software that will do anything. Good luck with that.
Well, if you have the right people and the resources and the time,
I mean,
it always, it always annoys me when people are like, oh just write a script to do that.
No,
no, I will not be writing a script to do that.
And, and again, I, I think, I mean, this is, this fit fits in completely where
if I have a computer in my basement
and I just need to do something a couple of times, I can write a script,
I can run the script and we're done right?
But now if I have an infrastructure where I have 7 million containers running on it,
and I need to do something half of those containers like that's not a script,
I need to rethink everything I know
about dealing with this infrastructure and obviously
containers are supposed to be immutable,
which I know they're not in many instances.
But you know what I mean?
It's
so,
oh,
this is the world we live in now.
Well, no, I mean, I worked with these products.
I read that like satellite and sand that were meant
to control tens of thousands of machines and it's like
-- this is complicated. Who knew?
-- No, I know. I know. I mean, I remember
one of my favorite examples of this is
I had a friend who worked at Google.
This was back in the very early days, like early 2000, right?
The 2000 knots. Was that what we call it?
Anyway? The good old days
I remember someone was talking about
having 1000 computers in their server room
and everyone around was like, oh, wow, 1000 and the Google guy just smiled
and I looked at him and I said, how many do you have?
And he said there's a lot more zeros than that.
And it's like,
I
can't imagine what it looks like. Now, you know,
-- I
-- just, I, you know, again that,
that Microsoft earnings call where they refer to
their data centers and data center miles.
It's like Star Trek kilo quads.
-- It's a bunch of stuff.
-- Wait, what is a data center? Mile?
It's a mile of data center.
-- Oh, like
-- the building is a, 00, I see.
They're measuring as if all the buildings were lined up.
How many miles long would it be?
-- You
-- know,
Amazon's putting in that new availability zone down
in Calgary and they're spending 4 billion bucks
and it'll be three physical locations and everybody's
like losing their mind about the $4 billion.
And I'm like,
no, a data center,
like a modern data center basically costs a billion
bucks and times three plus some other stuff.
-- Yeah, $4 billion.
-- And in Canada think of how the money they'll save on cooling.
-- Can they just like, open the window or something? I would hope.
-- Oh, no.
So what they do now is the,
the chilling units will essentially, they run a, like, for example,
they can run a Glycol loop for the coolant.
Right. And
yeah, and in winter
-- just run the Glycol loop and they
-- don't really
have to beat the air.
Yeah.
But no,
there's not actually not that much savings on cooling because you
still have to clean the air and filter it and everything.
Well. Right. Yeah.
You know, you can't just be shoving random.
Of course, of course, that's probably fair.
I suppose you're still running the fans, you're still doing all of that.
The more to the point is,
you know, that gives them,
you know, sub
millisecond access now to Western Canada because, you know,
the only other data Amazon are in, what is it?
I want to say like near Montreal or somewhere over there
in earthquake prone regions.
Montreal, no,
Montreal doesn't have earthquakes but Vancouver gets earthquakes. Right.
That's why they probably didn't put it in Vancouver and they put it
in Calgary where you have literally hailstorms and that's easy to engineer for.
-- Well, and
-- actually Calgary is really close to the US also.
So I bet you could leverage that
I could, I could host
pirate content in Canada now and the US government can't touch me
anyway.
Yeah, Alberta is wonderful. We have zero
seismic issues. We basically have hail, the occasional tornado
and snowstorms.
Oh, you get tornadoes? I didn't know that.
Yeah, snowstorms is an understatement, I think.
-- Uh,
-- well, no, it's, it's funny because it's not as bad as people imagine it because
the, the mountains eat up most of the snow. Like, we're in a rain shadow.
So,
it's not like you guys with the living next
to a lake and getting all that humidity and,
-- like, I'm
-- on the good side of the lake.
It's the people on the other side of the lake that have the trouble.
-- Like, if we got a foot of snow that would be like a world ending event here.
-- Oh, really?
Whoa. We get like, two or three inches of snow but it's minus 40 for a week or a month.
And it's,
it's, it's,
yeah, when it's minus 40. Well, it's, it's just minus 40 it sucks to go outside.
I've, I've been in it a couple of times and it,
like your face burns when you leave the building.
It's not, it's not, it's not good.
Anyway, we should call this one man now that we're talking about the weather,
like two old men.
So what I think getting back to
scale the issue is most people have never encountered it and they don't
like at scale. You have issues. Like, do we have enough parking for the analysts?
Do we have enough
to? How
many toilets does your building?
That's my favorite.
My, my,
my all time favorite was the Alberta government had their
alternate site of government was a building called Government House.
And it's a lovely,
beautifully historical old building next to the
Royal or the former Royal Alberta Museum.
And for example, it's got this mahogany table that had to be craned in, you know,
100 years ago.
It's amazing building.
And I think it's got like four toilets and about 20 phone lines.
And I'm like,
you're going to run the Alberta government out of there with 20 phone lines,
just plant some bushes out back.
It'll be fine.
You know, it's
like
I remember talking to the person. They're like, what do you mean?
-- I'm like, there's just not enough phone lines
-- or four toilets.
You know,
my house has 34 people live here. We run out of toilets on a regular basis.
Like
four people, man, I got two teenagers. They spend too much time in the bathroom, but
like
when I had my basement remodeled, I'm like, put a toilet down here.
Like that's the only thing I care about.
-- Yeah,
-- I'm actually thinking of
a little bit of remodeling here in my office space and putting in a bathroom.
Seriously, man,
actually being, being, having your office next to a bathroom is lovely.
I'll say because like a lazy slob, you barely have to go anywhere anyway.
All right, we need to end this. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you, everyone for listening.
Go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up the show, not UZ Pound.
Oh, it says podcast hashtag hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a lovely rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks
-- everybody. Bye bye.