This is the open
source security podcast with myself, Kurt
Siefried and my partner in crime, Josh Bresser.
Hello.
So today we're going to talk about what is open source security because that
seems to be a topic that comes up far more often than it should.
And Kurt and I have been kind of buried in
the weeds here for longer than either of us can remember
doing open source security and,
and handling security flaws and kind of all that fun.
And so why don't we start with you, Kurt,
why don't you tell us what is open source security?
What does that kind of mean to the common man, we'll say.
So open source security really applies to sort of three main groups of people.
You got your researchers who are looking for security flaws,
you've got your developers who are dealing with the source code in some way,
either they're the actual upstream
or there's somebody consuming it.
And then you've got your end users, the people actually, you know,
getting work done with this stuff, right?
Because that's kind of the whole point of this.
And so for open source,
what it means is the researchers and the developers and the end users
at a minimum have the ability to view the code.
And in my opinion, more importantly,
they have the ability to influence and change the code. Now.
Like most open source projects are run by pretty reasonably sane people.
I mean, there's obviously there's some exceptions and we all know who they are.
But by and large, you know,
your average open source developer is a rational human being who
wants to ship good software.
And part of the beauty of that is, is about 99% of them will take good code patches,
right?
If you send somebody a code patch that says
it makes this improvement or fixes the spelling
error or it prevents the security flaw.
And there's no, you know, you haven't
significantly impacted performance or something,
they're going to accept that code patch.
And most importantly, they're gonna ship the new version
quickly.
And I think that's one of the biggest differences between open
source and closed source is the majority of open source software.
They ship updates typically on like a weekly basis or, you know, monthly.
Like there's very few projects I can think of that
are on like six month or yearly release cycles.
-- I,
-- I think that is terrifying to a certain group of people and we'll,
we'll come back to that because
I think there's some important lessons in there. But
let's start here. Then
let's say I'm a researcher
and I've not really done a lot of work with open source before.
What kind of, where does it start?
Let's say I've got a project, um, we could pick on maybe open SSL in this case,
let's say I find a security flaw in open SSL.
What does, what do I do? Right. What, what's next?
Well, hopefully the open SSL guys and
they have, in this case, they have an email address that you can contact them on.
Um The majority of projects typically have an email address.
Sometimes it's security specific
and sometimes it's just more general like bug
zut,
whatever domain name
and you can report the issue easily. That's another big thing, right?
With a lot of commercial vendors reporting a
software issue to them is a Byzantine process.
It's,
you know, I've dealt with vendors where I,
I couldn't even figure out how to contact them,
let alone how to contact them for a security flaw.
And with open source,
typically there's gonna be an easily found email address and if there isn't,
you know who the developers are,
right, you can literally either look at the change log or look at the get blame log
and you can see who wrote that code or sort of who the main developer is
and nine times out of 10, if you email them
and say, hey, I have a security issue,
they're gonna respond to you pretty quickly.
Yeah, that's fair. And actually I'm gonna use this opportunity to plug
David Wheeler's badges program as part of the CI I initiative.
We'll have to see about maybe getting him on the show someday. But
uh I'll put a, a note, a link in the show notes as to where to find that.
But then actually,
one of one of the things specified in the badgers program is that you have
a way to be contacted about security issues, which is obviously super important.
All right. So
let's say you're the researcher, you do get a hold of the developer,
what can you expect?
So that depends a lot typically on the size and maturity of the project.
I mean, there's a lot of projects out there that are literally just one guy.
Uh and some of them, you know,
these guys are really busy uh with
their personal lives and their professional lives.
So
all the way up to you have major projects with a full
security team with half a dozen people like the Open SSL project,
you know.
So in the case of the open SSL project,
you're gonna get a response from basically somebody
who does this kind of work full time
or used to do it full time not too long ago.
Uh And in the case of a smaller project,
you're basically gonna get a reply from the guy
that wrote it and he's probably gonna ask you,
you know, what, what exactly is going on and do you have a code patch. And if not,
uh so recently,
we had this happen with LIB Archive where there's been a couple of uh issues found
and we Red Hat reported the issue to the LIB Archive guy
and we worked on developing patches with them and, you know,
he was super happy because not only did we tell him the problem,
but we had the beginnings of a patch,
but as it turned out,
Ashley needed quite a bit of work because we
found some more cases that weren't covered by it.
Right? And that again is part of it.
You know, the beauty of it is rather than just patch one specific issue
and then do it again the next week when somebody else looks at it, you know,
we actually managed to find about a half dozen cases and fix them all at the same time.
So in the case of LIB archive, you know,
he's happy because we're helping him do an update, you know,
it's not just him working on it on his own.
And that I think is one of the biggest things is a lot of people.
You don't often see collaboration like that because
the end result of it will be a code commit from one guy,
right?
But the actual code was written by uh several people. Him, some people at Red Hat
and some, you know, whoever else was involved as well.
OK. So let's keep moving up then
let's say I am a developer using open source code in my project?
What kind of expectation should I have on
the projects where I'm getting that code from?
And kind of what do I need to watch out for?
And, and what are some of the advantages that, that I have in this instance?
So the majority of these projects
will get a CV number for the security flaw and they'll use that CV number,
for example,
uh
in the change log, uh many will now get it into the code commit itself.
So they'll request a CV
in advance of actually doing the code commit.
So that when they do the code commit to update it,
they also include the CV in the change
in
the
commit.
Let's say,
-- I don't know what a CV
-- E
uh sorry,
my apologies.
Uh CV is a common vulnerability and exposures database number and it's just
a fancy way of saying we assigned a number to a security flaw
so that we can catalog and track it.
Uh And the format is CD E hyphen the year.
So like 2016 hyphen and then a four digit or larger number.
And so the beauty of this basically is if you see a code commit or
a change log entry or an email announcement and it has a CV number in.
So you see CV hyphen 2016-1234
then, you know, pretty much
then, you know, pretty much for sure that, that was a security update.
So, what about heartbleed? Does Heartbleed? The CV ID?
Well, so some of these issues get a brand name.
Uh,
to be honest as we've all, as we all know, humans don't really run on numbers,
you know, we run on names.
Um, and of course a number isn't very sexy, you know, but a,
but a name like heartbleed or HTD
-- Epoxy
-- or
deals the proper amount of fear. Right?
Well, not always because Poodle,
you know, some of the names are not quite as fear inducing.
-- You
-- don't
-- like dogs then. That's terrifying. Right.
Yeah. Yeah. I'm not a big fan of Poodles myself
a
lot.
Uh Let's assume at this point, people understand what a CV is and I'm a developer and
I'm using open
source code
and I know
I need to start looking for CV E I DS.
What do you, what's the best way to do that as,
as a developer that maybe isn't involved in the project itself?
So the simplest thing is to watch their announce
uh mechanism, whatever that is typically,
uh a lot of these projects will announce new releases via email.
Um or, you know, they'll basically draw up a new release with a change log.
And personally,
I've been encouraging all of these upstream upstream that I deal with
to
at a minimum, have a change log, right? So that when you release version 1.2 0.3
there's a change log and the change log has entries.
Like, you know, we fix this spelling error,
we fix this CV security bug and we fix this thing.
Uh So at a minimum, there is hopefully a change log and, you know,
so you should be watching your upstream for new releases because you're
gonna need bug fixes anyways whether or not they're security related.
Ideally,
they also have an email announcement because you get push notifications that way.
Right. Email is the only push notification system we have that works.
Unfortunately.
Um Some projects even, you know, they'll have a security web page
uh listing all the CV S currently available
and fixed.
Um And that's typically for the larger projects, you know, like,
say open stack elastic search that those kind of guys.
Um
Probably
saying too that some of those projects have not just a list of the CV E I DS,
but they'll have individual patches.
So you could just cherry pick that one security fix
if that's what you're looking for in your project.
Exactly.
Uh But I would say in general, you know,
if you're consuming open source code and you need to pay attention to it,
probably your best bet is to look for an announcement
mail list because almost all of them have this now.
-- And uh you know, just, well, I guess, read your email once in a while.
-- Sure. Sure.
Yeah,
and that's fair.
So, all right,
I'm my developer
I found a CV E ID announced on a mailing list that I care about.
What would you suggest I do next.
-- So
-- it depends sort of on how you consume the source code.
Uh Some places are into agile development so they can just, you know,
grab a new version and insert it
and run their testing suite,
you know, know that it works
and ship an update of their product.
Other places, you know,
they may have to extract the security patch and just import that code,
you know, because they might be
a good example being car manufacturers, right?
Like there was that recent posting by um, by Mudge showing, you know,
all the open source libraries that Mercedes ships and it's,
it's, I think about 100/100.
Uh and the reality is, you know,
car makers ship software that is relatively static and boring,
you know, they're not running agile development yet.
Uh So a company like that would most likely just extract the security related patch
and import that code into their, you know, system and then up and,
you know, and build a new version
-- or
-- I suppose the,
the sad reality for many projects is they just never update the code ever.
Well, you know, unless
they're being actively attacked or their customers are being actively attacked.
Yeah, they're sadly probably not going to, um,
security is typically seen as a cost center by these companies
and they're certainly not going to do a lot of proactive work, uh,
unless they get caught out.
I mean, if you look at the state of most
commercial software, uh,
you know, you look for security updates,
there's very few vendors doing regular security updates
of the big ones.
Yes.
I, we've been saying for years that it's going to change
and, and someday
we might be. Right.
So,
we'll wait and see. Right.
I think part of the problem is, is uh even if we are right,
we have so much technical debt to deal with.
I would just keep getting that down the road. It, it's fine
next year,
next year, we'll fix it next year. Right.
That's,
I think, I think most of us have some interest built up on that,
that we don't even know what's going on.
But that, that's a story for another day, I think. All right.
So
I think this mostly makes sense if you're a developer,
but let's say you're an end user,
you're a guy running a piece of open source software.
You will probably download it off the internet.
What does that mean for me? Should I care about security in any way?
I mean, I hate to say it but it depends, um
I have
the
-- answer from security, right? It depends, maybe.
-- Well, you know, and it does really?
Because I, for example, I have uh
I
have a perfect example.
I have one of those little Hutu wireless media sharing devices.
Uh
As far as I know, the vendor doesn't ship
updates,
-- let alone security updates. You own one of these two, don't you? I do,
-- actually,
they do have updates. You can, they're hard to find
you, you have to locate them and you can install them. And in fact,
I was
somewhat annoyed at one point because the Hutu, let me tell Net into it,
which is totally a secure protocol, right?
But I could tell that in
and then I updated the firmware and then I couldn't tell it in anymore, which I,
I suspect is for the best because the only way I can
see that coming to a logical conclusion is me breaking the Hutu.
It was still one of those things that I was very
excited to be able to tell that into what is essentially,
you know, a little box.
But uh no, no, in that case. So let, let's go even farther away.
Let's say you have someone running
Mozilla
Firefox, which is an open source web browser
should do. They need to care about security.
Well, if they're browsing the web, then yes.
Uh the reality is especially on the modern web,
there's so many drive by attacks embedded in ad networks and on websites
that I hate to say it.
But if you're running an out of date web browser, you're, you're gonna get nailed.
Now, I think it's also worth pointing out though.
I mean, this, this is kind of a trick question
is that
in the case of Firefox,
they have automatic updates turned on
and you get them magically,
which I think is totally the right thing to do in that case because you're right.
If you're using an out of date web browser, you're just,
you're running around with scissors, right?
Don't do that. That's a bad idea. But I think we can look at,
uh let, let's pick on some, what's another pop, uh, maybe like Libra Office,
which seems relatively popular and I know they have an update mechanism to a degree.
But let's assume they,
you have to manually do that one. I don't,
it notifies you and then you have to update it
so
well.
And one challenge and something a lot of us conveniently ignore,
even with automated updates, like Mozilla
Firefox,
there's still people with bad internet.
You know, there's still people on dial up,
there's still people on satellite internet.
And the sad reality is modern software has gotten so big.
The majority of them, even if they want to be secure,
it's very difficult for them because, you know,
they have to download a half gig update.
Could you,
could you browse the internet today on dial up?
I mean,
ignoring the fact that there are probably people who are,
I want to try this. Can, I don't even know if I have a modem or a way to,
but
I
want to
have your Linux
box filter it but a
lot of the web pages,
the front page of cnn.com and youtube are all, a lot of these sites.
Now, the front page is a megabyte
-- which on dial up will take 10 minutes to download.
-- Right. Right. Oh, my goodness.
That's, that's terrifying. Well, I guess it's not right.
This would be like people riding their horse on the interstate.
It's just don't do that.
I mean, apart from being II, I assume it's illegal, I've actually never
looked into that
as it should be.
But I guess dial up can be kind of seen in that, that light where it's,
it's not only incredibly painful. It, it's dangerous because you're right.
You're never gonna get updates if you're on dial up because,
man, I bet, I mean,
installing updates to my operating system with a broadband connection takes
long enough and I'm impatient and it annoys me every time.
Oh, my goodness. This is terrifying to even think about my, my brain hurts.
-- Sad
-- reality.
I mean, it's,
and I think this is a reason there's still a lot
of insecure systems out there is for lack of bandwidth or
a
lot of, a lot of the systems don't have uh an administrator, you know,
they just have a guy using it
and he doesn't want to pay, you know, 100 bucks a month for a service contract.
Um,
you know, at least with open source, the,
the barrier to entry of having to pay for the updates is quite often removed, right?
You can just get it for free or if you want, you can choose to outsource it to somebody
-- who will handle a lot of it for you. You know,
-- this would be Linux distribution.
Do you talk about or something else?
Well, I mean, the, the common case would be a Linux distribution, you know,
and some of them are free, some of them charge uh for support
and ongoing maintenance.
Um
And then there's also, you know, professional consulting firms, many of which do
open source work, you know,
for the simple reason that there's a lot of people using this stuff.
Uh You know, a great example being web hosting, right,
how many people use wordpress and don't even know that you need to update wordpress,
wordpress.
I'm supposed to be updating my wordpress install,
although doesn't Wordpress have an automatic update mechanism
have made it
automated
um for wordpress but not for the plugins
and some plugins will update automatically.
And
there was just an incident wasn't there with, with wordpress plugins.
It was, I think it was one of the major leaks that happened recently.
It was, they were running
a very outdated plug in,
in their, in their wordpress install
the
Fonseca,
Panamanian law firm.
Right. Right. Those guys,
yeah, that's fair. That's
interesting.
So I, I guess
what, what I'm seeing us head towards here is
from the end user perspective, automatic updates are key.
So if, if you run a project and you're listening to us,
you should have automatic updates.
And if you don't,
you should figure out how to do that because
unquestionably it's important.
And here we approach the sort of the emacs singularity
where if you look at all the major programming languages, for example,
like Java Pearl,
whatever,
they've all ended up having to build and engineer
their own update mechanisms because they're running on platforms
that may not have an update mechanism, you know.
Uh I'm biased. Of course, I run Linux
Red hat and Fedora especially.
And at the OS level, there is an update mechanism,
not only for the Os but for all the stuff they ship,
you know, and you just run yum update and hit, enter,
you know,
and everything gets updated, right?
Like for example, in the windows world, if I install Pearl on Windows,
uh I'm not really clear on how you get updates, but I know it's not automated,
you know, I know Microsoft doesn't ship Pearl updates.
Sure. Well, I mean,
but you can't say
that
in the Linux Universe,
the distributions have this figured out because let's face it.
If you're doing anything interesting,
you are almost certainly using libraries and applications
outside of your walled garden of the distribution.
And so once you exit that universe
updates become a huge problem.
And I think basically where a lot of
that's headed is people using continuous integration systems,
you know, the whole agile C I
landscape of,
you know, we do an update daily or weekly
so you import the code, run your C I run your tests and ship an update.
And I think for a lot of people that can do that, that's how they do it.
And then for the people simply consuming this stuff, I hate to say it. But,
you know, if they had the expertise to do this properly,
they would uh but quite often they don't have the expertise to do this properly,
right?
And
there, you know,
I think the reality is you need to look at some form of outsourcing it, you know,
either using a web host that like, like for example, rather than buying a VPs,
a virtual private server and running your own web server,
you know, you go to say wordpress.com and just
pay whatever monthly fee it is to use wordpress and they
handle the whole experience and update everything,
you know, in
a situation where you can't do that,
then I mean,
you have to develop some in-house expertise
and the good news there is, it's actually it's quite easy to do.
You know, there's a lot of people
who have used open source
uh both as developers and administrators,
you know, quite commonly, a lot of comp sci
grads have had
some exposure to this.
And so the reality is finding it a men who can handle this is, is not super difficult.
OK.
So they might have experience using open source,
but do you think they actually understand
this problem of keeping things updated and watching for security issues?
And I mean, let's even face it man,
in a lot of projects,
they're full of open source code and people don't even know what's all in there.
Right. True. Um The reality is you don't really have to understand this in depth.
You know, I still run some wordpress blogs
and all I do is I,
I hit the update button and then I go and select
the thing that selects all the plugins and hit update all.
You know, that's the extent of essentially my expertise with wordpress nowadays.
I, you know, if one of those plugins breaks, I'm gonna,
I'm just gonna roll back the version or I'm gonna, you know,
check the upstream to see if they're aware that it
broke and make sure they're gonna ship an update soon.
And, you know, because I honestly, I don't wanna be a Wordpress expert.
I just wanna have my blog run.
Right. Right.
You know, that's,
I, I suspect that's,
that's what most people want.
Nobody is in business to be an open source library expert.
They have a product or a goal in mind and open source is one of the many tools
that's going to help them get there.
And, and I think
that's one of the things especially like you and I forget
of we live in our bizarre security universe and we just
expect everyone else should be security experts because why not?
Right. Everyone I know is a security expert. I don't see why you're not.
Yeah.
No.
And the good news there is a lot of the more modern programming languages like, uh,
Rails, you know, N PM,
they actually have security efforts.
Um, so I know for Rails and N PM they both have a module you can import into your project
that will then look at all the modules you're using and consuming
and warn you when they're out of date for security issues.
And we will tell you which ones you wanna update to.
That is fantastic.
We should,
we'll put a link to that in the show notes because that is an awesome feature
that in all seriousness, every project should have.
So if you're a project owner and you don't have something like that, uh shame on you
work on it.
So
uh I, I think the last thing I wanna bring up is
there is an article I sent you from CSO online,
which is kind of talking about open source projects and,
and how people are using them.
And,
and here's the thing that I guess is my, my soapbox commentary for the day is
you read this article and it sounds like
open source is a choice
where you can
use it if you want. And the thing I, that just blows my mind still is.
There's all these people who,
who talk like this, when
in reality you're already using it.
You either know you are.
And so you, you have your kind of, you know, you're known, unknown so to speak
or you don't know
and you should,
so you really need to look around and figure that out and,
and that's the thing that just,
I don't know, it,
maybe it's just the universe we exist in where this is so blatantly obvious.
But,
but I sometimes feel like, you know, we're, we're, I,
I forget the movies but you know where it, it's,
everyone seems insane and there's only that one person who isn't crazy in the movie
and that's kind of what I feel like sometimes around this,
it's like this isn't a conversation anymore.
-- You are using open source if you don't know that. Well, that's shame on you.
-- Right.
I think part of this is because of
open
source, not only one, but it's matured to the point where it's like elevators,
it, it's just there and it works
and you,
you don't even think about
stuff like elevators or revolving doors or
you know, your car, it just, you get in your car, you turn the key
and
it starts and you go
and that's fair and, and that's kind of what you could call it,
infrastructure or commodity or, I mean, there's various terms for that.
But,
but yeah, I, I turn on my faucet water comes out.
That's just the way it is. In fact, actually I had my water shut off.
They were doing construction outside my house about three weeks ago. Give or take.
And
it is
unsettling to turn the faucet on and nothing comes out
and I kept forgetting this was the case and,
you know, I, I, I'm at home and I just kept going to it and turning it on
and at, at first it was the, the, oh, crap, I forgot it's off.
And then after a while I'm like, come on, when's this coming back? Like, let's go.
And I kept turning it on and I guess in hindsight I should have just turned
it on and left it on and I would have heard the noise but for some reason
I felt better getting up periodically turning it on
and having no water come out and then
being disappointed and then grumbling to myself and,
and going back to work.
Well, you know, it's, I mean, during a power outage,
how often have you been wandering around the house?
And you, you walk into a room and hit a light switch
because that's what you do when you walk into a dark room.
That's true. You don't think about it. You just,
it's unsettling. I, I hate power outages. They bother me.
Well,
actually the worst though is an internet outage because
I think all I do is keep running ping
against hosts that that are public waiting for the internet to come back
and
it's,
it's a total waste of my time. But,
yeah, you gotta love it.
Well, I mean, and that's, you know,
that's part of the beauty of this is 99% of the stuff works so well that
people don't even know they're using it.
Uh, you know. Ok. So that's,
I, I think the logical conclusion, we, we're gonna take ourselves to,
if we start down this path and you're right
in, in, in the context of open source, it works well enough until it doesn't.
But the problem, I think from the security aspect is
when you're using unknown open source, when it fails,
it is probably going to fail spectacularly.
I think heartbleed is a great example of this where there were probably
people who didn't even know they had open SSL in their projects.
And then one day someone was like, hey,
this heartbleed scan is failing on your device or your, you know,
application or whatever it happened to be.
And I bet they were like, well, what the heck, where did that thing come from? Right.
Well, and I think a lot of this, I mean,
if you look at the software industry in general,
especially the commercial side of it,
the majority of software projects fail
miserably, you know, they don't deliver on budget or on time. Right?
And so I think part of the challenge is the software industry as a whole is still
not mature.
I mean, compared to like, you know,
engineering bridges where there's seven kinds of bridges.
End of story, you
pick which one you want to build and then you pick the materials and then you're done,
you know,
um, with software, you know, we,
I've been in this thing for 20 years now and had, like,
basically everything I learned up until e everything I knew
that's less than five years old is so laughably obsolete.
-- You know.
-- That's
true.
Now, I'm gonna come back against you though here and,
and I agree with you that bridges are a fine example of engineering done.
Right. Where in general, bridges don't fall down. Ok.
But we've also
been building
for
-- 5000 years.
-- Right. Right. Well, that's my point. Right.
I can build,
or rather
I can't build a bridge in my garage,
can build software in my garage.
And so I think that's one of the great challenges here is
when you have an industry
that is
very difficult to enter into,
such as building buildings or bridges or something like that.
The bar is already really high, but it's like my, I could teach my kid.
In fact, he's learning to write software because he thinks it's neat
and
he's, he's 10.
I mean, there's no licensing there.
There's, he's gonna screw it up and it's gonna be a mess and whatever.
I mean, it's part of learning. Right.
It's not unlike building a popsicle stick bridge.
But now
this would be like, I built a popsicle stick bridge and someone says, oh,
that's neat.
And they took it and they went and put it, you know, in production somewhere and,
and it's like, wait, no, that, that's made of popsicle sticks don't use that.
And that's kind of what I see a lot of this software as where,
where you have people that might start a hobby or a fun thing and all of a sudden,
you know, it's running someone's infrastructure.
It's like, whoa, what just happened there?
Well, and that, you know, that goes back to the, the,
the projects consuming this stuff should be aware of what they're consuming.
You know, that to me is just common sense. I mean,
if you're gonna download random code off the internet and not only run it but,
you know, build things that it runs,
you should probably know what you're like.
You should at a minimum have a manifest and again, going back to open source, that's,
that's something that's actually relatively easy to do in the open source world.
You know, I look at, um,
I've dealt with companies that have bought commercial components.
We have no idea what's in those things. Why is this thing? 300 megabytes?
It converts HTML to PDF.
Why
it's
fine,
you know,
-- that, yeah, try not to think too much about it because it just hurts.
-- Right.
Pay no attention to the man. Behind the curtain, everything is fine.
So I think basically a lot of it boils down to is is maturity and you know,
the ability to take risk like if you're building space shuttle software,
uh my understanding is every line of code is fully documented.
They have
not only who put it there but why it was put there,
right? The majority of source code that's written in the world is like,
uh you're writing, you know, you're writing a,
a cash register application for dry cleaners.
You know, you're not gonna have
that level of software maturity because you don't need it.
You know, if it breaks, you just go out and fix it and they,
you know, they use paper for a couple hours while the cash register is down.
Well, except
we have things like cars
now running random open
source software.
So we're gonna hit the point where if there are bugs, people are going to die,
which is
a terrifying problem that we will speak of another day. I think it is,
let's end it there. All right,
let's say, let's say this. Let's say I'm, I'm a project. I'm a developer.
I've got some open source.
What do you think Kurt is the single most important thing I could do today
to make my life a better place.
Make
sure you know which open
source
projects you're using and subscribe to their announced list
or at least figure out where they do releases and you know, look at them once a month,
their web page
and that is great advice, Kurt.
And if we all did that the world would be a better place.
All right, folks.
So I'd like to thank you for listening to, to the podcast,
the open source security podcast.
And until next time,
take care.