Hello and welcome to episode 56 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
What's New Kurt
forest fires?
-- That's
-- right.
No, I heard about that.
-- Canada is like being ravaged by forest fires right now, which
-- is great.
Yeah. Yeah, we have an air advisory for tomorrow on a scale of 1 to 10.
-- It's going to be a 10.
-- What does an air advisory mean?
Uh So I remember the last time it was a 10, it meant, um, from my apartment building,
I could see two blocks.
That's crazy.
And that, and that was smoke drifting into the city from,
I think it was about three or 400 kilometers away.
That's
so the other.
So, and,
and here's the really ugly part is this year's Canada's 150th birthday and so parks,
Canada, you know, made access to all the parks free, which is, you know,
a lot of people have been looking forward to this.
Um But now they've had to either close a lot of parks or restrict access because,
uh
well, because either they have fires, uh they're expecting fires or option. C,
there's a lot of animals fleeing the fires
-- and find some
-- bears. I even thought of the animals. But that's
true.
No, they don't like fire
and they get
that.
Yeah.
So, you know, and like, so these, the, yeah, you don't want people interacting with,
like brown and black bears because people will get mauled because they're stupid.
And there's,
there's been a thing in the news recently about people like going, you know,
like 5 m away from bears to take pictures.
Don't do that. I'm, I'm not a bear expert, a bear ologist perhaps.
But, uh, yeah, going near bears is a bad idea. Bears
and search for bear chasing cyclist and there are some amazing GoPro videos.
Um, I mean, bears, here's the thing.
Folks, bears are fast and they actually have quite a bit of stamina.
Like they can chase you for a good 23 kilometers.
I'm comfortable saying a bear would almost certainly catch me on bike or,
or running.
Well, I'm not a fast runner. So catch
you running
-- and they can climb. So climbing a tree won't work. It's true.
-- They can climb.
They, they're like the, the ultimate
-- risk tool, right?
-- They're like
300 pound plus murder machine.
Right.
Anyway, anyway, well, well,
whatever happens, stay safe
-- and good luck.
-- Just stay indoors. Basically.
My default setting.
It's true. The sun is outside, stay away from the sun.
That speaking of the sun. That reminds me as well. Black hat
hacker summer camp is next week.
So we'll, we'll see. Hopefully we get an episode out. I will be there.
And, uh, sadly, Kurt will not make it this year next year. Hopefully.
But if, if anyone is there and you want to grab a beer or say hi or whatever, uh,
send me a message, you know, you can direct,
message me on Twitter or whatnot and yeah, I'd love to talk and
it'll be fun. I look forward to it.
Yeah.
Are you going to Defcon at
-- all
-- or I cannot make Defcon or B sides? Which makes me a little sad.
I'm basically flying in doing a bit of black hat stuff and then flying right back out
because I have many personal things on both sides of it that I cannot get out of.
So that's fine.
It happens this year, next year, next year, I'll be there for the whole week.
Yeah. Well, I guess so. What's the big news this week?
On the
security front?
No, I know the thing we wrote down that we talked about was fuzzing
and there have been a couple of stories about it that have been really interesting,
I think.
Yeah.
So, well, do you want to tell everybody what fuzzing is, in case they're not clear?
-- That's true. I suppose it's conceivable. Some people
-- don't know.
And it has grown a lot in the
-- last few years. It has
-- changed. I remember when was it like 09 maybe or 2010?
I think, I think
it was declared the year of the fuzz
because it was like brand new. I mean, I remember when fuzzing just started and ok, so
what it is, right? What it is? So for those of you who don't know
any time you have an application,
well, I shouldn't say any application but you, you, you process input essentially.
So imagine you're a video player, you take in the video file, you do stuff to it and,
and you make it into a video, right?
And that's called your input and you have trusted and
untrusted input and a lot of input is untrusted,
right?
The concept being trusted input is where you know,
it's coming from a trusted source.
Be it another part of the application or conceivably, even
some sort of uh we'll say other machine that you can guarantee is correct.
And then you have untrusted and this would be things like
html off the internet or a video file or whatever,
right?
And so anytime you're dealing with untrusted input, these,
these parsers are super complex
and they have to do all kinds of crazy stuff.
And a lot of them are written in C which we'll get to that point,
we'll get to that.
But, but the point is that
so essentially what happened is someone wrote a fuzz that
took these files and basically just like randomly started flipping bits
and they were incredibly successful at doing
this back when it first started because
you could literally flip random bits and you would crash tons of stuff.
It was crazy how successful they were.
And so basically, now what's happened is many of the easy bugs have been fixed.
So these fuzz keep getting more and more complicated where they,
they have to understand the protocols and understand the
file formats and they're changing very specific things.
Like a great example is I think it was JPEG or no PNG I fuzzed at one point.
But the PNG file has check sums embedded all over it.
And so basically, if you twiddle bits,
you also have to update the check sums or most parsers
are good about noticing bad check sums right away and they bail
so
and, and there are fuzz that do things like that where they'll, you know,
fiddle with some metadata and then they update the check
sum and then they throw the file inside of the,
the parser
and uh quite often they crash. And so anyway, anyway,
the reason this comes up is we ran across a couple of stories that,
that fuzzing was a central aspect of them.
And
Kurt and I got to talking and it's like
we've reached a point where why is fuzzing still successful?
I mean, we, these have been around forever.
They should just be part of a Q A process and, and they're obviously not though.
Yeah, Well, I mean, and
I remember part of fuzzing, the problem used to be compute time.
Right. Fuzzing used to, well, and still does require
a
reasonable amount of compute time.
Um,
and more to the point if you wanted to do your fuzzing, you know,
quickly to do it in parallel, you know, it was very expensive.
But now with the cloud,
you know, if you want to run a job on 1000 machines for an hour,
that's the same cost as having one machine for $1000 right?
So who cares?
Um And I mean, Google was a good example of this, you know,
they have a huge fuzzing infrastructure against Google Chrome, their web browser,
you know, so they're just manging
input constantly.
Um or they did an extreme thing,
we'll link to it in the show notes where
they basically decided to test out PDF parsing.
And so they were like, well, first of all,
we need a corpus of PDF S that basically goes down every single possible code path,
right?
Because,
you know PDF S for example, can have interactive content or they can have, you know,
forms that you fill out or they can have, you know, the the PDF format is,
is actually quite amazing in what it can do.
It's turning complete, actually,
it is actually yes.
Um you can and you can embed stuff into it that is also turning complete.
Um
So it's nested during complete engines
anyway.
So they were like, well, first of all,
we need a corpus of PDF S that go through all the code paths and like, well,
we have that we're Google, we've gone through the internet.
Um, you know, and then they reduced these test cases, you know, these giant PDF S,
they reduce them into smaller and smaller test cases so that they
had basically a set of stuff that would exercise every code path
and then they started twiddling bits and they started, you know, mangling them and,
you know, of course they found a lot of problems
and
the good news though is assuming you build a good fuzz and assuming you run it enough
and then assuming you fix all the problems it finds
you're gonna have a pretty much bulletproof application.
It would be, yeah, I mean, if you did all of that, I,
I think the barrier of entry for finding flaws in your stuff would be really,
really high.
Yeah.
Well, I mean,
heart bleed is a good example of something that could have been found by fuzzing.
-- What did they find it by fuzzing? I think they,
-- they,
they, they did not find it by fuzzing, but it was, it was,
I remember specifically it was something that
could have actually been found by fuzzing.
Like there's
sometimes let's face it, there's, I mean, fuzzing is good but to truly, you know,
for example, fuzzing a web application,
you'd have to understand the web server and the
back end application and do all sorts of,
you know, maybe understand that like
you can only register so many seats on a plane or what the rules about transfers are.
Um
you know, so fuzzing won't
certain types of problems like say logic airs are going
to be maybe much harder to find with fuzzing.
Whereas like an off by one buffer overflow
-- is something you you can very much find
-- with fuzzing.
And not only that, but fuzzing has a, a amount of randomness in it.
So you could literally fuzz something for two months
and have nothing and then start the fuzz up again
and in 30 seconds have crashed just because it
depends on what the randomness you're dealing with is.
Yeah. And then there's also
it gets more complicated.
There's like the feathers the,
but uh there's the fuzz that basically just generate
outputs that you shove into the program and you kind
of keep an eye on the program to see if it dies or not or if something horrible happens,
then there's also the Fuzzs that
allow you or provide hooks into the program. Um
So for example, with Apache,
you can recompile Apache with some hooks to make it much easier to
fuzz so that you're not actually like running the full server locally,
you're, you're basically kind of running it in a more limited fuzzing
uh sense that is a lot faster to test.
Um
And some of these can actually provide some guidance on kind of how bad
this is or where did it actually crash or how bad was it?
You know, like, what kind of crash was it? Right.
Yep. Yep. Yeah. And an American fuzzy lab
is a great fuzz
that can do many of these things and, and in fact,
you're speaking of Apache and one of the stories we reference is a
guy uses a fl against Apache and he found a bug just recently,
which
I haven't heard of a good Apache bug in a long time.
Well, because basically Apache has been fuzzed by the internet
in the sense of all these people who run Apache web servers and
if they consistently crash and you have a reasonably clued in admin,
they try and figure out why it crashed
and then they'll go to the Apache foundation and be like, yo, you know,
when this happens, Apache dies, please fix.
-- That is true. I
-- suppose we've had 20 years of that.
If you have enough users
just you naturally get fuzzing, right?
Your users are literally fuzzing your application.
Yeah, I mean, a great example is like SSL, I mean,
if you're running a major web property,
you will see every single SSL client at some point
and some of them will be broke
and then some right.
Yeah,
you know, I remember um when we, when we were, yeah,
we were going to turn on SN I So server name,
what is it, the SSL server name, virtualization stuff. So what's, what is SN I stand?
I don't remember.
Anyway, server name indicator,
right?
Whereas part of SSL TLS handshake or whatever you indicate what,
which host name you want to talk to.
And the, the, the concern was, you know,
like how many of our clients support or don't support this.
So I think I added like a web bug
to the site, you know, that would then be requested. And like
we essentially had three client types that wouldn't work.
And that one was a Chinese web crawler. So, ok, too bad. Uh,
another was some
weird custom header from a phone.
And the third was like a really, I think it was, must have been a really old blackberry
nice.
So, you know, at that point of course, the answer is yes, yes, we can turn SN I on and,
you know, well, we'll lose like three clients,
right?
This is one of the things that infuriates me all
the time is you have a new standard of protocol
and people will say, oh, it has to be backwards compatible,
which anytime you add backwards compatibility,
you almost always add security issues.
-- But then there
-- are
some
cases you can't have backwards,
you shouldn't ever
is, is the real lesson.
And it's,
it's to support like six ridiculously old clients that no one should even be using
the flip side. However, is if you have backwards compatibility.
You can have a much smoother transition.
-- I don't think that's true. I
-- think so. Well, I
think
we tend to add backwards compatibility, but then we never remove it.
And so for example, if we said, look,
we're going to be backwards compatible for two years
so that we have a two year smooth transition
and then we're killing it.
I mean, that's for example, what Google has done with those cas,
but it's, you know, less and less trusted
is that essentially we're not going to kill it today because, you know,
that will cause a lot of problems.
But
we are giving you a very strict finite lifespan and then,
well, if you didn't fix it too bad,
ok, I'll agree with that.
-- I think that's more than the
-- problem is that almost never happens. We almost always,
you know, a great example being the S
SSL and TLS handshake negotiations
that allows downgraded attacks.
And that has been how many, like how many really bad?
Like every other year there's a new attack and
they almost always focus on downgrading to something that,
that sucks.
-- It's just, well,
-- this
-- is
-- a perfect example.
The crypto ma
is good.
It's the stuff like the key management and the actual connection establishment
that is not so great.
Right. Right.
The reality is I'm never going to try and break Aes, that's just foolish
and nobody has to because all the other crap is broken.
Yeah. There's side channel attacks.
There's, there's people that put their keys into their github
accounts,
uh,
in their code, you know, like, yeah, why, you know,
I'm not gonna bother attacking a S when I
can just search Google for like begin private key.
Right. Uh Actually did you know, you can't search
github
for that anymore?
Yeah, they, they, yes, they did.
They've now blacklisted those terms, which I think is great and I think that is
um
in some ways, the responsible thing to do the flip side being is that,
uh there was that guy, I think we talked about this,
a guy wrote a little script that checks code strings for entropy
and the higher the entropy,
the more likely it is to be something like a password or a key.
And so then he basically sets this thing through, like, you know,
downloading github
and grinding it through the script.
And, you know, of course,
he found a ton of passwords and secret keys and Lord knows what else.
Yep. It's uh it's called Truffle Hog.
Yes,
that's the one.
But now on, on the downside though and,
and this is something I always wonder about a lot and, and I,
I don't have a good answer for it, but
so github
doesn't let you search for this. But
if, if, if a researcher can't help people identify, they've done this,
that means there are probably a bunch of repos that have private keys in them,
they don't know.
And it's very difficult now for people to help them understand they've done it.
-- Yeah. II, I generally agree with that. I mean,
-- I
don't know. I would hope. Does
github warn you? I should try that. I
-- don't
-- know. I
think,
see, and here's actually where we get into a segment we're going to do later.
But here's the thing,
if github actually starts really inspecting your
code and then giving you warnings or
kind of notifications on it like that.
Like,
uh maybe a simpler example would be
github runs everything through an antivirus scanner and
then sort of blocks what is an actual virus maybe or gives you a warning,
then, you know, there might be the concern legally that, oh,
if we don't detect it, we get sued.
Uh
And so I know in the security world there's a certain,
you know, for example, I noticed a flaw in my bank.
-- Do I really want to contact them and maybe have them yell at me or call the police?
-- I,
I understand this, this concern
and
yeah, I, I don't know. I mean, there's just not a good answer for it, unfortunately.
II I,
I,
I think we are moving to more of a
model where everybody gets that everything has security problems
or, you know, you have, uh, Verizon, was it Verizon with their third party
company that sort of accidentally dropped 13 million customer
records into an S3 bucket that was public.
That's happened to everybody
at this point.
Although you know what I love is people keep blaming S3.
It's not S three's fault like you screwed it up.
Well, S3 has amazing access controls. You can restrict by IP address.
You can tie it into, you know,
Microsoft's identity and authorization management system.
You can, you can do all sorts of cool things to really
lock it down. Give it very restricted access. But here's the problem.
People want to share data and sharing data securely is
a lot more difficult than putting it in a public
site. But, you know, with a hopefully secret name
that nobody else can find, you know, I mean,
we used to have this problem with anonymous FTP servers where, yeah, like literally
you'd have mainframes uploading batch jobs with like bank records and stuff to an
FTP site.
-- What was the
-- thing that would search,
was it called Archie that you could search anonymous
FTP?
-- Yeah, there was
-- Archie Jughead and Veronica the three search engine.
Right. Right.
You, you are, you know what people, you're gonna have to go read the Wikipedia page.
-- I'm going to try and explain this. I'm not
-- going to talk about it, but we'll say
-- is
-- like
-- fire
-- and
rocks
back in my day.
Yeah.
So,
yeah. Uh it's, and so yeah, that's, that's one of the questions is, you know,
if you sort of take on this
duty,
do you then kind of have that duty of care or that
responsibility to ensure that it's done correctly or can you basically say,
like, look, we're going to try and maybe warn you about, like,
sticking passwords in your code.
But fundamentally like, you know,
we, we're not going to guarantee anything.
And I guess to the point, the problem more is, is
there's perceived a huge negative downside in that, you know,
somebody sues you or takes you to court or raises a ruckus on Twitter
versus on the flip side not doing this while everybody doesn't do this.
So that's OK.
Right. Just like you said with the fuzzing, right?
We were talking about why don't more projects have a
good fuzzing test suite as part of their unit test.
So actually, I'm gonna,
I'm gonna do a call out here because I can is the Free Radius project.
Actually, uh a guy found a bunch of issues fuzzing
and they have a statement basically talked about how crappy C is.
And then they say that from now on fuzzing is
part of their testing process for all free radius releases.
Like that's amazing, right? That's the way you should be doing it.
I agree 100%.
The problem is, you know, a lot of uh programs don't even have a test suite,
let alone a good test suite,
you know, from a maturity model where a lot of projects are, are no way there.
And that actually kind of frustrates me because for example,
um, there's a, like that guy that found that Apache bug, he did a bunch of work,
you know,
with American Fuzzy Lop and tying some stuff into Apache to make it really robust and
um setting it up. So it would uh record the attacks and do replays because,
you know,
one of the challenges with fuzzing is you
send like 9000 fuzzing test cases to an application
and then it crashes at some point like which one actually crashed it, right?
Did uh did case number one crash it but it took like
-- a minute for memory to fill up or did case 9000 crash
-- it
A
F L is
actually pretty good at helping with that.
Yeah.
Um but basically what I would like to see is why isn't there like a
good web fuzzing framework that you can just easily call from your C I system
when you're doing, you know, your build process
or as part of your final acceptance test and
just have like a really good security fuzzing,
you know,
suite that like has like here's all the stuff we
found in the past and as we find more stuff,
we add it
and you know, all the web servers in the world, like especially like the engine X,
the Apache, the iis, all these guys, you know, flask and all the Python stuff,
all the pearl stuff,
you know, can run this fuzzing test suite against their web server
and, you know, if you pass, you're good. I mean, we're doing the same thing with CV.
Hopefully is we're gonna have a test suite of CV ES
in a reserved block.
So they're, you know,
they're not like real CV ES in the sense of like their real issues.
Um, but there'll be things like, you know, they'll have emojis in the name,
they'll have emojis in the URL.
Like they'll,
it essentially will be if you can process this block
of really ugly but legally legitimate Kosher CV es,
then your CV parser is probably OK.
Nice.
You know, a great example being um
we support language translations of the description now.
So how many languages are there? Globally?
Several 1000.
So what happens if we have a CV E with 5000 language descriptions?
I'm guessing a lot of systems will break?
That's crazy, man.
Yeah,
I can't imagine so.
Anyways. Yeah. So
I, I think it's a maturity issue. We will get there.
I mean, we've already gotten away from shoot the messenger largely.
I mean, that used to be a problem.
It's
true. We are a lot better about that.
Was it Ford officially made a statement saying if you
bring a security problem to us about our cars,
we won't
like sue you. We won't
make your life a living hell. We will actually try and work with you
and you know, from being an open source guy. I'm like, well, duh, of course.
But, you know,
realistically there's still a lot of large companies out there that, like,
I would be afraid to
-- stand up and bring a security issue to them. Yeah.
-- Oh, yeah. Yeah.
No, there, there definitely are.
In fact, this is, I know one of the big arguments in favor of a bug bounty is a bug.
Bounty is an easy way as an organization to basically advertise, you know, hey,
we're on your side, come bring us things and we're not going to come after you.
Yeah.
Yeah, I know. It's a good way to, so like to signal
that. Yeah, you're not going to shoot the messenger in the face.
Right. Right.
So, so anyway, I guess the lesson of the day is fuzz your stuff
and if you're not fuzzing,
do it for you,
that is true.
Right. I mean, people want CV S for their resume now.
Buzzing is a good way to get CV S.
Oh, man, it's true.
You know, I remember back in the day when people would,
would email like OS S security or one of
the other various security mailing lists and say something like
here, I, I fuzz your library. Here's like 25,000 PDF S that crash it
and, and it's like this is not ok.
I, I don't want to deal with this and,
and I remember more than once I went through it and it's always, you know,
two bugs same to
it's just,
they didn't check how it was triggered.
They just ran the fuzz, they dumped it over the wall and
it annoyed me that some project would still give credit where
it's like I just did all of the actual work here.
This guy literally ran a fuzz for an hour and emailed you the output.
Why are we giving him any credit?
I've had the same situation and to be quite frank, I, I won't accept those.
You know, I,
I will say I need a root cause I need
to figure out what's going on or work with the project
to get your CV.
I'm not unless it's something really like, OK, you know,
I here's a network packet that causes Linux to reboot.
That would be totally different
in which case. OK? You will get a CV.
Yeah, exactly.
Well, and I guess this is also a big advantage of a B bo
again where
you know what, I'm not paying you for 9000 PDF S,
you figure it out
and I'll give you a check
or you don't figure it out and then nobody cares. Right.
Well, and,
and this is something I've been looking more and more at is
this sort of idea of market forces in the security world where
a good example being, you know, if nobody is requesting CV ES
for a program, then chances are nobody's like
checking that program
for flaws because the reality is even a mature highly securely
architected and engineered program like open SSH is a great example, right?
Uh you know, they have,
uh was it,
you know, the, the two,
CV, triple seven and was it
776 or 778? I forget it was sequential,
you know, and they had like some really stupid flaws with some old code and stuff.
So everybody has CV S, you know, it's like everybody poops,
those
guys are literally some of the best in the world.
I mean, if I was going to pick people to write secure software,
like those are the guys.
Right.
Yeah.
And um so yeah, I mean, it's just,
yeah, we're at a point where I think,
well, on the one hand, we need more fuzzing but we also need better fuzzing.
Like, because like you said, you know, sending me 9000 PDF S that crash,
it is not actually that helpful because the reality is if you give anybody who
knows how to audit code a code base
and enough time they will find a flaw.
Yeah. Yeah. Right.
That's just how that works.
And especially, you know,
you look at like a code base like the Linux kernel or anything, you know,
these are huge million plus line code bases now with
logic and
um
culture issues from 20 years ago
when things were very different.
-- Yeah. Yeah.
-- Right.
Actually you want to know something really funny.
So I, I don't know if I'm still a part of the project, but I used to be uh
an upstream
contributor to a project called N MH, which is a new mail handler.
I think it's called, it's,
it started out at the RAND Corporation in the seventies, right? This was like,
this is like the craziest email program you can imagine. It was,
it was amazing.
It could literally do anything. And I'm not joking when I say literally do anything.
And so if you knew how to use,
it was super powerful, of course, it took, you know,
like four years to learn how to use it correctly.
But, but once you had it down, it was great, right? But anyway,
I remember at one point,
I thought I'm going to run this all through valgrind
and I'm gonna fuzz it out and see what happens.
Right?
No, no,
it was like, totally clean.
But here's the thing, here's the thing
in the seventies.
These systems had so few resources like it had to be tight and you
couldn't have memory leaks and you couldn't have logic errors because it was,
it would take the whole system down.
Well, yeah, true. You didn't really have true multi user systems and segmentation.
-- It
-- was
-- amazing how good the code really was.
I mean, granted it looked kind of ugly because it was using some old like K and R style.
But I was like,
I was flabbergasted by how few errors I found fuzzing and using Belgrand against it.
It was just, it was amazing.
Well, it's, if maybe we'll put this in the show notes,
but there's a good story about the,
the code and the quality of the code behind the space shuttle.
And it, it is amazing like they very,
they actually very strictly try not to work overtime because you know,
tired people write bad code.
Every line of code is documented and not just documented in the sense of like,
oh this piece of code is supposed to do this.
It's no, this code exists because of this meeting.
We made this decision and decided this would happen this way.
And therefore we have this case that blah, blah, you know, the whole
-- there's that whole cradle to grave kind of aerospace thing of, you know,
-- but
now you
see
exactly why this is not general purpose in any way.
And
I wonder what they charged or rather what it costs them per line
of code.
But when you think about what a code flaw in a spacecraft costs
a great example being that Ariane launch where I think what they got Indian
-- mixed up or something, then they had to
-- destroy it. That's true because
-- there was
-- several 100 million
dollars
that
-- you can, you can probably justify it in
-- that instance.
Or the Mars orbiter that like whoops metric imperial close
enough, we lost like half of the Mars or, or dose, haven't we?
The number is staggering.
Well, when you think about the problem though, the problem statement,
let's send a small spacecraft slash robot
to another planet.
Well, that's like the, the, the, the current two or one. Which one?
I forget what it is. The one that, the,
the sky crane that, that lowered the latest one down. You know,
I, I stayed up till like, three in the morning. I think it was
paying attention to this because it was, it was fascinating and it's funny because
there's all these people on the internet watching a live stream
and there's nothing's happening.
Like they're waiting for like, literally three beeps.
And then
I think
what a 26 minute transmission.
It was something crazy. I know.
And it was unreal and then, and then, like it lands and I thought, wow, that's neat.
And I went to bed.
It was the most
uneventful,
-- the
-- fact that they did manage to land something the
size of a mini cooper on Mars without breaking it.
-- I mean,
-- not
just,
and it landed, they lowered it from the sky crane.
It was amazing.
Anyway. Anyway, anyway,
-- all
-- technology is amazing. It works.
Why don't we move on to the topic we've actually been waiting for,
which is net neutrality and security
-- and why it's such a great thing for security.
-- That's right.
I mean, net neutrality is a terrible thing for security.
I'm going to take the contrarian view.
You're going to say it's bad for security.
I
understand the
worst idea ever.
I've been reading Republican Talking point.
Right.
Fox News.
So,
so here's the intent is
net neutrality.
It's been a topic in the US for years, I guess.
And,
and Kurt and I decided it would be way more fun to talk about
if one of us took a contrarian view and one of us didn't.
And so Kurt is going to represent the, uh, ignorant class, we'll say,
and I'm going to be the side of good
and say that net neutrality is bad
and, and Kurt is going to tell us why it's not
or rather wait,
you're saying net neutrality is bad. I'm pro
this is so confusing already.
Yeah.
And just for the record, I am for net neutrality,
I am also a Canadian and we just recently had our court
system decide that net neutrality is the way things are here.
So I'm quite happy about that.
But I believe it is important
to me, it's kind of like a, you know, it's like the prosecution,
you should have a vigorous defense and quite frankly, if the defense
can sort of outsmart the prosecution, then, well, let's face it.
The prosecution maybe didn't do a very good job.
And so I'm going to take the contrarian view that net neutrality is
probably literally the most terrible thing for security on the internet ever.
And, well, we'll see what happens.
Well, why don't you start? Because I, I have no idea why you'd even think that.
-- And so I'm curious what kind of talking points you come up with?
-- Ok.
So, fundamentally, well, first of all, let's define what net neutrality is for the
rest of this conversation,
right? Because
I think that's one of the problems is it's a very sort of nebulous set of ideas.
Um,
so I'm gonna basically restricted largely to the
sort of that idea of common carriers.
So,
um, a lot of people would argue that, you know, the, the network,
the internet rather is
akin to infrastructure now,
uh, such as, you know, public roads, gas, electrical
telephones
and that effectively, you know, these companies providing
network service should, um,
provide service and that's it,
they shouldn't modify the traffic or give preference to the traffic.
Uh,
and that essentially, you know, back to that common carrier status of, you know,
I don't know what's on my network.
We just move packets,
right? Like it's got a valid IP address we wrote it
right end of story makes sense. Um,
you know, and, and then the, the, the really tough problem becomes is, you know,
you have network providers that are sort of the last mile,
you have network providers that are more like, like sort of international
providers. And then you have providers that are both
right, like my ISP Shaw is,
it's the last mile, but they also like, go down all the way to the US
on their own. You know, networks
because they're big.
Well, it's also worth noting here as well that,
that some historical perspective is at least in the United States,
the National Science Foundation actually used
to basically own like the internet backbone
and they sold it
three
years ago.
Ok. Right.
And then to further complicate things around network. The tr
of course is that we have laws going back to, I believe, 1934 probably
than that. Yeah.
Title two is in fact part of the Far Reach and Communications Act of 1934.
So, yeah, we've got almost 100 years of law for technology.
That's only like 40 years old.
What could go wrong.
It's, it's tricky man.
Well,
and it gets even trickier because a lot of
the old laws specifically call out telephones instead of,
you know, some talk about communication devices, some talk about telephones.
And so how do we apply? This stuff? Doesn't make sense? We don't know.
Yeah.
Well, and,
and even today defining what is a telecommunications provider like Skype,
uh, they gave me a phone number
two
phone numbers. I mean, my favorite example of this actually is paypal.
Paypal isn't a regulated financial institution.
And so they're always like doing some dodgy things you hear about that.
Like if a bank did
the bank, the bank
get sued and lose. Right. And so
it's a great example of which is the right way. I don't know.
So, anyway, anyway,
so anyways, so many people would have, you believe that we should just have this,
you know, network that just carries whatever
and the traffic is never manipulated or given preference or anything like that.
The reality is how are we going to innovate new services?
If, for example, we can't prioritize traffic if we can't allow people to say, look,
you know, I really want my video streams to work
um, at the cost of, you know, my bulk downloads, maybe not working so well. Or
how do we secure the internet if we just allow people to do whatever they want on it,
you know, shouldn't we be maybe running I DS and IP S systems
at the national level,
-- you know, and blocking the bad traffic from other countries
-- like China do that,
they run the national firewall. Um Unfortunately, that's more about,
uh that's less about sort of security for the
end users and more about security for the state.
Right. I see. See. But, ok, so that's kind of the whole point, right? Is
when you have a large organization
in charge of, we'll say monitoring traffic
and, and especially when it's kind of the network owners,
they're going to put their well being ahead of the end user well being, which,
which I, I think is kind of expected.
Right.
Well, and part of my thought process there would be is, you know, uh
in general, I would hope that the government of a country Uh I would hope that,
that government's interests are generally aligned
with the people of that country,
especially
when you have a democracy such as America where
you guys elect a president and congressional representatives.
Um
But in general, you know,
I would assume your government kind of represents your interests otherwise.
Well, things have really gone a bit sideways.
Man. There's like 12 hours of content in, in your statement right there.
But let's, let's look at it this way. Right? Is,
is right now,
it's not even about the government necessarily
representing the interests of the people.
It's the fact that you have these network owners that are arguing, it's our network,
we should be able to do what we want with it.
And then
you have kind of the, the people are, are, I think in general saying, you know, we,
we don't want you to do that because we don't trust you.
And I mean, let's face it. I think in many instances,
your network provider
can really be viewed as an adversary in a way
where
-- can you trust them to not mess
-- with your
company that you deal with?
Right. Yeah. Yeah, I won't disagree
-- with. I mean,
-- when I buy breaks, they don't,
they're making breaks at
a certain price point and quality,
they're not making the absolute best breaks, they can at like a 0.1% margin.
You know, they're trying to make a healthy profit margin.
Right.
And, and that that is fair.
And I think that's what it, what you're going to get with net neutrality is
if, if you have an instance where the,
the providers
can mess with traffic,
you know,
they're going to make decisions that maximize their profits essentially.
And, and I don't blame them for that mind you.
-- I'm not saying
-- they're wrong on the flip side. For example, Shaw is a good example.
I have a residential Shaw connection.
I cannot connect out to port 25
anywhere.
So I can't send email from my home system
to random servers on the internet, right? I have to connect through,
you know, Google or something.
-- I mean,
-- that that's a great example we can use with security. Is that a good thing?
And conversely, I know at some points, I don't know if they still do this,
but I know at some points for Shaw,
some network uh neighborhood notes were so congested with SMB attacks and traffic
that they actually had to start blocking, you know, ports.
What is it 135 through 139 and uh 445 is CIFS because quite literally these
people had like windows XP machines or
windows 95 machines that had never been updated
and they were spewing out so much traffic. You know, if you get like 50 computers on,
you know,
say out of 1000 and they're all spewing out like five or
10 megabits per second of network traffic to their local subnet,
that's a problem
and that is going to degrade the heck out of the network.
And so in some cases,
there were some network uh neighborhood nodes where they literally had to block it,
sort of at that point of presence model where you know
that that node is servicing 100 or 200 or whatever customers.
And, and you can easily make the argument
that
the, the network providers should be taking some steps to, to in that case,
they're protecting their end users,
but they're also protecting their own resources and,
and this is where it gets super cloudy because
if you argue, like stay off my network, you know, get off my lawn.
You kids sort of thing of, I don't want you touching anything.
But at the same time,
like I like having fast internet and I'm glad my neighbor's
Windows X and my neighbor does have a Windows XP machine.
He asked me questions about it all the time and my answer is always buy a new computer.
But anyway, he legitimately has one
and knowing that
hopefully that thing isn't running amok, you know, and ruining my,
my local broadband because it's spewing viruses or goodness knows what it's up to.
But you know what I mean? I,
I'm
on
the
side in Canada, we've traditionally had fast internet speeds
offset by data caps,
right.
We've had data caps here for
quite a while now. Going on a decade.
And so, you know,
depending on which speed you buy and kind of how much
you get like 100 gigs or 500 gigs or a terabyte.
Um And most I SPS uh charge, it's I believe uh $15 a month for unlimited use,
which obviously I, you know, I pay for that because
um
you know,
uh
yeah, I mean, Netflix with two kids
that
-- eats up a lot of bandwidth.
-- I'm familiar with this problem.
So
here's the question though is so
like I can say that I think blocking part 25 is good and blocking S and B tr
you know,
here's the question and here's where it gets really crazy, right? Because I'm
nothing is ever black and white, right?
But now if,
if the internet provider decides to say uh
slow down Netflix on purpose and tell Netflix,
if you give me, you know,
10 bucks,
I'll speed up your connection,
right? Or rather I, I get whatever
I,
whatever
-- it did it did,
-- it actually happened because
so traditionally with networks,
um the way it works with the network is if you want to tie into the internet,
you basically have two options,
either one you pay to tie into the network
or b you are so large or so fantastically amazing
that people want to tie to you.
And so they will do that uh for free and do like an exchange.
So a good example being, you know, a company like Google, let's face it. Right.
Google is huge
and
customers want to access Google and have it be fast.
So it's in the network providers interest to, you know,
peer with Google and have a connection to Google.
You know,
network providers do that where they have peering agreements and they basically,
they're each sending so much traffic to each other.
It's not worth trying to figure out who owes who, what.
Yeah, it's well or more to the point,
maybe the traffic is not sort of symmetrical because for example,
like I send a lot less traffic to Google than they send to me.
Right? Like I'm downloading a ton of email. I'm downloading search results. I'm
you.
Right.
I make one request to youtube and then I
watch a video giving them your valuable personal information.
Exactly.
Well, but from the i from my network providers point of view, you know,
if they don't have good connectivity to youtube,
I'm gonna go find a new network provider,
right?
So basically Google is amazing enough that, you know, they can,
they, they want to
with.
And so what happened with Netflix is I think
it was Comcast was basically making the case of,
you know, people send very little data to Netflix.
Netflix sends a huge amount of data to us that they're
not paying for it, which is a factually correct statement. Um
However, on the flip side, you know,
people are arguing that the customers of Comcast had
paid for the data and were requesting it.
Yes.
And I think,
um,
it's hard to argue for Comcast,
even though I don't live in the US. I've read so much about them.
But anyways having said that
there, you know,
we can go back to that sort of protecting your own network and making sure it works.
Now,
also, on the flip side is, uh Netflix is big enough that they actually build these,
you know, racks of machines that will host content and they will,
you know,
if you provide them with a rack electricity and uh I think it's 10 gigabit internet,
they'll drop these machines in on your, you know,
uh data centers so that the content is served more locally rather than, you know,
from uh from Netflix's head end in Amazon.
And that to me is also a great example of,
you know, where we, where network network neutrality breaks down
in that,
you know, we want things, for example,
we want companies to provide the data more to the edge.
So it's maybe faster and more reliable,
right? We want to give people an incentive to maybe do these things
rather than to say, look carrier.
You're just going to have to make sure you have
a lot of bandwidth with Google or Amazon because that's where
-- we host and
-- then you can even make the argument
would Netflix have done that if Comcast hadn't played tough.
Yeah. And, and I, I don't know.
I, I honestly suspect they, they might not have because what's their incentive
to work with, with someone like Comcast in this instance? And so
-- this is, I mean, it's super cloudy and it's super crazy and,
-- well,
the problem is this isn't a technical problem so much
as it is also a business and worse political problem.
Uh,
yeah.
Yeah.
And also a legal problem because we also have case law because you,
there's certain things you can't just
decide to do certain things if you have like
80 year old telecommunications law that applies to you.
Right.
-- Right. Right.
-- You know,
unless you pull a paypal and you're like, I'm not a bank, we just
do money,
-- but we're totally not a bank.
-- Right. Totally not a bank. I think Netflix is,
is maybe tricky and,
and not as obvious because there are some super obvious things that can happen.
Right. You could have,
I, I, if a network provider was detecting viruses on the wire,
would anyone really complain?
Probably not.
Right.
But now if a network provider decides one day that, uh, you can't go to
Breitbart News because we don't like
what they're saying.
Now you have the question of, well, is that ok,
or what if they say one day that MS NBC is, is terrorist propaganda?
We're not, we're not letting you go there.
And so it, it, there's certain lines of fuzziness,
-- I think that start to
-- emerge that's already happened with, you know,
government censorship of sites, for example, in the UK.
Right. They have that big, uh, by default.
I think pornography is supposed to be blocked and you actually have to apply to
-- the porn unblocked on your internet connection.
-- That happened.
I don't know if that's happened yet,
but I'm pretty
sure that
-- they were talking about it. I mean, yeah,
-- that's actually a great example too.
Right.
Like things like pornography or content that you
might be considered taboo as to social norms
and just because you don't like, it doesn't mean I don't like it
or, or I think there's anything wrong with it. Even
the current legal status of ISP web blocking is voluntary
in the UK for this. But there are a number of I SPS doing it.
-- Why would you do that voluntarily?
-- Honestly? Um, I have kids,
uh,
you know, having
I, and now to be clear before people send me hang
up, I get that, like, blocking stuff on the internet and trying to, like,
somehow sanitize it.
So my kids only see the quote unquote good stuff.
Yeah. No, I get that. That's not,
that is a social problem that is very
difficult to solve with
technology and more to the point,
I don't think technology is the right answer because at
some point my kids are gonna, like,
have a friend with an unlocked iphone that can just browse whatever.
Right.
So, to be clear,
I'm I I see this as a social problem
that is probably best solved through social solutions,
like teaching my kids good judgment.
Um But on the flip side, it would be kind of nice. Like a great example, youtube
has an app on the iphone and ipad kids, youtube
with
somewhat sanitized content
-- for
-- youtube.
Even if you're not a kid has, you can,
there's certain explicit content it won't show you
unless you're logged in and have like the,
I'm over 18 box check
ticked or whatever.
And on the flip side, the kids youtube,
my one kid was somehow got into some videos about
weapons of mass destruction and he was talking about s
palma and smallpox.
-- And
-- did you get a visit
from
the authorities?
-- But
-- when he brought up, for example, he was trying to,
he was trying to talk about um,
three stage nuclear fusion fission devices,
but he has a hard time pronouncing the word.
Is this the same child you have that uh, like destroys villages in Minecraft.
I'm going to get to tell people I knew you Sunday, Kurt.
Yeah.
Oh dear.
But I mean that's the thing, right?
I personally,
I would kind of like for there to be a youtube that
doesn't talk about weapons of mass destruction because at one point,
my child was very afraid of black holes and couldn't get to sleep
because he was afraid a black hole was going to destroy the earth.
That's, it. Might, I mean, who's to say? Ok.
Well, yeah, I get that but there's a certain sort of, you know, let's just,
let's pretend the world is softer and fuzzier than it actually is
-- so that my six year old can get a good
-- night.
It's not gonna happen tonight. Go to bed.
That's what, that's that book or the f to sleep, man. Right.
Yeah, pretty much. I was read by Lamar
Burton, which is amazing.
Right.
And so,
you know, on the flip side as a parent,
I have looked at some of these blocking programs, but by and large,
the majority of them are terrible.
Uh, just from a technical standpoint. It's like,
I mean, I,
I'm actually waiting for one day for Tavis Ormandy to
start looking at these things like he did the antivirus program
-- and they're going to be an amazing train wreck.
-- It would be a train wreck
anyway anyway.
-- And
-- then of course, the, the content list they use are, are like bad because,
you know, they're blocking like, uh, breast cancer on Wikipedia
or, you know, prostate cancer.
So, so we're kind of in the weeds here. But I think here's,
I don't think there's a good answer to this.
I mean, I like the, the, the crazy liberally. Let's, let's all be friends.
Part of me thinks
that letting your ISP control anything in any way is wrong.
But then there's also a part of me that says
some of this isn't the worst thing in the world
and it's really hard to draw a line and, and who, who gets to be the police,
who decides what's good and what's bad.
And
I, I think what I would really like to see would be
proper competition
where like right now I, I have is it Charter?
I think it's charters, my current internet provider
and my options are AT&T or charter and I don't really like either.
And I literally have no other options.
The problem there you have is in Canada, for example, I have cable,
like I have physical cable and physical phone line coming to my house.
So I have cable uh
cable modems and Ds L as an option for
uh network service currently and hopefully at some point
in the near future fiber optics as well.
However,
um so for example, the Ds L uh
tell us physically owns all the lines and infrastructure in like Edmonton
and they are legally, they have to
uh provide access to other parties like tech Savvy. So I actually have DS L from Tech
Savvy
uh because they were
quite a bit cheaper than tell us and it's a backup line.
So I'm not super worried if it goes down for a day or two.
So that's the other dirty secret, right?
If like the tech Savvy stuff breaks, tell us is like, yeah,
we'll fix it when we fix it because you're not really a customer of ours so too bad.
Um But the problem we have in Canada is if you look at,
say the internet plans between major carriers like Shaw and tell us
uh the plans are basically all identical in what they provide and what they cost.
And so we have what's called an Oligopoly
where it's not a monopoly uh except
we have multiple companies providing
essentially the exact same product
and they just happen to, for example, do a $5 price hike
uh within the same month. And I
here's the best part. Shaws
their, their phone support.
I was kind of annoyed because I'm like, why is there a $5 price increase?
Like, what am I getting a faster service or something?
Because, you know, seriously, if you're gonna,
if you're like upgrading the network
and making everything twice as fast, five bucks a month. So
I must say this, I, I don't think I've told you this before, but
so I,
I used to be a Time Warner customer and then I think
it was charter bought them and now they call themselves spectrum.
And
when that happened,
the amount of money I pay for the internet went down and my speeds doubled,
which is like in the history of internet that has never happened,
it will never happen again.
Yeah.
But anyway,
Shaw's excuse officially for this $5 price
increase is that they had more customers.
Ok? Like they had more customers now.
So they have to, like, totally checks out, build out their network and stuff and I,
I felt like arguing.
Like, so economically what you're saying is if you get enough customers,
you go bankrupt because
apparently
apparently you have some sort of reverse economy of scale for
your network which honestly shaw being run the way it is.
I believe.
I, I mean, I know people that used to work for Sean, they all left because it's just,
yeah.
Um
but yeah, I mean, so
yeah, I it's, it's frustrating because yeah, I get it on the one hand,
I don't want,
you know, one day to be like, oh,
I can't access Facebook because that's an extra five bucks a month.
But on the flip side,
you know,
there's a good vice documentary talking about those
bulletproof hoster and all the horrible stuff they host
and I don't necessarily maybe want, especially if I'm a network provider.
I really probably don't want that on my network or,
you know, if there's a tax like a great example being Amazon,
uh go log into your EC2 instance and go run N map
and scan out to some other host
and you
basically get
an angry email within five minutes saying like, please explain yourself. Yeah.
Yeah.
And
I,
you know, I, I guess here's what I keep thinking of is
there are, we'll say societal norms and certain expectations
and
I don't think there's ever going to be a super good answer to any of this stuff.
But I think
you can't,
you can't let these companies kind of do whatever they
want because you're going to end up with crazy talent.
Right. Right.
But at the same time,
I think having it be total wild west is probably not ideal either because then you end
up in situations where you've got Windows XP machines
kind of ruining the internet for everyone else.
Well, just like back in the day spam, you know,
when spam started it was whatever and then it got to what 98% of you
was.
Right.
And I think now it's down to 80 or 60 or whatever,
but more to the point,
spam filters have just gotten to the point where it's
not really a problem on the flip side though.
We're spending how many tens of billions of dollars a year on anti spam.
Yeah. Yeah. Right.
And
II, I guess I hate saying this and I know there's people that will probably disagree,
but
this is probably where having a sane regulating body
comes into play
because you need people to be able to look at something
going on.
I
know that's, that's the trick, right? Is
we, we don't know.
I mean,
I think honestly if you kind of look at the way things have worked up to this point,
I would say it's been relatively sane.
Right?
And,
and that's going to be the challenge going forward is
regardless of what happens.
Can we continue to maintain some level of sanity? Because, and let's face it too.
All right,
if, if your cable provider one day says you have to pay $5 to access Facebook,
like there's going to be an armed revolt in the streets, right?
That, that is how revolutions happen.
Well, I, I don't think so because for example, the I SPS across Canada Jack,
the rates up by five bucks a month
-- but
-- not just for Facebook. You know what I mean?
And, and no, but just
this kind of customer abuse, you know, it, it becomes, well,
it's like any abusive relationship, right?
You get used to the abuse and, well, you know, he, he hits me but he loves me.
Right? And that's kind of, I feel that's generally speaking
that is people's relationship with their ISP. It's like, yeah,
you know, he hits me but he lets me like uses internet. So e
you know,
my, my bill keeps going up and service keeps getting a little bit wonkier.
-- But, and you know, what are you going to do?
-- Right.
Yeah, I, I don't know.
It's also going to get interesting in the future because I, a lot of young people
use their phones for almost everything
and now we have a whole new dynamic there because
you're not using a wire strung to your house,
you're using your phone that's going over the air and
like there's not a lot of cell phone providers either.
But if you kind of look at all of that
as one,
we're almost reaching a point where there's going to be competition here.
I don't know.
I, yeah, no, again, in Canada we have an
Oligopoly
because you guys have what Bell is pretty much your, you're really only have
about four national kind of, well,
it's complicated. But, I mean,
yeah, like, tell us, for example, was so hated that they actually created a new brand
that like piggyback anyways.
Um
But see,
and part of the problem too that uh with net neutrality is on the technical side,
something to remember is
everything is port 443 now, right?
-- Everything is SSL TLS encrypted http
-- because our providers are adversaries
-- and
-- also it's a good protocol, it works,
right.
And so now the problem becomes is, you know, you can't sort of be like, ok, well,
video traffic we're gone to, you know,
throttle a bit so that like stuff like SSH and email works.
The reality is, for example,
like video traffic is now the thing for bandwidth
use and that's what people use a lot.
And so,
you know,
you can't really throttle video selectively other than to say like, ok,
everything touching youtube or everything touching Netflix.
Right. Right.
Well, and there's been I SPS, for example, that actually on mobile,
uh we're doing, what was it? I think they were doing TLS and SSL interception and then
actually downgrading the video and smushing it a bit
before sending it like over the airwaves to yourself.
That is horrifying.
Actually, I'm a T mobile customer and they do that where if, if I use there's,
there's like a whole, they've got a website with a ton of video.
It's most of them for what it's worth.
But basically, like when I use Netflix, they only let me use the 480 P feed to my phone.
But I do not pay for any of the data
that, that I'm getting from.
-- And
-- that's something. It's, I mean that is totally not net neutrality.
I love it, man.
I'm not gonna lie.
I
I get two gigs of data per month. So unless I'm on Wi Fi, I'm not watching video.
And if I could watch Netflix,
for example, on my phone for free, not consuming my data.
That means for example, I could now watch Netflix out of the car,
-- right?
-- It's, it's amazing
-- and
-- my kids would love that
and, and I do so for my cell phone, I have a data plan that claims unlimited data.
If you use like a ton of it, they, they throttle you and things like that. But,
but then I have a my I,
I carry around when I travel
and I get like 10 gigs a month on that.
But obviously, if you're watching Netflix, you can eat 10 gigs in a couple hours,
right?
But with this. I can literally watch all the Netflix I want on my laptop
and I use zero data. Which is,
that's sweet. Right.
I mean, in fact, they're kind of screwing themselves with that deal because
if it wasn't for that, I would have a more expensive data plan. Probably
so I could watch
-- the exception
-- to the rule. Right. Most people aren't willing to pay more than five.
Like, it's funny to me that people will gladly spend five or $6 a day on coffee.
But, yeah, you, like, try to raise their internet rate by five bucks a month and they,
you know,
they lose their money.
I know.
Anyway, it's, it's probably time to wrap this up, I guess at the end of the day,
as much as I'd love to say, net neutrality is evil and earth crap.
I keep screwing this up.
Maybe
you heard it
here,
Freudian Slip. I, I know it's a terrible idea anyway.
You know, there isn't an obvious answer to any of this and I guess what it,
what it really comes down to is we just need to keep paying attention
and we need to understand what's going on and, like,
this is just true of security in general.
Right. Like,
if you're not paying attention
something bad is gonna happen
and, and that's just, well, heck, that's life in general. The
world keeps changing.
It, it does and,
and we have to change with it and we're trying to understand what's going on and,
and I suspect the real reason we have these debates
is because you have companies and organizations and even people
that they don't like change, they don't want to see change.
And so they're going to do things to try to keep things the way they want them to be.
And, and let's face it.
You're gonna lose at the end of the day, you might be able to slow it down a little bit,
but you're gonna lose.
Right.
Change is coming.
It's gonna happen,
get used to it.
All right, cool. Well, anyway, thank you, Kurt. That was,
you know what I came out of this being way more receptive to the
anti net neutrality people now than I was at the beginning of today.
So
-- funny enough, it's
-- like most things, it's a,
every time you have the intersection of politics, law, technology and
the social side of things. Plus it's global in nature, right?
Like Canada has one set of rules and we next door to the US that has a totally
different like, and things like data caps, not data caps, net neutrality,
not net neutrality.
You know, you have an unlimited
uh network plan for your phone uh data plan rather
-- I get my two gigs a month.
-- I, I, yeah, I burn through two gigs in like a week. So
-- I'm not, I mean, I
-- have to be very careful when I'm, you know, traveling this
-- year,
-- right? I believe it, man. Uh Anyway, anyway, so, so thank you.
This was an amazing conversation. Thank you, everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com
and get the show notes as well as links to Twitter and Facebook.
You can you see Pound Os S Podcast hashtag and I guess as a bit of housekeeping
at the end as well is we've recently changed providers for the hosting the MP3 files.
So if you're hearing this, you don't have to do anything
but just kind of. So, you know, it's, it's not on soundcloud anymore.
We're using something called Libin
now, which,
which seems to be working well enough and
if there's any weirdness or anything you don't
like or anything you can think of that we should know about by all means,
let us know and I will deal with it as quickly as possible.
So, yeah, until next time, Kurt have a great day, man.
You too. Thanks, folks. Bye bye.