Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Seyfried and my partner in not
having private conversations and Josh Pressers.
That's right. But before we get to the topic of the day,
I have very exciting news.
-- Victorio is on the switch. I learned this like three days ago.
-- How do you?
It's like when somebody did a Starcraft challenge with only the mouse and like,
you know, this was a good player
-- and playing Starcraft with only a mouse is like, it was like five A PM.
-- Ok.
So look, here's the thing. It sucks. Right. I'm totally willing to admit.
Does it like have, like at least snap to focus or something?
-- There's a snap to focus. You can, you can turn on?
-- Ok.
Because I'm like, if it doesn't do that, like
rights, you have to focus or you can turn on like a little cursor,
you can move around with one of the sticks
and it's terrible and it's hard to play.
But here's the thing, the fact that I can take Factorio, like anywhere I go now
delights me in Factorio is generally low key enough that I don't have to have, like,
super quick reactions.
Well,
because you're not doing those speed runs like that
German guy who's down to 124 and change.
-- Right.
-- Right. Exactly.
Like I can, I can take all the time I need and I'll just go, like, turn the machines off.
-- If there's too much coal coming out or whatever.
-- Can you sync the games?
Like, so can you basically start on your switch? Move it to your PC and vice versa?
You know, I haven't
looked to see if I can do that. I don't think so.
I haven't seen anything that suggests I can and not that I necessarily would.
-- But
-- because I'm trying to think because I think Factor like doesn't it,
you can save because hearts of Iron, you can save to the cloud Factor or can you save?
-- But
-- that's, that's steam, that's
Steam thing, isn't it or is it? I don't play Hearts of Iron. But I know most of my same
like cloud things is just steam.
I would assume it's, yeah, you know,
it probably is a cloud service because every game is
not going to build their own back end storage network.
That would be,
I guess one other, one other fun fact for video games is Little Inferno,
which is 10 years old, just released DLC like a couple of weeks ago,
which I just found out about literally
-- yesterday from recording and I'm very
-- excited.
I have no idea what that is.
It's
unexplainably odd. That's what it is.
You either love Little Inferno or you don't get it.
It's not a game calling it a game is
an incorrect description of what Little Inferno is.
Is it a multimedia experience?
-- Sure.
-- We'll
-- call
-- it
-- that.
-- See.
And that's one thing I've always wondered, like, like,
because remember when Mist came out and people were like, is this a game or just like,
are you messing with people?
-- I
-- mean, Mist had puzzles,
I
guess. Little Inferno technically has puzzles.
So maybe you could call it a puzzle game, but it's a very unique experience,
we'll say,
-- and you burn a lot of stuff, which is fun. This is
-- weird. So it's made by two Kyles.
Uh
It's, is it two
-- K? It's a tomorrow corporation, I thought, yeah,
-- it's Kyle,
it's Kyle Gabler and Kyle Gray. So it's like producer KG
designer
Kyle Gabler and Kyle Gray
artists, Kyle Gabler and Kyle Gray. Writer Kyle Gray. Composer Kyle Grable.
I mean,
I love it when people do that when they put
their name like infinite number of times in their,
their game or whatever they did.
There was, there was one thing I played, I forget what it was now,
but it was like one guy did it
and he had like 300 jobs in the,
in the credits at the end and his name was in every one of them.
It was so good.
Anyway,
we have a real topic as much as I'd love to yammer around about Factorio or something,
which maybe we'll do some day, but not today.
Freaking those biters and that
whole. Right.
Oh, yeah.
Whatever. I love Factorio. It's so good. Actually, it was really funny.
So, one more story
I help out with the first robotics team. Right.
And
one of the other
mentors makes a comment about Factory. I'm like, oh, Factoria, I love that game.
He's like, oh you play and he got
no, no, no.
Like I have a family and a job.
I don't play very often.
And
yeah,
and anyway, he got slightly less excited and one of the kids is like,
what's Factorial?
And we explained it to him. He's like that sounds like the dumbest game ever
-- maybe. But you
-- get
-- to
-- learn process optimization.
It kind of is and it's very funny because
this kid was just like you guys are weirdos like
we
are
anyway. Alright. Alright.
Topic,
-- topic of the day encrypted messages
-- is even encrypted messages.
I don't think encrypted messages is even the right term for this because there's
multiple terms, there's end to end encryption,
there's encrypted messages,
there's private messages
and these are all very subtly different things,
right?
We'll start why we're going to talk about this today.
So anyone paying attention at this point is familiar with the
just everything happening around Twitter
and there's been a an obvious migration to Mastodon,
especially by security goons and
sa
and, oh
my
goodness.
-- So we are not going to comment on any of this stuff
-- yet.
I'm a Canadian.
I got nothing to do with us
c
but anything we record
in two hours
old and irrelevant because I'm like, I can't even keep up. It's also bananas.
I, I stopped, I,
I like, basically I'll, I'll, I like, I stopped looking for
the Twitter
catastrophe. I don't even know what to call it. The catastrophe, whatever.
Because yeah, it's clear at this point like, OK, I've left Twitter.
I deleted all my tweets. I'm,
it's done
anyway. Anyway. So here's the thing,
ads, people come to Mastodon, they keep pointing out
-- that you have to trust your server admin
-- that,
that right. That, that Mastodon D MS aren't encrypted
and server admins can read them
and yeah.
Yes, that's generally, that's how servers work.
When you put data onto a server, the person who runs the server can read the data. I
-- think
-- you're being a little harsh because I think
that
the problem is we've existed in this kind of corporate social media
environment for so long where things like this just weren't acknowledged.
And there was this,
-- I guess
-- all access to that data is strictly controlled and blah, blah, blah,
you know, blah, blah.
And then it turns out some like teenager whacks
into the Twitter Twitter dashboard and takes over the,
you know, a bunch of accounts
and could read their stuff
but, but the point is, I think there's some value in
just discussing the various things going on.
There's a lot of moving pieces in this and there's everything from signal which
does most things. Right. But not quite everything.
And then you've got Mastodon where you have, like,
literally you're on someone else's server who is not a
-- company and not regulated
-- unless you're on your own server.
Well, that's true.
But even that doesn't really matter because you're
sending your messages to somebody else's server.
Right. Right. It's, it's definitely
-- a very odd and unique way.
-- No, it's just email. Well, it's exactly an email.
So
it's, this is what drives me nuts. Everybody's like, oh Federation Federer.
This is, I'm like,
yeah, we reinvented email. Like,
like, because it, it's just,
it's got a slightly different message publishing model where
you can actually pull as well as push,
but that's it activity.
And so to be blunt, like, like email,
the common model is your connection to the server is encrypted http S
easy.
And then
while the data is in clear text on the server and hopefully
you trust the server man and whatever platform they're running on because,
well, yeah, they can look at your data
and they kind of have to be able to look at your data because for example,
they need to route it
or
if you post a public tweet
with a hashtag people want to be able to search for that.
Hashtag Well, they have to read your message.
And so I also, I, I'm not sure dm like
message is the right term because the way
uh
masone
works is right is you can,
you can do a message. Um What is it publicly? Followers only
or uh mentioned people only, right?
And unlisted, which is public but like search engines stuff don't pick it up.
-- Right. Right.
-- So to prevent like, like a search clutter, I don't know.
-- So
-- let's think about this
like AAA sliding scale, right? Let's put Mastodon
on the right
and let's put
P GP all the way on the left and I'm going to use P GP.
This will make sense.
IP GP as the most control and Mastodon as the least control when we're trying to,
I'm sending Kurt a message and I would put email basically
-- next to Mastodon probably
-- about half a millimeter sig over.
They're touching
-- on the diagram
-- and, and,
and much like it like so um we're also going to ignore you running your own server.
Yeah. Yeah,
that is not the common case.
That's right.
So in the case of something like email or Mastodon,
there's
an understanding,
we'll say this is amongst technical people because I think normal
people assume much more privacy than exists in the system.
Like I'm the super
admin in my Google Ords
orgs. I like I can break into your account and look at all your stuff.
That's just how that works. And I don't
because
professionally and ethically and morally that would
be really wrong and also very illegal.
Right. Right. Well, that's just it. There's,
when you're in a situation of working for a company, for example,
there is like legal obligations and if you go off
the rails and start reading everyone's email or something,
they're going to take legal action against you.
Well, without some very direct and prescriptive,
like you need to do this because there's an investigation or something.
But again, corner case, we can ignore that.
-- But
-- now, but here's the thing,
I don't think we can ignore that because I think it's an important point.
If someone at Google goes off the rails and starts reading gmail
emails or messages or whatever,
there, there's organizations like the FTC
in the United States, the Federal Trade Commission
that is going to find Google.
In fact, Twitter got in trouble for this and are currently under
some sort of,
I forget what they call it,
but basically they have to send reports to the FTC on a regular basis,
which I'm sure they're not doing anymore.
But you get the point right now. If that happens on a Mastodon instance
that's hosted in Germany, you're probably sol, right?
The FTC is not going to help you. There's nothing you can do
and that's fine.
We just have to acknowledge it. I'm not saying it's bad.
This is a, I mean, this is a, like uh, just a quick story.
Like, I, uh, saw a journalist, I know move to Mastodon
and then 24 hours later I was like, what happened to their account?
Like, because it's weirdly grayed out or whatever.
I was like, oh, they moved to a Canadian server?
Oh, yeah. Oh,
yeah, that makes sense. Like Canadian journalists should be on a Canadian server
and, and I noticed, like, all these Canadian journalists went over to MST,
what is it M STD N dot C A or whatever?
And I'm like, oh, that, yeah, that's, that's probably a lot better than being on some
Lord knows where it is instance.
Yeah, I, I agree with that.
I mean, but ok, so there,
there's way on the end and then I want to go to P GP way on the other side of the spectrum.
And the reason I say P GP is the
most controlled
is as the user, you generate the key, you store the key,
you decide when to encrypt and decrypt messages
and you decide the, the transfer mechanism of the messages, right?
So now all of that is why P GP also sucks
-- because nobody can do it
-- right. There's more than that. There's key backups.
You get a bunch of email and it's encrypted and you decrypt it. Great. That's great.
Now, but then you lose the key a week from now and you can't access any of that email
and, and this is the challenge with things like P GB and the,
I think one of the fundamental problems like, let's skip ahead a bit at meta,
the more control you give the user,
the more responsibility you're putting on the user.
That's right. Like key generation is a great example.
OK?
You want to securely generate the key and as people are pointing out
with all a lot of these like claimed end to end things,
it's like,
but you're generating the key using a piece of software
downloaded from a website that it's this binary blob like,
you know,
and, and we'll get to that in a minute.
But what I'm trying to point out is the slider is not
just oh we can move it to privacy and that's good.
It's no as you move it to privacy,
you also move the slider for what the user has to deal with.
That's right. There's like many variables and they all change.
So you can't say I'm in increasing privacy
and also increasing
usability because you probably aren't it.
It's, it's a very difficult equation, right?
It's very hard.
It,
it sometimes feels to me like one of the best ways I had
relativity explained to me on some youtube video is think of like speed
on one axis
and like distance on another.
And you can basically, you have a finite amount of,
of, of energy, I forget what they call it. But basically, you know what I mean? Like
as speed goes up, distance decreases as distance increases, speed goes down.
Like there's nothing you can do about that.
It's just the, the law of reality. And I think
all of this encrypted everything
is the same story.
Like there are tradeoffs all over the place and
anyone claiming to have solved it all is,
is just lying.
And that's the thing I've seen even with all the clever math around like zero
knowledge proofs and all this other stuff which to be clear,
like things like perfect forward secrecy are very important.
But again, a great example, perfect forward secrecy is a great example because oh,
now every message is encrypted with a different key,
right?
Uh I'm going to keep those where
OK. Well, let's use a key
derivation scheme or derivation. I don't know how to pronounce that word.
So, but again, like just things get horrifically complicated and,
and you still have these underlying problems of
like the user at some point has to like
maintain control of and back up this key and people are terrible at stuff like that.
Right?
Well, so here's the organizations are OK,
but people are terrible at this
and that's the other problem too.
People confuse like, oh, but my company does this and it's not so bad.
Well, yeah, but your company is like a full time people of
like a full time team of 10 people to, to do this.
I'm just a person like I, I got, like,
I actually have all my physical UB keys here
on my desk right now because I was updating my
logins and I have to schlep one over to the bank and put it in the safe deposit box.
So it's off site.
Yeah. Such a pain in the butt.
Yep. Yep. So let's, let's, I want to pick on signal now
because signals kind of a little farther up the scale from
P GP. Well, way up the scale from P GP
in terms of usability,
it's, it's much easier.
So if you, if you pay attention to the world of signal,
you're going to hear people complain at length
that you have to use a phone number. That the only way to assign names to
signal users in the app is to give it access to your contact list.
You're gonna hear complaints about the way it stores the messages on the devices
and there's all these very legitimate complaints. But here's the thing.
So I think signal is at a place where they've created
pretty good
privacy
and relative use.
It still has some drawbacks by all means.
But I think
it again, you have to make these tradeoffs. And like an example is with signal,
there is an encryption key stored on your device.
But if you're using a, like a, a phone, which I guess you need a phone to set it up,
the key to decrypt, your key is stored in the,
the the, the enclave or whatever they call it on the particular device.
You have a secure enclave,
-- which is cool and that does its
-- job until your phone breaks.
Well, right, that's just it.
If your phone breaks,
you can reclaim your signal account but you lose all
the old messages and all the people you're connected with.
Get a message saying like Kurtz, what do they call it? Um,
some, some number.
Let me look, I,
I have someone who actually has a message for me that just changed phones.
Um
The safety number, they call
safety number. That's the one safety number in signal.
It'll say someone's safety number has changed
and then the intent is out of band. You ask them what's going on.
The idea with signal is obviously you've got,
let's say Kurt has a message, he sends me his device encrypts a message
the message is sent over the internet through the
signal infrastructure which signal has no way to decrypt this
and then I get a copy and my device decrypt it
now like one of the challenges here is
we're still using signal infrastructure and signal apps.
If signal decides to go rogue,
they could almost definitely start shipping those keys back home.
I get like so many signal app updates on my desktop like
at least one or two a week and I just hit restart signal
because what else am I gonna do?
Yeah.
Well, then on desktop especially, I don't like on my desktop,
I have a pretty old desktop.
I don't have any hardware backed, anything, storing those keys,
they're just all sitting on disk,
you know.
So, I mean, that's an example of where signal is actually very weak in that regard.
But, I mean, if you want to have it on a person's desktop,
yeah. I mean, like, my desktop is a bit locker encrypted for work. But
again, most people are not going to do that and you can't really force them.
-- That would be insane. I
-- can't do that because my, my motherboard is too old.
And I mean, and this is one thing that I think Apple gets right with, at least,
even if it's just the pin number, like on your phone, at least your, your disk,
I say discs, I'm old, your chips.
Yeah, let's go with chips.
Your chips are, the data on the chips is encrypted, you know,
via the secure enclave via the pin, via the magic blah, blah, blah.
Yeah. Right. Right. Ok. Ok.
We're, we're going to run ourselves out of time before we get to all this. But
so here's the thing,
right?
We,
we've put a ton of trust into the signal
organization and their infrastructure to route their messages.
And now in the case of signal because like Moxie Marlin Spike runs it
and the people who work on signal are
extremely vocal about privacy.
I have no doubt
that
we would know if shenanigans began. Right. That, that's part of the,
well, I feel like Moxy Marlin Spike, like, would tweet about it.
And now it's like, oh,
that's not going to age. Well,
I wonder if he's un master on yet. I need to look anyway.
But here's the thing.
Now, let's kind of move ourselves up and you get into some of these other services.
There's like, I think, what is it? It's whatsapp and Matrix and
there's a handful of other services that offer.
They,
they claim they have end to end encryption and some
of them do an OK job from what I've read,
some of them don't.
Perfect example, you can have end to end encryption,
but we're not saying anything about who has the keys.
Like it's just end to end encrypted.
Like a perfect example of this email, my connection to gmail SSL or TLS encrypted
their connection to the next email server TLS encrypted. Great, but it's not. And
so it's,
it's not technically end to end encrypted.
It's, it's like a bunch of armored conduit along the way.
But the, you know, the message itself is not encrypted.
But even if it, the message itself were encrypted
again, like I could do P GP and give Google my keys so that they can do spam filtering.
And that's a perfect example too is there's,
there's big usability tradeoffs with end to end with what
-- you can't do content filtering apart from on the end device now,
-- right?
That's right. And but at the same time giving Google your key
obviously now severely negates the security you were getting
with
end to end encrypted email, right?
And this, I mean, this is one of my complaints about so like key base,
which I haven't brought up yet,
key base I would say exists somewhere between signal and P GP probably.
But like one of the downfalls is key base will
give you the ability to basically like protect your key.
Well, it's like, well, if you have my freaking key, it's not protected.
I, I don't know if they've changed this. I haven't looked at key base in a long time.
You know,
they gave up when they tried to make that weird
swap to being a messaging app and I get it,
they had to like make money.
Yeah. Yeah.
But, but you get the idea like this is really hard to do and there's
any time you try to create usability,
you almost always end up decreasing security.
And I don't know if this is like a law of the universe II, I would like to think it's not,
-- but I think it might be,
-- I think it is
to a degree. So uh a segway money is a great example. Why do we use banks?
Because moving Sheep is hard.
Like I have to go to the bank to get my money.
But on the other hand, I don't have to store a pile of cash in my house and guard it.
And I'd also like to go out for dinner once in a while
and again, it's back to that whole, the more responsibility,
like the more control have, generally speaking, the more responsibility I have.
And I mean, I'm even looking at this in terms of cloud where this, we're going.
Um,
I'm trying to push us from a shared responsibility model
to a shared responsibility and capability model because for example,
I can't necessarily have a responsibility if you don't give me that capability.
So, oh, you know, I'm going to be in control of my key. Great. How do I back it up?
Oh, that's my problem.
Great.
Right?
Like that for
OK. Now what like, oh like print some stuff out and put in your safe deposit box. Cool.
I'm privileged enough to be able to afford that. Great.
Most people on in this planet don't have access
to a bank with a safe deposit box nearby.
And I think this is a fundamental law of
nature as you get more security and more responsibility,
you get more responsibility, you know, you have to do more stuff yourself.
And I think that's
one of the big
things holding this end to end back because like, I don't want to have to deal with,
you know, I want to be able to filter my messages for spam
and like not me do it. I want to be able to,
well, I want to be able to read my messages in two years.
You know, how many, how many P GP keys have we lost between us or destroyed?
I mean, well, we, we burnt our current keys.
I actually haven't gone through that many keys because remember
the insane episode of how I protected my keys,
but like I've lost old keys or just, you know, it's like I've lost track of them like
they're still valid and they're maybe floating around in a backup somewhere.
But man, I'd have to go through so many files to dig them out.
Whatever. It doesn't matter. It doesn't matter.
-- The point is,
-- well,
it does when that is like your will and it's
encrypted and your next of kin want to read it,
-- but
-- no
-- one's
-- gonna do that.
Like the point of having a will, you actually have to register the will publicly.
Well, ok. Will was a bad example. But
-- ok, your Bitcoin wallet,
-- I mean,
oh, I should, I should make sure that still works
-- while it's still worth some money.
-- Bitcoin will survive, I think.
But that's kind of another topic
because Bitcoin is the foundation of crime.
So it's money laundering,
-- literally,
-- it's money laundering and transfer of value between criminals.
-- It absolutely
-- has to
not today, not today, not today, encrypted messaging apps.
So, so anyway, there's this huge gamut, you know,
I'm I'm imagining in my mind the scale of all these apps,
they all fit in all these different places.
And
I think normal people think virtually all of them are safe. Right. Like
you can send a message with Facebook or Twitter
and theoretically their employees could look at it.
-- Like, will they probably not because they have,
-- like, not theoretically, they
practically,
well, it's, it's more complicated than that though because they, well,
I shouldn't say that
they should
have various controls in place that if someone looks
at a message it gets logged in a certain way
and then
action is taken if they weren't supposed to be looking at that.
And there's like a lot because you hear about this every now and
then where someone was looking at some celebrity photos or messages or whatever.
Well, and the thing to remember too is like,
sometimes companies have to look at it because if I hit report message, well,
now somebody like hopefully an automated system deals with it at some point.
But
at some point, you know, might have to get kicked up to a human,
which for example is where Mastodon is right now.
Like if you hit report
me
or user,
it kicks it into the moderation queue
or notification queue or whatever it's called.
And the Mastodon admins get poked and like
they have to go look at it to deal with it because what else are they gonna do?
Well, yeah, exactly. It's literally how it works.
So anyway, now in the encrypted messaging universe,
there is services that will encrypt the or, or rather
I I they'll, they'll keep the key for you, for example, in their service.
And so while the message is encrypted, the key is near the message. And so like
is how secure is that?
Now, you have to think about securing the key and securing the message.
There's no good answer to this. And I, I
find it infinitely frustrating
that
Mastodon doesn't have a better message saying like literally like the, the,
the wherever this message is going, they can read it,
which again
is technically correct. The reality is it's not going to happen in most cases.
And then there's also the instances of
when,
when a service is storing a key in a way that maybe isn't as secure as it should be.
They're just like, oh yes, we're and, and encrypted, everything is fine,
everybody.
And it's like, no, you're not signal, stop pretending you are.
And it's very, and how do people even figure this out? You know what I mean?
Well, it's also opaque, right? Because some,
oh a great example,
there were some various add ons for like send mail and P GP where
you could encrypt outgoing email to that person using their P GP key,
discovering, using Dane DNS.
Dane as a protocol to put your P GP keys into DNS and discover them and blah blah blah.
So now you don't have end to end encryption but for example,
it's like I send an encrypted message to
the server, the server decrypt it, the server
encrypts it to everybody.
And if it, you know, because we were on that list, right?
And um,
so it's like quasi
end to end with that decryption step in the middle.
But if it's done reasonably well and properly, you know,
there's nothing left around for an attacker to find
after the fact,
like if the attacker sitting on the
server watching everything and watching memory,
then obviously they would see every message coming in.
And that's the other thing people forget is
what are you protecting against? Are you protecting?
Like, are you, are you shipping nuclear secrets that like just cannot be seen?
Or is it like this is data
that we don't
want people to discover later and decrypt and read?
But like, you know, if they break into the server and they're reading it right now,
that's bad.
But we can serve like we can kind of deal with that,
but we don't want somebody to find this trove of 50 years
worth of documentation and just decrypt the whole thing and read it.
And again, it gets very complicated, very quickly of like, what's the threat model?
What's the attack model? What
I think
that's the key, right? What you just hit on is how the show has to end
is like, if I'm sending you a direct message in Mastodon,
there's a 100% guaranteed chance that if you copy
and pasted that message and stuck it in public,
I wouldn't care at all because
I'm not going to use Mastodon messaging for anything even remotely useful
because I understand what it is right
now.
If I use signal,
like I trust the signal people enough that I don't think my
message is going to leak and the person I'm talking to,
I'm still going to be mindful.
They could obviously copy and paste or screenshot or whatever.
And so it depends who you're talking to right there is or, or your instance where you,
you just mentioned the the email server where
you encrypt a message to the email server,
the email server un encrypts, it re encrypts it to all the people.
Like that's an instance where the untrusted parties
are the email providers for the users,
which was the case and the person who owned the email server was very trusted.
And so there was no concern there. The concern was where the email was going to go.
And so that was an instance where
obviously kind of the,
the the usability concerns were taken into account
and this was the solution to make this happen
and thrown out the door.
No, no, not at all.
Because here's the thing, the way this, the way it could have worked is
I have everyone's P GP key in my key ring,
I address a mail and then also encrypt it
individually to every single key and then send it
-- and that would be ridiculous. Well,
-- no P GP can do that. Couldn't.
I thought P GP could do like encrypted group
anyways, it doesn't matter.
You can encrypt to multiple people at the same time in one message.
But you have to obviously say like all of these people get encrypted to
and it's a pain in the neck
but no back to this. So, so what it boils down to is
your messages on Mastodon are not
in any way, shape or form encrypted.
There is work being done on end to end
encryption and Mastodon like the scaffolding is there.
-- But
-- so here's what I'm going to say about that because I've been thinking
about this a lot since I was reading some of the proposals.
If you give people true end to end encryption,
they're going to be real happy until their computer crashes and
they lose their key and they can't read their old messages.
I don't think that's the issue at all though.
I think Mastodon apps on a phone have the potential to do this
correctly because you can store the keys in enclaves and things like that.
But Mastodon as many of us use it is a website.
There is literally no good way to store that key on a website
that the server can't just slurp it up off of your machine.
And now that there, there are API S to work on some of this,
but they're not as good as they should be.
And so I think that's going to be the challenge of Mastodon running in browser
is you're still not really much better off than saying I have to trust the instant
app
because that's where you land
even with end to end encrypted. And of course, OK, run your own instance, whatever.
But the reality is no, most people can't do that
well. and you know, there's a great thread about this.
I think it was on Twitter where basically somebody tore into
end to end encryption and why it's so darn hard.
And
you know, even if you do this perfectly through a webinar face.
Well, where's that webinar face coming from? You know, where's that
executable blob coming from blah, blah, blah. Like people can't
-- be auditing this code every time it downloads to their browser.
-- Absolutely not.
And, and here's the thing,
even if the key is protected using whatever the fancy new web API S
are to store keys locally in enclaves and all this at some point,
the message is presented to the user
and that is when it can be stolen. Like there's just, it is such a hard problem to do.
And this is again why we come back to that sliding scale
of why P GP is way down on the end in the,
-- in the dumpster
-- and nobody uses
it
and it's terrible and like it, it's theoretically
perfect security.
-- But humans,
-- I think a great example of this,
the P GP commercial encryption product that does P GP encrypted email.
What does it do
when you send the email to a person with no key? I assume it just doesn't encrypt it.
Well, no, it does. And what it does is it sends them a link to log into a web portal
to view the message encrypted.
-- Oh, yes. I've seen this actually.
-- Yes. And that's it.
-- Like, because what else are you going to do though?
-- Nothing.
There's nothing else you can do.
And so I,
yeah, I think
end to end encryption.
I'm not against it, doing it properly so that people keep access to their data
is a lot harder than I think most people even begin to think.
No, it, it's kind of that, that whole ii I hesitate to call it even Dunning Kruger.
But it's, it's what, what? There's so much we don't know, we don't know.
And like, I'm even willing to admit that when we start getting into the math,
my knowledge drops off very quickly and there's all kinds of
new technologies now that I'm not even that familiar with that.
I, I was reading a whole bunch of them before this and like it's easy to say,
end to end encrypted is impossible or too hard or we can't
do it or whatever and have a very doom and gloom attitude.
I think there's a lot of good work happening.
And I think we are always getting better in this space.
And I think it's important we try
and we fail because every time we fail, we learn something new.
And I think this is one of the challenges, especially in the crypto space.
Oh I can't say crypto anymore.
This is
especially in the encryption space.
-- Well,
-- not after last week, even
the crypto space, holy cow.
But in the encryption space,
there's,
there's often this attitude of perfect or nothing and
sometimes it's very justified because like for example,
my my open S SS L running my web browser that better be perfect.
But
there's always room for change and growth.
And I think that's kind of the takeaway here is yes, it's hard.
Yes, Mastodon has no security. There are smart people working on it
and you can complain
and tell them they're dumb for trying or
go freaking help like,
-- you
-- know,
or run your own instance and only allow
trusted people and then have someone you trust,
run the server.
But even then I'm
OK, I'm running it in the cloud. Do I trust my cloud provider?
Like there's, oh my goodness. It's
so let me get this straight. I can run a Masto
on instance in my basement bunker
on hardware I control uh oh crap. I have to use the public internet.
So I mean, we're back to the people running their own email server still.
Oh, that's true. That was that,
that was last week, that was last week from when this goes out. Um
And it's funny because actually we put it in the, the, the, the toot, I guess from,
from Mastodon.
But we recorded that episode
before like Twitter and Mastodon and everything happened and I'm like,
oh my goodness.
And, and part
of this now I will say I'm rethinking some of the whole,
like Federated community driven everything, which I think we took a,
a kind of anti doing it yourself view in that episode.
And I'm going to have to rethink that in the context of Mastodon,
but I'm not willing to
-- say anything about it yet.
-- It's not that I'm against doing it yourself. But like
there's a reason I pay taxes so that we can have roads.
I don't want to build my own roads.
And granted that's really too hard.
Running a mass on server is definitely doable. But
the thing is
everybody forgets there's that operational ongoing cost.
This is literally a puppy that grows into a dog and you can't ignore
-- it for a week because this
-- is why if you're a Mastodon user,
I would highly encourage you to
go on Patreon and give your instance or the Mastodon project money.
Like they'll take a freaking dollar a month,
which for most of us is probably what it's worth.
Maybe it's slightly less. But
like this is, we're not the product anymore.
We have to start paying for the product and I
think that's probably a topic for another day as well.
But anyway, Corey
Drako, uh,
we should put that in the show. He just wrote a really good article about that.
How, even if you're paying for it,
you're probably still the product in a lot of these things
that could be, I should read that. I have not read it.
But anyway, all right,
I'm gonna cut us off because we're hilariously off topic as always.
So, thank you, Kurt. Thank you for listening.
Go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up the
show, UZ Power
Os S podcast. Hashtag Do hit us up on social media.
Have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks to everyone. Bye bye
the.