Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode
49 with myself Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime,
Josh Bresser.
Kurt, where do we start?
Uh with
what is most on fire
it down to like four things,
right.
Let's start with
Samba. How
about
Samba? I think is the most interesting
-- of, of all the things I don't know if I'd say poor Samba that well,
-- it just,
it does when you think about it, right?
This guy,
well, and team wrote, you know, an implementation of the, well,
originally server message block.
Now, what is it called common internet file system?
You know, and they managed to
through a combination of talking nicely to windows and
uh there was that court case to get the documentation and then, you know,
just probably some like really horrendous late nights
of like staring at binary packet dumps,
you know, they actually make this thing that works.
It does, it works very well. And, and they,
one of my favorite stories actually from the Sama guys is, I guess,
way back in the day when they were working on one of the first versions,
they realized that you'd authenticate against a remote windows server.
And
it would just tell you you're wrong,
it wouldn't actually block anything.
So you could just, like, keep going, like everything was fine.
Right.
And they, they told Microsoft Microsoft said, well, there's a bug in your client
and they said
that's not how it works guys.
Anyway. Anyway,
that's
true. That's true. It was.
-- Right.
-- Right. And, and this was way long, long, long ago. So, anyway,
this, this Samba bug though is super interesting.
It, it involves kind of one line of code where you open,
you upload a file and then open it as a pipe
and then the file get, if it's a shared library, it gets executed.
Which is,
yeah, it doesn't get any better than that. I mean, let's face it.
Well, see,
I that's one thing I love about UNIX is
this is this metaphor of like everything is a file
-- you want to talk
-- to
strength and its greatest weakness.
Well, it's, it's just, yeah, because there's a great example of like when you,
you know, if you treat everything as a file,
some behaviors are reasonably well defined and understandable.
Like if it's att Y and you shove date in it,
shoves it over whatever magic line to whatever remote system.
Well, I do
appreciate the permissions model because permissions are easy to understand.
Yeah, exactly.
But yeah, when you have something like, OK, well, it's a pipe
that's, you know, a shared library or a pipe that's an executable, you know,
the kind of,
because typically, well on the command line, at least if I pipe to a lot, you know,
a binary
I kind
-- of
-- expected to run.
I'm talking from the metaphor, right, from the metaphor perspective of like,
what am I expecting to happen?
And that's fair.
That makes sense. You know,
it, it,
I love it. But so here's the bigger thing, right? So Samba has a security problem.
It's, I think seven years old someone said, and
whatever that happens, right. People make mistakes.
It, it is life, they fixed it. They, they released an update. Everything is fine.
Well, but kind of, here's the problem is
I was talking to a friend of the show, Rich Morell, who you and I both know
and Rich pointed out to me that there are
literally millions of devices out there running old versions of Samba,
everything from
router,
sharing
files
from
windows. Yeah,
exactly.
Right. Oh, that's true. Printers too.
Right.
You've got like NASA and you've got routers, you've got,
and some of these cost $10 and some of them cost, you know,
thousands and thousands of dollars and fundamentally,
they're all vulnerable to an extremely trivial security issue now and,
and let's face it, most of them aren't going to see updates.
Well, and you'd also mentioned that, um, I guess, well, for a variety of reasons,
a lot of these devices are on what sound but I want to say two point whatever.
Yeah. The old version before they switched to GP LV three because a lot of
that.
Yeah.
But also the version that's been around forever and, you know,
we got it working and we're not going to like,
upgrade to sample version three or four because, you know, we'd actually have to,
like, spend a couple hours on the product.
That's true. It's, it's much easier to do nothing
than it is to do something.
Well, and in fairness, I mean, you know, like
people who expose their file server to the internet,
you know, it's
ok.
No, no, I don't think that, that, that's a valid reason anymore though is I think,
saying that a long time ago made sense.
But with the concepts like zero trust networking now,
you cannot trust your network.
Right? Well, see,
that's what gets me,
well, it's like the whole VNC thing I get that there are many times where you,
you really do have a legitimate reason to have, say Samba or, you know, VNC.
So you can remotely manage the system or look at what's on it,
you know?
But at the same time you need to recognize that.
Yeah, the internet is an incredibly hostile place now, right?
Like, what, what was that guy tweeting that he was putting up windows honey nets
and they were all getting popped in like 2 to 3 minutes and I
saw that
and they were getting popped with and then he
was putting it through virus total and like,
he was getting like, zero detection rate.
Yeah, I saw that 11 attempt per minute basically is what it sounds like, which is
less than I would expect to be honest with you.
I
figured it's way worse than that.
You know, it's so,
uh, on the one hand I get it, you know, these, these, you deploy a router.
Well, how are you going to put like a VPN in front of your router?
You know, that's the problem for a lot of these devices and stuff like
Samba,
they're so low end and cheap or
they're like your basic network infrastructure piece.
Well, yeah, how do you put like a VPN or something in front of it to secure it?
Well, so in so in the case of my router, actually, which,
which I played around this a bit, I do not run Samba on it for this very reason,
but it,
it, it does not expose Samba to the internet by default.
You can make it
you shouldn't.
And then internally obviously the the permissions model is terrible.
So generally, I would assume most people are allowing guest access,
which is obviously the issue because in
this instance, you have to be able to upload a file somehow and then make a call to it.
And so if you, if you can't log into Samba,
you're fine. But again,
I think in many instances, you've got Samba shares that you either have semi
untrusted users with access to or
you just have a guest share.
Because I mean, let's think about every organization on the planet has
like the, the guest directory, right where anyone can upload a file
and that's now incredibly dangerous. If you're using
Samba,
it's
remember public FTP S man where they had
the incoming directory and it was just full of wares on every system,
man. Those were the days.
Yeah.
No, I, I do remember that like all those, all those, you know, and then, yeah,
when pro FTP D and all those guys got it.
So you could like basically have an upload directory that
you couldn't download from. I was like, oh, thank goodness,
I've got a great story about that is a
long time ago.
Then it was my first job out of college
and
one day I set up M RT G to start graphing the network traffic coming from the internet,
right?
And I thought, oh, this will be fun to watch and, and I start graphing and I said,
uh why, why do we have
constant incoming traffic all night long?
Right?
Because you could, you could see when everyone left work and there was still there,
there's a couple of megabits coming in from the internet.
And I remember going to the windows admin, I'm like,
what's going on here because they, we were running windows,
whatever their firewall thing is called at the time for internet access.
And he's like, oh, so and so left their media player on
and I thought that seems like a lot of traffic.
But ok, that's fair and it happens again.
And I, I go to so and so, and I said, hey, what's up with this?
Why are you leaving your media player on? He's like,
and this guy says, I, I know what you're talking about.
And so I,
after speaking with him, I realized there's no media player.
So, so that's not it.
And of course,
my suspicion is the windows admin didn't even know what I was talking about.
And so he just made some crap up to make me go away.
And anyway, I started doing some investigation.
I was sniffing some traffic and whatnot and it turned out that there was a,
an FTP incoming directory
available to the internet which also allowed download.
And uh
Star Wars episode two was being uploaded to it
three days before it came out in theaters.
And I'm like,
I, I shut everything down. I deleted everything and, and I, I went home
and I said, I didn't even know what to do here. Like this is just, this is ridiculous.
I didn't keep it. And
all my friends were like, dude, you should have kept that file.
And I said, no, just, no,
this is like my hope now is the authorities just don't show up, you know, that's like,
well, I, I remember, yeah, that was always those holy grails, you know,
people are always looking for corporate machines or, yeah,
university machines with, yeah.
You know, like a
fast internet connection. Right.
-- Well,
-- and everybody did this. Right.
Because, like, you'd have, well, everybody did. Right.
You have to, like, because you couldn't email files larger than about, oh,
like four kilobytes back in the day, you know,
without horribly breaking everything.
And, well, and you know, what makes me laugh is to this day we still have this problem.
Here's a great example. I want to share a two gig file to you. What do I do?
Uh, you share a multi 100 megabyte file with me once a week and we use Google Drive.
Exactly. But like, ok, well,
let's, let's up it. I need to share a one terabyte file with you.
I can't even imagine how you would do that.
Amazon S3
-- or Dropbox. I mean, it would have to be like one of those services,
-- right.
I don't think S3 doesn't do files larger than two gigs, does it?
No, you'd have to, like, chop it up or whatever using like,
or whatever split.
But, I mean, fundamentally that's the thing, right?
So, like it's a terabyte now, but back in the day, like four kilobytes and, and it,
you know, there's a lot of people that legitimately need to share, you know,
lab data sets or backups.
Right. And we're still stuck in this. I love how we're still, you know,
um, I had to transfer like a couple 100 megs of data to, uh, my parents, you know,
all the photos of the kids and stuff and it was like, uh,
that just put that crap in like Google photos or something and share it. Right.
Yeah, pretty much. But, um,
no, it's, it's, I love that we still have these problems with sharing, you know,
whatever, whatever is considered a large file nowadays is still a pain in the butt.
It
is. But it's way easier than it used to be, man. You got to admit.
Oh, true. It's getting better. But for example, we just ran into an issue with, uh,
one of
a thing that was blocking email attachments larger than six megabytes.
I'm, I'm comfortable with that.
Don't, don't send you emails people. It's a
PDF S or whatever. But, uh,
anyways back to Samba. So,
yeah, I mean, the reality too is, I mean,
what always gets me is, you know, what underlying assumptions did we make about?
Oh, this is a file. So, how do we treat it? Right.
And I would bet a dollar.
But, you know, there's going to be a similar flaw in sound,
but at some point in the next 5 to 10 years,
I, I'd be surprised if there aren't a bunch more and, and in fact,
I'm sure people are looking now so it wouldn't surprise me.
If we see another one or two of these in the next couple of weeks.
Yeah.
Well, and the thing to remember too is it's not just Samba's fault. So, uh
tying this into uh well, that latest Windows thing, you know, the,
the MS D Os reserved device names, right.
So MS D Os back in the day had a couple of magic device names.
There's about 21 or 22 of them in total.
Oh
yeah, it, it still exists in Windows 10 even.
And, and so it's magic things like, you know, calm one or LPT one or whatever pr N.
So you know, these D OS apps could print
to LPT one and that would just magically make, you know, printing happen.
And so these device names are reserved by the
operating system except their behavior is not 100% consistent.
So for example, if you do like a maker,
Pr N on Windows,
it will fail and say that's a reserved device name.
But if you at least back in the day when I tested it, if you did a maker
with the full UN C path name, you know, universal naming conventional Windows,
it would work.
-- You know,
-- I remember
with this directory called PR N but now you like like good luck deleting that.
I remember that because I, I remember doing this to friends is you create and,
and you'd always create the printer one because
when they would try to do something to it.
It would almost always end up spewing garbage out of their printer then.
Which made it really funny.
-- Oh, we are, we are nerds
-- anyway. We're old nerds. That's, yeah, we're old nerds now.
Yeah.
But, um, but yeah, so, I mean, this, you know, you can't,
if you look at all these programs, like
Apache's great example, you know, they ran into this many years ago where, you know,
if you made a request for slash pr M on an Apache web server
-- on Windows, it just basically tipped over
-- is that actually
apache's fault though?
Well, exactly right. Like, you know, that's the thing, right?
You, you have this magic device name behavior. And
so the the problem is any program that interacts with the Windows file system,
which is like
every program running on Windows,
I I can't think of a single program that
doesn't interact with the file system in some way,
you know, is, is has this problem and you have to like code around it.
That's, that's clearly insane because, you know,
every single program has to be coded,
has to code around this one, you know. Gotcha.
You know, that's what worries me about this,
this whole with these magic pipes and device names and all this stuff is,
you know, when the behavior is not well defined,
we can't expect every single piece of software running on it
to do the right thing,
right? That's clearly never gonna happen.
Right. So I, I, you're not wrong
in all this about opening files and how
everything's arranged and all this crazy stuff.
But ee even if we ignore that,
I think the real story here is just,
nothing is going to get updated and we're going to literally have millions
of devices sitting on networks that are vulnerable to a super trivial flaw.
And in fact, there's a meta slight module for this.
-- It came out what, like 24 hours after it was released
-- 12 or 24 hours later.
Yeah, it's, I have a bunch of routers that, you know, I put DDW RT on.
Uh, but even DDW RT doesn't update for like, really old routers. Right.
I mean, because, you know, I
can't expect DDW RT to support something like f, you know, five years old, like,
come on, they got, you know, better things to do with their lives.
So I'm actually looking at that as an
-- excuse to upgrade my wireless infrastructure
-- and you,
any
excuse is good there.
I mean, obviously the, the real answer is disable Samba and everything. You can
no, granted some things you can't because, like, if you have a N A
that's kind of its job.
Right. Exactly.
Yeah.
No.
And I guess this kind of brings us to the bigger issue of
what do we do with all these weird little devices and,
and just stuff that's everywhere.
I think the reality is what's going to happen whether we like it
or not because it only takes like one dude to write this is
there's going to be iot brick worms.
Well, there was one, wasn't there where they use the, the mirror
botnet.
Yeah, the telnet
was going in through telnet through hard coded credentials and,
and uh bricking devices by, you know, basically
wiping, you know, slash DEV slash and then all the kind of busy box,
whatever possibilities there are and then like
scrambling, what was in memory or whatever and then rebooting it, you know,
so doing their best to break the device,
I
mean, you know,
the thing I always say is vigilant justice isn't justice, but at the same time,
it's like, is this the,
is this worse than having that device on the internet?
-- And, well,
-- you know,
if it's hooked up to an MRI or something and somebody's getting AC A T scan
-- and that's the problem, right? You know,
-- like the whole NHS running windows XP.
It's out of like,
I, you know, on the one hand, I'm like, you know, I, I don't like the NHS doing that,
but on the other hand, you know,
the politicians in Britain cut funding to the NHS. And so,
you know, as the NHS, what are you going to do?
Like cut patient care or like upgrade windows XP to something more recent?
Well, obviously you're not going to cut patient care.
And so, you know, they're, they're in, they're,
-- they're between a wall and a tree chipper,
-- you know, I,
I, right. I, I'm sorry, your grandpa died but we upgraded to Windows seven.
Right?
Yeah.
And, and so, but I don't, but the reality is whether or not we,
we like this kind of vigilante justice, it's gonna happen, right?
Because I literally like, look at the, um, the wanna crime malware
that doesn't take like a huge nation state level team.
No, no.
You know, it takes like one dude, I mean,
this Samba thing, you have a Metis point module,
like you literally just go to like cut and paste
a bunch of code together from like stack overflow metas
and
whichever botnet
-- strikes your fancy and, and you're done.
-- Right.
Right. Right.
It,
no, I know, I know it's,
here's, here's a thought though and this is something for us to chew on is
through having thinking about this at length last
week and having a handful of discussions,
the topic of regulation always comes up. In fact, Schneer
published something basically decrying regulation as, as their only savior here.
And
of course many people are,
are incredibly anti regulation and many will even say you can't possibly regulate
all this stuff because it only costs $5 and who's gonna pay,
who's gonna deal with that?
-- You know,
-- do regulate things that cost even like,
you know, fasteners, fasteners are a great example.
I love fasteners because I buy fasteners,
bolts and nuts and screws and stuff at Home Depot and at Lona and Ro,
uh, whatever and, and they all work, they all are compatible.
-- They're all
-- correct.
I don't know if that's necessarily regulated by the government that
are hard
and have a certain strength rating are definitely regulated.
-- That's
-- actually fair.
-- And that's an even better example than, you
-- know,
because I don't want my car seat flying off in a car
or, or when you build something,
you don't want like the building to fall down because you use sub par.
Although
I use 50 pound construction screws and I use like eight of them to hold up, you know,
100 pound dynamic load,
those better be 50 pound construction screws.
But, but again, even if they're not, you've used eight of them.
So,
right,
you've got
built in.
But unless, you know, they're like five pound construction screws.
Right.
Right. Right. So, so, but anyway, that, that, that's a great example, right?
Is, that's an incredibly inexpensive thing
that apparently regulation has worked with.
-- But now
-- the problem is too, is it's an incredibly mature
industry,
well understood.
-- Testing. It is easy, right? Testing software. Oh my
-- God. It is impossible.
It is impossible. Let's just face
it.
And, and right, that's the second half of this.
Well, actually, it's, let me actually let me make one comment,
testing software to prove that it's secure is definitely possible.
But testing software and being and generally proving that
it has a flaw is actually not that hard,
especially if it's bad software, you'll typically find stuff really fast
and even automated stuff like the Mudge. What's his real name?
I can't pronounce his last name. It.
Yes. Uh, you know, he's working on that sort of automated,
sort of smell, test of software to, you know, do like a consumer report.
-- He's
-- not anymore. He's
-- the
-- CEO,
well, his wife is still doing it. Uh, the, the CITL stuff.
Uh, where did we
go? He, he just got a job somewhere. I forget. Is it?
He's like their, their
ciso or something like that.
Let me look.
Well, and, and see, that's the thing that gets me,
even if you can get the software testing, that kind of works.
And you can say, like, look, this software is provably terrible. Well, then what?
Right.
I mean,
the manufacturer is probably not going to want to spend
thousands or tens of thousands of dollars fixing it.
Uh,
yeah. No, I know.
And so actually you brought up a good point though
is
you talked about
bolts were easy to test
and it's not that they're easy to test. It's that we,
we understand the use like you can just test the bolt,
but let's say you have a bolt that's under heavy vibration.
Now it's changed. Right. And,
and
I think over time
we have basically, there's a failure
and they create a new standard or they update an old standard
-- or
-- they update the testing
and I
think that's our watching
and
watching when I was binge watching all those airline disaster things.
That's one thing that became apparent is the
testing regimes for a lot of these parts.
You know, after, like the Sioux City, um,
airline disaster crash, you know where that giant titanium
ring
snapped,
like it just broke apart and now they're using all
those fluorescent dyes and stuff to look for small cracks.
Yes, exactly. That's exactly correct. Is, is, that's kind of what it is. All right.
Just, uh, Mudge went to stripe
that. That's where he
just looked it
up.
Yeah. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Good for him. It's,
I
get it and, and the CITL work has been kind of slow. So,
my, my, I'm just
not
-- sure
-- there's a
good market for it. That's my concern.
That's probably part of it.
Well, it's being funded by the government right now, which is ok.
And then what,
uh,
maybe nothing. That's how regulation works though.
Regulation doesn't have a, then what? It's just it exists.
True.
Well, and actually that,
that's the whole, that's really,
that's the story of everything we talk about is the vast majority of this stuff.
There's no market, there's no economic incentive.
Right.
It's quite the opposite. There's
incentives to just avoid it and run away in life.
And, and so this is kind of where we need, like
the government's job isn't to have economic incentives.
It's
like you,
you have the crap job and you deal with it like that's what you do.
Yeah. I mean, that's the problem with all those externalized costs. Right?
Is there's often no way to,
in,
like, there's no way to change it so that, you know,
they actually have an incentive to do the right thing.
It's just, yeah, you say, as the government look
this huge negative externality, like, pollution or bad off or whatever, look,
we just can't have it.
So
either you fix it or you don't ship it.
Uh
Yes,
yes.
And of course,
there are challenges around that and I think it's easy for us to throw
our hands up in the air and say this is too hard to do.
But II I don't think we cannot do it.
You know, it reminds me of actually is,
do you remember the really old refrigerators that
had like that crazy metal latch on them?
And the,
the issue being that uh Children
and, and granted this probably happened to like 10 kids,
but Children would get locked inside and they couldn't get out.
Ok.
And I'm sure this is like mobster's best friend
and, and basically what happened was one day the industry said, well,
reg regulators said, uh you can't use those latches anymore, right?
This is, this is not working out.
And of course,
the refrigerator industry like they were wailing and gnashing
of teeth with how could we possibly fix this.
This is just the way they work, but there's nothing we can do.
And then somebody was like, uh, let's just put a magnet on the door.
And
also
I just checked the refrigerator safety act is codified, uh, blah, blah, blah,
as public blah, blah, blah, blah
in 1950 six.
Yeah, it's, it's pretty old
and, and
this is what I feel like
security is, is, we're, we're,
we're busy proclaiming we can't possibly fix the latches on these doors.
And the real issue is no one's thought of the way to do it.
And I know that sounds overly simplistic because
there isn't gonna be one easy answer.
That's kind of what I feel like is
it's too easy just to declare it too hard to fix and then to,
to go on to the next emergency.
But I mean, I think we've reached a point like
every day I wake up and I just wonder, I wonder what's on fire today
and,
-- and it never falls. Speaking of.
-- So, for example, I actually, um,
one of the last motherboards I bought, I think it was an Asus
has a built in hardware firewall that, you know,
there's a windows user space program to interact with it.
And so that actually runs like on the network card.
Yeah,
it's a really nice nifty feature.
-- So
-- this is like a level
what zero.
-- So wait, it interprets it
-- built into the TCP/IP chip set, right?
Like
you have a TCP/IP chip set on your motherboard.
-- That's amazing. Well,
-- to some degree, I mean, it had,
it does,
does it?
Yeah,
it was,
what level are you filtering at? TCP,
Ethernet something
beneath it. Well, there's
-- really nothing I believe it was
-- TCP/IP.
That's crazy to me. And this is done in hardware.
Well, I believe so. I mean,
it works basically, it claimed that the packets wouldn't even be seen by windows.
This, this is amazing to me. I'm,
-- this
-- has been around for a while. Hang on a sec, a
firewall.
I know such technology exists but like not just into a motherboard,
right?
Well, these things get cheap after a while.
Yeah, but
so the two things that come to my mind is number one, that's super cool.
Everything should do that. And number two is
how much do you want to bet there's security issues in that code?
Of course, there are.
Oh, good Lord.
I can't even begin to imagine how bad they are.
Yes.
-- Well,
-- and more to the point,
it doesn't really matter anymore because you have to do things like allow port 443,
which is the new, allow any.
-- It's
-- true. Right. H DJ
is the magic protocol and it can do anything so it doesn't matter.
I love it. Well, that's like I always love too.
There's all these VPN services and things that run in
443 because nobody blocks port 443 and it works through proxies so
-- well.
-- A lot of I SPS will block VPN traffic on residential connections. Now,
I do not have that problem. Thank goodness.
But a lot of countries do this as well
in
Tel
-- Telcos wanna have that sweet, sweet call revenue or
-- they have a repressive regime
who is
Right.
Right. Right. And, and they may have uh firewalls around countries.
Yeah.
Well, speaking of repressive regimes, the whole, uh the whole
watershed moment,
potentially of banning every piece of electronics bigger
than a cell phone on the plane.
Oh, man, that's so crazy.
And what's interesting to me is so 20 years ago, like,
nobody had cell phones basically.
Well, they were big phones
and here's the thing, right? They're, they're,
is,
I think at this point there is literally no
way you could ban cell phones in pretty much any
area other than like change rooms and like the pool
-- because
-- remember when airplanes had phones in every seat,
like that big ugly telephone. Oh,
that's a blast.
Anyway, we should back this up first is so right now as we're recording this,
there are certain countries in the Middle East predominantly
that you are not allowed to have a,
a laptop
in the plane cabin
as it travels from the country to the United States,
you have to put it in your check bag
due to security reasons we're told.
And supposedly they're talking about now enforcing this ban
for every country flying into the United States,
all
international flights,
all,
and you know, the next step,
all
-- flight as well
-- outgoing to the fantastic, that's just great.
Well, you know,
you know, that's next. Right.
Assuming there's any reasonable justification to this, which,
which everyone suspects there isn't,
but whatever that, that's neither here nor there. The bigger point is
if nobody's allowed to bring a computer on an airplane, like,
well, that's crazy.
What do you
know,
what am I
on the zoo for? Four hours?
-- Four
-- hours.
I just flew to the Netherlands a couple of weeks ago and it was like 8.5 hours and
they did have the, the onscreen entertainment do hickey.
But the thing that would scare me more is
I would be very frightened to check my computer
in my bag,
which I forget which airline I flew.
But they don't have the in seat entertainment systems anymore.
They have, you know,
the little wifi server on the plane with media and I
think it was Delta and you have to download the app
so you can access the content and they did have tablets
for like five bucks that you could rent for the flight.
I never stupid question.
I think it was Delta.
Anyways, whatever the point being is,
would the airlines be allowed to have like
their loner tablets or laptops on the airplane?
I would assume so because it would go through
some rigorous security check and we'll put them,
-- but
-- then where do you leave those things on the airline? And, like, what the cleaners
that was like when they were talking about the whole, you know,
guns and cockpits thing and everybody was like, yeah, think this through,
it might not be a good idea, you know,
because, like, what are you gonna do when you park the plane? Like, who takes the gun?
Where does it go? Right. Like, what does the cleaning crew do with it? You know, like,
well, it just, what gets me is, is this seems like, you know,
it's a real pain in the ass policy change, but
I suspect it would actually be like a significant watershed moment for technology
because it would force a lot of change in behavior for people.
I don't know if it would. I think
this would,
I, I think if they do this
as soon as the first senator
gets on an airplane and can't bring his computer, he's gonna get pissed off and,
and go pass some legislation that neuters the Ts a
well, see, and that's,
that's the other thing that really gets me about
this legislation if they were talking about banning cameras.
And, like I said, anything bigger than a cell phone essentially.
And here's the problem, like, it's one thing, you know, I went to, um,
I was flying home from Germany and I, I had, I bought a new corkscrew really nice one
and I totally forgot that they were at that time banned. Right.
So I get, you know, to the airport and they're like, you know, they,
like, they're like, here's your cork screw. You can either mail it or you can, like,
put it in the bin and I'm like, obviously I'm not gonna spend 20 bucks
this home. So, here you go.
Whatever, I'm annoyed. It was a really nice corkscrew. But
such is life.
People are not going to do that with their laptop or their tablet. Right.
These things cost like 1000 bucks or 2000 bucks, you know,
and like, you can't just mail a tablet without, you know, it's gonna get wrecked.
And is it, you get through customs?
I mean,
exactly
in
a
foreign country. Good luck.
Um, and so, yeah, I mean, people can't, like, they're not gonna walk,
-- here's
-- here. Let's even set that aside. Let's think about this. Just
we, we'll say from an insurance perspective.
Oh, God. No, no.
Is the cost of
the potential damage that's gonna be done because let's face it.
You're gonna lose one, maybe two airplanes, right?
Is the, is the monetary loss of that?
Less than,
than the loss that will exist from people not being
able to bring their computers on airplanes and do work.
And
again,
it's one of those classic externalized costs. So the airline doesn't give a rats.
Uh, they don't have to care, but I suspect societal cost.
I suspect the cost of society would outweigh by several magnitudes.
The cost of an actual attack happening. But in reality,
you'd be better off thwarting this attack by
having like proper security at check in and,
-- and to get through the little line. Well,
-- the Israeli methods with
you
make sure you're not nervous.
Well,
this reminds me of it's kind of like the whole nuclear power
plant versus coal power plant debate when it comes to radiation release,
right.
Nuclear power plants tend to not release a lot of radiation
except once in a while when they break like Fukushima,
which
three Mile Island,
right?
And, but then you compare that to a coal
plant which is burning coal which typically has various radioactive elements in it
and they're just constantly putting out a low level of radioactivity.
Well,
not just
there's all these other terrible chemicals.
I mean, I know people that, that own property that was downwind from a nuclear,
I mean, a coal plant and like their,
their soil is just contaminated beyond reason at this point from all the,
the mercury and the sulfur.
Yeah. But I mean, it's one of those classic things.
-- If you do it a lot, sort of at a low level, you, you basically can get away with
-- it.
You know what it is?
It's just like if you look at airplanes versus automobiles,
lots of people are afraid of airplanes.
But your odds of,
I, I think this every time I, I get on an airplane is
the odds of dying on the ride to the airport were
significantly higher than the odds of me dying on the airplane.
Right.
But no one, no one's afraid to ride to the airport,
but people are afraid to get on that airplane.
And additionally
an airplane crashes, huge news. Right.
Literally thousands of people die every day from automobiles.
Nobody talked about it.
Yeah.
So, yeah. No, it's, I, I think this would be interesting because
I can't even take my laptop to a foreign,
you know, country without checking it. And, I mean, it,
the bags, I mean, I've seen what they do to bags.
Oh, I know.
Every time I check a bag, especially on international flights it looks like a truck,
ran it over when I get it back.
Probably because a truck ran it over. Right.
-- Yeah,
-- it's got tire marks on it. I've actually, yeah, I mean,
yeah.
No, it's, but I'm just really curious because, you know what it would this really,
you know, because
I remember back in the day, you know,
teleconferencing is going to destroy business.
Travel. Well, no, no, face to face meetings are still very much a thing.
So, here's the thing I keep thinking of
in the context of this, this travel ban is
if I can't bring my computer with me in a reasonable way,
I'm either not going to use a computer which
seems ridiculous or what's more likely is I'm just
gonna get somewhere and I'm gonna buy a chromebook
because you can get them for next to nothing.
Well, I mean, the,
the good thing now is cell phones have gotten
to a point where they're powerful enough to,
you know, uh,
hook up to a TV and basically be a little baby
computer and especially if you're using stuff in the cloud,
you know, the heavy lifting can be done on the back end,
you know, with respect to word processing and spreadsheets. And
because there's what is it?
I want to say, a Samsung,
that that's actually seems to be the major part
of their ad campaign is like the little phone,
lots of,
lots of companies have been trying to do this for a long time because I think motor,
-- you don't have a choice anymore.
-- Right? Yes, seriously.
And, and I think even the canonical phone did this, right? The bu
phone,
I think that was they,
-- they tried to make that their selling point and
-- every
single apple phone currently can do a Bluetooth keyboard.
Uh
They do not do a Bluetooth mouse as I understand it.
And you can easily like with an Apple TV or a Mac, you can display
-- that
-- actually you could get away with this with
an Android phone because if you had a chromecast and
Android will do a Bluetooth keyboard and a Bluetooth mouse or heck,
you can even just plug a wire to in if you have the right adapter.
So,
and now you have a trusted web browser that you can put
your credentials into and you don't have to worry about using some,
you know, public terminal.
Like we were talking about those hotel
business machines.
-- People who
-- God
-- only
-- knows
it, it, it pains me to see it happen.
-- So,
-- no, I think that's honestly kind of the future because we,
we're already there where everybody is carrying a phone around in their pocket.
And I know I've had to make the mental switch of,
from carrying a phone in my pocket to carrying a computer in my pocket.
That also happens to make phone calls.
I, I almost never use mine for phone calls.
Yeah.
You know, but I, I mean, I still think of my phone kind of primarily as a phone,
not as a computer for my kids.
They don't make like to them, an ipod is an iphone.
It's just, it has like poor internet connectivity when you're on the road or,
you know, but that's kind of what I see it as too is,
is my phone, the data connection is worth far more to me than minutes.
Oh, yeah. Yeah. If I had to give up data or
-- minutes.
-- Oh,
it's,
I
want,
in fact, I don't, my phone never rings. Nobody calls me.
We just use text messages and, and,
and what not.
It's, this is
what a mess.
That's all I'm gonna say it will be interesting
to see what happens here because my suspicion is
we're either going to get
good security out of this because the right people,
we're not annoyed and I don't think we will
-- or
-- the TS A has had the chance to do good security forever and they've tried it,
you know, they have the
-- training and all that other stuff
-- but
they haven't
happened.
No one's made them,
they basically had a blank check to do nearly whatever they want.
And,
and do you remember a couple of years ago when they kind of shut down
a bunch of security lines and security at the airports was taking forever and a
day
because
they were, they were upset about something. I don't even remember what it was now
and of course, everyone just talk about,
I'll get to get TS a precheck and that's kind of the, the, the savior of it all,
which I had,
which did make a huge difference. By the way,
I'm still waiting for my nexus travel card.
Right. Right.
But anyway, the point is, uh, you know,
what happened is people got annoyed and they gave them the
money they needed to hire the people or whatever it was.
Right. They, they didn't fix it by everyone getting precheck.
They, they actually made the experience less painful.
And so I'm, I'm hopeful that they will make this less painful,
but I'm not at all convinced it will be the case,
I
think part of the big problem with air travel though
is that you've got just so many different types of,
you know, like I go to the airport and there's obviously the people that, like,
business travel constantly and they're just, you know, they're the pros,
they know what to do.
They're, you know, they, they don't,
they get on the plane, they get their bags in pretty quick, you know,
and then, and, and you've got that all the way, like,
somebody like me who only travels a couple times a year.
But I'm, you know, I'm a relatively well behaved air traveler, I think. You know,
and then I've seen people where, you know,
because of baggage fees and stuff like a family of
four has one bag and the airline lady is like,
no, it's like way too heavy.
Like,
it's 100 and 20 pound bag, you know,
you're gonna have to take some stuff out.
Right.
And, and they're all like,
wailing and gnashing their teeth at the front of the line and it's
like I just need to check my bag and get on the airplane.
Get out of my way, please.
You know, if you're a frequent traveler, you just don't check bags. I
know this.
I know I'm, I'm getting there. I'm, I
almost never check bags now because
actually this is part of it too is if I had to check a bag with a computer
in it every time I'd get super annoyed because
I hate checking bag because it takes forever.
And then when you get there you have to sit and wait for that stupid carousel.
And then your bag looks like it was run over by a truck because it was.
But
conversely, you've got people trying to shove absurdly large bags into, you know,
these, like, regional air jets.
Where,
uh, yeah. Yeah. I'm, I'm,
I know it's,
-- you
-- can't,
but anyways, the, the, what I was getting at is the problem is if, you know,
if you were doing security for a bunch of seasoned travelers, it would,
you could,
you'd essentially have the chance to train them and get the system working well.
But the problem is you've got all these people who almost never fly or fly,
it's their first time or whatever and they just,
they just gum it up.
Right.
They don't know, to take their shoes off before, you know, while they're in the line,
they don't know to take their belt off.
Like,
how many people have you seen go through the metal
detector and have to go back and forth like,
four times because they keep taking crap out of their pockets.
I experienced that
on Friday.
Yeah, exactly. So, see, that's my concern is even if you have a really good,
you know, system,
these people just don't know how to behave in it.
Right. And they're just gonna do silly crazy things and just muck it up and,
you know,
uh,
yeah, I, I, so I don't think really air travel will ever,
you know, be super well oiled, uh, like,
look at driving people drive every day of their
life and they still don't know what to do.
-- So,
-- here's, here's to, to also kind of define this is while you were talking,
I just looked it up and it says, uh, like,
less than 10% of travelers are what you'd call, like,
frequent flyer type travelers that have, you know,
the awards for the people who travel a lot.
Right.
Yeah.
And so you think about that
90% of the people on the airplane are not frequent travelers,
we could maybe assume 20% have a clue.
And then so basically 80% of these people, like they,
they don't know what they're doing and this is going
to be a monkey show like we've never seen.
And then you've also got like the random drunk guy
on the plane who in some cases it's so bad.
They have to, like, land the plane somewhere and boo,
I'm so glad I've never been on an airplane with that guy.
Well, you know what else I think of is we hate security lines. Now,
imagine when the TS A is standing there telling people
you can't bring your computer on the airplane, you have to check it
and then they're gonna say,
but I don't have a bag to check or they've already checked their bag.
Do you think the airline's gonna go dig that bag
by the time you get to the security line?
Right.
That's the whole point of that.
Oh,
my goodness. This is gonna be,
I, I, again,
I don't,
I,
I don't think the answer is going to be
everyone using their phones because let's face it too.
We're
as lame as we think we are. Sometimes we are
way more tech savvy than nearly every other human on the planet.
Right.
So, so normal people are,
are not going to be able to use their phones even if they wanted to.
They, they don't know what a Bluetooth keyboard is.
They don't want to know what a Bluetooth keyboard is.
They will never learn what a Bluetooth keyboard is.
Right?
And so you're gonna have a situation where it's going to be so bad.
I don't see how they can do this long term. I suspect they will try it
and it's going to explode
and then they'll,
they'll find some reason why the threat is gone now and everything's fine.
It's like, it's like, remember when you used to,
you couldn't bring like fingernail clippers on an airplane
right
now. Now it's fine. What changed? People complain. They wanted to bring their
finger clippers like that's all they
did,
you know.
Well, but the thing is, you know, that's a relatively low impact, low,
you know, risk thing and it's, it's easy to change.
I mean, they still don't allow a lot of stuff on planes that they used to allow,
you know, um, like small knives.
Like, it's, what, two inch blades or something now, like,
so if you buy a set of steak knives, you know,
you got to throw them out things like that,
-- you know,
-- I, I don't know, I never tried taking a blade on an airplane,
-- so
-- I know, I know in, uh, oh, jeez, which airport was it? Um, anyways, I was,
they gave us like plastic cutlery
but we weren't past security yet.
And I was like, what? And she's like, yeah,
so what happened is somebody, like, grabbed
a knife and went running at the security people. So now
all the, like, metal cutlery has been banned in the airport, like,
whether or not you're on the security side or not.
And I'm like,
I'm like
one
airport, right?
Not
-- just the
-- one
and it's just like I, because I really hate those little plastic knives,
you know, they're
so
annoying
actually. What was, where was it?
I was on an airplane once on a, on a flight and they gave us like, real silverware
and I thought,
no, no, it was not
the European
airline.
It was,
but I, I was flying from the US O
so II, I just kept thinking, I'm like, this is
why are they doing this? This seems,
yeah, whatever. Anyway.
And, and amazingly the plane still got there and,
and nobody stabbed anyone else with the, the dull metal.
Well, I feel like, yeah, like I just, I, I have this, like,
mental image of you sitting in the bathroom for an hour, like,
sharpening that knife on something.
I'll show that you have like your tiny little stabby thing.
Well, it, it's Schneier
always says this is, you know, we can't keep weapons out of prison.
How are we going to keep them out of an airport?
You know, if somebody wants to build a sho
they're gonna do it.
It's just, people don't want to because they're generally there for a reason.
-- Right to
-- go.
People are reasonably sane and well behaved.
They are, they are
for the purpose of noting each other random,
the crazy people ruin everything.
Yes, they do
anyway.
And security people, maybe the
part of me actually really hopes they do this just
because if nothing else it'll be such a gong show.
I, I will appreciate the gong show
of this but I travel enough that I don't want to do
because
I'm gonna be stuck in line behind the, like 75 year old man that doesn't,
they'll have a line for no electronics and then for everybody else.
-- Yes,
-- we need more lines and security. That's exactly what the solution is.
If we already have two,
we need more.
Mhm.
Just have your, well,
I guess we already have the evil bit in terms of you can get a pre clear.
So we have the good bit.
-- Uh,
-- they do,
they do.
-- But
-- anyways,
let's bring it home, man.
It's, it's time to go. All right. Thanks for listening, everybody.
Thank you, Kurt for this bizarrely enlightening conversation.
If you want the show notes, you can go to open source security podcast.com
where we'll have links to all the fun things we
talked about as well as links to Twitter and Facebook.
You can use the Pound Os s podcast hashtag to get a hold of us.
If nothing else, Kurt, you have a fantastic rest of the day,
youtube and I guess the moral of the story is uh buy a Bluetooth keyboard.
Thanks everybody.