Hello and welcome to the open source Security podcast.
Episode 137.5 with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner thought crime,
Josh Bresser.
Yeah, just to clear that up. So
I cut episode 138 literally last night.
And I told Kurt I'm too lazy to fix it.
So we're just going to call this episode 1 37.5 or I guess
we could call it like the emergency cult of the dead cow episode.
Yeah,
it is. Uh Yeah, it's pretty interesting.
So anyway, it's like
this is huge freaking news, man.
I don't even know what to say.
Well,
I'm actually more surprised that the cult of the dead cow had
secret members and they managed to keep it secret for 20 years.
That's
an impressive level of secrecy keeping.
These are, these are people who they know what's up. These,
these are people that they, they've done some things and seen some things that they,
they know better than to talk.
Right. Well, why don't you tell us?
Because I remember vaguely what cultivated cows, but it's been like 20 years.
So let's refresh us.
They were like my freaking heroes.
So OK, so
I'm gonna, I'm gonna put on like, I'm going to geek out on this as much as I can.
So back
a long time ago,
there was a very healthy B BS scene and kind of a alongside of it,
there was a really healthy hacker scene back then and these were,
there was like cult of the dead cow. There's a legion of doom there was
and I, I
yeah. Right. The laughter part of that.
There's, I, I, anyway, I can't even remember them all off the top of my head.
I know there were tons and tons of them
and
remember them in HP.
Yeah. Right. Right.
And, and anywhere you lived there was a hacker scene like I am from Green Bay,
Wisconsin and there was a hacking group here.
Right.
So it didn't matter where you were like these people were everywhere and it was,
it was fun. Ok. Now,
Cult of the dead cow was one of the better note and when I was, but a wee lad,
like these were people that I looked up to as I would,
I wouldn't call them heroes.
I don't even know if I technically call them role models necessarily, but they were
something to aspire to in a way.
Right. I, I agree with that. I think
if you were a young person in technology at the time,
these were people doing things and saying things that,
-- that sparked your attention
-- Well, they were, the,
they were clearly,
I think part of it is they, they were both
technologically sophisticated
and cool. Like they were doing cool things with technology.
Exactly. They were, they were pushing the limits and now
sometimes
they were,
we'll say, uh, on the shady side of the law
and
this was before the C FAA
in a lot of instances. And so a
lot of these activities,
what would be grossly illegal today were maybe questionable back then.
Well,
I always laugh about that because remember when Dan Farmer came out with Satan,
the security analysis tool, the what is it, security analysis tool for
the networks
anyway.
And it was like, it was decried as the literal end of the computer security world.
And now it's actually something that's like required by most security standards
by the government.
And I don't know which group Dan Farmer belonged to,
but I guarantee he was in the hacking scene wherever he was because
man, I was always jealous of the hair. Like I wanted long hair so bad.
But I, I,
I'm one of those people that has very unruly hair
and every time it gets to a certain length,
it, it begins to drive me insane and I have to get it cut, but
they had the best hair.
But anyway, anyway, all right. So,
so cult of the dead cow and these guys, they, they claim they created the
Eine, which for those of you who don't know,
there was a thing we called
Eines, which were kind of like before blogs.
And this is where people would have like a digital newsletter.
One of the most famous is something called Frack,
which if you don't know about Frack, oh my goodness,
go look it up and just read them all because you won't regret it.
And so anyway, the CDC claims to have invented the E Zine, which maybe they did,
maybe they didn't, it doesn't matter.
The point is they could have,
I think it was one of those things where probably a
lot of people invented it all around the same time.
Uh,
probably they probably were one of the more popular ones
without a doubt.
I mean, I remember, II, I know,
I read all of their stuff when I was young because it was,
it was interesting and it was insightful in many ways and of course,
a lot of it was stupid and edgy too. And that's kind of that.
I, I think that it's going to be a fair bit
all the hate on for the telephone companies back in the day.
-- And,
-- yes. Right. So, that's right. Everyone,
I mean, and it was totally deserved in hindsight, but
we hated AT&T back then too
before. It was cool.
That's right.
No, it was cool then too.
But, but anyway, so, uh, so anyway, the news that,
that we're talking about and I'm like, I'm so excited in my brain,
I keep getting ahead of myself.
But so Beta o'rourke, who is a,
he just announced his candidacy to run for president in the United States,
which of course, as a Democrat now being the opposition party to Donald Trump,
there's, I think like 700 people running for president.
Now on the Democratic ticket,
I was, I was gonna say that's part of my,
so I'm a Canadian and I don't really quite get this
thing the US does for presidential elections,
the way it works is very different than what I'm used to.
And so my understanding is you have like a
lot of people announce they're quasi seriously running for president
and then, like, anyone could, like, I could announce right now, I'm running
president and
I guess I would be, but
I'm not.
But then the main thing is you need to get on
the Democratic Party ticket to get the Democratic Party behind you,
which as I understand it
is actually a private organization like the Republican party.
It's technically not a
government party. It's a private
organization that does. Yes. Well, fundraising and, and king making basically,
I mean, essentially, yes, because
I
fundamentally in the United States, there's a handful of political parties,
but there's basically two,
there's the Democrats and the Republicans and they
make up like 99.9% of all the politicians.
And so you can run as an independent or whatever. But at the end of the day,
the president is almost certainly going to be a Democrat or a Republican.
Well, and more to the point though, it's, those two entities are not actual
political parties, they're just private organizations. Correct.
Well, that's the DNC, the Democratic National Committee,
like the Democratic Party is, I guess an ephemeral creation
that is all of the people as part of it.
Right.
And you can have people, like, for example,
Bernie Sanders who is technically an independent,
is he he caucuses with the Democratic Party?
But that what we're thinking of here actually is
a Democratic national committee is kind of the,
the,
the weird organization that has all the money and gets to make a lot of the decisions.
Well, they get to control where that money goes. So,
right, which fundamentally decides how this all works.
So, so why should we be excited about Robert Francis o'rourke also known as Bedo
O,
right.
Which, which I didn't know Beta wasn't his first name.
Uh Actually,
although we must also say his cult of the dead
cow name was Psychedelic overlord or no psychedelic warlord,
right?
Psychedelic warlord. I think it was
uh look this up quick.
-- Yeah. Psychedelic warlord.
-- Psychedelic Warlord. Which is, that's fair.
I mean, that's a pretty good handle
in 1988. Wow,
he was, the guy is 46 and I keep thinking in like 88 he would have been like 16,
which is, although I guess that's about right, because I am,
I'm six years younger than
Beto.
I would have been like 10.
And,
yeah, like,
like I was basically 12 when I found out about the internet and then I was
basically just a dysfunctional youth for probably a year or two while I figured out,
like, what does any of this mean?
And I mean, back then, man, it was, I had a shell account. Right. I had a shell account.
I dialed into a modem at a university
and it picked up and I had a login prompt on uh what was,
what was the silicon graphics Iri
Iris
machine?
That was my internet. And then I had to figure that out. So it was,
I bet I spent a month just not knowing anything.
Well, in fairness in fairness,
my first internet was dialing into the public phone line at the university.
They had a public gopher system.
And if you found a dead gopher, if you found a dead gopher link,
it would drop you to a telnet
prompt.
That was my,
that's a nice bug. I like that.
So it would drop me to a telnet prompt.
And then from there I could tell net to things and log into, you know, public systems,
right?
I didn't even have an account. I just was
piggybacking on the whole
thing. And, and
after about six months of that, I actually went and bought like a dial up account,
you know, a Shell account with a, uh, an actual ISP.
Right. And in fact, I remember my first ISP account was Shell only.
I had no, it was PPP back then
and I had no PPP.
Uh, well, you could run, oh Slip was before PPP. Yes, that's right. Oh man.
Well PPP, ran over slip kind of
eventually. It did. It's,
yeah,
it was, uh,
it was messy and it, but it worked,
it did.
That's right. And that's all that matters. So, anyway, anyway,
Beo
is in the freaking cult of the dead cow, which is like,
it's still blowing my mind and this is ok.
So
he kept it a secret for 20 plus years. That's impressive to me.
Uh That doesn't shock me at all. I think
there are many of us conducted many things.
Like I wouldn't dare tell anyone what my, some of my handles were just because, well,
for the most part, I've avoided any, any real, I guess legal troubles or issues.
I could be a jerk,
you know, I don't need people to be like, wait, that was you like, no, I'm,
-- I'm cool with that. We'll just let that.
-- I
just used my real name. Part of that was to not be such a jerk.
I, I totally didn't,
yeah, I, I started using my real name in
probably 2010
ish,
I guess before then it was very handle friendly, I guess.
But anyway, anyway, so the freaking CDC now here's
I guess here's where I would like this conversation to go is, first of all,
we should clarify.
Is this a good or a bad thing?
And
obviously, from my perspective,
I think it's a good thing.
I think it's a great thing.
Right? Because
here's my view on this is that if you look at
most of our political leaders and technology,
I think calling them inept is a generous description.
These
-- are people
-- who don't have a clue.
I would say it's worse than that.
I would say a lot of politicians don't seem to have that spark of curiosity.
-- Yes. And that's the second part of it.
-- Exactly.
That thing
is the real thing is,
you know, like, well, I look at Brexit right now and it's like you,
for example,
there's an article in the Economist from November
of last year pointing out that it's not
that Britain can't buy enough medicine to stockpile
in case of disruptions in the supply chain.
They simply don't have enough warehousing with temperature
control to house the stockpiles that they need.
So even if they could afford to buy the stockpiles, which they can't really,
and they could somehow magically get these manufacturers to be like, oh yeah,
by the way, if you could just make like an extra three months by Tuesday,
which is the point we're at now, right? We're less than two weeks away from Brexit.
Um They, they physically can't keep it anywhere without it spoiling.
But how is the cult of the dead cow going and you fix that?
All right, I'm gonna, your shaggy dog story. I'm going to hold a candle to it.
Well, just that, that's that spark of curiosity. I'm,
I'm guessing
basically I'm guessing somebody like beer
or work
would either have thought of those kind of things
or would have people around him smart enough to think of those
things and tell him and for him to really understand the impact.
I mean, it, it's certainly possible. II,
I don't know, I guess,
I don't know if Brexit is necessarily the best example
because there was just so much misinformation and madness.
A
lot of politics is heading into the unknown by definition.
It, well, it should be, I mean, I think it's not right now
and that's what CDC was. CDC was literally
not the edge. They were like the knife like they were, they defined the boundary.
But beyond that, there wasn't any reality because they hadn't created it yet,
you know, things like back orifice like
that was like, oh my God.
And now it's like, oh yeah, of course, that's like, you know,
that's just a normal thing nowadays,
right? OK.
We should explain, we,
we're gonna have to keep in mind
to explain everything because basically anyone who's probably
younger than 35 isn't going to have a freaking clue what we're talking about.
So back orifice
was what we call a rat. Now, which is a remote administration tool.
But the intent when it was released was basically you
can install this in any computer and take it over.
And more to the point, it was small.
It was reliable because these things sort of existed beforehand. But they sucked.
Right. Right. I mean, I remember
doing CIS
admin work and using back artifice as a legitimate
tool because it was like the best thing ever.
But of course,
oh dude, it was way better than the commercial ones
and, and, but now,
but now here's the other important thing to point out
is because this is cult of the dead cow.
They had a very hands off approach to what you should do with this.
You could use it for the power of evil or you could use it for the power of good.
-- It's up to you
-- and remember how they announced it, you know, they
Microsoft was having kittens about it and wanted early access
so they could figure out what was going on because
there
it was one of those classic giant unknown things that turned
out to actually not be all that scary after all.
But remember what they wanted from Microsoft for payment for early access to it.
-- Oh, it was, I, I don't remember. It was ridiculous
-- though.
-- A million dollars in a monster truck. Right.
-- Right.
Which is,
which is fantastic.
And now, now the other thing to remember for,
for those of you who may not is Microsoft was super evil back then.
Like, nobody liked them.
It wasn't even that they were super evil.
They were also super corporate and like they had no idea
how to interface with security researchers or the open source community
and, and in fairness nobody did.
Right?
And this was like,
I remember when loft crack came out and they lost their stuff over that too
and I'll never forget I was listening to it.
I think it was a Hope talk from way back in the day. What's hope?
Hope is hackers on planet earth.
It's a conference in New York City put on by the 2600 guys
which by the way, the 2600 guys,
their radio show off the hook is still on the air
at, at WBA I in, in New York,
which you should totally listen to because it's still freaking awesome.
Like,
it's all Emmanuel Goldstein is the only like regular person who's been on the show.
Like, I've been listening to this show on and off for
what, like 20 plus years now. And it's fantastic. I'll put a link in the show.
But anyway, it's been a while.
I
remember like love
comes out and there's some. So for those of you who don't know, love
was a tool to crack windows, passwords, which was what NT
password hashes,
right? The hashes. It was what NTLM hashes, I think they were called
-- and they were
-- really bad nt
-- manager.
-- Right. Right.
And I remember there was, they were telling a story one time where,
uh, apparently authentication for Samba way back in the day
used to work where basically the client would tell the
server here's my password and the server would say yes,
that's wrong or no, it's not.
And then the client could just make requests,
but either the server could say it's wrong and you could just
make requests and the server would honor it because they said,
oh, it's a client's job to enforce login.
And they're like, what? No, you can't work like that.
Well, and there were also problems with, you know,
you could trigger by just adding an SMB link to anything like an email,
whatever you could get the client to send its hashed password,
you can
very easily decrypt and
right. And they were, they were so bad and there were collisions. And anyway,
but the thing is like this work,
these people move the needle forward and this was super controversial back then.
And, and I guess here's my fear
I have of all this is, I think
Beto being in the CDC is awesome,
but I know his opponents are going to try to use it against him
because let's face it. First of all, let's look at the name Cult of the dead cow.
Now, we know the word cult is in there just to be ironic and edgy.
But let's face it if you tell a normal person, hey, Beta was in the cult, the dead cow.
They're gonna say Beos in a cult. What?
On the other hand, it's so ridiculous that cult of the dead cow,
it just sounds ridiculous.
-- So, it might not be as terrible. I don't know.
-- I, I hope so. I'm, I'm hopeful. So.
So that does give me hope.
You say that because actually I've asked a handful of normal people.
Did you hear the news about Bedo
being in a hacker group? And they're like, yeah,
and then I said, what do you think? And they said,
what, what's the big deal? I'm like, it's a huge deal. Like these guys were awesome,
but I'm hopeful. Most people just don't care.
Well, part of me is happy that it's normalized somewhat.
I,
-- I
-- it might be that it's just not because being
labeled as a hacker used to be like jail time.
Right?
Actually, I remember that when I was in college people would be like,
are you a hacker?
No, no, no, don't, don't call me that.
You know, you're like, looking around to see who's paying attention
because you're right.
-- That was, that was not a friendly term back in the day to be known
-- as well.
I mean, and they kept trying to and people still, oh, cracker versus hacker,
you know, hackers are cool.
Good people. Crackers are the bad guys. Like guys
that,
that etymology ship sailed and caught fire and sunk like
two decades ago.
This reminds me now I'm going to put a link in the show notes.
Do you remember Richard Stallman? You'll be free hackers song.
He plays his little pipe and sings this song. It's fantastic. I'll find a copy.
It's, it's the best.
-- Uh, but anyway, in the
-- term, a lot of these memories I've repressed successfully.
So.
Right.
That's right. Let's peel back the covers and see what's underneath it.
It's not a soft gooey inside. Right. It's
no. Anyway,
anyway,
so I guess here's,
here's one of the things I want to think about and this is for you and I to discuss is,
let's say there's someone that says, oh Beto
is a hacker. We can't trust him.
I think this is a terrible thing that he is in this hacker group.
And I guess
because let's face it. I found a handful of text files he wrote.
-- Well, he was, I mean, isn't, is he still in the
-- CDC?
Probably not? Like, do you ever leave? I don't know.
-- Did
-- he, did his membership expire?
-- I don't,
-- I don't think there is membership.
-- I did he
-- re up, right.
Are you pay your dues?
Yeah.
Right. Like send the check here.
Uh It, it, let's, let's not focus on whether he is or isn't still in it.
I'm sure if someone asked him today, he'd say no, I'm sure if you asked
anyone in the CDC, they'd be like you don't ever get to leave, dude. Right.
Like you're in it forever. So it does, it doesn't matter though, it doesn't matter.
Here's my thought on this is you can look back and
the CDC did a lot of edgy things, some ethically questionable things,
some legally questionable things.
And I
don't think you and I are going to disagree that you can mix it all up
in a pot and it's a net positive for society at the end of the day.
But people are going to look at, say some of the things Beto
wrote way back in the day.
And if you look some of them up there, of course, it,
it reads like a 16 year old trying to be edgy, which is exactly what it is.
And so the question becomes
like this is the, the proverbial,
be careful what you put on social media because
someone who could use it against you someday.
Well, here we are.
So I guess, let's say someone says, like, look at the crap this guy wrote, you know,
we can't trust him.
What do you say to that?
Well, I, I haven't read his old writings.
Um I'm guessing they're not going to be,
they're not going to be super racist or terrible,
-- but more just sort of stupid and edgy in
-- 16 years.
It's stupid and edgy, right from the things I found. And I guess
the way I look at this is
if, if anyone found any of the stuff I wrote when I was 16.
It was terrible and badly written.
The ideas sucked and I thought I was awesome
and the reality is, thank goodness.
I'm pretty sure everything I did when I was young has
been wiped off the planet or can't be attributed to me.
So that's great. Right. Obviously, in Beto's case, he's kind of screwed.
Well, also, I mean, if this is kind of the worst stuff you can find about him, was it?
It's like those people complaining about what is it, Alexander?
How do you a OC, what's her name? Alexander Ocasio
Cortez. I apologize for portraying her name
but they're like, oh my God, here's a video of her in university dancing.
-- Right.
-- Who cares?
Yeah, that's, that's kind of what people do
and,
and I think that's one of the things people might
have to come to grips with is you look at
really anybody,
-- they did terrible and dumb things when they were kids, not
-- even terrible things,
but like just kid things, just dumb kid stuff.
-- Right.
You know,
we got to make our mistakes in private because we
didn't record everything and shove it on to the internet.
But let's face it over the next 2030 years, every single politician will be like,
especially with facial recognition.
That's really going to be interesting to me. Right? Is when you start
plugging a politician's face into the youtube or to whatever and getting
all the videos they made when they were 16 or 17.
You know, like those things where people set their pants on fire and it ends poorly.
I mean,
those are the best.
I
know. It's like, what do you think? What happened?
But like, here's one of the things I think of all the time.
I, I think we are probably anyone, five years,
like 35 ish and younger at this point is almost certainly
going to have tons of stuff that's negative about them.
But the question is, can Bedo
get past that?
Are people going to be willing to say he was a
kid and he did dumb stuff and we don't care.
I don't think people are going to actually care all that much.
I think some people are going to try and care to make it an issue because whatever,
but fundamentally,
I think it's one of those issues that's so kind of abstract to most people,
but it won't.
The problem is OK. He was a member of cult of the dead cow.
Now did cult of the dead cow do anything
really illegal and get rounded up and arrested.
-- Uh
-- not, I mean,
some of their members did I think like fundamentally as a group that was on their own,
I don't think they had like that level of cohesion
to sort of maybe compare it to something grossly inappropriate.
Like for example, the Black Panthers, right?
The Black Panthers like people like, oh
those are those people that did a bunch of bad things and, well,
I'd have to look it up to actually
quantify what those bad things are.
But I'm pretty sure they did bad stuff or something. Right.
Whereas Cultivated Account it's like, oh, they were a computer hacking group,
did they like, cause a power outage or hack the stock exchange?
-- Like what?
-- Well,
-- not that we know of.
-- They released this thing called back orifice with a really,
I'm gonna say amusingly rude logo.
Well, no, no,
I mean it goes beyond that though because actually there was so there was,
there was a member, a guy named the Death Vegetable and I believe he had
Yeah. Death Veggie was hardcore dude. That guy was awesome.
But anyway, he published, I don't remember it Anarchist Cookbook or it was,
it was some bomb making manual.
-- Yeah, but that stuff so tame compared to what we have now.
-- Right. Well, yes and no.
But I mean you have to think like without question,
someone took that content and they hurt someone else with it.
-- Well,
-- but,
and in fairness, I've also seen people do youtube video
of going through the Anarchist cookbook recipes trying to get them all to work.
And the one,
the main one was that the sugar
based smoke bomb actually apparently works really well
and everything else kind of just fizzled out.
This interests me. I'm afraid I'll be put on a list. But
yeah, there's some youtube videos of people
of them trying out the Anarchist cookbook. Nice, nice.
Like does this, you know this urban legend of this, this forbidden knowledge book?
You know,
that's only available as a text file that you invoke at
midnight by downloading from A B BS using a secret number.
It's like making a sugar smoke bomb and like
I remember reading the recipe for
explosive.
Uh No, I mean, there was,
there were legitimate recipes in there for like bombs and stuff.
-- Like I remember
-- reading it, I'll be blunt. Most of them.
If you don't do it right. You're,
you're going to hurt yourself.
II,
I would bet that more people hurt themselves than ever hurt other people.
But it doesn't matter because look,
this is a group that has some questionable content like this.
And so
what do you say to someone who says, oh, these people are criminals
and I guess here's what I, I've been thinking about this nonstop for like three days.
Well, very simple. You asked them to quantify that statement.
-- What do you mean criminals? What did they do? That was a crime.
-- No,
no one's no one's going to answer that.
That's not how you, you got to remember when people react to things like politics.
It's solely based on emotion,
right?
They don't answer questions truthfully, they don't use logic and so they're gonna,
they, they have the emotional feeling
that this is a group that does bad things
and
I mean, you probably can't change many people's minds.
But I would say that the thing to really talk about is just the fact that
while this was a group that potentially did something
that some people might have frowned upon and,
and some of them might have gone to jail.
Well, I would say part of it too is this wasn't a super cohesive group, right.
-- It was more people who were members of the city. No
-- hacking group is cohesive.
Like that's how they work.
I think that's what will partly help here is, is it's very easy to distance yourself.
This is
more of a brand name than an actual cohesive group.
And that's going to be very true to a certain degree.
But, but I think I would honestly just chalking it all up and putting it all together.
I would say this is one of those instances
where people can do silly things when they're young.
But fundamentally I think if the world didn't have the cult of the dead cow,
it would be worse today. Oh,
yeah.
Unquestionably
-- computer security would be at least months or years behind where it
-- is.
It would be, I think years behind these guys pushed a lot of envelopes and they,
they had the ability to anger a lot of very
powerful people at the time and get away with it
and I have a feeling that it was, you know,
you're talking about the group being not cohesive,
but I think they have enough cohesion
that they could speak truth to power.
Well, OK, it's, it's hard to let me quantify that
the type of cohesion is very similar,
I think to open source groups and that they definitely
have some underlying principles that they very much agree to
giving them a degree of cohesion that most companies don't have.
But at the same time as to what you actually specifically do,
that's kind of up to you.
That's fair. That's fair. I'll agree with that.
And I think,
and that's very hard for a lot of people to understand because let's face it.
Most organizations,
especially corporate organizations don't have a very
strong 12th elevator pitch cohesive statement of like
I worked for Red Hat for seven years.
And
when I heard the core, what was it, what did they call that thing?
-- The, the, the core mission statement or whatever it was? Uh
-- which one
it was like the one that was like to be the
leading open source technology company or something in the 21st century
to be the technology company to be. So it used to be, they changed it.
But the good one was to be the defining technology company in the 21st century.
That was the, the mission statement,
which was, and they change it to something that was harder to remember.
And I don't remember what it was, but
that was the old one and I like it.
I worked there for seven years.
I can't even remember it, let alone, I can't even really quantify how I helped
move it forward.
You're in security. We played whack a
-- Mole for years. And that's with
-- CV E.
Yeah.
So, and that's something I think that where the hacking groups are,
are very interesting because they,
you don't get involved with a hacking group unless a,
you're very interested in it and b, unless you're competent enough to be allowed in.
And that's a good point too.
Yeah. Right. These things are very much meritocracies.
They don't just allow anybody in
-- and,
-- yeah. No, no, no Lamers. Right. Like,
that's the rule.
So, I, I suspect
with younger people once they kind of understand what this is,
I think they will think this is cool and it
will be something beneficial to him and his persona.
So young people should think it's cool and they should start their
-- own hacking groups
-- and they should hopefully start voting as well.
-- Uh, yeah, that's also really important because,
-- like,
no offense if you have political opinions and you don't vote, you can shut up.
Right. I agree with that.
Sorry. That's, but that's how I feel.
It, it's totally true. I agree.
-- And that's what I always tell people,
-- you know,
and I don't even care if you go to the booth and spoil your ballot,
go vote.
I don't care how or who?
But you gotta, you gotta, you gotta go do it otherwise
you don't want to talk about politics
-- and now we can vote for a hacker, which is pretty
-- freaking.
You can, I can, that would be
a,
you can't,
I'm pretty sure if I vote for po, I work in a presidential election.
I've just committed a felony.
That's, yes, I, is it a felony?
-- It might be, I guess it
-- is a felony.
Ok.
-- I,
-- I
-- don't
-- know, federally,
anything to do with elections or the post office is almost always a felony
also. Cow tipping.
-- That's true. Stealing someone's mail is a felony, which is,
-- it's a federal felony.
Right. Right. Well, they are, they, yeah, they're state felonies anyway.
Whatever it doesn't matter. Right.
We, we're in Red Hill so vetos in the freaking CDC, which is amazing.
And I,
here's, here's the thing, I think we should end this on because I don't wanna,
I don't wanna eat up too much time and I know we've kind
of just rambled on a lot about this because it's so awesome.
But is
the way I kind of look at this is if you are part of the kind
of like hacker subculture or ever have been or want to be or anything at all,
I think
it's going to be critically important for us to stand up for Bedo whenever
we can because there are going to be people who use this against him
and I think we need to make it very clear that this is not an issue. That is a bad thing.
No, like if, if you want a 3D printer, you,
you probably want to pay attention to this guy.
You know, if you,
-- I could 3D print
-- beta.
Well, for example, you know, uh, pushing the copyright enforcement
onto the hardware level of 3D printers.
For example, like if you want your 3D printer to print what you want it to print,
yeah, you probably need to pay attention to this kind of stuff.
Right?
And, and I mean, that's, I think that's part of it is,
there's going to be a lot of really crazy things that start happening
in the world because technology, you know,
-- like software is eating the world
-- start happening.
-- Like,
-- well, have you not been here for the last few years?
Right. If only I had a podcast documenting my thoughts and opinions
in the last two years.
But, but no, I mean, for real,
I think we need someone who has this sort of technology acumen and I think
it's also helpful that look,
this guy knows people,
right?
That's part of it. This isn't one of those.
Oh, you know, please,
please find a security person to talk to about some of this stuff.
No, like this dude knows people, right?
-- Like he doesn't have to
-- ask well, he knows the right people.
Right. Right. Exactly. He, he's going to know what's up, which is,
it, has me so excited to think we could have a technologist running for president.
Well, and I'm also guessing that his BS detector,
especially when it comes to technology.
Very well tuned. Oh, unquestionably.
That's something I see as,
like I've worked for people with good BS detectors
and I've worked for people with bad BS detectors and
there's a reason some of these companies get into so much trouble because they,
they don't,
they just write.
Yeah.
-- So much synergy. It's everywhere.
-- Yeah.
Yeah.
That the Rhinos thing. Holy cow.
When I read about it, I'm like, that can't be true.
-- Yeah, it turns out it wasn't,
-- uh, fill us in, help us out. What was
it?
Uh,
so it was supposed to be like we take a drop
of your blood and we can detect all the diseases,
like, in minutes.
And I was like, I'm pretty sure that's not how that works. That, I mean, at some point.
Yes, definitely in the future Star Trek. Yeah. Absolutely
not. Not this week.
You know, not today.
Sadly. And, but they claim to have results and I'm like, that seems really dodgy.
Well, they have results. They just aren't good results.
Well, no, they were all fake.
-- Right. Of course,
-- they were, they were doing the classical blood test.
Of course, they were all fake, like,
just fire out that random number generator and spit something out.
-- It'll be fine.
-- Three.
Um,
so, and, and I think that's, again, that's one of these things with,
not just that he has like technical knowledge that's out of date, but he,
he understands how these things work.
He understands
-- that we
-- actually, you know what's funny?
Here's what I love and I think we've, we've, we're assuming
Beto understands all this stuff. We don't know.
But however, I will say
if you were smart enough to get into the CDC back in the day,
you almost certainly know what's up.
-- You,
-- you had to because for him to fake it for that long.
No, you can't fake it with those people.
And that's an important thing to understand is, is that,
is a culture of people that you,
you might be able to trick them once but you will not trick them twice.
Unquestionably if you were in and you stayed in, you were legit. Yeah.
No, to trick them over a long period of time. No, that's
because I remember what happened when some people were
found out to not even be faking but like,
fake one thing.
And I mean, that
most of these communities were pretty merciless
-- about,
-- it was completely merciless.
You got one chance and if you screwed up you were done.
-- I mean, that's how it was.
-- Yeah.
No, if you broke the rules or the unwritten rules, yeah, you were out,
you were ostracized and, yep.
Yeah. No, they were, they were pretty strict about their meritocracies
to a point. That was actually quite unhealthy in many cases.
But, um,
well, you know, still to this day anyways. But, uh,
no, I think, I,
I think people like this are what we need because
part of what I'm seeing is politics in the world.
It's an interconnected, complicated system, much like computer networks.
You know, you can't just twiddle some knob a little bit
because, you know, you, you accidentally blew up Africa or, like,
got like just something horrible happens five minutes later,
you know,
like the,
the world just is so crazy, complicated now that
you, you really do need to have a level of expertise
and
other people to help you
and be willing to accept that help
to make good decisions.
-- And that's something that i it sounds like he has, which gives me some hope,
-- right?
I, I'm excited and, and I think it's,
it's time to wrap this one up and I know I guarantee this topic is going to come up again
without question. I'm just, I'm super excited about this. And so
it's, I mean, this is one of those situations that just, I guess let's wait and see.
But at the same time, if, if you're listening,
make sure the people that, you know, who, who wouldn't listen to this podcast.
I first of all, tell them to listen.
But then secondly,
that's a joke. Please don't make them.
Uh But secondly,
is this is an opportunity for us to talk about
them and make sure they understand what this means.
Like
Beto
o'rourke is not a bad person and, and the things he did when he was young
are actually a benefit to us as a society today,
right?
That is the important message we need to make sure we convey.
And so I would encourage everyone listening,
talk to the people who aren't technology savvy about all
of this and make sure they understand what it means because
there are going to be people who try to use this against
Bedo
and let's make sure they are
sad that they did.
Awesome.
All right, I'm calling it. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open
social security podcast.com. Hit up the show notes, you can use the Pound
Os S podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media.
Yeah, Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.