Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in dealing with
the outfall of decisions made 25 years ago.
Josh.
-- Oh,
-- my
goodness. I know. Right. So we're gonna, we're gonna talk about CD E today.
CBE has been
in the news, let's say for the last what, two or three weeks probably
and is not there for a good reason.
-- And there's a lot of misunderstanding.
-- Kurt.
-- Has it ever been in the news for a good reason? I don't think so. Probably
-- not.
I mean, it does suffer from the typical security problem of if you do your job. Right.
Nothing happens. But I think in this case, they're doing a lot wrong
and it is systematically broken and there's not
a lot of understanding about any of this
and I think to be clear, it's, it's actually more subtle than that.
It's not that they're doing things that are wrong
because wrong sort of implies intentionality.
They're doing things that are wrong because the world changed and CV E did not.
I mean, that's still wrong. I'm not, no, don't, don't do that.
I just, I don't want to, I don't want to make this like a moral argument.
-- It's more of a technical
-- wrong. Ok. Fine. Technically wrong.
Technically correct is the best kind of correct.
-- So, technically wrong must be the worst kind of wrong. Ok.
-- It is.
It is actually because,
yeah.
Oh,
my goodness. Straight
up.
So let's just start out with the reason CV E has gotten most of
the attention for the last couple of weeks is because there was an ID
that ended up filed against curl.
That basically isn't a security vulnerability. No one talked to curl.
A random person
got the ID. It looks like they might
be going through old commit messages or something.
And it was what, a 2020 ID, if I'm remembering correctly, I could look at it.
The tab is literally in front of me, but I won't.
And then post Chris QL had basically the exact
same thing happened to them like a week later
and there's blog posts and links, I'll put in the show notes to kind of all this stuff.
And fundamentally the thing, the reason we're talking about this now
is
no one seems to grasp how we got where we are today.
And very few people understand how this works.
And the thing that really kind of set me off was there was someone on
linkedin basically did a nice write up of kind of some of the mess.
But then they, they hand waved away the solution and I was like, look,
you can't hand wave away a solution because the fundamental problem
here is CD E and NVD have zero accountability or transparency.
And they were like, oh, no, no, they're transparent and have accountability.
I'm like, oh, no,
I was on the CV E board and I didn't even know what was going on half the time.
That's just it. Right. There's, there's so much wrong with it.
It's, and it's a lot of it is basically because it's a,
it's a 25 year old program. Right.
So, ok, first of all, let's lay down some basics who pays for CV. Well, ok,
-- it's complicated but fundamentally it's
-- the US government, it's not complicated.
The Department of Homeland Security pays for the Miter Corporation,
which is a nonprofit, the Miter Corporation.
They're a defense contractor. They're a US defense contractor.
Yeah, they do about 4 $4.5 billion a year. Go to the,
uh, to the GOV spending, uh, what is it? Spending.gov?
And look for what Miter does for them and it's all over the place. Like it's, it's
bioterrorism all the way to cyber
anyways. Miter has a cybersecurity mandate,
right. So they run a number of programs, they run
CV. ECWE,
I forget the rest of them.
There's like a million things and there's like attack,
the Attack framework is part of this.
They do. Miter does a lot of good work.
Mind you, like, we're going to crap on them a lot.
But I think
Miter in general is a net positive for humanity.
And see,
that's why I want to get away from this moral wrong argument because it's more, it's
miters kind of in a rock and a hard place
situation and they're dealing with the government and they're anyway,
so back to this. So the DH S pays for this. Miter runs the program
and they run the program like it's 25 years ago, which is 25 years ago.
It made sense 100% for Miter to just run the thing and do it their way
because he didn't have a massive information, security community like we do now.
That's right for, for sure. 100%. It was,
I mean, back when Steve
Steve Christie is a person who kind of,
it
was the inception of much of this.
He was the only person talking about this at that time,
like literally the only person.
And so basically the US government rightly so well, and again,
we can't talk about the US government,
look at some cohesive whole that behaves rationally.
Elements of the US. Government
understood that, hey, we run software, software has security flaws.
We need to track those security flaws and deal with that.
How do we do that?
Well, if we track each vendor separately at each department level separately,
that's not gonna work.
So we need to centralize it's the many to many CV
E is trying to solve the many to many problem of many
bug producers to many bug
six consumers.
And it's the only database that does this freely unavailable.
There's a lot of private
-- ones.
-- They were the only database that did this freely unavailable.
Yeah, there was OS V DB for a while but they went, they closed up shop and went private.
There's a couple now we'll get to those maybe at
the end.
And
this is part of the problem is there's not even within the CV E program.
There are CV numbering authorities
and they're different. There's commercial ones, there's project ones,
there's miter who's the CV E CV,
numbering authority of last resort and handles
what we call the retail assignments.
So that's where you
go, like their shop front.
Right. What is it? CV, form.miter.org or something?
-- It's CV
-- e.org now and there's a link there.
Oh, yeah. Yeah, they changed it. Right.
And you, you know, you, you fill out a form saying give me one CV, E, please, sir.
And in theory if there's AC N A for that software, they, they ship it off to the CN A.
-- No,
-- they don't, they don't,
they tell you there's AC N A and it's up to you to go find them.
-- Oh,
-- sorry. Yeah. Yeah,
that's right. It's very obnoxious.
-- Yeah, they
-- don't, I, I keep forgetting that.
Yeah, they have a list of CNAs and they're like, good luck,
go contact them and some of the CNAs are not easy to contact because
again,
well, without going into a tangent, one reason a lot of places become AC
is to control the flow of CV S with respect to the product.
So they can basically say no to it.
OK. OK. Hang on before we get into the technical details.
I want to back us up and I want to talk about the structure of CBE CV E we just said Mir
is basically the organization in charge. But then CBE also has a board
-- which is ineffective and useless.
-- It's completely ineffective.
It's lifetime appointments.
-- And
-- I say that as a member, former member and former member
quit, I
resigned.
That's
true. Well, resigned, quit, whatever.
But it's,
these are lifetime appointments and that is like the worst thing you
can do for any organization is just stick people on something.
There's no fresh blood. No, it's, it's very old thinking.
And a lot of these people on the board are not like hip and new in,
in the world of cybersecurity.
They exist in a space that's literally 20 years old now.
And so, OK, I want to set that as,
as the first chess piece that helps explain everything going
on is just the fact that the CBE organization is
not current. We'll say the way they operate is very 1990
there is zero accountability or transparency into what goes on.
So when you end up in a situation like curl did. There's almost nothing you can do.
And, and
to put it bluntly,
this is part of fundamentally how miter
is structured with respect to the US government
is the US government pays for this. They
answer to the US government, they don't answer to us,
they don't answer to the public.
That's also true. That's a good point.
They do have accountability.
It's just not the sort of accountability we expect or need or want.
That's,
-- you
-- know,
it's the same kind of accountability. Lockheed Martin has
to a bunch of senators.
-- Lockheed
-- Martin doesn't care what I think. That's exactly.
They really don't.
There's a lot of challenges with the CV program but,
but fundamentally part of it is people also like,
people don't even get the source of CV, correct.
They say, oh, the national vulnerability database. Well, no, that's not.
-- Let's explain what NVD is.
-- NVD
is not CV E no NVD
consumes the CV database.
They enrich it and in the past they would enrich
it and then have their data that they would ship.
Now, in theory, they, I think they're also
shipping their data back to the head and CV database.
Uh And the two main enrichments they do are C pe which is common product enumeration.
So that's like so
o
version six or, you know, Red Hat Enterprise version nine, whatever.
I think it's platform.
No, it's common product because it's, it's, it's application platform,
whatever hardware and then the second thing they do is the CV SS scoring.
And for example, here's a thing, most people don't understand
NVD must
take a worst case scenario approach
to assigning a CV SS score
because they don't know how the US government uses the software necessarily.
For example, at Red Hat, we would say things like, oh Samba, you,
you can't expose file sharing to the internet.
That's insane. You
just can't and we would score it as local network, right?
Whereas NVD would have to say, well,
-- yeah, that's, that's how it should be.
-- Show Dan disagrees with you.
Yeah, exactly.
Show Dan dot IO. Look for uh dot gov
IP space and port 445.
Right. Yeah.
Right.
So, and that's,
there's a lot of these misconceptions about how this whole thing operates like,
oh my, my favorite is well, but they, they validate the CV S.
No, they don't,
they can't like when Schneider
Electric does a CV, I, I don't have a bunch of Schneider
Electric relays and PL CS to test it on.
And I don't have the time for this. Like I assigned somewhere between six and 8000 CV.
Si lost count at some point. I used to have the data.
People seem to think I validated them.
Uh
Right.
-- There's no way you can
-- not.
No,
no,
I literally would like make sure the CV request was reasonably somewhat sort of San
-- and maybe ideally linked to a code commit and That's
-- right.
And, but this is where transparency becomes an important factor in all of this.
-- And I was open to feedback,
-- right. Well, that's just it like the github
data. Github's database is currently the best that exists on the pause.
What is the github
-- database? So we talking
-- about
the vulnerability database, github
-- has a vulnerability database.
-- We're talking about GH SAS now see
-- the GHS A
-- data.
And here's another problem is where's the actual CV database?
And the answer is it's on an internal miter system.
Well, what you see on github
is a essentially not the source of truth. It is a
if you look at the github
logs,
you
mean
you mean the CBE database stored in the github
repository,
which sort
-- of the CV E list repo,
-- right? It's not stored in the github
repo so much as it's published there.
Because what happens is they essentially,
if you
basically, if you go to this github
repo slash CV project slash whatever and try to commit to the database,
do a poll request something, the answer is no.
What you do is they do a poll request
and that data is then ingested every hour to some back end miter system. You know,
God knows where
I do know it was written in Pearl back in the nineties by Steve.
Uh Well, what else are you going to write in the nineties? Right?
Um Probably still chugging along in Paarl because I know every
time some unicode got in there it would just cause havoc.
It's still bad.
Yeah.
So anyways, they, once an hour they pull data out of
github, do some stuff on the back end and then push it back out,
plus whatever else they got through the CV form or
through the private whatever.
There's,
they're, they've been trying for years now to like,
go to like an API model and to kind of,
to, to put it on uh simply to use it correctly
because they're not using it correctly right now.
They're using it as a publishing platform, not as a development,
actual collaborative platform. These details do matter because these details
what they can do that
I wanna stop us because I feel like
there's way more, it is a giant mess and it's way messier and way giant than I thought.
So let's just focus, let's walk through this particular curl CD E
and we can explain what happened along the way and how this happened
because this is the part I don't think everyone understands.
So as far as we know, and this is also a lot of this
is hearsay and conjecture.
It's relatively safe conjecture because I've been through this, we've been,
this is not our first rodeo.
It is.
But I'm saying like there is no
transparency to this process. This is any the only reason curtain and I,
the only reason Kurt and I know what's happening behind this curtain is because
we got to see behind one of the curtains for a period of time.
-- We did it a couple dozen or 100 times. A lot
-- of times. But there's still other things.
We don't know a lot of other things and there's probably very,
there's probably less than 10 people on the planet
who actually know the answer to this stuff.
Like honest to goodness. So,
so here's what happens. There's a, A curl CV E.
So someone
apparently went to Miter and said, hey Miter,
I want a CV E for this curl issue
and they gave Miter the data. OK?
Miter issues A CV E.
That's not unusual at all.
You can go to Miter's Web form and say I want a CV E for
this thing and if there is no CN A which there isn't for curl,
they will say here's a CD E and then they add whatever information you gave Miter
Tweet, the CV E and Bitter does.
They will probably click some links and make sure
like you're not going to porn sites or something,
but they aren't gonna like
read the links and then look at code and things like that, right?
They're basically just gonna say, does this look mostly correct?
And that's basically what I would do is I would ideally, I,
I would often push back and say I need a, I need a,
I need a link to either the code commit or to the like where the code is bad because
the vast, like for open source, at least the vast majority of bugs,
once somebody points out to you what it is and where it is, it's like, oh yeah. Yeah.
Ok. Yeah, you should fix that
-- like a
-- pothole. This is a legitimate integer overflow, right?
It is an integer overflow like, but there are lots of integer overflows.
Some of them are security bugs. Some of them aren't OK.
OK. So this CV E goes into the CV E data set which then means NVD brings it in
and NVD,
they add a CV SS score. OK.
Now, Kurt and I have talked,
it just look at the archives like we have talked at length.
What's wrong with CV SS and there is much wrong with it.
But again, NVD sees integer overflow in curl and they're like holy crap.
This is probably bad, right? Because they don't really know the context.
They don't really understand curl, right?
And now mind you, no one has talked to curl so far at all.
-- So NVD gives it a very high score.
-- Well, and in fairness curl
is hard to get a hold of like that guy
straight up. I think he lives in the middle of nowhere and has no internet.
I don't know,
he has internet, he publishes Curl
and he's on Mas
-- on all the time. I don't know, I don't know.
-- I'm being sarcastic, I'm pointing out.
OK.
But there, there's lots of open
-- source people that live in the middle of nowhere.
-- But the point is like a lot of open
source projects are actually
not that hard to get a hold of. Some are slow to reply.
-- But
-- curl at the same time, here's the thing.
Given the current structure of NVD and CBE,
you cannot expect them to reach out to every open source project.
-- Every time a vulnerability is filed,
-- I would agree.
-- However, for certain things like curl that run on everything on the planet,
-- maybe,
maybe.
-- Ok, I won't,
-- there's
a
library on everything on the planet
and even off the planet.
Yes.
-- Yes. Yeah. On other planets.
-- So I think maybe an exception could be made.
OK?
I'll give you that.
So anyway,
so NBVD gives it a very high score and then
obviously everyone starts talking about it because they're like,
what's going on.
And of course, a lot of people are yelling at Curl because they're saying curl,
why are you so dumb?
-- And
-- they find out by people like emailing them
and yelling at them and their issue tracker.
Not exactly.
And, and here's the thing I don't, I don't buy is
it's not that hard to have a pattern of regular expressions like curl dash star
and his email address
-- and just have a simple fire off a note.
-- No, I don't think that's the answer.
-- The answer is proper transparency. Oh, no, no,
-- it's not the answer.
-- Yeah, that, that is not the answer. So
-- don't, don't even suggest a terrible fix.
Like that is not a solution for what is
-- currently a completely broken system
-- to be clear.
That is not the fix. I'm just pointing out
for them to have not contacted curl at all is the bar is so low to contact and curl that.
-- Again, it shows how broken this is.
-- I'll leave that story in because you're not wrong
but
technical,
you are technically correct. So anyway, now,
now Daniel goes to basically, he sends an email to CV E saying this is ridiculous.
You need to pull this out
and here's a question. Um No pause.
How do you send an email to CV?
-- Well,
-- you don't, you have to use their terrible form,
-- I think
-- because there used to be CV at miter.org.
But now you get a bounce back saying don't contact us here.
There's basically no good way to contact them, right?
So he sends a message to CV E basically saying this is not a security issue,
please reject it
and CD E replies back with
no,
and it's not like you know who you're talking to. It's signed like
the CV. What did, what did he say,
the CV E assignment team?
And
I don't even know who that is.
I,
-- I don't even
-- know.
That's what ticks me off about CD E is an enormous amount of what they do.
Like when they tried to fire me. It wasn't signed by people.
Also, there's, I'll put a link in the show notes about the story when,
when CV E tried to get me fired from my job.
Well, they also made threats against me in the DWF and the blah, blah, blah.
It should also be clarified. These people do not like Kurt and I
not
at
all
-- at all which I I wear is a symbol of pride. I will add.
-- Yeah. And
one thing to be clear too is Miter is big enough that like, yeah, there's
even within the CV E I OK.
Storytime,
this is maybe a decade ago is when I managed to get Miter CV E project to move into, get
even within the CV E
team at Miter,
there was a kind of a 5050 battle going on of should we
make github the source of truth or continue to use our back end?
And unfortunately, the back end won out because I think
it makes it easier to justify funding it to the DH S.
If it's like in a ma
database,
it's control github.
Yeah.
But even within
I know within Miter's CV E team,
there are like there were the people that were more pro
open source basically and
open source in the sense of turning this into
an open source project versus the very regressive.
Not like this is a, this is a budgetary line item that we're going to milk
that
that's it.
And
so
that's the thing within Miter and the team.
It's, there's big enough and there's enough politics going on. But
like, even Miter, some of them hate you and me and some of them are like,
I wish Kurt had won. That's probably true.
Straight up. I had one of them tell me,
Miter
doesn't
hate us. CD E doesn't like us. There's a huge difference. Miter is a giant company.
-- Even within CV E, there's people that hate us and like us,
-- whatever. Ok.
Anyway, ok, we're, we're off on too many tangents. Ok.
-- Well,
-- but this is part of the problem is that this is,
this isn't an open source project.
This is
a government funded thing
that's run by a quote unquote
nonprofit corporation.
So now, so, so Daniel asked meter to reject this meter
says, no, he asked NVD to resort
it.
Right?
And again, like
NVD scoring is not like some open transparent thing. It's a magic black box.
You can at least have an email address. Thank goodness.
Well, and I know for a fact, I don't know now, but I know back in the day they,
it was subbed out to a defense contractor.
-- It very well might be. I have no idea. No, no,
-- no, no, it was
100% sub to a defense contractor back in the day.
-- No,
-- I mean, it was, I don't know if it still is.
-- I think
-- they brought it in house because they just realized how much they were paying
for something that was not high quality.
It doesn't matter. It's, that is an unimportant detail.
Again. Well, but again, it shows how broken it is.
Why, here's a question,
why is NVD scoring this and not, you know,
the people who own the software
or why aren't they at least giving the people
that own the software the chance to score it?
Right. And then the answer is because their process is 25 years old
and the whole project is designed as a funnel as a 25 year old work process.
And they don't, for example,
here's what's wild to me.
You think at some point after issuing a couple dozen cvs for curl,
they would have like approached him and said like, hey,
let's make you AC N A and like have you handle this?
It's possible. They did.
-- And he said no, because being AC N A adds cost for little value. Uh
-- actually, no,
-- it adds cost for negative value.
-- OK?
But anyway,
so Daniel does say in his blog post that there he's going
to become AC N A just to deal with this BS,
which is
ridiculous.
And again, this shows how broken is the only way to interact with this program
is to become a full fat CV numbering authority. There's, there's zero
and essentially your two options are become a CV numbering authority or
-- join the board and join the board is you
-- can't join,
you can't join the board.
You can only,
yes, you can if you are a big enough CV,
numbering authority with enough political clout.
-- Like, say Microsoft. Well, that's
-- just it. Right. Right.
So the answer is basically your, your,
your entry and access to CV is either not at all.
Go
-- way or you have to literally jump all the way up.
-- Yeah, it's 0 to 100.
There's nothing in between. Exactly.
-- And this is obviously one of the
-- problems and
that's something I tried to fix and failed at.
-- Sorry, it's not
-- your fault.
Uh, so anyway,
so he emails MV DMV.
D does rescore it but he says it's not a vulnerability
at all and they rescore it to a 3.3 I believe,
-- which they at least got back to him and they did something.
-- It's like,
it's like 3.6 and
not so bad, not so great.
I mean,
it should have been a zero but whatever, whatever. I mean, this is again,
who, who scored it? Why did they score it the way they did? We have no idea
-- it
-- should have been
like the GSD does
-- an informational with a score.
-- That's just it.
There, there, there is a concept of informational and you can make the argument that
under some completely bizarre set of circumstances.
This is a concern you might have because it can create some network traffic.
But fundamentally
this is like,
uh,
I stuck a fork in the outlet and stood in a bucket of
water and then turned on the light switch sort of like just no,
no one does that.
More importantly, it's like what the, the one kernel person wanted is.
They want informational tracking of all of this so that they can say, look,
every time we use this type of
C data structure and memory, it results in a flaw, right?
-- That is a different conversation. We will talk about that some
-- other day.
But see, that's the problem is
CV E air quotes here only does real vulnerabilities.
-- Well,
-- that's what they tell people, but it's,
-- it's full of tons of garbage
-- 100%.
And that,
that's one of, I mean, that's one of the other,
I guess urban myths around CV E is there's this perception that if it has a CV E ID,
it's an actual real vulnerability.
But the reality is, I bet you
80 plus percent of this data isn't ever vetted by anyone except the submitter.
I mean, I worked at security firms prior to Red Hat. Uh We,
no, uh the open source stuff we kind of looked at briefly but like close source stuff,
how you,
you can't vet Hitachi data systems product bla unless you show him
a copy of that thing and it's like a million bucks.
Also a quick thing. There's a couple of misconceptions here.
Number one, you can only have a CV, if you have an actual vulnerability.
Well, obviously not, you can have a CV
to put it bluntly, you can have a CV. If somebody assigns a CV,
that's it.
You don't have to have a code patch, you don't have to have exploit code.
You don't have to have exploitation in the wild.
You straight up just have to have this looks enough like a problem or,
and,
and this also a lot of people are focusing on the
open source world where you actually have at least some degree of
transparency and knowledge about the code and what the heck's going on.
-- But I have seen CV S issued for close source stuff where it's kind of
-- like, OK, here's,
here's a good example.
So let's say I and this used to happen all the time.
I'm a security researcher, I find a problem in,
let's say Microsoft was super notorious for this.
And I'd say I found a bug in, in IIS and Microsoft says, nope, not security
and then I could be like, I think it is security.
And now you get into some sort of argument with Microsoft and you can go to CV E as the
researcher and say I found this vulnerability.
Microsoft says it's not a vulnerability.
I want a CV E and that creates a whole weird like flow chart of madness.
But if, if you can convince the CV E people, oh
actually, uh so that flow chart.
So some of that stuff used to be properly documented in the CN A guidelines.
-- Version three. It was taken out in version four
-- II. I haven't read them in a long time.
It doesn't surprise me.
-- Yeah, that's
-- anyways, I'm just going to read this and this isn't some hypothetical.
This is just uh sorry. The word you want to search for is unknown. OK.
-- So this is from 2023 yesterday.
-- From the time of recording.
Yeah, from yesterday, the time recording
a vulnerability comma which was classified as critical comma has been found in
Yong
Gu
ya
dash
NC up to 2023 0807. Period.
This issue affects some unknown processing of the file, print template file serve.
Lett Java,
the manipulation of the argument file path leads to path traversal.
The attack may be initiated remotely.
The exploit has been disclosed to the public and may be used
the identifier V DB something something was assigned to the vulnerability.
So that's a perfect example of the vulnerability database assigned this as AC N A.
OK.
-- Do you see any useful information here?
-- No, no, certainly not, not really.
And then there's a link to a PDF and G out
exciting.
But OK.
So here's the problem
-- and no, but here's the, this is an example of a good high quality unknown CV.
-- Of
course, they're all high quality.
-- What was that one
-- you found that was like 20 or 30 characters long in the description.
Oh
-- my goodness. And it was like
-- in the SQL
-- error exists,
-- it was something like that.
It was,
it looked like they did like a copy and paste but
only copied like the 1st 2.5 words and pasted it.
And here's my favorite thing is the CV D description used to require things like
a product and a version and uh what it is and where it is.
And so I literally have like a Python script that just did a fill in the blank
and it was better.
But now
they don't actually even require the product name or version
in the description because that can be in the links.
So now is the beautiful part is CV, is a database
that is fundamentally not machine consumable because a lot
of the data is in that free form text,
which maybe A I can read now.
But essentially you have to click on all the links to
read all that stuff for it to be any use.
And this is where companies like I defense and eyesight came in is we would do all that
-- and then turn it into an XML feed that was actually machine readable,
-- right? OK.
So here's where I want to finish this up
because we've already spent like 20 some minutes talking about
all of the problems and there are many,
-- but that's
-- the point people think that this is some machine that works smoothly,
you know,
it's this Rube Goldberg contraption that's 25 years old and falling apart.
It is, it's falling apart. I agree with that 100%.
And I think there's still too many people who either don't understand
or are, are misled purposely.
Maybe there are people that only look at a few CV S A year. They don't look
hundreds or thousands.
Here's the thing I want to focus on is the transparency and accountability aspect.
Let's look at, I'm going to use github
-- as the example because I've been working with github's data quite a bit lately.
-- OK.
Pause when you say you're talking about the github
Security Advisory github's
-- vulnerability
-- database. OK?
-- So the GHS A database, the
-- CV E data in github is that is CV ES data that is not github
data. When the word
github, I'm literally talking about github, the organization
-- and that's fair because
-- this and one comment. So you uh the github
security Advisory Database is
-- CV data. So basically all databases are CV
-- database. The github
data
is
the collection of GH SAS which like projects can file using github.
There's an option to file a security vulnerability, right? And they import
the miter CV E data
and they, well, they actually they,
they pull in NVD data as well because they have those
-- CV SS scores
-- CV data and NVD data are still different.
They are,
they are
and then they
github
enriches the data for the particular ecosystems. They care about. So like Python
and Ruby and Java and there's a handful of this stuff, right?
And then they add version information,
they add a bunch of stuff and then it goes
into their data set which is conveniently stored in github,
this
JSON files.
And then here's what happens.
So let's say I'm working with this data and I find a problem.
I can submit a pull request to github
that says here is and they have a very nice web form you can fill out.
And
so I
submit,
I submit a pull request. Well, I fill in the web form.
Let's say it submits a pull request
and then there's discussion about what, what's going on and in some cases it's just,
oh yeah, you're right.
You missed a link or, or this version was off by one or whatever
and that happens all the time,
but sometimes it's a little more confusing and
discussion has to happen where it could be.
I found this. I don't think this is a vulnerability for these reasons.
Here's my supporting evidence because if I show up and say, hey
github, this isn't a vulnerability.
They're gonna say
prove it. Like show, show us, show us your homework, we want to see, right?
And they do this all the time where they'll be like I,
I need more evidence like give me more
and so then you provide more and they might say yes, you're right or OK,
I see what you're saying.
But I disagree for this reason and there is a discussion in public
so anyone can go look at that discussion and say here is why
-- this particular thing looks the way it does
-- and not just
look at it, they can participate
for sure.
No, no, no. That's a huge thing because
I see discussion of CV ES on hacker news on Mastodon.
Now, I would have said on Twitter, but I,
that's dead. Wonderful, high quality discussion of CV S
and that data dies there.
It doesn't go back to the database. And that makes me very sad.
And, and so this is part of, I think what
infuriates me more than anything is
in the CV E world. I, so I do a lot of work with this data at anchor
part of like the sift and Gripe Universe in our product.
And I go out of my way to send changes somewhere else whenever I can. And I would say
more than 50% of the time I ask CV E to fix something.
They, they give me the thing.
Like I, I, I'm serious, like
it's everything from, no, we don't care or go talk to the CN A over here or whatever.
It's not that it's, again, you're ascribing sort of uh a reason.
It's no, it's, I remember the story about V and V MS.
My Children don't belong together with the IBM mainframes.
And basically, there's a quote from the story where it says is basically,
it's like watching a semi truck towing a double wide
house trailer run over a moped on the freeway because,
you know, changing lanes would have been too much work.
-- It's nothing personal. It's just sorry, I, I splatted you.
-- No, it's not personal.
I, no, I totally get that. I'm not saying it's personal against me.
It's just, this is the way the machine works.
Anyone who would like, I have sent them data before where they were like
like versions X to X and I was like, look,
here's the actual advisory from upstream that says this version is where it starts.
This version is where it ends. The data in your pros description is wrong
and they came back with, we didn't assign this.
You have to go talk to someone else and I was like effort. I don't even care.
So you know what I do, then I go to github.
I do my type
tye
thing in their little form. They say, oh, hey, you're absolutely correct.
-- Except holy cow.
-- But the problem is that
-- what people perceive to be as the source of truth for CV is wrong most of the time it
-- is.
And this is where I, I mean, I'm telling, you know, anyone listening,
if you are doing any work with vulnerabilities, just start using the github
data. Like for real, you would, you're a fool not to, it's easier to consume.
It's easier to consume. It's easy, you can update it.
So anyway, here's the thing that infuriates me.
-- So I do all this research on a particular vulnerability,
-- right?
And that knowledge dies in your head.
-- Well, it doesn't
-- anymore because I send it to get,
but you get, the point is like, I remember at Red Hat, we would keep
enormous quantities of
milk cook in Godzilla.
That way anyone coming after us could look at what we had done to say.
Why did you mark this as won't fix?
-- Why did you mark this as critical
-- or stuff with customers?
-- Right.
-- It's not just for customers and even for me,
like, I don't remember what I did yesterday.
I can't, there's too much data.
You know, this is the thing that
is missing 100% missing from the vulnerability universe is just the fact that
like if Daniel didn't write all this stuff down in a blog post,
would anyone know he'd done any of this stuff?
Not
at all, not at, not at all. There's zero records of this.
There's zero public conversations.
No one knows even now that it's been updated,
let's say he didn't write it down and things just magically changed in CV E and NBD.
No idea why no one would know Daniel did it.
We could think like, oh, someone must have sent them a correction who knows.
But
the thing it could have been me, it could have been you.
-- It could have been Dave and
-- you know what's funny, I've done that before. For, for NVD
is I have sent NVD updated C CV SS scores and said actually, if you read the advisory,
it specifically says this,
so we should be rescore it as this and they've accepted it.
No one knows, I sent it. No one knows where the score changed.
The score just changed like holy cow.
-- That is bananas
-- and it, it does blow my mind that these like large,
like basically the majority of the world relies on this data
set because it's the only public data set that's available.
It was and like a lot of data sets, it's kind of OK. Not terrible enough.
And they think it's good enough and they think it's fine
but they just do.
And I think part of the challenge too is a
lot of people don't work with this data at scale.
They only look at a few products or they look at, you know,
yeah, like log for log for shell, right?
-- Lots of people
-- probably looked at that.
I've actually had what I love is when, when people tell me no, Kurt, you're wrong. CV.
Does validate CV S and I'm like, oh, I know, I know, I'm like, even
like it's physically impossible to do this,
right?
Like there's stuff in the CV database that is like, it's like a nuclear reactor.
-- Like you can't go buy one and try it out.
-- So here's the problem.
So we're ranting about CV E and we're
declaring it fundamentally broken on countless levels.
And so
it is conceivable that CV E will say, hey, Josh and Kurt, those guys are idiots.
Just don't listen to them.
Right.
Well, they probably will. But you know what I mean?
Like, that's what they've been saying for 10 years.
-- This
-- is, what is it, is it, um, um, Brand
Dole's Law, right?
Which is, it takes like magnitudes more effort to refute that type stuff. And
if someone, if, if, if someone who is part of CV E or someone who works with CV E says,
oh yeah, all the data is validated.
How do you prove it?
Isn't even, we can't prove it's not, I mean,
you can look at the evidence and it's pretty clear but like,
you know what I mean?
-- There's so many examples of it being wrong.
-- Well, sure.
Well, we know that, but how would anyone else figure that out?
Well, that's, well and more to the point, why am I gonna go bother?
Like I used to go through the CV, data set and correct it because that was my job,
right?
Yeah, I remember doing that all the time
when I was at like eyesight and eye defense,
I would send in so many corrections.
Uh Like nowadays, why would I spend time going through the CV?
Data set to prove that's wrong? Because I've done that. I go to the GST.
Um What is it in the tools repo we have that CV,
post mortem where I went through and did some simple checking of stuff
and found
-- hundreds or was it 1000 major errors?
-- Right. Right.
-- But here's the thing I do this all the time.
-- Kurt.
And I, no, but my point is,
or I could spend time drinking beer and playing with my kids nowadays.
-- Well,
-- ignoring that. Look, your, your, your comparison is not correct.
I, my job is to have good data for a vulnerability scanner.
And I used to try to work with CV E and I've given up like I can work with github.
No problem github
is a source of truth as far as I'm concerned because
they listen,
it's a, it's a project that isn't a,
a scary black box that no one knows what's going on.
You can send them suggestions like
it is.
It's not as open as I wish it was. I, I wish it had more of a, a like
I, I guess open source project deal to
where there was more because like github, fundamentally, it is their data.
-- They get to make the rules which is fine right now.
-- But part of it is
there's the chicken and egg problem of it can't be a true open
source project because there's not enough people to be involved in it.
-- And I agree with that. That is definitely part of
-- the
-- problem.
-- You know, it's
it's kind of like Os V, it's like, why is the file form out this way?
Well, because Oliver made it that way. Why did he make it that way?
-- Because like, nobody was around to help him.
-- That's what he needed.
It solves his problem.
Yeah. And same thing with like, like why is the CV? Jason that way?
Well,
because that's what Kurt needed and Kurt asked the board and community to help.
Nobody did.
So Kurt did four versions in like six months and like, or a year and,
and then I had what the solution that I needed and well, sorry y'all
right. Right. No, IE Exactly.
But it's better
XML.
There were people that wanted XML and I held the line there. So you're welcome.
I can completely see.
And I would, I would bet you that conversation would happen again on the CBE board.
Uh It did happen multiple times after the CV E went to Jay Z on,
there were people that kept pushing for J XML for,
I'm
not
even
sure,
not even a little surprised. There's, well, why? Because
whatever
anyway,
so we've been ranting for nearly 40 minutes now
and
I want to end this on a positive note because I don't want
to just have us bashing CD E and telling everyone it's crap,
-- even though it is,
-- I think you're right.
The the most immediate best initial step people can take,
go consume the github
-- CV data from GHS A help
-- them make it
better.
Yes and well, and that leads to the second step, which is,
you can like, like and subscribe, leave comments below,
right? You can do that. Whereas with TV, it's like,
good luck.
That's right. If they give you the finger and tell you to go away,
that's
it. Like there's absolutely nothing else you can do about that.
Now, at the same time there, you could file a
change, data request to github APR and they could tell you absolutely not,
we're not taking this
and you don't have a lot of recourse at that point,
which is one of my complaints like github
is the final arbiter in that
context.
You can have a discussion, but at least it's done in public
where they can say github
can say absolutely not. We will not take this
and there's a public record that you can then say, OK,
this discussion needs to happen.
Let's have a discussion about this because there is a place to have a discussion
that does not exist in the CD E or NVD world.
-- And that is a problem that is a huge problem
-- that
also leads then to what we did with the GSD,
which is the name spacing because here's a fundamental problem,
there cannot be a database with a single source of truth
because as a very simplistic example,
your bug
-- might be my regulatory requirement.
-- Yeah, for sure, for sure. Absolutely.
And that happened all the time too with like your,
your Samba example where Red Hat would say don't use Samba on the internet.
-- We're calling it.
-- And even simpler,
remember every time the Department of Defense would come to
us with those root can shut down the system.
And we're like, yes, that's the
-- yes and really
-- its job.
But from the department of Defense's point of view,
-- that is a legitimate problem
-- and, and that happens.
And so there's always the context
or my other favorite is there will be times like a sequel injection would be
incredibly important for a particularly library.
If it's used as a web app versus I'm using
a local thing that's reading, you know,
a config file that root put in place like that's a very different situation.
And so there's always going to be context around that. But again,
this is where
having a, a secret private
club
that's supposed to try to maintain this, you can't have conversations,
you can't have a discussion.
Again, I don't think it's so much that they want to keep this secret is just,
that's fundamentally how defense contractors operate.
I
agree.
And look,
it's just their culture. Here's the other issue of it
is
it's not.
And there are probably a lot of people who want to open it, but they,
they don't know how and quite frankly, they, they can't,
this has been running the way it's been running for so long, like by definition,
if they could fix these problems,
they would have by now because this is problems that have been
plaguing these projects for a decade or more at this point,
this is not new,
it's just people are starting to notice
because I think vulnerabilities are becoming more mainstream
and there are just a lot more of them, right? Like there, this is what happens
when things get bigger,
people notice.
Yeah.
And I mean,
yeah,
part of it is the world has so fundamentally changed, the scale has changed
all these things. Like people need to be able to discuss this stuff somewhere.
That is
-- it, it, it has to be open source.
-- Well, no, no, no,
no, there has to be like an official
community in place to discuss this because
having random side conversations on Mastodon,
oh,
Daniel writes a really great blog entry and there's really
good comments or there's a great hacker news thread.
No, I'm sorry. That's
not good enough. No, no, for sure.
And that's one of the reasons I moved it into github
is I was hoping
not only would the source of truth be github,
but then there'd be the issues and the discussions there.
And if you go to the,
the CV E project github,
it's, it's, it's a frigging.
There's, there's not even tumbleweeds, it's that dead, right?
Like anybody files an issue or does APR they're
told to go away basically and use the form
and that's part of the problem is, so at least github
gets that right. With the
github, GHS, a data set,
you can go talk there, you can file issues, you can say, hey, blah, blah blah. Right.
Right. That's right. And that,
and that
there has to be official places for these discussions
because you can't ask people to be like,
oh, there's this really good threat on mast on.
-- So you should follow these seven people. And
-- that's,
oh, I know, I know. And now I want to add one last point long term,
we need some sort of like neutral worldwide
organization to fundamentally wrangle all of this.
And I know there have been like Mark
Ky said at one point, the UN should do it. Mark Curvey
is a guy who created O
api don't know if the UN is the right place. Maybe it is, maybe it isn't,
but it needs to be something like a nonprofit or a foundation
or some NGO type is and is the UN an NGO?
I don't know.
-- Anyway.
-- No, the UN is very much a governmental organization.
-- It's,
-- it's all the government organization, you know what I mean?
Like that is what we need. And we also, I want to say we also need
-- significantly more funding than we have for this
-- and it's never going to happen.
No, I
think.
No, no,
I'm not saying we have enough funding ever.
I'm just saying we need more than we have today.
And I'm saying this is, this will never happen.
I think it might. I think I'm, I'm hopeful.
I think if we can get enough people talking loudly enough to the right people,
I think it is conceivable because Kurt,
all it would take is the US government in the eu to each
dump like $10 million into this which they can find under the couch
and this problem is going to,
well, now we'll have the problem of how to spend the money.
You know what I mean?
Sorry not to go segue but you,
you and a lot of people always focus on the supply side of these vulnerabilities.
And I've always thought the demand side is the place to go. So for example, requiring
-- proper labeling or something, I think it would be better.
-- You are correct,
the demand side will help drive the demand side will drive supply.
And that's why we need the people using this data,
have to be complaining to their politicians and their governments
to go fix this.
The government is not going to fix this by itself,
right?
That we need the people trying to consume this data.
And unfortunately, I think we exist in this universe where people just think oh,
the data is crap.
Oh Well, like it doesn't have to be crap. Github
is proved, it doesn't have to be crap. And github
is doing this
with a hilariously tiny team,
but they also get to leverage the power of the community to amplify their work.
And that's the thing,
like, we don't need a government doing all of the work.
We need a government coordinating the work.
You know what I mean? And that's the thing, that's the thing
-- that just eats me from the inside. It turns
-- out project management is hard.
Who knew, who knew that was true.
And that's one thing I really respect,
I don't know if you've been actually tracking Daniel on Maston.
But
one thing he does is every time there's a new committer,
he celebrates that there's a new committer to
curl and he's celebrating the fact that his
contributions to curl as like the percentage of
the whole is shrinking and it should be.
Yes,
I,
I was about to say I have a suspicion that that
is the sign of the ultimate healthy project where somebody like
Guido Van Rossum or Lina Toral
is literally able to
step aside.
Yeah, that's
for sure.
-- The train keeps going and
-- that has to be the way it's
done because if you have like one person or organization in charge,
you have a serious problem.
-- So OK,
-- welcome to the open source world
there. Does that does happen and that is problematic.
That's a different discussion we're not having today.
So I guess all in all my closing thought
is if you're working with vulnerabilities, please, please please use the github
data and go help.
That is it? That's my only request and your life will get better if you do that.
And to be clear, helping doesn't mean you have to do a lot.
Literally, even just complaining in a public place where it's captured is helpful.
-- Yes,
-- it's a start for sure. Yep. Absolutely. 100% just filing a bug complaining.
Having a discussion. You can do that there.
They, like they have a github repository.
You can go to and open an issue that says, I think we should do this
and they might say no, but that's ok. That's at least a discussion.
Well, let me put it this way.
If you go to github.com/github/advisory dash database,
47 issues, 42 poll requests versus let me just pull up the uh
um hang on a second. Where is it? Because they keep moving stuff around. Uh Here we go.
The version 5,
14 issues, no poll requests. And let's see, the CV list is
14 poll requests, no issues
and the poll requests are all uh the issues are, wow. Ok. 2022.
Yeah, some of these are kind of old.
-- We
-- know that that's not
a surprise like there, it's non response.
It's basically, it's again, back to the whole dead zone.
It's a dead zone.
That's right. All right. Anyway, go ahead, github.
Well, more to the point. Github
will let you help. Yeah.
Right. Well, they're excited
for
you. Don't really have a choice.
No, I'm serious. Like,
thank you, Kurt. Thank you for listening. Go to over source security podcast.com.
Hit up the show, not its UZ Pound
O
podcast. Hashtag I Master
-- on Kurt, have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks
everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.