Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime.
Josh Bresser. Hey, Kurt, how are you doing?
I'm doing well.
It's getting warmer here
-- and by warmer, I mean, slightly less cold,
-- minus 10 °C,
-- something like that.
-- Yeah.
Right. The ball me get out the shorts.
Yeah. Baby steps.
It's winter. I get it.
Yeah.
Yeah. So I, so some really,
we finally,
the industry has crossed a bridge that I don't think has ever been crossed before.
Which bridge might that be
the remote bricking of cell phones for your own safety?
Yeah, that's the Samsung. Was it the Galaxy Note Seven or something or other?
I,
-- I don't know,
-- just for some context for our viewers because
they
probably heard about the, sorry. Yeah. Whoops.
Uh, they've probably heard about the Samsung seven, although, you know,
maybe they're listening to these five years in the future.
So this phone very nice phone, very thin phone,
very thin battery. The battery apparently doesn't have enough, um,
material between the layers.
Uh, so if you bend it even slightly the,
the various layers of uh electrolytic and capacitors and whatnot.
Touch each other and, well, they get excited and catch fire.
Um,
so Samsung did a recall.
Uh,
the carriers have done a recall and apparently some
people just are refusing to return their phones.
Right.
Uh, some people apparently really love these phones.
Uh, some people don't want to deal with their carriers or, you know,
they're out in a remote place and don't really, well, there's a good point.
Right. What if you're out in the remote
outback of Australia,
you know, the nearest phone store might be like a four day drive.
Do you have a cell phone if you live there? Is there cell service there
probably. But regardless,
you know, or, or you have an American phone carrier? Right.
Right. So,
anyway, so,
uh they've, I think they've basically gotten to the point where they, you know,
obviously they've recalled as many phones as they can.
So now the solution is
they're going to remotely, uh upgrade the firmware. Um,
and obviously there weren't a ton of details,
but it sounds like they're essentially
breaking the phones, um,
to the point of also the firmware.
Uh, the new firmware from what I read won't let the phone charge.
-- So, like once you run the battery out, it's done.
-- Exactly.
Which is really clever because once the battery is dead,
it is considerably less dangerous than when it is full of electrons.
Exactly.
But this also then does raise the interesting point of, you know,
typically cell phones are required to be able to make 911 calls no matter what.
Even if they're like off contract,
obviously, you can't make a 911 call with a dead cell phone battery.
That's true. But you, i,
if it lights on fire and maims, you, you also can't call 911 to tell them you need help.
True. So, I guess what we really need are two statistics.
How often do these phones catch fire?
And secondly, how often, you know, say,
uh per hour of carrying a cell phone, how often do people actually call 911,
you know, in a meaningful way?
Right.
Uh And of course, we don't have that data.
So we're gonna make some stuff up.
Why
not?
I,
I would,
I would pause it that
like many things.
This is a good intention.
II, I do, I, I think it's a good intention and this is kind of, you know, this is unlike
or rather not unlike,
this is similar to your typical
enterprise risk scenario where everything carries risk
if you do or don't do something.
And is the risk of these phones injuring people
greater than
the risk of them not being able to dial 911?
Yeah.
Well,
and there's a second thing here that really
makes me quite curious because this scenario,
typically the scenario
with a software problem is that there's no more manufacturer
to update it or the manufacturer just doesn't care.
In this case, it's an actual hardware problem
and we have a manufacturer who does do well,
is updating the software and has a mechanism in place
to shove that software update out, right?
Like these, these are literally connected devices, they are cell phones, right?
Like a lot of
-- IOT devices may not have that connectivity.
-- That that part is true.
But however, even with the phones,
they still need to work with the carrier because I believe I
read somewhere that Verizon has said we will not push this update
to our customers.
-- Interesting.
-- Yes.
So yeah.
Well, I mean, my understanding is for the,
and this is one of the reasons I went with an iphone
is so that there are no carriers involved in my updates.
But
in general, yeah, with the, with the updates shipped through the carriers,
the carrier has to put them on their servers
and actually push them out to the devices.
And, and you think about the
incentives here is if you're Samsung,
you want
a dangerous device off the market.
If you're Verizon,
if you break these devices, you now have angry customers.
Yeah.
Well, especially at this point, I mean,
the kind of person that hasn't handed their phone in
either really loves that phone or really hates dealing
with their phone carrier or some other version.
No, like by definition right there. It's a, it's literally a self selecting group
that probably is really going to be unhappy that you break their phone
probably.
But it's, oh, man, this is such a weird problem.
Now, now there's, there's kind of another thing to think of here is
so
in the context of the telephone,
there is actual physical harm that can result from a manufacturing defect, right?
And
the way the law works in this instance is
this is something I'm not a lawyer.
And so I'm certainly not an expert,
but I've discussed this with a handful of lawyers in the past is
you have to show physical harm for there to be
some sort of liability suit you could file.
And obviously in the case of an exploding phone,
there's certainly physical harm. Right.
Whereas
if it's just a device that
steals all of your information,
there's no actual physical harm there. And so
this is such a crazy problem to think about and
it's not something we've ever had to deal with before.
Well, we've had, well, that's not true. We've had bad hardware.
Like a perfect example. Hoverboards, right? Hoverboards were so bad that
they were entirely banned from import to the US for a while is my understanding.
Um, but of course, hoverboards generally don't
do over the air software updates
-- and
-- they don't hover, which
I,
no, I was quite annoyed about that.
I
remember when I saw the headline at the hoverboard.
I'm like, oh my goodness, someone did it.
The
thing
is wheels. Like what the heck this isn't a hoverboard. This is just
the
seriously.
But, um, so that's the thing. Right.
We've never really had a hardware device that was this
clearly badly affected. Right. We've had hardware devices that, like,
die after a certain amount of time or just, you know, whatever fail or don't work.
Right. But not, like,
really catch fire.
With the exception of a lot of those hoverboards with cheap batteries
combined with the fact that we have
an actual device that does have that
internet wi fi capability and most importantly,
a manufacturer who will shove out an update. Right?
Most of those,
my understanding is like you look at these hoverboard manufacturers,
they're not, you know, brand names you would recognize,
right?
And I really, you know,
obviously based on the fact that these things were catching fire all the time,
I don't think any of the manufacturers really care all that much.
Probably not
because, I mean, let's face it.
If the phones didn't have
a, we'll say very well established
international brand associated with them.
I wonder if the manufacturer would even care or, I mean,
in the case of some of this dodgy import stuff, how much of this stuff is,
I, I guess sold by companies that,
that are just paper companies that they were
spun up just to sell this one particular product
and if it fails miserably, they just dissolve themselves.
Well, that's, I mean,
that's exactly what happened with all those digital video recorders, you know,
you had the, um, the Chinese company whose name I can't pronounce
c
actually creating the hardware and software and then basically shipping boards
with software preloaded out to uh white box manufacturers who,
like physically, you know, wrapped a case around it, put a sticker on it and then,
you know, sold it via
alibaba.com or any number of importers. Right.
And those companies, even though they're not technically a paper company,
they're,
they're quite happy to, to, you know, change their name and, and keep.
-- Right.
Well, and let's face it too when a lot of this stuff, like,
especially when you're buying a hoverboard.
How many people said, oh, what company built this, I'm only buying the name brand.
You know, nobody said that they were just, oh, Hoverboard,
I'm going to buy the one for 100,000 a
name brand. Hoverboard.
Are they all Hoverboard? I don't, I don't even know.
Well,
I was watching a TED talk talking about this and so the
name Hoverboard actually was a viral thing because at first they were called
all sorts of things.
Like, uh, well, actually some people call them segues or stick Segways or,
um, you know, uh,
what was it?
Unicycles or?
Exactly.
And, and Hoverboard is funny because this guy showed, you know,
these listings on ebay and on, uh,
I think it was Alibaba or one of those related sites,
you know,
showing that eventually everybody converged organically on hoverboard.
Right. And that's just the word that won,
you know. So it's not like somebody picked that word.
It just, it's what ended up happening.
Um,
so, yeah, with the Samsung phone, it's, I mean,
you obviously Samsung does generally seem to care a little bit about their brand,
uh, which is good
and,
yeah, I, I really wonder if.
So talking about product liability law, what does the law say about, you know,
a phone that fails to make a 911 call resulting in actual harm to somebody?
That's an interesting question.
I don't know how that would work because there's obviously physical harm
in that. Well,
there is, but there, I don't,
-- well,
-- there was lack of action,
right?
The phone did not cause the harm but the phone maybe made that harm worse by, you know,
not being able to call an ambulance.
-- Right.
-- But I guess
so, here's part of it too though, is,
can you blame the phone manufacturer when you have had
a ton of warning to get rid of this thing?
And they told you they're going to break it
and, you know, it isn't going to work.
See, my thinking is that would be the exact,
-- that would be one of the arguments if I were a lawyer I would look at, I mean,
-- this,
this seems like a, a pretty dodgy position if you have one of these phones.
If the manufacturer has told you get rid of it. It's dangerous.
They've taken
incredible steps to deal with this problem and you're still holding on to it.
I mean, this, this would not be, you know. No, no. You know what
I wonder because let's say you have an automobile
and there's a recall where if you say
get into an accident, it bursts into fire
claims and you don't get the recall work done on the, on the vehicle.
If you get in an accident and someone gets hurt,
I would hope if you've been contacted multiple times by
the the manufacturer that basically it's your own
fault for not doing something reasonable about it.
So here's an interesting area we move into.
I don't want to say blame the victim, but in the sense of you own a device that,
you know, can
ultimately cause harm in some way to another person, either by
catching on fire or in this case by being bricked and not being available.
Um
I mean, we've, we've sort of seen this to some degree with cars,
although to the best of my knowledge,
you know, it's never, well, it's
there are not laws per se against this that I'm aware of, but there are, you know,
if you get into an accident with somebody and their car was not well maintained,
you can, you know,
your lawyer could definitely argue that they did not take due care,
um, you know,
with their vehicle and thus created. Um
well, basically they would be liable for the lack of action, lack of say,
maintenance, right?
Or lack of whatever that resulted in their car hurting, you know,
if the brakes failed.
So that's already well established that, you know, to some degree you have to,
you know,
you can't like tie pointy sticks to the front of your car and take the brakes off.
-- So,
-- so that flame thrower, I mounted on the front, That's a bad idea.
-- Uh, yes. Yes. It's also illegal, I think in all States except for Nevada.
-- I
-- wonder is that illegal?
-- I don't know. I'm pretty sure flamethrowers are illegal.
Uh, because
I remember Mythbusters did that episode. Um,
but you can get those propane torches
but they're not technically flamethrowers,
but they did. I, well, I know they ended up using a guy's flamethrower in Nevada.
So I'm thinking it might have been legal but anyways
back to the car thing and the, the device thing is,
yeah, I mean, at some point, if a device manufacturer has contacted you and said,
you know, we,
we sold these light bulbs, they catch fire.
We've told you about this, we've offered a trade in program or, you know,
something reasonable.
Not like a dollar off your next light bulb.
What a deal.
Yeah.
You know what, at what point do you,
the consumer of this faulty product start to become liable?
You know, is, is it a month, six months, a year? 10 recalls
avoiding an over the air firmware update.
I, I
don't know.
-- I mean, this is crazy, crazy stuff to think about it to say the least
-- it's,
but it's gonna happen.
-- It
-- is
-- happening, right. We're in the middle of it right now.
Yeah,
I mean, and the thing is what's interesting to me is,
is with an over the air update of your cell phone that's harder to block.
But with, uh for example, like a Wi Fi device like um well, for example,
I have n smoke alarms at home.
I could
block their access to the Wi Fi internet, right?
I could just turn off the access point and
they would no longer get over the air updates from Google.
But conversely, I would lose a lot of the functionality of that device in that,
you know, when my smoke alarms go off,
they talk to the Wi Fi which sends a message to Google which in turn then sends a,
you know, a message to my phone.
So my phone starts ringing whenever somebody burns dinner
with these devices, some of them probably won't
suffer as much from lack of connectivity to the internet.
So for example, light bulbs maybe or
you know, something along those lines.
Does any, I wonder if anybody has
run into this before with electronics or with a car where, you know,
there's been a recall
and people have ignored it and then caused harm
as a direct action of ignoring the recall.
I mean, it must have happened at some point like, uh,
the Firestone tire recall. I don't you remember that from about a decade ago?
I do you know that was, I mean, when they showed those rollover tests it was like, oh,
dear,
that, that's bad.
Yep. Yeah,
it's,
but, but again, we end up in a situation where I feel like
automobiles
are more clear to people.
If you don't do this, you're going to get hurt
-- and
-- well, self driving cars are not too far away with
software like
Tesla is already do over the air updates.
Right.
And that's a whole another ball of crazy right
there when we think about devices in that context.
But, but so back to the phones though is,
I guess you could make the argument
that
if you bring your phone in.
Do you get a new one immediately or do you have to wait for some sort of warranty type?
Depends
on your, see,
that's part of the challenge here is that depends
on the carrier that depends on your contract.
That depends on a whole bunch of different things. Right. I mean,
and it could even vary between customers. Like,
uh, at one point I know I've been a customer of my phone company for like,
10 years and I had, you know, and they were like,
they actually were trying to get me to trade in my phone for a new one for free.
Right.
So that they could lock me into another two year contract.
And so like you could have, I'm, I'm certain there's Samsung people who, you know,
have been with their carrier so long that their carrier would be like,
we'll give you whatever phone you want. We don't care.
You're a great customer versus, you know,
the people who are not such a great customer and they're like,
we're gonna take your phone and hang on to it for like,
Lord knows how long and we may or may not give you a phone
at some point or you have to buy a new one. Sorry,
I, I don't even know what the deal is. You know, if you have the phone on contract,
do you technically own the phone at that point or is it like a lease thing?
I,
I always assumed you own it and you just have like the payment thing going on. But
again, I, I really, I, I don't know.
So I think that's part of the problem, especially with phones,
most devices are very clearly sold,
right? Like when you go buy light bulbs, you go and you buy light bulbs, you don't
sign a contract.
Uh saying that, you know, you'll stay with the light bulb carrier.
I don't know, whatever for a few years
carrier, you know,
you know, even with things like Nest, right?
If I buy a Nest camera, I can cancel my contract with Google. Uh I believe.
But, you know, I would still, well, I would lose a ton of functionality of the device,
you know, whereas with a cell phone you can change from one carrier to another.
So I,
I wonder if cell phones are maybe gonna be a
weird corner case because of just how strange they are,
you know, and that they have this, like,
they require network access to work, obviously.
Uh, but you can switch carriers, you can switch networks.
Yeah, I mean,
yeah,
you can, you can. And so it, it depends. Oh,
man, it's
my brain can't handle this.
I think the lawyers are going to have a heck of a time with this.
I'm gonna apologize right now to any lawyers who might be listening for our,
we'll say
egregious
-- armchair lawyering that's going on right now.
-- And,
and I mean, of course,
it varies by jurisdiction because remember those European jurisdictions where,
uh it was just recently in Denmark,
the guy,
it was like a four year court case
and he basically took his iphone into the Apple Store
to get it replaced because it was broken or something.
And they wanted to provide him a refurb and he was like, no,
you'll give me a new phone and four years later he, well, he's getting his new phone,
I guess.
Um So that's the other thing to remember, right?
Is some jurisdictions have laws that say literally like this product
has to be suitable for purpose and the customer has,
you know, one or two years
that, like, it has to work, you know,
you can't just poop out after 30 days,
you know,
and I'm pretty sure that remotely bricking your phone counts as not working.
I think that's fair.
Yeah, it's, I mean, this is one of the reasons I actually,
I think with self driving cars I would much prefer to see them
as much as I dislike the idea of like,
these large companies like Uber kind of controlling the whole fleet
at the same time. I'm not sure.
Something like a self driving car maybe should be owned by individuals.
You know, I don't think it should be because what happens
if I go into my car
and I tell it quit stopping at intersections and all the other
self driving cars are smart enough to not run into me.
Well, it doesn't even have to be something illegal like that.
It could be something like,
you know, don't let people, people in during a zipper merge
or don't, you know, don't, uh,
there's all sorts of things you can do while driving that are not illegal,
but they're certainly, you know, kind of not very polite or safe.
Right. It's,
I get this right. It's crazy
what is happening to these devices in the world
they are going into and I think it's safe to say that
humans are totally unprepared to deal with this as well as our laws
as well as just the, the corporations building this stuff. I mean,
we're rushing out to IOT
and we, like, we don't know what's out there.
We're, we're running into a field full of razor blades and monsters.
Yeah. No, it's, I mean, socially too, I'm kind of really,
uh, you know, a great example being every time I've flown in the last few months,
you know, they have that specific announcement saying that the, uh, what is it,
the US Department of
Transportation has like explicitly banned this one model
of phone from being on a plane?
A a
-- oh, sorry,
-- the
-- FAA
-- ban.
Yeah,
you know, that's like
specifically this is banned, like if you have one, tell us now or I,
I'm not really sure what the consequences.
It's a federal
offense.
I believe it's a felony if you're caught with it,
which means you could technically go to jail.
They
bring
something that is known to catch fire onto an airplane.
I mean, you're effectively bringing a bomb onto the plane, right. That's what it is.
Yeah. So are we going to see a lot more of that? Are we going to see that,
you know,
something along the lines of that with the road system?
You know, this, this, uh, this car with this version of firmware is, you know,
illegal, it's just so dangerous or something?
Right. Well, and where do you draw the line though? Right.
I mean, in this case, a phone literally starting on fire
is easy to understand. That's bad.
If you have a light bulb that is burning your house down,
that's bad.
If you have a car that gets into accidents, that's bad.
But what happens when you have
smoke alarms that maybe sometimes fail?
-- Sometimes?
-- Well, Nest had that
they
did,
Nest had, uh, Nest
had, I don't know if they still have,
but they used to have a feature where you
could just essentially wave your hand at the smoke alarm
and it would stop alarming. Um,
instead of having to physically hit the big button in the middle. Right.
Because, you know, I guess, well, yeah, if you have like 12 ft ceilings, you know, go
get a broom.
Um,
and they remotely over the air updated that to remove that
feature because apparently during certain types of fires or certain situations,
the fire, the smoke,
whatever could essentially replicate that it
could trigger that motion sensor type deal
to say, basically don't alarm. Right.
And obviously, you know, if you have a real fire that, that's a huge problem.
So they disabled that functionality.
Now, I'm lucky because, you know, I have 8 ft ceilings and I'm 6 ft two. So,
ok, it's annoying, but I can,
I can go hit the button.
Can't you just
my
cell phone to push a button or something?
Uh, I
think you can remotely, yeah, I think with the app you can tell it to stop alarm.
I'm not certain that you can, I think you, maybe you can't hang on a
second. I
just
need
cell
phones.
That don't.
I
actually, no, I don't, I've never noticed that feature in the
app.
Um, but anyways,
so,
you know, that's, that's an obvious health and safety thing. Right.
The smoke alarm doesn't alarm me when there's a fire.
And so, yeah, Google updated it forcibly. Too bad.
You're getting that update. Um Unless you like unhook it from the internet,
basically,
I don't think that's unreasonable in some ways, but in other ways,
you clearly don't own that device if the manufacturer can effectively
make whatever changes they want to it at any time.
Right?
Well, I mean, that's true of
essentially anything running software at this point because how,
how can I even open source stuff?
I can't possibly review all the changes that made
in the last Linux kernel update I installed or
Gnome or emacs or, or on my web browser. Good Lord. I mean,
the web browser is how big now
it's
and for example, you know, chrome just decided like, well, not just decided
a whole bunch of browser vendors. Oh, this is a good example.
Actually, a whole bunch of browser vendors have decided
that, you know, shaw one,
the signature uh algorithm sha one is no longer secure enough for, you know,
certificate use.
And so they're phasing it out right, starting in um what is it January of Well, yeah,
2017 so we can.
Oh
wow, six weeks.
So
yeah, that's ok. That's coming up quick folks.
Um you know, they're gonna start disabling it for root certificates.
And by my understanding is by 2019, Chrome will
will stop supporting sha one end of story.
Like you can still use sha one for
intermediate certificates or for end certificates currently,
but come 2019 that ends like chrome is
just chrome is basically saying like look if you
use sha one that's too bad for you go find a different web browser or you know,
fix your certificates because sha one is no longer considered safe.
So this is a very similar case of, you know, there's that
again, there's this very
small potential for harm.
It's more than
-- we've
-- seen this already though where how many organizations
had to keep a copy of IE six laying around
because some, some,
some server they had
only worked with IE six.
Yeah. Well, or the South Korean banking industry, right?
They standardized on that uh one algorithm,
encryption algorithm that was then really only available in an active X component.
So South Korea for the longest time was beholden to internet explorer
that if you wanted to do online banking, which of course, you know,
pretty much everybody does.
Um I believe they finally changed that.
And so now the browser usage in South Korea is changing, but
the reality is I think at this point, you know,
the software's gotten so large and so complex, I have to proxy my trust to a
lot of,
there's, there's two, there's two sides to this,
I think is there's the concept of proxy and
trust where I run yum update on my Linux machine
and stuff happens and I get updates
and if you have AAA Mac,
you get magic updates. If you have Windows, you get updates.
It's, in fact, I think in,
in Windows now you don't have a choice like you're just getting the updates.
Well, what they did is they used to provide updates,
essentially one software update per sort of vulnerability kind of model, right?
Uh or not necessarily per vulnerability but per block, you know,
group of vulnerabilities and say a specific version, right?
And you could download them separately and test them and install them and blah,
blah blah.
And then starting in, I think it was October of this year.
They like for Windows 10, there's every Microsoft Tuesday is now one file
for Windows 10,
I believe for server, they're still broken up, but don't quote me on that.
Um But for Windows 10, for the desktop especially,
it's like here's your update for October, either install it or don't
right there
by default they install,
which means the vast majority of people are just going to get updates magically,
which I do think is the right thing.
Mind you, I think that is correct.
But now
at the same time,
you've got
these operating systems and applications
that
-- I, I think for the
-- most part
critical systems.
That's fair. I agree with that.
But then we look at these devices
and
is it, is it, this, is it a comparable
thing that's happening with the way we're updating
a computer versus the way we're updating,
say a smoke alarm
where Google is just pushing things to it and you don't,
I think you just hit the nail on the head.
That's not a smoke alarm. That's a computer
that happens to behave as a smoke alarm.
But fundamentally it's a computer. It's a general
-- purpose computer,
-- isn't it?
Was, it, was it Bruce Schneier who said, uh, it's not a car,
it's not a car with a computer.
It's a computer with wheels.
Yeah. And I would agree. I mean,
I,
I look at my bathroom scale,
my bathroom scale is a general purpose computer that just,
its main purpose happens to be displaying to me how much I weigh.
Ok.
So, so we can call it a computer that also does something else, which I think is fair.
Well, I think the problem is,
is it used to be that even if you had a somewhat general purpose computer in a device,
it wasn't networked.
Right. So, the attack scenario for it was very limited. Like you had to have,
let's not even get to attacks.
I mean, we, we're just worried about updating this stuff.
And what about when manufacturers intentionally break something?
That's,
it's never really been a problem before.
Well,
the majority of these computers I think were doing things
that were simple enough that they almo like a toaster,
you know,
uh, a toaster definitely has the potential for failure most, like, just,
you know, burning the heck out of everything right
-- now.
-- Ok. So, yes, I mean, let's use a toaster is I
am on probably my third or fourth toaster since getting married
because the old ones will break eventually.
And
underwriters labs did some testing and said when the toaster fails,
it won't explode and burst into flames, it'll just stop working,
which is what happened.
And then I went to the store and I bought a new toaster
and
that makes sense.
But now let's think about it in the context of iot
there's failure modes for things
and let's even assume someday your smoke alarms will fail due to
whatever manufacturing
I've actually had
a smoke alarm fail.
Ok.
It started randomly going off at three in the morning.
And what was most interesting to me? What a good feature.
Yeah, it was awesome. It was a great week. What was most interesting to me at first?
I was like, whatever the first time it happened, you know, also I was so, like,
woken up and just so disoriented.
Right. I had no idea what was really going on.
Um, you know, I'm stumbling around the house looking for fire. Like, what the heck.
Anyway,
-- so after like four or five times of this happening, I phoned
-- four times.
I think after the second, I would have thrown the thing away.
Uh, well, it was intermittent, right?
Like it happened once and then it happened like a month later and then,
you know, um, and then it happened like twice,
I think in one week anyways point being is I phone Google
and the guy, you know, what's your name?
Like some security questions for your account? Fair enough.
And then he's like, ok, let me check the records
and you know what? He immediately said, he said, oh yeah, that doesn't look right.
Yeah. No.
So, but the point is Google had the data where they could very and he's like, yeah,
we'll get one to you.
Like basically the way it works is they send you a new
one and then you send the old one back in the box
and you have like 30 days or something to do it.
And it literally showed up like two days later.
And, but the point being is they had the data on their end
that allowed them to very easily
apparently make that call of.
Yes, this is broken like the smoke alarm definitely went off,
but the temperature sensors weren't going off.
There was no smoke
sensor more to the point why doesn't their system automatically flag that?
-- But I
-- digress because it would cost them money to be proactive.
Yeah.
So, but what was interesting to me was that they, they, you know, like the,
I don't know if you remember the Tesla Lemon story,
but basically Google had the data
to essentially say, oh, yeah. No, you're right.
Your smoke alarm is broken and we'll fix
it right away because it's clearly our problem,
not yours.
And I think that's an example of things going. Right.
But now if you bought, I mean, smoke detectors are a terrible example here.
But if you bought smoke detectors from some dodgy internet site
that are,
-- you know,
-- you know where the
Depot
comes from.
But are they internet connected?
Yeah, dude, go to Home Depot now. They have an entire aisle of home automation.
Even if I went in there and looked,
I would not go down that aisle because I'm sure I would,
I would be weeping by the time I made it to the other,
I, I've looked at these and I recognize I'm like, oh, Google Nest. I recognize that.
And then there's a whole bunch of brand names where I'm like, uh,
you know, Honeywell's gotten into it. Ok. Good.
Did Honeywell do it, or did they subcontract?
I don't know, you know, Google probably subcontracted this stuff.
Yeah. Well, they bought nests. So.
But, um, yeah. So,
you know, it's, um,
yeah, it's, it's worrying. But,
yeah, the failure modes. I think the problem is it's
kind of going back to quality of life.
You know, if your fridge fails, that's, that's a pain. Right.
You know, those things are big and heavy to move.
They're, you know, they're typically full of a couple of 100 bucks of food,
um, or a freezer, you know, a freezer just turns off. Right.
You're gonna lose a couple of 100 bucks of food, potentially.
Right.
But, ok. No, no, no, there is.
That's a different.
I I think the problem is there's like 10 things going on here at the same time,
right?
Because failure is not necessarily the same as updates,
which is not necessarily the same as
the the whether you own something or not.
And and we can even confuse it more by throwing in that open source angle of, you know,
does it run Linux, which is always the first thing I ask when I get a new device of,
you know, can I put Linux on that?
Which granted there's no good reason to do it. It's just can I,
let's see.
And so now you also have the issue of,
let's say you have a smoke detector and let's say,
Lord forbid you put Linux on it because you can
and now your house burns down and, and your cat dies.
Well, I would argue that's no,
that's no longer the device the manufacturer sold to you.
And more to the point, I'm sure that it is covered in the U
the
user license
agreement which
you know, you don't get to fiddle with this.
So
you,
you just,
and uh you said a really important thing is by chain by putting Linux
on it will say it's no longer the device that was sold to you.
And I think that might be the key is once
you change the operating system or anything about the software
enabled devices will say
it's not the same device you bought.
Well, we already have that right.
If you make modifications, physical modifications to avoid a device,
you know, then you typically void the warranty,
but these aren't physical modifications.
I mean, this is,
-- I'm just
-- saying we have that established process that,
you know, if you, if you modify your engine significantly and it blows it,
it throws a rod and blows up,
you know, the engine manufacturer is gonna be like, well,
that's really too bad for you.
And
now if you change the software in your car and the same thing happens,
which could be done just given the way this all worked.
I assume you'd be in the same boat, right? Where the car manufacturer would be like
you put Linux
in your Toyota, man. I'm not actually probably run
well. It's, you know, because there are part of the challenge here, right?
Is a lot of people have moved safety
systems from being hardware shutoffs to software shutoffs.
Right.
You know, so there are actual governors and limiters, especially in car software,
right.
That limit, you know,
when things happen, like, when do the sparkplugs fire, when does the fuel, you know,
how much fuel, how much air?
Right.
Uh, so you could easily break a car, you know, by mucking with the software.
-- I'm guessing
-- without a doubt.
And I suppose if you bring that back to the manufacturer,
they're gonna tell you not our problem.
However,
in a lot of cases,
it's, you can't make these changes.
Well, and I guess that's kind of the way these devices are going, which is very anti
open
source.
Richard
Stallman
was.
Richard Stallman probably isn't a very happy guy right now.
I'd imagine that
it's, but at the same time, I mean, this is where I'm super torn is,
I love the open source universe and I
have obviously spent a significant amount of my life
working in that place,
right.
But at the same time, I don't want people putting Linux in their Tesla.
I don't want a self driving car being controlled by some crap,
some guy downloaded off github.
You know what I mean?
Well, yeah, it really comes to that competency angle.
I mean, a great example of this where we had problems was, remember, mail servers,
right?
Remember back in the day when actually people used to run their own mail servers
and a lot of them were poorly run and spam was a huge problem.
So we had things like blacklists and, you know, Oh, this IP address is known to
the
relay.
Well, true.
Well, you know,
but we've gotten pretty good filtering now so I
get very little spam actually into my inbox,
you know.
Um, but anyways,
so we have that, you know,
where basically the majority of people no longer run mail servers,
they use a mail service.
Um, the challenge being with email, we have that network effect of, you know,
I have to talk to other people with a car.
My car can be totally rude and that's great for me. You know, I'm running,
run anyone over though.
No,
but that's the problem, right?
Is with an email, you have this network effect of, you have to
communicate with other people with cars. Like your car can be a total rude,
you know, speeding butting in line and that's ok.
You know, until the cops catch you
except they're in self driving cars too so they can't get you.
Yeah.
So I, I really wonder, you know,
there's a lot of uh a great example being like wi fi access points, right?
Like if I juice up my access points, so I get a better signal in my house.
It, you know, interferes more with my neighbors.
Yes. And it may burn your radio out faster. So I've been told,
um you know, so I,
I it boils down to,
I'm not necessarily opposed to people changing the
firmware on these things or modifying them,
but I would have to question. Did, did they do so correctly?
Did they do so? You know, and
so what would the intent of the change? Right.
Are they intending to make it better or are they actually just trying to be, you know,
rude?
Well, but, but here's the thing again,
if I take my wireless access point and I crank the wireless up to an 11,
so it's drowning out all my neighbors.
Nobody's going to get killed.
And I think that's,
that's the
stop working.
I would stop getting, well, no, they would work locally,
but I wouldn't get the alerts.
For example,
you wouldn't get the alerts, but the device would still be functional and,
and, and,
or what if you, what if,
what if you have some sort of radio jamming and the cell phone stop working.
You can't dial 911. So there are angles to this. But fundamentally, right.
Fundamentally,
if I modify an access point,
there isn't an immediate,
I, I guess danger. Whereas if I have a car that's
driving like a maniac,
that's very odd.
And I guess this is part of our challenge is how do we wrap our heads around
this concept of what is dangerous, what isn't dangerous, what's harmless,
what isn't harmless?
And
it's,
it's not obvious.
Yeah.
No,
I think what's gonna happen is we're gonna basically computerize a lot more stuff.
And currently, you know, we've never really,
we've not computerized.
Uh, well, we've computerized airplanes and ships quite heavily actually.
But those things tend to be professionally operated. Right.
Like, you have, you know, to be an airline pilot,
you actually need to know how to fly one of these things, you know, reasonably well.
Whereas I hate to say it, but with cars I know,
especially in some places like North America, you know,
and other jurisdictions, Eastern Europe, for example, or whatever,
you know, there's, there's a pretty low barrier to entry.
Um, they actually just wrapped up another season of Canada's worst drivers.
And what always I'm reminded of, you know, is for Canada's worst driver.
These people have to have a license and insurance to go on the show.
They're legally allowed, like they legally are allowed to drive
and these people are terrible.
Like, like I remember the one lady, uh, on one of the first, uh, seasons was like,
well, I only drink and drive when I go to Bingo.
Yeah, that, that was her rational.
-- It's late at night and there's not many people on the road. Here's
-- the problem.
So firstly,
I'll say I've been through enough countries now
that I think I can say with confidence
there is nowhere that isn't full of terrible drivers,
right? So there's that, but more importantly is
your, your thing of I only drink and drive when go to bingo
and that's the problem with people
is everyone thinks they're special and so they think they can
do something that breaks the rules and it's no big deal.
So, because it's my car,
I can install Linux on it and that's ok because everyone else isn't doing it.
And I'm smart and I'm special when in reality
I'm not.
And
in some instances you might have someone who has enough knowledge to not, like,
be killing pedestrians by installing Linux on their car.
But in many instances it won't be, I mean,
I don't know if you still have this problem, but I remember back in the day
I would have people I knew be like, oh,
I just put Linux on my computer and now everything's broken.
Can you come fix it?
And that's what, that's like my,
that's my horror of letting people like mess
with these devices is they're gonna be like,
oh yeah, I tried putting, you know, th this thing on my car and,
and it's broken now and I need someone to fix it for me.
-- Would
-- you be
-- more
-- concerned about the,
the more quieter failure modes where like the breaking,
the breaking doesn't work on ice in winter anymore,
but you don't find that out for six months because
you know, you did the software modification in June.
That's true. That's, that's a really good point actually.
And that's,
that's what really terrifies me with a lot of this internet of things is like,
for example,
with these nest smoke alarms knowing what I know about them. Now,
I don't think I would buy them to be honest.
But the problem is I didn't learn about sort of all the failure modes
and all the problems with nest smoke alarms until I had operational experience.
And quite frankly, I don't, I, I'm probably not rich enough to, like,
buy six different self driving cars and somehow test
them out properly and make sure that they work,
you know, I'm really gonna have to rely on like the law and consumer reports and, and
whatever,
you know, to same thing with like these, you know, that,
that's why I've essentially banned the internet of things from my house.
I, I refuse to invest money into these things. Like a great example. Being Pebble.
Remember Pebble watches? Super awesome. Watch kick started.
Yeah.
So Fitbit bought them
and then an email went out saying, you know, the, the servers that
I guess make Pebble do useful things.
Um, yeah, they're, they're gonna do less of that and, or be turned off.
-- So, you know, good luck.
-- Right.
It sounds like
they pebble bought mostly the intellectual property and the
employees and then everything else is up too bad.
Yep.
Well, and you know,
you,
you spent money acquiring this company and now you're going to spend more
money making sure their old product keeps working that you don't sell anymore.
Yeah, that's, that's going to be a common case, I think for the internet of things.
I mean, it totally will be
so,
you know, and that's why I've just literally banned.
I mean, I was given an internet of things device for Christmas.
Uh
and it only worked on 2.4 gigahertz
Wi
Fi not on five gigahertz wi
Fi.
And to talk to it, you had to talk directly to it,
right? You didn't talk through a server, which was kind of nice. But then
when I upgraded my wifi to five gigahertz, I mean, if I wanted to control this device,
I had to like
leave the five gigahertz wi Fi join the 2.4 gigahertz wi
Fi.
Talk to this device, make it do something and then, you know,
go back to the five gigahertz Wi
Fi.
-- Ok?
-- But look, let's face reality though as well. You talk tough.
But if your kids show up on Christmas Day with some little toy
that's IOT and internet connected and they beg you to use it,
you're gonna cave,
right?
You're gonna cave. You don't even pretend you are,
you know,
but I'm not gonna buy, for example, light bulbs or a thermostat or,
all these other things that require internet access and software updates.
In, in fact, I know my, my wife one time asked about, oh, we should get one of those nest
thermostats.
And I said, no, my,
like $10 piece of crap mercury filled thing I have on the wall that works great.
I'm not getting anything else.
Yeah. No, it's Yeah, I, the thermostat thing really blew me away.
That Google essentially said that these things will not operate
without internet because that's not the experience we want people to have.
Right. And I know someone, I forget who even told me this, but
their internet died
in their house and the furnace quit working or something
like
that.
Well, yeah, especially if you live in a cold climate,
but it wasn't that cold at the time.
But, yeah, it's, it's terrifying.
So, I've actually seen that happen.
Uh, my kid ripped the thermostat off the wall at their, their house,
broke it. And, um,
so I had to tell my ex-wife essentially how to hot wire the furnace. Right.
Luckily you just touch two wires together to turn it off.
Yeah, pretty much.
But I was like, just take, you know, what is it like,
the white and the red one just twist them together,
you know, and do that for like half an hour every hour or whatever
and, you know, and we'll, we'll fix the thermostat tomorrow or whatever,
you know, it's, but, you know, when it's minus 40 blowing outside you like right now.
So, just so the listeners know,
I have to turn my furnace off while we podcast
because it makes enough noise that you can hear it.
And typically in the 1 to 1.5 hours, we do a podcast,
-- the temperature in my house drops by about four degrees Celsius
-- and,
and to avoid looking like a huge dirt bag,
I have told Kurt on multiple occasions that we can
live with the noise and to turn your furnace on.
Yeah. But, uh, no, it's not so bad.
It goes from about, I,
so what I do now is I have that I set the
temperature one or two degrees higher than it normally would be.
So that way it only gets down to about 17
°C in the house.
Yeah. So it's, my feet are a bit chilly, but beyond that I'm, I'm not going to die.
Um,
but fundamentally, you know, II, I,
-- yeah, I really do like heat in winter. It's a good thing.
-- It is a very nice thing.
And if it's any consolation
I am very cold as well because I live in a really old
house and my office has two exterior walls and when I shut the door
it gets freezing in here and my windows are super old too.
So, like, everything sucks.
Yeah.
I,
I've looked at buying one of those Dyson bladeless
heaters but they're like four or 500 bucks,
you know,
you could probably go to the store and
buy an internet connected space heater for $25.
Yeah. Right. Exactly.
Yeah. I actually, oh, what was it? Oh, yeah. Those USB cup heaters
just get
a,
yeah.
Right. There, there you go.
There you go. That's probably energy efficient. I think.
I think I have a Bitcoin miner in the basement. I should go dig that thing out.
Ok. So, so, anyway, anyway,
I
think,
I think what we can agree on is that it's probably a bad idea to modify software on a,
you know, 2000 pound device that can approach speeds of over 100 miles an hour.
-- Ok.
-- But, so there's that aspect and let's say
you buy a device
-- and you can't update it, which is very anti
-- android
phone. Anything
like, like your toaster, your refrigerator,
you are not allowed to change the software.
The things the manufacturer
gives you
is the way it is, it will self update,
it's gonna run its own thing and there's nothing you can do about it.
Right.
Not open source friendly, but that's kind of the way things are going today,
-- but
-- it's kind of how things are. I
mean, look at your
existing
toaster, how would you modify it?
Magic?
You know, you'd have to dig it apart. Replace some custom circuit maybe or,
-- I don't know.
-- Ok.
So, so there's that, ok,
let's say we can't update anything and that's just going to be the way it is,
which is very anti
open ideals.
But
ignoring that argument for now,
even though this is called the Open source Security Podcast. But ignoring that
right
now, you have a universe where
the manufacturer, if they go out of business or they decide to end of life, a product
or
goodness knows their server room crashes.
Now,
what happens to the device when it can't receive updates or it can't phone home or,
or whatever?
There's a bunch of things that can happen here.
Yeah.
Well, and that's why I,
I would really like some sort of labeling system for internet of things,
devices that say, for example,
you know, does this device require internet for setup for operation?
What happens if you don't have internet?
You know, can you set it up? Can you?
Well,
yeah, I mean, I used to really enjoy Razor
mice, you know, they're gaming mice.
But then I realized, you know, if I don't have internet,
the mouse doesn't quite work properly.
A
mouse, Razor mice have software um
that for at least for the setup and stuff requires internet access and
they have this thing where you can store your profiles on their central server
so that you can have like you can download your profile.
It's like for the gamers and stuff, right?
So they can download their, their key mappings and whatnot, you know, easily.
Um But fundamentally it's like I'm, I don't really wanna
use hardware that depends on talking to some
random internet server doing God knows what,
especially when you know, it can download and install more software,
right? I just, I have trust issues,
right.
Well, you do,
but most people do.
Well, most people aren't even aware it's happening,
right?
You know, that's the one thing I love.
So I use Macs and I, you know, run Linux and virtual machines,
but I use little snitch firewall program that, you know,
especially for outgoing connections is quite fascinating.
All the stuff that wants to make outgoing connections to weird stuff,
you know. Um My favorite case was like Webex,
Cisco. Webex doesn't use my DNS servers.
It uses 8.8 0.8 0.8 whether you like it or not.
Interesting,
you know,
um, from their point of view, I totally get it. You know, they,
that's a way that's a DNS server that typically works
from my point of view. I filter out going DNS and incoming DNS and I log it all.
So I'm not a big fan of that.
Oh man. All right. So we've rambled on about this for the longest time, I guess.
Let's wrap it up. Like this
is updating the Samsung Galaxy Note seven to brick itself a good idea
or a bad idea.
I think it's a great idea.
I would say
part of me thinks it's a good idea,
but part of me is worried other manufacturers will
then use that excuse to do terrible things.
It is certainly not out of the question.
My concern is the thin end of the wedge.
You know, what about when a device reaches end of life?
What do they
-- force the end of life?
-- Is it?
I mean,
that's we should,
that's a whole sale
doctrine, right? Like
I bought my toaster, let's say it's supported for three years. Great.
But what if I want to keep using it because it still kind of toasts. Ok. Mostly,
you know, or for example, like, um, you know, the cabin, we,
we have internet over well via cell phone.
But,
you know, with, at the cabin,
what's gonna happen when these devices don't have internet
all the time or only part of the time?
I don't know. All right. So let's do this, let's
call it quits
and acknowledge that getting rid of the Galaxy Note
Seven is probably a net benefit to society.
However,
I think something we should do is go away
and do some research in a planned obsolescence,
which is a thing in industrial manufacturing,
forced obsolescence would be the
planned obsolescence is where they basically build a device
to only work for a set amount of time.
And this is like physical, non internet connected things.
But I think forced obsolescence is kind of where we're going with this.
And
is that,
is, is that the future?
I, I don't know, I think this is something for us to go and look into because I mean,
let's face it.
Like
we all heard stories about, you know,
grandma's washing machine that lasted for 75 years.
And now like if you get five years out of a washing machine, you're doing pretty good,
you know.
So it's just, it's, it's interesting how this all works. So,
I'd actually be less worried about the obsolescence
thing and more worried about the fact.
Can I resell this device?
-- I never sell
-- anything, you know,
on
my
neck,
my car, I sold my own car.
But anyway, alright,
thank you folks
for listening. Thank you, Kurt for this
ridiculous conversation in all the bizarre places it went.
This is an insane problem to say the least and I know this won't be the last we talk
about it and it certainly won't be the last
we hear about it because I'm sure there are countless
precedent setting events.
This is gonna be the first Christmas where there's gonna,
I think there's really gonna be a lot of internet connected toys,
especially for the voice recognition.
You're absolutely right.
And not only that,
but there's gonna be tons of disappointment
because some of these servers will crash.
Right.
It's gonna be great. Merry Christmas. Everybody.
-- Happy holidays. All right,
-- Kurt, I'll talk to you later. Thanks.
Bye bye bye.