Hello and welcome to the real open source podcast.
Not that fake one you got from somewhere else
-- with myself. Kurt. You just
-- said the real open source podcast.
It's the real open source security podcast. Kurt.
-- Well, and that proves it's the real one.
-- This is not the real open source podcast.
I don't even know if there is an open source podcast
probably.
Anyways,
that proves that this is the real open
source security podcast because we make mistakes.
-- We, I I remove all of my mistakes and edit.
-- This is true.
But yeah, so like, so Notepad Plus Plus recently
announced essentially that somebody grabbed,
uh what was it? Notepad dot Plus.
So plus is a new top level domain because there's like 2000 top level domains now
and is essentially, I don't even know what word to use.
They're, they're not squatting it because they own the domain legitimately.
The content that they've posted is a copy of the real Notepad Plus Plus.
And they're like, ok,
so they have a like disclaimer thing at the bottom and I'm just going to read it
and it's, it's titled Disclaimer. And if you go to the website, which
I didn't even notice the disclaimer. Where is it?
How do I know it's a disclaimer because it says it's
a,
no,
no, I'm saying I didn't even notice it.
I just scrolled all the way to the bottom and now I see.
Ok,
this is funny because when I go to a website I almost always scroll
to the very bottom to see whatever legal crap they've included at the bottom.
Which is where like infinite scrolling websites really drive
me nuts because I can't get there anyway.
Here's what the disclaimer says. Notepad Plus Plus is a trademark of Don Ho.
Notepad dot Plus is not affiliated, sponsored or endorsed,
endorsed by Don Ho in any ways.
This is an unofficial fan website created
for general information slash educational purposes only.
Yeah, that old chestnut from pirate,
any context. Found
this website is our personal opinions and do not purport to
reflect the opinions or views of Don Ho or its representatives.
-- All other trademarks are the property of their respective owners.
-- Yeah, that's
a,
there's at least three errors there
and two.
Yeah, you can't just disclaim your way out of like, trademark infringement, right?
Like there's fair use stuff.
I'm pretty sure this is not a fair use.
Like,
it's like those youtube React videos where they just
play the video and sit quietly while they watch it
versus like cinema sins where they tear the thing apart for like an hour.
Let's back this up a little bit because
the reason this came up is Kurt sent a link
to,
I don't, not technically, to me it's just a response on Mastodon that,
that you tagged me in.
Yeah, I added you in it to take you in. So you'd see it.
Yeah. So we, we talk about it.
But anyway, the notepad plus plus and we should say notepad plus plus is a,
like text editing.
It's a good piece of software.
Yeah, it's a text editor on Windows. Right?
Well, and it's been around forever. It's to put it bluntly, it's like
what emacs is to Linux
-- Notepad plus plus is to Windows except
-- Notepad plus plus users probably won't
like hound you and follow you around until you run their editor.
Well, and, and you can just take control us to save and control like all the,
all the normal key bindings work.
Ok. So the Notepad Plus plus website puts down, puts up a post thing.
I don't know what to call it that just says help us
announcement.
That sounds good.
And it says help us to take down
the parasite website,
-- which has a very parasite website just has a ring to it that
-- well.
It reminds me of the Mo the Korean movie
Parasite where they live in the rich people's basement,
which is kind of actually exactly what's happening here.
I
have never seen that. It probably doesn't have a spaceship or a lizard.
So
-- No,
-- but it won a lot of awards
anyway.
And basically this, this the Notepad Plus Plus people go on to explain
that
there's a website called Notepad dot Plus.
That
is clearly pretending to be the official Notepad Plus plus website.
And if you type into Google download Notepad Plus plus,
the fake site is the second hit.
And they're asking people to go to the
Google Report malicious software website and report this site
-- that as
-- harmful.
First off, I actually did some spot checks.
I downloaded a bunch of the like it, it is, it is basically bit for bit identical,
both the web content like the download pages and the content that you download.
Ok. So
it's not technically malicious
because they're just serving copies of the files and, and in my too, I put,
it's not malicious dot dot dot yet.
I mean, you could say yet,
I think
I will, I did not say you
not malicious I disagree with because this is a website
clearly trying to trick people,
right? But I'm saying specifically by the letter of the law,
it's not a malware. It's not a bad download. It is a good copy of the file currently
and sort of like member sourceforge.
We all used to love sourceforge and trust.
Source Forge and sourceforge was awesome. And then one day sourceforge
did a thing
and you remember what it was?
I mean,
which thing are you talking about when they
tried to backdoor all the downloads with their,
their adware.
No, they didn't try.
They did, they put, they put that adware stuff in all the downloads and then
we all sort of realized, oh, maybe Sourceforge isn't, you know,
where we want to host our stuff and
everybody moved to github.
But the point is like,
Sourceforge had a ton of goodwill and community endorsement and, and
trust
and,
and then they blew it away And now this website is starting
from a position of already sort of stealing that trust literally by
copying the website and everything and like,
seo magic winning,
like they're basically stealing the goodwill and the
trust from the real notepad Plus plus,
like they're not building it themselves.
Right. Right. Right. And that's
wrong.
-- And look, there's, and there's a couple of pieces to this
-- wrong.
How it's, well, it's illegal. It's a trade
violation, unquestionably
assuming the OPEC plus plus is trademark. I actually didn't check.
I don't, you know, that's a good question.
It talks about the trademark and their, their crappy disclaimer,
but I didn't actually look it up.
But let's pretend it is.
Well, no, let's not pretend, let's look it up.
-- Well, ok,
-- you look it up and I want to kind of explain
there, there,
there's like the open source world and we'll say the traditional world,
I'm going to put them in two separate buckets,
which I think the open source world is the world now.
But whatever.
Historically speaking, if you were an organization doing a thing,
you would get a trademark literally for this purpose
where if someone tried to pretend they were,
you, you could take them to court and you could get them to change something.
Right now.
I understand that going down the path of trademark enforcement is not cheap
because you have to hire lawyers and you have to send
letters and you have to do all this crazy work.
-- I
-- get that. It's like
-- hundreds of thousands of dollars,
-- minimum, tens of thousands, for sure.
Right. Right.
So,
it's one of those sort of protection activities that is not designed to support a,
-- like, random hobbyist doing something for free
-- and not to be a jerk.
But I can't find anything about a notepad Plus Plus trademark
and that could be, and they may not have trademarked it.
I can't find anything on their website. Yeah.
No, I, I cannot, I mean, I could, of course,
be wrong but I am trying to find the word trademark, like,
doesn't seem to occur on notepad Plus plus website.
Like, and it's, I'm not finding it and they might not have.
So that, and that's kind of a big problem here because all of a sudden
the lay, like, basically Notepad plus plus is saying we have two legs, sort of,
we have one leg to stand on, which is, this is malware.
Well, it's not, it's a bit for bit copy.
And there's a second potential leg which is trademark infringement, which
if you don't have a trademark, you, you can't claim trademark infringement.
It is correct. I don't see anything in the
United States patent and trademark office search.
I'm not looking real hard but
well and getting a trademark, like it's not super expensive, but it is also
-- not many open source projects do
-- it. It's
hard to get a trademark correctly and you often have to
show that you're an actual like organization using the trademark.
It's not like
I can't trademark. Kurt
sucks. Right? Unless I create a, an organization.
-- Well, a line of Kurt sucks. T-shirts,
-- right?
-- Something
-- like
-- that,
-- which are now available in the store.
That's right.
No cafe press just on demand, right?
-- Uh Is cafe press still a thing even, I don't know, I'm
-- old.
I for all I know it's gone the way of source forge.
I
don't even know where you'd get like a, a cafe Paris still exists.
I don't know, whatever it doesn't matter. Ok.
So if it's not trademarked,
then there's definitely not
the like trademark angle to this.
-- I don't think there's anything,
-- it,
it may not be illegal and that could be why they're asking people to
report the site to Google because they don't have any other avenues here.
Well, and my one thought was, what about copyright?
Like copyright by default is, you know,
I can't just take a copy of somebody's website and host it.
And I should know because remember 20 plus years ago I wrote
the Linux Administrative Security guide and if you google it in quotes,
there are dozens and dozens of websites still
hosting it or PDF versions of it claiming,
you know, essentially that like here it is.
Oh, wait, wait, wait,
when I click. Download from the notepad dot plus site takes me to Notepad
Plus plus.org, it takes me
the actual download site.
-- So
-- for now,
that's why it's the same
because
it is the same.
But like you and I both know that the web
server could randomly serve malware one in 1000 times.
It could. Exactly. And, and I would not trust this
-- at all
-- for sure. And so it's,
I, I suspect it is what it looks like, which is the person found good content.
Like people used to find my Linux
a security guy because it was like hot for
CEO for Linux security because there was no other, there wasn't anything else.
And so he made a copy of the website.
And yeah, he doesn't even want to host the,
the files because they're too big and too much hassle to host.
They, they might be. And so he just literally
is, is he has advertising or p I assume it's a, he, we'll just say he for now,
statistically it's probably me
jerks.
He's just, he has, you know, ads on the site that people see and
like this. What gets me is this is both ethically and morally wrong
and economically inefficient.
Like the amount of the amount of money they're probably making from,
this is not significant.
I imagine it's terrible for sure.
Like,
basically we're going to spend more time talking about this monetarily than he,
the person will probably make in a month.
Ok. Look, I think there's a piece to this
that I don't want to dwell on. But I think is important is
this happened during the last election in the United States.
It's probably happening here. It happens all over the place where
there are people who live in parts of the world where for example,
a dollar to you and me isn't very much money,
but a dollar to them can be quite a lot of money.
And so a couple of dollars a day from a website for
people in the western world in North America,
you're not going to blink at that.
But there are places a couple dollars a day from
a website like this is going to feed the family,
right?
So I think it's easy to say, oh, why are they doing this?
It's not worth the time and the money, but for some people, it literally is.
So, I, I didn't mean it so much that way.
It's just, it's more that I'm, I'm like, morally and ethically this is wrong, but
-- worse economically it's inefficient. It's gross. It's, it is
-- very inefficient.
But
but I'm saying there are economically inefficient to
us isn't necessarily economically inefficient to other people.
Now,
I, I want to wind this back just a little bit because
I just got back from, besides Milwaukee in Cipher con like literally
Friday night. We, there's now a Sunday we're talking.
So I'm, I'm like,
still super tired and I will say anyone there who said hi to me who listens.
You're awesome. Thank you for listening. We had, I had a whole bunch of people.
It was really cool. I love that.
So if you, if you ever, if anyone listening, ever sees me around it,
a show or something, like come and say hi, I absolutely love it. It's so much fun.
But anyway,
so I talked about at uh cipher Con the size of
open source and how big it is and it was a very
unusual talk because there's like at the end of like, I have literally no, no advice.
There's no actions, there's nothing,
I just want you to know everything's giant and it not looking real good.
-- I,
-- I'm working on a paper with a similar conclusion of like,
so now that you've seen from the mountain top, what it looks like, um,
-- good luck. Can't unsee it hopefully.
-- Well, you can ignore it.
-- People ignore stuff all the time.
-- We'll, we'll ignore it.
But anyway, one of the things that happened was during the talk, I was like, look,
it feels like the universe is crushing us all to
death because the universe is crushing us all to death.
Like it's literally happening.
If you look at tech everywhere, you've got like the XZ,
you've got this notepad plus plus thing,
you've got the gigantic size of open sources like log for J there's so much going on.
There are still people hosting
25 year old copies of a PDF file. Of course, there are like if you search for Linux
Administrative security guide, you don't even find me
until I was about to say the second page of search results.
But apparently Google went to infinite scroll now and funnily enough,
you mentioned going to the bottom of the page to look
for the Legalese and stuff.
Yeah, you can't do that in infinite scroll.
-- Well,
-- I'm, I'm like trying, but I'm not get like
-- there's
-- more,
I know you can glimpse it and then it fills it in and it like infuriates me to no end.
-- Oh,
-- interestingly, they, they pause and they,
they have give you a more results after about
the equivalent of about four screen fulls of results.
So they actually kind of pause at a point that's to protect them so
that you can't automatically just keep scrolling down with like a web widget thing.
You actually have to have a clicker
because
the one thing I've always been annoyed, Google doesn't have an API
and I would like to use an API.
-- So
-- I've, I've had, they don't want an API, they have to sell you ads.
-- They don't care.
-- Yeah, I know.
And so that's there again, this whole more results thing is, is not for your benefit,
it's for theirs.
Ok. Ok. Anyway, anyway,
the, the point of all this, right.
Where, like, I, I talk about the crushing weight, lots of people were like, yes,
I feel there's crushing weight also.
Right. Like, things, something is weird. We don't know what's going on.
-- I think it's because we're noticing it finally.
-- No.
Sort of, well, we're noticing it because I think it's happening more often.
I think
historically speaking,
when
there were weird shenanigans, it often didn't affect very much people and, like,
people stealing your, your, you know, Linux security guide,
they're paying you with exposure.
So it's fine.
Actually a lot of them removed my name,
which I actually prefer because then people didn't complain
to me about it being out of date.
So
that,
-- that's
-- even
-- worse.
But anyway, and, and look, this happens like on youtube and all over the place,
right?
Where people take the work of one
and they, they functionally just are, are, well, what is it called?
Um, the Hello Internet guys, uh, uh, free, booting, free booing.
That's what they named it free.
Yeah.
Yeah,
there was, this was, uh,
what C GP Gray and Brady Heron used to do a podcast called Hello Internet.
And it was really cool. It was, it was non topical and I loved it
anyway.
If we look at everything going on right now, it just,
it feels so big and so different than it ever has before.
I also can I add one thing? I just, I was thinking and I realized
it used to be companies strip mind open source,
but they didn't really interact with open source.
Like they didn't complain, they didn't make demands,
they just sort of took open source and ran with it.
Sure. Now we're increasingly seeing like with log for Jay, people say
security questionnaires saying like,
like fill out the security questionnaire.
What are you doing about log for J to some random open source project?
We're seeing the FFM peg thing where like a
Microsoft DEV files the ticket saying like,
basically this broke our team's product.
Like it's been a week, we need you to fix it.
And actually what it was is they changed a default setting
and you had to just change the command line thing.
-- Oh,
-- I haven't seen that. That's really funny.
Basically, the Microsoft DEV was like, saying this is a high priority bug for us
and I'm from Microsoft and you know, base I think they kind of expected.
Oh, you're from Microsoft? Yeah, like, oh, you must be important and it's like
the open source doesn't care. Well, some of them do.
That's like the classic. Do you know who I am?
And the answer is like, no, I don't, I, I, like, I don't,
nor do I care.
Well, I've had people try to argue from authority with me.
I'm just like, I, I don't know who you are. Like, don't care either.
So, it was funny you say that because while I was at cipher con that happened,
someone was like, don't, you know who this is?
I was like, no, I don't. They're like, oh,
well, you should talk to them. I'm like, ok, but I still, who is this?
-- Like, yeah,
-- there's,
there's actually a lot of people on the planet as it turns out and I don't know,
Tom from Toronto.
I hope he's doing ok though.
Right. Exactly.
You know, and it was, it's amusing and honestly, even if I knew who they were,
I might pull that off just because I think
anyone who pulls it, do you know who I am?
Like, you need someone to, like,
-- kick your ego in the crotch
-- unless you're like the US president,
like, trick
-- question name, the German president.
-- I literally don't know who it is anymore.
Does Germany have a president? Don't they have a prime minister?
-- No,
-- they have a chancellor who holds power and the president is essentially ahead.
Anyway, the point is the president is a figurehead position in Germany.
It doesn't matter. So, like, you don't need to know who they are.
That's like knowing, you know what I mean? Like
-- who's the, the, the second house whip
-- the president of Canada
that just hurt me on the inside.
Does Canada have a president and prime minister?
So
we have a prime minister.
So the political party that wins the election
is essentially invited to form a government,
right? Either if they win a mature
or whatever,
essentially the way it works in Canada is you go to the lieutenant governor,
who's the queen's representative in Canada, who,
who is our provisional head of state king?
The king's sorry? Damn, I keep forgetting.
Well, I didn't vote for them like, you know, anyway, so, um yeah,
you go to the lieutenant governor who is the king's sorry.
Thank you. The king's representative in Canada
and essentially
the, the lieutenant governor uh says you can form a government
and they can say no and they have in the past, oh, how exciting.
Like they can straight up say like I, I don't like the results of this election. Like
do it again.
Wow,
we're a constitutional monarchy. We're not a democracy, we're not a republic
anyway.
We're off
the
anyways.
This,
this speaks to this somewhat is that open source has been away for
a long time and people were freeloading and that's kind of OK.
But now a lot of them are becoming like the classic choosy beggar
and people are like, I can get offended by that. Like if you steal the lasg
uh whatever, OK? But if you like, start demanding that I fix it
-- like no go away.
-- I think, I know why this is happening.
And this is related to all of the research I've been doing for
like the last six months on this talk I did at Cipher Con where
I have, um, I'll put a link to the,
the slides in the show notes because it has all the graphs and I love those,
-- those graphs are like,
-- they're, they're all insane.
-- They're
-- so
-- stupid. Even if they were logarithmic, they'd still be stupid.
-- They
-- are loga
well. Oh right. No, that's right.
They're, they're,
I showed them all linear because it's all just exponential growth.
And here's the thing like the the amount of open source that exists
today is like literally double what it was a couple of years ago,
right? And it's,
we're talking like
I think the number of packages and I took the ecosystems data,
the number of packages and ecosystems is like almost 9 million.
It's like 8.6 million or something like that.
And then once you add inversions,
you end up with like 96 million or something like that packages, right?
And the the the users of open source are growing in a similar way.
Every, every number,
every graph you make of open source of anything of just software,
even just like humanity, everything.
-- It's all exponential growth which is
-- totally sustainable by the way, totally
exponential growth. Never fails,
never fails.
Especially in the housing market because houses
are this is no financial investment advice.
-- What's that?
-- What's that island in Alaska?
That was like full of exponentially growing reindeer.
And then in six months they were all gone.
-- That's everywhere with predators and prey.
-- Like, well, they had no predators.
So they just kept multiplying and then,
then there were none left for some reason.
But anyway, everything is growing like crazy.
And let's say 1% of open source users are like complainers
where they they come and they demand what's going on.
Now. If you have 10 users, 1% is going to statistically be zero, right?
But if you have 10 million users,
1% is a lot of people, right? If you have 100 million users, 1% is
a million people literally.
And I think that's what we we are hitting like the insane growth phase
of exponential growth with like open source
and the internet and software and everything.
-- And I think the reason it feels crushing is because it is crushing us
-- well,
and I think it's also an element of eternal September is hitting.
It's been September for
it's eternal September in the sense of the companies
now are making demands because what's the downside?
I, I think they, they were before
though.
It's just, there's so many more they were making demands before.
This is not new at all.
I remember when we were at Red Hat, this was like the,
the mid 20 tens give or take and you
would see open source projects where people would say,
oh, hey, you know, why aren't you fixing my bug?
I can't do my job
and the developers would be like,
and
you know what?
And there's a,
but I think there's a subtle second piece of that now that you mention it,
it's not just that people are demanding that we add a feature for them,
fix the bug. It's
I am using your open source to make money.
I want you to support me for free and fix this thing so I can make more money.
And that is inherently a bit offensive to many people, right?
Because if I come to you and say, hey, I need youtube downloader,
you need to fix the ID thing because my like my son who has autism really,
I need to be able to download his youtube video so I can put them, you know,
on pluck so that they don't go missing.
I don't think many people are going to be offended by that.
But if I say, hey, I use youtube
Charlo to make a lot of money and I'm not giving you any
it by the way.
And I really want you to add this feature,
fix this thing for me so I can continue to make money.
Sure.
Yeah.
Statistically, I suspect a lot of people would be kind of offended by that demand,
right? I mean, OK, I have another good example, right?
I've got I just pulled up the email.
So I think I mentioned this a long time ago where I found a bug
in
the way,
the whatever the, the
gnome for window drawing
is right?
And I found a bug in it. When you're using X 11, it works fine in Wayland.
And at the time I couldn't use Wayland because
what the, the Audacity audio editor wouldn't work correctly in Whalen,
but it worked fine in X
and I don't use Audacity anymore. So I switched to Whalen.
I don't care anymore like this buck and II, I get the mails.
But in anyway,
I reported this. It's been more than a year now, right?
And, and well, I shouldn't say I didn't report it.
I figured it out and someone else reported it,
but they didn't give the developers any useful information.
-- The developers are like there's nothing we can do
-- realistically.
Like most people that run into a bug or like I ran into a bug. It's broken.
I spent like literally three hours
starting with fresh
-- gnome.
-- Normal people don't do that
for sure.
But I was like,
I need to figure this out partially because it's a fun challenge and partially
because like this bug is driving me nuts and I want to fix it again
for most people. This is not a fun challenge
and I have no doubt I would have submitted a patch.
Had I not switched audio editors at some point. But anyway.
So like someone just replied to the issue that's basically like,
you know,
this issue is still happening on 45.51 full major and five bug fix releases later,
it continues to be super annoying and blah, blah and they go on and on and I'm like,
do you think the developers are going to respond in a positive way to this comment?
-- Like, what do you think is going to happen?
-- What if you don't fix it?
I'm taking my business elsewhere,
-- right?
-- Like, seriously, like great.
First of all,
that doesn't even work at stores because either the
person working at the store is like a,
I'm going to use the word peon. I don't like that word but I don't have a better word.
They're just a worker there and they don't care
or like my favorite comic bookstore,
they have one employee and the owners are a married couple.
So reading the negative reviews on Google is so much fun
because they just,
yeah, no, like they're like, yeah,
we spoke with our employee and it turns out you were a
jerk to them and so on and so forth or you know,
like, yes, I remember that interaction.
You were a jerk, blah, blah, blah. You know what I mean? Like
they and they straight up in their reviews are like,
it's cool if you don't like our store,
like there's different stores for different people and
clearly our store is not for you.
And it's, it's a very nice way of saying, you know, some rude words.
Like, it's like, bless your heart.
Basically.
-- It's a Canadian version of bless your heart
-- anyway.
But, and, and I think that is comparable to what we're kind of seeing in the open
source universe, right? Where, like, comic books are a great one.
I would guess that in what the nineties, remember when there were like,
barely any comic book stores and it was really hard to
find comic books and it was like a huge deal.
And now you got the internet and comic book stores are everywhere.
I was never really into comic books. But yeah, I know what you
mean.
And now locally we were kind of,
we have that growth and now we're back down to only half
having about a dozen comic book stores.
Well, but the thing is like, there's the library and there's like,
comic books have really, yeah, they've kind of died out.
-- Like, it's a, it's a niche thing
-- that could be, I don't know, I,
I haven't paid attention in years but I,
I remember there were a lot of comic book stores for a while.
There's a lot of board game stores. Now, I see a lot of board game stores, for example.
Right.
There's all kinds of stuff and this is normal, right?
Where you're always going to have growth and then waning of like,
every industry you can imagine.
-- With the exception of open source.
-- Well, that's the thing I wonder about that.
-- Like, is it ever going to go down?
-- No, because everything has software in it now.
Like it does.
Like, here's the thing by definition,
if we build something with software that uses software, we need it,
we're using it and one of two things is going to happen,
we're going to continue to use it
or it's going to be replaced with something even better that
has probably more software and my evidence of that would be,
remember all the stuff, like, look at my washer dryer behind me.
Right. I'm waving my thumb at it, which no one can see except me.
They have simple software
because they're like 10 or 15 years old, I'm guessing.
I don't know, they were here when I moved into the house and they work.
-- So
-- I paid extra for stupid washers and dryers.
So that's the thing. Well,
if I were to buy a,
like a normal modern washer and dryer,
it would like, want an internet connection and it would have a whole s swack
-- more software, I
-- mean,
-- software and that's the thing.
-- So I don't think it will ever go down.
Just like logistics will never wane.
Like logistics is a thing now and it's just more and more crazy and efficient.
I want to bring us all the way back now
to the actual topic of open
source security, which is kind of where we started here way back when
I, I feel like
everything we look at,
we can see massive insane growth. Right.
Even, even,
like I know we've complained about CV E I DS
and then they're not growing as fast as they should,
but they're still growing
and we're gonna have, we're gonna, in,
probably in 2025 we'll have double the CD ES we
had in 2023 at the rate we're growing right now.
Right. With, especially with the Linux kernel
and their malicious compliance of, of vulnerability filing.
Well, it's not, it's not malicious.
It's true.
I,
I believe
it's the common vulnerabilities enumeration database.
And so don't we want to enumerate at all?
Like, I'm, I'm hand waving and blinking here, right?
Like, you know, I do this with a I vulnerabilities and people are like, but you like,
and I'm like, I have stuff in there that's garbage,
but we have to collect everything.
So that first of all, we can see what's good and what's bad.
We can see patterns and to do that, we have to have everything
ideal
and also conveniently enough,
we have way better data analysis tools now that we did even
two years ago, let alone 20 years ago.
Right. Well, and we need it because
there's billions of things now,
which anyway, anyway, here's,
I think what we need to kind of maybe sort of discuss to
close this one out and this is vaguely related to like Notepad plus plus
and
there's just, there's so much going on, there's so much money around
-- and there's, it's, it's easier than ever to host the website. For
-- example,
I can't say money, I would say value because there's also non
monetary values. And I think, and Notepad plus plus is a great example of that.
There's the value of the goodwill of Notepad plus plus where like it's,
it used to be one of my standard things I installed on windows like
on day one of a windows reinstall uh for a lot of people.
It is
you, you
it's on the top 10 list of things you install on windows to
make it usable because Notepad dot exe was not usable like it was because
I think they're fixing it,
but it's getting better though. I will give it that.
But
so the point is there's value to be captured there and this person found a very
inefficient but effective way to capture that value, just like people copying
the Linux administrative security guide and putting ads on it,
found a way to capture that value.
And there's look, there's al I guarantee there's other open source project.
This is happening to,
right where people are taking their websites, they're,
they're taking their downloads
and they're re hosting it.
And in some cases, it might be literal malware.
In some cases, it's gonna be just stuff like this where
maybe they're, they're honestly trying to be fans. I doubt it.
I suspect they're trying to sell ads.
No, they're stealing ad revenue. Right. They're straight up stealing ad revenue.
-- Like
-- this is,
this is not going to slow down.
We're going to see more and more of this as
just everything around us grows and it's growing exponentially.
And the problem with that exponential growth
is when you notice exponential growth,
it's too late.
And that's, I think the thing
that is, is starting to boil the minds of a lot of people.
And in fact,
this was a theme at cipher con I noticed is a lot of
talks were basically saying nothing we used to do seems to work anymore.
What should we start doing now? And of course, there were lots of, oh,
we should start doing this thing instead. And it's like you're making this crap up.
But
the fact is
everyone is starting to realize like the things we used to
do don't work and they aren't working because exponential growth.
Well, it's the law of large numbers kicked in a long time ago.
But nobody noticed because like you said, when, by the time you notice it,
it's too late.
No, I mean, and,
and there's corner cases like weirdos like me who read every single CV and noticed
it's getting busier,
-- like a lot
-- busier. It can't anymore. But,
but even when you were doing that cart, it was linear growth in those days,
we've, we've exceeded the point of linear growth.
I mean, this is part of the reason I know NVD
and everyone's pretending it's gonna go back to normal and they're saying, oh,
it was just a minor blip in our funding and stuff
like the numbers like, no, it's exponential growth.
I like how they put up a new notice and it's a very soothing blue.
Yeah, it is. Now that you say that
-- it's a
-- very
soothing
-- shade of blue. It's quite, quite lovely,
-- exponential growth. You
-- everything, everything
-- happening.
And so
I
think, and this is going to sound weird,
but I think one of the one of the effective ways
that we as humans can deal with this sort of whole mess
is having stricter attention filters
where, for example,
I don't follow a lot of people on Mastodon because there's like
a damn near infinite number of interesting things to follow on Mastodon,
but I don't have time for it.
Um Same thing with blogs, same thing with articles, news, you know, I,
I found out about that interesting gold heist
last year in Toronto at Pearson airport,
right?
When I uh
some other uh the L A heist came up and somebody was mentioning this Toronto Heist.
So I'm like, I didn't even know about this.
I was a Canadian shouldn't I know about this.
I have a suspicion they weren't
blasting that news.
Uh Well,
it was on the media but it was also one of those kind of
like classic Canadian gold heist where the guy came in and said like,
hey, I'm here for the gold and they're like, OK,
and then he left with a bunch of the gold and
there was like
that was it.
I know that's, that's good. Social engineering, well done.
But regardless, regardless of all that, here's
how I want to end this and it's not a good ending,
but the reality is
the whole world
is growing
in an exponential manner
in all of our
tooling, especially in the world of security.
All of our ideas and tools were basically outdated.
-- A couple of years ago, I would
-- say a decade ago
maybe,
but it's not like linear out dating,
right? It's exponential. So like
two years outdated on an exponential curve is more like 20 years outdated.
And I think
the problem is we keep talking about
all of these problems as like these
individual singular events we can handle and deal
with and solve when we need to think about things like in larger context,
right?
This is
this is the problem that we have now is we
can no longer obsess over like individual singular things.
This is a big data problem functionally.
And we need to use like some big data tools which we are completely unprepared for.
I'd go a step further and say we need
not just new technical techniques and research,
but we need new ways of thinking about this. So
a great example is I've classically said you can have bad security.
This is like forestry management or health management. Where,
yeah, you're gonna have some sick people.
You're gonna have a forest fire once in a while. That's part of the ecosystem.
That's ok.
You know, I,
I'm noticing people are starting to talk about data breaches in the sense of like,
yeah, they happen,
it sucks, but they happen and we can't really stop them.
And then a lot of people get very upset
about that saying that's a defeatist attitude and everything.
And it's like, well, but it's also the truth.
It's kind of like if you look at public health emergencies,
generally speaking,
there's not tons of effort put into, like, for example, pandemic prevention,
but there is a lot of effort put into like,
handling a pandemic because the reality is you can't prevent
-- a lot of this sort of stuff.
-- We can't get people to wash their hands.
I know. Right.
And no,
this is why I won't shake hands in public anymore is I actually have been paying
attention to other people in the bathroom and if they wash their hands or not,
-- and I've noticed quite a lot of men don't wash their hands.
-- Oh, I know.
It's horrifying. I was just at a conference. Yeah. Tell me about that.
Right.
Like, I, like, I,
I personally think there needs to be a video camera on the way into the
bathroom that takes a picture of your face and a set of cameras at the sinks
and if you walk out without washing your hands, a giant alarm and horn goes off and
lights show on you and like, you know,
like dirty hand disgusting person don't wash their hands.
I'd be ok with that.
-- Ok?
-- No, no, no, no.
I, I appreciate
your, like, internal hatred for this topic.
But the reality is this, this is, this is exactly the right example.
And I want to end it on this is
you're talking about like an individual solution to a group problem.
Well, yes,
shaming people for not washing their hands would be
like lovely and it would make me very happy.
But the reality is like, statistically speaking,
some percentage of people don't wash their hands,
it's probably a pretty high percentage.
And so the correct response is to just
not touch people's drummy disgusting hands,
right? Versus trying to get them to change their behavior.
If you'll notice at the CS A booth,
there's always a little cardboard thing propped up on them desk because behind
it there's like a half gallon hand sanitizer pump that's been there for like
the,
the person who has been doing this for 20 years and they know so there's always
been like half a gallon of hand sanitizer at the CS A booth at every conference.
And like,
everybody is religiously like every five minutes
like a sushi chef sanitizing their hands
and I learned that from this person. And I was like,
-- yeah, thank you for teaching this to me because it's
-- something to do.
All right, that's a terrible story to end on. So I'm ending on it. Thank you. Thank
you for listening. Go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up the show notes.
Suzie Pando
says, podcast, hashtag Find us on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too.
-- Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.