Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast
with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner Thought Crime. Josh Bresser.
So, what are we talking about?
Well, I finished building a tree house on the weekend.
Oh, well, that is exciting.
We're the base of it actually.
-- That's not
-- our topic though, is it
no
related? But, but building a tree house is
-- awesome. I have not built a tree house and I bet 30 plus years. Yeah.
-- Well, I mean,
it helps that I have kids now because of
it's just
-- do, are adults allowed to build tree houses?
-- I don't see why not.
I mean, we could build awesome tree houses. Our tree houses could have Wi
Fi,
wouldn't it
just have it from the house?
It could or you could put Wi Fi specifically in the tree
house and you could give it an SS ID of tree house wi
Fi.
No, I'm just,
I'm more thinking about how to run electrical out
there and be code compliant because then I get,
you need to get Nema 40.
It's, it's fine. It'll just burn the tree down.
It's, it's fine. I like that.
It's a nice tree
No, I, I detest this concept of, there are Children things and adult things.
I feel like
if kids are allowed to do it, I could do it and I don't care what you think about me.
So, when I bring my kids to the park, I go down the slides, I play on the swings.
I do all that stuff.
Well, the one challenge I find, like I get stuck on some of the slides now.
Yeah, I'm too fat for certain things. But, and that's ok. There's certain tubes.
-- I don't necessarily enjoy crawling through. I
-- was going to,
with my hips are too wide, but sure. Yeah,
-- it's entirely wrong,
-- but it's still fun. And I love the swing.
The swings are my favorite thing in the whole world. Man.
I could literally sit on a swing all day long and just swing back and forth.
It's lovely.
What makes me sad is though is when I do that other
kids come up and try to play with me and I'm like,
I'm sorry, but like, I can't chase you and take you and touch you.
-- Like, I've never had that problem.
-- Don't ask you to play with them when they're
too
much, look more friendly than I do.
It's kind of, it feeds.
So Microsoft has basically come out and said, not surprisingly, that C++
is just not
safe to quote C++ at its core is not a safe language which comes as a huge shock.
I'm sure to most of our listeners,
anyone who's ever used it completely understands that statement.
My one thought is like, given the average C or C++ project,
how much percentage like of time and mental effort do they spend managing memory?
-- Not
-- enough is always the answer and more than you should is the second half of that
or things like concurrency.
-- I mean,
-- concurrency is a problem in almost every language so that
-- I can forgive
-- some languages,
give you better tooling and capabilities and some like C++
give you a box of sharp Met
bits that you're expected to somehow safely glue together.
I won't disagree with that necessarily.
But yes.
So, and, but the good news is now we have some answers, you know, for example,
the Rust programming language, which, well, because you did that,
I think you had a slide deck or a talk about, you know,
talking about web applications and how, you know, web applications
essentially, you can solve the majority of the oo
what is it? Top 10 or top 20 problems by just using a framework.
You know, I'll, I'll dig up the talk. It's, it's actually online. It was at the,
it was at Madison, Wisconsin devops days.
-- I gave it this man, this feels like it was 100 years ago now. I don't, it was pre
-- COVID.
Yeah. Right. Like a decade
ago.
It was four times.
I mean, it's been a couple of years, at least but basically I took the O
A
top 10 and the talk came at a really interesting time
because it was whenever the last switch over from the old O
A
list to the new OO
list.
So I even had some comparisons,
which is funny because the list are the freaking same.
Basically, I took them and broke them down into kind of categories.
And I think I called it the O
A
top four.
And
yeah, a significant number of the problems are solved by using
-- not see and the web framework,
-- maybe even at a higher level,
the majority of these problems are solved by
using a tool that already solved these problems.
-- I
-- mean,
that's a good point. That's true. That's the reason Rust exists. Basically.
I, I love the fact that, you know, we're,
we're finally getting languages where it's like memory management.
Yeah.
No, like it just does it, you know, we've had that for a long time,
but performance has always been somewhat of a concern.
-- It has. That's been the kicker,
-- right?
Realistically, we've gotten past that where you can write high performance,
like really ridiculously high performance code now in memory safe languages.
Well, some of them,
the thing to remember too about Rust is Rust is a unique beast because
they kind of took a different attitude to memory safety where there's the Java
kind of universe and this, I think
small talk is really where it came from of you have your language
and you put absolutely no effort into memory management and the system,
there's, there's a magic dwarf in a box behind the wall
and he does it all.
And I mean, Rust has the attitude of, you can kind of,
sort of tell me what to do here and I'll make sure you
don't shoot yourself in the leg because you really just have a nerf gun
even though you don't really know that.
And I, I think that's the correct way to do it because I think, I mean,
from a purely computer science perspective,
there was a very,
we're going to build like the ultimate machine that will make
all the right choices and do all the right things.
And the reality is humans program and we suck.
So everything is programmed terribly. And if we rely on magic
it,
it's like you,
you've dumped in a bunch of Turds and a bunch
of magic and now you just have Turd covered magic.
Well, but I mean, when you look at the quality of most software, most programmers,
I think it's fair to say that most programmers lack
-- the skill to actually make these decisions.
-- They all lack them.
Kurt, I'm going to tell you now, like there's, there's people,
there's some who are better than others and I'm not going to deny that.
But functionally speaking,
there is not a programmer on the planet who is programmed
in C or C++ who hasn't added a memory leak accidentally.
-- Absolutely.
-- Right. Exactly.
But it's, it's interesting to me because, like, looking at Rust,
I think two of the biggest things are, you know,
number one obviously is memory safety, right?
I'm not even going to say memory management at this point.
And number two is concurrency because that's the other thing, right?
Software has changed, like it used to be
more than enough to have a single thread,
you know, like a word processor, right? Just waiting for a keystroke input. OK.
I got a keystroke input. What do I do with it? OK. I put it on the screen or?
Oh, no, he's trying
to
a menu through a hot key combo. OK. You know? Oh, he wants to print this thing. OK.
Let's go talk to the angry printer, you know, and that's not enough anymore, right?
Like even a simple application nowadays,
-- pretty much all of them have spell check
-- going.
They all do lots of things.
And part of it is because they can, I mean,
do you remember the days when you had ac pu in a computer and it was ac pu one core,
one thread
and when you had any sort of multitasking it was just the, the,
the operating system quickly switching back and forth between things.
Well, I remember going from Windows 3.11 to Os 22
os 22.
No, it was 2.1. It was not 2.0 it was 2.1
whatever. Os 22 is the best thing you've ever said.
You know, and it blew my mind that like, oh, Windows 3.11 could sort of,
technically you could run more than one program at a time.
But in the sense of like
the program is running, I've sort of put it in this box over here and if you need it,
I can bring it back to you.
Whereas OS two could actually run two programs
at the same time properly without crashing repeatedly.
-- And
-- then Windows 95 came out and ruined it all. Pretty much.
Yes.
And, and the other one being like this, this concurrency thing,
you know, I,
the other day I was doing some work on my computer
and I ended up having to run top to see,
you know,
basically,
I wanted to make sure something was actually using the CPU and
running and doing something because I wasn't sure it was basically,
was the gooey being non responsive and had the program basically crapped itself
or was it actually just thinking it was doing, you know,
apple photos doing facial recognition?
Right.
So when it does that,
it just kind of the whole system grinds to a halt and the app
just sits there and it could have crashed or it could just be processing,
you know, 4000 photos.
So I had to run top and the amount of stuff running on my Mac.
-- Like, I have no idea what any of this is.
-- It is pretty bananas for sure.
Even, even analytic system.
Now, if you're running any sort of desktop, there's a ton of weird stuff there.
Now, this is where
there is a,
I, I'm sure it exists in Homebrew or something,
but there's a command called PS tree where you type PS
tree and it kind of shows you where everything came from.
And that was actually really handy for me yesterday because I
was running some container scanners and there was some stuff running.
I'm like, is that from the container scanner is something wrong?
And so, yeah, like P S3 and I'm like, aha.
Yes, it's the container scanner running Python. It's fine.
The other thing too is one thing that
a
lot of people don't make the distinction between code that is
sort of safety or security critical and code that can be,
you know, maybe a bit more me,
whatever. If it fails, it fails,
you know.
So there's things in your computer, like your, your computer,
the kernel of the operating system or,
you know, the networking code,
things like that where you really want them to run reliably.
But do you remember that episode?
We had a while back where we talked about the security issue in the beep command on
Debian.
Well,
I, I think all seriousness,
I think that's an attitude that also needs to die eventually is saying, oh,
this code is important.
This code isn't the code that isn't important could
be important someday and so treating it like just,
you know, some, some gremlin we hate.
That's bad.
Well, but from like a resource allocation perspective,
I would rather they spend time, you know,
locking down the kernel than locking down beep.
I mean,
you, you'd think
that's fair. That's fair.
Well, it's not, I'm not saying this code isn't at
all important or can't have a security impact.
But like a great example is in windows.
You know, for apparently some historical reason,
font handling is done in the kernel. I thought they took that out.
Well, and if they did then good,
then they made the right choice and they put the effort into that.
And that's a great example of, you know,
where I want them to allocate their resources
because I don't want some wonky character set,
owning my system, like, has happened in the past.
-- Right. Right.
-- You know, through web browsers and whatnot.
Well, and it's also really difficult because true type fonts are turning complete,
which most people don't realize,
I think at this point anything that is interesting,
ends up
being turn complete.
That's actually really true.
I mean, postscript was turning complete pretty much from day one.
Yeah, you're right.
You're right.
That's just sort of, unfortunately,
the nature of any compute thing is it just ends up being turn complete real quick.
-- Everything turns into emacs eventually. Well,
-- or powerpoint or
the guy that made a computer using Excel and color changing cells.
-- I haven't heard of
-- this.
Powerpoint is turing complete in the sense of
you can have like objects interact with themselves and
-- images and stuff.
-- I mean, that doesn't surprise you.
There, there's the weird people who figured out how to make the game magic,
the gathering into a general purpose
processor. I mean, you can,
yeah, whatever, everything eventually gets
complex enough, you can build a processor with it.
There's the Minecraft computer processors where there was the guy who programmed
an Atari 2600 in Minecraft, which was
-- ridiculous
-- using Redstone or something else
-- with Redstone.
-- Yes. He basically emulated in a Tari 2600 in Minecraft.
And then I think he played Donkey Kong with it. Like
just what
I'm, I'm always impressed and jealous
and I'm jealous because I don't have that kind of free time
because the dedication it takes to actually follow through on that is absurd.
What got me was building the tree house.
It needed a bit of a foundation, right?
Because the tree is big, but it's not big enough to like just stick a house on it,
right?
It's not one of those giant trees. So it's got like a nice y
you know, fork in it that I rested one of the beams on.
So basically the tree is one corner of the house.
And so I used four by four. So four inch by four inch as sort of the post.
So there's three posts in the tree to make a square
because squares are easy to build.
Not a perfect square.
-- Mind you, that's, that's basically impossible to build, but
-- it
is,
it's
a lumpy square I would go with, but it doesn't really matter because
as long as the two cross beams on top are level and you know,
reasonably parallel and far apart,
you know, you just drop your platform on top of that,
right? And who cares? So there's an eight by 8 ft platform sitting on top of all that.
The uh the three posts originally, I was looking, you know, classically at like, OK,
I got to like rent an auger, I got to drill this like 3 ft hole times three, you know,
put in a concrete form, go get, you know, a couple 100 pounds of concrete blah, blah,
blah.
And I'm like, that's a lot of work. Yes,
it is.
And so I looked at alternative solutions
and now it turns out there's a much better thing,
there's this thing called an easy spike.
And the old easy spikes are basically what exactly, what they sound like.
It's about a 2.5 ft long metal spike with a metal
cup on the end that holds the four by four,
right?
And so you're basically balancing into the ground with a sledgehammer and
put your post on it and then there's a newer version,
which has an adjustable top.
So you loosen a bolt and it can wiggle around
and move about five or 10 degrees in every direction.
Because here's the thing, when you drive a spike into the ground,
are you going to get it perfectly vertical?
-- No, nobody will.
-- More importantly is if you drive it into the ground
and you said it goes in a couple of feet,
about 2.5 ft
and then it's got like a metal cup on the top that sits on the ground.
Yeah,
but it doesn't matter because what's going to happen is the frost in the winter.
Most people don't realize how much the ground moves when it freezes, but it will.
So what's going to happen is the end of the part of your
house attached to the tree isn't going to move because the tree is big
and then the part you have on these posts is going to
rise up probably between one and three inches in the winter,
depending upon how much moisture you have in your soil.
But anyways, the point is
you pound this
easy spike into the ground and then you loosen a bolt,
you adjust it to get it vertical, you tighten the bolt
and to put in three of these easy spikes into the ground and get them all adjusted.
-- Took me like a total of two hours as opposed
-- to three days or
concrete footings. And
so
you know, the simple point is there's better tooling available.
It's like a framework.
It's, there's better stuff available than doing it the old fashioned way.
That's true of everything ever.
I mean, you look at cars today, you look at,
we were just talking about plumbing yesterday.
I mean,
plumbing is a great example where the
plumbing technology available today versus say,
like my house is 100 years old.
I have a 100 year old plumbing in my house. It's horrific. I do not have lead.
That was the first thing. Well,
that was the first thing I checked when I moved in after I got asbestos taken out.
Well, you know, it's funny to me about lead pipes is old,
lead pipes are safe because the calcium build up inside the pipe covers it.
Well, I still wouldn't want them.
But yes, old lead pipes are generally relatively safe.
-- Yeah, until you put, like acid down them or whack them with a hammer. Right.
-- Exactly.
-- I mean, I still wouldn't keep them in my house if, if I had them. But.
-- Right.
Well, dirty secret. A lot of supply lines in the US are still lead.
-- Not
-- where I live at the moment.
They did replace all the supply lines in the, in this old neighborhood I live in.
Now I know in the city next to me
they just got a grant from the federal government to
replace the remaining lead pipes they have in the ground.
Which is, I mean, that seems mind boggling.
-- We've known lead is dangerous for 100 years.
-- We banned it in gasoline as an additive.
-- Granted that took way too long
-- and paint and all kinds of this stuff. I mean, yeah.
Oh, I remember that whole thing. Yeah.
Don't, was it,
don't chew on your blinds because they have paint that's contains lead.
-- I remember as a child it was always window blinds. was the thing,
-- window blinds. Hey,
-- yeah,
-- with lead covered paint,
the technology moves forward.
I think you could easily make the argument that like let's look at the Linux kernel,
the Linux kernel was created in
what? 92? Probably give or take
94. I
mean, somewhere in there it's written in C because I mean, quite frankly, when,
when Linus built it c was what you used
there literally was no other tool theoretically, you could have built it in list.
But
yeah,
we'll just say C was the only tool because
you could argue for hours about other obscure languages.
But functionally,
-- if you were writing an operating system in the early nineties wrote it in C
-- Well, no,
no, no, if you were writing any program of size.
Yeah, that's probably true because really, I mean,
did Java even exist at that point?
And even then Java was very slow when it first came out.
Well, I, you know,
the biggest thing I remember about Java originally
is how many different Java interpreters were there.
I remember people working on Java code base where it's like you install the,
what was it, Norton or Semantic Java, you can't install the
one like ours is not compatible with it.
They were all different, even, even the sun one man,
it was different between architecture,
sometimes depending upon what you were doing where it acted different on windows.
Yeah, exactly. So, I mean, c was
the only thing that had a hope
of sort of cross platform and actually freely available tooling thanks to the
-- GNU project.
-- And, and so you figure
it has been
decades since then and we're still running
a Linux kernel built on sea and you could easily make the argument of, oh,
you could build it with something else and it
would be better and in some ways it would,
but
you would lose the obscene amount of backwards compatibility and just
-- battle testing of the corner cases.
-- Yeah. Right. Right.
So, like there, there's some instances where you could maybe make that argument.
-- Well, like
-- how often, I mean, you remember back when we worked at that company,
you know,
somebody would make a minor tweak to the Linux kernel that nobody
thought was a big deal and then it turns out that,
oh, it, like, totally destroys performance for this.
I don't want to say corner case because it's actually
something like 20% of the internet needs to work.
Right. Yep.
Yep. I remember weird things like that. It's
like some of the security patches where it's like, well,
this fixes the security problem.
But I mean, my favorite was uh yeah, it was um the stack guard stuff.
The initial research said, OK,
like one megabyte stack guard page should work and then, you know, no,
that's not gonna work.
You need like a three gigabyte stack guard page,
which means you can run like three processes on a 32 bit system now.
Right. Right. And it was like that, that's going to be a problem.
You need more than three processes on a system.
Ok.
I don't want,
I don't want to get too much in the weeds on the Linux kernel because we're
talking about tooling.
-- Well, the point
-- being is that something like Rust doesn't have these issues,
it just that this class of problem just
-- doesn't exist,
-- it has issues, it just doesn't have these issues.
I mean,
-- that's, that's one of the challenges,
-- but here's the question.
Does Rust have more issues overall or less issues overall than C I mean,
so I wouldn't, I wouldn't think of it that way.
I would say
that Rust solves the problems we know about.
But as,
and as you start using it, you're going to find new problems,
you didn't even know you had.
And I, I've got a great example for this.
So I've worked on projects that let's say didn't have proper authentication.
Right.
So everyone
just comes to you and says, you need to add authentication,
you need security on this thing because I'm, I'm basically building my own with,
with proxies.
So this isn't working at all, figure something out and make this work.
And that's the only thing you hear.
So we build authentication into the system. You get authentication.
Now, since nobody has to harass you about authentication,
now you have 30 different asks, whereas you used to have one,
this is going to be the same thing with something like rust.
So let's say you have people coming and saying, oh,
we need memory safety and memory safety and memory safety.
And you could easily say that because memory safety is probably
the biggest problem in computing today or it used to be.
We'll say
we've definitely spent several 100 thousands of people years
-- working on it.
-- So now you have memory safety
check that box. Now, what do you care about?
And like you might care about concurrency, I might care about.
Yeah,
-- but
-- you're at least moving the ball forwards like you're moving the game forwards.
Right? No. Absolutely. Absolutely.
But my point is this is, I mean, this is one of the challenges though when you're,
when you're building new things is you solve one large problem
and now you have 10 slightly smaller problems that are next
and then you solve some of those and it's like this,
this expanding tree.
-- Well, but that's just how progress works. I mean,
-- it is. Absolutely.
I mean, you know, that's what gets me about, like, a lot of these stalwarts of,
you know, various computing technologies.
It's,
you know, they're like, oh,
I don't want to use this new thing because you have new problems.
Well, yes, but we also get rid of old problems. We get new capabilities
and, you know, these people that are still, like, I look at things like,
pretty much everything still written in C and C++ still, you know,
we're seeing CV S for very well known memory safety related issues.
Yeah, they'll never go away if you have c you have memory safety problems.
I mean, the end of story, there's, there's absolutely no way to get rid of them.
There, there are some
is you can use the kind of abstracted away and solve like 90 some percent of it.
But again, people just don't want to make that change.
Like I remember, well,
somebody I worked with who had to deal with people who refused categorically to use,
make
S temp because it wasn't quote unquote portable enough.
And this is back in the, you know, late nineties, early two thousands.
-- And they were like, every modern operating system has make secure
-- temp,
but it's not pos
-- exactly,
-- it's not pos
and some older systems may not have it. And it's like, well, if
you could just, if def
-- that
-- I solved this a long time ago.
So I used to work on a mail system called NH,
and I was one of the upstream developers for NH.
And I mean, this was, we're talking like more than a decade, right.
And NH, was this ridiculous mail handling program that it was,
it's almost undescribable. Weird what it is.
-- Oh, it's a G new project. That's why
-- it's not a GNU project.
It was, it actually has its,
you can trace its history back to the RAND Corporation in the seventies.
Well, that explains it's, it's hard core man.
So anyway,
we would get into these long arguments about adding
support for some library or function or something that
someone would inevitably say,
but this doesn't work on like some sun machine from 1995
and the argument eventually became
OK, great.
Then just don't ever upgrade. NH you keep running the old version of
NH we're going to march forward by adding, you know,
support for things like make us temp that.
Yes, it is not available on this old version of Solaris
and we don't care.
-- Well, and
-- there used to be a lot more diversity in the industry, right?
Like I remember, you know, HX
A I,
all that stuff was actually,
I don't want to say widely used, but, you know,
more than single digit percentage wise.
Whereas now it's what Linux is probably 90 some percent
followed by like a little bit of maybe free BS D
and then Solaris, I guess.
And then
A
it's Linux, it's all Linux
now. Draw
blank.
And so I think the arguments are different these days than they used to be.
I mean, I mean, back then we literally had people developing NH on Solaris, right?
We had people like, I was using Linux, we had people using BSD.
-- So well,
-- I owned a Solaris box at one point. I
-- have
-- never
owned one.
Like I had a pizza box. That's awesome. You know, I got it used for like, 500 bucks.
I don't even want to think about what it costs new. Right.
And it used $1000 worth of power every year. So you
not too bad,
but basically it had to NFS Mountain
everything because the disc guy always just like
-- that.
-- Awesome.
I remember,
I remember I had a friend giving away some sun gear one time that only ran on 220 volts
and
it was like,
and, and you needed three people to move it.
And I thought part of me thinks it'd be cool to own this.
And a big part of me says don't touch that stuff because it's
going to be a millstone if you ever get it in the house.
-- But
-- it's a floor ballast. Yeah.
Right.
Anyway, anyway,
the point being to all of this conversation I think is
the fact that I think there's two sides to this,
this is how we should kind of wrap this all up is on one end.
I think there's a certain amount of sunk cost fallacy.
And
there's always going to be people that say, oh, this thing is written in C,
this thing is written in C++ and it's really big and we spend all this time
on it and it has all the support and we should keep it around forever.
That's a difficult decision to make because I
think sometimes it's sunk cost fallacy sometimes.
-- Yes, you're absolutely
-- right.
Well, historically, large scale rewrites tend to fail.
I would agree with that one 100%.
-- There's only a handful of large scale rewrites that have been successful.
-- Yeah.
And most of those, even those successful,
it took them like five or 10 years to be successful like it, like Firefox and Mozilla
and all that just about killed them.
I would argue that Firefox did not do a full scale rewrite.
They just slowly, slowly genetically engineered themselves. True.
And, and that's the thing. Right.
-- If you try to do like a full rewrite,
-- well, that's the only way to do a full rewrite.
It's going to take years.
Yeah,
-- it's terrible of
-- any code base of size.
Right. Right.
And actually this is something that makes rust particularly useful in
this space is rust can talk to sea libraries very easily.
So you can start replacing portions of your sea
code with rust and still make it relatively functional.
I mean, you lose some of your memory safety if you're crawling into sea but that's
like, that's probably an acceptable trade off.
-- Well,
-- but you didn't have that to begin with. Right. Yeah, exactly.
-- Like you're not losing anything.
-- I'll agree with that.
There's that sunk cost aspect and I think this is where
it becomes difficult and that's everyone has to make their own decisions.
And then on the other side, I think there's the concept of progress. And
II, I just, I had this conversation literally
20 minutes before we started talking of,
there are always those laggards in every space it is.
I, I always, I always struggle with this. If at some point you just have to say
-- good luck, you're on your own.
-- You know, people who want to ride their horse to work
like no, we're not putting in a stable, like we'll put in a bike lock up. Sure.
Like we can do a bike lock up, but we're not putting in a stable for your horse.
-- And,
-- and that's always my comparison when people say about, oh, self driving cars.
What if, what if I want to drive?
It's like, well, what if you want to ride your horse on the interstate?
You know, you can't, it's illegal and yeah, I, I think that's part of it is
there, there's, there's just always going to be people who don't want to, you know,
that, that talk about, oh, I don't know about this cloud computing thing.
And it's
what, why are we talking about this and I feel like this is,
this is a similar conversation where there's just
always going to be some people who,
who say, oh,
I like c, I don't want to use rust or I'm going to use Java forever or whatever. Right.
They've got their, their pet language they like, and they love
going to keep using it.
And this again is a delicate dance of, at some point you just have to, you know,
cut him off and say good luck.
-- I wish you the best and you got to go forward.
-- Yeah. No, I'm not going to disagree. And
of course, that's easy to say when it's not someone, you know, and like, but yeah,
I don't know.
I think about this one a lot and I don't know if there's ever going to be a right answer.
I,
I think technology just continues to move forward and, and in some places,
things like if you have containers,
memory safety is less dangerous than if you don't.
So now you've got all that kind of stuff to juggle too.
Well, I just, I look at where things have gone and I look at, you know,
I remember back in the day where, what was it?
Like?
One admin could easily or a good admin rather could take
care of about 10 windows servers or 50 UNIX servers.
And now,
-- you know, add three zeros to that,
-- at least,
you know, things like Kubernetes that's
Yeah.
And I mean, you know,
I'm getting all our stuff moved into platform as a service because I just,
I don't want to have to ever deal with servers again.
There's no value for me to add. No, I hear you man.
And so I think that's the other aspect of progress
is that initial progress tends to be expensive and painful.
But then at some point it gets cheap.
Like I look at what cloud hosting costs now compared to.
Well, can you imagine going to somebody 20 years ago and saying basically,
I want to outsource like an entire D C's worth of compute to you.
What's that going to cost me?
And the answer would be, well, it's going to cost you a DC plus, you know,
my margin of 10 or 20%.
And now it's like, well, it's going to cost you a 0.05 cents per hour.
Yes,
absolutely. And yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
And I think even due to this, this is, this is moving a lot of tooling forward.
Things like, I mean, if you, you have platform as a service, no one is
running letting you run C, right?
You're going to be uploading Java or you're going to be uploading no Js or
Python or something, right?
Well, more to the point,
the people who write their stuff and C are not going
to be progressive enough to use platform as a service,
but there are platforms of service that will let you run C and anything you want.
Really?
That's
like some crazy VM that they just have, like,
in its own little zoo away from everybody else
pretty much
anyway. Anyway. All right, we are, we are about out of time.
So I, I think this is an interesting conversation.
I know we'll keep having it forever and I know we've
talked about similar things in the past on the show even.
It's,
it's just,
it
is
the old curse of May you live in interesting times. And I feel like
we are in such an incredible place of disruption right now in technology
and I don't know exactly where it's going to end, but I assure you
c isn't going to win this race so.
Well,
I think to add to that it's not just
the rate of disruption but the adoption of disruption,
you look, there's that great graph.
We should maybe check in here where it showed
the time it took for people to adopt electricity,
radio TV, internet, smartphones.
And I, I would love to see one of those for these kind of core technology pieces,
like the rate of adoption for languages that use garbage collection.
And sadly, that curve is still at the oh, probably 50% mark.
I think that's a big part of it is just not only
the rate of change but the amount of it in technology because,
-- you know, when you look at what's available to us now, how much stuff is on
-- github?
Now, you know what I'm going to,
I don't want to talk about this right now because we're already out of time.
But
I think something to think about and we'll come back to this in the future is
I
don't think the,
the adoption curve is as bad as you say because I bet
if you would count the lines of code written per year,
the number of lines of code written in memory safe languages.
Be it no Js or Ruby or Python or Java or whatever is probably 10,000 to 1
to see
if you look to say github
commits.
I bet you anything.
-- I,
-- I think a more useful metric because that guy did not only lines of code but
for each line of code, how much machine executable stuff does it generate? Right?
Because there's,
there's a big difference between writing a web client
and C and just calling http lib in Python.
Yes, that is also true, you know,
and that was one of my favorite articles to read was pointing out that,
you know, as a,
as a Python developer, I can write you a web client in like what three lines of code.
Yes, there'd be an import, open it up, grab it
-- and doing that and see. No. My answer is no
-- 1000 lines and 12 memory bugs. Anyway,
I'm calling it. This is, this has been a good one.
I got, oh man, you're going to be thinking about this all day now,
so. All right, cool. We'll have plenty of show notes for this one. I'm sure.
So, thank you, Kurt. Thank you very much for listening. You can go to open
source security podcast.com. Hit up the show notes, use the Pound
Oss
podcast. Hashtag Do hit us up on social media. Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the.