Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 38 with myself, Kurt
Siefried and my partner in crime. Josh
Reser.
Oh, Kurt,
it feels like I haven't talked to you in a month and it's been one whole week only.
I know what you mean. I've been sick for
like the last two weeks. I just can't stop blowing my nose.
That sounds great. Thanks for sharing that.
I guess we'll start this week off with a little bit of I told you. So,
what have I done this time?
What did I do? I didn't do it
well, not you. No, no, no, but everybody in general. So this whole,
you know,
there's this constant argue about crypto and how
crypto will make you secure and safe and,
you know, like XK CD, I think said it best. It's like, oh, you know, we,
we, we'll have to hack this 4096 bit encryption key and factor the,
we'll have to factor the Gibson and all that and
you know, the correct response is no,
just go get a lead pipe and beat his
kneecaps until he tells us the password pretty much.
And uh, so in the US, somebody is apparently refusing to give up their password and,
or claiming that they forgot.
And so the law in its, you know, slightly we're not going to play games with you.
Fashion has, uh, stuck them in jail
for contempt of court.
It's, yeah. Which,
you know,
and I love because Contempt of Court is one
of those wonderfully old things that we have,
you know, that just,
it covers a multitude of sins.
Well, it's because you didn't listen, I mean,
if the judge tells you to sit down and you don't,
you go to jail for contempt of court and in the case of something like this,
the problem is if the judge thinks you have the password
and you refuse to give it to him,
then he can put you in jail for contempt of court until you give him the password,
which means you could literally sit in jail forever
for contempt of court in an instance like this.
Yeah. What's interesting to me is in the US or sorry? In the UK.
They actually explicitly passed a law covering, you know, the so called,
like I don't have my password.
You can't get my data ha ha ha situation,
you know the UK Rip Act, right?
And it kind of,
and I'm kind of wondering now why they just simply didn't use Contempt of Court.
Although obviously having a law on the books that specifically covers something
makes it easier to apply.
Well, I mean,
this is almost certainly going to be appealed and
I'm sure it will make it to the Supreme Court
and in something along the lines of 1/5 amendment. Right?
And
just for those of us that aren't American,
what is the
fifth amendment?
Right. That's right.
So, in America there's certain, uh we'll say undeniable rights you get
and one of them is you do not have to incriminate yourself,
which is called the fifth amendment.
There's a constitution,
they've added some amendments to it to fix things that were missing.
And the fifth amendment basically says when you're in court,
you don't have to testify against yourself.
And historically,
passwords have been viewed as 1/5 amendment issue of
giving up your password is seen as essentially,
you know, taking the stand against yourself in court.
Now, in this case, it's, it's a, a
contempt of court that they put the person in jail for and
I don't know how this is going to work out.
We'll see, we'll put the story in the show notes for this.
And of course, I'm not a lawyer as, as any real lawyers know from all the weeping,
they do when they hear me speak.
But
it should be interesting to see how this one plays itself out over time because I,
I have no doubt we're gonna see this at the Supreme Court.
Well, see what's interesting to me. So, historically speaking, you know, a
bad analogy of safes, right?
You give us the combination to the safe so we can get in there and look
at the evidence and if you refuse to give up the password to the safe.
Well, that's unfortunate, but fundamentally,
you can physically cut a safe open given enough time and patience.
And it's actually not that,
you know, it's not that hard actually given like,
you know, physical access in a few days to monkey around with it.
It's even trickier than that because now if, if you're safe has a key,
they can make you give them the key
-- and if you
-- don't know
that,
so we're talking a physical key like a mechanical,
-- like
-- an actual key.
And if you don't give it to them, that's contempt of court
or if you have a fingerprint reader on your phone,
they can touch the phone to your finger
and that's not protected by the fifth amendment.
Well, you know what it reminds me of is like the old banking secrecy where, you know,
essentially, hey, my money's in Switzerland most likely.
So the authorities are like, hey, Switzerland,
what's the deal with this guy's money?
And the Swiss authorities at least back in the day were like, yeah, no,
you know what I mean?
And it's kind of like,
similar to encryption in that way and that there's no
way around that sort of like launching a war on,
you know, Switzerland.
Um Although the Swiss banking laws have now significantly changed and, you know,
that's not a problem anymore.
But,
and that's the thing with encryption, right is given, say a strong,
you know, 4096 bit key with a good pass phrase, protecting it.
Like in theory it,
you, you can't,
you can't get around it without, you know, getting it out of the suspect.
Like you just can't,
you know,
uh I remember there was one famous case many years ago where the guy
used his prison ID number as his password.
It was a mob case. We'll look that up and put it in the show notes.
But, you know, it's a classic case of like,
don't use your birthday or your pet's name or, you know,
your prison ID number is your password,
right?
So, yeah, I mean, I guess this is, well, it, it had to happen eventually, right?
Because the law, you know, if there's how many cases are there where, you know,
they want access to somebody's cell phone or their Facebook postings or, you know,
whatever.
Right.
Yeah, it, it comes up quite a lot.
Well, when you,
when I think about how much of my life is not
just like I carry my cell phone all the time,
but how much of my life I transact on my cell phone, you know, email, calendaring,
online banking,
you know, booking trips, buying things from Amazon, you know,
I actually finally folded and set up my phone to, you know,
actually logged into the Amazon app so I can buy things on my phone.
And
because no, what I found happening is I, you know, I go to stores,
I check the price and I'm like, oh, you know, Amazon's like 50% cheaper and, you know,
prime will have it out in two days,
but someday the stores are going to disappear because of people like you,
that
you have to buy it at the store after you look at it because that's terrible.
Otherwise
it,
I feel like that I do and I know
I know not everyone shares my, we'll say a false sense of morality here,
-- but
-- it's tough because like for example,
like we were looking at some board games over the weekend, right?
Um Shout out by the way to Rhino Hero.
Awesome board game takes 30 seconds to learn
board games are so expensive in the stores,
but I, I buy them there because I do not want my local game store to go out a bit.
And
I know
they're, they're raking me over the cold.
You have game stores but not so a big thing here
locally in Edmonton now is we have about six or seven
tabletop cafes where essentially it's like a cafe
and they have like 1000 board games.
And for example,
the one you pay five bucks to sit down and play as many games for as long as you want.
And then they also sell, you know, coffee and beer and snacks and food.
That's pretty sweet,
you know, and the beauty is, of course, you know, they have like 1000 house games.
So you can try all these different games that
are, you know, some of them are not cheap.
Um, more the point also you don't have to clean your house to have people over.
Right.
And so anyways, they, most of them also sell more popular games and
in some cases like this, the, the one place we went, had Rhino Hero for like within,
like it was like 16 bucks and it was within five cents of what Amazon could get it for.
And that was without shipping and handling. So, of course, I bought it in the store.
But, you know, then I'm looking at these other games and they're like,
you know, 100 and 5200 bucks in the store and like 100 bucks on Amazon. And,
you know, I feel for these stores because, yeah, they want to sell stuff. But like,
if you are like 50 or 100% more than an online store, like, uh,
sorry,
I just,
it's hard to justify dropping an extra 100 bucks.
So I can just support my local business.
I've never dropped 100 bucks, but I, I bet I've spent more than 30
to buy things in person just so I can
again have that, uh, moral superiority over you online game shoppers.
Well, I'm just searching for the best price, you know.
No, I, I know what you mean. I know what you mean.
But, uh,
so for what it's worth my local game store does similar
things where they have kind of a room and back and,
you know, you can go play games or, or Pokemon or whatever it is you want to play
and they have a wall of games that you can try out and use and,
and it's fantastic and I love it and,
and because of that I probably bought more games than not.
But again,
I kind of feel like now on the other side, though, they don't charge you to hang out,
you can just go because obviously I assume they,
they figure rightly so that you're gonna buy a bunch of crap while you're there.
Which
I,
I don't think I've ever left the game store
without giving them money in some manner for something.
No, these ones are more first and foremost, like a cafe slash,
you know.
Yeah, they don't have
that at my game store. And man, if I could drink beer while,
I don't know,
beer while playing board games could go hardly wrong.
It's awesome. I mean,
it's, you know, and, and the thing, I like
a
lot of
the people I do.
Yeah.
But, uh, and the nice thing is too, a lot of these places will have, like,
I know the one place they have, um,
like these kind of nice private rooms that
will seat about eight or nine people comfortably.
And it's just,
and it's literally just $100 minimum and it's $100 minimum
in the sense of you have to spend $100 minimum,
which, I mean,
if you're there with eight or nine people that's gonna happen in the 1st 15 minutes
each maybe.
Yeah. Well, drinks, snacks, you know,
and then, I mean, and it's, you know,
the thing I was is I was working it out on in my head
and it's like if I spend more than 15 minutes cleaning my house,
it's actually cheaper to take everybody out to the board games place.
That's the spirit. All right.
So anyway, while we were, uh, rambling on about games,
I looked up the Fifth Amendment
and passwords
and so what it basically says here is that
the lower courts have given conflicting decisions about if
password disclosure is a violation of the fifth Amendment.
So, in this case,
the, the issue we're talking about, the judge obviously believes that
you can compel someone to give up their password. However, it also says that
no case has made it to the Supreme
Court specifically about passwords and the Fifth Amendment.
But it sounds like the general opinion of the court kind of the view.
Now, granted this is the
in the past the, the court is changing as we speak, but
it sounds like the,
the court generally believes that you cannot compel someone to give up a password.
But again,
that could be different
when this, because again, this case will probably make it to the Supreme Court
if I guess.
-- And, and we will finally
-- have
a
right because you have to.
Well, no, but I mean, with,
with the amount of people's lives being transacted on phones and more importantly,
the fact that I know Apple, for example, is really starting to, you know,
they've already got like the secure chip and, you know,
hooked in with the biometrics and the, you know,
all that stuff like this is going to become more and more of a like you,
you just can't get into somebody's phone without their fingerprint or
a zero day exploit, you know, of some sort to, to break in. Right.
And I think that's quite reasonable.
Yeah.
So which kind of leads then to the second interesting court related thing?
So apparently um
there's a small town in the uh just outside Minneapolis, Minnesota, so called Edina
Minneapolis. Uh Minnesota. Sorry.
And there's a, it's a,
it's a pretty standard wire fraud case
where somebody basically stole somebody else's identity,
you know, ginned up a fake passport
and used it to uh to get a credit union to transfer uh what was it? Oh, wow.
$28,500 out of the account,
get that stuff out of your bank account, man.
That should be in a stock market brokerage account
-- or
-- under your,
you know, sock drawer
buried in the yard. That's totally, totally.
Yeah. Print out Bitcoins, laminate them and bury them in New York.
You can buy like, physical Bitcoins that apparently have.
That's so weird.
Anyway.
Um, but anyway, so, you know, pretty standard wire fraud case, you know.
Um, but what's interesting is where is it?
Do, do,
do investigators are focusing their probe on an online photo of
someone with the same name of a local financial fraud victim?
The image turned up on a fake passport used
to trick the credit union fraud to fraudulent,
fraudulently transfer 28,500 out of an Adina man's account.
Police said the bogus passport was faxed to the credit union
using a spoof phone number obviously to mimic the victim's phone do
according to the warrant application. So basically the deal is
they found
there's this password or a passport photo, sorry that um
doesn't show up in Bing or Yahoo
only shows up in Google.
And so what they're asking Google for is
essentially searches of this name that would then,
you know, result in that photo coming up.
So they can see basically, you know, who um
ideally, you know,
took that photo and used it on a fake passport.
Sure.
Uh and the trick being though that of course, you know,
this warrant applies to global
uh
internet use, right? It's uh was it the warrant demands.
Google helped police determine who searched for variations of the victim's
name between December 1st of last year through January 7th,
2017.
So basically, they're asking Google globally,
every
single person who searched for this name.
We want all the records like and, and it's, you know,
standard warrant information language.
So it's like things like social security numbers and stuff,
which obviously you don't really apply here.
But
they basically want like as much information as Google can
give them about every single search for that name.
I can understand why Google is hesitant to do this.
-- Well,
-- just the cost of fulfilling this request.
Yeah, I'm sure it's not cheap
and
that's a pretty wide net they're tossing into the ocean here.
Yeah.
Um, I mean, because I, I believe,
remember the same thing sort of happened with Hans Reiser
going back in history.
Uh, so th those of you don't know, is apparently, was it,
was he the one that was doing Google searches on,
like how to dispose of a dead body like a week before
-- or
-- was that the case?
And there was a case in Florida? I think that also this happened,
there have been a handful of them
and, but, but so in, in an instance like that
you could even make the argument
this person
doing these searches. That's the information I want. And that's a lot tamer
than saying
everyone who's ever
logged into
Google,
Kurt, they know who you are. Don't even pretend they don't,
you can go to the freaking library and not log into anything and they know it's, you,
I guarantee it,
they know.
Right.
And so that's, that's different. This is really,
uh,
I mean, this is one of the problems with the way the world works now, is it,
I think in some ways it's getting worse because
they're talking about repealing net neutrality in the US.
That's right. The, the least crazy problem we have. Right.
Well, no, but, but they're talking about, you know,
and so for those of you who don't know, don't know,
the idea of net neutrality is this idea that essentially the,
the people providing the pipes.
So the I SPS
can't monkey with the traffic. Really?
Right. They can't be like, oh, you want access to Netflix? That'll cost you $5 right.
They either sell you internet access or they don't,
you know, kind of like the phone system. I give you
access to the phone system. You can dial any number you want. Right.
I can't like, oh, you know,
you wanted to actually be able to call Sweden. Yeah, that's an extra 20 bucks. Right.
Um,
and so with Net and tr they're talking about repealing
it and also allowing I SPS then to do things,
like, collect a lot more information on your,
on what you're doing online
and to sell that information
-- to third parties.
-- Well, they can do that already. I believe
it
-- varies.
-- I don't know, it's
whatever,
but
my head hurt.
Yeah.
But I mean, what, what it really boils down to is I'm really beginning to think that,
you know,
basically everybody needs to use a VPN for five or 10 bucks a month or something.
I don't know. Like,
yeah,
it, it's not even just VPN.
I mean,
this is part of the reason everyone wants everything encrypted and this
is very much in line with that whole Google beyond CORP strategy of
just assume every network you touch is compromised in some way.
And so you have to ensure, right, you have to ensure
essentially data integrity between the end points because everything in between,
you totally can't trust it.
And, and that's exactly the right way to look at everything.
Well,
the problem there though is that so I can have
completely encrypted network traffic to Google and I do.
But then Google keeps a copy of all that traffic forever,
right?
And
then quit using Google, I mean, right. Quit using Google is your, is
your search engine keeps, you know,
quit, quit using search engines.
I mean, this is, this is just how right. It's totally prac
but here's the deal is
I use Google, I understand
the amount of information Google has about me.
And I, I accept that I, I may not like it necessarily, but I have to accept it
when I'm
traversing the internet to get to Google.
I do not want anyone in between to know what I'm doing because I don't trust
them and I don't want them to have access to this and this is the same deal
dealing with your ISP.
I do not trust my ISP. I don't want them to know everything I do.
So, I mean, I, I go out of my way to make sure as much of the stuff I'm doing is encrypted.
Well, that brings up a problem in that.
Um, your DN Ss lookups can reveal every web page you visit.
They certainly can.
I do run my own DNS servers but they can still, no doubt,
pay attention to the DNS traffic coming in and out
and
I'm, I'm not a huge fan of that, but I can
accept that
as
well. You could
VP in your, your gu
that's a huge pain in the neck and part of every now and then I
get tempted to just start putting together
some nice infrastructure internally to do that.
But
fundamentally,
I, I'm not a huge fan of it but I will deal with it is kind of the way I look at it.
Well, I'm actually wondering so, like, I mean,
I'm assuming there's a lot of web pages that have very specific fingerprints
of DNS lookups.
Like not just what is being looked up but the order, you know,
the order that the javascript loads the ads
or, you know, the various other tokens and stuff. Right.
And I'm assuming, because I'm that kind of guy,
I'm assuming that a lot of these places maybe do that
intentionally change the order and loading and stuff so
that they can essentially fingerprint traffic by your DNS lookups
because
it would be actually relatively easy to do,
you know, conceptually, it's not that hard.
Um,
and I mean, I've, yeah,
I've looked at like what happens DNS request wise when you load
like the front page of cnn.com and it's like 200 lookups,
at least, maybe more
whatever. Um You're depressing me with this conversation.
Let's move on to something more fun like pa
to own.
Oh Yeah, that went well. This week
it went really well. I'm,
it was awesome,
right?
So why don't, what's, what's P
to own for those people who don't know
P
to
is um So
there's this nice guy called
Dragos Rui
who started a security convention.
It's gotta be like, it's more than 10 years ago, I
-- think
-- forever. At this point,
it
started,
it started in Vancouver, Canuck
West. And then I know he does one in Japan uh and one in Europe, I believe.
And essentially he had the bright idea for like, you know, um well, capture the flag.
Everybody loves, capture the flag.
But why not have like capture the flag with like real money prizes and like real,
capture the flag.
And so simply put
people show up, you know, prone to own, essentially large companies, um,
put up some cash and in this case, one of the major sponsors, uh, is
I, I think it's still tipping point. Right.
Oh, goodness, I couldn't, I,
-- there's so many now, honestly.
-- Yeah. Well, so
I think it was originally,
it was tipping point was one of the major
sponsors and basically the deal was they wanted zero days
because then they could write, you know, essentially, um,
protection things for their network product to block them and then, you know,
report it to the vendor like Microsoft or whatever and they would fix it
and they would be able to go to their customers and say,
look like Microsoft fixed this horrible, horrible flaw.
But had you purchased our product,
you would have been protected for like three or four months, you know,
before the patch actually came out.
Um So the whole thing always reminds me of this weird, you know, like, hey, that's a,
that's a nice story you got there.
I'd be ashamed if it burns down,
you know, it, it's really, to me there's this, like, weirdly fine line between like,
yeah,
that and like all these contests and stuff and
-- bounties, I feel like
-- this is protection money.
Maybe, maybe the Wikileaks story is, but that's another
issue.
So anyway,
so
traditionally, you know, they had the, the good targets, you know,
like Microsoft uh like the, you know, like the um
the chrome web browser, the Microsoft web browser,
which is what is it called edge now or something?
Um You know, and a couple other, you know, like Adobe Flash Java because, you know,
everybody loves beating all those poor things.
Um
And anyway, so yeah, this year, apparently somebody managed to,
you know,
do enough zero day exploits to what was it
break like to basically compromise a Microsoft edge browser
-- and break out of the VM ware virtual machine. It was running
-- within. OK.
It's crazier than that because here's what has to happen is it come,
you started a website,
the website exploits the browser,
then you exploit the the machine the browser is running on
and then they exploited the the was it running in VM Ware? Yeah, the VM Ware uh
guest essentially to break into the host.
And then they, yeah, they had a host level access from a web page.
You think about that a web page made it all the way to the VM host
well
execution
within the web browser.
Chances are, you know, there's always going to be flaws in the sand boxing.
But I mean, yeah, no, this is like a multiple,
like this is a multi-layered hack with probably what a dozen exploits.
I
don't know how many they used. But if I had to guess it was probably at least a dozen,
just because
it, it's not enough. It's not like the good old days where you just wrote an exploit.
Now you have to, you know,
you need information disclosure so you can figure out
what the addresses are you need to carry.
I mean,
it's conceivable you could do it with as few as four,
but I would be very surprised if it was only four.
Yeah.
So, I mean, this really makes me wonder about the whole, you know,
all these places that are, um,
I've been dealing with more and more places that
their security strategy essentially is we assume things are compromised
and assuming things are compromised, what can we do
to make it less? Terrible?
You know, for example, with logging and auditing or other, you know,
network protections or
whatever.
That's absolutely the right way to think about it because
I mean,
now an attack like this mind you is not something you're going to see every day,
-- but
-- what is the price for pool?
It was like 100 grand,
100 and five grand, something like that.
It was 100 and five grand. It was a weird number
for the big break out. I don't know if they, if all these chained together
to give them more than the 100 grand,
it
half a million
or
even, let's just say a million dollars,
right? Nice big round number. But a million dollars to say,
you know, be able to like, have some bank administrator just visit a web page and bam,
you know what I mean?
That's,
well,
so
in that context,
the correct solution is to make sure your bank administrator
can't do anything valuable.
Right.
The
problem is though, is that all these places, you know, they want to be able to like,
do their job and browse the web once in a while to look for tech documentation.
They
do. But, ok, let's back this up. There's,
there's two views I have here. View number one
is that
uh we're all doomed
and
we can't fix this.
This is if somebody wants to target you for some reason
they can and will be successful.
Ok?
Period,
there is nothing you can do
that will keep you safe if someone wants to get you.
That is the reality
of this. Now, moving past that though, let's use your example of a bank executive.
If, if one bank executive can be attacked
and money can be
infiltrated from the bank based off of this one executive,
you have banned security.
-- You
-- should need at
least
two
people.
It has because they had terrible security.
But also they have like the second person didn't
do their job properly and was just like,
oh, you know, Bob said transfer the money.
-- Okey doke.
-- Ok. And if that happens, that is a breakdown of your internal processes.
-- That
-- is
reminds me of all this code reviews.
Everybody's like, oh, we have code reviews, you know,
every single bit of code has to be like a two man commit.
And I'm like,
do these people actually read all these changes because they've also got like
their boss yelling at them to commit code and get stuff done.
I mean,
you know, to properly review code is a nontrivial exercise.
Cause like, look at all the, you know, uh,
every single time there's a Linux kernel flaw, it's like,
invariably like we added a feature
and whoops,
we added a feature 12 years ago.
Somebody just found the bug today.
Yeah. So,
you know, it's, it's,
well, ok, here's the deal.
If code commits, well, humans aren't lazy, humans suck at doing this kind of stuff.
Here's the way I would see code commits is
what is the job of a code commit?
Is it to catch security issues from getting in or
is it to catch egregious mistakes in obvious attacks?
I would say ideally it's to ensure the code commit is correct,
which would also
cover security.
That's like saying
no, ideally, no one's going to
security issues.
Ideally, you
know,
cows.
Uh, yeah. No, I would say with code commits.
Yeah, I mean, you're, you're trying to like, you know, insert function back door,
blah, blah, blah.
Right.
Exactly. Exactly. And, and so I think the right attitude to have
around that is to say
you need to be able to move fast.
Like, so for example, actually speaking of fast isn't the p to own
Mozilla got pawed and they fixed the issue in 22 hours.
That's awesome. Right.
Like that's the way it has to work is you have to be able to move quickly.
If you, if it's gonna take you 30 days to fix a critical issue,
you're doomed.
I mean,
and, and additionally,
if you're the consumer of this software and it's
gonna take you 30 days to install the issue,
you're not 60 days out.
That's terrible.
Well, especially your, your 30 days.
Like, because I remember, you know,
back in the day when Microsoft drew their patch Tuesday and we had a,
like I worked for a different company that had a smart guy
that would, you know, take bin
diff and all the DB G and one or two other
tools and usually within 12 hours he'd have a working exploit.
Yeah. Right.
You know,
and he's not the only guy in the world that can do that.
Yeah. Absolutely. Absolutely. And, and again, this comes back to move fast
and then that's really the only answer but
not only move fast is you have to remember if someone wants to get you, they will.
So what does that mean
around how you're designing your systems and processes?
Because
it basically, if you have single points of failure,
someone's just gonna attack your single point of failure.
They, they know it's what is it, is it, is it the CIA or the NSA who said
basically when they break into a network,
they just understand how it works better than you do. And that's how they win.
I mean, that,
that's exactly how it works.
Anytime you have an attacker that wants to
come after you is they're going to understand
what's going on better than you do. In fact, funny, funny we bring this up is
I had someone ask me, I think it was last week or the week before. Basically. Like,
what the hell do you, security guys do? I mean, how do you find these problems?
Like what's going on here?
And, and I started explaining about the fact that,
you know, there, there's a bunch of things to do and of course, I,
I lost them and I had to keep kind of backing up and making things more exciting.
But, you know, fundamentally it's
at the end of the day,
a security researcher is going to understand how an application
works better than the developers do in many instances.
And that's how they find the problems because they have this stuff in their head and
they can see the problems and they know how to think about it in that.
Let's do things the wrong way
because that's what we do.
Right.
Well, you know, that classic, uh, you know,
uh a security engineer walks into the bar and orders a beer
orders, negative one beers, orders, zero beers orders 7000,
492 billion beers orders, a
cri orders, a smiley emoji.
Yeah.
And I, I literally, I've stumbled onto bugs like, literally like that where, I mean,
well, that's my favorite was like, cross site scripting bugs where people just,
like, put,
you know, script alert, blah, blah,
blah into like all the text fields and eventually one of them like,
oh, pops an alert box.
Right. Right.
Honestly, almost every time I see a new website,
that's what I do is I just start pasting script things into various tech
because why not? It's something fun to do
and I can't help myself. It's well. And so, I mean, on that note
is I remember a million years ago,
I was working for a small company
and they were uh web washing. I don't even know you not cloud washing, you know, back.
But, but essentially they had this
application
adding a web like a website to it.
So you could use it as kind of a thin client sort of thing. And anyway,
I, they, they had
like the login box
and I just typed in SQL injection into the user name.
And of course it, it, you know, II, I got it all
and II I said you can't do this, don't
you?
You,
you cannot allow these characters and we need to filter it
and when you escape all this stuff and you know,
let's use prepared statements and all whatever, blah, blah, blah.
And I remember a developer looked at me and was like, why would anyone do this?
I had that exact same with my first
time explaining cross site scripting to a developer.
And I was like, he was like, why would anybody do this?
And I'm like, well, what if somebody links to the website with that stuff?
And I did this, I just did it like,
I am not even that smart, you know.
Yeah. Well, you know, it's like physical security, right?
You know, looking around the world and it's like, you know. Yeah.
Why would somebody throw a brick through that window? Well, why not?
No.
You know?
Oh, I know.
I
know.
The world is terrible.
It is. We ruin everything. Security people are the worst.
Speaking of terrible security people. Should we talk about wikileaks?
Yeah, I
see that.
I,
so I know they mean, well,
I think, I hope, I really hope they know.
I used to,
I,
if that's true.
Well, I, I think they're so far into their own little version of the world but maybe,
-- you know,
-- that, that could
be,
I don't quite understand their version of the world anymore.
Um,
and part of this too is like this whole thing.
I've actually somewhat recused myself from because I,
I'm not an American and I have traveled to the US.
And so, yeah, so the deal is this Vault Seven CIA Wikileaks thing where, you know,
supposedly all these
zero days slash, well, they're actually, apparently,
maybe not zero days and they're just known security flaws or blah, blah, blah.
But,
yeah, basically, as I understand it.
Wikileaks has put, uh, was, was supposedly going to tell all the, uh,
the vendors affected,
-- you know, so they could make sure they fix the stuff,
-- which is a good idea.
Yeah.
But then apparently they came up, they required some sort of like
-- terms of use essentially
-- it. Right.
And it sounds like their conditions are bizarre.
That seems to be
the theme that keeps coming up here is.
And these, and they're talking to people like Apple and Google and Microsoft.
This isn't like
Joe Bob's consultation and see that doesn't have a security team.
Like these guys wrote the book, they know what they're doing,
-- their
-- first rodeo for sure.
You know,
you remember. Oh jeez, what was it?
Uh back in the day,
the guys that wanted a monster truck and a million dollars for their exploit.
-- Oh jeez,
-- what was
it?
I don't remember that.
A
monster truck. That's fantastic.
A million dollars in a monster truck
for early notification to Microsoft and Microsoft,
of course, was like, yeah.
No.
Well, in so, in a case like that though, they obviously made it easy to say no. Right?
When you ask for a million dollars in a monster truck, you're clearly not serious,
right?
So, well, I mean, you know,
is that
different than a
-- bug bounty? What is back
-- orifice?
Kurt, we should explain this for the people who aren't old.
I'm actually gonna have to look it up.
I'll do
it.
I'm just trying to remember if it
was part of the problem is everything gets mixed up in my head.
I know. I know. So back orifice was put together.
It was the cult of the dead cow guys, I think, and,
and cult of dead cow.
That's a whole another topic for any of you who aren't, aren't as old as us.
I just look them up. They, they were a hacking group from back in the day and they were,
they were like my heroes way back when I was a kid. I love those guys.
They were,
it
wasn't even an exploit. It was just,
it was just, it was essentially a bit like I wouldn't even, I,
they call it ransomware. It was like spyware essentially.
-- No, it was
-- just like a metas
module.
That's it, it was just a, it was like any normal modern day, you know,
-- shell code you uh back door, you would insert,
-- right.
Yeah, it was a back door.
-- Although back in the day, these things were really rare and who fancy
-- they were.
And these guys basically made it consumable and
of course they called it back orifice and part
of the fun there was all these like legitimate
news sites were showing pictures of a back orifice
as their logo, which made it extra fun.
But yeah, it was, it was essentially these guys had found a nice way to take over and,
and kind of control a window system, which
wasn't something that was easy to do back then
and then.
Right.
Yeah, this is from,
so this is going back a long ways,
20 years.
That's like almost 20 years. Holy geez.
Yeah,
I got a lot
and, and now it was too
long.
I know. I know.
So, yeah, I mean, you know, it reminds me a lot of things essentially.
I think the big deal is, it was one of the, it was, like you said, it was the first one
-- to do this in a way that was easily, sort of consumable and usable and they
-- gave it away
for
free charge money for this. It was awesome.
So, it freaked everybody out, right, because everybody would now have this.
But, yeah, going back to the vault seven stuff. I mean, that's
the,
I mean, if we think Wikileaks, well, by definition,
supposedly the CIA has access to this and also, apparently Wikileaks has,
has access to this.
So, like,
you know, who else has access to this?
-- Right. I'm, I'm guessing any competent nation state could also have access
-- to this.
Yeah, maybe, I mean, it wouldn't surprise me and, and I think
here's whatever that doesn't matter
because first of all this is what the CIA does.
So, whatever, that's their job good for them.
Uh, Wikileaks got a hold of this somehow, which is of questionable value, whatever.
But now
they're trying to pretend they're the good guys who are you know,
sprinkling information
from down on high, from up on high, down on high, whatever.
And
they're making it difficult to work with them though.
And I, I don't know what the angle is to that. I, I don't
understand
also,
there's,
there's a couple of things I know about this that I can't talk about publicly.
But I'm also
the, the, the vendors they're actually talking to.
I,
I think I can state basically that those are probably not the only vendors
that are affected and it's interesting that they're not talking to all the vendors.
So I, yeah, I,
again, you know, I, I love that,
I hope that they have good intentions but
just the way they're executing this is like,
it leaves a lot to be desired.
I mean, the reality is a place like Google Apple or Microsoft. You just,
you know, you can email them the world's most horrible,
terrible security flaw.
And like, that's a normal Tuesday.
It's like,
you know,
like, like, you know, I, I've assigned 5000 CV S so people come to me with like,
what they think is a horrible security flaw and I'm like, eh, it's like a three,
maybe a four on a scale of 1 to 10
and even the stuff that's a 10.
It's like, yeah, you know, we should probably fix that.
I, I sadly know exactly what you mean.
Yeah.
So, you know, it's just like a part of it is just, you know, it's like house fires,
I'm sure if I ever experienced house fire,
I'll be terrified and I'm sure the fireman will be like.
Yeah.
Uh huh.
You know, cause it's what they do every day.
It's true.
It's funny how that is that when you have a job like that,
it totally changes your perspective where, what should be like a horrific event,
you're just totally desensitized to it.
I mean,
it's gonna be like when you're an, er,
room doctor in the inner city you probably see some of the most horrific things ever.
You want to see some of that. Um,
-- don't, you don't need, no, no, no, no,
-- no. Uh, the, so it's, it's, it's well done.
It's, um, it's a British series on the British Rail Cops
and of course,
one of the recurring themes is removing dead bodies from the
tracks because people commit suicide by jumping onto train tracks.
Right.
And so, you know, these, these rail people,
the deal is they have two hours to deal with this and get the body off the,
off the tracks and get the trains moving again.
Right.
And to determine if it's a suicide or if it's murder or an accident or whatever,
right.
They have like, basically two hours is their goal
because, you know, literally they have to get the trains moving again. Right.
You can't just like,
not have the trains going, you know, for a major commuter area
and just, and obviously they don't show the dead bodies and stuff, but, you know,
these people's reaction to it, of course, is, like,
you know, this one episode, they had to deal with it twice in one day,
you know.
And so obviously they have all sorts of, you know,
they like black humor and stuff to kind of, you know, try and deal with this without,
you know, breaking down and,
yeah, I mean, you know, like, I'm staring at this and I'm like, oh my God,
that's horrible.
And these poor people are like, yeah, they do this, like,
at least once a week kind of deal,
you know, that could be an interesting topic is
to talk to security people about how they kind of deal with the,
just the constant horrors of this work of every, everything's always hacked,
everything's always broken.
I mean,
let's face it.
If, if you're working on an infosec team of even a moderately sized company,
you probably have double digit machines that have been compromised, you know,
about and, and
you know, what,
what do you decide this one I'll really investigate and this one's like, yeah,
whatever.
Just wipe it reinstall. That's how it is.
Well, like the, you know, like the whole Yahoo thing where they, it was so bad that,
you know, when the,
when the chief security officer found out about what was going on,
-- you know, stuff was being kept from him right about the
-- uh
that's because they had a back door from the government. I mean,
it's totally different
man.
Like, I mean, what, what I'm saying though is like, is things, you know,
it's not just you gotta worry about these outside Attackers as a security person.
You also have to worry about like
potentially.
Now you have to worry about like,
your CEO doing a deal with the government behind your back.
-- Like,
-- yes, you
said,
you know, this is one of the reasons I decided early on in my career, I would never do
real operational security because it's just, it's,
it's just this constant train wreck.
It's really hard, man. When we say that it's, we, we have a constant train wreck too.
I mean,
product security is not a whole lot better, man.
It's just slightly less emergency on fire typically
usually. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. I don't know. It's, I mean, it's a tough one.
I mean, and II, I do know, for example, in the industry, like there's a lot of burnout.
Yeah. Yeah. I know. And I, I totally get it. And it, I don't know.
There's, there's days I wonder like, what, what have I done?
But it's all I know at this point and I've invested so much of my life into this.
It's like
this is, this is the train I'm on in
the end.
Well, and see, that's one thing that gets me is like developers,
at least when they ship a new product.
It's like, wow,
you shipped a new product that actually works and does something useful haza,
you know, with the security thing, it's like, I'm not even always 100% clear.
-- I'm like, what is our goal? Like,
-- obviously,
you know,
of life,
like, I mean, we can't, uh,
obviously a goal like having no hacks or no security issues.
Obviously that's, that's just not realistic.
So, actually this is something was I talking to you about this?
I forget who I was talking to about this. But
oh, no, it was you, we were, we were chatting on signal
and you, you mentioned that
small incremental changes add up over time.
And if let's say you have 5% improvement every year in 14 years,
you've essentially doubled whatever it is you're trying to improve.
Right.
And
because, oh, we were talking about
old desktops and there's people sitting at
desks with probably five year old desktops,
apologies to you listener if you're one of them.
But you know, for like literally what a couple of 100 bucks you could buy a
new desktop and, and maybe
double their productivity in some cases,
-- even
-- improve their productivity by 10 or 20%.
Right. Right.
So,
unless you're paying this person absolute minimum wage with
no overhead that'll pay for itself in one year.
Right. Right. And, and so anyway,
then
the question becomes, well, what about security?
How does security fit into a world view like this and
I don't think we're there yet.
I don't think we
have the tools or the know how in our industry
to be able to have even five or 10% improvement
per year because we don't even know what that means.
In some cases.
I, I would generally agree with you, but I would also caveat, for example,
uh we now have languages like that are not C and C++ when it comes to memory management
and, you know, it is a great first step.
And also we have things like,
you know, import of libraries that, you know, can very easily be updated,
you know, like no Js or, you know, NCM or Ruby Gems, right?
I don't know if those are the best examples,
-- but
-- at least you can get something up to date
pretty much the second,
-- you know, the, the library vendor or maintainer updates it.
-- I understand,
-- I know what you're talking about, but
-- when you consider like 20 years ago,
what it took to get up
to like, remember DLL Hell on Windows
and how like,
you know,
applications would ship their own old versions of DLL S and scatter them among,
you know, around the system.
They just don't put them in your system folder anymore.
I guess that's an improvement.
Seriously. It's, it's totally how it works.
Containers, man,
that's how containers work
well. Or the,
the existing fuff kerfuffle about Apple actually,
apparently now enforcing some of their sandbox and security
on various mobile apps and stuff.
And so there's that, what is it roll out dot IO,
which is this like framework for mobile apps to like
ship updates to them,
you know,
essentially outside of the operating system and outside of the Apple Store.
So that or you know, whatever Android store
so that the app itself can internally update.
And you know, Apple is basically saying, no, you can't do that.
Like you, you can't have self
modifying code that can do God knows what?
Because then obviously, you know, we can't
like even remotely begin to certify this code and say it's safe or not, right?
You know,
and so uh you know, because I know I've had kids,
my kids have a couple apps where like the first time I started them up,
it's like downloading like 89 megs of data.
And I'm like, what?
You know,
and um wasn't clear on what that was, was it images? Was it like the applications?
And so,
you know, these people are losing their minds because
uh Apple is essentially enforcing, you know,
you can't use these really unsafe library calls that can like self modify
the code and you have to use our sandbox and technologies and stuff.
So,
you know,
if Apple were to actually enforce that and then start kicking stuff out of the store,
we would have measurable progress
in that space, you know, that one specific instance, right?
Yeah,
I, you're not wrong and I think,
I guess you're right.
This is part of our incremental change is doing these little things.
But I think this is where security fails a lot is
we love to look for the perfect solution
instead of this one thing will make things a little better.
And if we keep making things a little better
1000 times now things are a lot better instead of looking for that one,
a lot better event.
Yeah.
Well,
and part of it too is we security traditionally
wants to fix things and fix it permanently somehow.
You know, and that's kind of not how the real world works in that. You know,
people have reinvented the wheel badly. A million times
and people will continue to do so with code. Right.
And I think that's where part of the whole Dev
ops security agile thing comes in where, you know, at
least now, you know,
in theory a shop doing like agile dev
ops
can fix bugs quickly, do a build quickly, test it or smoke, test it, test it and get
it out the door, you know, within
maybe days,
you know, whereas the old model, like,
say the waterfall model of software development would be like, yeah,
we'll schedule that in for like, you know, Tuesday in January of like 2055.
Yes.
Or,
or you treat security as a snowflake and
it's like you're constantly throwing the emergency stop switch
and, you know, the train is like piling up and back because
no one knows what's going on and, and it's,
you're not wrong.
I think that's a really good point. And I,
yeah,
-- it, it's,
-- I mean, I think part of it too is just these link.
Like here's the reality, being able to ship code faster and update code faster,
ignoring the security implications of that.
It gives you a competitive advantage
end of story.
So there's, there's an incentive to do that now, which is good,
you know,
um, things like encryption, you know, you kind of have to encrypt everything now,
otherwise I SPS will start monkeying with
traffic and inserting ads into your website.
They aren't generating revenue for you.
So the websites will want to start encrypting everything
because they want to protect their ad revenue.
Yeah.
Yeah. Right.
Well, and it, it affects the user experience if you have people kind of monkey.
Oh, and you remind me, you know, adding things in between is uh cert
just a note.
Was it last week a couple days ago? Maybe that uh
they believe that the like corporate uh TLS man in the middle devices,
the things that basically decrypt web traffic, inspect it,
re encrypt it and then ship it back to whoever's requesting it.
Uh
They may be
unsafe.
Well, and, and it's funny because I've been saying for a long time, you know,
if your security posture depends on you behaving like a hostile nation state,
which is essentially, you know, http s decryption and interception.
People like Google are like out to prevent that period
and even better, you know, TLS version 1.3 it's still in draft,
but fundamentally TLS 1.3 does perfect forward secrecy,
full stop.
So doing interception and decryption of
that traffic will become incredibly difficult,
-- if not
-- impossible, become impossible at all.
Because I mean,
we're talking about like corporate man in the middle
firewalls that have installed their cert on your system.
It's essentially
trust star.
So literally, any website
can
show
the
thing
is
like, for example, you know,
Google Chrome and stuff are doing certificate pinning.
-- Uh
-- they are, which is really good. And that,
of
course, and that's what I mean is essentially
for some subset of traffic, you know, for example,
if the website is doing certificate pinning and the web browser isn't,
you know,
um I know currently, for example, like web browsers are explicitly, you know,
being said to, you know, if you have a manually installed Shain
certificate, you know, it's OK to trust,
you know, but if it's like from the default trust store don't,
-- right?
-- But except
if you're in a corporate environment, you have to remember. I mean,
you and I have what, what do we call it? Like self service
workstations where we basically get to do whatever we want.
Like there are a lot of people that are literally handed a computer that is,
every bit of it has been configured by their IT department and in many instances, it,
it's not good.
They've made terrible mistakes like some of these.
Well, I shouldn't even say terrible.
I, I had a discussion with like an actual security guy.
It was an infosec person where they were very much operational focused
and
we were,
he thought that these HTTP S interceptors in a corporate environment
are a good thing because you can view the traffic.
And I'm like, this is a terrible thing.
Like, can you even tell me how your key is protected? And of course, he couldn't
and well, it creates a really massive single point of failure.
But here's the thing, right?
At some point, the web browsers,
you know, and by web browsers, I mean, like Chrome Firefox and
you know, whatever internet explorer is being called now
because really those, you know, and, and then the, you know,
and uh what is it Safari on the Apple devices?
And uh what the heck do Android devices run? I don't even know anyways.
OK. So Chrome,
so
we were down to four browsers.
Yeah.
Well,
basically we're down to four main browsers and at
some point these guys are gonna be like,
yeah, you know what we this this whole SSL interception thing,
it's more bad than good.
And they're gonna, you know, for example, maybe, you know,
have certificate pinning that doesn't allow you to
-- bypass it with this, you know, custom
-- cert,
there's gonna be ways around it.
And these,
these man in the middle vendors are
gonna have plugins that disable certificate pinning and
there's always gonna be something you can do. And it kind of reminds me of antivirus.
And in fact,
I antivirus, these, this stuff is,
is terribly written software and Tavis has just been ripping it up
and there's still tons of people who think, oh,
you need antivirus and it's like you're probably more at risk with it than without at
this.
Well, actually that,
that came up too with was how these antivirus vendors
are tying into the web browsers to do http S
traffic inspection and stuff.
And uh because there were some bugs in the Mozilla, you know,
uh in the like Firefox bug tracker talking
about what these vendors were doing and it,
it's horrifying like they basically like Rube Goldberg
the worst possible way they could
traffic. And
I mean,
this is not dissimilar, in my opinion of,
you know,
these systems are probably cobbled together with various
bits of pieces of string and sticks they found
and
just given the nature of this and the way you're talking these,
these large enterprises and it costs piles of money to
get this stuff that security researchers aren't looking at these.
Yeah,
it's,
it's horrifying man.
Um If you, you know,
so one of the classic metrics of how secure is this
code is how much are people willing to pay for,
you know, security, like vulnerabilities in the code?
Right.
And honestly, like for some security firms that buy vulnerabilities,
they just won't even bother buying flaws in certain, you know,
products because there's just so many flaws.
And I do, I do remember there was a couple of antivirus,
uh corporate solutions where they were just like, yeah, no, we,
we just don't care anymore.
Like
some I remember
or there was like that backup solution where the
guy went through and found like 100 vulnerabilities.
And then the,
you know, the company buying these flaws was just like,
OK, we're done like,
yeah, that's it. We, we don't care about this product anymore.
It's just so terrible. All we can say is don't use it,
right. You know,
and that's,
I
mean,
but it's tough because apparently there are in some,
in some industries,
there's regulations that they have to be able
to inspect the traffic on their network.
So you, it's like the whole PC I compliance thing where it's like,
you know, PC I compliance says we have to have an antivirus scanner on every server.
Well, but you know, this is a database server running UNIX,
what
C
A
V
solves
it does.
But
I
mean,
you know, with these cases where like to be
essentially to obey the law, I have to do something stupid
or,
you know, I get the spirit of the law was one thing, but unfortunately, you know,
the auditors aren't going to,
you know, they're not going to go with the spirit of the law.
They're gonna go with like what it says,
you know.
Yes,
it
like to get an exception is gonna be
-- a lot harder than just buying an antivirus
-- program
on this. And, well, and this is gonna be one of the challenges is,
there's a lot of infosec people who think
they need antivirus for a variety of reasons.
And in fact, one of the people I, I brought this up with someone and like,
they didn't know who Tavis was or what he was doing,
-- which is why,
-- why would you, was he an antivirus guy or a
security guy? Infosec
just random
infosec and he
doesn't know who Tavis is,
but here's the deal, man. I mean, not everyone does. Sorry Tavis,
but it, I get it,
there's so much going on in the universe.
And in fact, I, I had someone asked me at one point, you know,
do you know this security guy?
And I'm like, I don't know if you heard of this person and like, oh, I really like him.
I'm like, great, you know, there's like
thousands of them. I wish I knew them all.
-- But I don't,
-- the thing I always keep in mind is, you know,
the majority of these people have like a solid,
more than 40 hours a week of just putting out forest fires.
Yeah. Right. They don't have time to necessarily
deal with or just to learn in many cases to
read Twitter for an hour
and see what Tavis is up to. You know. Like,
that's my sad excuse of an evening.
Yeah.
So, no, it's, I get it, but at the same time, yeah, it, it's,
that's one thing that's always gotten me about infosec is, you know, we,
we are actually quite terrible at disseminating information internally.
Like, how many web developers have you run into that? Have never heard of? Oap.
-- I bet there's probably
-- 90%
I
would say, probably 90%.
Yeah. And they should
know the open web application security project, I think is what that stands for.
I don't even
know
they've been around for like, 10 years at this
more than that. I bet more than that.
So,
I mean, yeah, it's, I, you know, that's the thing, like, it's
things like uh new languages have definitely, you know, gotten out.
I mean, and I,
you look at some of these uh language communities and they do an amazing
job of educating people about their languages and what they can and cannot do.
You know, and, and then these languages rise, you know,
up for a variety of re like javascript.
Right? Clearly that thing is, you know,
it's, it's doing well, you know,
um,
you know, and they've got amazing resources, amazing,
teaching amazing code libraries, right.
But then you start looking at the security side of it and it's like,
uh,
you know,
yes.
Anyway, anyway, we're,
uh,
we're not gonna solve this today.
This is, this is one of the problems though, is how do you decide what is,
or isn't correct?
And even things like antivirus don't have obvious answers necessarily. Like,
in my instance,
I know Tavis, I know how smart he is.
So I'm inclined to trust him, but there's a lot of people who don't.
And so why should they listen to this guy?
It's, it's tough, man. I mean,
there aren't always good answers and I guess this is kind of
where things like regulation and compliance are meant to be the leveler,
but even those are, are so far behind in some cases
it, it's,
and they're not universal, right? I mean,
so what if one company has great, you know, regulation and compliance,
if the companies don't like it,
they'll just move operations offshore or outsource them
if, you know, it becomes too costly or too much of a pain. Right. Exactly.
You know,
um,
the one thing I'm hoping to do is, you know, add transparency and data so that,
you know, you can make an informed decision.
Like, so that, for example, with CV ES,
we'll have more information about who found this, who
helped patch it, who helped whatever, right?
And thus you'll be able to be like, you know,
you'll look up Tavis arm and then you'll be like, oh, wow.
You know, this guy's got a big pile of high quality CV S and products I care about.
Therefore, you know, maybe I should listen to him.
Yeah. You know,
maybe we recently had a case where this guy posted some, you know, it was a colonel CV.
And it was like,
who is this guy? Right. And, like, his information doesn't seem quite right.
And I, I, you know, Google stalked him a bit and I'm like, well, he
sort of seems legit, but I've never really heard of this person or their work.
So, and I don't know.
Yeah,
I don't know, man. I don't know. All right. Anyway, let's, let's bring it home.
We're not gonna solve this today.
Anyway. Thank you everyone for listening. Thank you, Kurt for the conversation.
If you want to see any of the show notes or any
of the links to any of the crazy things we talk about.
You can go to open source security podcast.com.
We have links there to Twitter and a Facebook group.
You are welcome to join and chat with us
if you are horrified by any of the legal advice we did not give today.
Uh Please, by all means, let me know.
I'm happy to correct myself in future episodes because I am not a lawyer
and please for the love of God, don't take anything. We talk about
legal advice under any circumstances.
Uh Well, of course, keep an eye on this, this, uh, case though,
with the contempt of court to see what happens and if anything exciting goes on,
we'll, we'll surely speak of it.
But,
yeah, I guess if nothing else, Kurt, you have a fabulous day.
Thank you for listening. Everybody.
And until next time, folks,
yeah, I guess, uh, I guess the,
the important note is write your passwords down somewhere safe,
so you don't end up in jail forever.
-- That's right.
-- Keep them under your keyboard. I take a note.
All right.
We'll get to probably password managers next week because
Tavis is tearing those up right now too.
So
he just ripped a big hole in the last time.
It's only
code execution.
We're all doomed. Kurt, we're all doomed.
All right. Thanks, folks. Have a good one. Bye bye.