Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 133 with myself,
Kurt Siefried
and my partner in Thought crime. Josh Bresser, man.
It feels like the world is more on fire than usual right now,
which is pretty bad because it's generally pretty on fire.
Yeah, I mean, it's,
there's even stuff that we won't talk about because of the political side of it now.
Right? Like the world, the world burns all of it.
It's pretty much getting nonstop radio on the news radio here.
Although our news radio is CBC,
-- which is quite boring and respectable
-- versus it should be boring and respectable.
I don't want exciting news radio because that means either something
terrible is happening or more likely
it's just a bunch of annoying idiots yelling at each other.
Speaking of annoying idiots yelling at each other.
Welcome to the podcast, everybody.
Yeah.
Well,
so it's interesting because we were going to start this
one with that whole piece about the Japanese government scanning.
I don't know what word to use exactly their network
networks within Japan
IP blocks registered to Japanese companies
or not so much Japanese companies, but Japanese network providers.
And it's not like they were, you know, using zero days.
They, they literally were going to take a list of known
default passwords for devices and, you know,
see if they were, had been changed or not
and then something came up on Twitter, which I found quite horrifying.
I'm going to leave her name out of it,
-- but it's not hard to find,
-- everyone knows who Leslie Carr
-- is. Hacks for pancakes. You don't need to leave her name out of it.
-- Ok. Well,
so,
and apparently this is happening to a lot of people, not just her,
but I guess she's the first one to kind of really not be ok with it.
So the premise is basically she lives, it sounds like in an apartment building
and when you live in an apartment building,
you don't
have as much control over the building and stuff in general as maybe you'd like.
You know, for example,
I know a lot of us apartment buildings will
sign an exclusivity agreement with a network provider,
like say Comcast or Verizon.
-- And that's your only choice as
-- opposed to me living in a house where I have
one choice. Yeah, in my neighborhood.
Yeah. So basically it sounds like this com
this, the company that owns the apartment building
is essentially changing all the locks
which, ok, that's
kind of abnormal because that costs quite a bit of money,
but they're going with smart locks. What's interesting to me.
Well, there's two sort of main aspects of this.
Number one, normally when you replace a mechanical lock,
then you give the person a key and that's it.
There's no sort of additional cost to them or ongoing
maintenance or ongoing fees to keep that mechanical lock working.
And that's not the case with smart locks with a smart lock,
it needs to be able to talk to the internet.
Right.
And number two is the the safety and security aspect of it.
I've been looking into smart locks from my house
and to be blunt,
I have not found one that will reliably unlock and let
me in every single lock I've researched has had incidents,
shall we say where for example, glitch in Yale, smart lock security, uh
Yale smart security system sees Brits locked out of homes.
Now, I live in a house.
So I have a front door and a back door and,
and part of my plan was I was going to put a smart lock
on the front door and leave the mechanical lock on the back door so that
if I come home and the smart lock is not working or the internet's out or whatever,
I can go to the back door, use the mechanical key to get in.
And that's wonderful if you live in a house with two doors.
But typically when you live in an apartment,
I'm not really aware of any apartments that I've ever seen with two doors,
you know, to
both doors to the same hallway.
So
the second thing here is, you know, is this lock actually safe?
Is it reliable enough?
-- All right,
-- I'm gonna interrupt you for a minute because you,
if you already have a key for your backup back door,
like why even have the freaking smart lock,
then isn't the whole point to not have any keys?
-- For
-- example, I could allow my cleaner in
when I'm not at home.
That's fair. Ok. I mean, that, that's a good reason. Right.
I could allow my cleaner in or my kids could use their phone
instead of a key point being is the mechanical locks I've had,
I've only ever had a mechanical lock once, fail to let me in my house.
And that was because somebody tried to open it with
a screwdriver and just beat the bejesus out of it.
Right.
You know, like it was pretty clear when I looked at the key way.
It's like, oh, it's all mangled and there's scratch marks and it's,
it's kind of bigger now.
It's about the size of a screwdriver.
Whereas with these smart locks, you Google it, they're,
they're terrible and that's assuming that the apps even work.
Right.
You go in the app store and look at the reviews of these apps and, and their garbage.
Um, we stayed at an airbnb
and it was an ordeal to get this smart lock to, you know, we had to, like,
we had to download an app, we had to get it registered.
We have to get the key,
the key to work.
And it,
there were times where it would take us upwards of five minutes
after we left the apartment to get the door to lock,
it just did not want to lock.
They didn't have just like a lock thing. You could twist on the outside to lock it.
-- No,
-- the
-- whole
-- point was just a smart lock.
I mean, that, that's just dumb.
Well, a lot of these smart locks were not well made or designed.
They're, they're dumb, they're all dumb.
And I'm just gonna say that we, we're at a point where the,
the people making these things clearly don't know what the heck they're doing.
-- And it's very
-- sad but they don't need to because people keep buying them.
-- I, I guess
-- I, like, look at the lock picking lawyer that, that biometric,
uh smart lock. Where, what was it? If you unscrewed it, you could just open it
like the lock itself wasn't really physically secure.
-- Uh
-- It had, you had to take off one screw on, I think it was on the back and then
you basically had unfettered access.
It was supposed to be a padlock that unlocked with the fingerprint and it sucked.
And the company's response is, oh, well,
bad guys typically don't have screwdrivers.
-- Like what? No,
-- what they, they all have screwdrivers.
I don't know, I, I guess here's my take on this. Right.
And, and I'll make it short and sweet.
We have automatic locks on automobiles. We have for a long time.
They also have manual locks on automobiles and they have pretty much,
I think since day one because not having one is dumb.
Right.
Carmakers know this,
I have a suspicion that the carmakers are also
somewhat controlled by the Department of Transportation or somebody
because they can't sneeze without having to fill up paperwork and,
and that's a good thing, right?
I have no problem with that. I,
I don't think the home lock market
is controlled by anyone really.
I imagine there are insurance companies that will say,
what kind of locks do you have?
And if you say I have a lock made by Hasbro, the toy company,
they will say you're gonna have to fix that.
But I mean, fundamentally, yeah,
these things suck and you know how you're going to get them fixed is
the insurance company just need to show up and say like this lock sucks,
get it off your door now.
And because I, I don't see another way and these lock companies, like you said,
if people are buying them, they're gonna make them right.
We're basically building
out a very
sickly ecosystem of internet of things, devices. You know,
these devices. This is and assuming for a moment these devices will even get
software updates, which a lot of them won't.
And even the, you know, quote unquote air quotes, good ones from, you know,
large American brands like Yale Lock or Quick Set or
Mode
o or whatever. Right.
You know, these are not tech companies, uh,
you and I both know and a lot of people listening to our show will know,
maintaining a piece of software and shipping updates to it is difficult
and making sure you don't break somebody's front door lock
is hard and, and that has happened where, you know, software updates have bricked
a percent or two of the smart lock population for a given vendor.
-- Every
-- software update is going to
deactivate some low percentage of devices just because there's,
there's a million reasons why.
And I'm going to point you at De
Bold as the poster child for companies struggling
to switch kind of what they're doing now,
for those of you, I know de
bold anyone in, in security, like you say the word
Deol and they, they start frothing at the mouth and go into a rage and that's ok.
But like so historically speaking at
my bank,
the the lock of the the safe safe deposit box I have
is made by De
Bold, right? Like they make most of them and they do a nice job. It's a very nice box.
The ATM outside is probably made by De
Bold. Again, they do a nice job
and
I have a feeling the company just thought voting
machines that can't be any harder than an ATM
guess what guys it is.
And, and I imagine these lock makers are the same deal like locks.
We know how to make locks.
We'll just like, put a raspberry pie inside of it and, and plug it in or whatever.
I don't know. Just make it work.
Yeah. And it's like, yeah, those are two really different skill sets.
Well, I mean,
your car lock analogy was a great example
because most of them use various radio technologies
that are actually quite trivial to intercept and
hack with about 60 bucks worth of electronics.
-- Uh,
-- yeah. And it's just having SDRS were hard to get before
and,
-- and I know some of them have gotten a little better
-- software to
find radios for those of you that don't know what an SDR is.
That's true.
-- That's true. I, I just assume everyone
-- does. I had to think about it for a moment.
-- Yeah.
-- They're like 20 bucks go get one they're fun to play with.
Yeah. So
this, this
Japanese government,
uh project which apparently starts in a month or two so, quite soon
where they're going to, at least,
I mean, at a minimum if you have devices on the internet. Yeah.
Change the default password that allows you to control them.
That, that's a minimal start
except the people who need to hear that message
are not going to listen to this podcast.
But
then my second thought was Ok.
So they scan the, they scan the Japanese portion of the internet,
they find all these devices that are, you know, insecure that.
What, what's step two? Right.
We've talked about this before with the law of large numbers.
Like, do you hunt them all down and tell them
to fix it?
Do you, do you block their network access?
So, from what I've read,
they're going to try to contact the device owners.
Now, I don't exactly know what that means and
I haven't actually found and I don't read Japanese.
So everything I'm reading is either come through Google translate,
which I'm sure is doing a bang up job
or I'm reading American
authors that have written news stories which again,
probably got their info from Google translate.
And so
I have a suspicion, there's a lot of things we don't understand.
But from everything I've read,
there seems to be a consistent message of humans are
going to look at this stuff which obviously humans don't scale
and then they're going to try to contact the owners of
the devices and the devices could be owned by people,
they could be owned by corporations, it could be owned by I SPS.
Like, it doesn't matter who owns it,
they're going to try to get a hold of them. And then
I don't know what step two is because it's like high,
high old person who can barely use the phone,
you have to change the password on your router.
Good luck.
And this isn't a social engineering attack.
Right. Exactly.
That's right.
And, uh, if you could send me some itunes gift cards, that would be great.
Yeah, because we've been through this before with old D MC, a takedown thing where,
you know, record companies and whatnot would
contact the I SPS and the IP S would send
nasty letters to people based on their IP address.
And
that
works except for all the cases where it didn't work where the
wrong IP was attached to the wrong person or the person's like,
oh, I have an open wi fi point.
Sorry, I have no idea what you're talking about.
Uh, I don't know what the deal in Japan is with, for example, open Wi Fi access points.
Hopefully it's not that bad anywhere in the world now. But,
yeah, fundamentally
given an IP address, tell me who I need to talk to,
to get the thing that's doing that fixed.
-- Yeah, that's a nontrivial problem.
-- Well, ok, let's ignore that problem. Right.
Let's back it all the way up to the beginning.
Is it ethical to essentially hack into someone's stuff? Because let's face,
even if it didn't change a password, it's still,
well, are they hacking it or they just, they're testing the password?
They're not necessarily changing anything. A court.
Well, at least from the US perspective,
if I log into your device with default credentials, I'm hacking it.
Right. And I have a suspicion.
Nearly every legal jurisdiction on the planet agrees with that.
So, fundamentally they're hacking. Is it ethical to do what they're doing?
Two arguments? I would have number one and I hate to use this argument.
It's kind of the, what about is argument is, well, effectively,
the bad guys are already doing this.
If the good guys do this, then potentially, maybe some good can come of it
and we can make the situation better.
-- And now we're at the ends justify the means philosophical argument.
-- Exactly.
And, and that's a, that's a, that's a very slippery slope.
It's not a slippery slip dude. It's like a drop off the face he had,
yeah,
I remember um,
the, the University of Washington guy that used to deal with the
of service attacks a lot. I apologize for not remembering your name.
But
people were asking him like, oh, these machines that are just spamming all packets,
why not just turn off the network access?
And he's like, because it might be an MRI scanning a patient.
It was a teaching hospital in a university and whatnot.
You know, we just can't turn off internet to that thing and maybe kill somebody
that would be bad.
Tm. Right. Yeah. Exactly.
So, I, I don't know, I mean,
the reality is, this is such a low level of hacking.
I mean, this is literally reading the manual,
like I've literally had to do this where I've reset a
network device like my PF sense firewall back when I had it
and I reset it and then I was like, what is the login? I have no idea.
So I had to like Google,
you know, PF sense default password. And I'm like, oh, it's, it's admin PF sense. Ok.
That makes sense. Type that in, I'm in, ok, reset it. Great.
I'm just, I'm not sure much good will come of this. That's kind of,
that's the second part of the argument, right?
Is in theory some good can come of this, but I'm not
sure any good will come of this. And
-- mostly because of scale,
-- I
-- think
-- good will come of it.
And the reason I think that though is convoluted and bizarre.
So
I would, I would compare this to
Leslie's Locke story in
regards of both of those are early adopter situations where the the people
implementing these smart locks are early adopters
and what they're getting is garbage.
And unfortunately,
a nontrivial number of people deploying them don't realize their garbage.
Well, no,
I think a lot of them do realize their
garbage and they don't care because for example,
the apartment company,
honestly, I've lived in apartments, run by big apartment companies.
They don't really care about their renters beyond getting the check on time.
That that could be too.
I mean, I, I don't know the answer to that but,
but let's assume that let's assume that the apartment company knows it's garbage.
Right? Does, it doesn't change the story. Now,
we look at the Japanese government,
what they're doing is going to suck. It isn't going to work.
But
what they're, they're going to gain knowledge they need
for,
we'll say acceptable change in the future.
One of the things we fail to understand in security a lot of times is
the, the pioneers get the arrows
and I don't mean that figuratively that's like,
quite literal is the first people to do things.
They usually have a bad time,
but they're the ones that are paving the way for the rest of us.
And now I'm not going to use that as a justification for say,
putting smart locks in someone's apartment because I, I don't like that.
And like, I know if you read,
we'll link to Leslie's Twitter feed,
but basically she's moving and I don't blame her either because
it's like I would not want to live like that.
This is one of the reasons I won't live in an apartment or even a condo anymore is
II, I want to have a certain level of control over my living space.
For example, the locks, the security of the building.
I don't know, man, I'm sick of fixing things.
Apartment sound pretty good to me right now.
That's because you moved into like a money whole house.
-- Money pit.
-- We call that
money
pit. And
I think calling this a money pit is doing a disservice to money pits.
But yes,
anyway, anyway, right from my perspective, like,
yeah, whatever. Give me, give me smart locks, you know, leave the windows open.
I don't care, just as long as I'm not paying for things.
Yeah.
-- But
-- she's moving because real and, but the problem is, I mean,
straight up unless she buys a house, this is a risk and II,
I suspect this will become more and more common.
Probably so.
Yeah, it's a, it's an ugly problem and an ugly situation.
Uh, right.
So anyway, let's focus on, on the Japanese story because I think that's depressing.
So,
so we can say that there,
it's ethically questionable to be doing what they're doing right
now. The second part of it that I, I latched on to when I read it is
there, there seemed to be a stress on humans doing it
and I don't know if that's just a weird translation problem or if that is
one of the things they're focusing on because I can see that in two ways.
Right. There's a number one,
you could say humans are doing it. We're not automating it.
So we hopefully won't crash anything because obviously if you just like,
set some bots for doing this, it's gonna be crazy town.
Right?
Because obviously a bot can scan the whole I PV four space in what,
like an hour or something now.
-- It's
-- crazy. It's about 15 minutes now.
Right. That's
exactly actually funny story.
I'll tell you is I was recently talking to someone about showdown
and explaining what it does.
And they said, well, how, how long does it take him to scan all of the internet?
I said a couple hours probably they're like, what? Like they couldn't fathom.
Well, and, and the thing to remember is they do it a coup.
Like, I think they do it weekly or more.
-- I bet
-- it's kind,
it,
it
is. Well, no, the date is up to date.
Like II, I used to buy access to it just for, to see what was out there.
And it was, it was quite shocking.
-- Right.
-- Right. So, so anyway, anyway, uh
Japanese scanning the internet, humans are doing it. Humans don't scale
and
my suspicion
is what they're going to do with this is they're going to let people do it,
they're going to collect a whole bunch of data
and then they can make some,
we'll say informed decisions about what to do next.
And I think this will tie into the ethical argument at the beginning of
maybe it would be ok to say
this group who is sanctioned by the Japanese government
has permission to look for these kind of devices.
But then what's next?
Because obviously, ok, so you tell people to take them off the internet,
I bet less than 10% are going to be
taken off the internet or have the passwords changed.
And I think that might be a high estimate.
So in a couple of years are, you're going to say if we find your device,
we're just gonna shut you off.
Right.
Well, what does that mean? Right.
What happens when it's, like you said, if it's hooked up to, you know,
somebody's smart lock, they need to get into their house and it's, I don't know,
-- cold outside or whatever,
-- or even more simply an IP address typically at home now
is matted.
Right.
You know, when I think about how many network connected devices are in my house now,
it's about 40 or 50.
And, you know, I only have one IP address
actually, that's not true. I think my I PV six is actually real. I PV six.
I have to check into that.
I don't think it's an adding,
I think it's actually proper IP S but regardless you start shutting stuff down,
you're not just shutting down the IP of one device.
You're probably going to be shutting down the IP of a house or an entire building.
Right. So I just pulled up my uh I have, I have a Google Wifi
and it says it sees 19 devices on my network at this
moment and I know it should be much higher than that.
So a bunch must have turned themselves off, which is, which is fine.
-- Uh
-- Oh, mine says zero devices. Oh, it's
quite,
-- you might want to fix that.
-- 0, 26. Here we go. 96.
See, that's what gets me is if we could actually properly
determine this IP address who to talk to, to get it fixed. Sure
that, you know, do that easily.
Maybe what action do we take that is both safe and effective.
And I can't think of any action that is safe and effective.
That doesn't suffer from some like 10% chance of really doing a lot of damage,
like just turning off network access or, but I think having data might be good
in the sense of then maybe, you know,
-- which manufacturers to go after and you say look, you have, I,
-- I think data is key.
Like that's just, even though I don't think this is going to make any
real difference in any way, I think they're going to learn a lot from it,
which is why I totally approve of this
even though there are moral and ethical and all kinds of other questions here.
-- I, I think it's a good idea. Well,
-- so, I mean, we have similar things here in winter
where you're not allowed to leave your car running with the keys in it.
I think there's actually specific laws against that in
most jurisdictions because it's kind of dangerous because,
you know, it's really easy to steal a car that's running and unlocked,
right?
And so the cops will occasionally go around
ticketing people for doing this and what they'll
also do sometimes is just try to open your car door and if it's unlocked,
they'll kind of leave you a warning note like this
is for cars that are not running but just unlocked.
Right?
And they'll leave you kind of not a ticket, but like a warning note saying, you know,
we find your cars unlocked.
You, please lock your car because
people keep complaining to us about their cars being broken into.
Well, now here's my question for you
and I'm going to, this is a, a huge leaking of sensitive information on my part.
But
in the winter, I don't lock my truck door because the locks freeze.
So
yeah, for real, like, like they freeze constantly there for whatever reason.
Like when Ford built this truck, now, mind you as well.
I don't drive it very often because I work from
home and I feel like selling it would be a disservice
to the environment because somebody who owns it might drive it
and the thing like consumes gas at an alarming rate.
But anyway, anyway,
I don't lock it because like literally the lock is frozen
shut for nearly all of the winter and it doesn't work.
And,
and so like this is an instance where the police would give me a note and I'd be like,
I'm not locking my door.
Like when I lock my door, I can't get in the last time I got locked out. I had to, like,
I went and got a hair dryer to melt the front
lock. Like
-- I don't, I don't
-- care. They actually make these special electric heater things.
It looks like a key and it's got like an electric wire running through it.
So it gets hot. So you stick it in the key lock in the lock and it warms the lock up.
They're battery powered.
-- You might want to get one of those
-- or I could just not lock my door, which is way easier.
Well, so the reality is there will always be some corner cases.
For example, if everybody that can reasonably lock their doors does. So
then, well, it's not gonna help crime.
I mean, recently in my neighborhood we had a couple of car break ins
and they actually broke into my neighbor's car and tried,
like they broke the window and tried to hotwire and luckily they couldn't.
But, you know, if they left the car door open,
maybe they would have had a bit more time and been felt a
bit more safe and they would have spent more time hot wiring it.
Right.
That's actually a joke I have too with my kids is I don't lock my doors,
so no one will break my window trying to steal the nothing I keep inside of the car.
No, I think we definitely need more data and I think
at some point
I'm hoping we'll see regulations that say things like for
this device to go on the network and fully activate.
It needs to be securely set up.
So I've had,
I've seen a number of devices now where you basically turn them on and
they have very minimal limited functionality and until you actually log in and,
and configure them securely,
they, they don't do whatever it is they're supposed to be doing. Right.
So until, for example, you set a secure password,
the device, like, for example, it's a light bulb, like it won't turn
on and off until you set a password on it securely
or you register it or whatever, you know.
And I think things like that
are the solution because
you make these things be secure by default and only
work if they're securely deployed and that solves the problem,
right?
Because if we're relying on everybody buying these
things to take some action to secure them
that will fail a certain percentage of the time
and by a certain percentage of the time,
I'm guessing somewhere between 20
-- 80%
-- I bet 8080 or more
was the number I had in my brain.
-- Yeah,
-- it's, I, I wouldn't be uncomfortable with that either.
Uh Let's go with between 20
95%
-- right? Because humans are bad at technology
-- and more the
point how do, how do I securely deploy this stuff too? Is that in the manual?
-- Probably
-- not.
No, you,
you can't expect people to do anything because even the smart people screw it up.
And so expecting normal people to get it right. Even 20% of the time. It's probably
in
acceptably high bar.
Well, and a software update might mess something up in reset settings.
We've had, you know, remember for example, II, I
had, hey Siri disabled on my phone. Remember that one time?
And then I said, hey Siri and my friend was like, yeah, what do you want?
I'm like, I what, you know, and I found out software updates, disable that.
-- So it's
-- really weird and it's annoying me to no end is on my android phone.
It keeps disabling like the hey Google
and like, oh crap, my phone just did stuff. Um
No way.
Oh,
that's good.
I I've been meaning to record that myself saying it to
see like if I could unlock my phone doing it.
So I'm gonna actually process the podcast,
put it up and then suck the audio out and see.
Uh my phone does not unlock when I say the
words.
But if, if it's unlocked and obviously like, if I'm driving the car,
I need to send a text message to my wife.
Like it's a lifesaver there because I'm, I'm like crazy anti texting in the car.
I yell at people if they're driving, I'm like, no, like I will drive,
get out of the freaking driver's seat or put your stupid phone down
-- because I,
-- yeah,
but it's pretty crazy dangerous. It's like half of all collisions. Now.
-- It
-- not only that man you, like,
you look at people and they're just staring at their phone.
It's like there's a red effing light, like, come on
-- and they have no idea. It's, uh, it's terrifying. I hate
-- that.
Wait, aren't you supposed to be stopped at a red light?
Now, if you're looking at your phone, it's fine then just keep going. No big deal.
Anyway. Anyway. Anyway.
So. Right. I,
I, like I said, I think
what the Japanese are doing
while I'm sure will be a disaster for multiple reasons.
It's actually going to be really funny when they break into like, uh, you know,
a Norwegian government server or something accidentally and
there's some sort of crazy diplomatic incident.
Oh, there's a good point. Right.
Because all the embassies would be in Japan on Japanese networks most likely.
-- And
-- even if they're not, man,
how many there's IP addresses that you think should be somewhere that aren't
-- right. Like, that's super common actually,
-- you know what Japan could,
in theory, Japan, they're an island nation.
They could check the latency to the IP and say, for example,
we're only going to do IP S that are within
the latency of not going through the undersea cables,
just have to add latency to my network and then the Japanese government can't find it
exactly because they think it's offshore.
I'm just saying like there are ways to make it
reasonably safe and to make a good faith effort,
but more to the point.
If you have devices that are exposed to the internet and are this fragile,
-- they're gonna get popped at some point anyways
-- probably.
And that's,
well, yes and no,
I think they will and many of them maybe have.
How sad would you feel for me if I left my wallet out
on the street instead of bringing it into the office with me.
Like if I literally went to work every morning and put my wallet on
a park bench in front of the building and then came out at lunchtime,
picked up my wallet, went and bought lunch,
put it back on the bench, went up to my office.
And then when I went home, I went out, took my wallet off the bench.
That's not a reasonable comparison though because you know, better.
Well, how is putting a device on,
you know, the internet full of every state actor any different?
-- And most people don't know better. I guess I'm not saying it's
-- right.
It's, and to be clear, I'm not trying to blame the victim here.
I'm just saying realistically, like, for example,
even though I typically have the right of way
when I cross the street at the pedestrian crosswalk,
I still look both ways.
-- I hear
-- you, man. I don't know. Like I said, I think this is going to be a mess,
but I applaud them for doing it because I
think they're going to learn a lot of crazy things
and my hope is it just doesn't start like World War Three because they scan
the wrong country, something
and then, and then broke into it.
Uh,
so anyway, yeah, I, I don't know.
We'll see, I guess, and, and I guess on, in terms of smart locks, II, I have no doubt
there will be a time in the future
when smart locks are acceptably safe.
-- But it is not here yet. Cars
-- became acceptably safe.
-- I mean, it took Ralph Nader in the sixties and seventies.
-- It took
what,
100 years almost to make cars safe.
Yeah.
So we got what? 80 years to go everybody?
Woohoo.
Oh man, I, I think about that actually, that's something
I forget why we, oh no,
I was talking to my wife about Netflix and Amazon Prime and all those things and,
and actually, if you've never seen it, the show,
uh the Marvelous Mrs Maisel and on Prime video is fantastic.
I highly recommend it,
which is what we're watching and it's in like four K and it looks amazing and it,
it consumes an enormous amount of bandwidth.
My bandwidth graph is, is hilarious right now. But anyway, we're talking and like
you think 20 years ago,
if you would have told people about the
streaming services and all the things we have,
I'd have been like
no way, no way.
Oh, I remember what streaming video looked like 20 years ago. It was a postage stamp.
Yeah, right. It was like 100 by 100
it was super grainy and it was like one frame a second. Exactly.
And my hope though is that all of this iot garbage
the mess were in
the unsecured devices, all of it
in 20 years. We look back and think those were leeches and bloodletting.
I think the, the problem though is, is with streaming services,
you have to keep people happy because they pay a monthly fee.
Nobody wants to pay a monthly fee with their
locks because the mental getting over the mental hurdle
of why do I have to pay $10 a month to unlock and lock my front door,
you know,
ring doorbell and all these nest cameras and stuff have
the same problem where I have a security camera.
Why do I have to pay a monthly fee?
Oh, so you store the data for one year and make it easy? Ok. Well, maybe I'll do that but
no offense if you're going to sell me a door lock and you want a monthly fee out of me,
-- it's gonna take a lot of convincing. And
-- that is a perfectly reasonable
argument
and it is possible we never solve that and we just always have door locks.
I, I guess the, the comparison perhaps is
I love watching Star Trek when they have their crazy futuristic glasses they use
yet. Yeah. Pint glass is a pint glass man and it's been a pint glass for 100 years.
Right. And I, I have a suspicion in 100 more years.
We're still gonna be using pint glasses. You know why?
Because it works, they hold beer, right. Which is super important
anyway. Anyway.
All right, man, I'm going to call this one. I feel like
I, we've answered nothing.
We've, we've brought up a bunch of crazy, philosophical and strange arguments
and I guess that's ok because I think much
like my suspicion about the Japanese government just discussing
these things and thinking about them and revisiting the
topics on a regular basis is very important because
answers to questions like this are not simple.
It's kind of like you, you imagine in the days of your, when philosophers and,
and even scientists to a degree would just sit around and
talk about hard problems like that's how you solve hard problems.
You don't solve them by whining and complaining
on Twitter about how dumb everyone else is.
It's, it's all about like this is what's happening now.
Let's have a reasonable discussion about it.
Well, one thing just,
I think the thing is first we need to understand these hard problems and I
don't think we're even there yet with these things with a lot of these,
that Twitter thread.
-- I learned a lot from that Twitter thread. Right.
-- Yeah.
Go,
look at it but not only the other important
thing is there's tons of people that are like,
oh, this is no big deal.
Just do this. It's like it is a big deal. And what you're suggesting is dumb.
Like no read, what's happening and empathize you idiots. Right.
Don't solve the problem. You can't fix
now. Some of the suggestions for solutions just I'm like that, that absolutely
doesn't
address
profile at all. Seriously. Right. Like you're dumb. Go away anyway. Anyway. Right.
-- I'm dumb and we should go away. So. Right. I'm
-- calling it Invest in
Sunglasses.
Right.
That's right.
Awesome. All right. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you all for listening. You can go to open
social security podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes,
you can use the Pound Os S podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media.
-- Yep, Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks
everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.