Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast
by contributing to the open source security podcast.
The contributor hereby grants the open source security podcast,
a perpetual worldwide nonexclusive royalty free, irrevocable license
to modify use and distribute the submitted contributions,
the contribution,
sorry. The contributor affirms that they have the legal right to grant this license
and the contributions are provided as is without warranties with myself,
Kurtz Fried and my partner in
the amazing thing that this is
Jo
Pressers.
All right.
So it amuses me that you just read
the text of a computer contributor license agreement
when this podcast
is
Creative Commons licensed.
-- It's uh I think ccbys A, you can, what if
-- we need to change that in the future?
And monetize that like we could monetize,
like we could charge people to train their A is off of this and get
a
super
smart security A I
-- that is not a guarantee by the
-- way. OK.
So I can answer this question from the perspective of us,
we own the copyright on this show,
-- but you'd have to get my agreement.
-- We technically own the copyright on this show
and this part gets even more dicey
because you don't publish the show. I publish the show.
So
I probably own the distribution rights to this podcast,
which we have an implicit agreement.
I would be interested to see how that court case would, would rule out.
In fact, I change, I assigned the license to the
podcast without your explicit permission as well.
And so
in summary,
nobody knows, but also just, just for reference, uh Kurt is joking there in no way,
our contributor license agreement for this podcast
to be serious for a moment when somebody,
there are people that send us an email and we're like, oh,
that's an interesting idea.
Or
a bunch of the show is as a direct result of me reading an interesting too.
Or I say something on mascara
and somebody replies, I'm like,
oh, this is kind of like messed up and deep and I have no idea. Let's,
that's a show.
Yeah, for sure, for sure.
Like, well, you, you, there have been court cases where somebody's like,
I came up with the idea for X, you know.
Yeah,
granted the company did all the work and
everything in the heavy lifting and monitor,
you know, blah, blah, blah.
But I want my cut and I
think in general, the courts have not been very kind to these people.
No, without a patent, you generally have no rights in that regard.
-- Yeah,
-- or a copyright of the content if it's whatever,
if they if you can prove they're stealing your copyright.
But, ok, so this is a show about contributor license agreements.
I told Kurt, I wanted to talk about this because
at, at the point in time we are discussing it,
the previous recording was when we discussed the hashy Corp cl A.
But this show will not come out immediately after that.
Well, it might, I don't know, maybe it will, we don't know, but at some point,
this show will come out.
And so we thought a contributor license agreement
is an interesting enough topic by itself,
-- it's very misunderstood and
-- it is extremely misunderstood.
Like a perfect example is I,
you will see
not necessarily contributor license agreement but because it's not exactly
AC L A but it's similar to AC L A
in, for example, when you sign up to Facebook or Twitter,
and they say essentially
you have to assign us the right to redistribute and
broadcast your crap because that's what our website does.
-- Well,
-- and that's viewed as an end
-- user license agreement.
-- Right?
Ya,
but there's kind of a continuum here where
they're under an end user license agreement,
you are assigning certain rights to the company.
They're like we,
because a great example is the company is like, well,
we can't just say we're going to do X with your data because six months from now,
there might be
the augmented reality might actually take off, who knows? Right.
Uh
Sorry, spatial computing. Is the new term. Augmented reality is dead.
It's spatial computing. Now, folks,
that's what
Apple
and Apple is never wrong. You're holding it wrong. Apple knows best
Apple knows best you're holding it wrong.
And so that's part of it is because for example, as Facebook, I can't
go out and get everybody's permission to like, so I can deploy a new technology.
Right? That's right. You know,
and um there's a, well, a lot of um
like Wikipedia, for example, like some day, they might want to print that thing out
or put it on tablets and fire them off into outer space. I, I don't know.
And so, you know, by contributing Wikipedia blah, blah, blah,
they get to do whatever it is they want to do with the data.
Now, the, the
I think the problem is a lot of people don't understand
what that means and what it means is at some level,
the company has to be able to redistribute your stuff as they see fit
because there's new technologies. But on the flip side, that also means,
well, what about training A I
and large language models? And that's the current thing, Du
Jour
with, you know, Zoom and everybody kind of messing that up.
And my understanding is the majority of these licenses as they're written,
never sort of explicitly anticipated this, but they do allow it.
So, OK, there's a lot you just said and some of it's kind of wrong
Well, it, let's start with Wikipedia.
So Wikipedia is not and this is, I'm, I just, I just look this up so I don't have the,
the depth of knowledge
I would like.
But my understanding with Wikipedia is Wikipedia is you aren't
giving them the rights to your content in the.
And so as they own it,
you are giving them
content licensed by ccbys A which is Creative Commons, share alike,
meaning content submitted to Wikipedia
is
not owned by Wikipedia.
You are technically still the copyright owner, but it also is create, it is
licensed under Creative Commons in a liberal way.
Well, and that gets even messier because for example, that means technically,
I own one word of the entry for Edmonton on Wikipedia because they, they had it.
Edmonton is dissected by the river of the North Saskatchewan.
I'm not close, it's bisected but good try.
But this is where we get into that Pamela Ches
stack
blog post on copyright and who owns the copyright, the last person to touch it.
All the contributors we don't know today and
we're not gonna talk about that particular,
that's for the lawyers to sort out.
Yeah, that too.
I want to talk about cl A specifically because
I think the Wikipedia instance is a good example.
We're gonna,
we'll run with that for now because I think it's easy for people to understand
and it, it is
not going to be contentious versus some other things
Right. Obviously
famous last words. Right. Of course, of course, I can't wait. But these are,
they could be
who likes puppies anyway.
Dogs are the best, by the way,
like cats, but dogs are the best.
Everyone knows that we're on day seven and inky is si t
once per session without me putting the finger over his head
to get him to si t like he's getting there.
But you can't say the word sit without your cat doing something weird.
-- Well, we're training him to do that on command. So yeah.
-- Oh I see.
So you're not whatever. OK? Anyway, that's why I like dogs.
They like that's not hard to do.
-- But
-- we're at, we're at a stage in his training where I need to be careful
and not confuse him, right? I need to be very consistent
-- anyway.
-- OK.
Anyway, so
when we talk about contributor license agreements, right?
There is a big difference between contributing to open source
that has
a license, for example, like let's say I contribute content to Wikipedia.
It's covered by ccbys. A
meaning
I'm saying these contributions I'm giving to Wikipedia, you are free to use.
This is not something I can go back later and be like, no, I've changed my mind.
I'm taking this stuff back.
It is
content I'm giving them to use with the
understanding that this will be reused and redistributed
-- in an understood manner, right? Like that's very
-- open source.
And also one critical point
that you have the right to give this contribution
-- for
-- sure, for sure. That's true too. Because
when you and this is where that stupid sign off thing you
get with a DC O which is developer certificate of origin,
which that exists funny enough because when
SCO
sued IBM for stealing
UNIX and putting it in Linux, which is like the most hilarious flow chart ever.
But
basically,
the DC O was created as a way to
push liability under contributors and contributors have to say,
I pinky swear that I have the rights to contribute this code to the thing.
I'm contributing it to which I'm still skeptical would
hold up in court in any meaningful way.
But that's another
really
lawyer. I just love it.
-- So I, I don't know, I don't know.
-- Well, but here's the thing, if I use the DC O and it
sheds a bunch of risk for essentially zero money.
Well,
here's the thing. Does it make things worse?
-- It annoys me that I have to remember to use. That's
-- an externalized cost.
That's I'm not annoyed. You're annoyed, but I'm ok with you being annoyed.
Like, no, seriously,
like every time I have to hunt through VS code and find that stupid
check box,
right?
You know, because every time I contribute to the Os V, I'm like,
I forget to do signed off by and then it like bounces back
-- and I'm like,
-- right,
right now I have to remember how to do a force push
-- and
-- it's like a one line change to AJ on file.
I don't think
I know. I know. OK.
So anyway, so now if Wikipedia had a contributor license agreement,
what that would mean
is I would have to sign a thing
that says any contributions I am giving to you, Wikipedia.
I am also assigning the copyright of it to you,
meaning
I have no say over what you do with this content after you get it for me.
And so Wikipedia could
relic
it.
They could say we're closing Wikipedia up and now you can
only look at Wi Wikipedia for $10 a month or something.
And there's literally nothing you could do about that with AC L A now,
even with ccbys A, like they could say we're closing Wikipedia up,
we're charging $10 a month.
But because it's licensed ccbysa,
I could download all of it
Wikipedia and be like, I just made a mirror of Wikipedia. Everybody called wi
a
media or something and everyone can look at it and there's nothing they could
-- do about that because of the license carried on the content
-- and see,
and this leads to a meta topic that we probably shouldn't get into. But
I've been talking to people a bunch about copier and why do we care about copyright?
And the general answer is we care about copyright because it allows us to
enforce our rights and gives us
control of that thing that we created and have copyright over.
But for example, the cloud security lines, a lot of what we create,
we then try to give away as freely and widely as possible
or back to my support ticket example, like telling you how to change your password. I
don't really care.
And so what I'm realizing is the
traditional media companies and the traditional companies.
Yes, they very much care about copyright because
oh
perfect
example, Disney is no longer doing physical media in
-- Australia. I did
-- see that you said
that
there will be no more Disney DVD S or Blu Rays in Australia.
It's all gonna be on Disney Plus
or
whatever,
like
it's on Disney Plus but then they license it to somebody else.
So they take it off Disney Plus and so that could happen. No, it could, it does
it happen that there's been movies that just go
missing for a while because somebody else licensed it and
oh my God drives my kids nuts and me nuts because I'm my son would literally be like,
I want to watch this and I'm like, yeah,
I'm like, it's gone. That sucks.
And then I have to go by Paramount plus or like Nickelodeon plus or some other.
-- So
-- this is a perfect example
of
when, when one entity is the sole copyright holder of content,
they can literally do whatever they want with it
because it is their content and it is up to them and that
is fundamentally the purpose of AC L A is you as a developer and
like I know you mentioned Facebook's ya
and whatever. But the cl A and
ya are legally probably the same thing, right?
-- But it is a way for an organization to
-- say it looks like a duck.
It looks
like a duck. Probably. I don't know.
It's, I'm assigning a bunch of my rights away like it.
-- If, if
-- there's lawyers listening and there's a difference like let us know, I think
so as a, as a developer, right, I want to contribute code,
I sign AC L A that says I'm giving this
organization permission to do whatever they want with my code.
And of course they pink he swore to me
that they would never relic
the code is something else.
But as we're seeing this is happening more and more often it's not going to stop.
Well, and I think the challenge is again, the way these are written
like this is a real world one for all materials you submit to the blank,
you hereby grant the blank and the blank, a perpetual worldwide non exclusive,
no charge, royalty free, irrevocable copyright license
too.
And here's the important part that they do care about to reproduce,
prepare derivative works of publicly display, publicly perform,
sublicense and distribute such materials and derivative works now
because it's on a website
and maybe some dates on an FTP site or
who knows?
But the problem is as this is written,
it means we can also shove this into an A I and build a large,
a large language model or we can, they want to turn it into a rap song and like,
make a kajillions dollars off of a cool rap song,
whatever.
And I think that's the,
the people are realizing that like, oh, I really signed away my rights.
And
the problem is then when somebody like, has
a
corp
does the license switcheroo,
everybody's like, whoa, wait a minute, what? And
you know, I'm always reminded of
if it's not in the contract, it's not in the contract and it's not real.
I was watching, oh the founder, great movie, by the way,
uh Michael Keaton, I have no idea what that even is. It's the founder.
-- It's about the, it's the mcdonald's story.
-- Oh, the mcdonald's movie. I know of it.
-- I haven't
-- seen it. Yeah. And Michael Keaton is fantastic.
Like, like just, oh,
the actor is amazing and they basically stay very true to the story.
So they don't embellish it a lot because they don't need to. It's just such a crazy
story.
But they basically,
when Ray Croc bought mcdonald's from the mcdonald brothers, right?
They mcdonald brothers,
like we want 1% of worldwide royalties in addition to the million dollars and blah,
blah, blah,
and Ray Croc was like, oh man, like my money, people just can't, I can't do that
but
we can take it out of the contract and do it on a handshake deal.
-- Oh, yeah. Yeah,
-- they never got their money.
-- Shocked. I'm shocked about that
-- because 1% of mcdonald's
like that, that is so much money.
Like
those big
add
up.
So, anyways, but that's the thing, right? Like,
people are realizing, like,
i,
it's like the zoom thing I'm going to pick on zoom.
They changed their terms of service without really warning people that much and
they wrote it poorly. So it sounded like
they could use your material,
your your conversations that were you talking over Zoom
to train a large language model? And people lost their minds.
-- I
-- have a very strong suspicion that was not an accident just for them.
And then they walked it back rather quickly and
said we explicitly won't do this unless you opt in
in the future now.
-- But the point is they can change those terms of service
-- until each and,
and that's the thing.
All of these yah
have basically a thing at the bottom. That's like the
escape clause.
Whenever we change this, you automatically agree to what we're changing it to.
So ha ha gets
too bad.
So I feel bad for companies like Zoom because companies like Microsoft Google,
all those guys, they have a copy of the web,
they can train off of cool a company like Zoom does not not yet anyways,
people are realizing that these licenses are like they have power,
-- they, they matter,
-- they do. And I think
if you look at the history of open source, there were,
there have always been contributor license agreements in
place like the free software foundation has one,
lots of open source projects, have them, lots of companies had them.
I will, I will give Red Hat credit for this.
Red Hat has never used AC L A to my knowledge.
Well, I shouldn't say that I'm sure they have projects, but generally speaking,
Red Hat was not focused on cl A content whereas
I, I think canonical might have been for
ubuntu if I'm remembering correctly. So,
and, and, and here's the thing many years ago. No one worried about this.
-- Uh
-- Canonical. Absolutely does have AC L A. They do have
AC L A. OK?
And one thing I'm just going to point out
you can almost never say Red Hat doesn't do X because Red Hat is so big and,
and has done like everything like Red Hat has shipped
uh closed source binary,
-- commercial software, real player.
-- Yo. Remember real player
or
like they,
they bought a company and stapled the Red hat logo onto the software and shipped it.
Oh
And then we but open
sourced it later on. But that takes time.
You can't just, it takes time to open
source stuff. Trust me, folks. If you
-- and I
-- remember the,
-- the KVM product.
-- Yeah, I was
that's the one
ran on Windows server when they bought it, which was an amusing lull as well.
And it's like, I mean, now it doesn't, but like, people seem to sort of expect, oh,
it's,
you can just change the code and fix it and it's
like it's gonna take more than a week or two.
It's a little, it's a little more work than that. But, but anyway,
I just got to read this story. I have to read this at Canonical. We manage a lot of open
source projects.
This is true
and we're required to have agreements with everyone who takes part in them.
It's the easiest way for you to give us permission to use your contributions in
effect, you're giving us a license but you still own the copyright.
So you retain the right to modify your code and use it in another project.
Technically,
everything is true.
Several upstream projects require all contributors to agree
to the rules for inclusion of their code.
We encourage ubuntu members to support those
when working with UPSTREAM on contribution of patches
back to those projects or direct contributions.
Well, obviously, if you're going to contribute to a project that requires AC L A
and you don't sign the CL A, you're not gonna get to contribute.
Right.
Like, right. Right.
So anyways,
for most projects that Canonical,
the preferred approach is a wide license rather than an assignment of ownership.
So that, that's the, the less evil, the good part
and the agreements are documented below
other projects take their own view,
but we typically recommend supporting their preferred approach
to contributing and licensing whatever that might be.
And see, that's the challenge with canonical is even if canonical is like,
we hate CLAS, we don't want to do CLAS.
Well, they have to ship software that has
like c
there's just, there's open source stuff that you can't, not ship
there doesn't
mean they need AC LA,
I mean de
and doesn't have AC L A. Right.
-- Well,
-- but the thing is if you're going to contribute to a bundu
fork of law,
they're gonna wanna upstream that.
So they're going to need you to sign the CL A so they can contribute back upstream,
right?
-- They need the rights to your work to push it back upstream. You,
-- you might be right.
But this feels very obtuse.
Well, the, the point I'm trying to make though is
it's not
a company like ubuntu doesn't necessarily want to do Clas,
but it's part of the legal reality of, well,
there's all these projects that do CLAS that we need
to ship and we need to update and interact with.
I'm not a lawyer
but lots of other Linux distributions use software with CLAS
that don't
have you sign AC L A
-- true
-- and maybe they're not as aggressive about contributing back to
them or maybe to put it simply they're not evil.
-- Who knows?
-- And I don't know that canonical is evil or not.
I, I don't think they're evil because
-- if they were evil they'd probably be richer. Like Oracle.
-- That's probably fair.
-- Anyway,
-- like Oracle is famous for having a contributor license agreement.
-- They don't just have clas, they have, like, the Dewitt Clause is from Oracle.
-- Right.
That's the one where you can't publish benchmarks of the software.
Yeah. They,
well, they didn't invent it but they definitely made it
-- popular.
-- They pretty much,
yeah, they made that a thing.
But, but anyway, Clas, right.
Ok.
So after we've gotten ourselves a bit off track, we'll say fundamentally right,
early days of open source clas existed,
people at canonical had them and no one thought a lot about them.
I mean, I remember signing Clas for various projects
and it was like, whatever, no big deal. That's fine.
There's not a ton of money in this stuff like,
well, they're probably, no, no, there wasn't at the beginning.
That's fair until you get bigger.
Like let's be real elastic search prior to version one.
Yeah. Whatever. It's a neat little search thing.
Right. Right. For sure. For sure.
Engine
X,
I remember Engine
X from before. It was cool. And a big company
didn't, doesn't Cisco own Engine
-- X
-- now F five, bought in
-- for 670 million U. Si.
-- Mean, that's respectable.
That's some real money.
I
know.
Right.
That's a lot of money.
Good for them.
But. Right. Does Engine X have AC LA? I bet they do.
Oh, I would
think better.
In fact, they probably do because I, I suspect you would struggle to sell
a project such as that without AC L A.
Well, the challenge is if you don't have a contributor license agreement,
you can never relic
the darn thing.
And that's kind of seen as, as
companies don't necessarily want to do that,
but they definitely want the option of doing it right.
You know,
and so, uh I don't know that I, I'm Googling engine
X contributor license agreement and they don't,
-- it's not popping
-- up. Maybe they don't. And if they don't, I think that's cool too.
I think it's phenomenal if you can get away with that.
But anyway, OK.
So the point is,
-- so why do companies like CL
-- A S gives them
the perception of control and the option of control?
It does the option. I don't think the perception is necessarily important
because here's the thing,
if you have an open source project without AC L A,
but you are the like primary owner of the github
repository,
you are in control of that project. If people send you fixes
and obviously when they send you fixes,
it's understood that whatever their patches are will
be covered by the license the project uses,
be it Apache two or GP L or whatever you send them a fix, your patch goes in,
but they they could say no, I don't want this.
I mean, this happens all the time, right?
Where someone will send a patch to a project and the project is like, absolutely not.
I mean, just go look at the Lyonel
mailing list.
I mean, that's fair. But a
better example might be
you have a company with an open source project and they have like
an open core add on or a commercial add on or whatever.
And if you submit a patch to the open source that tramples on their commercial value,
they're gonna be like no way we're not taking this
and that happens literally all the time, right?
You can run that project without a contributor license agreement. It just means
the source code in your project is viewed as being owned by all of the contributors,
even if you contribute
99% of the source code,
it's viewed as
having other contributors as like the copyright owners, right?
And so that means
if you're looking for investment or to sell your company or whatever
the investors are gonna be like,
you don't own your source code
and it's complicated. I know, but that's going to be the discussion that comes up.
-- I hate to say it really depends on what that source code is and does because for
-- sure,
-- for sure
-- some things are
more infrastructure, some things are more niche,
you know,
it
and some things lend themselves to being as a service and some things don't.
That's right. Exactly. Exactly. It's, it's a complicated discussion.
But now if I'm a company
and I have AC L A
I own every contribution to that software,
I am the sole unquestioned copyright owner of the software.
If I want to relic
it, if I want to close it,
I can do anything I want, I could sell that project to Oracle
and that's just the way it is. Yeah.
And I think historically, that has not been a concern people had.
Well, yeah, 20 years ago,
nobody would have bought a web server for $670 million.
Exactly.
That's what I mean by. There's no money there back in the day.
-- Like, well, there wasn't.
-- Exactly.
I
remember redhead going public and its valuation was a
-- lot.
-- But,
yeah, for a week
and then,
like, and what blows my mind is Engine X is
like, I don't want to say it's a one trick pony. But
I mean, it's a good web server but
-- it's a good web server. Like, come on. There's
-- no, no, here's the thing.
Name, three web servers. Kurt, I bet you can name two
Apache
and jxiis.
-- What
-- is, is, oh, that's a Microsoft. One name. Three open source web servers.
The is, doesn't count. I forgot that even existed. To be honest with you. H A proxy,
I don't, is H a proxy web server. Yeah,
-- it has a web server.
-- That's fair.
You know what I mean,
-- yeah, I agree. I agree. And to be
-- honest, engine
X has captured the mind share, for sure.
I've been a long time Apache user and I've been a long time engine X user. And if I had
to pick one to actually deploy and care and feed for,
I would pick engine
-- X,
-- I haven't run Apache
in probably 15 years. Everything I do is Engine X now because it's just so much easier
the config files along
and not just that when I need to do something weird, like if I need a reverse proxy,
whatever, like if you search for the engine X configuration, it's like,
oh these two lines do it and then you're like, I search for the Apache configuration.
They're like this zip file contains all of it. It's like, holy crap. What is this?
Well, and then there's all the out of date answers but back anyways rabbit hole. So
I,
I
think part of the challenge is
is it's, it's
one of those things where a lot of this ran on gentlemen's agreements
for sure.
And
that
works
until it doesn't.
And then when it doesn't work well, I'm sorry. But the contract says X
and I think, I think you also like a good example of this is historically speaking,
you would have something like GP L, right?
And you'd have a handful of people who violated it. And then
there were a handful of court cases.
I mean, I remember the first couple of GP L court cases where we were like,
is it gonna stand up in court?
-- Like, is this gonna
-- work? Can you actually use copyright to do this?
Right.
And like, we didn't know and it did so far it stood up.
But like there are,
there are still instances where people violate the GP L and I bet in 80%
-- of the cases they probably get away
-- with
-- it
-- more like 99% of the cases.
Because if you look at iot,
-- no, look
-- at IOT, that's probably fair. There's a
lot of iot that
there
is
and the thing is, there's just,
there aren't these massive corporations behind these projects
with tons of money trying to defend this.
And that's part of, to me, the beauty of this is because we've commoditized and,
and put this so far into the utility category.
There's not a lot like there's no money in Auck and Grep and said, but
like if those tools cease to exist, I would cry and drink for a week,
but no one's paying for them either,
like for sure,
I would probably pay for them because I really rely on
because you're a weirdo but no one else would. But anyway,
so
I think
this is what kind of makes it different is, is a lot of open source.
People, people recognize
that some of these licenses come with rules and, and you know,
things demands that are made on the user.
And as that is discovered, I think legally, companies start saying like, OK,
we need to understand what we have what's going on
versus the CL A is I think the opposite of that,
this is where the developers need to say, all right,
we need to understand what's going on and what's happening.
And I,
I have no doubt
that the, the age of the CL A
is going to end because no one is going to contribute to a project that has
AC L A at some point in the near future just because they keep getting screwed.
The thing is if the project succeeds and becomes Monetti
Zable,
then it kind of has to push the cl A button if they have that button available to them
because
you can't tell people like, oh,
we could totally make $100 million off the software
or sell it to F five for $670 million.
But like we're not going to, you're right, you're going to be deposed.
No.
What I'm trying to get at is somebody is going to see that potential value
and go,
I want to take that
and
they might like
open source projects have been kind of hijacked in the
past because they have value some of them for sure.
You know, and, and this is what I'm getting at. There's those incentives of,
you can't leave a half billion dollar pile of money.
-- Sitting there without expecting somebody to take a crack at it.
-- Well, ok.
No, let me, let me rephrase this. I think you have the right idea.
But I think how you got there is wrong engine X
isn't source code.
Engine X is a community of knowledge that was
built around a project that shares the same name.
Yeah.
And I think that's the thing people often don't understand is they
equate engine X equals source code like we need source code.
But the reality is the source code is irrelevant.
It's the fact that the engine X name is very recognizable. It has a good brand.
You can go and just type like engine X reverse proxy into any web search on the planet.
Heck,
I bet you can ask chat GP T and it would tell you the
answer without issue because there are so
-- many documents already explaining this so
-- well.
Uh
the way I see this is and the source code is relevant, but it's
1% of the ecosystem and what you want is the ecosystem. Right. Right.
For example, that's why. So I needed some GP US to run A I on my workstation here
and I picked NVIDIA because C A
because C
is popular and it just,
there's so many guides and
like
there's
I, I literally seriously considered intel cards
because they are sort of, they're,
they're better bang for the hardware buck.
But the software ecosystem and the
people ecosystem.
It's like seven people compared to the NVIDIA ecosystem, which is
-- everybody for the last 20 years, except
-- with NVIDIA cards,
you have to install their horrible drivers on Linux.
-- I'm running
-- windows. Oh, you are?
-- That's
-- the trick
windows. 11 plus
to drivers
running
the
windows. Subsystem
for Linux.
There's
a
ton of tutorials out there because it just works.
That's fair.
-- I mean, I'll accept
-- that.
I spent like,
an hour getting it working and 30 minutes of
it was wasted reading out of date tutorials.
Then I was like, oh, this is dumb.
I'm just gonna do it my way, which is try and get it working.
Read the error message, fix the error message,
repeat it like three times and it worked.
I mean, if you were on Linux,
you would have spent three hours getting their drivers installed
one anyways. But so back to this is
the
in general there, there is some value in the source code, but there's
far more of the values in that ecosystem. Like, can I get help for this?
Is there answers for this that are up to date?
Like Apache is a great example of this. When you search for Apache, how to things,
you'll get a ton of answers for like a patch of 2.2
which is so hilariously old and out of date,
it's the opposite of helpful and
yeah, you know, and so anyway, sorry to backtrack of it.
Part of it too is licenses are an expression of the culture of that software
even going so far as to
uh one thing I never really understood for a long time was GP L versus BS D.
And then I realized the GP L and BS D view
the end user differently in the GP L. The end user is the end user
in the BS D. The end user is the developer.
Yeah, I won't disagree with that.
And when I figured that one out, I'm like, oh, this totally makes sense now,
I get sure,
sure.
And
this is something
where again, having the cl A
gives you the option of making changes.
OK?
I want to take this home in one last push
and this will give everyone something to think about
and we are not going to answer this today.
So don't you dare try to go down this rat hole?
But
AC LA I truly believe is a response to open source
not keeping up with the current just environment around it.
I think all of our open source licenses
are from 20 plus years ago
and it was a very different world. And so while I don't like cl a si understand
the idea and intent behind them.
And so I think what we actually need is we need like Bruce Perens,
I'll try to dig up his talk, Bruce Perez.
Oh,
I have bad news for you.
The GP LV two is over 30 years old now.
Yeah. I, I, right for sure. Like, they're, they're all ancient.
Like Bruce Perens has a nice talk where he kind of talks about some, like,
what does the future of open source licensing need to look like?
And of course he, he doesn't have any money or, or people working on this.
So it's, it's not going anywhere at the moment.
I, I remember I sent him some messages about it and he was basically like,
do you know anyone who wants to fund this?
And I was like, sadly, no,
but
I think that is the thing we need to think about things like the CCLAS are hammers.
You know, we're trying to put in,
we're trying to screw in a screw with a hammer is what we're doing.
It's,
I think it goes past that these, these software licenses were written for a world
that doesn't exist in it
and it's not just that there's new things like cloud and as a service
and a I trying to gobble up all the data to train stuff but
the software problems we were trying to solve. Like, yeah, open
source one. We're good. Yeah,
exactly.
But the thing is, I,
I don't know that it could have won without these licenses
and without CLAS to get us along the way 100%.
But here's the trick is in some ways we're really stuck with them because,
like, the, you can't relic
the Linux kernel at this point and you can't not live with the Linux kernel.
-- So like, what do you do?
-- Well, that's fine.
I think there are certain things that are different,
but I still think that for
new upcoming organizations, I mean, we talked about this in that,
that the hashy Karp episode where like start ups
are using open source as their marketing wing.
And so you end up with this like just bizarre usage,
like we need open source licenses that reflect what's happening
in the universe around them and we don't have that.
And I think that is like my whole ending point of all of this
is CLAS are
as open source licenses abused copyright.
CLAS abuse open source licenses when the correct answer is,
and this probably is partially copyright needs to evolve,
partially open source licenses need to evolve.
Like there's a lot of moving parts
and we certainly aren't going to fix this.
But it is something
that I would love to see movement on and I
don't see anyone really doing anything meaningful in this space.
If there is someone let us know because I would absolutely love to learn about it.
Well,
and one challenge is these existing open source licenses allow people
to abuse them in ways to monetize them and get away with
-- basically murder. In some cases,
-- I don't think it's abuse, it's just how it works.
Why
would I want to fix that? I mean, and as a start up.
I don't
have a million dollars to spend on legal fees to create a good new license.
-- No,
-- no one's creating new licenses.
You need to use existing licenses and, and I think many start ups would gladly
use a more business friendly license. That,
because look at the same time,
like I'm sensitive to the fact that there are large
companies strip mining the crap out of open source.
And I don't like that either.
And that's kind of what we want though because I don't want
the reinventing crappy web services that are full of security flaws,
complicated, right?
It, it, there's commodity and then there's interesting things, but all right,
I'm going to call this one here and this is just food
for thought and we will no doubt revisit this topic many,
many times in the future because that's not going away.
So, thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. Go to open source security podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes. Yi
Pound O says podcast hashtag on Mastodon to get our attention.
-- Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks
everyone.
Bye bye.