Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siegfried
and my partner in using open source. Josh
Reser.
Uh
I do use open
source. We all do. That's
true.
Well, it's,
I mean, I, I use it, use it. So,
no,
no, I
have, I have a good example of this. So Anor
has two open source projects called Sifting Gripe. Right? Sift is the
bomb scanner. Gripe is a vulnerability scanner and
I run Fedora on my laptop.
Like we are literally recording this show with me running Fedora on my laptop.
And basically all, almost all of these shows have been recorded on Fedora on my side.
Many of them have been edited on Fedora.
Well, squad caster does the recording not.
You're making it sound like the local thing is recording it.
-- Look,
-- Kurt
getting Linux
to work in like any capacity is a feat.
So don't,
don't degrade my effort.
I used to spend two weeks every summer forcing
myself to like run whatever version of Fedora Linux,
whatever
and getting everything set up. And then at some point, I like
I ran Linux on my desktop for kind of the first
five years because it was actually better than windows and stuff.
But then windows caught up and I gave up, I'll be blunt
lies.
I've given up
anyway. So sift and gripe,
they do containery
things right where they interact with Docker and they pull
containers from registries and all this and I run Fedora.
So I thought I'm going
to build
and test
these applications on Fedora because Fedora has pod man and pod man is weird.
Pod man is
I call it uh like containers with hard mode enabled
because everything almost works but not quite. And
I have learned
an amazing amount
about the internals of these two applications because of open source.
-- And
-- well,
I always love like when you have an incumbent player like Docker and
then you have like a second tier kind of player like pod man.
And it's like
they kind of do the same thing but they kind of don't. And
yeah,
you very rapidly learn about what assumptions were made
by people that may or may not be sane.
That's right.
And my favorite example is still everyone's like, oh pod man doesn't have a demon
and it's like, yes it does. The demons called system.
I
was
like
you,
yeah. Anyway,
anyway,
basically you have to run system D and CD now or you can't do anything.
-- System D
-- is the biggest demon of them. All. We're not talking about system D.
Today we're going to talk about open source is
unfair and we're going to base this entire discussion
off of something Microsoft just did.
I will let you do the honors of telling us all what they've done.
-- So,
-- Microsoft ships,
Windows and Windows has an App Store and the app
store is generally what you would expect it to be.
It's
apps, games,
stuff like that, Fortnite, whatever,
but that has changed a bit in that Windows now has the
Windows subsystem for Linux now up to version two and it's,
it's really good. Like you run
an X program and it just pops up in sound and everything works. It's magic.
You have this Windows subsystem for Linux.
Ok, cool. Like I want to run well, Linux and stuff on top of it.
Where do I get my Linux thrown on top of it? Well,
you get it from the Windows store.
Now there is free stuff in there like ubuntu and whatnot.
But
like the last time I looked, I was looking for,
I think a cent toss just this was like ages ago back when I was, I think still at Red Hat
and there was a cent toss for like 100
and over $100.
And now if I quickly look like there's a Fedora remix for WSL for 1279 there's
um there's an X server for like $63.99
and some other stuff. But,
and the point is so there's these open source apps
that
they haven't
really done anything to it.
Like, they, it's not like they took a library and built an app around it,
you know,
or they basically just, like, got Fedora running
and then
sold, you know, packaged it in for 1279 or 100 bucks or whatever.
And so what Microsoft did is, and I think, because this is like,
because when I was looking through the app store,
I'm a reasonably sophisticated user and I know how this stuff works.
And I know my Linux distro
and even I had a hard time finding a good one that wasn't like
going to charge me an arm and a leg and do stupid stuff.
And so Microsoft kind of went well,
if you're just sort of like taking an open source app or operating system and just
kind of making it work and shipping it and charging a lot of money for that,
that's not a great experience and it kind of tricks the
user and they're not going to be super happy about this,
especially when they find out that it's free.
Like there are free versions.
And so they,
they basically said we're going to get rid of
these sort of low value open source apps.
And personally
I'm ok with that because like, it, it would have reduced the crap clutter in the,
in their store.
Well,
-- yes,
-- but because the problem is like, previously, well, it's not as bad now.
They definitely got rid of some stuff.
But, like, it used to be, if you searched for ubuntu,
it was kind of tricky to find the real ubuntu.
You know,
there's like some keyword stuffing and stuff going on.
Um, oh, well, yeah, there's still this thing called tunu.com and it's apps,
news and weather.
Um, or there's, you know.
Yeah.
But it looks like now
ubuntu actually pulls up just real
-- Ubuntu.
-- Well, and that's good and, and this is a
difficulty and they also put in their rule that
you can't
charge an abnormally large amount
for, I think just things in general, not necessarily open source,
which is funny because I actually remember paying like 500
bucks for an ex server back in the day.
So to me, I'm like, that's, that's a difference.
But,
and we've seen the same thing in the apple
app.
Remember early on
where that guy made that app that was called 999 and
it cost $999 and it displayed 999 and it was like
basically an expensive pet rock.
And again, it was to show you our, we,
well, to show that you were, you know, willing to spend 999 wealthy and dumb.
I
do like the guy that made the app where it timed how long you
threw your phone up in the air and the app store banned it.
-- Oh, that was epic. I remember that one.
-- I was, I was like,
uh
yeah, that was so good.
We've talked about this in the past, you know, with the apple walled garden.
But part of the expectation is if I'm going to a place with walled garden,
I don't want there to be weird mosquitoes and snakes and stuff.
I want to go see some nice flowers
and,
and this is
like, I want some degree of curation and I don't want to get mugged.
All right. All right.
Your explanation was very long, but I want to just sum it all up with this.
The people republishing open source applications in the
Windows store are technically doing nothing wrong.
And that is just the honest to God's truth of it all.
Like this is one of the places I think where open source is very unfair.
Where
if you're an open source developer, someone can totally take all of your work,
they can repackage it, they can claim they wrote it
and they can sell it
and that's not against the rules. It's unethical but it is not illegal or
technically wrong.
Like with the majority of widely accepted
open source licenses. Yeah, that's
that happens.
And I mean, they, they can easily comply with the license by like, oh yeah, you know,
if you,
if you search in the basement for the filing cabinet behind the sign that says,
but where the jaguar, yes, we left the BS D notice in there that says,
who actually built this, you know, but good luck finding it.
Right. Right. Exactly. Well, in most,
I shouldn't say most many companies now
are only allowing like MIT style and Apache
two style licenses which have no advertising clause.
And so you can literally take what someone has done
and pretend it's yours and
that's it like you're done.
I find the experience of the Microsoft and Apple app stores.
Uh, I don't use Google so I don't know what the Google Play Store is like,
but I assume it's roughly the same.
I find it
very hit and miss in the sense of like, there's the big apps
that are kind of like, OK, like, you know, if you want to do linkedin,
you get the linkedin app or reddit, the Reddit app, they're, you know,
they're terrible but whatever, they're free and, you know,
they're trying to monetize you.
It's, and then when you start looking for sort of specialty apps, things
-- very rapidly go sideways in a lot of cases.
-- Absolutely. Actually,
I just had this on Apple.
I was looking for a nice SSH client for my phone
just so I could like SSH into and reboot a machine.
I bought 30 of them. They're all flaming garbage.
I tried a bunch and I just gave up because I was like, whatever because it was funny, I,
the reason I did this is I have uh the computer that runs my TV,
was acting up and I, I just needed the Sschn and reboot it every now and then.
And I was tired of like walking upstairs to the computer to reboot it.
I was like, I'll just put something on my phone.
I would have just set a Cron
-- job at 3 a.m.
-- That is exactly what happened.
Actually, I shouldn't say that. What, what I did do.
I, I run Flex and I had a TV tuner plugged into it
and the TV tuner was flaking out.
And then I bought an HD home run device which is a box,
you plug into your network and then it does like weird magic like TCP TV or something.
And that is flawless and now I haven't had to reboot it since.
-- But anyway, anyway, but open
-- SSH or sorry, not open SSH.
Apps on the App store are a great example because
I tried to write an article about this probably about eight
or nine years ago and I bought and downloaded all of
them like there was about 20 or 30 at the time
and I was going, you know, I had my checklist, like, can you import a key to it?
Can you generate a key in it? Can you export the key from it?
Can it, does it show you the, the,
the key signatures and stuff? Right? And they were all, they all had deficiencies
essentially in sort of basic SSH usage.
And then I tried to track down the publishers.
Yeah, that did not go well.
Right. Like this one publisher linked to a web page.
They'd also done like a little card game,
you know, I've,
I've run into the same thing with the crypto wallets where I'm
trying to track down these crypto wallets who built them some.
It's easy.
Like Coinbase, crypto wallet was done by Coinbase and they sort of stand behind it.
Cool. And then this other one is like a collective of two guys in the, I
think they're in the Bahamas. I'm not entirely sure.
But, you know, it's just, it's like, it's just crazy stuff and,
and so
I look at the experience of just trying to find a reputable app and,
and even if I'm willing to pay money for it,
it's just, it's pretty horrible. And so,
yeah, getting rid of these kind of obvious scams, would
it basically, it'd be like cleaning dog poop off the sidewalk.
Like it's, it's not great,
but it's better than having dog poop all over the sidewalk.
Well, except
the dog poop looks like the sidewalk
and
you can't tell
it
the app store problem I think is something very different and very hard.
And I don't want to dwell on that today and I know we're going to keep coming back to it.
There's no escaping it, but
I, I'm more interested in this, this whole, like,
what is ok and not ok and open source because
like, here's, here's my example.
So
let's say you wrote some application, Kurt and you put it out as,
as an Apache two license and I take it and I package it and I sell it on the App store,
right?
That seems totally bogus and unfair.
And now if you take the same app and you put it on the App store,
right? I could charge more than you.
But still, you know what I mean?
-- This is one of those angles of open source that I just like, well,
-- we've,
we've seen this happen
in the security world with N
map with Nessus, right? Like
Renaud wrote Nessus Great Tool
and
a ton of consulting firms used it to make a ton
of money and he saw exactly $0 no bug reports,
no bug submissions.
And so they went with this really crazy
license where it's like it's still open source.
But if you do the plugins
and you want to distribute the plugins or whatever,
you have to buy a license or you have it, it's complicated.
I, I it's been a while, you know, same thing with N map.
They kind of like lock down their data set
and you know what?
Yeah, I don't blame them because they pour their hearts into those tools
and
like they need to eat.
And I think part of it is
in the short term, it'll work. But in the long term,
ironically, if the,
if the shyster
is successful,
it's kind of almost more likely to kill off the original thing.
Now, you can't do that with, like, Fedora or Ubuntu.
-- I,
-- I, I don't, I don't know if I agree with that.
Well, no, I mean, it's, if, if,
if somebody sees their work being monetized and they're getting exactly $0 from it,
I feel like they're more likely to kind of like, just give up.
Oh, I, I think that'll happen a lot.
I think we're seeing some of that in open source now. I mean, Tide Lift did
a survey maybe a year ago
where like half of open
source developers are basically, like at their wits end.
-- Yeah,
-- I experience existential dread on a daily basis and want to die.
No,
that's, that's not open
source,
that's not open
source's fault.
It's, well,
you know what it reminds me of is eternal September.
I, I, I've seen people sort of saying,
like these companies and stuff don't know how to use open source correctly, like,
in the sense of they're not nice and polite about it.
And it's like, yeah, they're not gonna be because they don't have to be.
And, and I agree with that. I think that's,
that's a topic I think about a lot because
I feel like there is
the kind of a couple of camps I see in
the open source world where there's one camp that's like,
yeah, open source one, it's everywhere, everyone's using it.
Good job, everybody
and there's another camp that says, wait a minute.
So everyone's using this stuff, they're not giving back.
-- They're getting mad when it breaks. Well,
-- not even,
they're making new demands.
Yeah. Right. Right. That too.
The classic thing being, can you fill out our questionnaire for security?
Oh,
well, ok. Look, those are funny when they show up but they are not common.
I want to be clear like they happen but it's not like you're getting 10 of them a day.
But if you look at like a lot of github
-- issues, there's a lot of people demanding features or demanding things
-- that,
that.
So it's funny that actually just happened,
I think with it was gripe the other day where someone was like,
oh we would like a Phipps 1 40-2 compiled version of gripe.
What?
Well, my response is basically patch is welcome.
Like if you want this, you're going to have to do it because like we're done,
that is a bit more work than maybe they think it is.
I don't know.
And that's one thing that always gets me too is some of it is
I don't think a lot of these people are like malicious and like,
oh
ha ha ha
I will,
the open
source developers,
I think they honestly are just like, yeah, come on, how hard can this be?
Like I bought this commercial tool that does it. Why can't you do it?
But there are sometimes adding these features or capabilities are like
an obscene amount of work.
Uh
Phipps is a big deal, especially Gripe is written in,
go in getting anything and go to build
as a Phipps 1 40-2. Just, just using Phipps 1 40-2. Crypto
is a huge deal. Redhead actually made it really easy, it looks like,
but you have to, it, you,
you're building like a Frank and Go application
at that point because it's calling into red hats
PS 1 40-2 open SSL instead of putting it all in the GOBI.
So now you can only run it on the Red Hat system and it's, it is what it is.
But anyway, anyway, like here's the deal, right? So
I'm a project,
I get these requests
and I can of course say no, it's very frustrating.
But it's again, like it comes back to that like open source isn't fair
because there's nothing stopping people from making these silly requests.
There's nothing stopping people from profiting from
it and like sort of hijacking it and you know, being more popular,
which we've also seen happen.
And it's like,
yeah, like,
because some people are just better at seo like search engine optimization than,
you know, the original developer.
And, and that's, and again, it's just, it's really unfair, but it's also like, well,
that's just kind of how it is.
Does that my suspicion is that is exceedingly rare
that that happens I think if you have
a moderately successful and popular open source package,
forking, it
-- almost never works.
-- There's, I, I, there's been a,
there was some articles
of successful forks, I can probably count on one hand.
Well, and there was also, you know,
there's the use cases where people are kind of forking it to add it
to their resume to make it look like they did it things like that,
you know,
-- And again,
-- that would be
impressive, impressively dodgy. I would, I would love to see someone CV with that.
Let me put it this way. I've seen people's github
repos where it's like,
like the level of your issue comments versus the level of your code.
These are two like,
you know,
you,
you hire somebody with a phd to write your essay about the Korean War or whatever,
you know.
Um, but again, and, and this is fair or not fair, this is
allowed, but is it fair? Is it ethical?
Is it moral, is it, you know, is it, and part of it too, is it sort of,
does it add to the sustainability?
And does it, does it make it a better place or is it just they're kind of littering?
Well, ok, look, this is a topic. I was curious if we would get to
and we did, where you asked, what does it add to the sustainability?
And I think if you look at
just capitalist
society
and this is not, I, I love capitalism. Right.
I don't want to go on anyone think I'm
like some socialist or communist with this rant.
Oh, dude, I've read, like,
I've studied the economic history of Russia and it's like, nope, I do not want that.
That is not communism though. That is cronyism. But that's another story.
-- It's
-- not as ugly anyway, it's like democracy. It's terrible.
-- But it's the least worst thing we've kind of discovered.
-- I agree.
Right. So anyway,
history has shown us that corporate corporations
will never do the right thing.
And I'm using air quotes when I say, right, unless forced to.
And so saying, I expect companies to pay for open source,
I expect companies to contribute back to open source
saying I expect companies to be good citizens in the
open source world is almost certainly never going to
happen unless they are somehow forced to do it.
It's like saying I expect them to, you know, be environmentally conscious and,
you know, socially responsible.
-- Like, no,
-- don't pollute.
I mean, there are companies will literally move states and countries
so they can pollute like
it is,
they, they do what is cheapest
and right now strip mining open source for most of them is exceedingly cheap.
Well, also more to the point,
there's no other option
like if you need to put something together that has a web server,
a web server is now so complex
that
you can't write it. Like, like lib curl
is a great example.
There are how many hundreds of people, years of knowledge and work into a uh a
lib curl into a web client basically.
And to replicate even 10% of the functionality would be
tens of years
-- of work.
-- A competent human could probably write
a very simplistic http library
in a week. But
there are literally millions of corner cases. The corner cases
are what curl does exceedingly well.
But that's like, you know, I mean, that's like saying I could,
I could build a basic functioning car in a week
and you could, but it would probably kill you the week after.
Yeah,
I just,
I keep coming back to the fact that there is no other option for these companies,
like software is so complex nowadays
that
you can't, you just,
you can't. And then also
they're already stuck here like they're already in it.
It's not like they're coming in fresh.
No, no, they're already all here using open source
and there's no way out. And so how, how do we encourage them?
Maybe instead of um trying for the panacea of like, oh,
they'll be good citizens and contribute back and stuff,
but at least get them to stop littering and stop kind of, you know,
crushing the hopes and dreams of open source debs.
And I'm just, I, I don't think this issue can really be solved.
I maybe maybe I,
I think about this a lot because part of my job is to think about stuff like this.
But
I think
this is
we are thinking about the problem and trying to address it in
the incorrect way because we see people strip mining open source.
We see people using open source and not giving back. We see people
like stealing but not really because it's technically legal stealing open source
and,
and trying to sell it to someone else.
And so our obsession is focusing on
the unethical consumption of open source. And I don't think that's
the place to focus on because I don't think it works. It's kind of like
imagine telling a company
you're polluting into this park, like you need to make the park nicer
and they're gonna be like, great,
just we'll put the pipe up the other end of the factory
and then the park is fine, right? Because there's,
I think this is where
some of the government regulation around
like keeping track of the software you have
and having certain standards around like vulnerabilities where I think if,
if organizations are forced to say, create
bombs and keep track of them, if organizations are forced to
have vulnerability reports and keep track of them,
that changes some of the incentives.
Now, I think because like,
if I have an S bomb and I have to give an S bomb to you when I sell the software
and I have to give you the vulnerability report or you
just create your own because you have the S bomb.
Now we have different incentives because if I'm looking,
it's kind of like if I sell a car
it's going to have a safety rating and if it does a safety rating of zero,
I'm gonna be like, I don't know about that. You know, and I think some of this, like s
mom and vulnerability and these efforts,
they're not there yet,
but I think they're approaching that like
safety rating type territory where the incentive isn't
to be a good steward of open source.
The incentive is if I don't take care of my house, I can't sell on this other side.
Well, part of that requires mature consumption, right?
Like car safety is a good example.
And to be clear, I don't,
I, I want companies to consume open source
and I want open source to be healthy enough that a lot of companies
can consume it without giving back because
I don't want people reinventing the wheel.
I don't want people running their own web servers.
Like I've, I've seen what happens when that happens. It's not good
-- like,
-- well, and, and I don't, I don't think they ever will.
I think fundamentally most corporations are consuming open source as
part
of a larger thing, right?
Where they're building product, they're building services.
Well,
it's like I want there to be this kind of common knowledge base that
you can just use for free and get a certain level of standard,
like everybody should know at this point that if you're building a car,
three point seatbelts and airbags, like, even I know that I'm not a car engineer.
You know, there's this basic level of knowledge that you don't even have to pay for.
It's just, it's common, it's best practices, it's whatever you want to call it.
And I want there to be more of that so that we can level up the whole industry because,
like, I look at IOT
and there's absolutely no way I want them running anything but Linux
-- because anything else is, is terrible.
-- That's not true.
The James Lowe Space telescope is running the X works.
-- Yeah. Good luck connecting to that thing and attacking it.
-- That is true.
I wonder what the security VX works looks like on, on earth.
Yeah. So more to the point, I want my light bulbs to be cheap and functional.
I don't want
a James Webb level quality of light bulb. I want a light bulb that costs five bucks.
-- That's true. As opposed to a what 9 billion dollar
-- light bulb.
It's tough. I mean, I,
I don't know what the answer.
And part of me also wonders though,
is it maybe not as bad as we think it is because for all we know,
like 20% of open source is now being funded indirectly by people who
have jobs at these companies who are doing it on the side.
No, no, it's not.
And we, well, maybe we don't, we don't know. You made that number up.
I think one of the important numbers though is like I looked at all that
data and half of the popular N PM packages and half of the popular Python packages
are
one when maintained
and so a lot of them are individual and some people are
perfectly happy just doing it on the weekend and they don't care.
Some people are annoyed, everyone's taking their stuff and profiting from it.
There's,
it's the gamut and I think,
I mean, this is a trap we fall into all the time. We literally fallen into it right now.
It's like open source isn't a thing.
Open source is a million things that we put into the same bucket.
Well, we can't even agree on what an open
source license is.
Uh, no, we can.
An open source license is a
license approved by the O si
that is the literal definition of open source.
You don't have to agree with it, but it is the literal definition.
I would and I would argue that that is
incomplete because there's a whole pile of licenses that are
open source that they don't cover and so on and so forth. Right. Yes.
Yes.
And I would also argue the vast majority
of open source licenses today are woefully outdated
compared to society. Uh Bruce
Perens has,
I know we've talked about this before Bruce has a really nice
talk where he kind of goes into a lot of this stuff.
Well, I mean, nobody could have imagined the services stuff 20 years ago
-- to the degree it is now,
-- or even just open source being used
20 years ago.
If I would have told you literally,
every software product on the planet will contain open source in 20 years.
I would have been, like,
no way. Like that's ridiculous. Never happened.
And, oh,
-- look,
-- but economically companies love free stuff. Yeah.
Right. Oh, absolutely.
Well,
it's funny you say that they used to claim open source didn't work.
I mean, the, the,
the beginnings of the software composition analysis products
were based around like this concept of like
you have to find the open source because your developers are trying to sneak it in.
Right? And it was all about control and then it turned into.
-- But
-- then what happened is they figured out what it would cost to replace that open
-- with written stuff and, and the answer is you can't do that.
-- Right. Right.
And so then it turned into, OK, so you have open
source, but you need to know what it is
and then it turned into, oh, that GP L license,
you got to watch out for that because if you ship
something with GP L now you have to open source,
your entire application
and
it's complicated,
you can engineer around that and companies often do.
There's many ways around it. Right. Right. And,
and, well, it's actually funny too because there's, there's this perception
that if you release a product with GP L in it, you have to open it.
It's like, no, you don't like if it's an accident,
there are accommodations for that, you just replace it and move on.
That's another story.
But anyway, the point is that
if we look at this whole environment kind of what's going on
there,
there's everything from people being paid to
work on open source by their companies.
There's people doing it for free that are happy to do it for free.
There's people who are doing it for free that are annoyed that someone's taking it.
There's no easy answer.
There's no one thing to say is right or wrong. And, and I think
this is part of why open source is unfair.
Like it's unfair that some people get to work on their project
as their job and others don't right. It's unfair
that a company can take my work
and not even acknowledge it's being done.
Well, part of it though is they kind of have to at some point do that because
there's so much
knowledge and information going into a modern product.
I can't acknowledge every single like, oh, you know,
this person came up with this idea 20 years ago that we're now leveraging,
I mean with,
with software,
at least there is that sort of attribution piece that is possible because like,
I don't know,
like who decided to make tables?
Like, at some point,
somebody decided to make a table and it was a good idea as it turns out,
you know, so if I, if I make tables and ship them, I'm not going to be like, you know,
hey, this caveman og came up with this great idea.
We call tables and, you know, we should give him credit for it. Right.
The wheel, let's use the wheel.
A table is just
-- a rock. Like at least a wheel required some
-- invention
or something like, you know, a steel belted radio wheel.
Like, hey, let's make this thing out of rubber with steel belts in it.
So it's durable and doesn't blow up and like takes a beating.
That's a great idea. Like I, I don't know
that I'm not even talking about that though, Kurt,
I'm talking about there are open source projects that like run the world,
right? Like
there are things in N PM. Everyone depends on. Look for Jay
uh log
for J is a great example. Log
for J was a couple of people kind of doing it on the side
and it turned out everyone was using it.
And when there was a problem with it, everyone lost their minds.
-- Like
-- good old Jasper Lib J peg, right?
The guy wrote it as a thesis defense and because it was open source and it
could turn a string of data into a Jpeg on your screen.
Everybody used it.
That to me is part of the beauty of open source. Like now
how many thousands or tens of thousands of people, years of effort did that library?
-- That one library safe?
-- Oh, it's, it's astronomical without question.
But,
but now we get to the question of companies aren't necessarily tracking this stuff.
Companies sometimes don't know what they're doing.
And so again,
we kind of come back to the unfair that they're profiting off of
work others have done and they don't even know they're profiting off,
profiting off work others have done.
Well, I, that's part of the supply chain and value add.
Like I, I consume this widget in a way that I get to,
you know, like buy me, there's a washer and a dryer.
The guy who made the screws is important,
but
I'm sorry, you make screws, you're not, we're not gonna pay you $7 a screw
unless it's for the James Webb telescope.
That's a good question. I wonder how much they pay for a screw,
probably pretty expensive being that they're made out
of like titanium or some exotic craziness.
Right. Well, and the tolerances are probably ridiculous. But,
but no, and, and I think your point is valid because there are open source libraries
that are
simplistic like, like what's the, the left path? Right?
That was a very simple library and the
developer obviously got angry about something and deleted it
and it's a library that you could reproduce in a couple of minutes if you needed it.
And so
like, that's an example.
Even though it was in every project, no one's gonna be like, oh, this,
this library is critical, we're going to pay millions of dollars for this library,
right?
Like that's very different versus saying
the Linux kernel is critical and we literally need this to
be like rock solid and spot on all the time.
More to the point.
I keep coming back to uh it's a bad analogy, but it's,
it reminds me of copyright in that people are like, oh, we need copyright.
So artists will do work. And I'm like, no, we don't
cave paintings. There's my counter
argument.
No, no.
It always astounds me that there's like people who
work in the food services industry because when you learn
the hours they work and the pay they make. It's like,
-- why would you
-- do that?
I, I agree. I
think about that all the time. Why do people start restaurants?
Like you start prep, work at 10 in the morning and you're there till midnight.
I know,
I know, man, I know
what
you know,
and but these people have this like deep seated
urge or voice in their head that they need to,
they need to bake or they need to make paintings so they need to play music or sing
or like in your case, in my case, we, we do a podcast. Like we don't, like,
-- we rant about things on the internet,
-- you know, it's, and,
and what gets me is there's this really deep
seated need for people to create and express themselves.
And open source is one of those ways, like, how many people have written,
you know, like little scratch my h open source projects that then, you know,
turn into, oh, my God.
Like
now, well, likely
Tovaz.
I, I can't afford UNIX. So. Huh, I'll just write my own.
Right. Right.
I mean, I remember those days when I didn't have any money, I was like, oh,
I'll just build something to do that for me.
Just go pay for the service for 10 bucks a month rather than in the past.
I would have written a couple of scripts to do it.
That's right. Exactly.
So, exactly that
it, it, I think
it won't die,
but at the same time
the benefit is so massive. Like
I can't even fathom a world where everybody would have to write their own web server.
Like we, it would set the industry back 20 years.
-- I, I,
-- it, it, it, you don't have to because it's never going to happen.
I mean, that's the reality of it. Like we, we have these things, we have open source.
You are correct that
I think a lot of,
a lot of these single maintainer projects are
there because people want to be creative.
And so
as long as you don't like literally badger them to
death to the point that they want to quit,
they're going to keep doing it.
And, and I do think that's probably one of the issues is
you're going to see
somebody has something that becomes popular and then for some reason,
it starts getting attention
and
it's not out of the question that people will show up and create like github
issues making unreasonable requests.
And the problem is like, let's say 1% of people make unreasonable requests.
But if you have 10 million users,
that's a lot of freaking people now versus if you have 100 users, it's manageable.
Well, even just
like, even just the attention to read these issues and close them out.
Yeah.
And the other thing is it's not so much that they're willing,
it's not so much that they're making unreasonable requests.
It's that they're,
they're not willing to help or contribute or even
in many cases really speck out what they want.
They're like,
I want
X, well, what do you mean by X? And they're like, just make it,
you know, I think that's an unreasonable request. Well, that's what I'm saying.
Right? Is that
it's not even just that they're asking for something complicated in many cases,
they're not really asking a well formed question,
-- you know.
-- Well, and there's always that again, unreasonable request. Um
This is why I, one of the things I love is when
I'm part of like some working group or something.
And that's trying to solve a problem and there's always people that are like, oh,
we should do this
and I'll say
you should do that.
Like, if you want that done you need to go do it and they're like, oh, well,
I don't think we need to do it.
I'm, like, interesting.
So, it's ok if I do it,
but as soon as you have to do it now, it's not important.
Well, I think we all agree that putting a bell on the cat is a good idea.
Yeah.
Yeah. Anyway, I mean, I'm gonna call this one man.
We've been, we're, we're over time but like
it's,
yeah, open source is unfair.
That's it.
What it is.
I kind of can't help but wonder are we gonna get to a situation where
more and more developers
hopefully, maybe realize I, because I think there is maybe a,
I don't want to say a third way out of this, but
I can imagine some developers just sort of
doing open source development in stealth, like the releasing it publicly
but, you know, ignoring the issues, ignoring, like, just
really kind of making themselves unavailable.
-- Like, I mean,
-- you can do that now and just don't read the issues.
Well, but I,
I feel like I think more and more are going
to consciously choose to do this to avoid these problems.
I, I don't think so. I think the, the social
the innate social desire of humans.
We want,
we want to know people are using our creations and we
want other people to come work with us on our creations.
And so I think the,
it, it again comes back to what you're saying. It's cave paintings.
It's not just cave paintings
because as soon as someone painted that,
what do you think?
The first thing they did was they went and got someone else to show them what they did.
And that's the second half of cave paintings. And anyway,
all right, that man, that's probably a show in itself
I think. Well, if there's one thing I can say is if you are doing open
sourcing your stress, maybe take a step back,
you know, take a breath, take a week off because
realistically the world's not gonna end.
Not, not because of you.
And I, I just, so many
other things I feel like a lot of people get caught up in this, you know,
and it's sometimes you need to take a step back
because I like that happened with the DWF and, and,
and vulnerability ID assignments and stuff where I just,
I was like, you know what, I'm,
I'm,
-- I need to take a step back because this is taking up too much of my life.
-- Absolutely.
That's right. Take care of yourself folks. All right, I'm calling it.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening. Go to social
security podcast.com. Hit up. The show. Not, it's Easy Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag Hit us up on social media. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day. You too.
Thanks everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.