Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
So I have a sort of funny story to tell. My son
is part of the robotics club at his high school.
And one of the things they want to do is add like the computer
vision thing, like where you can detect a red object, you know, in the,
in the screen and all that stuff and,
and they didn't really know what to do.
So I thought I will learn how open CV works,
which is the Python Library that does this stuff and then I can help them.
And obviously the intent being I, I, if, if I want to help, like, guide
the Children,
I don't want to just do their work for them. So I need to know what's going on. Right.
And there's this weird color format they use that.
I've never heard of called HSV, which is huge saturation value, I think.
I don't know. Anyway, it's like a complete mystery to me.
I've tried to figure it out and I'm like, I'm too dumb to learn this.
And so
the
kids laughed at me because I just literally wrote a
program that I hold the color up to the screen
and it calculates to the HSV value for me and then spits it out and they're like,
isn't this harder than learning?
I'm like, no, this is way easier than learning something new.
When me and a friend,
he got a dedicated dial up and we had to
figure out subnetting and we figured it out like,
basically
backwards wrong but got it working
because there was no documentation on it.
Uh There were I ETF standards, I'm sure
which we
-- couldn't access because we didn't have internet access.
-- Just don't use
subnetting. Just have a flat network that encompasses everything. It's fine.
I
remember
when I was in college, this was in the late nineties,
the university owned a class B which was a
192.168 dot And then
the two octets after that.
And it was, I don't, I don't remember what it even was,
but rather than segmenting their network,
they operated the entire university is one flat class B network hardcore.
I like it.
Like,
it was something you could get anywhere. You could mass scan the thing. It was just
in hindsight.
I'm amazed anything worked.
Yeah, I'm kind of. Yeah.
Yeah.
Well, it's like every time,
every time somebody complains about plugging in a network cable wrong and
breaking it and it's like you don't have spanning tree protocol enabled like
you,
how does your network ever work? Let alone reliably. You know what I mean?
When?
Yeah, a simple mistake brings the whole thing down.
Or my all time favorite is like, you know,
people accidentally turning on a DH P server
and, you know, it just totally thrown the network into a, into a epileptic fit.
-- Basically,
-- that's
a treat for sure.
-- And weirdly enough switches deal with that now,
-- uh, they're, they're better than,
yeah.
-- Yeah. And I mean, I remember hubs back in the day.
-- Oh,
yeah.
Yeah,
I remember an ISP locally using hubs because I
ran a network sniffer to solve an email problem.
And I was like, whose email is that?
And it was, well, here's the thing if you're selling 10 megabit,
so bursting to 10 megabit, unlimited use connections.
What's the easiest way to meter that?
And it's stick all your customers on a 10 megabit hub?
-- Oh, I suppose. Right.
-- Because then they can't ever use more than 10 megabits.
That's an interesting idea.
Well,
the only challenge being is that all the customers can see all the customers data.
-- Yeah, but that's not their problem.
-- I would. Well,
fun story. They also put their email server on it.
Of course, why wouldn't you
so good old away net
anyway,
they're long gone.
So, yeah.
Well, I mean, some of these vulnerabilities recently, I just got to wonder.
Uh, no, no, no.
I think this is good and healthy. I think
we exist
in
this unique place in security where
people are,
they're becoming more aware.
There's more research happening, there's more communication.
This is great. This is great.
Oh, yeah, I, I know, I just, I'm kind of wondering like,
how are we still making these mistakes?
Ok. No, it's fine. I want to start with the Twitter,
the, the Twitter story. So I'll get the quick summary here. Basically,
some researchers search
github for Twitter secrets. They found a bunch
and the way they told people their secrets were
in Twitter is they sent a tweet as the person
basically saying, oh, hey, your credentials are in github.
And
like
I heard this and I of course,
laughed out loud because I think it's really funny and then I'm like, wait a minute,
this is probably breaking the law.
And then I also thought, however,
my, I have a strong suspicion if you just did the research, you mailed a lot of people
and well, assuming you can even contact some of them.
II, I
don't think the story would have gotten a lot of attention,
but I think this particular stunt
is going to get them an enormous amount of attention.
Well, realistically given a Twitter account attaching an email address to it.
Uh because email is the only push protocol we have that everybody uses.
And this speaks to that Twitter is a push protocol.
And if I can, well, essentially if I can push something to your Twitter account
yet. There's a good chance you might see it and read it.
And so that's what they did and, you know,
yeah, they actually technically broke the law by, you know,
computer access and I'm kind of surprised their Pinata Hub
Twitter account wasn't closed down for, like,
some sort of terms of service violation.
But, um,
it's,
who knows? Well, because, like youtube is removing videos that, like
g,
like, uh that teach how to hack and stuff. And I'm kind of like, sort of get it.
But like, on the other hand,
how does like the lock picking lawyer has over 1000 videos there.
-- How does that work?
-- It's completely uneven.
All these services take the,
my suspicion is, it probably works like the,
the FTC,
is it FTCFCC in the United States where they
really don't do anything until they get complaints,
you know,
when they get complaints now they make a big
deal about whatever it is they're getting complaints about.
There was a good study about that that basically found out that the vast majority of
sec complaints were a couple of small organizations
that just organized letter writing campaigns basically.
But anyways, that doesn't surprise me at all.
No, I think, like, as we learned from Log
for Jay, there's just,
there's so much stuff out there that's
kind of a, I don't want to say abandoned because it's not like abandoned,
abandoned if it was.
But it's, it's in the sense of, you know,
somebody has an old junkie car on their lawn and they just don't care.
And, you know, the same thing with their, like, there's, there's
tons of Twitter accounts that people set up and just kind of never use
well and people check things to get
and they forget and they don't realize they've checked secrets in and there is
and not only that, so one of the other things, so if you checked in, let's say a, a
Bitcoin wallet into
github, that thing's going to be cleaned out in about five minutes.
Whereas if you check in Twitter credentials, like they don't really have any value,
it's gonna be hard to
most
of the people
and yet the,
depending on the account right there was that the famous Twitter hack,
that teenager that got in and then, you know,
got into those famous accounts and did the Bitcoin Doubling scheme,
-- which was beyond stupid, but
-- I'm pretty sure that most of these accounts
are not that
-- they're
-- low value for sure.
That's the thing. Like if I found
like a Twitter accounts credentials that had four followers and I couldn't tell
exactly where this account was, like, who was behind it or if it was, you know,
you know what I mean?
I'd be like, hey, whatever, it's not worth trying to deal with this.
I mean, and that's the reality of that, I think,
whereas when you compromise thousands of accounts
and you tweet as them. Now we have a story.
Well, and it's also, it's,
it's the most efficient way to do it.
Like, as a researcher,
are you gonna spend even 10 seconds trying to track down a Twitter account?
No,
you don't have time for that.
It,
yeah, just blast it out.
Yeah. Yeah.
I mean, that's always one of the challenges is when you find, say
1000 problems, how do you report that at scale?
You, you kind of can't in most instances.
Well, and even if you do automate it, you,
you still have to spend quite a few hours automating it.
Yeah.
Yep. Yep. It's, it's, it's a hard problem for sure.
Whereas just sending out a bunch of tweets, that's funny.
Well, and people do react
well to these sort of a slow trickle problem people will happily ignore.
But, you know, all of a sudden
you have
some, you know, like
AAA, like, for example, a 30 car pileup will make the news every time on I, whatever,
you know, because it's snowing and blowing.
But
in that same 24 hour period, how many people, you know,
went off the road because they're driving like idiots a
lot.
Yeah,
it's not
right.
Plane crashes always make the news whereas
infinitely more people are killed by car accidents every day.
But
that's not news.
I just wonder sometimes because a lot,
there's a lot of security problems that don't lend themselves well,
to being easily able to publicize them and get
people's attention and get people to pay attention.
And this
is
literally the topic of the day is how do we talk about some of
the security stuff in a way that maybe gets the attention it needed and,
and log for J, obviously, we're going to be picking on this for years to come.
But like the, the J MD I problem behind log for J was reported in what 2016 at, at,
at Black Hat or something or at defcon, I forget which conference the,
the point being that.
So the JNDN problem was reported,
but it wasn't reported in a way that was sensational or noteworthy.
So it was functionally ignored until someone created a functional exploit.
And now all of a sudden it's very real and very serious, right?
They're, they're fundamentally
they weren't different.
It was just one of them managed to get our attention.
Yeah.
Well, it's like this recent uh what is it? The P
kit, the local privilege escalation and Paul kits PK exec.
And I like how
Kace, I mean, and
Kiss does great research, right?
And they intentionally did not release exploit code because they're like,
you know, we want to give the defenders some more time than exploiters.
We'll give you two hours basically. Yeah, two hours later,
there's now, well, there's now two github
repos with exploits,
you know, I, I personally think in this case, Kac
should have just released the exploit code because it would have gotten,
it would have lit a lot more fires under people.
You know, they would have said it was irresponsible and then ironically,
probably nobody would have bothered to release exploit code because Wallace did.
But yeah, it took like Attackers two hours or not even Attackers.
It took just random people to
two hours to come up and post this on
github.
-- Yeah, the Attackers probably had it immediately. It's fine. Yeah.
-- So I, yeah,
I, I personally I'm kind of, I used to be like, you know, we should do no harm,
we should blah, blah, blah, you know, don't do exploit code unless you have to or de
weaponize it.
And now I'm kind of like,
yeah, I mean,
that's, well, I, I think the world is different if you look back 10 years.
So this is a heat buffer overflow exploit and it's kind of complicated how it works.
It's super interesting, go go read about it if you want. But basically
exploiting this would have been kind of difficult because we didn't have all
of the tools and the process and the knowledge we have today.
Whereas today,
there's so much amazing tooling that exists
that you, if you know where a bug is, you can pretty much write an exploit very,
very quickly because the ability to do so is now
a very low bar compared to where it was.
And so this is why the whole, oh, don't release exploit code.
If someone reports a bug,
the tooling is so good you have to assume
in a matter of hours,
any remotely competent attacker can turn that into a weaponized exploit.
Well, I,
I just remember back at eyesight and I defense there was a guy whose job it was, was,
you know,
to take essentially it was voted the most severe Microsoft bug of Microsoft
Tuesday and to make an exploit code for it in 24 hours.
Right.
And I don't think he ever failed.
-- And
-- I'm not surprised at
all.
-- And, and this is like over 10 years ago,
-- right.
That was a super specialized skill set. And you had very little tooling.
Now,
there's all this tooling that exists. You can inspect memory, you can decomp
things you can,
it's, it's phenomenal. It's like
there's never been a better time
to be involved in this sort of research.
It's amazing.
Yeah. So I kind of,
I suspect overall it's probably going to be better in many cases
to just
release the exploit code from day one and get the
press coverage and actually get people to deal with it.
I don't know. I, I think it would still be apr nightmare if you did it.
Like,
-- I, I don't know if I'd do it if I was them.
-- Here's the thing
realistically, is this the only vulnerability that your system has?
And the answer is no.
Right. That's the thing I I keep coming back to is like
this is one reason II I got the cloud security lines
off of infrastructure as a service and onto platforms of services.
Because
what value can I add to keep a system up to date?
Like the, the best I can do is I can apply the vendor patches.
I'm not gonna, you know, keep a ear to the ground and apply prepa
and compile it and reboot it before, you know,
an hour before the vendor releases the patch.
Literally, the value add I as assisted man with a quarter century of experience
is basically nothing
like
there's so little value add I can provide.
There's no doubt that somebody like Hiroko
can't do it better or at least as good as me, it's, you know,
it's somebody else's problem now because I I
there will always be a Linux vulnerability
that somebody can use locally to exploit to root that will be exploitable
-- for a few hours before I can patch it
-- a few hours.
Even in the sense of
in the sense of if like and that's assuming the
vendors get the patches out like right away right away.
Well, like I got to sleep and stuff.
I, you know, do we have a 24 7 ops team applying patches to our Linux servers?
Well, actually, yes, because we outsourced it to
-- Hiku
-- now
it's
you, you don't know
and look anyone running servers, you can't just reboot, whatever
you, you need outage windows for stuff like this, you know.
Yeah.
Well, and even if you have highly resilient systems and don't need outage windows,
it's still, somebody has to be awake to deal with it in case it goes south or whatever.
So,
yeah, I mean, ii, I
fundamentally think the way
I'm going to say something that's probably not very nice.
But if you're doing it the same way we did it 20 years ago,
you're basically doomed from a security perspective.
Don't do it the way we did it 20 years ago. There's so many nice tools. Now,
how many,
how many small medium businesses do you know that
are still not using any automation at all?
-- Lots.
-- I, some of those are special
but you get what I'm saying, right. It's,
they're, they're basically doomed. It's,
you know, if you refuse to build,
using modern methods and materials and put in like locks, you,
you can't have a physically secure building.
I mean, I, you're,
you're entering a dangerous territory.
I'm going to pull you back.
I think the biggest thing with this though is that this also presumes
that these vulnerabilities are found
by an organization that does coordinate disclosure
and the vendors can fix it quickly
and you know, and so on.
There's a lot, there's a lot of assumptions because for example,
as we found out in shell shock, oh, we fixed it.
Oops. Oh, we fixed it again for real this time
and I think it was what four or five vulnerabilities in total.
Yeah, there were a couple, I mean shell shock is special,
I think because for a variety of reasons
it it look coordinate disclosure is difficult
talking about this stuff is difficult.
I don't know the whole story. Coal is historically has been really good
about treating all of this stuff well and reporting it in the right ways.
But
I think
the challenge today is even more unique because
like let's take this policy kit thing where
it was reported, it primarily affects Linux distributions,
it was reported to the distributions.
But if you find something that say is a critical issue in like a node package,
there's no good way to tell. Like who, who would you tell? Right? You can tell N PM,
you can tell the node project
and what then like,
you know what I mean?
It's not like you have a couple of say distributions, distributing this stuff,
it's basically available to the whole world.
And so it creates
a unique problem. I think in that regard.
Well, there's, there's no coordinating body,
not even like security wise, there's just no coordinating body.
This is all a wonderful mishmash of open source.
And, and I don't, I don't necessarily think there should be either.
I think this is one of the things that,
that always scares me a little bit when we talk about the open source universe
is like there was just a White House meeting,
there's a bunch of notes all over the internet about that where the White House was,
was discussing open source.
And
I think it's easy for a lot of us to fall
into the trap of thinking of open source is one thing,
open source is like 7 million ant colonies that are all independent and a blue whale.
And sure,
you know what I mean? Like you can't, like you could say, oh, all open
source projects should generate S bombs. Well, I mean, I, I have like 70 repos in my my
-- github. Right. For me, I'm not generating S bombs for those.
-- What about the open
source projects that do documentation?
What about the open source projects that don't do code?
Right. Right.
-- No, absolutely. You
-- know, like it's
even just assuming open source means
so like software is is wrong,
creative
commons license. That's part of the open source world.
-- It's,
-- it's complicated and I think this is one of the challenge.
And again, this comes back to kind of the grand theme of talking about security
in ways that are effective, right?
Like there's stunt hacking, which generally is effective,
there's coordinate disclosure
which can be effective depending upon the circumstances.
That's assuming you have somebody to coordinate with.
And I think that's no, and that's a big
part of the problem is
like
there's no where like your N PM package example, there's OK,
there's definitely the package maintainer,
hopefully who's alive and cares and has time to deal with this because for all,
you know, they could be on sabbatical for six months.
You know, people do like to take time off once in a while,
especially from unpaid work.
It's weird. I know.
Right.
So
there's, there's like nobody to coordinate with. There's no
sort of implicitly.
Linux vendors have registered their interest in, you know, well,
in the sense of like Debbie and Chipsy packages were interested in them,
we want to help take care of them.
Same with Red Hat, same with ubuntu, same with blah, blah, blah, blah,
right?
But with N PM.
Yeah, no, that's not how that ecosystem works.
-- It, it fundamentally ships and uses software differently
-- or most of open
source today. It's not just N PM. I mean, how many libraries are we using that
aren't controlled by?
I mean, like if you're going to Red Hat, for example, for all of your R PM,
right? That's kind of a funnel.
Whereas
when I'm installing Python packages
who is, is distributing those if I'm installing N PM packages, who is,
you know what I mean? It's
such a different environment and ecosystem.
And yet we still talk about open source as this like singular entity
that
-- we can somehow solve.
-- I mean, we can't even agree on what is an open source license.
-- You know,
-- we, we can the O SI is quite clear that they control that
and there's people that disagree with that
-- in the open source community.
-- I agree with that also,
I feel like the O SI has let us all down by basically not
changing anything in the last 30 plus years.
But that's another story we want to talk about today.
Well, see,
and this is what I'm saying, like how,
you know,
how can we agree on what open source is when we can't even agree on what open source is?
And, and
yeah,
and I mean, but, and that's fundamentally one of the inherent, it's one of those,
you know, like I, I always tell the truth.
I'm lying right now. Things is this is one of the inherent
challenges and beauties of open sources that open source in and of itself is
what people define as open source to some degree and it may
or may not be open source depending on who you ask,
right?
And, and not only that, if I'm a developer,
I probably don't really care.
There's a lot of like node packages that come with these bizarre licenses that
are not o si approved but are consumable by me as a developer.
And if it solves my problem,
I don't really care, I'm going to use it, you know,
you gotta love it.
It's well. And the thing is also, I love that people are like
just discovering how much open source there is in the world like this, literally,
these White House meetings are like the A FTC and stuff.
Are
we, we kind of use a lot of this open source, huh?
Like a lot of, and I don't mean just directly but
we rely on companies that rely on this stuff
and they're just discovering that. And it's kind of like, yeah, like, no offense.
But me and Josh, we, we've kind of known this for two decades.
Well, I,
I think a lot of the old school open source people have been very aware of this.
But again,
how do we communicate it?
We have been very bad at communicating a lot of these details because I,
I think generally speaking, especially from the security perspective,
we've taken the view of I'm going to try to scare you straight
and scaring people straight has worked uh zero times in the history of humanity.
So that just isn't an option
and it's even worse than that because then we also pull the whole, it's open source,
open
source owes you nothing good luck with that.
That too, which I mean that that part is true though,
-- but
-- more to the way it's not whether or not it's true.
That's what the open source community is
capable of doing the open source community.
Like OK,
let's bring this up those insane questionnaires
being sent out to everybody saying like,
are you affected by log for J what are you doing about log for J blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah.
Cool. If I have a contractual relationship with you and you're paying me money.
I might actually reply to that email
but if I'm an open source project and you send that to me,
saw it off.
Yeah, I, I agree with that. I think those are automated systems gone haywire
and shame on the companies that are
just adding open source maintainers into their systems
as, as if they are a vor
more to the
point.
It doesn't matter how we feel about this morally or ethically
from just a, a version of reality that we live in.
-- The majority of open source maintainers can't and won't deal with that stuff.
-- No.
And they shouldn't and, and good for them don't, don't. There's no reason to,
but again, we come back to this communication aspect of it. All
of
we can't talk about this necessarily and, and because it's not well understood,
you have,
I think some groups that think they understand open
source and they think open source is one thing
and then they have all these big meetings and they talk about things and,
and the reality is my favorite part is so the White House has a meeting.
They're gonna probably come up with some sort of guidance
and if the open source universe decides the guidance is crap, like
that's it.
What are you gonna do?
You can't make them do things
well.
And I've been thinking about this a lot because it,
it intersects with what we're doing with the Global Security Database.
And I, I'm really coming to the realization of
even if you get a good chunk of developers on board wanting to do it
numerically at most, it's going to be one or 10%
maybe 20% or 30% if you're lucky.
And so again, back to that whole, you know,
black holes don't care if you believe in them or not.
Like if I want to see a world where with good GSD coverage,
well,
somebody has to go do that GSD coverage and it's
probably not going to be all the end developers.
No, no, absolutely not. And that's it.
And then, and I don't have an answer yet as to like, how do we get that coverage,
but at least, at least I'm not trying to solve a problem that can't be solved.
And I think that's part of this whole universe we have to start solving.
I like one of my favorite examples is
I keep hearing people say
that the projects,
open source projects should be responsible for building their own s bombs
for the project,
right?
Why, why is that their problem? And if they, if they don't, what are you gonna do?
You're gonna not use their project.
No, you won't.
If
it's the only library that does what you need, you're going to use it no matter what.
-- And
-- the thing is what tooling are they going to use?
Because there's so many like I remember the XML hashed off stuff.
Do you know how many projects embed
a
of G zip or of XML? So that it'll build on windows?
That's
a slightly different problem.
-- I don't think of those. It's the same thing. I,
-- no, no. What I'm saying though is, is
you want these projects to build S
bomb? Cool.
So where are the really good tools you're going to
give them for free that are easy to use.
Uh There's actually some S
bomb tools that do a good job
of figuring out the dependencies you have embedded source is a very,
very different problem and nothing does that well.
But I also think we've reached a point where that is far less common than it used to be.
I think it is
and I can't prove that that's me making crap up. I'm not gonna pretend it isn't,
but I don't feel like I run into embedded source
nearly as much as we used to back in the day.
Well, but more of the point is unless these github
is rolling out security features that you just have to click a button
to use and how many places are still not using them
-- a lot
-- because they get in the way and they're annoying.
I mean, I, I look, I, my favorite example is Depend
aot,
I love, depend
Aon. I think it's a great tool. But the reality is if
so when, when you run, when you turn to depend a bot for your, your project.
It's going to start telling you about your dependencies you're
using that are out of date or have security issues
or whatever. Right
now, what do I do about that? Depend a bot
has a like, oh, please fix this for me button.
That literally never works
because every time you auto upgrade something, it just all your tests explode and,
and nothing's functional.
So now as a developer and I'm doing this for free in my spare time,
I'm told, oh, you have 30 vulnerabilities in your package.
And I'm like, I don't care,
like I want to work on this little feature I thought of in the shower this morning.
I don't give two craps about the vulnerabilities in my package.
If someone else cares, they can fix it.
Yep. Right.
I mean,
and that's kind of how open source works and that's how open source is going to work
if there's some super critical thing that, that might affect me, OK?
I might think about it. But if it's like a bunch of low issues,
I don't care why, why, why should I care about that stuff?
So, you know what I'm gonna do, I'm gonna turn depend
about off because now my problem goes away.
-- Well,
-- and there's almost never a solid upside for the developer in the sense of,
you know, upgrading these dependencies will definitely make your life better.
It's almost always
best case scenario. This doesn't break anything, worst case scenario.
Oh, it breaks everything.
And now now let's go back to our our communication angle. So
I'm a company using your open source project.
What am I gonna do? Am I gonna send you a mean letter?
Maybe?
Am I gonna, am I gonna
it does happen?
Am I going to spend the time and have one of my developers patch all the packages
maybe? But I have 7000 packages in my product. Do I want to do that? 7000 times?
Look now, I'm not adding features. All I'm doing is managing dependencies.
Congratulations. You've discovered what
Red Hat is like.
But that was literally Redhead's business model and that, that works, right?
But Redhead also has a very constrained number
of packages on purpose because of this,
right?
Whereas if I'm a company of 10 people and I'm building
a web app and my web app has 7000 dependencies,
whatever, like as long as nothing's critical,
-- I'm not touching anyone
-- even if it is critical unless it blows,
-- you know, if a tree falls in the forest and doesn't kill anybody, do we care?
-- Right.
And now we're going to have a situation where we have governments saying
uh you have to patch all of this open
source project.
The open source project is gonna be like, yeah, whatever we don't care.
And now you've got companies using it.
Well,
that's a good point actually because it's the CIA
just has that new guidance like for example,
log for J has this deadline
and they're coming up with those like lists of vulnerabilities,
um both what is being exploited
and some of those have deadlines on them.
Ah So this is where SISA is getting
this right is those deadlines are for federal agencies
CIA is well aware that they can tell a federal agency you have to listen to us,
but they cannot tell anyone else.
-- And so they're very, very good
-- about that.
The F DC though apparently is making noise about
getting companies to fix log for Jay.
There's been some stuff in the press about that. I was
and
I wasn't able to find the original source.
So I didn't mention on the podcast after that whole debacle,
like what can copyright do for you with Apple?
So I actually learned my lesson folks,
but I suspect the FTC is going to wave that
stick around because waving the stick around costs nothing.
It doesn't, I mean, actually, you know, hitting someone with it,
we'll see. But,
but uh I suspect that's kind of
because these sort of soft squishy standards of like, oh,
you have to keep data secure.
What does that even mean?
Like I've been in this industry for 25 years and I don't know what that means.
Well, I think again,
we've not communicated a lot of this correctly and now this is one
thing I will say when you work with organizations like Nist and CIA
and a lot of these
federal agencies,
they are,
they're legendary for
pedantic. This is why,
because there is no question about intent when
you're working with some of these groups.
And that is a good thing.
And that is literally what we need, we need security to be boring and pedantic
and we got the pedantic.
Right.
But
it needs to be accounting.
Exactly that. And I'll apologize to all you accounting nerds
out there.
Yeah, I, I think it's gonna be interesting because, um,
it's just, these systems are so big and complex and interlocking.
I'm not sure anybody actually has a grasp on what the system is anymore,
let alone how to secure it.
Part of it is. Can we even agree on what security means?
No,
no, we can't.
You know,
because for example, a lot of people would want privacy.
-- Well, that's definitely not what Facebook thinks of security.
-- Right.
It's, I mean, it's, it's complicated and I guess we, we need to,
we need to wrap this one up but
like, it's just
as the industry matures, we have to start
understanding how to talk about what we do.
We need more standardized terms, we need more standardized process.
And I think things like involving open source,
I feel like we might have been on some of the right paths,
but now open source is a big deal.
So now we have to redefine everything and I sometimes feel like we're starting over.
I don't know what the answer is.
I don't think there's an easy solution.
I have a strong suspicion.
Every single profession in the history of humanity has gone through this.
They just did it like 300 years ago.
So we don't remember. Whereas what we're doing is very new and welcome to the jungle.
Well,
and the fact that people are talking about it now and talking about it at a high level.
I mean, that's step one.
It, it is,
it's totally step one is as much as I love to harp
on like the White House and big companies talking about open source.
These conversations need to be had,
they're going to get it wrong and that's ok
because every time you get it wrong,
that gives you a new opportunity to get it right.
All right, I'm calling it.
Thank you everyone for listening. Thank you, Kurt.
Go to open social security podcast.com.
Hit up the show, not at Suzy Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye bye.