Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
I'm super, super duper. Excited for our guest today. We have a guest.
We have Joy Lynn Kirui
who is an infosec evangelist covering cloud security
among the top 50 women in cybersecurity,
Africa, 2020 finalist woman hacker of the year Africa,
2020 finalist and Young Cecil Vanguard 2022 among others.
She's a senior cloud security advocate at Microsoft.
She focuses on DEV
ops on github
and Azure, which includes application security. Joy Lynn.
Thank you so much for coming on the show. We are so excited to have you here.
Thank you for having me, Josh.
I don't even know where to start.
I, it was funny,
we were talking in the kind of the pre show about like her curtain eyes,
tumultuous history with Microsoft.
And so I'm excited we're not going to talk
about that today because that's not the topic,
but
I guess Joly,
I'll, why don't you just kind of tell us what
you're up to tell us what you're doing because I've listened to
a bunch of your stuff over the last couple of weeks.
And it is fascinating what's all going on.
Yes. So as you mentioned in my
bio, I do a lot of depth
setups and what I do is mainly train developers on secure coding
as well as automating security within the software development life cycle.
Not only about tooling because Dev
Cup is not only a tooling. So that's where people go wrong.
So it's all about uh culture shifts
because security is everyone's responsibility. So I've been
mainly in the offensive security path um for the last,
OK, for my whole cybersecurity career as an ethical hacker,
what we call security assurance and having worked with developers um helping
them like find security vulnerabilities to the coal that they're building or
um the software that they are actually building.
So, and I've actually seen a lot of pain points,
like even me working with them and on some of the tools that we've actually deployed,
uh which actually give a lot of false positives and whatnot.
Like I've, I've,
I've listened to them complain and they shouldn't complain
a lot like security shouldn't be their problem.
So, yes. Um Yes. So that's what I do in the, in, in brief.
Awesome. I love that.
One thing I'm curious about is so obviously I come
from more of a cloud background now being that I,
you know, I at the cloud security lines
and I'm definitely
one thing I've seen is I feel like with DEV SE
ops, especially
there's this traditional view of like, oh, you know, I build app,
throw it onto server, server person makes server work.
And then in the cloud it's, it seems to be a bit different in that, you know.
Oh, well, for example, the cloud security line, my devs throw the app into Hiroko
and make it work. And I, I literally point to DNS record of them. That is
the extent of my, it support to them
and I pay the Hiroko bill and that's it.
And
one thing I find is,
well,
I find one danger and is this what you're finding a
lot of places where they kind of might ignore that?
Ok, who's running the server because it mostly kind of runs itself. But,
you know, are people missing that because that's,
that's one thing I ran into like,
we've,
we've hit the situation where, you know, who's in charge of X
and it's like, well, it kind of works. So who cares?
Or are you finding people are being conscious of that,
of that?
So, like what I
do
evenings
do your due diligence,
you have to know where your data is actually sitting where your application is.
Like what infrastructure your application is actually, um, sitting on.
So you have to read the fine prints like within the policy, like, um,
so it might be like a software as a service provision.
So you have to know, like whose responsibility is it to secure the infrastructure?
So is it your responsibility to secure the application alone?
And can you also have influence in the infrastructure like um
maybe the reports,
the auditing tool reports that are actually built by that particular platform,
you also need to like have access to that.
So you have to read the fine print like and be very intentional about your security
because I should say like if you don't
that it's actually a repetition. That's actually at risk.
Yeah.
-- So you have to do a lot of due diligence in this case.
-- OK.
So that's really interesting that you say that because
if you look at the history of developers,
developers never had to worry about where the data
was or any of these sorts of things.
You just wrote your application and you threw it over the
fence to somebody and then they had to run it.
So how, I mean, how do you, how do you talk about that?
And I think the other thing too is back in the past, we only had one computer.
So like it was really clear when we put the application on it.
That's where the data was.
OK? So I'll give you an example a scenario.
So I'm a developer, I can say that I am probably like a cloud developer.
So I build my code on an ID
and then I push it to, let's say application service within
Azure. I know my application is already running and it's
running also a database in the cloud.
So as a developer, in most cases,
you just
worry that yes, I've already built my code,
I've compiled it and I've pushed it and it's running
so in traditional days, like you wouldn't care.
Like, ok, so yes, it's already running.
It's no longer my business uh in terms of monitoring, in terms of security as well.
But right now it's more of the developers
and as well as the security team and as well as the operations team working together
and knowing that they all have to make sure that security is incorporated,
they have to do post mortems and they have to,
to avoid the blame game when an exploit or availability is actually exploited and
maybe a lot of money is actually stolen from the company in that,
in that case.
So
yes. So in the cloud, once the data is there,
so there's several regulations as well. We have like um the GDPR.
So whereby if you're using like um customers like in Europe,
in some cases, it regulates as well, like where the data has to see.
So you they have to make sure that they meet all these um requirements otherwise,
otherwise they will be fine.
Yeah.
So in most cases, yes, it's not only the the developer's job,
uh It's for the whole team,
it's for the developers and the security team
and the operations team to work together,
but yes, it's a team spirit of some kind.
It's a teamwork, teamwork here that's needed here.
Definitely tell me how you deal with
situations where you're talking about teamwork.
Everyone has to work together. And I think that's very much the date of things today.
And you mentioned something uh a little bit ago about, for example,
false positives.
So what is your suggestion when you have a security
team working with the developer team working with an operations team
and you have things like security findings or
false positives or something from a tool.
And now everyone has to work together.
I'm I'm always very curious in what this answer looks like.
Oh,
trust me before
in the early stages when you're adopting a new tool.
Um And yes, you're all working together.
It's hectic
because um I remember the first time I
was working with developers like adopting DEV Jacobs
tools.
I remember this particular two generated false
positives like almost in the hundreds.
And it took,
it took uh it took the developers a lot more time to fix or to
identify the false positives than the time they actually took to build the code.
So
it was just like,
yeah, so it it's it kind of look like.
Uh That's why we talk about the depth second maturity model as well.
So you just don't take a tool as is you have to make sure that uh it meets your needs,
you have to make sure that you just not take it off the shelf as is you're doing a lot
of in depth analysis to make sure that it meets
your needs and it removes the false positives as well.
So by this, I mean,
it can be to ignore some particular um issues that you know,
are actually false positives.
It can be to only identify maybe critical or high risk capabilities.
So it depends with how you actually configure the tooling within your
maturity model to make sure that at least it meets your objectives
and reduces false positives as well.
One thing I'm sort of wondering is how often are these tool make
sort of open to feedback to kind of dial down these false positives because that's
are we getting to a point where they're starting to dial down their false positives
and make the tools actually better and have feedback or is that still a challenge?
-- Um
-- I feel like it's still a challenge because
it's on a case by case scenario because my,
my code is different from your code, isn't it?
So the tool that they
might be might work for
a
set of code but not mine like.
So it depends,
that's why you have to take some time
to make sure that you're actually configuring it
to fit your own use gift. Yeah, it, it's still the same
case.
Uh when you're talking about like using like open source um tools,
you probably have a lot more uh freedom or flexibility to go in,
in terms of bits of things.
But if you're using something like commercial tools and in some cases,
they have support which you would not have in open
source tools. So if you're using like a commercial
um source code, uh analyzing tool,
in some cases, they work with you step by step here
to make sure at least uh it fits your environment.
So it's up to you just to choose which one works best for your organization
as a tool maker. I understand this problem,
but
all right. All right.
So I, I want to focus on maybe the tools a little bit because uh uh Joy Lyn,
I've looked at
some of you,
I'm going to put a couple of links to some
of the kind of presentations I've seen of you in,
in that you've recently done.
And I think one of the really interesting things is
you've demoed a bunch of the technology like Microsoft and
Azure in github have started to integrate together and
I think this is really cool for developers and and
why don't you give us the I guess brief tour of what that looks like.
So in this case, like for the, it starts all the way from the developer.
So yes, we have the S code
and or you can use visual studio, visual studio code.
And so from from the developer perspective, you can integrate several extensions
from the marketplace um that will help you to
identify security vulnerabilities as you as you develop.
Um So at least you can be able to
shift left and identify security,
which is very early on.
So this is where you can also use like code QL. So code QL is part of github
advanced security. Um So
github,
but advanced security has three components. It has
code scanning as, as well as
secu uh secret scanning and dependency scanning.
So code scanning, that's where we talk about code QL.
So Q 12 is a query language and uh you can be able to build your own query queries.
And as you can also be able to use community
built queries.
So if you go to the QQL repo, you can be able to download some of the community
built queries
and some of them actually have security query.
So you can be able to identify if your code has close
script. If it's, if it has um less Q
injection,
there are several ways that you can be able to
just right click and run against your code base.
Yes. So the thing with code QR, it identifies your
A
Q code in, in terms of database.
So you have to convert your code into database and then
now you can be able to run it against uh code Q
within your ID A. But within, if you in your
github report, it's as easy as going to the security tab
and enabling the um code scanning and as well as secret scanning
um and dependency scanning.
And then you can be able to just identify this um from uh github
itself.
So it's uh it's all about having a better together story of
Azure and github,
whereby at least you can be able to incorporate and use control even from the onset
um from your ID.
And then by the time you're even pushing it to
eo uh you can be able to identify a
lot more security vulnerabilities to these three features,
the code scanning, the secret scanning and dependency scanning,
and the bit of uh secret scanning,
you can be able to prevent, you can have like pre
hooks whereby before you push your code to um to your
gabrio,
if it identifies security
um security uh secrets, if it identifies secrets,
like it can be your API keys can be your maybe hard
coded credentials as well. So the thing with github,
they've partnered with a lot of um
uh authentication companies. So it is to identify
um
um uh
secrets within your code. So it can even prevent you from pushing if it,
if it identifies that within your code.
So this is really amazing because it sort of covers an end to end dev
se
of story.
And then when you, when you push it even to the cloud,
um you have um defender for cloud,
which gives you an overall view of um your
security posture um your security score as well.
And um
one thing that was actually announced during ignite last year,
um it features like having uh using
github advanced security with the
Azure devops.
And also uh we also have um a defender for devops.
So uh if you've not used defender for,
just go in and try it out. So this is very good feature for, for developers because
it covers all the way from source code analysis,
all the way to infrastructures code using open source tools.
Yes. So you can say Microsoft really loves
open
-- source. All
-- right, let me, let me ask about depend
bot
because you kinda, you kinda jumped over that one. And I think Depend
is my favorite tool that github has integrated for open source projects where
I'll, I'll just let you take it from here.
So the thing with the depend bot it scans because yes, we are talking about offenses.
So
this is around 70 to 80% of the code that we actually push or build is actually third
party or offenses
components as well that we're using.
So you can imagine if you're using like one vulnerable component,
you actually like leaving one window into your whole
code base for uh to be exploited.
So that's why we have software composition analysis tools.
So that's why we talk about SC A tools
and depend
bot
is one of them.
So there are several other open source SC A tools as well. If you go to the OAS site,
you can be able to see some of the sc a tools that are available as well.
But yes, as I said, my favorite is actually dependable
and the thing is it will go in and um
look for security vulnerabilities in your dependencies
in your third party dependencies and as well as your open source components as well.
So
all you have to do is also just enable it within your github
repo
uh in your security tab and then it will be
able to scan your code and give you security vulnerability.
So the thing with third party
finances is if you're using one that is outdated,
they definitely have security vulnerabilities.
That's where we talk about CV ES every single day, we have zero day vulnerabilities.
And you'll see most of them actually are actually targeting like third
party third party components, open
source um components as well.
That's why it's very important for us to do this bit of scanning.
It's also important to know II I know Josh you mentioned. Um So
you also need to know uh what components are used during your software.
You have to know your software built of
materials you can imagine in a company um
you know, even a small company like mm maybe a start up,
you find that they're actually using like thousands of dependencies.
So how do you keep track of that?
So you actually have to have an so,
and then you actually know, like which component is actually vulnerable.
You have to do some bit of auto.
It's almost humanly impossible to do
manual check. Like all which co which component is actually
manual.
Sorry,
me and Josh actually spent a lot of time doing that at a red hat.
How long, how long ago was that?
Uh, you know,
uh
-- it was at least 10 years
-- ago
because I wasn't guilty of that.
Look, that's the way it worked is
a decade ago. We didn't have any of these tools.
And so, and, and I mean, kind of fun, fun fact for anyone listening,
Carne
actually discussed a whole bunch of SBO
topics that we recorded over the weekend because because cart had
an epiphany and that will come out the week after this where
there is, we, we cover like what s bombs are kind of the, there's stages of
bombs.
I mean,
this is one of my favorites and I don't know
if you've touched on this yet at all in Microsoft.
But like for example,
when you're creating an S bomb as part of like one of your github
workflows or something like that, that would be a source S bomb, right?
Where you're functionally scanning the source code versus
if I take the project and I build it
now,
I have a distribution artifact and generating an S bomb on that is totally valid.
But then also if I take that thing and I put it in a container image, for example,
now I have like a deployment s bomb and that's also
totally different.
And each of these things tell you something different along the, the DEV
ops journey, which is really cool.
Yes,
I totally agree with you. Like s
should be deployed in different stages of the, of the pipeline because
you see like in the next phase that you're actually incorporating,
you are actually adopting a lot more uh stuff, isn't it?
So you have to know. OK, so what new complaints have I added?
Uh So you have to know every in every stage of the, of the,
of the pipeline as well. So I agree with you on that.
Uh I'm not sure if you've, if you've heard of this framework, the
um secure supply chain consumption framework. Um This S two C two F.
Yes, that's the worst name in the world.
It's, it's a bit word, but I think we'll, we'll get used to it F two C two F.
So
uh
yeah,
so it's working within the open SSF uh So it's all about uh supply chain integrity.
It works to uh securely make sure that you're consuming
open source software dependencies uh within your developer workflow um securely.
So um
if you have not heard of it, if you can go in and uh download um
the S two E
but it's a bit word.
S two C two F specification
uh and just go through it because it's, it's, it's a absolutely amazing.
So, apart from uh so there's the Microsoft SBO
as well
that was released to it was open
source last year,
I think it should be like in May.
And then now we also have this framework that
can help you in your supply chain security journey.
So open source software dependencies. So
go in and check out the S two
C two
F.
It's fine. I'll put a link in the show notes for anyone looking for it.
Yes,
there are an enormous number of tools and processes and standards and
just options in the world of security.
And this is kind of my question to you Joy Lyn is
how as practitioners
can we keep track of everything going
on out there because it feels impossible sometimes
to know what's happening or what I should be
doing or what the current best practice might be.
So
the one what I would have is automation
because um as I mentioned earlier,
it's almost impossible to keep track
like manually of everything that's happening.
So one thing I like,
I always have these tools deployed and then they give me notifications.
So most of them actually it agreed to,
they have some bit of threat intelligence as well like and they keep
like um there's this new C VA and then it will
notify you that this particular line of code is actually vulnerable.
So it sends me like email notifications that so it depends also with how often you,
you set it.
But yes, so within also, I can say the security operation center,
that's why it's quite important, whatever size of company.
And you also have like a saw
deployed,
you need to work harder hand with the sock analysts.
Uh whenever you're deploying an application
to make sure that you're actually monitoring
whatever uh use cases that are important to the company.
And then in the event that um they actually know that at
least the the thing with working with the
SOC uh is that they also get to know
all the companies that are within your application.
So in the event that when they're doing the incident um
analysis,
um then, and then they identify that there is this particular
um security vulnerability that has actually been
released that particular day zero day,
they now notify you to be able to
possibly um take it offline and uh
fix it or if you can be able to build it within
uh maybe appeared when
uh maybe there's less traffic.
It depends also with you, maybe the security vulnerability is not critical.
So it's all about also deploying safeguards or putting in
or maybe security in depth.
Yeah,
one thing I'm consistently seeing is obviously,
well, let's put it real Microsoft has more people on their security team than,
you know, most small and medium businesses have people working for them entirely.
And so, for example, I'm just looking at this Microsoft DNS defender stuff and
you know, Microsoft, for example, apparently is tracking the dark web.
And so if you enable this DNS defender
and you make DNS requests out to a dark web server, obviously,
that's potentially really, really bad.
And
like there's no way I can build that, that's, that's just impossible, you know, like
it would take forever.
And this is kind of the thing I'm seeing is Microsoft and you know,
Amazon and Google are building these capabilities like antivirus vendors, right?
I can't track all the anti, I can't track all the viruses anymore.
I, if I want to do it, I have to pay, you know,
antivirus company and sort of the challenge I'm having though is there's
so much new stuff. How do I keep track of it all?
Because I actually used to read every,
like the weekly email from Amazon of all their service updates.
And I stopped doing that like five years ago because it just,
it took like two hours a week to read.
And so I'm, I'm kind of
like,
does Microsoft have a program where maybe you'll kind of give me a
basic education of what your platform capabilities
are because I'm just looking at this
and there's like amazing stuff in here that I had literally no idea existed at all.
If it's for security, we also have communities. Um So under the tech community.
Um they push up blogs and have a couple of discussions as well.
And uh you can also join the private communities as well.
So whenever you have like uh new features or capabilities,
you can be among those people who help to
even have the use cases incorporated into the product or
uh into a new feature.
So it's just more of plugging into the community,
uh especially like the tech community, I'll share a link of uh
uh the Microsoft um Security.
It is whereby at least you're gonna be notified of what's actually happening
every so often.
And as well as
attend all these
Microsoft
1st, 1st
party events that we have
um the like build, we have Microsoft secure happening in March.
So that will be a very good platform as well.
So not to have an overall view of what's happening within the
Microsoft Security Space
uh with keynotes with uh different products uh coverage as well
and as well as Microsoft build for developer security content as well
with ignite as well.
So like it's good just to be notified if you can subscribe
to the newsletters as well and the blogs within the tech communities,
you'll be notified of all this.
Amazing.
I have a question though for, for cuts, how,
how often do you do security awareness for your developers?
OK. Maybe without breaking
or something.
Like we don't really a perfect example of this
is actually about it a couple of years ago,
the main DEV came to me and he's like, Kurt.
So we have a Ruby on rails stack that runs our cloud security lines.org website.
And the, and the main DEV came to me and he's like, Kurt,
you know, like, how do we track CV S? And I'm like, well, what are you currently doing?
He's like, well, you know, we run, I think it was the
Auditor Bundle audit
and it uses the Ruby Sec database and, you know,
we're also using Brakeman and I'm like, ok, great.
I'm like,
and how often are we, like, updating the website?
And he's like, you know, usually twice a week, right.
We do an update twice, maybe three times a week.
And I'm like, ok, if it was an emergency and we absolutely had to, like,
fix a thing and push it out.
How long would that take? He's like, you know, like
a couple of hours. I'm like, ok, keep doing that.
And he's like, what do you mean? I'm like,
so when you update the website, are you using the most up to date components?
He's like, generally, yeah, unless it explicitly breaks something and then we,
you know, pin it and try and fix it,
but we try to keep up to date on software and I'm like, cool, just keep doing that.
So, like, I'm lucky in that my devs we basically just run current software
now
having said that the, the vast majority of people don't have that reality.
And I think that's where things get tricky is where, you know, like,
well having worked at Red Hat.
Right.
And back porting security fixes for 13 years into some poor little version of Linux.
I think the problem with security awareness is kind of
like the problem with the technology is that it's so
situation specific.
You know, we have a service where we control it all.
If we have a bad push, we can revert it and fix it.
Whereas, you know, if I'm an IOT maker and I have a bad push
and I brick 10% of the light bulbs.
Now we have a lawsuit situation,
you know,
and I think that's part of the problem is there's,
and I've never seen sort of good templates or decision flows for this, but
there are vastly different kinds of software like IOT versus a
public facing website that doesn't, you know, even do commerce transactions,
you know, versus one that does do ecommerce transactions
there.
I,
I think fundamentally they're so different with
their risk profiles and what they do
that. Yeah, there's no one size fits all, but also there's
not a ton of good guidance. And, and ironically actually, we have a dev
ops working group currently at the CS A that's just in the process of, you know,
making a bunch of new guidance for this.
And I think that's part of the challenge is that it's
the technology got ahead of the process, right? Because let's be real,
the technology we have like,
I can literally
turn on a
github repo push a bunch of code into it and like with an average of like 3 to 5 clicks,
hook it up to Digital Ocean or Microsoft Azure or Cloud flare
uh workers or pages or whatever. And just like poof have a working website
in like literally 3 to 5 clicks with, you know, very little hassle.
And
I,
I think that's part of the challenge is the technology ran way ahead of the process.
And that's where,
that's why one thing I like to see is Microsoft's always about integrating things.
So
I'm hoping
that the process will catch up with the technology eventually.
But I,
I think it might start to lag behind
just because technology is moving so much faster.
And also uh I think part of the process as well, especially like in the devops
process, like
we are adopting too much tooling.
So we have too much noise as well. So you don't know
uh what is that tuning
they
take
and what is not. So you might end up missing something important.
So that's why it's very important to really pay attention on
the process based as well because uh as I mentioned earlier,
people are focusing a lot on the
tooling. That's why we're having too much noise. So you have to just say, OK,
so this ones meet my needs. Um This is what actually works for me and yeah, work it out.
As you said,
what actually how can you be able to identify all this
um CV S or keep up to date with all this?
It's also by reducing the noise just having the few tools that work for you.
Yes.
-- And
-- that's definitely a big challenge because like I find a lot of the,
the feedback loops as to it, Like we know this is noise,
but we also know that there's like one in 100 gems in that noise that
we do need to pay attention to and sorting those out and figuring out.
Which is which. Yeah, that's, that's a challenge.
It's, it's always a growth thing. Yeah, I have a growth mindset.
Like what did we learn and
just learn from the journey as well?
Yes, absolutely. I love, I love that advice. All right.
And, and kind of one last thing then.
So Joy Lynn, you have an event coming up is your open source day.
-- Why don't you tell us about that?
-- Yes. And as well, we have the
Azure opens so day
happening on the March
March 7th.
Don't miss this as uh at all because it will be,
it will be a free digital event covering
um various um open source uh best practices
as well as new capabilities that are available
and how you can be able to protect your data and business assets as well.
So go
in and register for the
-- Azure Open Source Day. We'll share the link as well.
-- So I'm going to call this one.
Thank you so much joy. It has been
an absolute treat having you on this show.
Thank you so much for having me, Josh and cut.
I really enjoyed myself and I hope the viewers also learned a thing or two about
open social security.
Fantastic. I have no doubt. I have no doubt. Ok,
so you can go to open
source security podcast.com.
Find all of the show notes we talked about today UI Pandos
podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media
curtain Joy Lynn. Have a marvelous rest of your days.
You too. Bye.
-- Thanks
-- everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.