Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 135 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
-- Josh Pressers,
-- man. I burnt my finger super bad in my 3d printer today.
It like really, really hurts.
Isn't there? Only one tiny little part of the 3D printer that actually gets hot.
Well, the bed does but you won't burn yourself. Yeah, the extruder.
So my story which I feel like has a security tie in which is why I'm going to tell it is.
So I, I bought some wood filament
and I have some projects.
What?
Yeah, I'll explain.
Uh So
basically I have some, I have radiators in my house, right. And
I have pipes that come up out of the floor and
over the course of the 100 years this house has existed,
all of the radiator pipe covers are gone
and I've tried to find some I could buy,
but just given the fact that the pipes
are like ridiculously sized because they're very old.
I can't get one right.
You probably have to go to Europe.
It, it doesn't matter. Right. That's not the point.
So, anyway, I got the idea. Hey, they sell this wood filament.
I could print radiator, like nice sleeves that, that are two pieces.
They kind of snap together
and I'll make them out of wood so I can stain
them and make them look really nice because that's the whole
point of this wood filament is you can sand it and
-- stain it and make it look kind of like
-- wood.
So, wait, it's actually physically wood.
No, it's not. It's weird though. It's not, it's not exactly plastic.
It's not exactly wood. I have a suspicion.
It's some sort of weird amalgamation of stuff.
It smells a bit like burning wood as you use it.
So I have a feeling there's some wood product in it.
But anyway, anyway,
so I'm,
I'm printing all my stuff and I go
downstairs this morning while it's printing and it,
like, just had stopped.
The, the, the filament had stopped,
stopped coming out of the extruder. Right.
And I look and thought, well, that's not normal.
And then I was looking at every, you know,
the various dials and gauges and things and saying, I wonder what's going on.
And then my first thought was, I wonder if the extruder is not hot.
So, guess what I did. I touched it and guess what? It was really freaking hot.
-- °C. Man,
-- this is my theory that
almost all people need to learn either hot or sharp the hard way.
Possibly more than once.
Kurt. Do you know how many times I've burnt myself touching that extruder
more than I can count.
And, and that's, that's the lesson.
So, so put a sign on it or something.
Yeah, that,
that
wasn't gonna work and you know it,
but that's the lesson, right?
Humans are dumb
even
though we know we shouldn't do something. We, we do it
generally because we have like a momentary lapse of sanity
and, and then we obviously regret it.
And like, now I'm sitting here and like,
my finger really freaking hurts and it's probably gonna hurt for a week.
It's, it's not a third degree burn or anything, thank goodness.
But like, holy cow, it freaking hurts.
Well, I feel like this whole thing with the, so, uh, not today,
but February 1st was change your password day.
-- Oh,
-- my
-- goodness. You, you sent me a document about that.
-- Just
the stupidest thing I've heard,
but not only that, but this person, the interview for this,
I'm not going to say their name because this is terrible.
Um, he basically says use a passphrase instead of,
uh, a password,
like one W 3 $3 sign, you know, Carrot, capital ad GF I star bracket bracket TYU.
Because you know that password is apparently not very secure
and it's hard to remember which is legitimate. And here's the secret folks
don't remember your passwords.
No, like, seriously, that's the secret II, I have
two passwords that. I know
one to my encrypted backups and one to my encrypted icloud
and then,
and my, uh, last pass, so three passwords
and everything else is in the last pass and an icloud.
-- That's it. No,
-- II, I agree.
I don't even make like it's, I, you know, I,
I don't even know my Google password because it's a
combination of something stored in last pass and my,
you know, my UB key.
right? And obviously two factor
off is obviously the best possible solution.
And in fact,
not just two factor off because there's something we should clarify at some point.
And I remember uh Tavis Ormandy had a, a Twitter rant about this a while ago is that
the U two F style keys where you put the
key in and have to push a button are vastly superior
to the like apps on your phone that give you a token.
Well, no, they're vastly superior to anything
they're easy to use.
Like I, I it's funny because I had to do like, well,
I don't want to call it user training, but, you know, we did some UBQ deployment
and of course people like, how do I use this? I'm like, you plug it in
and you touch it and then like, and then what? And I'm like, nope, that's it.
And they're like, oh, ok.
Right. And you know, that's, that's what this should be.
It should be simple and easy. It shouldn't be
although let's, let's specify as well.
Just for people that are like, wait, what's wrong with my phone app is
the issue being someone could fish, you,
you could type in your real password and your token into a fake site.
Whereas things like the U two F and then now web off
keys,
they look at the URL. And so if you're at not google.com,
it,
it won't work, right? Because it, it, the URL is kind of part of the magic. So.
Right.
And of course, uh don't use S MS ever, right. That's like
the agreed upon
two points.
Number one, the other aspect of phone apps is that the,
the seeds and the keys can be copied off your phone,
right? It's not like your phone has
some magic encrypted partition beyond like what's built into an iphone.
Like once an app can get in there, it can get to all your stuff
uh uh with respect to S MS in
principle, I agree. But the fundamental problem is
so, for example, my bank doesn't offer anything better.
So I can either have, I can either have a password or I can have a password and S MS.
Now, I, I'm not a big fan of S MS because yeah, hijacking SS,
MS is not actually as hard as it should be,
but it's, it definitely raises the bar,
you know, now it's got to be a targeted attack.
They can't just, you know, be trying random passwords.
They actually have to hijack my phone.
So I, I guess the problem is S MS will prevent you from,
I guess you would call it like a casual attacker or
a non targeted attacker,
but a targeted attacker will hijack your SM SS
because there's services out of various countries that
will let you do that for 10 bucks.
Um, and what's worse is my,
the other bank I deal with was using voice as your password.
And I'm like, that's not gonna work for me. And they're like, why not?
Well, because I have several 100 hours of audio recordings online. Right.
Right. Well, heck, man, in the, in the last episode I said what?
Ok, Google,
which I think is what you say to unlock android phones if I recall correctly.
Exactly.
Yeah. So
I'm doomed.
Yeah.
Oh, crap. My phone just did it again.
It was unlocked next to me and I started doing stuff and I'm like, oh, crap.
Yeah.
So here's what it really,
and we keep harping on this,
but maybe someday it'll start to get through is number one,
you should only have at most two or three passwords. Good.
And you actually have to remember.
And those should be to things like your password manager and you know,
your encrypted data storage
-- and,
-- and in that instance, a passphrase is exactly what you want.
I actually use a passphrase plus a password.
I, I just brute force memorized like a string of random characters,
it's about eight or nine characters long
that on top of the pass phrase, I figure is reasonably safe.
Uh, I bet just a passphrase.
I mean, so kind of for the audience, the reason this matters is generally speaking,
if a human types in a string of gibberish letters,
it's probably between six and eight characters long
and using things like GP US today,
you can crack probably most eight character
passwords in a reasonable amount of time.
And so the issue being if someone steals, you know, the hashes of the passwords,
-- they're going to totally break them
-- at RS A.
There was that company demoing their um they had a system with, what was it?
Eight Titans in it?
So eight Honk and huge GP US for password cracking.
Yeah. Yeah, there's tons of cool info in doing this.
And I know like uh is it solar designer
from, what is it open wall? He, he's super active in this space.
He wrote, what was it, John, the Ripper, I think way back in the day
and like this password cracking rigs now are, are unreal.
Whereas the, the point is when you have a pass phrase,
unless someone kind of knows you and is going to guess your song lyrics or something,
you know, make sure it's not something super obvious
cracking. A 30 character password is going to take
probably longer than
can be accomplished in a lifetime.
-- Whereas obviously short, passwords
-- are short,
assuming it hasn't been used by somebody else
and breached and it's not in the dictionaries.
Right.
And that's very true because the dictionaries dictionary
attacks are super simple and super common.
There's good news, there's a simple solution to that,
which is
amongst other things. Google has now released password checkup.
Uh, it's an extension for Chrome
that essentially checks the passwords you type in against the,
have I been
pwned? I think it's the, have I been pwned password database
and tells you if you're using a password that's been,
you know, publicly leaked and thus is easier to break.
And before everybody's like, oh my God, you know,
Google is taking all my passwords and sending them to some Rando.
No, what they do is they take a hash of your password
and then they don't even send the full hash. They send part of the hash
to the backend service and the backend service sends you like, ok, these are,
you know, the 1000 or 100 or whatever records that match that partial hash.
You take those hashes and then look at them and see if it matches what you just type in.
-- But Kurt Google's reading all my passwords now. Oh, my goodness.
-- Yeah.
Well, that's how your web browser works.
The web browser kind of has to see your password when you type it in.
But that's another big thing that I think is going to
have to change in the next couple of years is that
to put it bluntly, let's face it.
The majority of apps we use are through a web browser.
And so having,
you know,
and also those tend to be the sites that get compromised in your password exposed.
So I think it basically has to become standard that
things like password checkup get just become the default.
So every time you type in a password, you, you're going to get warned that.
Yeah. Uh, we've, we've seen this password, it's out there publicly.
You might not want to use it.
-- Yeah,
-- I, I agree. I think it's a great idea.
Now, here's the thing I keep wondering though
is as more and more sites are breached and Troy Hunt collects more and more passwords
at one point.
Do we just have like every possible human conceivable password in this,
in this backup database?
Right.
Well, I, I suspect we already have most of them because there's, I think his,
his thing is over.
Is it a billion or something? Now? It's, it's a lot of password.
Oh, it's, it's more than that.
It's, it's, well, it's probably tens of billions if I had to guess.
And more to the point again,
this is why you should use a password manager that generates
-- passwords.
-- Right. Nonsensical passwords.
And also, I mean, one thing I've run into too is a lot of sites, for example,
block various symbols or slashes.
I suspect it's in some sort of misguided effort to protect
their software from like SQL injection or something goofy like that.
Probably one nice thing about these password managers is
that most of them will not only know that.
Ok, this site, this field is a password. Do you want me to generate a password for it?
But they know about the restrictions?
Oh, I can't have an at symbol or I can't have forward slash
back slash or
star or carrot or
whatever.
So like an example being
I, you know, it's, if you listen to the podcast, you know, I use last pass and
when you tell last pass to generate a password,
they have like little sliders and buttons and things.
And if somebody says you can't use any weird characters,
I can untick that and then I just slide the bar up.
So I've got a longer password because
the, the hard part,
I guess when you're dealing with passwords is the concept called just entropy,
right?
Where you want more bits of randomness in your password.
And obviously, if you take out all the special characters,
you've just reduced the, the amount of complexity that password can have.
So obviously, you can increase complexity by making it longer.
And that's how we ended up with pass phrases because
humans beyond the 26 letters and some basic punctuation can't remember
anything past, you know, what is it?
The quick brown fox jumped over the lazy dog while I was fishing the carp.
I know I'll make the a, the at sign. No one will guess that.
Yeah, Google has like a nice picture of how, under the password or, um,
how password checkup works under the hood and how it, you know,
it's not disclosing your personal data, blah, blah, blah.
And the other nice thing, I,
I haven't seen a password alert yet but it
says that it makes the password alerts actionable,
not just informational.
So I'm assuming it's prompting you to not
just, you know, oh, you got a bad password.
Feel bad about yourself, but, oh, you got a bad password.
I'm hoping it tells you where to go to change it
and what to,
you know,
and to help you change it to something secure and, or ideally,
I don't want them recommending a specific password manager,
but I think in general they should
be recommending password managers because we're,
at the point I, I have a spreadsheet with over 1000 passwords in it that
I've migrated all the important stuff into last pass. So,
you know,
the average person has at least dozens of
websites that they interact with using passwords.
And,
you know, everybody, I know their strategies to have two or three passwords,
you know, a high quality one for their brain and their web for their email and then a
lower quality one for kind of where they do all
their shopping and then like a third tier low,
low quality one for,
you know, looking at the news or whatever, stupid stuff wants to log in
and again, you know, humans are terrible at this.
This is why we have computers, folks.
Right.
And it's not like people can say, oh, but
I, I mean, I remember one thing back in the day is, you know,
not everybody actually had a computer 20 years ago.
Right. You had your desktop, that's it? Not like,
you know, actually having a laptop was kind of special.
Right. Going back 20 years,
-- I'm trying
-- to think. Did I have a laptop?
I think I did have a laptop 20 years ago and I paid an ungodly sum of money.
My first laptop cost four grand
and it had
eight megs of ra M.
Yeah, that's about right.
It was very expensive.
So, you know, now everybody should generally have a smartphone in their pocket.
They're not that expensive.
And trust me, the value you're going to get from a smartphone is, is worth it.
So, so that's the bad part of this newscast. But the good news is
Google is trying to make it better.
Yeah, I think it's awesome.
I,
I really appreciate some of these efforts and I know there's going
to be a lot of people who complain and whine about it.
But it's,
it's kind of one of those things, if nobody's complaining about what you're doing,
you're not doing anything interesting.
And I feel like the vast majority of the
security industry is so painfully stuck in the past,
if they're complaining about you, like,
keep going because you're probably doing the right thing.
Yeah.
I'm actually getting ready for death threats from my RS A presentation because what
we're presenting is so completely opposite to what most people are used to.
-- Oh,
-- whatever. Stop, you're being overly dramatic. I know what you're presenting.
You are going to get death threats.
Uh If I don't get death threats, I'll be disappointed.
-- You're going to be very disappointed. I think
-- that means we didn't go far enough.
-- Yeah,
-- you, you're not getting death threats, dude. It is cool though.
You have to talk about it after, after the show. That'll be cool.
And then, so this is kind of awesome because I mean, I just, I love where A I is going and
there's a lot of common uses for a, that we would think of like, you know,
self driving cars.
A I? That makes sense.
But I think this is fantastic is, um, what's the company's name? Mccormick? The?
So they make spices.
They're using a I to find new flavors,
which is like
crazy. That's so cool.
I love it.
What, what I'm worried about though is, you know, when you go to buy paint
and you go to the paint aisle and you look at the swatches and the names on them
are just
what now like some of them, you know, like ivory white. Ok. It's an off white.
That makes sense. I get it.
But
you know, some of these like
colors,
uh
they have like a place name and then Bay.
Right. Right.
Well mccormick's gonna do the same thing is that
because by giving a color of ridiculous name,
you can totally, you know, trademark it and other things.
Yeah, copyright and trademark.
So,
but on the other hand, I'm looking forward to new flavors like this is fantastic.
I mean, and, and part of me is like, this is one of the few uses of A I where
what could go wrong? Nothing, right. I hope,
I don't know.
I until it figures out some mysterious
spice combination that creates vampires or something.
And then we're like, oh crap, what have we done?
Well?
It's like how we added sugar to everything to
make it tastier and bulk up the calories,
you know, post World War Two.
So people weren't starving all the time
and now we have an obesity epidemic.
So I'm wondering, you know, can it's like futurama, can you make, you know,
a spice so flavorful and tasty that people have to eat
-- it. The
-- essence of flavor, right? Yes. The
essence of flavor.
Which folks it was LSD so don't do that.
Oh,
that's such a good episode.
So for the people who might not know and if
you don't know every episode of Futurama by heart,
shame on you go watch more Futurama,
but essentially Bender,
the robot wants to be a chef and of course
he can't taste anything and he's a terrible cook.
Then he goes and trains with a special chef. It's a master chef that
the character Elza who's supposed to be Emerald. Basically.
Uh I forget he backs stabbed him or something. I don't remember the details.
Exactly. Shame on me for not knowing.
But then, yeah, at the end, Bender wins and then,
then the professor tested. He's like, it's just water. Oh, wait. And there's LSD.
So it was awesome. Whatever happened to Emerald. Uh, he's still around, I think.
I don't, he was, it's like anything, right? You become known for a thing
and then when that gimmick wears off, if you have, I guess nothing else to do next,
you just kind of get forgotten.
Yeah. Well, you're always going to be doing something new.
Right. Exactly. And, and I think a lot of celebrities
get stuck in a place where they're known for one
thing and it's very difficult to go to another thing.
I, I guess so, even on that note, thinking about this,
I see a lot of people who,
who kind of speak in public and actually I'm going to pick on security here again.
Is there are a lot of security people, these,
a lot of the older folks who've been around for a long
time now I'm old so I'm not no age as I'm here.
I'm older than many of them.
Uh, they've been talking about the same freaking thing for 20 years.
-- It's like, come on guys, you know,
-- it's, it's actually worse than that.
Not only have they been talking about the same thing,
but they've come to the same conclusion and they haven't changed.
You know, I'll be blunt,
my view on passwords and password management has changed drastically.
100 and 80 degrees since I was younger.
Oh, completely
my take on, you know, how do you, how do you give grandma a computer that's secure?
Well, the answer is simple. You get her a tablet.
Yep. Yep. Exactly. That's it. Like the
sorry folks.
But, yeah, that's, you want something that'll work reliably and be secure.
Well, it better be an up to date Android device or an, an I device.
Yep. Yep. Actually. So I, I, I'm sure I've told this story before
but my parents came to me some years back and said we need a new computer and I said, no,
you need a tablet
and they're like, we don't want one. We want a computer.
I said, all right, I tell you what,
uh, let's buy this cheaper computer and a tablet. All right.
And funny enough now,
the only reason they still have a computer is because their
printer is an old printer that doesn't do like cloud printing.
So I keep telling them, like, if you guys get a new printer,
you can throw that computer away.
They're like, oh, we like our printer.
You know, the ink's only like, $200 a cartridge now. It's like, oh, my
God,
freaking ink
jet printers.
Yeah. I have a really nice old laser jet that I like that.
Osco
-- sells the toner cartridges pretty cheaply. So I'm stuck with that for a while.
-- I
just got, I just got a new printer actually. So my old printer
was, it reached a point where the,
for a new toner it was going to cost me $500 because, like,
nobody was making it anymore.
And I bought some knockoff third party cartridges just to see the toner.
Yeah, they were bad.
They were, they, they, like, streak the pages like they sucked.
And so anyway, finally I'm, like, all right,
I got to bite the bullet here and I bought some, like, crazy printer that does, like,
scanning and copying.
It prints on both sides. It's full duplex pages.
-- It's only scans on one side
-- of the page. See, that's what I love about my printer.
It's, it's a full duplex printer.
Yeah, that's like the best thing ever.
And, and it's, it does like the internet web printy stuff. And I,
I don't know. II, I guess the way I see it is
it's just a printer basically. If, if somebody starts printing garbage to me.
Oh, well. Right. I'm, I'm not gonna cry.
My, my, I treat my home network as if it's the public internet already.
-- So I figured, uh, I'll see what this is and it's ok.
-- Well, it kind of is,
I mean, that's one thing, sorry, just to go on a rant.
But this is one thing that drives me
nuts is people who heavily secure their home network
but then they take their laptop to the coffee shop or whatever. Right.
So, unless you're actually also securing your laptop, well,
you're going to get that thing infected somewhere public at some point.
Uh, well,
it's even so funnier than that is how many security people keep talking about.
Oh, you can't use public Wi Fi. You can't use public Wi Fi.
Everybody uses public Wi Fi. I don't care who you are.
I guarantee that people saying that are totally using public Wi Fi.
Well,
unless you go through and actually change some settings to not hop on
wifi and you forget all the networks that you've got in there,
you know, like, because my, if my laptop sees anything remotely labeled Starbucks,
it's like, oh, yeah.
Yeah, I'm so happy to see you. How are you, buddy? Oh, my God. It's been so long.
We haven't talked in years,
you know, so I'd have to, like, have it, forget all the networks
and, you know, not automatically join networks and I'd have to,
you know, I've done the thing with, um, I think it's Amazon where, you know, it,
my Amazon devices.
Remember the Wi Fi passwords. Because,
and I don't know how this works but it's magic.
It's just the devices somehow set themselves up mostly.
Right.
Which I don't fully understand how,
because how does it set itself up and get on
the internet if it's not already on the internet?
So,
I, I don't know, it's black magic as far as I'm concerned. Whatever. I don't care.
All I know is my fire sticks.
I, I plug them into a TV and it says hi. Are you current? And I go, yep. And that's it.
That's the setup. I'm like,
uh,
my head doesn't understand this but whatever.
Well, and speaking of that.
So the dod, uh, the department of defense actually released a really good, uh,
short paper.
It's marked unclassified.
It's their cloud strategy.
And what I love is is they specifically go over
not just the stuff you'd expect, like, oh,
we gotta find cloud providers that are secure and blah, blah, blah,
but they talk about
getting infrastructure ready for the cloud,
right? Because when you think about it, like they have systems
that are still running on floppy
disk and by floppy
disc, I don't mean those cute little 3.5 ones.
You know, there was that article about what was it, the, the nuclear launch, uh,
systems running on eight inch floppy
-- disk or whatever,
-- which is, I'm kind of ok with that one. But,
so do
you,
you sent this paper to me like two minutes
before we started recording and I've not read it.
It's 18 pages uh sum this up you're talking about.
So the dod releases a document and it's about
well embracing the cloud for everything except for administrative work.
So like the really sensitive stuff
and, you know, it's a lot of different reasons,
cost uh agility being able to grow and shrink, right?
Because
uh well, for example, you know,
all of a sudden you need a whole bunch
of resourcing to support a mission in Afghanistan.
Well, now we're done with that,
you know, like the dod is not going to go build data centers in the middle of a war zone.
I
think
not,
you know,
I imagine that would be quite expensive and the cloud might be a better option.
But what I'm really impressed with is they
sort of embrace and lean into their challenges,
which are, you know,
we get that we have a whole bunch of old it that just is not suited for the cloud
and that has to be dealt with in some way, you know, we need to make our data
sort of more cloud smart.
So talking about, you know, what, what
when you have big piles of data,
how
do you manage that data in a cloud sense?
It's very different when you have all your data and processing in one location
and say a 10 gigabit network to t all together.
But you know, when you're talking with cloud providers,
you might want to move stuff around the world quickly.
And so it's honestly, I would recommend
any, if you work for a large organization, you should probably read this because
there's definitely some parallels for all of us
from what we can learn from their pain.
That's wild man. And
you know what my feeling is here is
if, if the the dod
is embracing cloud like they are,
I I said before
it's over cloud one
and I think at this point, if you're a naysayer, you're complaining about the cars
on the freeway. Right? It's, we're way past the point of cars versus horses even.
It's just
cloud one.
There's nothing you can do about it like it or not, it is what it is.
Well, and they specifically talk about
two, not just cloud but that it's cloud cloud, not on premises cloud but like
the big cloud, not your
little,
you know, couple of racks running open stack or whatever.
Nothing wrong with open stack. But let's face it, folks.
You know, Google can scale up a lot faster and cheaper than you can.
Yeah. Right. Exactly. I get it.
And I guess at the same time though, it just, it's a new paradigm. It's
the way I keep thinking about this and I keep talking to people because there's,
there's always some weird conversations around.
Is it, you know, tell me about the security of this. How does it work? It's
it's kind of like
if you
think about security in the old way
in a new environment, of course, it's not going to work. And this is true of anything.
Right.
I mean, if you try to apply security concepts from, let's say, the 19 twenties to say,
-- say, like, physical security,
-- dude, having a perimeter firewall, uh,
except we have, you know, thousands of IP S and locations.
-- Right. Right. Exactly.
-- Good luck. Yeah.
Oh, and all those locations have Wi Fi,
but people are attaching.
-- God knows what
-- to and,
and their cell phones are connected to them and
their cell phones are connected to the cellular network.
Right.
-- You know,
-- so, well,
it's like all those banks that have been hacked
by people physically attaching stuff to their networks.
And I'm like,
if you get hacked because somebody physically attaches something to your network,
you're doomed.
Your network sucks.
You can get a full proper computer. Now, the size of a pack of gum for like 20 bucks.
Uh, they're less than that, man. They're so freaking cheap. It's not even funny.
And so how are you going to physically secure a network when
I can basically cut a cable and jam a device in line?
Right. Well, and, and did you see that
there's a new story now about some
Bluetooth devices that only use like ambient wireless
power,
like with,
with stuff like that?
You're doomed. There's, you can't win.
Well, and then SpaceX
is going to throw up their gigabit wireless magic satellite network.
Right?
And so all of a sudden there's no way you can
prevent data exfiltration even if you completely control your network.
And that's ignoring, of course,
Wi Fi locally and somebody parked out in the parking lot sucking down the data,
you know, like, what is it,
all those um uh ATM and gas station skimmers now that are Bluetooth.
So the bad guys literally just have to go gas up and they have a laptop running
in the car that connects all the Bluetooth skimmers
and gets all the data and that's it.
They don't even have to
open anything up or, you know, get out of their car.
That's right.
So
fundamentally, I look at all networks including my own network.
I actually specifically now I flattened my network.
I bought a bunch of Google Wi Fi devices
and I just have one flat network with everything attached to it.
And I assume that the network has goner
and syphilis floating around on it
-- and it does
-- and, and all my devices are set up to, you know,
be as secure as they can be themselves.
Right? Actually, so I've got, you'll appreciate this.
So I still have a guest network and the only reason I do it
is because I have like a comically bad password for guests to use.
And I tell it to them and they look at me and they said is that really the password.
And I said, yeah.
And they said that's the worst password in the world. And I said, yeah.
And they say
what, like, what's wrong with you? You're a security guy
who cares? Like, this is
the only reason I have a password at all is just like to
keep the homeless people from hanging out in the yard or something.
Right. Like, I don't care. You
-- can drive into my, my, my driveway and use my Wi Fi like I don't care.
-- Yeah.
And all those classic arguments of, you know,
what if somebody sucks down the intern?
Well, yeah, an extra 15 bucks a month for unlimited internet.
-- I,
-- I, I don't have a cap and in fact, I use an obscene amount of data.
Iii I read a news story the other day that said
like only 4% of internet users use one terabyte or more of data per month.
And I thought that seems low.
And I looked and I had like 1.5 terabytes already and it was like the 20th of the month.
Well, I'm special.
But you know, the thing I noticed is when I watch four K video, for example,
the amount of data I'm sucking down during that is insane.
-- 04 K is bonkers. It is,
-- it is ridiculous without question.
And at the same time, the really funny thing is I, I honestly couldn't care less.
They could show it to me in like SD quality and whatever.
I'm not like, I'm not one of those people that really, really minds.
-- Either way
-- you got 40 year old eyes, they're not going to notice the difference.
-- Yeah.
-- Exactly. Exactly. Maybe if I was young I'd care. But I'm an old man, whatever.
It doesn't matter.
So,
but, but at the same time it's like, uh, the cable company is not yelling
me. I don't care. I'll just keep using that data.
Yeah. So, no, the whole thing is just, it's,
the world has changed and more to the point.
I, I actually checked the other day,
I think I had seven computers on my desk and the majority of them were tablets,
phones or other little flat devices.
And I realized there's really nothing I can do to secure them because,
and there's nothing I really have to do to secure them.
-- Yeah. Exactly.
-- Right. They're, they're generally quite secure by default.
Uh, well, maybe whatever. It probably doesn't matter.
Well, the I devices, the fire, the fire tablets, I mean,
it's not like they're running,
here's the thing like a fire tablet or an Android tablet.
What, what is it running that you can attack?
It's not like it's running a network service,
uh, not remotely.
I scan them very fishy or, or hit websites because for example,
a lot of android devices are comically out of date.
And so if you can get them to visit a certain URL or something
you can definitely cause some problems.
I probably, I don't surf the web like a normal person. I mostly stick to a few new sites
-- and that's fair. The web on a tablet is a nightmare because of just all the
-- garbage.
The ads,
the ad, well, you know,
so for the ads I use Firefox and you can install an ad blocker and Firefox on my tablet,
which is fine.
But, no, I mean, I agree. I, I often don't go to many interesting places.
I think Reddit is the most exciting place I go to
which anyway,
edits its own set of problems. All right, man. Uh
We're about out of time here. You got any closing thoughts?
Yeah.
II, I just,
I'm curious to see what other crazy things people will come up with to use A I for
like new colors, maybe new, new,
I don't know. Right.
If I knew I'd be rich.
Uh Maybe,
maybe
anyway. Awesome. Yeah, I can't wait. I can't wait for my A I powered spice rack.
It'll be fantastic.
All right. So thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up the show notes.
You can use the Pound Os S Podcast. Hashtag Do hit us up on social media.
-- Yeah, Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day. You
-- too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.