Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 187 with myself,
Kurt Siegfried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Pressers.
So I have a fun story. I don't, I don't usually have stories that have happy endings.
So just as a, as a warning, it has a happy ending. So
I bought
the Nintendo Switch on launch day, which was more than three years ago at this point.
And a couple of weeks ago, the fans started making
terrible noises on the switch.
-- So the switch has a fan built into the little thing it does.
-- It has a fan inside of
it.
I've never seen a switch. I've never handled one.
Yeah. Well, you can't tell.
I mean, it's, it's pretty small but there is a tiny fan in it.
I mean, obviously, depending upon what you're doing,
it runs at different speeds and when you have it docked to the TV,
the fan runs harder than it does say if you're holding it in your hands.
Right. So anyway,
the fan on the switch starts sounding
like a jet engine like a cracked ball
burn or something. No idea. Doesn't matter. It's really small. So anyway,
I call Nintendo and I say, hey, the fan is making a ton of noise and they ask me
an absurd number of questions. Like, did you install the updates?
We would, you know, check this, check that I'm like, it's just the fan is bad.
-- Just please
-- in fairness though.
Like,
look at all the Macs that had all those wacky thermal throttling
problems until there was a software update that magically fixed them.
Maybe.
Except I just kept telling the person I'm talking to on the phone.
I'm like the fan sounds like a jet engine. The fan is bad.
Well, let's see if you have the latest system update and I'm thinking the fan is bad.
Literally,
I
did, of course, but it does not matter. The fan is bad. I want a new fan.
So after spending way more time on the phone than I was comfortable with,
they finally tell me, ok, we can fix this.
But basically the, the fans going to cost me 100
bucks,
but then there's shipping and there's tax.
So it's going to come to like 100 and 20 when it's all done.
And I said that doesn't sound like the best investment in the world to,
to fix my three year old switch.
When a, the handheld switch, the little one there's,
I think it's called the Light is $199 and a regular switch is, I think uh,
$300 like 299.
Right. So
I
said, I don't, I don't think that's a good idea. I'm not going to send you my switch.
And so of course, the next thing I did is I look on Amazon and thought,
I wonder how much a fan costs on Amazon.
I'm guessing $4.16 dollars.
Yes. Which was more than I expected.
And, and so I buy the fan, I also bought a tool set because of course, Nintendo.
So all the screws are weird.
And that's cool though because I enjoy owning the weird tools.
So now I've got all these funky screwdrivers but no, I
it was, it was cool crazy man.
I had to like take this thing apart an incredible amount.
I,
I'd removed way more from the switch than I expected to replace
the fan and it just the whole time I'm doing it.
I kept thinking that whoever designed this never imagined
anyone would ever have to replace the fan.
It's
not that they never imagined anybody would replace the fan, but it was,
it costs more time and engineering and
processing and manufacture
-- to build something that is user serviceable
-- even.
But even when they do it,
I understand why they charge $100 to replace this stupid thing because it,
it was a crazy amount of work to get at the fan.
But anyway, my switch is fine.
The fan works
and I am happy.
So There you go.
That's my,
that's my happy story about my Nintendo switch and I figure in like a
month it'll probably explode or something because I'm sure I screwed it up.
But, yeah. Yeah, there were no left over pieces.
Yeah, I'm just looking at it.
Is this pretty classic, like apple style, you know, glue, the thing together,
lots of little screws, stuff is buried.
-- So
-- there was no, like glue or the little clicky plastic tabs or anything.
I mean, once I took screws off, things basically lifted apart, which was quite nice.
-- OK.
-- It looked like they were using a spudger to rip something open.
-- Here in this picture,
-- I did not need a spudger.
Well, what I needed the spudger for was there's some of those,
I don't even know what kind of connectors they are,
but it's where you have the connector that kind of clicks into the other connector.
-- Yeah. The flat ribbon connectors.
-- Yeah. Kind of like those.
-- Yeah, those things scare me because they're so easy to mess up.
-- That was my concern.
But again,
I figured what's the worst I'm going to do is I'm going to go buy a switch mini
because
-- Yeah. Right. So anyway, $16 later, that's my, that's my happy story
-- today.
I was thinking there's been a bit of recent,
I don't want to say controversy because it's on hacker news.
So it's just a bunch of crazy people arguing about crazy things.
But um
it was an interesting point.
So Wire Guard is becoming more mature,
although I would argue it's definitely out of beta and ready for prime time.
Oh, yeah, definitely.
It was interesting because the argument boiled down
to Wire Guard is bad because it doesn't let
me configure everything the way exactly that I
would like to and it is therefore better.
And I just, I literally read that and I was like,
I've set up like full mesh ips I VPN S and it was a nightmare
and I went and looked at the documentation for the modern stuff and guess what?
It's probably worse. No, it was, it's basically exactly the same
or you can actually do some really fancy stuff, but it involves like PK
I and DNS
and auto discovery, which is
if you've ever set that kind of stuff up, man, it is
-- crazy, hellacious, not fun.
-- That is exactly the response I would expect
-- from hacker news unquestionably. Like,
-- I love the fact that ips
still makes the distinction between authenticated
headers and encrypted something payloads.
So like it literally when they designed IPIC, they were like,
well, you know,
people might not want to actually encrypt their stuff,
they might just want to like authentication header it
so that they know it wasn't altered in transit,
which OK, 30 years ago,
kind of made sense as a design
decision because encryption was computationally expensive,
like really expensive.
And you know,
there's a lot of valid use cases where it's like
I need to know my data got there without getting,
you know, mangled.
I don't care about the safety of it.
So a great example of this always like say stock data, right, of,
you know, stock quote data, right?
You, you really don't want that stuff being modified in transit.
I would be shocked if there,
if they're doing any sort of verification
because for those sorts of organizations,
speed is going to be more important than correctness.
Well, now it is, yeah, with high frequency trading now it's, it's, yeah.
Ok, bad example.
But anyways, you know, there are valid cases where you have data that
can be public, but you definitely want to make sure it's correct. So weather data,
let's go with weather data, right? So anyways, it's
looking at wireguard, it's, it's
the thing I realized too is so IPIC comes from a time where, you know, bare metal,
right?
We barely had virtual machines.
Not only that, I think it's really important to remember that I
PEC is your typical protocol development committee where
there were probably no less than 50 people
involved in the creation of this and everyone had to bike shed it a little bit.
And so that's what,
yeah, I'm just seeing how many RFC S are there for this.
There's a couple.
Yeah, when there's more than one RFC then, you know, it's complicated.
There are
a lot of RFC S for this.
I would be shocked if there's less than 20
-- let's see.
-- 2468, 1012, 1416, 1822. 46
32. 468, 40. I think I skipped a few back in 4042.
That's
the standards. There's 42 on the standards.
One on the experimental 2468, 1012, 14, on the informational one on best practices
and then two for about a dozen obsolete ones. Good God.
So OK, it's basically impossible to implement correctly,
right? Because just to, to, to actually, I dare
OK, listener challenge
anybody
that can go and read all of those RFC S.
You don't have to read the obsolete historical ones. But you can, if you want to,
if you read all of those RFC S and write like a
one sentence summary of each RFC and send it to us.
Good for you.
No, don't send those to Kurt. I'm not reading them.
I mean, this is very typical, I think of old I ETF engineering
where
it just so many of these protocols are so complicated.
I mean, my favorite example actually is TLS 1.2 versus TLS, 1.3 where in TLS,
1.3 they just got out the poop sh
and they threw out almost all of it because they
were like this is madness and it doesn't even work.
-- And I'm shocked they did
-- that. That was a great example too.
People are talking about, you know,
ips
has backwards compatibility and wire guard doesn't really make that a priority.
And I'm like, thank
God
backwards compatibility is always fraught with bugs and problems.
Throw away backwards compatibility. It is a terrible idea
and it's a tough one though because for example, with iot and smartphones,
there's a lot of people with cheap phones out there that for example,
will never do TLS 1.2 and higher.
And I don't want to punish them for not being able to
like or wanting to buy a new smartphone just to have,
you know, TLS 1.2 or 1.3.
But at the same time,
at some point that stuff starts to do more damage
than it's worth. I think, I suspect
I agree. But I also would be willing to say in an environment with something like IPSA
backwards compatibility, you have control over that.
You're not talking about randos connecting into your environment,
you have control over what's going on.
Well,
unless you're talking about oftentimes it's used
to connect with partners and stuff.
And I've heard, you know,
the horror stories where the two partners both have a 10 dot Star network and then
-- a gigantic argument about over who has to renumber.
-- Ok.
I mean, and you can make that argument,
but you could still even say I'm not partnering with you.
Unless you run a modern version of
IEC,
you can't run the one you found in 1985 on that router in the closet.
Well, and that was the other thing too,
as simple as wireguard is to set up and there's
packages and more modern operating systems on the Raspberry Pi,
there are some sort of VPN specific distributions that have it,
but on the default Ras Bian
and
don't mean default globally, but like kind of the default most people grab is rasp,
right? I know it's one I grab.
Yeah, I would, I would say that, yeah,
you've got to compile this thing from source and just the get checkout alone
on that Raspberry Pi for to rebuild it and do all the deltas took,
you know, the better part of an hour,
I will admit I've not tried making it work on a Raspberry Pi.
We should probably clarify. I think we've talked about Wire
Gard in the past, but I mean,
kind of the nickel tour here is obviously anyone listening.
We'll assume, you know what a VPN is if you don't,
I don't even know how you found this podcast.
But
basically the old VPN S
will say the, the VPN S from the older public, they are
stodgy and complicated and they do everything
because they were developed by committees.
Well, they were developed as frameworks, they weren't a product.
It was like, well, we want a framework that can support every possible use case.
-- Yeah, that's fair.
-- And so we'll give you all the options, right.
And then someone built it
-- and they almost always support all the options.
-- Well, and here's the best part.
This is what I love about ips.
Trick question. Which one do you install on? Linux?
-- I don't install any of them because I hate
-- it. Right.
Is it strong Swan or Libra Swan or? I think there's a third one I forgot.
So the times I've used them, the person I'm connecting to, had it set up and said,
here's how you make it work.
And they gave me all of the configuration files and I installed which
particular demon
that they told me to
-- because,
-- oh, here it is open Swans the third option.
Sure.
I don't even remember anymore. Thank goodness.
Whatever VPN S are the same deal where there's a million of them.
They all work a little different.
I do remember a long time ago connecting to there was a Cisco VPN.
I used that when you were on Linux every eight hours.
It needed to be re keyed but the client on Linux couldn't Rekey. So it just like puked.
-- It was
-- great.
I remember having
VPN just bounce up and down every six hours or whatever to do with stuff like that.
Yeah. Yeah, they were terrible.
Anyway, anyway, so Wireguard is kind of the new kid on the block.
I don't even know who built it,
but it's easy and fast and it lacks a lot of configuration options.
It works natively in a container with
IPs.
You have, well,
rather I shouldn't say that it works natively in
a container if you give it the cap admin,
the network admin capability,
which is not the most fun thing to do in the world, but it works.
I'm confident you could make
IPs
work in a container.
If you just tried hard enough,
you need a kernel module that is actually
officially people say like you shouldn't use this.
-- But if you want it to work here you go.
-- Maybe, I mean, you can Wire Shark
kernel module now. It was just accepted into the Linux kernel a couple of months ago.
-- You
-- mean
-- wireguard? But yeah,
I'm going to say Wire shark a lot. I mean wire guard.
No, you can definitely get IPIC working in a container, but it's,
it's a nontrivial amount of work.
Whereas Wireguard works a lot more easily and natively in a container,
which kind of got me thinking, I mean,
part of me is I'm kind of over the whole VPN thing because to put it bluntly,
I run most of my applications server stuff
on other people's stuff and I'm connecting to just totally strange random people.
So,
you know, cloud flare is a great example, right?
They're my content delivery network.
Like I'm not going to set up an I PSY or a
VPN tunnel from my server to them to encrypt my web traffic.
-- I'm just going to use http
-- S you might not. But now don't you have a VP
service you use for
-- downloading things
-- for torrenting.
-- Yeah, because only, I don't have a better option.
-- I also have one of those for things.
And another example is I don't use Wireguard.
Actually I keep meaning to do it at home, but I'm still too lazy.
Is I ssh into my home computer.
I've got a file server in the basement and I can ssh from the outside world.
-- Well, that's
-- what I'm saying is at the I'm saying, basically that where I,
I want this stuff to live is at the
application level so that my application can conclusively say.
Yeah. No, we're cool. I'm safe. I'm using HTTP S or SSH or whatever. Not. Well,
-- I'm going over the network and hopefully my underlying host is doing a VPN
-- sort of, I,
I don't care enough to want that feature.
I rarely use VPN S.
And so funny enough, in fact,
there are some computers at work that I can only access through a VPN.
So I just don't access them. Like that's my solution.
Yeah,
everyone's like, oh, just connect to this machine.
I'm like, I don't have access to it.
Like, oh, I'll set you up like, no, you don't understand. I don't want access to it.
-- Like, it's not
-- correct me if I'm wrong,
but there is no facility or concept in UNIX of
a program being able to ask the underlying operating system,
you know, or being able to specify to the underlying operating system.
This traffic must be encrypted.
I mean, not that I'm aware of
-- and I don't think anyone, I mean, that's kind of why TLS even exists.
-- Well, exactly.
I need to know the application level what's going on.
I need to be able to say with certainty
this web request was encrypted or, you know this uh for upgrade.
Now, I do a data backup and I transfer the data backup from server A to backup
B
Well, yeah. Was it encrypted in transit?
I need to be able to say yes, with 100% certainty.
Right.
Anyway,
I also, I,
I think maybe we're in the weeds a little bit because I
know we wanted to discuss this at a higher level and talk about
people complaining about lack of features or new things or
I think especially in the world of Linux and UNIX,
you get a lot of the change is bad crowd and wireguard is
very different and very new.
Well, I'm also thinking that a lot of it is, is not just change is bad, but
I want to do things my way.
I don't want to do them this more normal standardized workflow way.
And I see this a lot in cloud computing, right, where I go to a cloud vendor.
So I'll just a generic email list server type people, for example, right?
And a lot of them are like, you know,
we will put mandatory unsubscribed footers in your email.
So, you know, somebody clicks on that, they come to our site,
they can unsubscribe from your list,
they can leave a reason, you know, saying it's abuse or it's spam or whatever,
meaning thus, if you are on our service and you become abusive, we can boot you.
And you know, I know a lot of people don't like that because they're like, no,
we want to handle the anti,
you know, the unsubscribe and all that. And I'm like, no, you let the vendor do it
and you behave and I, and I, I think that's better long term for everybody, you know,
but a lot of these vendors, you know,
want to have that more perceived control
over everything that's going on and not give
up any control or not change their workflow to be a more normal standard workflow.
Right? I mean, I understand what you're saying and
I think I would have agreed with that attitude a couple of years ago even.
And I think the world of open source especially is built upon
this kind of
concept of choice.
I
did it my way, right?
But I feel like especially in the world of security that the
observations of the world today are showing us that too much choice
is bad because too much choice can't be secured. And I will perpetually pick
on TLS 1.2 here where TLS,
1.2 supports every cipher ever created by humans it feels
like and like half of them are now insecure.
It's like, so just freaking take them out. I mean, what's up with this?
It's very frustrating and very difficult. And I think VPN S are a great example of
these VPN S do everything and when you do everything,
you're not going to get it all right
-- and you don't get it all right.
-- Oh, yeah.
I was looking at some of the options and I didn't recognize them.
I'm like, I would have to look up what this does do. I do.
I need to set this option is the default safe. Like I have no
-- idea.
-- I agree.
I think it's very complicated and it's unnecessarily complicated in many cases.
But again, we're back to the protocol by committee and I mean,
I PV six is another example.
I, I PV six does an insane number of things because it had a million people work on it.
And so now you probably
50 RFC s and nobody knows how it works.
Yeah, I looked,
I remember looking at the I PV six roaming stuff and trying to
understand it and just kind of gave up after 20 or 30 pages
-- and
-- no one's going to use it.
I mean,
I PV four even has some Bizarro extensions like that and
nobody uses any of them because they just don't work.
I mean, it,
I love this about computers where you have these
protocols and you have these features where
they can do amazing and incredible things,
but in many cases, it's so complicated, nobody can figure them out.
So just, nobody uses them. And at that point, why is this even a thing?
The whole thing sort of reminds me of, you know,
where cars have gone in the last 50 years from being,
you get this collection of parts that sometimes works together but you got
to tune it a lot or pay somebody to tune it to,
you know, I take my car and
I think I'm supposed to take it in twice a year for an oil change.
That's pretty much the extent of my maintenance. Oh.
And I get the tires swapped in, you know,
fall and spring for my winter and summer tires and that's it.
Like, I don't really make a lot of choices about my car other than, you know,
the radio presets
you could make the argument.
Cars are more complicated than ever before, which is obviously not wrong.
Well, but it's hidden from me in the sense of when something does break.
I take it to a mechanic.
He plugs in one of those OD, whatever ODBC two or whatever readers and,
and tells me, you know, how painful it's going to be and then I see him
-- and come back like a day later. It,
-- it is true.
That is how it works. I see what you're saying though.
And that's where it's headed with cloud. Right.
Like we have these vendors where it's like, either you,
they can fix it or they can't fix it for us.
And, well, we had this with, you know, our,
when we moved from
Zencastr. Wow, that's Zencastr had problems. Right. And what was our option?
Well, we can either live with those problems or find a new provider.
No, we couldn't live with them because it didn't work.
It got so bad but it just kept tipping over, you know.
Yeah, I remember we'd spend 23 hours trying to record and
it just didn't work at all.
So, I mean, I get why people kind of hate that world, you know?
No, you know, this thing contains no user serviceable parts. But at the same time,
you know, if you want like a really flat smartphone,
yeah, we're gonna have to glue it together.
I'm, I'm cool with the big fat thick one, but I,
I hear you and I'm ok with restricting choice to a certain degree.
And I feel like this is a situation
where if you're unhappy with the way Wireguard works
and you think it needs some fixes or you think it needs to do something else.
Patch is welcome. I mean, there's literally nothing stopping you from.
Well, there is because most people who complain are just bags of gas.
But like there's no reason you can't go do your own thing.
Well, you can fork it because my understanding is that Jason,
a Donenfeld who created wireguard is pretty strict on his
stance of what it will and will not do.
And I respect that, you know, it kind of reminds me of, you know,
like Python or Pearl where you have this, you know,
benevolent dictator for life who decides, you know,
this is where this is headed and, you know, we're going to stick to it.
Didn't, I think Guido gave up Python?
-- Yes,
-- he, well and yeah,
he's since handed it over to a foundation or a committee or I don't know,
whatever I have.
I have no idea who owns it now.
-- But
-- yeah, but at that point too, you know,
the Python culture is pretty firm like they,
-- they have culture and
-- that's fair.
-- I don't even know. Is pearl, does pearl still exist? I haven't used pearl.
-- Yep.
They changed the name for Pearl Six.
Raku.
-- What is
-- it? Raku? Raku.
I've never even heard of that.
Raku is a member of the Pearl family of programming languages,
formerly known as Pearl Six.
It was renamed in October 2019. It introduces elements of blah, blah, blah.
It's Pearl Six.
-- As I understand it is this, you know,
-- my favorite part of Pearl Lois was,
was Larry Wall.
Yeah, exactly.
Larry Wall is one of the greatest and most entertaining speakers I have ever heard.
-- He's awesome.
-- He had style and taste so well. There you go, folks.
Maybe we should stick to products that are run by people with style and taste.
Well, no, really.
Actually, Larry had some interesting comments and this,
this is kind of on par with this discussion is.
So
I I forget exactly what the comment is.
But he basically said when someone asked about making pearl easier because this
is back during like the pearl versus Python versus Ruby fight where I thought
Ruby and Python were all about. Oh, let's make it easy.
And Pearl is Pearl and Larry Wall basically said something about, you know,
you can make this easier.
But it's kind of like if you make writing easier just because everyone can write,
doesn't mean I want to read the novels they create, right?
I want to read novels from good authors, not from anyone who can write.
-- And like he's not wrong
-- php is the poster child of this argument, right?
Oh my God
must be
real.
And I'm not saying it's a bad thing.
Like look at what, you know, wordpress and Facebook have created with PHP.
It can be awesome, but you look at the majority of PHP code and it's just,
it's terrible.
Yes, we can keep taking this towards the the authors
and writing concept is
if you think back, you know, probably two or 300 years,
the number of people who were actually literate was fairly low in many places.
And so if you could write,
you were probably a good author for a variety of reasons.
-- Well,
-- by definition,
you were a good author because there was such a small pool of authors.
Yeah,
-- that's true. That is true. It's
-- like music. It's, it's funny.
I listen to music and some of the older music that I used to think was good as a kid.
Now I listen to it and I'm like, or even better example, children's cartoons. Ok.
There's 10,
my goodness.
I
looking at older children's cartoons now I'm like,
this is just got off like this is just objectively bad,
poor quality Hannah Barbera animation with.
Yes, exactly. I, I understand.
I got Disney Plus and Chip and Dale Rescue Rangers are on Disney Plus.
And I thought, oh, I watched this as a kid.
We need to watch this and I told my kids I'm like, hey,
let's watch this and the intro starts and I'm like,
I don't remember the intro being this bad and then the cartoon and literally I made it
about four minutes in and I had to turn it off because it was so bad.
Took my, the, the local,
one of the local cinemas does like free
children's movies every Saturday with cereal or whatever.
And we went to the Muppets movie and my kids wanted to
leave and so did I after about five or 10 minutes,
no, the Muppets movie is awesome.
-- You take that back?
-- It's terrible.
-- No, no, I watched that one. A couple of months ago and it, it holds up. I
-- love it.
I think we're gonna have to agree to disagree.
No. No, you are wrong
anyway.
Yeah,
that's fair. But, no, I, I agree with you 100%.
It's, it's always funny how that, that changes. But anyway, the point being
in kind of the world of development, obviously, like anyone,
anyone can write code now, but I don't want anyone to write code.
Well, not just they can write code, they can publish it,
they can get it into the ecosystem.
Like there is no barrier of entry to get stuff into like Ruby gms.org or,
or N PM or whatever.
No, no, not at all. Yeah, but I would then also that if you looked at like the
PM ecosystem,
it's probably very long tail where there's a couple 100 packages that are used
-- by a lot of projects and then most of them probably have one or two
-- uses. Y
oh yeah. Well, I mean that, that applies to everything that's ever been created.
-- Basically.
-- No, I, I agree. I agree. So anyway, anyway,
the concept of, I guess the paradox of choice, right?
Where I feel like we are learning enough about
security these days where choice is bad choice.
This is not a feature.
-- And I think we used to think it was a
-- feature
choice is very hard and to make a good choice,
you need to have a lot of information and I would consider
myself like an above average computer user slash computer security person.
But if you asked me to actually, for example, go in depth on I
pec options. My answer would be like, I'm not an expert on that. I will mess it up.
There's probably six people on the planet
who could do that.
I agree with you 100%.
And I mean,
this is one of the challenges with a lot of these security technologies and it's not,
I mean, not even just IP
A right.
You can pick on countless technologies, everything from antivirus to firewalls,
to encryption,
to, you know,
TLS to VPN S where we've created these monsters that
just have so many options and so much choice,
you have everything from the development of it is nearly impossible to get.
Right. So no one does. The deployment of it is nearly impossible to get. Right.
So no one does and the usage of it, it's nearly impossible to get. Right.
So no one does. And it's like if you were trying to set someone up for failure,
this is how you do it where there's just insane complexity from top to bottom.
That's terrible. Right.
Whereas then you look at something like wire guard and they've taken away.
I mean, don't get me wrong.
It's still not like super simple to set up like I could not teach my mom to do it,
but it's pretty freaking easy compared to most things.
Well, there's, I mean, there's just way less things,
options to type in and get wrong and fat finger.
Yeah. Right.
And I just,
I love the fact that it doesn't really play that well with modern technology,
like containers.
-- You mean, the old stuff doesn't play well?
-- Yeah.
The IPs doesn't, you know,
you have to install a kernel module and do
some other shenanigans to get it working and behaving.
It was built in a different time.
I mean,
Wireguard was built in the world of containers and it
wouldn't shock me if it was developed literally in containers,
right?
But there's lots of things that work fine in containers
or have been easily modified to work well in containers.
Yeah, but they probably don't have 50 plus RFC S.
Yeah, I guess they've sort of painted themselves into a corner there.
Yeah.
And like, look that's, I mean,
part of the beauty of RFC S and the downfall of RFC
S is the fact that it's very difficult to make changes.
And in certain things like IBV four,
I don't want people making random I PV four change.
Like, I mean, imagine the Microsoft of the late nineties if they were like, oh,
I think I PV four should work like this.
-- I remember that actually because I, I
-- did, they do that
well. No, no, no.
Microsoft didn't.
I remember like paying IBM for the OS two TCP/IP add on pack and like TCP/IP stacks.
Were not always completely compatible with each other, you know,
-- or there were glitchy things like, no,
-- I don't remember any that didn't work
well.
They would work together. But you'd get like, you know, just
things where like packet sizes, things like that, you know,
where just things would go wonky or,
you know,
this thing with this router and this packet size just can't work things like that.
I mean, that, that's fair. That's fair. But it,
thank goodness we fix most of those problems.
Choice and RFC si, I don't even know what to say.
I feel like this is one of those situations where less choice is better,
especially in the world of security.
I would rather see two products
that each do their own specific thing than one product that tries to do both.
Well, or in the case of
IPIC one product that literally tries to do everything.
Yeah.
And there's no way to really secure it.
I mean, you might think it's secure but I guarantee there's,
there's skeletons in those closets and
part of it is people just haven't found them. And I mean, I feel like the number of IP
S a security issues,
I've seen it's drastically lower than it should be
when you compare it to something like TLS,
which I think even TLS 1.2 is less complicated than IPSA.
-- There have been a but there's a lot of research, but I
-- think there's 152
ips flaws. And that's multiple vendors. Granted. But still,
I feel like it should be way higher than that though.
I mean, how many, what do you get when you search for TLS?
Oh, well, TLS, you're going to get a lot of stuff that uses TLS improperly.
-- Not so much TLS
-- itself. There have been a generous number of TLS flaws.
Oh, yeah.
I'm not saying there haven't been, I'm just saying with TLS, you also get
all the applications that make use of TLS and for example,
forget to do host name checks.
Well, you can't really blame
TLS for that as a protocol as an implementation. Like when was it open SSL?
And, and also Python didn't check the host names by default. That absolutely like
-- everything worked well.
-- Great. Yeah,
so
everything works so well. All right. Anyway, we should, we should end this one.
I'll give you the last word. Kurt. What are your final thoughts?
Yeah, that's it.
-- That's my final thought is a heartfelt sigh.
-- That sigh is a nice thought. I like that.
That,
that sums up all of security. Just a big long sigh. All right, cool. I'm calling it.
So, thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening. You can go to open
social security podcast.com, hit up the show notes, you can use the Pound
and
Os S Podcast hashtag to send Kurt
hate mail about why you think VPN S are great and why your guards
And yeah, you can, I forget where you, where you were at. Pando
says podcast hashtag
on social media. And I see, I, I tried being clever and I confused myself.
This is, this is what this is a problem with complexity, right?
Don't try to be clever.
-- Like
-- I have proven the problem with cleverness
and complexity like it just doesn't work.
-- So anyway, thank you, Kurt. Have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too.
-- Thanks
-- everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the.