Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in promising you that
this podcast will always be available at the URL open
source security podcast.com. Josh Pressers.
I don't promise that at all.
Yeah, but you bought a DNS domain name and put the content there.
-- So by definition, it has to be there forever.
-- I'm looking does open source security.
Yeah, open source security, podcast.com forwards to open
source security dot IO.
-- That was the original UL I think
-- it might have been.
No, I think I bought did I,
I don't remember anymore how we had it because we have the URL S we have is open
source security dot IO. Oh, no, I remember now because we had open
source security podcast.com
which was hosted on blogger way back in the day
and then blogger did something that like really upset me
and I don't even remember what it was now,
but it was so bad that I also own open
source security dot IO,
which was just like the wordpress site that I basically took the wordpress site,
added a podcasting section and then migrated all of the open source security.com
into that site and then just redirected the UR
because I think the Os S podcast.com or there's,
we have, I think Os S
-- Os S podcast.com also forwards to open source Security Ion.
-- I
-- did not know that.
-- Yeah, that's our, our shortened URL.
Yeah. And this ties into today's show, which is now the Apple people are discovering
that there's a whole bunch of Cocoa pods which is,
it's just a software name space repository for
-- chunks of code.
-- It's the package manager
for Cocoa.
Yeah,
-- I guess
-- that's it.
They're rediscovering like the rest of us that when you
have a name space like DNS or N PM or PP
that when somebody owns that name and provides something there
that essentially
people are gonna behave like that's a guaranteed thing forever
that it will be maintained and loved and cherished.
-- And,
-- well, I don't think that's a reasonable description of what happened.
It sounds like what happened was
they like, disowned
all of the packages and owners had to go back and reclaim them,
but a lot of people didn't.
-- Yeah,
-- because they,
the, the premise of these name spaces is that the,
when a name is taken by somebody that it will
somehow magically be used in correctly and forever and forever.
But that's not the case.
Well, sure. It's just a package name.
I think calling it a name space is misleading in this context.
But anyway, what happened though?
The Cocoa Pods project,
basically removed ownership of everything for some reason.
I can't remember the details of right now.
It's in the, it's in one of the news stories, then
you had to go reclaim your ownership and obviously they had some sort
of checks for checking emails and things like that to verify you.
-- Are you? Which
-- is good because nobody ever lets their email domain expire.
-- Obviously
-- not.
And then
10 years later, some security researchers found out, oh,
we can just make an api call that will transfer ownership of unknown things to
us.
Which is
neat.
I,
I
the thing is, I don't know what to say here because really the, there's,
there's no real sort of kind of the only air quote
solution to this problem would be to kind of require again,
sort of active ownership of it like,
but on the other hand, what if it's a mature piece of software?
And it's like, like my favorite example from Ruby,
like American date conversion where it converts a date into that goofy month, day,
year American format.
-- And it's done,
-- I mean, but you still want
an owner, you don't want it floating in limbo.
Well, this does raise the issue is I think it
would it be better or worse if it's kind of frozen in time
and nobody can hijack it or if you allow it to be taken over
by some entity because
here's the dirt. Like here's one of the truths is validating. Identity
is very difficult.
Like I,
I run into this all the time people send ad po request of like
I want to delete my email address at the CS A and I'm like,
cool.
First you're gonna have to email me from that address because like otherwise,
you know,
you're just some Rando emailing me saying delete this other
email address and we we don't do that right?
And sometimes, but they really say like, look,
I don't have access to that email anymore.
Like I don't work at that job,
-- blah, blah, blah, whatever, right? I don't
-- know. Does the, does GDPR
-- have like a definition for that particular instance?
-- Yeah. Well, more to the point.
Do I want to deal with the GDPR regulator and a possible fine?
No, that's true, I suppose because if you don't believe them,
so the good news is,
most of them are pretty like we do verification via their linkedin profile,
which in most cases is like to put it bluntly like
if they're going through this much effort to delete someone else's
email address, uh
-- you know, the CS A and like it's the same name basically, you know.
-- Oh, wow. Ok.
So I just, I just looked and the, the text that showed up,
it says the controller should use all reasonable measures to verify the identity,
all reasonable measures.
That's so that, that all the
-- a lot of work
-- not commercially reasonable, just all reasonable. Yeah,
all reasonable measures.
-- But yeah,
-- and,
and this actually raises nothing where we had somebody
say I want you to delete my email address.
And I'm like, OK, and they're like, but I just want you to do it this way.
And I'm like, no, like I'm just deleting it. Like this is not,
this is not like a menu.
Like if you say you want me to delete your data, I am deleting your data
gone
because
again, from A G like they invoked the GDPR that we weren't timely enough.
And they basically said, hey, you didn't respond quickly enough.
And I'm like you never saw the first email. Like I have no idea.
Like I checked like it's,
it's a freaking Google group like it's not
like it must have bounced it or something like it's not, there's,
there's not a lot of places the email could go missing. OK?
-- I don't want to turn this into identity conversation.
-- Yeah. So, but based on all this
identity is very hard,
but identity is only step one. The second step is, is this identity
-- authorized to do this thing? I,
-- I don't think separating those makes sense.
Well, but if you're in a hospital because you get, you know,
hit by a car while you're on your bike,
-- that's a thing which is
-- a very real possibility.
-- I ride my bike a lot
-- and I go to a DNS registrar and I'm like, oh man,
like I need to fix our DNS entry.
Can you please give me access to this? Like,
I'm
the Kurt
Siefried Dawn the podcast. Like I should be allowed to do this.
-- They're gonna be like, no, go away. Yeah,
-- they wouldn't let you do that.
I, I get that
right.
And so with these packages,
like the community can't, the,
like,
like I'm waiting on pp to validate our organization's profile, blah, blah, blah.
And
it's probably not going to happen for months.
And that's ok because you know what,
it's a volunteer led organization that I'm not even paying a penny
and for me to expect service from them
in a reasonable time. Well, no, too bad. That's not how this works.
I, I think we should just tie in the second story
right away
and this is titled The Expense of Unprotected free software.
It's high time F Os S Maintainers got a bit of appreciation
by Paul Henning
Kamp
and this one was sent to me by our dear friend Toma De Pierre.
And I'm like, you need to put this on Mastodon.
So like I can, I want, I want to re to you because you get the credit here.
But basically what this kind of comes down to is
just pointing out the fact that like open source is
really underfunded and under everything right
now and these maintainers are average
pressure.
See, OK,
this actually raises another thing I've been thinking
about a lot you say it's underfunded.
I think that's the wrong word to use because
saying it's underfunded somehow implies that it has
some degree of funding which technically it does.
But for example, somebody was talking about how
you can't really call it an open source supply.
It's, it's a community resource that is being like strip
-- mind.
-- I'm comfortable with the word underfunded.
I think that's fine.
I don't
like it because to me it implies that
-- funding it properly is a possibility which it is not.
-- I think
it should be, I don't think you should say it's not.
I think there's a lot of things
that need to be come to grips with in the open source world.
And basically the point is though ignoring the the fine details like
this, this post kind of ends with like
what what happens now, right, where we've got this,
all this basically technical debt that's piled up for for forever.
And this actually ties in with the open ssh episode where we were talking about like
just the size and growth of everything is ridiculous and out of control.
And that's like part of open source.
And so this like this, both of these stories, it was wild because I read them.
I'm like, oh my goodness, this like these are, they are the same problem.
-- Both of these
-- I finally, I think come to terms with
basically two sentences that describe why I find this problem.
So intractable to even think about, let alone find a solution for
which basically boils back to. We can't make people work for us for free.
That's slavery.
Yes. Right. People can choose to work for free.
Like if I choose to pick up a piece of trash
on the side of the road and put in the garbage.
Cool. Thank you. You know,
if an open source developer chooses to write a really nice library that does
XY or Z and make it available under some license that I like.
Fantastic, lovely.
But then the other flip side of that is that looking at how do we fix?
Because you and I tend to focus on security,
but it's not just security bugs,
but there's other real like YTD LP. Right.
Again, the youtube ID format changes, Y TT LP breaks.
Everybody's like I want an updated package that fixes this
and the developers are like, well, the code is fixed, it's this two line fix,
but we're not doing a release until we fix our C I CD and it dragged on for a year.
Maybe it still is. I don't know anymore.
But economically speaking,
the only kind of really
reasonably efficient and sane way to fix this is to make the maintainers do it. So uh
-- Yeah.
-- No, no, no, no. OK.
I, I think this is a bunch of pieces and I don't think saying, oh,
make the maintainers do it.
That's the easy.
No, no, no, I'm not saying that I'm saying,
I don't see any other reasonable solution to that.
No, no, I, I understand. I understand.
But that's,
I'm not saying that's the solution because the problem is that I'm saying, well,
yay slavery, which I don't like.
Well, it's a solution but yes, it is and not ideal solution.
I think from a security perspective,
especially risk is that thing we always talk about, right?
And when we use open source, we are today
pushing the risk onto the project.
For the most part, I know people are like, oh,
you have to analyze your open source and you have to
understand what you're running and all this, but no one does that
they're pushing all that risk upstream and they're being like YOLO open
-- source. Thanks for playing
-- well.
I'm going to interrupt yours because they don't have a choice.
They can't write a web library, they can't write a PDF parser.
I don't think that's the right way to look at it again.
I
think you're, we're, we're pushing too much upstream.
If I decide to use an open source library,
what am I doing to have reasonable
expectations around the maintenance and supply and,
and just the overall risk that comes with it.
Right? For the most part,
I am doing nothing. I'm doing no due diligence because I can't,
I don't know who's writing it because I can't,
I'm not paying attention to security vulnerabilities because I can't.
Yeah.
So I'm just taking free stuff and I'm using it and
hoping everything works out and for the most part it does.
Well, I mean, because an example is the open ssh vulnerability.
If open SSH upstream doesn't fix it,
the economic cost of having a million people patch their
own instances of open SSH and build their own packages.
Number one, let's ignore the fact that most of them can't,
they technically lack like
I'm sorry, but as easy as building an R PM is
-- like, I bet less than 1% of technical people can do it.
-- Oh man, it's
adding a patch to an R PM
is harder than it should be.
-- That is what I will say
-- or ad package or whatever, any package, they're all
the same.
Yeah.
Right.
Like,
because I've done it. You
Yeah, we worked a red hat.
That's I literally took ownership of a package to buff my resume when I went to
for
hat.
Yeah.
Well,
I also needed that silly open HPHP open ID thing of a jigger
-- to work
-- got you
because it literally needed like this one patch.
So it would actually work
and the maintainer hadn't touched it in like four years.
I have built and released thousands of
RP MS for security updates
and you've probably done Open SSH even I,
so I have many stories about Open SSH actually.
-- But
-- let me put it this way.
Do you want a world where every company using open SSH builds, their,
not even builds their own package.
Let's not even go there.
Just say they download the source R PM or the source D package or the source,
whatever thing for their distro,
add this one little patch and rebuild it.
I do not want to live in that world because it would be a disaster.
I don't think that's a so, so here's one of my
complaints.
But what I'm saying is economically the only sane way for
this to happen is for as centralized an effort as possible,
which in this case means the open sh developers ship a good patch that we
know we can trust reasonably well and then all the distro consume
it and roll updates and roll packages that we did update.
That's economically the only thing that makes sense.
I don't think this is a valid comparison though
because open SSH is special. A lot of. So here's, I think here's the thing
that I'm, I'm having a thought as I speak, there's kind of two worlds of open source.
There's things like open SSH in the Linux current
and
we'll say well maintained, open source. OK?
We're like, we don't worry about open SSH,
not releasing updates like that's just that is expected and it is going to happen.
It is a properly resourced project. Now. It, it certainly could use more money.
I'm certain of that. Right.
Linux kernel, same idea,
they have resources but and that is not comparable to an open source project that is
a guy
or a lady or whoever in their basement,
that is not a comparable comparison,
comparable comparison is that whatever it's worked out.
And so I think this gets this, this creates
this difficult talking point
of
like saying, oh,
you have to rebuild open SSH and that's really hard to do and it is hard to do.
I'm not saying it isn't versus
I'm using a cocoa pod
from a website
that does a thing and maybe I could replace the thing. Maybe I couldn't, I don't know.
-- But you know what I mean? Those feel very different to me.
-- OK.
Similar example, let's say
we need a, a
widely used Python package
for people to roll their own update and deploy it locally.
Less than 1% of technical people would be able to figure it out
just how would they even know
exactly. And this is what I'm saying. So from an economic perspective,
I keep coming back to the only sort of
economically rational way to do this is a centralized and
upstream as possible. And then I get back to my counter.
I like, but I'm not in favor of slavery.
So I don't know like, how do we do this if the developer says no or no, thank you or
you know,
or is on vacation because God forbid this
person maintaining some critical piece of the internet,
but well, not even the internet, that something that all of society depends on.
Right. I'm always reminded of XML hash offs
where the guy is like, yeah, I can work on it in three months.
Like I have other, I have my life and we're like, ok, well,
we'll do the work because we need this now.
-- And, but that happens very rarely
-- in that instance,
that was also a literal redhead employee
offering to help with the thing And we just saw XZ,
which was a very similar situation
but a less than ideal outcome
and, and that's the thing, right?
-- So that I suspect
-- these stories though are way more common than we think we're,
but we're only seeing it when they like,
basically mark their repo is archived or read only.
But I'm guessing that there are hundreds or thousands of
bugs, even security bugs, performance bugs, whatever bugs,
bugs that people really, really want fixed
and developer like, yeah. No, I can't or I won't or I don't want to or whatever.
-- And it's like now, now what?
-- Well, and look, that's
the question and that's the thing,
I think as consumers of open source where the relationship is broken
because there are consumers of open source that will try to give
them money or go try to work with someone like tide lift
or,
you know, maybe go talk to the Sovereign Tech Fund or, or,
-- or whatever and they'll
-- have a employee spend
half their time working on upstream for sure.
Yes.
And, and I, I mean, I remember when I was at Elastic,
we would do that where if there was a library we needed a thing
and for whatever reason
it wasn't getting done, we would get it done. Right. We would go and help.
And of course, again, coming from somewhere like elastic,
coming from somewhere like red hat.
I think it was easier to have that conversation though. Right. If, if Kurt
siefried shows up at a random project, people are gonna be like,
who the heck is this guy?
Well, or a Fortune 500 A to get the funding and resourcing.
But b yeah, like some Randall from a Fortune Five 100 shows up. Good luck.
I might be more perceptive to
an email address from a Fortune 500 than from
-- a Rando.
-- What about an, a large cloud provider that's known to take open
source and modifies it?
-- Well, I mean,
-- look even that. So
that's funny.
I mean, I know like we've crapped on Amazon a lot for their, well,
all the cloud providers do it.
Yeah, I mean, Google and everyone
and we've given them a hard time more than once.
And I was actually thinking about that specifically in the context of this,
this Paul Henning comp.
Um Ph I'm gonna call him phk for the rest of the show,
but I was thinking about that specifically, like in this context
and I think if you look at the big open source projects.
It's easy to say they've done a bunch of strip, big old big cloud providers,
not big old projects.
It's easy to say they, they strip minded open source and to a degree they have,
but it was often
some sort of like corporate
open core open source thing. Like you had, you know, Reddi
and
Mango and Elastic search and these sort of things.
Hashy Corp is another one, those are the things that they've kind of taken
and twisted versus like random small packages, right?
And they're using them and they probably
aren't contributing back in any meaningful way.
But I feel like again,
we have this like dual
conversation of,
I've got this basically resource project that's being taken and used versus
I have a open source project that's one person
and I'm taking it and using it.
And again, to go back to economics. A
the licenses specifically allow the cloud providers to
go and grab the stuff and use it for
our contributor nickel back and B that has resulted
in one of the biggest transformations of it.
And one of the biggest,
like
the fact that you can now stand up a website with email and with everything for
like six bucks a month and just have
it work or deploy some custom application for like
10 bucks a month.
Like
everybody, I, I mean, as much as people hate on cloud,
I dare anybody to build an email server from scratch and I mean, by scratch, I mean,
go by the parts of like, best Buy or whatever,
figure out how to get an IP and route it and like, you know what I mean?
Because you and I have done that and it's horrible. I don't ever want to do that again.
I want to read a paragraph from this paper
by
what I say. Phkphk. I got that right.
That I think
it, it, it captures a lot of this
very well.
It says over the past couple of decades, our world has certainly transformed to
the point where washing machines no longer can
start without a connection to the internet.
We've reached that point by drawing on an almost unlimited credit line extended by f
volunteers like Lassie, which is the, the XZ maintainer.
In many cases,
these folks have been more than happy to
forgive that debt along with the compounded interest,
but that simply matters
the problem until these generous souls finally lose interest,
retire or simply die off
that, that should scare you to death.
That paragraph should send chills down your spine.
Well, that's the thing.
Like I've noticed a lot of open source projects and efforts that
the average age of the maintainers is increasing by one every year.
Yes. Right. Like where's the, like,
like I get that there's new people coming in. But by and large
part of it too speaks to like,
because, well,
we just I just did another round of stf um evaluations for these projects.
And one of the
common patterns we're seeing now with some of these projects
is that they're basically not messaging it the best way.
But they're basically saying, look like we're the experts.
We're the only two or three people who can do this work and upgrade the software.
So we want money to pay us to do this and it's in some cases, the software is highly,
highly
like one was a Computational Fluid Dynamics Simulation suite
which yeah, like it's,
you're not gonna have like a bunch of random people show up
and actually be able to help with what they want to fix,
which is the the transfer of heat through um uh
transparent materials, right?
You as an engineer probably know that that's mildly complicated to, to model.
And so it is kind of like it's a rock and a hard place of like where we want, we,
we like the STF doesn't want to just pay
people to write software.
They actually want more, have a, a more of an impact with community funding
and you know, maybe improving governance and growing the community and all that,
right?
Because, and some of the projects very explicitly had as part of their funding,
like we want to have 100 hours to
spend on improving governance and growing the project.
And it's like, OK, good because that's sustainable, that's
long term.
But like there is the flip side of like there's
a lot of open source software that is real technical.
Well, here's, here's a great example.
So did you read the story about the PC RE two maintainer?
This is a couple of weeks ago, I'll put, I'll put a link in the show notes. Um
I know enough about PC RE to know that I
would never even attempt to think about modifying that code.
Well, so here's the deal with PC RE two is the
-- OK. So for what is PC RE
-- Pearl compatible regular expressions, right?
It's a regular expression.
Regular expressions are hideously complicated.
There's a famous saying that if you solve a problem with
-- Red Jacks, now you have two problems.
-- I agree with that 100%.
And because every time I've used regular expressions, I'm like, oh, it works
and then when it doesn't work,
it's because it's like some insane corner case that takes you a week to figure out.
But here's the thing, the guy who maintains that package,
he just turned 80 years old
and he created an issue on github. That's basically like
he titled it long term Maintenance of PC Re two with basically saying like, what,
what is, what are we going to do?
This is like straight up like Japan has their idea of living masters where, you know,
they some guy's awesome at pottery or making swords or whatever.
And
the government actually has programs to try and you know,
get them an apprentice to keep these skills alive because,
yeah, like when those,
that one,
like
nobody on the planet knows more about PC re too than that guy.
And it would be nice if he had an apprentice to, like, mind dump into.
-- But,
-- I mean, my suspicion is he's not sustaining his life on PC RE two either.
No,
but he's also statistically not gonna be with us for forever.
-- right?
-- You know.
Yes.
And that's the thing that always gets me is like for a people worry about projects,
not having enough developers.
And
we're also starting to maybe realize even worse than like
much more complicated and difficult than that is like,
does this project,
can it outlive its
benevolent dictator for life if they die and
not many projects I suspect would survive that?
Ok. So, so let's let's move on
to the like, maybe
it, it's funny,
we actually talked almost exclusively about this and I think Cocoa pods is, is,
well, it's, it's similar, I think it's part of the story, right?
So here's the thing I've been thinking about putting all of these pieces together,
you know, like PC re two Cocoa pods, the PHK story,
kind of just I've been spending more time than you can imagine.
Like, like building these scenarios in my mind.
What struck the middle with Cocoa pods is like if a nation state
agency paid to get about five or 10 of those cocoa pods,
you know,
updated and maintained by them.
Then at some point in the future,
they could very easily slip a back door in that ends up in like mobile apps on.
Yes, that's it. Like not a percentage
like on the mobile apps in that ecosystem.
-- It's,
-- it's objective c right, objective C is like the Apple Development eco
system. So you'd get like iphone
and, and OS X stuff.
I'm guessing if you basically got five or 10
well positioned packages you could basically get on every
-- place on the planet
-- for sure, for sure. OK.
Anyway, all right, all this stuff put together, right?
Yeah,
I feel like
we are reaching a point
in all of open source and everything we're seeing
and these developers are getting burnt out and angry and
frustrated.
I I'm not saying they should sabotage their projects.
But I think like if you're fed up and sick and tired,
we,
you need to be able to step away and not feel like crushing
guilt that somehow you're letting society down because the problem is if you,
let's say archive your repo,
there's good.
I mean, you saw it when, when the guy for the what the node IP project,
archive your repo and there were all these news
stories about how terrible it was this guy.
No, like
the guy
he needed a break, cut him some slack. It's not his problem.
I still love
cried.org with 20 year old content.
On it because people keep coming to it and reading it and I occasionally
get an email about it and I've seriously thought about just turning it off.
People would probably complain.
I think when you create something like an open source project,
when you're working on any community, anything,
I think you end up in a place where you feel like you have to do something. Right.
Because, you know, there's people who are counting on the work you do, right?
And I mean, I've, I see this, there's,
there's some open source stuff I work on like at the open ssf that it's like if I, if,
if I don't do it, it's not going to get done.
And I know people need this to be done,
right?
-- And so there's this like
-- they need to be done so much
so that they'll rely on you to do it for free.
That's
just,
it's
like Belling the cat, everybody agrees. We should bell the cat.
But like, ok, is anybody gonna buy us a bell or even?
-- Well,
-- and that's just it. Right. And I think
there are, and I'm not,
I'm not saying these are bad people or bad companies or anything like that, but they,
they've created this like
sense of,
of purpose.
I don, I don't know,
I don't know what else to call it for these open
source projects for these users and they're giving them guilt.
Right. You know what this reminds me of entirely is the whole recycling.
It's your job to recycle and that will save the planet. It's part of
it's
no, it's you
and your plastic straws.
That is the problem.
Not a Fortune 500 with actual resources
that can change your manufacturing process.
It's you, it's your job to recycle. And as we're all discovering
like something like upwards of 80% of recycling ends up in
landfill in North America because there's no market for it.
You know,
like I recycle and I feel so ridiculous doing it because I,
I know the numbers like here in Edmonton and everything.
But I feel that if I don't, right, like that's the thing like they poisoned us.
Yeah.
And I think part of this kind of I'm gonna say this quote
because I think it kind of applies here in a sideways way.
The markets can remain irrational longer than you can remain solvent.
And I think that's kind of what's happening here is I think a lot of these people
are scared because they realize they've given all this
power to the open source community because like,
they're running open source, like they can't, you,
you can't replace the Linux kernel.
No, like
if no,
I
mean, in theory, you could maybe switch to free BS D,
maybe that's like kind of the closest ish
-- thing,
-- but it's still the same problem.
Exactly. Yeah.
But I mean,
like the only people who can write their own operating is more
like Microsoft and Apple and even they lean way heavy on Apple
didn't write their own operating system. Apple took free BS D
-- actually.
-- No, you're right.
They basically did just repackage most previously and a bit of, uh,
what you might call it
-- space and out. What's that old thing called?
-- Which the old thing that the next,
-- yeah.
-- Next,
because they bought next to get Steve jobs and then,
-- yeah,
-- even, but, but that's my point, like even a modern massive multi multi
gazillion dollar company like Microsoft or Apple can't
not use open source,
the economics of it again
like
that,
that's it. You know, it's
here we are.
And I think what we're going to see is these companies not,
not like maliciously or really intentionally kind of do these things.
But I think they are going to try and create that expectation of like, oh,
you provide open source.
-- Well, you know, you do have a duty to humanity
-- to
create that expectation. They create it right now for these projects.
And I don't know if they know they're doing it even. But anyway, the point is
I think open source maintainers have to recognize that it is OK
to put your project on hold, to abandon your project to walk away.
And you don't have to feel eternal guilt
because you're letting some people down because look,
yes, you're gonna let some people down,
but there's also no reason they can't start to help either.
Right.
These are also the people that would like literally show up in your house and demand
all the food out of your fridge because they just can't be bothered to go shopping.
I, I don't think so. I think that's an unreasonable comparison.
I think there are people like that. There are people
that have inflated senses of self worth and,
-- and that they deserve everything you keep
-- talking about people.
-- But in a lot of this, it's organizations and companies,
-- it's people,
it's not organizations, it's fundamentally people talking to people.
But that's the point is, I think
at the end of the day, most of the people filing bugs
making requests,
having
inflated expectations.
They're not bad people and most of them probably don't even know what they're doing,
right?
They probably don't realize the pressure that they're
putting on something like an open source project.
I think it's just part of the machine.
I'm going to disagree with you there because remember that VLC media
player bug that was filed by a Microsoft employee that basically said,
look, your VLC changed broke teams and we need you to fix it now.
That was definitely
a bad person,
right? But that's, but bad people don't exist in a vacuum in these organizations.
They don't.
And that's because the weird thing is like, I've, I've met people that work for,
tell us my local phone company and these people were nice, decent human beings.
And the organization they work for, tell us is
evil.
Like tell us health and the things telehealth has done
to try and privatize healthcare in Alberta is evil.
I know for American listeners, you're like, what?
Of course that of course for health care,
there are good people working for bad companies.
There are bad people working for bad companies.
But one challenge I see is I see
good people working for bad companies doing bad things
-- and that does happen sometimes I agree
-- and they're not really good people anymore
and, and that that can happen sometimes they don't know they're doing bad things.
It's, it's complicated, right?
People are complicated and open source is
complicated because open source is just people.
My point is all of this.
I think we have to build an environment
where we can make it ok and safe for
open source project owners and maintainers to step away
-- and not have to feel impending, horrible guilt and doom.
-- I have a possible solution
and hear me out. You know, the contributor covenant,
yes,
maybe we should have a user covenant that kind of actually lays
out the rules and the expectations and good behavior and bad behavior.
That is interesting.
-- I wonder if the O SI would approve that license where, well, it's
-- not a license,
it's an agreement.
-- Right. Well,
-- it would be a license.
-- I mean,
-- contributor covenants, not a license.
It basically is.
I
know it's a code of conduct. But I'm saying when, when you are a user of open source,
you must accept the open source license to become a user.
Well, what I'm saying is this goes back to a show many years ago or months, years,
who knows what the,
where remember we talked about how like if you have 10 users of your open source,
sure, whatever.
But if you have 10 million users of your open source and even 1/10 of
a millionth of a percent of them come back to you and ask for stuff,
you're going to get slammed.
And that's what I'm saying is have a user covenant where like
literally before you can file an issue against this thing in github
that I maintain, you're going to have to agree to this behavior contract.
Like my, my son, both my sons are going on
summer camps
and all the summer camps. Now, I don't know about that in the US.
But here in Canada, every summer camp here now has a set of rules that like,
not just the kid has to initial and agree to, but the parents have to agree to.
And it's,
and it's obviously stuff that's happened because it's
like no verbal abuse of the camp counselors,
like no blah, blah, blah and it's just insane stuff.
But
you read about like kids sports teams down.
-- It's, that's crazy
-- what you've just described. Kurt is a license
-- that is how the license works. Well, No,
-- no, no.
But I'm saying you, you,
I have a license to use my software and do whatever the heck you want with it.
That's independent of you talking to me and getting my attention.
-- No,
-- I, that comes with that. Like
when you look at open source,
there's the, the free as in beer
and there's free as in speech, right?
And the intent being and this is so this is an interesting concept, right?
And I don't think I I it will deserve more thought and future discussion.
So freezing beer is just like free stuff.
You're getting a free thing, whatever, that's it
free isn't speech
is about conveying freedoms onto the person receiving your stuff.
And it's always been a very,
I am conveying freedom
onto the users of my stuff.
It has never really been an expectation of my users conveying a
-- functionally a sort of freedom back onto me.
-- Traditional open source.
The users were generally not problematic because
there just weren't enough to be much.
Yeah, it was very small. I agree.
And I think that ship has definitely sailed,
right? Like now everybody is an open source user. Every company is,
and I think part of the challenge is is that
when I release an open source software and I give you this
license and I give you this freedom to do whatever with it
that should not create an obligation for me to then
even answer your issue on github
it doesn't
because the license says
that this software is provided as is
and what I'm saying, but then the users behave as such that they expect that.
And we've never really,
we've never really handled that as an industry.
And I literally think,
and I'm not talking about a contributor coming in the sense
of like it necessarily being effective as a leader agreement,
but being more effective in a sense of here are like the rules we want to play with.
Because for example, a lot of projects now do not take kind of randomly filed bugs.
They have a template and you better fill that template out.
And for example, uh Linux kernel is a great example.
If you don't tell them what version of the LINX kernel you're using like, yeah,
they're going to ignore you.
-- And rightly so, I mean,
-- sure and any project can do that,
right?
But I
that we maybe make this a bit more official
and actually start teaching people so that we,
we add a bit of a gateway and the gateway has the simple
of you need to not be a jerk and you need to like,
tell us what version of the software you're running at a minimum, right?
Because I've dealt with that where people report a bug and I'm like, what,
like what software is this even?
And I wanna,
we're gonna end this conversation and we're going to end this show because I,
I don't think you're wrong.
I think there's something interesting here,
but I also think it's very complicated and it could probably stand some thought.
See, I think what it boils down to
as a maintainer.
-- I want the nice people to reach out to me
-- and, and that's not the point.
The point is,
and the thing we have to end it on is that if you are an
open source maintainer and you need to step
away from your project for whatever reason,
it doesn't matter what it is. It's ok to do that.
Like it's over
to step back and not read bugs and not supply patches.
-- It's, it's
-- ok.
I would go even a step further and say, you know, it's your project,
you can do whatever you want or don't want to do with it.
That's easy to say.
-- But that's not, people are proud of what they do.
-- I know.
But I think we need to tell people like, look,
don't maybe let this define your life as much as
well. No, they'll let it define their life.
It should, they should be proud of what they did.
I'm not saying that I'm saying though that
when somebody demands a feature or a bug,
feel the freedom to just like ignore them or to say no.
And that's ok
because that's one thing I, I see a lot of developers
in the open source world have a hard time saying no.
And it's funny because the ones that do often say no are then made out to be like mean,
yes. Right. We see that all the time.
Like those people complaining about the links
from developers issuing CV S and like,
but they're mean about it and it's like, no, they're not.
And like,
or they point to a male thread and I'm like, no, this is like,
-- it's not polite but it's not
-- mean.
All right, I'm ending it.
I think this is a lot to think about. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. Go to social security podcast.com YZ Podos
podcast hashtag on Mastodon Kurt and have a marvelous rest of your day. You too.
Thanks everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.