Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in possible copyright infringement.
Josh Bresser,
are we infringing on anyone's copyright? I said possibly
that's fair.
I know actually the music, the intro,
music I made very certain to acquire a public noma
song that also the recording had no copy claims against it.
But what if, for example, we have, what is it?
-- Four minutes and some number of seconds of silence? Is
-- that? Oh, that's true.
That's true. I would never do that to anybody because that sounds terrible.
So there's a podcast that it hasn't come out in over a year now.
I think it's called Hello Internet.
And one of the favorites the editor would do C GP Gray edits it.
He would have like a minute of silence
in and then like a little little outro snippet y thing
that they'd leave in.
And it used to drive me insane because I don't have skip silence enabled on
my podcast player because I feel like when there is silence in a podcast,
it's meant to be there for whatever the artistic purpose is from the host.
-- But like this frigging podcast would have like, like dang
-- it.
That actually sounds annoying.
-- It was
-- very annoying. I did not care for that.
Yeah, this was a reference to 433 which is a three movement
composition
of just silence
-- and it's apparently copyrighted.
-- You can copyright anything.
Anyway, today is the day
that Kurt and I talk about open source,
the licensing of it, everything because it's just been a huge topic in the news for
months now and probably years.
Well,
I think it's finally come to the point where we can no longer ignore the problems.
I, I would agree with that. Now, I'm going to
preface all this
with,
I work for elastic and the elastic search license has been a huge topic in the news,
-- didn't you guys just use the Mongo DB
-- thing?
We did, we moved it to SSPL
which is service side public license and
I do not speak for elastic.
So,
anything I might say does not reflect on the company Elastic has
done an enormous amount of public comments and discussions on this topic.
-- Go read what they said. I'm not elastic.
-- Yeah.
And obviously, you know, Josh and I have been in this for a long time.
We're not lawyers and this is not legal advice.
Yeah. If
you're coming to us for legal advice,
you have way bigger problems than a lawyer can solve.
-- I suspect
-- I would expand that to more generically
if you're coming to us for advice at all.
That's true
outside of like,
maybe waterless toilets and a few other domain specific knowledge pieces.
-- Right. Yeah.
-- Sorry.
-- No,
-- that I could just pull a Fox news and say, oh, we're just entertainment.
We're not news, we can say whatever we want. I'd forgotten about that. Right.
It's America. It's great. Yeah.
-- Anyway,
-- so, yeah, open source licensing,
I think what's interesting for me is it works really well for
-- a while and now it's clearly not working so well
-- and I,
I mean, I kind of agree with that.
So
it kind of the set some of the thinking curt and I KT and I have done a bunch of research.
We've done a bunch of discussions obviously off podcast about this.
And the thing I keep coming back to is there's two angles is number one,
the current open source definition published by the O SI,
the open source institute.
It's an institute. I think it's Institute,
the O SI was published in 2007. What did the world look like in 2007?
Well, and it came out of the whole, it really came out from the decade before it,
-- yeah, I mean, the, the late nineties,
-- like, it's not like it just popped out
in 2007 and they spent a week writing this up,
you know.
-- Right.
-- Right. The point is, it's decades old. Right.
-- Well,
-- it's literally from a different time
there was no cloud computing.
There was barely smartphones had just come out right.
-- There was no concept of an app store. There was no
-- IOT.
Well, there was, it just wasn't actually hooked up to the internet. Thank God.
That's right. That's right.
And so kind of that, that's aspect.
Number one and aspect number two is the current
definition of open source is controlled by the OSI.
And the O SI is a foundation and I am not a fan of
many foundations because I think they become
this sort of weird self serving tautology.
They become a bureaucracy that
exists for the purpose of existing as opposed to its original mandate, which is,
that's a well documented
of these things.
Look at the Linux foundation sponsors, look at the O SI sponsors,
look at like any of these foundation sponsors and it's,
it's all the big companies you can imagine.
Well, it kind of boils down to number one
who actually benefits from open source and ends
up capturing value in the form of money.
Amazon.
Yeah. And then who then is willing?
You know,
it always reminds me of like zoning and
building codes and real estate related stuff where
I wish I could have a bit more of a say in that, but I don't have the time for it.
Whereas a real estate developer can cheerfully spend $10,000 lobbying or hiring
-- a lawyer or whatever
-- and they've got skin in that game too.
-- In ways you don't.
-- Well, the thing is they've got a way to capture value from changing
-- the bylaws or changing the requirement
-- right now.
I also want to say that there's going to be people who comment.
Well, if you don't want your software being used in a way you don't like,
you shouldn't make it and source that is a ridiculous argument.
That is the, don't be poor
-- of talking about poverty.
-- It's funny.
Well, actually this will be linked in the show notes, but the Bruce parents,
his new kind of concept where he talks about
this about how these people want to kind of right social wrongs.
But they're typically, as he put it like a, you know,
world court level of types of things,
you know, typically these people aren't saying like I don't want people to,
you know, use the software while they're eating mayonnaise.
It's more things like
you, you can't use the software for evil. Well, who defines evil?
I think we should create the mayonnaise public license now,
I'm just saying,
but Right. Right. And, and
what Bruce is talking about is, is something that I think we'll,
we'll just weave it into the show
and kind of to set the stage and we'll put some links in the show notes
to a document and a talk Bruce Perens gave and Bruce goes back to like,
he's one of the people who defined what open source is.
And
-- I think that's kind of his claim to fame.
-- He helped Chisel the tablets,
right?
So where he came from is,
is actually the Debian project was a huge part of everything he did is so Ian
Murdock created Debian Bruce Perens made it real is how I would always think of this.
You keep talking about open source success.
And I was just thinking about that and I was about to say that
Debian was like one of the first really
successful open source distributions because of Bruce.
But
it's interesting,
there were actually there and there still are other like slackware,
very successful open source distributions in terms of people using them.
But I wouldn't say necessarily successful, maybe in terms of community, right?
Like
slackware is infamous for being a guy who like, well, when he got sick,
there was no slackware for a while whereas Debian has built community and,
and I think that's one of the challenges is this whole, what does success and win
and
you know, having a healthy ecosystem look like for open source.
And I think part of the, and I hate to give this answer, but I think
-- the answer for that is it depends, there is no one answer.
-- Well. Right. Absolutely.
But I will say that I think the vast majority of us who are involved in open
source and especially those of us who got involved in open source a long time ago,
it was all about the community.
It was all about. I'm part of something bigger than my,
for me, it was literally just,
I needed software that didn't cost an arm and
-- a leg and require signing agreements and worked
-- well.
I mean, that's part of it too. Obviously. I, I couldn't afford a Sun workstation.
-- No, like
-- I, I unapologetically
just
needed software.
Like, and I, you know, Windows didn't have a web server or a web client.
OS two was nice and all. But compared to Linux and the tooling I had in Linux,
-- it was flaming garbage.
-- That's fair.
And I will say that's how I got started because I got all this.
Like I wanted a development environment and ac compiler was expensive.
And so Linux had a free C compiler. So I was like, well, I'll just do that.
So eventually I realized like there's so much more
going on here than just a development environment.
And I think that's where like whole community aspect became a huge deal.
And that's what
I still, I wrote a blog post about this, like in my opinion,
and this is just me talking like, I don't view open source as some licenses.
-- I view it as the people I interact with.
-- It's a culture
like
and what I love too is it's a
loosely coupled culture potentially or tightly coupled.
-- It's
-- a mess. It's lovely.
Well, I, I was running,
I was connected to the internet and I realized
I could connect out to everything on the internet,
doesn't that mean everything on the internet can connect to me?
So I started looking for security documentation and there wasn't any.
So I wrote some and at one point, my,
my website was getting over 100,000 visits a month which back in the, you know,
99 2 thousands for a private website.
That's a lot. That's awesome.
Right.
There's other projects obviously where it's much more tightly coupled, like say,
you know, the Linux kernel where you know,
if you want to start mucking around with some subsystem,
you probably need to actually coordinate a bit.
You can't just,
you know, just do what exactly whatever you want.
There's coding styles issues and whatnot but, but even then
I keep coming back to meet what open source is all about
is I don't have to ask for permission,
ignoring the monetary aspect, which is a form of permission, right?
You need to pay me $5 to use this.
You need to sign this legal document to use this. No, it's just
you can download it and assuming you're not
going to do something really troll with it,
like
redistribute it and not
abide by the license.
Yeah, go
go nuts.
You know, I was looking at the um the open source initiative,
open source definition, right?
And um I mean,
really pretty much every point boils down to so you can include
it and ship it without having to pay or sign agreements.
Right. Right.
Now, now, the one thing I always ask and this isn't something we have to answer here.
It's just kind of a thought exercise for the reader is if you look
at the O SI today and you read their writings and everything going on,
do you think
-- they would approve the GP L today?
-- Uh GP L original GP LV, two or three
of them?
Tough to say.
I, I, we don't have to answer it and I don't think we should,
-- but I just think about that
-- and one thing to keep in mind is GP L
and V two and V three are quite different. Like they share, they share that in GP L.
But if you actually look at them, it's like, whoa, there's,
there's some big differences which I,
I think is sort of speaks to the challenge of this stuff is evolving.
I think it's very presumptuous to define something back in 2007.
Well, and even earlier,
because obviously it didn't just come into being overnight,
but to define something 14 years ago in a, in a
environment that moves as much and as weirdly as the open source world moves and to be
essentially,
yeah. No, this is good.
We're done.
Right.
-- Right. Exactly. And
-- like, I feel like this needs an update.
I agree.
I think it all does. And now the idea Bruce Perens has that I do kind of agree with.
Is he thinks that the current definition of open source
is should be set in stone and not changed.
And in fact, in his world,
the definition of open source should really be three licenses, which is Apache two,
the
L GP and the
GPL and like that's it.
And
I would say the vast majority of open source licenses fall
under one of those three umbrellas in some meaningful way.
And there's some weird ones, but I think generally speaking,
those are the three ideas, right?
Where Apache two is essentially do whatever you want. L
GPL is, you can do whatever you want with this, but you have to share it. And a
GPL is basically, if you use this,
you're going to end up open sourcing pretty much everything you've got
it is I always did find it odd that there are so many
actual open source licenses, you know, like a, like the MIT one or whatever.
And I just, I kind of always wondered why are there so many, but then, you know,
the open source world, we have how many implementations of whatever thing,
you know, it's, this is just normal.
-- Well, in
-- everything, I mean, back in the day, it was hip to have your own license,
even if it was virtually identical to something else.
And there'd be one little pet thing you wanted to add in. And
I mean, things like the MIT license and the BSD license, those predate open source
by probably decades and
obviously in their intent,
it was just a matter of like we're pushing this out the door, don't ask any questions,
sort of thing.
-- Well,
-- and, you know, the lawyer said we had to put something on paper. Right.
Right.
Well, and because at, and T sued them, but
that's another story.
But. Right. Right. And so anyway, what, what Bruce is kind of talking about?
So open source is cast in stone, we're not going to change open source.
And part of me agrees with that because I think
what we call open source is well understood today.
But then he's saying the world has changed and we need something new
to kind of replace this
and accommodate developers and the universe
in the world we live in.
What's interesting to me is he really comes at it from this thing,
sort of the two big takeaways for me from his talk where
number one, we need a copyright and patent free or not free unencumbered space
where it's
where the software is sort of known to be safe.
There's not my favorite all time example is Rambus. Remember Rambus.
So like they worked on this memory standard and this company called
Rambus basically held patents on stuff that they shoved into the standard.
And so the standard was approved and Rambus is like, ha ha pay us, right.
And so there's a reason you haven't heard of Rambus is because it died.
Turns out these manufacturers didn't want to pay Ram bus, you know, and,
and that's a real problem in the wireless space.
For example, you know,
there's major chip manufacturers that hold all these patents and there's,
there is literally no way
for
-- an independent entity realistically to go get good wireless patents.
-- Right.
-- It's just not possible.
Well, that's like, you know, you know what that reminds me of is I remember,
do you remember the MPEG Consortium from back in the day
with like MPEG two and MP3 S and all these compression algorithms?
And I'll never forget. So there was
a,
a guy used to be at redhead, his name is Tom Calloway.
We call him Spot and he gave a bunch of talks and like the legality of these patents
and like the M PEG Foundation would say, oh, you have to pay us if you want to use these.
And I remember one day
spot said he asked them, he's like, well, what are the patents discovered? Then?
They said all of them, he was like, what?
And I mean, you know what that, you know what that really means?
We don't know, they don't know, but they just want your shake no money.
And it's like, that's nuts. Right.
And
fortunately though they probably have lawyers and, well,
-- do you want to spend 50 grand or 100 grand fighting them or
-- you
pay them like five grand and you get their license and whatever you're done.
You know,
-- it's a no brainer from just a risk versus reward perspective.
-- Well, as long as
in
that classic terms, you know,
as long as you only actually have to pay them once and they don't
keep coming back or threatening you for more like the patent trolls do.
And then the second sort of tenant that he keeps coming back to
in his new thing is about
the developers, like right now basically have to go beg for a job or funding.
I just literally saw one where it's this app,
it's a mail app that supposedly allows you to handle
high volumes of mail gracefully on your Android device.
And the, the guy is basically trying to fund, you know, €52,000 a year for it.
And I'm like, I'm sorry, but good luck buddy.
But at the same time, are there people using his software getting tens,
if not hundreds of, you know, dollars of value out of it?
Absolutely.
Probably. I mean, how much would it cost to build a library like that?
That actually works. It'd be very expensive.
Well, it's not a library. It's, it's an actual male client on, on Android.
Like it's a full fledged app.
And
so, I mean, that it's not one of those like hidden libraries.
-- It's an actual, you go to the App store, download it, start using it.
-- I got you.
-- Why doesn't he charge for it then?
-- Because nobody would pay well,
that's fair.
How many people spend literally as much time
fetching about a $5 app as they would about buying a house,
right? Like humans don't
the way humans make decisions about
yesterday, I bought a used car. I
had spent like two or three hours looking online
at various types of cars kind of learning,
you know, a bit about what was available and blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
And then I found what looked like a decent, you know, like a little four door sedan
and I basically went and test drove it and the guy brought
out his magic foursquare paper and started trying to do the financing.
I'm like, no, it's a cash sale.
They wouldn't let me put on my credit card
because I wanted to do that because the points,
but also
I suspect they wouldn't let me put on my credit
card because then if there's a problem with it,
the credit card company would get involved on my behalf.
That's true. Right. So back to our house insurance, fire argument. But
anyways
with this is, you know, these developers either have to get like a,
a job at some company that directly supports open source or get a job at a company
where the company will graciously allow them to work
-- on open source or
-- try to acquire funding.
Like, like for example, Linus Torvalds
is paid by the Linux Foundation.
The thing is though it's not like, say academia where yes,
you have to acquire funding and spend, you know,
half your time doing grant proposals.
The thing is in academia, there are well understood and
there's actually money flows in the open source world.
-- There are money flows. Good luck trying to find them and acquire them.
-- I mean. Right.
And, and this is where
I feel like we, we're going to run into the people who say, oh, then don't,
don't publish your software, which I think is a little bit silly.
-- Yeah. If you use a computer, you probably shouldn't say that. I
-- mean, I kind of agree.
I feel like that's a cop out.
Every computer on the planet has, if it doesn't ship open source,
open source was used to help build it.
-- Right.
-- Right. Full stop that there's just, there's no alternative.
Absolutely.
And, and I don't, I don't like that because I feel like this is an example of you.
I mean, open source, develop just developers in general are
they're artists creating art, you know, think of it that way.
And these are people who
are they, they want to create art and send it into the world.
It doesn't matter if they get paid or not necessarily.
But I think they're like, there's,
I have a bunch of crap github that is basically just junk.
I do. And I don't care who uses it.
I usually stick an Apache two license on it because I don't care like, whatever.
I'm just gifting it into the world and it's never going to be big enough that,
that I would expect it to, to pay for anything for me.
Right. Ever, ever. Now, if I wrote a library and it was used by all of the Fortune 500
that's when I feel like we start getting into this situation of like, hold on.
You're telling me this person wrote something that's running the world
-- and they're doing it for free. That seems
-- broken.
Perfect example of this is insulin, right? What was it?
Frederick Banting discovered insulin in 1923.
He refused to put his name on the patent.
He felt it was unethical for a doctor to
profit from a discovery that would save lives.
The co inventors sold the insulin patent to the University
of Toronto for a mere $1 and you know,
the idea being that we're just going to mass
produce the heck out of this and save people,
I assume they also
had employment probably for life after, after that discovery.
Well, sort of, but anyways,
but it boils down to these companies with software, you don't really have to
spend money or effort making sure it's healthy because
if it does what you needed it to do, who kind of honestly,
unless it has some horrendously exploitable, remote security flaw,
kind of who cares
-- about updates or changes,
-- that's how we exist today.
And I mean, I do think that's wrong, but that's another
-- thing,
-- but it works economically and it does, it's, how do you tell a company?
Well, if you do this thing,
give a little money to this guy or to this foundation or to whatever
it'll, things will be better and the company is going to go.
Well, how do you mean better?
Well, and that's it. I, I don't, I, I can't really explain,
you know,
unless
you get to that situation where,
well,
there will be a problem someday in that software that might be
a Showstopper or a compatibility issue or some new standard comes out
and it won't work.
And if you had funded it, you'd be able to get an update and move along.
But by having this, you know, very, um,
I don't want to say fragile ecosystem but this ecosystem that is not
healthy per se, like it's not, it's not as robust and resilient as it could be.
I mean, and it might all fail, kind of like Texas's power grid.
I
know.
I know. But, ok, ok.
So the time zone guy gets sick and we spend a month mucking around with
who takes over the time zone file
in that month. You could have some real problems if you're a bank.
-- And,
-- and I guess here's part of what I keep thinking of too is when,
when, like some of this stuff was done in, say the early two thousands,
the world was different
and there weren't a lot of companies really doing anything
I would say from an economic perspective with open source,
like you kind of had Red Hat.
Well,
there was a bunch of companies like Red Hat and
there was a ton of companies using open source and,
you know,
gaining the benefit of hundreds of thousands of dollars
of work that they didn't have to pay for.
But yeah, there was no
empire built on open source like Amazon web services or,
-- or
-- literally every company today, every
company today has built everything they have on the back of open source.
Do you remember the time when there
were multiple commercial web servers available?
Yes. Or like Sun, Sun, right?
Or if you wanted a UNIX computer, you had like 10 vendors,
you could buy a UNIX computer from now.
If you want a UNIX computer,
it's running Linux just that's it.
I mean,
Linux one
-- for obvious reasons,
-- but open source one won well,
open source totally won.
But, but I mean,
that's the thing I keep thinking of is there's all these
organizations that have built these enormous empires on top of open source
and a significant number of them are just all about.
I'm going to take everything I can get
and some of them give back. Some of them don't.
I mean, my take on this would be then why are we focusing so much on the companies?
It sounds a lot like open sources, infrastructure like public roads
and for example, in general
with public roads, we say, look, public roads
are good, right?
They, they let the police and the firefighters get to your house quickly.
They packages get to your house or condo or apartment.
It allows you to go to work, it allows you to go buy food.
So it's, it's a public good that we will taxpayer fund.
Well, open source sort of sounds like that.
Now, I'm not saying the government should take over this.
I think that would be an absolute disaster, but I'm saying
this, this idea of, ok, let's try and get companies to pay for it.
I'm not sure that's going to work.
It's going to be tough because there's going to be a lot of free riders.
Whereas, you know, for example, a taxpayer funded system, well,
there are no free riders if you're
paying taxes and ignoring the whole corporate tax, shenanigans,
Irish Dutch sandwich, whatever the heck, those avoidance strategies are called.
But I'm, I'm,
I'm of the opinion that I,
I like the idea that Bruce Perens has about building this new structure that,
you know,
allows companies to more easily get sort of
open source compliance and use open source more.
I, but I feel like it's
not so much, not enough, but I feel like it's,
I think open source really is a public good
in an infrastructure issue like roads. Now, it's just that fundamental to society.
-- I
-- would
-- agree with your statement now.
-- How we execute that.
Yeah, I don't know, like no that and you know, to, you know,
the devil's in the details, so to speak.
-- But
-- OK, you know what you just made me realize there is,
I think an important connection here and
like let's look at
some of these gig economy companies and I'll pick on Uber right now.
There's actually a very nice thread Cory Doctorow put out,
I think it was today or yesterday.
Basically talking about the fact that like Uber is
literally built around exploitation of the people who work for
like no questions asked, right?
And so Uber is like this great example of there they
are this huge company that's exploiting humans as their natural resource.
And I think if you look at the history of a lot of big companies, they're all about,
I'm going to take a resource and I'm going to literally like
abuse it as long as I can.
You look at people like your Amazons and your Googles and your Facebooks,
they're taking like open source is just a forest,
they're cutting down and they don't care,
happens to it in a lot of cases, right? I mean, I think this is a similar problem.
I think my concern with,
with things like Amazon and Google is that they reduce the sort
of the vibrancy of the ecosystem if that makes any sense,
do they?
I mean, do they, I don't know this is, this is a hard question.
I remember a time when we used to have a
dozen Linux distributions companies and now there's sort of two,
I would say there's three. You've got Red Hat, obviously you've got so,
and you've got
-- Muntu. Right.
-- Right. I keep forgetting about them. Sorry.
But then I would say also, you look, you've got like Arch and Debian,
there's a handful of your community.
I think that says something when these community distributions I think are
probably healthier than any of the company distributions are today because like,
let's face it.
Linux has basically become a commodity.
I mean,
a freaking IBM bought red hat. Like what the heck.
So my concern with these large companies is, is
fundamentally, they're not violating the license.
And I wouldn't, I would say they're not even violating the spirit so much.
But what I,
where I have concern is that they're
benefiting hugely from these open source projects.
It's the tragedy of the commons, right?
If everybody behaves like that, then we have a problem.
If only one or two people behave like that, that's OK.
But I guess the question then becomes if, what if one or two people behave like that?
But they're the size of Amazon.
-- No.
-- Right. That's a good question.
You know, it's one thing if I, if I graze my one cow on the commons,
but if I have 10,000 cattle,
-- yeah,
-- I mean, that's
an excellent question. Now, at the same time there's going to be people who argue.
Oh,
but Amazon funds open source developers and they hire open source
developers and Google has open source developers and they all this,
do they, for example, do they actually return a lot of work upstream?
-- Do they play well with the community? I don't actually know
-- some of them do.
Some of them don't. I mean,
it varies. Like I remember back in the day dealing with Google.
Google was notorious for being like, hey, I'm Google, I'm here to help.
And people were like, oh, not again.
And I mean, even, I mean, I remember this happening at redhead even or, you know, oh,
we're a red hat, we're here to help.
I'm like, oh go away
and it just varies, right?
Because there's some, some interactions are good, some interactions are bad.
I think you've got a wide variety of interactions.
But I think fundamentally, I would say what I see
most of these companies doing
I feel like is a net negative just from
the context of making the open source ecosystem better.
I don't know, I don't have the,
I suspect I keep coming back to part of the problem
is I feel like a lot of people are giving up.
They see Amazon and Google succeeding so heavily.
And I also worry that they're sort of changing the ecosystem in ways
that make it harder for smaller companies to get started or compete.
-- Oh, without question,
-- I like vibrancy and weirdness and
-- you know, having lots of alternatives and differences,
-- right?
And actually this is something,
this is a good place to kind of kind of drive this home is,
this is something Bruce talks about in his presentation is the fact that
if you look at open source today,
it's basically almost completely consumed by companies
where the company takes open source,
they bring it in and then they basically create a product people use.
And obviously one of the intentions and I think the
birth of open source was around making a thing for
people and other people would take your open source and
they'd combine it with this open source over here.
And then
it was a very interesting cycle where people were working with people for people.
And that doesn't exist.
-- Now it was
-- artisanal and then it became industrialized and
that's true.
Just like industrialization. We have ugly smokestacks belching out.
God knows what churning out shoes that are really cheap and you know,
fall apart in a year.
I mean, that's a good point that, that, that makes
to me at the same time, like one of the tenants,
Bruce Perens is trying to push is like this aspect of
it should be easier for normal people to
kind of get involved and use this technology.
I think that's easy to say. And I think that's a very altruistic vision.
I think it's going to, it's, it's hard because people aren't bad at technology.
-- I
-- would be very scared to ship an open source
product nowadays because of the patent trolls and everything.
I would much rather ship a close source product that is harder to, you know, kind,
look at it and figure out because you can easily infringe upon a
patent without realizing it because there's so
many ridiculous patents out there now.
You know,
a computer controlled system that allows you to buy a cookie online or whatever,
right?
You know, that whole, that whole
of business process patents where like blah, de blah, de blah on a computer
-- or mediated by a network of computers was my favorite.
-- And that's part of it too.
And this is something I feel like a Bruce Fanboy today.
But he, like, he talks about the fact that these, like all these companies
who fund all these foundations are also the largest patent holders in the world.
Well, I think it's not so much a causation thing.
It's just a correlation thing of who,
who has the time and effort to actually assign a person to work part time or half
time or even full time on just even interfacing
with this foundation of this open source group.
Well,
a large company that you've got to be making a lot
of extra money to pay somebody full time or something,
you know,
to work on this.
-- Yes,
-- because every now and then I think, oh,
this foundation is doing some working group that I'm interested
in every time I go to the group and it always
starts out with good ideas and then the huge companies
show up and they just drive it off the rails.
You know, my favorite is like, you'll say, oh, we want to work on this problem.
And six months later IBM has us writing a white
paper and it's like this doesn't even make sense.
-- Well,
-- and isn't what we wanted to solve at all?
The problem is it's,
I don't think they're even capable of doing that kind of thing anymore.
And it's definitely not in their best interest to have a free solution out there.
Probably that if you pay attention in the, like, working group space,
it's always like the same group of people that I think they
just work at these companies and their job is joining working group.
-- Well, but
-- who else has the time and effort to do this? Right. Right.
Or the knowledge of how to get involved? Right. Because there's,
-- you know, there's a knack to it, so to speak.
-- Well, no, I don't think there is.
I think there's a knack to slowing everything down and being a pest,
there's a huge knack to that.
And you figure like these people are like, oh, look at all the progress I did.
We wrote six white papers this year and their boss is probably like, wow, six,
that's a lot good job when the reality is like, if these didn't exist,
would it matter?
-- And the answer is no,
-- I think you're being a bit harsh on white papers.
Yes, I'm going to be harsh on white papers because I think
writing code and creating an open source project is way more valuable to the world.
I was about to say one of the big differences,
you can write a white paper and doesn't have
to necessarily be correct to sort of work,
people read it and whatever,
whereas software and code has to be correct.
And as we've seen, you know, from this whole work from home mediated over computers,
a lot of stuff fell apart because you could
no longer plaster over the cracks of fixing stuff,
sort of with face to face conversations.
You know, now it's like, no,
we actually need to do this work correctly the first time.
That's right. That's right. But
as far as this whole open source thing goes,
I think fundamentally it needs to change.
I don't think it is sustainable the way the way things are going and
that's not to say it's all going to fall apart and not be available.
I just think it's a lot of people are going to give up.
-- And
-- I feel like from my perspective, I see,
I feel like I see fewer young people engaging with the open source community.
Why would they man,
you do one app on the App store and it goes
viral that there is no way to get involved with open source
easily that actually allows you to pay your rent and buy food
and people and young people sort of need to do that.
Well,
-- old people do too
-- well. Yeah. Yeah.
But, you know,
but we kind of know how to get a job where we
can also finagle 10 or 20% of our time writing open source.
-- Right.
So, ok,
so it's time to go.
I always love starting these conversations because you never
know where we're going to weave our minds.
But I guess here's my parting thought on all of this is that
I think what we call open source today is nearing its breaking point.
Something has to change.
And I think if we don't guide the change, it's
going to be like an explosive eruption is what's going to happen.
And I think it will be very difficult. I don't think anyone has any good answers here.
I think Bruce is doing a lot like he's doing the Lord's work on this stuff.
-- Well, he's about the only one thinking about this. Actually,
-- I know
-- writing well about it in public,
-- which is slightly terrifying to me.
That's the literal open source way. There's that one time zone guy or that,
you know, like it's true,
like the fact that Guido Van Rossum managed to retire from Python
and it, it went smooth. I was quite amazed.
That's true. The open source way is one person holding up the world on their back.
And Bruce, we, we need Bruce's help, I think right now. But anyway,
I'm going to put a link in the show notes.
Go, go look at this stuff and, and if you can, Bruce asks for help in his presentation,
like give it if you can because I think this is a big deal.
So. All right. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to opens sources, Security podcast.com. Hit up our show,
not, it's U
Pound
Oss
podcast. Hashtag Do hit us up on social media. Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too.
-- Thanks everybody. Thanks
everyone. Bye bye.