Hello.
And welcome to the open source Security podcast episode 168
with myself Kurtz Fried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Pressers. It's new man.
Uh, well, I was almost bit by an aggressive dog this morning.
Oh, that's exciting.
Yeah.
So I was walking and, uh, this lady had, you know, about a 1520 ish pound kind of, uh,
that fluffy white dog.
But I don't know, whatever, that small fluffy white lap dog type of dog.
Not really. I, I don't know, dog breeds apart from like, the popular ones, you know.
Um,
and, you know, I'm walking on the sidewalk and, um,
the dog notices me and just lunges at me and starts snapping and snarling and,
and I'm like, you know, who?
And I take a step back because I don't want to get bit by this thing.
And I'm like, you know, that's, that's a pretty aggressive dog and she's like, oh,
I'm like, you know what if I was a child?
Right?
Like,
you know what if it attacks somebody and she's like, oh, no,
no, it's fine. She's, she's perfectly fine with Children.
She only is aggressive towards men.
And I'm like, seriously like,
ii I didn't know what else to say because clearly this lady just doesn't care.
And, and she also had the dog on like one of those elastic retractable leashes.
So my, my thinking here is this really,
I think demonstrates uh kind of a perfect
example of a security risk incident waiting to happen
much like, you know, an out of date piece of software or, you know, oh,
I don't know what database protecting financial
details with the password and user name admin
a fact.
And, um,
so this lady knows her dog is aggressive towards men.
She, she's perfectly aware of this fact
and there's a couple of really easy things she could
do to reduce the risk of this dog attacking somebody.
Uh, number one would be having a leash that's not
spools out when the dog runs away from you. Right.
Just actually have it on a proper leash. Right.
Right. Right. Number two, she could have put a muzzle on it.
I believe that's something we typically do with
aggressive dogs that try to bite people.
I mean, I mean, and I actually tried to,
but,
well, I tried to Google when muzzles were invented for dogs and, and I basically,
it's, they've been around for so long, nobody knows.
I believe that. I mean, it seems pretty obvious.
Right.
You know, I mean, we even put them on horses and stuff because, you know, there's,
I've met some bitty horse, one of which had been the nickname Hannibal,
the cannibal,
uh, very bite horse. And again, because he'd been abused and he hated men.
And so everybody at the stable knew that this horse hated men.
So only, you know, women worked with this little nasty pony.
Yeah. Anyways.
But so I, I was just thinking because, like, she knows her dog has a problem.
She know, like, to be blunt if this dog hasn't hurt somebody,
it's just a matter of time.
Right. Maybe
and maybe not. Right. Exactly. Maybe it
never happens, you know. Well, look, man, so
I deal with this on a regular basis.
I own a dog and my dog is actually really big and really stupid
and everyone's afraid of him because he looks really scary
until you actually see him and interact with him.
And then it's like, all right, this dog is just a big idiot.
And
so I go to lots of dog things, right. He loves other dogs.
We go to the dog park,
we call it school where he goes to like this doggy daycare and it's wonderful
because he runs like crazy and then comes home and just sleeps for a day,
which is marvelous because the dog needs a lot of exercise and I'm fat and lazy,
so I'm comfortable with that.
But anyway,
you go to a lot of these things and like, for example,
someone's dog will take a big old poop
in the middle of the dog park and then they just walk away and it's like, hey,
now you got to go be picking that up.
It's like, oh, it's ok. The rain will come later today. I'm like, no, that's not.
And you get this kind of behavior out of people constantly and I think it's
extremely related to security where you have that it won't happen to me aspect.
You have the, I'm special so the rules don't apply to me aspect and you have the,
I don't care whatever man
kind of aspect. Right.
Well, that it's, it's externalized. Right?
He's not going to get that dog crap on his shoes. Right.
Yeah, because he knows where he is, he's walking away from it,
you know? Right. Right.
And then, and then like the good security person, I am. I go and pick it up. But
I, right. And I think this is human nature where
we have certain rules that have to exist for us to function as part of society.
And if we kind of lay the, the security overlay on top of that, there's
just kind of certain things that have to happen for any environment to be secure
and there's always going to be people who are like, I don't need to follow the rules.
I don't need to, to use two factor off.
I don't need to worry about patching my, you know what I mean?
And I think these go hand in hand and it's just kind of,
this is who people are and what they do.
And I mean,
I think my favorite example of 11 of the solutions to problems like this are,
if you give people a choice,
most will probably do the right thing.
But there's always a subset that are going to do what benefits them the most.
And this is like having airbags in cars, right?
Why can't people turn their airbags off?
Well, you kind, they can in some cars, you know, generally speaking,
you can't because a bunch of people would turn them off and then they would
die and then they would blame the airbag manufacturers for letting it be turned off,
right?
Like you need these, these controls that are just built in.
One thing I'm thinking is I, I can't help but wonder.
So this seems to be a very deep seated human nature type thing, right?
And I can't help but wonder if part of it is due to the fact that like up until recently,
resources were scarce, right?
Having enough food, having enough shelter, having clothes,
you know,
people forget like cloth used to be incredibly expensive
and difficult to make and clothing by extension,
you know, people had like a change of clothes, that's it up until, you know,
a couple 100 years ago.
And so, I mean, it makes sense if you have something that is a risk,
like let's go back 300 years, you have an aggressive dog.
Well, number one, you're probably really happy about that because that's,
you know, your guard dog.
But, yeah, let's assume for a moment you have an aggressive dog
that's unnecessarily aggressive. Right.
It's attacking people who aren't breaking into your house.
So you could go make or get a muzzle for it. But,
you know, leather goods again or you have to go kill an animal process.
It tan the hide, cut it up, make a muzzle. This is not cheap.
I mean, it's cheap now because, you know,
manufacturing got ridiculously efficient and plastic.
But, you know, uh, 100 200 years ago, I'm guessing a good dog muzzle would have been
probably the equivalent of a day or two salary for, you know, a decent job,
I
guess.
And so then,
well,
are you going to do that or just maybe let your dog bite somebody,
especially if they can't really effectively sue you or punish you for that?
What
is the context of your story to the modern age?
So, essentially this lady has something that she knows might be a problem.
There's a, let me put it this way if that dog does end up biting a person. Well,
it's not a surprise, it's not. Oh, we couldn't have foreseen that. It's
no, no, no. This lady
knows her dog is aggressive towards men and tries to attack
them and yet she hasn't taken any steps to reduce the
risk and what is the bad thing that will happen to
her if her dog does attack and bite a person,
I would assume she maybe gets sued.
Although in Canada it's difficult that, that kind of lawsuit is,
is quite difficult.
So, yeah.
No, I mean, it, it, I think fundamentally she's one of those people, you know, that
walks away from the dog poop and somebody else will take care of it. or the rain.
Dude, the rain does not take care of dog poop. I imagine it doesn't,
it does not.
But like I said,
it just got me thinking that this seems to be a recurring theme in security.
I mean, uh the,
what's really fascinating to me is Microsoft is doing something sort of,
I don't want to say, get ahead of the race, but they're, at least
they're addressing
a really fundamentally difficult
problem in security, which is firmware, right? So
the way most people think a computer works is that
you have ac pu and hardware and it just runs software
but, you know, you control, that's absolutely not how it works anymore, right?
Your, your hardware comes and we've discussed this in previous episodes.
I mean, your average hard drive or your, I mean, your video card. Good Lord.
I can't even imagine how many millions of lines of source code are living in
your video card now or on your motherboard or in your CPU you know,
micro code updates.
And so,
uh Microsoft is basically
looking at several problems, one of which is, you know,
firmware that's malicious or mangled or modified
and, you know,
when people load it and it messes up their system or compromises their system.
And number two attacks that try to then load hostile, you know,
malicious firmware so that the attacker can stay in your system.
Right?
Because I mean, if, if an attacker loads malicious firmware into your CPU,
good luck like getting them out of there, you basically, as we discussed in the past,
you basically have to throw the hardware out and buy new stuff.
You, you can't 100% guaranteed to say we cleaned the system, right?
They're looking at essentially the classic security co processor with, you know,
essentially console type security, you know, like all the,
all the game consoles have, right?
Because the console makers don't want you uh loading,
burned C DS into your console and not paying for games.
That is correct.
So, yeah, it's, they,
they're actually apparently in talks with a couple
of the major CPU makers and they're actually,
it sounds like going to be, I mean, it sounds like there's actually going to be
progress and products coming up in the next few years
helping to address this vulnerability.
And I couldn't help but think that this is
going to be especially critical with IOT stuff because
like with a desktop computer, I at least have
like I can uh, I can go to, uh, what is it?
Malware bytes, download their stuff and try and clean the system off. Right.
How do I clean off my internet of things? Light bulbs,
you throw them away and you buy new ones.
Yeah.
I mean, I'm completely serious.
It's not worth your time or effort to actually try to recover them.
Well, it's, it's not even possible more to the point, even if it was,
unless these things, I mean, in all seriousness,
unless your device costs more than probably $100 it's more worth your.
There are,
there are light bulbs with speakers built in that cost more than 100 bucks an hour.
I believe it, man. The fricking Phillips hue
bulbs, I have the ones that I
had to return. The, one of
that was, I think they're 50 bucks,
which they were gifted to me. I would not pay $50 for a light bulb. But
like, yeah, they're expensive
again.
Even if I could clean them though, for $50 would I, I probably would,
I probably throw them away and go buy cheap ones.
Well, more to the point.
So even if you remove the infection or whatever's on there,
you're not going to get a software update to prevent it happening again.
I mean, it probably not. How does this relate to your
dog story? I'm trying to connect these two. Well, essentially that
there are steps we could be taking, but to be honest, as the owner of the dog,
is it worth it to make that effort?
If there's really no significant negative externality and you
just fundamentally don't care about other people getting bitten.
You know,
there's always that argument that people should keep their
computers kind of clean and virus free because A,
it benefits them
and b
it benefits the rest of us.
You know,
how many systems are compromised in sending out spam or being used for a classic,
the distributed denial of service attacks?
What was the one that took down D DNS back in the day? And it was based on um
uh what specific thing was hacked but those were
routers with what they call the Mariah Botnet.
I think it was known
as,
I mean,
OK,
I guess here's the thing
that always eats me
with these security code processors on, on anything
we could get into a long drawn out philosophical debate. But fundamentally
the sort of DRM you're talking about
has historically been used to remove rights from users. It's not,
it,
you could make an argument that it's been about securing the systems to a degree,
but let's face it.
Fundamentally removing rights has been the purpose behind this stuff. And so
it has a black
for that. And I think
Microsoft trying to come around now saying, oh,
but think of the Children where we want to do it for the good reasons now,
like I don't buy it, man.
I'm sorry, I, I don't think I'm gonna, well,
it's tough because Amazon is already doing it
right.
Amazon has security code processor in their cloud
stuff Apple has their T two chip in.
Well,
all of their devices now and I mean there was that
recent USB based exploit that allows you to jailbreak your,
all the previous phones and allows you to get around this uh
all the older security co-processors and, and boot loading,
you know, security in the older Apple devices.
So
whether we like it or not, it's happening. It is, I agree
and whether or not we can disable it.
Like, I mean, I, that laptop, uh, I think I mentioned, you know,
that friend's laptop that I had to fix a few weeks ago,
like I had to go into the bios to disable the trusted boots so I
could boot off of a USB stick that had lyrics and the malware removal stuff.
And that's normal. We still have that control. But yeah, at some point,
well, you know, for your own good, we're taking that away from you and,
and as long as they're clear, they've taken it away.
I'm
less grumpy like Apple, for example,
they make no qualms about the fact that we've taken away all of
your ability to do all of this stuff and we don't care.
And while I can disagree with that, I can at least respect them for not pretending
there's some other, like altruistic purpose behind it.
Oh, we're going to make the world a safer place.
It's like, no, you just don't want people to mess with your stuff. It's fine.
I would say, you know,
apple's gone even beyond the walled garden metaphor into like a
botanical garden where it's like you can walk around and look,
but you better not touch anything.
They have a botanical garden with sniper towers, right?
Like you get off that path pretty
much like you, you're going home in a bag
and,
but they, they're not,
they don't pretend it's something that isn't,
which I think is the most important part of all this.
If somebody is working on,
you know,
signed lockdown firmware that's going to make sure
you can never touch your computer ever again.
Don't pretend it, it's something that it isn't,
is always been my attitude on this stuff.
Like we're not idiots. We know what you're doing. Yeah.
And on the flip side though, I mean, I have, I mean, well, let's go back in time.
Do you remember a
minor CV E incident which involved firmware updates from ac pu
maker that ended up breaking a whole pile of systems.
I mean, I don't remember it off the top of my head,
but I know it's happened more than once.
You know, the whole, uh, heart bleed thing or not heart bleed. Sorry. Uh, what's the,
wow, I'm getting old and forgetful. What was the CPU stuff that was named in all big
one. Specter and meltdown. Yeah. Those ones where there's been a bunch of them now
where the whole, yeah, I mean, there's just, what was it with?
Uh, especially if you were running VM ware or something,
you would completely break your system pretty
instantly.
I
don't remember.
I, I didn't care.
I'm not gonna,
I didn't run computers and the internet and whatever. It's fine.
Everything's fine. I mean, I think we need to address firmware security and
part of the brutal, honest truth is we don't
really have any other tools other than DRM,
like nothing comes off the top of my head that would really
make this better other than trying to lock down the process,
make sure only good stuff gets in and,
you know, prevent bad guys from loading stuff. So I would say
this is the same problem we have around writing secure
software which to date we train people and whatever.
There's all these stupid things that don't work.
I, I feel like we are at a tipping point in the world of security where we need
brand new concepts and ideas that don't exist.
Well, we tried that with A, I remember A I and me ML were going to save us all.
I'm still someday the A I will take over and it will be a beautiful day.
I'm, I'm waiting for it but I mean, like, like for real ignoring like our
silly jokes about all the marketing BS around A I and ML.
But I, I think the reason they got so much hype
is because people secretly know
we need new ways of doing things.
And there was a subset of people that was hoping that was it.
And I think you can safely say
at least up to the point of the time we record this,
that has not been true.
Maybe it will be someday, but it's not true today.
I mean,
heck we talked about David Brumley with his for all secure
crazy hacker computer where they won the DARPA Grand challenge.
Like maybe that sort of thing has some potential. But I think fundamentally
we need new ways to do everything we do because the way we do them
isn't working and pretending using Draconian and
DRM to make your firmware more secure.
I'm skeptical it's going to work.
I just, I keep coming back to the, I'm not sure we even,
it's not so much that we need new technical ways to solve this.
I suspect a lot of this is just based on the fundamental business
and economics of these problems and that I sold you a device.
I got your money.
Cool.
Like why, why am I supporting it?
Uh Well, I mean, historically,
that's been the way nearly all consumer goods
work where once the transfer is complete,
we're all done here
and this is where some of these subscription concepts get
interesting where like obviously I pay Netflix money every month,
right?
That is beneficial to them versus if I would have just written them
a big fat check once and then I use their thing forever.
Well,
I can't help but think this is one of the advantages of
cloud computing and that they have to keep your business monthly,
right?
And being secure is going to be a part of that.
Uh Yes, they do except owning a device is different because obviously
how, how, how does that work out? Like
how do I pay for hardware and then pay for a service or whatever? Right?
I have Apple phones and I pay a few extra bucks a month for extra storage.
Same thing with Google, right? I was just watching a review of uh what was it?
The new Google pixel four phone that came out.
Yeah, that thing sounds like a hot mess.
Yeah, and well,
even better though he pointed out that the free cloud storage uh no longer applies
the full quality of the image like the high quality, full quality image
won't you have to pay if you want to store those, basically,
you can store the lower quality ones for free.
And uh so I mean,
I'll be blunt, these phones top out at what 100 and 28
gigabytes.
He was pointing out, you know, if, if you're into taking photos,
you're going to fill that thing up pretty quick.
And if you can't offload the photos.
Yeah, it's going to get full fast
so you have to pay for it. So the reality is the majority of hardware, like my
doorbell and security camera.
I mean, they're nice and all and that they work as a doorbell and a security camera.
But the real value is
the cloud video storage. So I can refer to an incident, you know,
60 days from now or a month from now or something.
Um, because, you know,
I may not have realized something important happened
or that car that drove by then was,
you know, later spotted,
uh,
associated with burglary in my neighborhood or something. What's your point?
Well, that basically we're there.
I,
I think that subscription model and you talked about
how you buy hardware and you own it.
Well, no, I mean, most of the hardware you're buying now
is attached to a subscription service because
that's what the companies want.
But I think what they're doing is they front load the
cost onto the hardware and then the subscription fees are minimal.
Not in the case of Google Photos because holy
crap buying storage from Google is crazy expensive.
But I think in the case of most like we'll pick on ring
where like the doorbells aren't super cheap and then the service is affordable.
It's pretty pricey. I mean, 60 bucks per, uh, it's, what is it?
30 or 60 bucks per device per year.
That's not
terrible.
And no offense but that video compresses because
like
it, well, think about it, it's a doorbell looking out at my front lawn. Basically,
the picture never changes
the, I mean, this is exactly what NPE four was designed for.
You know, the mailman walks up, walks back, you just need those,
the data of him walking.
The rest of the frame is the same unless it snows literally the, you know,
the that video compress is so tight
that I, I can't even imagine how many,
I I'm guessing my entire video storage back
end at ring is probably tens of megabytes.
I bet it's a lot more than that. I bet they have terrible compression.
That's my guess.
Ok. But even so whatever I feel like again,
ring, like you don't own your ring doorbell,
I mean,
right. You, you have no control over that.
Not at all. And maybe that's the answer is just admitting I have a computer.
I don't own it and I'm part of someone's ecosystem
and that's just the way II, I don't know, man, I,
I go around in circles on this one and I think like from my perspective,
I don't like that.
But I look at my parents and
I mean,
their computer is a hot mess because like they,
they don't know what they're doing and they type things into Google.
I'll never forget the time my dad got uh a
virus because he needed Canon printer drivers.
He typed in Cannon printer drivers and ended up on a spam site
that installed like a back door in his computer. And it's like, oh, my goodness.
And I even told him, I said you have to go to Cannon's website. Right.
And, but did he listen? No, because he didn't understand what I told him.
And it was annoying and it was my own fault and
I ended up paying for it anyway because I cleaned it.
But
I don't know.
I don't know. And that is part of the problem for me.
I hate it and I don't want it, like, I want to be able to do whatever I want with my stuff.
But then I look at my parents and it's like, holy crap,
don't let them do whatever they want to their stuff.
I mean, I looked at building my own security camera system.
Uh, two main options were, uh, the Linux
based stuff,
uh, which actually now there's even just a pie
image
like that, you load on a raspberry pie and bam.
It's a security camera and then there's a couple of security
camera options like kits where you actually control the data,
have the storage locally, so on and so forth
and they have the full, you know,
thing where it'll alert you via email or your phone or the app or blah, blah, blah,
blah, blah.
To be honest, the cost of setting it up and maintaining it,
it's definitely more than paying ring 60 bucks per year. Uh, unquestionably.
I agree with that 100%. It's,
I don't know, I don't know.
This is,
I don't know what to tell you. And I feel like
again,
we come back to the fact that there is
mostly draconian problems
we're trying to use
or no, I, I, you mean solutions that? Right.
It's draconian solutions to new problems.
And I think we need some breakthroughs in this space and I,
I don't know what they are and if I did, I
probably be not, not doing what I'm doing today. Right?
So, well, I mean, again, a related topic of these. So a vast got hacked
and Nord VPN also got hacked.
Everyone got and again, sorry, I said everyone got hacked, man, that's life. Now
it's fine. Everything's fine.
And what, what I can't help but wonder is like just
the,
the amount of time it took for these guys to realize they were hacked and then the,
the really waffly, well, you know, they didn't hack anything that important.
We think so it's ok, hand waving.
That's perfectly normal behavior when someone gets hacked.
Because first of all, they didn't really know what happened, I'm sure.
But then as they learned,
they wanted to brush it off as being not true or not
as bad as people said it is because that's what people do.
But it also makes the story way juicier which gets you way more
attention versus if you're just like here's what happened and then people say,
oh OK,
I can't help but think a lot of this keeps coming back
to sort of that transparency and that food labeling idea of,
you know, what like
these cameras, where is the data stored? How you know, how is the data processed?
For example,
my smoke alarms have microphones in them. I did not know that when I was buying them,
that was not mentioned
that was found by accident, right? By somebody,
right? Yeah.
You know, and the fact that uh what is it Google, Alexa
and all of these other things have human beings
listening to the conversations and transcribing them for,
you know, when the device gets confused and can't figure out what you're saying.
So, you know, they're trying to make it better, right?
So that, you know, they're trying to
um
create their machine learning corpus of, you know, Ham and spam as it were
so that they can then train the machine learning on it and
understand people who have accents or whatever better.
But again, you know, this was
my understanding was Alexa
was a computer, you know,
analyzing this data, not actual human beings.
Does it make a difference if it's a human
listening to you versus a computer listening to you?
It's kind of like that classic thing where you
remember call centers had people taking your credit card
number and some of them would like memorize your
credit card number and then rob you later.
Uh,
which is one of the reasons I prefer
using online commerce because with the bigger sites
that have generally reasonable security,
I can be reasonably assured that giving them my credit
card number isn't going to result in me having to
get a new credit card a month from now when they get hacked,
you know,
versus using my credit card at some dodgy gas station in the middle of nowhere.
You know, with the guy
who's like, oh, the machine's down, I got a
like, I literally have had a cab driver who's like, oh, my machine is down
and he like
wrote down my credit card number and CV V code on a slip of paper with the amount
and that thing's getting stolen.
And then I was like, can I get a receipt?
And he's like, yeah, and he handed me a blank receipt and I'm like, ok,
then that's how this works.
Right. He's like, you can put in the amount. I'm like a ha.
Right. I'm expensing my $2000 cab ride now. And
yeah, exactly.
So,
so here's my takeaway on that and I don't
want to dwell on it too much because honestly,
I don't think these stories are all that interesting.
I think the Nord story is funny
in a sad way
just because they were kind of ridiculous about everything.
The story isn't, they got hacked.
No one's actually talking about that.
They're talking about the fact that they responded like clowns.
That's the story.
If you don't respond like a clown and you don't try to hide it,
there's no story
because you people say, oh, they got hacked. Oh, ok. Right. That's all great.
But when you,
when you respond to this stuff,
like a clown that becomes a story and nobody ever seems
to remember that that when you try to cover up,
you try to lie,
you try to make things look better than they are that
always becomes a story people talk about in that story,
you can't make go away
because the there's literally nothing you can do to make that better,
right? Whereas the other story like, yes, we got hacked and we fixed it.
What do you want?
It's like no, OK,
like there's no more story there, right? It's all done.
Well see and that's there's, you know, I think cloud flare is a good example of that.
Every time they've had a hack or an incident,
it's like here's an incredibly detailed postmortem and we fixed it
and we did a bunch of stuff to make sure it doesn't happen again.
And we put in some new process to like look
for similar things that may or may not happen again.
Right.
So they basically they put a muzzle on their dog and got a leash
and put the dog in a crate and took the dog to obedience school.
Like, thank you. But, yeah, most companies don't seem to be willing or,
I don't know that it's not that they're willing to do it.
I think fundamentally, a lot of these companies just can't,
because quite honestly if they were,
if they were capable of being competent at security,
they wouldn't be in this mess in the first place. No.
No, I'm going to disagree with you there. I think it's easy to say
you're not competent.
No, I don't mean in the sense they wouldn't get hacked.
I mean, they would still get hacked even with competent people.
But just that, like you said, it would be such a non event because they would be like,
well, we, we isolated the problem,
fixed it and put a new process to make sure it doesn't happen again.
Thank you. Bye. II. I can, I mean, I can tell you how this happened is
they probably have pretty smart people at both places.
A bad thing happened and no one knew what to do.
And this is,
this comes down to your security leadership is how it ends up being resolved where
a good leader can take control of the situation and they can calm the storm.
But they also need a certain amount of worldly experience to be able to do that.
Because
if you've never been through an event like this,
you're going to freak out and you're going to make a lot of bad decision
if you've been through an event like this more times than you can count,
you're gonna be like, oh, ok.
Yeah, we can, we can handle this
and it makes a huge difference, man. I mean, how many times didn't you?
And I go work with heck and still do this where you, you go to an open source project.
It's like I have a security problem.
I need to report to you and they start freaking out and you just say,
I, I will help you. It's going to be ok, here's what you need to do.
But if someone isn't there to help them,
they freak out and they start making bad choices.
And this is just, again, it's human nature, right?
When people are under duress, they don't make good decisions
and that's what happened and then the lawyers show up
and the marketing people show up and they're like,
oh, I know what to do.
We'll say this and we'll say that and we'll say that and the security people are like,
ok, I guess, sure, why don't you go, go do that, help me out.
And the reality is those people are making it magnitudes worse for you.
So anyway, it, but again, like it, it's security leadership.
That's what it comes down to. If you have, if you have a weak leader
and you have a big problem that appears like you're
in trouble and that's the way it's going to be.
And there's nothing you can do about it because the lawyers and marketing
are gonna take over and they're gonna spin this in some crazy way.
That's going to make the story 100 times worse than it should be. Yeah.
No, I'll buy that. I think you're right. Yeah. I,
I know,
I'm right because I've been through this on every which side
of it you can imagine more times than I can count.
And I can tell you now, the only way to deal with this is just
tell the truth, the whole truth and nothing but the truth right away the first time.
And it's much, much better long term. It sucks at first.
But things go away quickly.
Whereas if you try to spin something in the wrong way,
the story doesn't die and you get beat up for a very, very,
very long time and it's terrible.
All right. Anyway,
any parting thoughts on that topic, where do people get this training?
Right. Because it doesn't scale to have people learn this on the job.
The school of life, Kurt,
the training is from the school of life.
There's nowhere you can go. Unfortunately, I don't think that's gonna scale.
I don't think you can teach it. I think you,
this is just how it is. You need like trial by fire man.
And I would love to say we can train people to do this stuff.
But I don't, I don't know if you can,
I think you just have to deal with it because I remember when I was young,
I would run around like a crazy person and make terrible decisions.
And I remember I'd get mad at the old guy.
I'd be like, go sit down, go sit down for 10 minutes and then come back in my office.
Like, no, but you don't understand, like,
just go sit down for 10 minutes and then come back and I would like,
I just sat there for 10 minutes and freaked out.
And in reality now that I'm an, I'm an old man, I'm the old man telling people to stop.
I
get that like in 10 minutes,
nothing is going to change. That's really going to make a difference.
And that's the thing you need to understand. And unfortunately,
the only way to do it is to get angry at an
old man who tells you to go sit down for 10 minutes
and
yeah,
I,
yeah. Again, it, it's a leadership. Let's pick on CEO training.
Is there CEO training
probably. Is it terrible? Probably do the best CEO S take that training.
Definitely not, right.
It's no different.
So, anyway, anyway, all right, man, I think we're going to call it.
So, thank you, Kurt, thank you for listening.
You can go to open social security podcast.com, hit up the show notes,
you can use the Pound Os S Podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media
and Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day. You too, everybody. Thanks.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.