Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in blaming DNS.
-- Josh Pressers. It's
-- always DNS. Right.
Yes.
And do you know why it's always DNS?
-- There's actually a very cute underlying issue
-- is
-- there
-- because DNS is the only globally unique
name space apart from IP addresses and IP addresses are not very useful to humans.
And that's probably fair. That's it. Like because if you want to find something,
well, first of all, we only have 4 billion IP S.
So we share DNS, we don't share like walmart.com should
in theory only ever be walmart.com
and that's the thing is there's, and, and then as a consequence,
everything that hangs off of that email web, whatever
those can be if they choose to be globally unique. So uh github
is a good example of github.com/whatever
github
owns that name space and keeps it unique and to the point of being annoying where,
you know, github.com/red hat is not at all.
Red hat.
Well, right.
Or, or same things with email address,
like you could set up an email address to forward to multiple people or whatever,
not be globally unique, right?
But, and, and you hear all those stories of people are like,
I keep getting email for somebody who's handing out this email
address and it's like I keep canceling the flights and like,
oh, I know that's, I get that every now and then.
It's so weird. Like, and I own a weird domain though. Like I have my own domain.
-- How are people using my email address accidentally?
-- Well, like if you have
um
for example,
I've seen people that believe like they don't
understand the whole.in an email address thing.
So a dot And that's fine.
But the problem is, for example,
they think that some people were claiming you could register like Jane dot
Smith at gmail.com and that was different than Jane Smith at gmail.com.
But the part I don't get is that they would use an
email address that like and that they wouldn't get the email.
-- And then like there,
-- this is not the topic today. We are not going down this rat hole.
This is part of the human condition about this
DNS stuff where fundamentally the biggest problem with using DNS
is that if you provide a service on a DNS domain,
you are now making a promise that you will always own and control,
maybe not own but control that DNS domain
forever. And of course, that doesn't happen.
People forget to renew people let stuff expire.
It used to be that domains got hijacked.
Yeah, that's harder to do now. I mean, it's still very possible, but
it's
so, so it used to be now. Well, ok, what is it now?
A domain expires and you have, what, like, three or six months to reclaim it?
Someone?
-- I thought it was a while,
-- isn't it? Usually the DS registrar will hold it for a while
and then it's gone.
And so, like,
my friend forgot to renew her DNS Domain because she
was working crazy long hours when the email came in
and like the second it expired and went up,
it got sold and like we tried to reclaim it and contact them and
you know, nothing is gone.
Ok? I just looked, um, so the registrar I use a lot hover,
they say most domains a period of 34 days that they will hold it
-- after a grace period
-- depends on the TLD and the registrar you're using.
But regardless, like back in the day,
I remember waiting for domains I wanted to expire and then literally gobbling it
up like on that day it expired like the moment it was free,
it was like, wow, I got it.
But a great example of this is siefried
dot I register.org dot net
and I was going to register.com like the next week and, and a spammer bought it.
That's funny like this is over 20 years ago.
They've never done anything with it as far as I
know it's just sitting in some spammer domain registry.
Idly, I've tried contacting them to buy it. No luck. Right.
And so that's the thing, like, once you lose control of a domain name,
unless you're some massive company who can, like,
basically get cloud Fflur or somebody like that to go to bat for you.
It's gone.
Yeah. Yeah. I, I remember so fun stories.
You know, we have open source security dot IO. It's where we crossed all our stuff.
I tried to buy open source security.org for a Bitcoin a couple of years ago and, like,
the person would not take it.
I'm like, this is back then. I think it was, I think it was 20 grand
is what
is worth and I had it and they would not take it.
I'm like, holy crap, what the heck is wrong with you? Like open source security.org.
-- It's never had anything on
-- it. Yeah. It's names pro dot C A.
-- It's a domain park and, and
-- it's funny because the Rando is like, oh, yeah,
I'll take that and then literally two hours later they're like, no,
I can't accept this.
I'm like, what, what is wrong with you?
Yeah. For real. It was insane.
-- Anyway, anyway,
-- anything over, like, three or four figures.
I know. Right.
I'm like,
I figured for sure this was like a done deal
and I could finally have that domain and no,
no, nothing.
So, anyway,
ok, we have a topic that is not us rambling about DNS.
Then it's this uh who is server story that is making the rounds.
The article or the blog that was published
from Watchtower,
which tower spelled funny Watchtower labs is we spent $20 to
achieve R ce and accidentally became the admins of dot Movie.
So let's back it up in the moment.
So there's DNA registrars who, you know, run a top level domain.
Yeah. Yeah.
And they basically have typically one core function which is to take your money
and provide a DNS clue record for like food dot
Mobi points at these IP S that are serving it.
Another common feature that they're historically
uh supposed to provide
is a who is server and who is, is literally a command called who is one word, no space.
And like if you do who is see.org,
it'll basically, well back in the day,
it would have actually told you who owns it
and like what their street address was and their,
you know, abuse and
all of that is behind privacy stuff now because people used to
grab the who is domain and like span the bejesus out of all of us. And
-- so now it's all privacy registrations
-- and and it should also
be noted that the who is info is required by icann.
Yes.
According to icann, which I don't, I forget what icann stands for,
but it's basically the organization behind like all of the DNS magic.
And icann says, if you lie in your who is info, we will take your domain from you.
I don't know if they ever have,
but that's the threat they hand out constantly because I get the
notices for all my domains.
Like, what, once every couple of months or so, once a quarter maybe.
-- Yeah,
-- the reminders to update your address. And I'm like, I still live at 12345. Ave.
Well, no, I, I just use, um, this is one of the reasons I,
I use hover as my registrar is they were they let me do free
privacy shield whenever they call the where they fill in their info instead of mine
for the who is info.
They did that for free back when everyone else was paying for it.
I, I suspect it's free everywhere now, but I'm too lazy to ever move.
I just put in fake data all the time because how are they going to validate my address?
-- I
-- don't know, I don't want to risk that. Kurt, I'm unwilling to, to
have that kind of responsibility on my head.
So literally the who is
command on a UNIX system has like a little database of like here's a bunch of
top level domains and here's the who is server to to go talk to it,
right?
And in true classic business fashion, Moby forgot to or not Moby rather,
but whoever runs the who is server for Mobi
like forgot to renew the DNS.
And so Yeah, researchers,
yeah,
registered the DNS
and set up a who is server that could, you know,
return funny ask yard pictures or whatever.
Well, and there was, uh, one of the PHP apps has a real control execution
-- in it
-- because who is data is trustworthy. It comes from a trusted source.
Well, that's just it. Exactly. Like if I was writing a who is client, I would
incorrectly assume
that there are no malicious who is servers.
I would assume that there's always
because the who is protocol is not
like secure.
I don't know that I'm just a random developer writing a who is server in PHP
or who is client in PHP. Like
here's the thing like we're broken security.
People think weird normal developers aren't gonna be like,
what if the who is server is malicious?
-- What would happen? Then they're gonna be like whatever this is
-- the who is,
it's fine
or a person in the middle attack or whatever,
right. So, anyway, anyway,
so I'm, we're not going to recount all the details of this whole thing.
Well, there are, that's it, there are no details. They, they let the domain.
Well, there's, it's the story is interesting. They weave a thrilling tale.
-- Well, you have to because it's pretty boring. Otherwise
-- it is kind of boring.
They're good storytellers, which is great.
But here's the thing I've been thinking about and I put this on Mastodon is,
does this really matter?
And
I'm gonna frame my thinking of this.
I know it's easy to be like, does this matter be like, oh, whatever, grandpa, shut up.
You always say that. But,
so here's the thing.
So this feels really bad because the internet is big
and
every time there's some sort of weird corner case bug,
it's easy to sensationalize it.
And I don't think, does this have a name?
Um, who knows?
I don't know, Moby for
Shell or something,
but who is for Shell? Who is Moby? Who is Moby? Oh my. Who
is Mo
Mo?
Anyway,
young people don't know. Look at Moby. He's a singer pretty good.
Um Anyway,
so
you actually got the joke. That's awesome.
-- Well,
-- yeah, because we're freaking old, like, because we lived through Moby. Moby.
Still look while I'm talking, look at the Mo
is still performing. So, anyway,
so here's the thing, right? This sounds important.
But the reality is like,
-- what can attacker really do with this in a meaningful way? I have
-- an answer for you.
-- Is Moby still on the road?
-- I
-- don't
-- know.
-- I keep getting things for bike stores and stuff.
-- I asked you one question.
Sorry. Uh, Moby singer, I guess
he's still, wow. He looks old. He's older than us.
Uh, uh, when was he born? Oh, wow. Yeah, he's born in 65.
-- Yeah. And I mean, he still looks like he's still cranking out stuff.
-- Good. Right on.
Good for you movie. Ok. Anyway. So we've got
this sort of thing
and the question is gonna be, is it, is it important?
And I don't think it's unimportant, but this feels like
it can
by itself, it's probably
relatively harmless. Let's say it needs to be part of something bigger.
And what I mean by that is, let's say I'm gonna, I'm gonna,
my analogy will be based in the real world.
There's the old saying,
like you can put on a hard hat and carry a clipboard and you can go anywhere
and that's generally been proven true, right.
There are tons of people that have proven you can do this right?
Go to a sporting event, go to whatever.
So let's say I have nefarious intent
getting into the venue is step one
and I can probably accomplish that without issue.
But then taking my nefarious actions after that,
it's now I have other security hurdles.
I need to get over
in order to accomplish whatever my goal is.
And I think this is a similar thing like by itself,
this is probably not a big deal because it's just going to be part
of something bigger and hopefully we can catch the bigger thing along the way.
So I'm not saying we should ignore problems like this,
but I don't think it's world ending either.
No, but the problem with catching the thing along the way is
there's like thousands or millions or whoever knows
how many clients deciding to use that.
Who is server? Yes, you can't fix them all or get them all to behave also.
Correct what this would actually be.
Basically, there's two real things you could do with this.
Number one, you could serve malicious,
whoa data and compromise those remote sites.
Sure. You know, because there
most whose clients I'm guessing are not very robust. Right.
And number two certificate authorities,
a lot of certificate authorities will issue you a certificate
and you have to prove you control the domain.
And there's a couple ways to prove you control the domain.
One is with the DNS record, one is with a web record.
Another one is through an email address.
-- Now, how do we find out what email address is in charge of a domain?
-- Right?
-- I mean, the who is info obviously?
-- Right.
Yeah, exactly.
And
there used to be some historical ones like root
and host master or postmaster that they would use.
But then we discovered that that's a bad idea
because modern systems don't have those as reserved for admins
as much anymore as they used to. And like
I have, that's one of my checks. When I check an email services.
Can I, can I be host master? I would like that email address
and some will tell me to take a hike and some will be like,
oh, that's already taken or some will be like, sure, here you go.
You know, it's like the time I took local host as my host name of my uh ISP.
And then my network fell over. Right. Good job.
Yeah, it was funny.
Then they put that on the reserve list so that this could
definitely be part of either remote code execution in bad clients or
getting certificates for daunt mo
sites. And then,
-- but again, and then more nefarious things. Right.
-- Right. And that, that's my point.
Like there's a, there's a step too now,
granted a lot of these places that you could attack,
probably have zero protections against
any of this stuff. They're, they're not monitoring anything,
they're not using
any sort of software to watch for nefarious activity like nothing. Right.
Well, more to the point if I now
am controlling the who is and I'm, and I managed to get a certificate.
Well, I can do a man in the middle attack legitimately.
-- No,
-- you
can't.
What do you mean? No, I can't. I have the certificate.
-- Uh
-- How are you going to man in the middle? Anyone?
Like a man in the middle attack?
-- It is
-- on a Wi Fi network on through what was part of other things?
No, no. Look here. OK.
I, I'm going to say this and, and like send the hate to Kurt if you like, but
man in the middle or, or what are we calling man? A person in the middle?
I don't recall him anymore.
Like I know man in the middle is frowned upon but those attacks, right.
Those interceptions style attacks
are
very hard today, even
with like the whole, oh, I'll use a wireless network. No,
no, it doesn't work that way anymore.
-- Like there are, well, it
-- would be part of a targeted attack.
-- It wouldn't be some,
-- not just a targeted attack.
Kurt, you're talking about a highly resourced attacker here
because in order to actually
intercept
and
stop traffic and then pass it along and, and kind of be in the middle.
You're talking about like
someone is in the ISP type event, right? This is not trivial at this point.
I mean, it was easier when we had like open Wi Fi
and we had no encryption, everything was hubs and networks and stuff like that.
But it is.
Well,
no, we had encryption on Wi Fi but everybody had the same key.
Well, there's sure. But, but you know what I'm saying? Like
that is not
a, I'm not saying it's an attack we should ignore,
but I don't think it's a practical attack for the vast majority of Attackers.
I would agree. Right.
But
we're saying like, what could this be part of?
Well, that's what it would be typically part of. Right.
That's why you would want to get fake certificates.
Well, not fake certificates, they're real certificates just for the wrong person.
-- I think
-- what's more valuable from a certificate
perspective actually isn't even getting a fake certificate necessarily
is that
you could get a certificate for something that looks really close
to like, like, for example, like the, the, this was dot Moby,
like
Apple dot Moby, right?
If you sent people there and it looked just like the Apple site, they'd be like, oh,
it's just Apple doing something weird, you know, or whatever.
Well, you can already do that because it's not like cas have. That's true.
It's not like, like when you register a business in most of the world, they do a
business name search, not just for like that exact name, but for sounds like names.
And
you can actually have apple plumbing, apple computers.
As long as there's like enough distinction, they'll generally allow it. Right?
-- Because apple doesn't get to own the word apple forever and always like too
-- bad.
I have a fun fact for you.
So I live in Green Bay, Wisconsin and I think I've told this before.
There is a store here called the Apple Store.
And it has been here since the fifties and they sell like apples from trees.
And it's always funny because if you look at like the Yelp reviews and stuff,
people like this isn't an apple store.
They sell fruit. It's like, yes
they do.
And they've been selling it for like 50 plus years at
this location and they're never gonna give this name up.
-- Like
-- Hungry Jack in uh Australia, you know, there's
Burger King. So now you gotta go to Hungry Jack's. If you want your whopper.
-- And,
-- and I, I just,
I love that like David and Goliath dynamic of like this is obviously just like some
crazy old person at this point.
That's like just fighting the good fight because they can
even for a reason.
But um so back to this, that's the challenge with DNS is like,
I've known people that have not renewed their DNS or somehow lost control of it.
And for us, mere mortals it's gone forever. Yes, for sure.
Like they're like, I've been trying to get seafood.com
back kind of for 2025 years on and off. It'll, yeah, it'll literally never happen.
It's not even parked, it's just like it's registered,
but there's nothing associated with it as far as I can tell.
And so
that I really,
it always drives me nuts when people talk about
digital sovereignty on a personal level and they're like,
oh, just get your own domain name and host your own services or whatever, blah, blah,
blah.
And then you can pick and choose and move.
Well, for somebody like me and Josh are a lot of our show listeners.
Yeah, we have the expertise to do that,
but most people don't and they probably don't have the
money to pay for the DNS to pay for,
you know,
Google workspace because it's not like you can hook
a domain in up to your free Gmail account,
right?
You need to pay for Google workspace,
right. Yeah. Yeah. They used to give it away for free.
-- Yeah.
-- You used to be able to get free Google Domain, whatever.
And,
and I had a bunch of those but they've
all sort of since grandfathered out and expired.
Yeah.
I think you still have one that's kind of quasi
-- free. Or did they? Finally?
-- Mine's not free.
No, I, I converted it to a proper paid account because
I became very concerned that by staying on the free plan,
I was going to have too many problems.
Whereas in my mind,
I feel like if I'm paying them money
they will
maybe read my email,
maybe not accidentally delete you.
Right. Right. I
like that
one.
Yeah. But I mean, so, so in all seriousness. So this is also the reason
that I use a domain registrar
separate from Google and all the other call providers because, like,
if Google for some reason decides I violated their terms of service,
like, wipe out rest.net,
I still have control of the domain,
I can move it somewhere else versus if they're the registrar,
-- I'm probably sol
-- at
-- that point
-- a
-- 100
-- percent.
Yeah.
And the problem too is like, you can't,
how do you talk to them because your email address doesn't work anymore.
-- That is a good point actually, like, really
-- thought about that.
And that's something my friend has is where her
old email address is hooked up to our Apple account
and
you can't
change it because Apple emails you a confirmation
which is totally
not going anywhere.
And like, even on the phone, they're like, yeah, we'll email you a confirmation.
It's just like,
that's
the problem.
I love it when that kind of stuff happens. All right. All right.
Anyway, back to this movie thing.
-- I don't want to keep, we keep going down the, the DNS rat hole because it's
-- well,
but it also speaks to how most companies build business
process around the assumption that you own this domain name.
You will always own this domain name and there will never be a problem
and they don't handle it very well either themselves losing it.
-- But
-- why would you handle it?
-- Well, why, why
-- are, well, because people do lose these domain names.
Not that often though.
I mean,
I don't think it's a common enough occurrence that you
can really justify planning for that in any meaningful way.
Well, a simple thing like having a backup email address.
-- So that on a different domain, I mean,
-- yeah, but that's,
that's something different obviously.
And, and I actually do have that for what it's worth.
But because I back in the day I got Josh dot Resor at gmail.com
and I log into it like once a year to clean up the spam
and then it's just there in case I ever need it for anything.
But anyway, ok, so here's the deal, right?
We've got this, these security researchers, they find this clever bug.
Well, it's not a bug. It's just, it's a, it's, the DNS expired.
And so they registered it, like, let's assume there's an embassy in a major city
and they decide to move to a new location.
And so they moved to the new location and the old location goes up for lease.
Well, I could lease it
and put up a flag and put up the signs and,
you know, a bad accent
and I'm guessing a lot of people like your apple store,
people would go to the old location because that's, you know,
what if that's illegal?
How's that illegal? Is it?
Well, I mean, that's
about it.
Maybe.
I mean, there's laws against Impersonating certain,
like officials and things like that.
Well, ok, but ignoring all that, the point is there's,
there are sort of this happens in the real world where businesses,
uh, a business fails or closes and some other business grabs that kind of good name.
Yeah. Yeah. Uh Oh, perfect example.
There's a big company out here I think I mentioned before called Standard General.
And they do paving and parking lots and road building.
Like they're a massive construction company, right? Big legit.
Like we're talking probably a couple of 1000 people
and there's some dude in Nova Scotia,
I think it was who called his company Standard
General because then on the web searches and stuff,
it shows us having a good review and of course he's a total scam artist and like,
there's a ton of incidents with him
and, you know,
so he's trading on Standard General's good name
and because it's in a different province like
that was allowed.
And so
the thing is as a, as a business say, like in Alberta,
I'm not going to bother to register my business name in all 10 provinces,
I guess.
Or what about every city? You know, like
at some point, I just sort of give up like
I've done defensive registrations of cloud security lines dot A bunch of stuff,
but there's over 2000 tl Ds now. So like I'm not doing them all.
I don't have time for it
for sure. I did.
I
mean, ok, look, I don't think that is a reasonable comparison. In this case.
I think
there are legal mechanisms for dealing with some of these situations,
maybe not in Canada.
But I know like in the US, you have things like trademark law.
Yeah,
you can register a trademark and a DNS name can be part of a trademark.
-- Like that is what happens sometimes,
-- but a trademark is more specific.
And so for example,
you can still have apple dot whatever and be an Apple store online and Apple,
depending on the jurisdiction
may have to pound sand and that's the other prompt.
Remembers this is global,
it is global and we're in a hole because this is completely unrelated, I think.
-- But
-- it is, it's it's DNS is a global system.
OK. No, no, I don't want to talk about DNS. I want, I want to rope us all the way back.
I want to, I want to ask this, right.
So these researchers publish this blog and they
even kind of towards the bottom of it.
They talk about, you know,
there, I'll just read this paragraph.
It says we continue to hold concerns around the basic reality.
We found this on a whim in a hotel room while escaping the Vegas heat surrounding
black hat while well resourced and focused nation
states look for loopholes like this every day.
In our opinion,
we are not likely to be the last to find inexcusable flaws in such a crucial process.
Well,
more to the point, DNS
and spammers have been doing this for over a decade where
a popular DNS Domain lapses and they grab it within seconds,
right?
Like this is not a new thing. This is
-- like I let domains lapse and, and then they get snapped up,
-- stop it.
You keep going back to DNS.
Here's my question.
-- Is this an inexcusable process by the Moby people so
-- well,
first comment is so Mobi outsource they who is server to somebody else that or
they basically did such a terrible job running it that they let
the DNS for it lapse and didn't notice like to put it bluntly
to put it bluntly, they're at DNS registrar,
maintaining control of DNS should be a core competency.
-- That's all I got. Ok.
-- Here it is.
Uh we discovered that a few years ago the who
is server for the dot Mobi TLD migrated from?
Who is 0.0 my goodness. It's who is dot Then dot Moby registry.net. So there's li
the letters dot After a dot Which is someone
thought they were clever when they did that.
-- I'm
-- sure.
No, because it probably was grabbed. The other one was probably already taken.
Oh, that could be. So anyway, to who is dot Nick dot Moby?
And then obviously the the old domain expired,
but lots of things were still using it.
That and, and
now the question is like, is this the fault of the dot Moby people for not just keeping
the domain forever because of what they did?
-- It's
-- like when Microsoft bought the corp.com thing, right?
It's cheaper for Microsoft just to buy that
domain and make sure no shenanigans happen than
-- it is to deal with all the support calls if an attacker grabs it and
-- does
I agree with that?
-- And we, we did a whole show about corp.com, didn't
-- we?
If a DNS registrar can't register and control a domain name?
I kind of got to wonder about their competency.
-- I mean,
-- that's a good point. I won't argue with that.
That's right like that.
Yeah.
-- Ok. Ok. I'll accept that.
-- And so for example, we have the
name.
Oh, perfect example,
we have a piece of documentation at the CS A where somebody mentioned a domain name.
And I'm like,
when did we buy that domain name?
We didn't
and we used it as an example.
And so I'm like, well,
I better go register that and grab it
because it's in an official piece of documentation.
We're telling people something, something,
this domain name and I don't want people going there
and seeing like a porn site or something.
Like, remember the Heinz QR code thing where Heinz did a QR code
and it went
anyways, it ended up going to a porn site,
you know, I don't remember that. But that's pretty funny.
Let me
just
let the
intern generate the QR code and no one checked it.
Uh Yeah, Heinz says sorry for ketchup QR code that links to porn back in 2015.
Mine's like a trap. Everything's in there.
It may not be useful but it's in there.
Well, also I'm, I'm a Heinz ketchup person.
-- I
-- could
-- not tell you what kind of ketchup I have in my
favorite. It's the mouth
-- feel. It's got that just, it's got that richness. It's good.
-- I literally don't care
as long as my ketchup tastes good. I'm fine.
Yeah,
but um see that's the thing, right? Like it
on a does this attack really matter?
No,
but do I want to avoid having to deal with apologizing
for a porn site being linked from one of our documents.
-- Yes.
-- Yes, I agree with that. Yes.
Does it cost a few bucks a year to maintain and keep that registry up?
Yeah. It's kind of annoying but in the long term it's way less
-- than having to deal with a porn site there.
-- That's a good point. That's a good point.
It,
yeah.
Yeah, it's definitely, it, it's probably a signal for competency in the MO
-- TLD
-- fail.
But if you own a mobile
-- domain, what choice do you have?
-- I mean, there's, there's also the issue of like,
I wonder how many
instances of things like this exist where there are expired domains
that are referenced in
-- some sort of tool or document or whatever
-- for, I have an exact example for you.
The CWE database. I went through it
and I grabbed a bunch of domains that had
expired that were linked from the CWE database.
What do they link for?
Like I don't understand
-- like
-- for sources in C in CV E sorry. When I said CW si mean CV es oh CV
E oh man. Yeah,
like what 30% of those
references are dead, right?
-- Um Well, no, I registered the domain names. They work now.
-- Not all of them.
Well, no, but a bunch of them.
It was, it was several, there was quite a few links actually.
How many are getting hit? Do you have logs?
-- Uh I don't know, I don't, they're not set up for anything.
-- You should log that.
That sounds interesting.
But because part of it is I, I,
at various points have downloaded every reference link in the CV E database.
Yeah. And like,
a lot of them are dead in the sense of they go to, like, a marketing web page.
Yeah, I, I remember
you told me about this. It was like 20 or 30%. Right. It's,
-- no, no,
-- no, no, no,
it's far more because we're just gonna pretend like
all of sun.com just got deleted from the database.
Yeah, that's true. There were a lot of those
and all the old, almost all the old references are like just gone now.
Tons of that stuff.
Yeah. Uh Yeah, I got rid of all those domains that were uh
that were uh from. Yeah, I just let them expire.
Um Now someone else can register them. Exactly.
But yeah, see,
and that's the thing this is trivial to do because literally
all you do is you find something referencing domain names.
-- Well, no, it's
-- not. Ok. It's trivial to do, but the outcome is not trivial.
I think there's probably very limited value
in a lot of this, which is why it doesn't get more attention.
But we see this with domain parking where you make a type in
a domain name and you end up with some crappy parking site that like
is trying to make some ad revenue.
-- Yeah,
-- I also like
github. I often do go to gihub.com because I can't type.
Yeah. And, and it's not github.
-- It brings me to some crappy shopping site.
-- Oh.
Oh, interesting. Uh, chrome popped up for a second. Did you mean github.com?
Ok.
But then that went away and it loaded the webpage
and, oh,
apparently my computer has all the internet herpes and
I need to contact this 1 800 number.
-- Oh,
-- yeah. It's like
random. It's, it, it goes to like, different things.
It's some sort of weird shopping aggregator thing.
I think that just sends you to probably affiliate links.
I get a um what I get a windows.net site claiming that I
have Windows defender security center and to call this 1 800 number.
All right, github
dot com from Firefox. And this one's blocking me,
you block origin is blocking it.
I will proceed. Thank you. You block origin.
-- Oh, now it went to star choice
-- wise, staffing.
This is
ok. This is not, no, we are not ending like this.
All right, we're done talking about.com or whatever it is. So ok. So here's the deal.
Here's what I find. Interesting.
Yes, it is a problem. Yes.
It almost exists in probably hundreds or thousands
of places that are using expired domains.
But I also think
the, the potential badness is low at the moment.
It doesn't mean it will stay low forever. It is very conceivable.
Something incredibly important could expire
that there are, there's something we haven't thought of yet. There's some novel
attacker we haven't thought of yet.
Well, or a major company forgets to
like we have documented cases where major companies have
like fallen over for a day or two.
Well,
Microsoft let hotmail.com expire once and then like some Rando
registered it just so they could get their email back.
Like then they gave it to Microsoft. I mean,
now, but like here's an, if that happened again,
I'm pretty confident Microsoft could get that back
either through legal or just be like,
here's a bag of freaking money.
Give us our domain back type things.
Well, no, they, they just threaten the other registrars and stuff. And like
the part of the problem is this goes back to that kind of classic.
If you know who to talk to at the place, they can fix it for you right away
and you see that like all those threads on hacker news where somebody announces
like I have this problem with youtube or I have this problem with Gmail.
Who do I talk to or? Well, heck on Mastodon where like Jerry Bell is like, uh,
what was the pizza place that he wanted to contact for? Cosmos?
Pizza, something like that.
I don't know if that was serious though. Was that real? I think that was a joke.
I don't know.
But I've seen that where I've literally had people come to me and they're like,
like for some Canadian thing. And I'm like, I don't know. Tom in Toronto.
Like, come on,
all Canadians know each other. Kurt. Come on.
Like, we're contractually obligated.
There's what, like, a couple 100 people in Canada, like, it's fine.
But that's the thing. Right.
Like, so it's kind of like that where, yeah,
if you know the process and the people to talk to you can fix it very easily.
But for the rest of us we're, we're up the creek without a paddle,
for sure, for sure. And then, I don't know, I guess here's the thing,
this will be interesting to watch, but I don't think it is world ending.
It is good research.
Like good job Watchtower folks that this was a great find like
DNS Parkers have been doing this for 2030 years like this is,
yes, it's not new, it's not new for sure, for sure. But I love when people
take something like this to the next level and then talk about it because just saying
we bought this domain, we'd be like big freaking deal.
Now. Now, granted, I'm also glad they didn't try to turn this into a spectacle.
It is not
because you do get that too where people are like, oh, look at this research.
I did and look like I'm gonna like,
hack the planet with this and the world is going to light on fire and it's like,
uh probably not,
I don't know. It's interesting. It's fun to watch.
It's fun to talk about, but I also don't think
this is
a world ending event and I have a suspicion
even though it's always DNS and even though DNS sucks and has tons of problems,
there's, it, it's really only the stepping stone to something bigger.
And hopefully we have protections in place that
will prevent the next step or maybe the
step after that or the step after that because there is no such thing as,
like most attacks are not like one and done, right?
You need, you need multiple steps and that's, that's how you catch people.
The thing is there are those like one and done attack
like the, the what was it the, the recent like various TCP packet,
ping things and windows and Linux that could cause code execution.
-- So they do happen. They, they,
-- yes they do. But
-- this is not
-- it walk for
she is a great example of like you just fire off this packet,
well, a couple of packets of the web server and like
go to execution
no big deal. What's interesting is in CWE there is ac we
dash 350 reliance on reverse DNS resolution for security critical action
because again, Attackers
control reverse DNS,
right?
So the trick is you have to do reverse DNS,
then forward DNS and to make sure that they match up,
right?
Or vice versa, right?
But you can't because one IP address can host 1000 domains.
Well, uh I was actually just dealing with this yesterday.
Google bought, for example,
uh they say it's like Google bought, dash, dash, dash, dash,
dash dot Google bot.com or whatever.
So you basically look for this red jacks and,
and then also look forwards and to match up.
All right, anyway, I'm going to call this one
and there's also,
but here's the best part.
There is nothing in CWE for like essentially
the domain name got hijacked by an attacker.
Somehow. There's, there's nothing in here at all.
An expired domain should have ac we because an expired domain is a legitimate risk.
The problem is this is a hard one to fix because once the attacker has DNS,
-- they stand up everything and look legit,
-- I mean, to a degree.
All right, I'm not going to argue this one anymore. I, I think again,
we'll see, we'll see how it all turns out. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. Go to the
Security podcast.com. Head up the show notes. Yui
Podos says podcast. Hashtag and Mastodon. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye.