Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
and my partner in tearing apart possibly bad legislation. Josh Bresser.
That's not even the worst of it.
So, we record this show on Wednesdays and since the last recording,
I think two decades worth of news have
occurred and I'm concerned of what will happen between
today and Sunday.
This is why we're not discussing Twitter because whatever we say will be obsolete.
Yeah, I know. I know. Exactly. So, I mean, just kind of to set things where we're at.
There's been what the NDA A legislation which we want to talk
about today because I feel like that's at least calmed down enough.
We can have a sensible conversation.
There's the Twitter news of Mudge,
like Outing Twitter and that's like a whole nother can of w
not even just Outing Twitter but like, sec fraud
related stuff. Like that's
no, like, as businesses go,
that's one of the few things you can do and end up in prison.
That's probably true. Not prison, prison.
But like,
that's one of the few things you can
do as a company where corporate officers actually
are harshly sanctioned.
That's true. That is true.
You can literally kill people whatever it happens. But like
you mess with fraud and security
related acts,
-- I suppose. But then there's also flex was
-- hacked.
-- What was up with that? Because I'm like,
-- no one knows yet. No one knows.
-- But here's what I, I
-- haven't received a freaking,
-- oh, you didn't
-- get an email? I got an email this morning.
Oh, here we go.
-- I just did. But
-- here's where it gets
more strange is they just claim an attacker acquired.
We,
we'll say we'll put the word hash passwords
and quotes because even that's not totally clear.
They claim
they're resetting everyone's accounts out of an abundance of caution,
which is fine.
But then when I,
it took me multiple tries to get my password reset this morning.
But then when I logged into plex to like, look at it to make sure it was there,
none of their services worked.
The machine in my basement worked fine, but their stuff was all down.
-- So I'm like this, this doesn't smell quite right.
-- Honestly, that was my first thing.
I was like, I made sure my local plex is working because of the my kids will be annoyed.
And I'm like, ok, great.
Yeah, it's so, yeah, because yeah,
they were saying hashed or salted or whatever passwords.
The email says encrypted passwords.
And I will say one thing in their defense, people often mix the two up. I agree.
I, and whatever, you know, we'll see. Right. Let's wait and see.
But then also there's a pie, pie, fish going around
where people are trying to fish, pie, pie, maintainers, passwords.
And I'm just like,
I don't know what's happening anymore. Everything is ridiculous
and there's, there's other things I'm not even going to anyway, whatever
everything is bananas. And so
I,
I don't even know what's going to happen between now and next week
I have a new thing.
I, I think we should think about doing at the beginning of some of the shows is
every now and then I stumble across like a podcast or a
news site or just something that I think tickles my fancy and,
and I have two that I found recently that I'm really enjoying that.
I want to give a shout out to the first is called the Hacker Mind Podcast.
-- It's by the, the, uh David Brumley group.
-- You have to give me the,
I can react to it.
Yeah, I'll put it, whatever it doesn't react thing.
I'm just, well, I'll put it in the show notes.
It's the for all secure guy.
We had David Brumley on the show and like years ago, it feels like now.
But anyway, they have a podcast that's pretty good called the Hacker Mind.
And there's another one that Linux foundation just came out with and they,
it's called the, the Untold Stories of Open Source.
And it is really freaking
where it's just old people telling stories,
which is like my favorite kind of podcast.
But I love that
we have this, like, sanitized view of history and I mean,
like all history where it's just like, you know, stuff happened,
people were sort of in charge and like, things happen.
But when you actually dig into history, it's all like,
people were just like, reacting and being crazy and dealing with insane stuff.
Be it a world war or like the open source world?
Like,
and it's even more wild than that sometimes
I think because obviously it's totally survivor bias,
right?
That anything we hear now.
But then
it's fun to listen to people explain
an event
and there is what they tell and then there's what I
remember and I know both of those accounts are incorrect because
there's something entirely different happened and you remember what you want to,
but it amuses me to no end of being like, oh, I remember that or I was there for that or?
Oh, yes, I, that person I hated them too.
But yeah, it's a lot of fun. Anyway,
links in the show notes.
But I, I think it's
as I find amusing things, I think it would be enjoyable.
We could do like a site with a directory of pages linking to these things.
-- Maybe,
-- I don't know. I'll think about it. I'm really lazy.
I remember when Yahoo like Netscape. Oh, no, sorry, not Yahoo.
Not even Yahoo that Netscape.
Remember when Netscape, the Netscape directory of the internet
and, like, trying to game yourself onto certain pages. And
that's right.
Well, and I mean, that was what made
like, like things like Yahoo and Google so amazing is they were automatic.
They weren't hand
curated lists
anyway. Anyway.
All right, let's, let's get on to our, our actual topic of the day,
the National Defense Authorization Act.
So
it is, I,
I'll give a little bit of background and then we'll kind of get into the meat of it.
So, every year,
well, this is my understanding, some of this might be wrong.
So if I'm wrong, like just yell at me on Twitter or something. But
every year, the US federal government basically gives the, the,
the US Department of Defense a budget
and it's called the National Defense Authorization Act where they basically say,
like these are the things we want you to do and then they
turn it into a law and they give it to them and say,
here you go, go nuts.
And
you can imagine this is a, a multi 1000 page document.
Like this is not something any human is going to
sit down and read in a reasonable amount of time.
I'm skeptical any human could actually read it because it is, we'll say it's not the,
the edge of your seat sort of reading material.
-- It is very dry and very long and very boring. Well,
-- it's like reading code.
-- It's, yes,
-- yes, it is a source code to the government.
The only problem is the compiler sucks.
-- That's
-- a good joke. This is why I don't program.
This is why I write articles for humans because humans
are fuzzy compilers and I can write basically borderline garbage.
And if the words are even remotely in the right order, people understand what I say.
That's so good. That's so good.
The NDA A
has a couple of there,
there's some moving parts to how this works. And
the House of Representatives passed their version.
The US Senate has to get their version passed which will
be slightly different and then they have to reconcile the two.
And in the House of Representatives version
at this time,
there is language that I should actually look up the exact language that,
-- that it says
-- it's in my blog post
and
we'll put a link to your blog post and but it,
but it basically says each item listed on the submitted
bill of materials is free from all known vulnerabilities or defects
affecting the security of the end product or service identified
in a the National Institute of Standards and Technology Nist,
the NV,
the National Vulnerability Database and any
database designated by the under secretary in
co ordination with the director of
the cybersecurity and infrastructure Security Agency.
That's a mouthful that tracks security vulnerabilities and defects
in open source or third party developed software.
So basically
what this says is you cannot sell software to
the US government that is affected by known vulnerabilities.
No, that's not what it says
because later on it says you can have a mitigation plan
-- or you have to have a mitigation plan.
-- Mitigations don't count as affected.
Like the vulnerability can exist if you can mitigate
it or it's not actively exploitable in the software
that doesn't count.
Well,
what they say here is a notification relating to the plan to mitigate repair or
resolve each security vulnerability or defect listed
in the notification required under paragraph two.
Ok. That's fair. Having a plan. But this is where it gets complicated, right?
Because there's,
it's, it's hard to untangle all this. Now, here's the most important part.
Before we start this conversation, this text will not survive the Senate.
I talked to some policy people.
I know and basically said, like, how big of a deal is this? And they, they all said
it's not gonna make it through the Senate
guaranteed,
right?
Like this is a bit of a wink and a nudge sort of situation where the many companies
and many people in positions of power are going
to make sure it doesn't happen this time.
However,
it is going to come,
-- it's basically a warning shot across the boat.
-- Yes, exactly.
It, it's not going to happen for 2023 but we are almost certainly going to see this
probably like 2025. Ish give or take is my suspicion.
So keep that in mind as we discuss this while this isn't going to survive this year.
It is definitely going to be something we have to worry about in the future.
-- I think that's enough background. Also.
-- Fun.
Fact, cutting and pasting it into word, almost broke my computer.
-- What,
-- how does? Because it's a really big chunk of text.
Wait, what did you copy and paste the whole NDA A text?
I cut and paste the whole thing into word because I'm trying to do
a word count and I don't know how to work the modern word.
Oh Where my oh, this ribbon menu thing is just
where is anything?
Where's word count?
No, I'm serious. I don't know if somebody could. Well, by then it'll be too late.
-- It's not under draw
-- just copy and paste it into the, the UNIX command WC.
Well, I also wanted to get the reading comprehensibility level,
which is always amusing to me,
do this on your own time and put it on Twitter.
The,
the thing that gets me is, yeah, it's, it's
even if it, OK, let's say theoretically survived. It's not that insane.
It's basically saying
you have to give us a list of all the defects that are known,
especially like in our National Vulnerability Database, which is
literally exactly what it says on the tin. Like a Gin and tonic.
The National Vulnerability Database is literally
the national vulnerability database for software.
This is why CV E is.
So us, government centric is because number one, us government pays for it.
And number two,
they want stuff that they use covered, right?
Which always amuses me because things like Drew Paul are
ridiculously well covered in CV E and the CIA stuff. And it's like,
I guess the government must use a lot of this.
-- It's weird
-- or they have a security team that's competent and
acquire CV E I DS for everything that needs it.
Well, no, no, but CIA, like, for example,
when there's known vulnerabilities and stuff and exploits and Dr Paul, they,
they publish it right away then.
Yeah, they must use it then.
But, but so, ok, ok. What I, I think
we should take the stance that this isn't completely insane.
I'm comfortable with that. I think there are,
I'm seeing
kind of two groups
in the wild right now discussing this.
-- There's people who are, well, this
-- assumes that they read the whole thing.
Well, no one read the whole thing.
No
one's going to read that
anyway.
So there's people claiming like this is completely bananas
and there's no way we can do it.
We obviously do not agree with those people.
Well, I, I point out like to cut, to cut to the very final stage of this
in my blog post.
I point out that you have even like a remotely competent, secure,
manage the security process for your software or service.
And that's the other thing this applies not just to software but to services,
which I find fascinating because that
I would not have expected them to be that on the ball.
But anyways, let's take Red Hat, for example,
red hats basically compliant with this.
They acknowledge and aggressively or used to not so much now, but they,
they, they acknowledge every CV in their product.
You know, they have a page for it and they have
uh like they have a statement saying like,
yeah, well, like it's bad or, you know, in the case of like cross site scripting like,
yeah, we'll get to it when we get to it.
I, I don't know that that will be good enough for this
thing.
They might have to amend the language or commit to a deadline or something.
But fundamentally, there's not a lot red hat would have to do to be compliant.
-- I
-- mean,
that's one of the challenges I think is it's not particularly clear
if you acknowledge it how long until you have it fixed?
Like some of that is,
and I don't think it should be spelled out in the this legislation necessarily,
but that's definitely one of the questions
one size does not fit all.
Like, I mean, I, I totally respect like Google zero day,
going from 120 to 90 days disclosure,
but like you, you can't do that for like a nuclear submarine software system
and then
there are people on the internet claiming this is no big deal. It won't matter at all.
And I do think it is a big deal because
I think there's a lot of organizations that are unprepared
for this sort of universe where you have to manage your, I guess,
just security of your applications in a, a more,
I
-- guess, purposeful manner, we could say,
-- I would say accountable
because that's, that's what gets me is the language here. It's like
you don't have to give them an S bomb.
But if they ask for one, you have to give it to them in a timely manner, right?
You don't have to XY and Z, I mean, you're supposed to,
but basically if they ask for it,
you better be able to come up with that documentation quickly.
I mean,
everyone I granted I'm in a weird place but when we work with the government,
we're getting requests for S bombs on a regular basis right now.
And of course, being a company that
literally makes s bombs, it's like sure, here you go.
Yeah. Well, but there's no teeth,
there's no teeth to that request, right?
Like, and this is where this is my favorite thing about the US government is
and a lot of governments, in fact, it's,
we can't make you do X but we can attach money to not to not doing or to doing X.
So like the federal government raising the drinking age in America,
they can't force the states to do that,
but we can withhold highway funding.
Right. And so all the states fell in line eventually,
you know, and same thing here, it's like we can't force companies to give us an S bomb.
But,
well, if you're not allowed to, you know, sell to the government without an S bomb,
but they're, they're going to do S bombs pretty quick.
-- Right.
-- Absolutely. That's,
I guess the beauty of, of something like the NDA A is
by putting some of these rules in it has
just like 2nd and 3rd order effects that are amazing and, and in some cases good or,
I mean, it could be bad, but I, I'm all for
keeping track of what's in our stuff as well
as understanding the vulnerabilities that are in it because
while you and I are both very aware that
there are magnitudes more vulnerabilities than we're tracking.
Like the first step of this story is we have to get a handle on what we have today,
which we don't at all.
And then we can kind of move to the next place.
This reminds me of the open badges thing where
it's like you have to have a testing framework,
you don't have to actually have tests,
but you have to have a testing framework because, well,
then you can start adding tests and if you can hand,
if you can ingest the National vulnerability database
and properly handle it.
Like you can ma like, basically there's a couple of steps here.
One, you, you have to have an s palm of your software and all its dependencies.
Number two,
then you have to have the data vulnerability feed
and you have to marry the two together.
Which ironically, I think your company does something there. I don't know.
That's actually his company's core purpose. Right.
And so,
and then, and this is the tricky part,
then you actually have to do something about it, right?
You can't just generate reports. Like here's a list of our flaws. Cool. We're done.
No, you kind of maybe have to go fix them at some point.
And that speaks to actually being able to do
software updates and push them into production and blah,
blah, blah, which again, like some companies are hilariously terrible at,
by forcing them to kind of build the infrastructure to handle this.
That's, yeah, they won't get every vulnerability,
but now they have the infrastructure to handle this.
That's right. That's right.
And
I think part of the beauty of all of this as well is if you're requiring S bombs,
you don't have to scan your S bomb for vulnerabilities.
If I have your S bomb, I can scan the S bomb for vulnerabilities,
which I think is part of what makes this so powerful.
It's one thing if I have to rely on a vendor
to tell me what the vulnerabilities are because let's face it.
We've been in this industry
every now and then. It's like, pay no attention to the man behind the curtain.
It's like we're working on that. You just don't worry about it.
Versus if you have a literal s bomb, you can be like, why, why is this here?
Why haven't you fixed this particular thing? And, and I think
it amuses me sometimes because the product security person in me
gets annoyed when someone asks me questions, like, why haven't you done this?
It's like, I'm doing my job, leave me alone.
And at the same time, it's like
there's really nothing wrong with asking that.
It would kind of be like, why is there lead in this salad? Can you tell me that?
-- You know,
-- a
great analog of this is like,
both my kids have skin uh sensitivities to Aloe and Aloe is in every dam I
can't and
I don't even know how you deal with that. It's actually really simple.
Either the product has a list of ingredients on it that is complete and correct.
I hope
or
like most diapers don't list all their products, uh all their ingredients,
but they have a 1 800 number
and you call it and about two minutes later you get a
human on the phone and they will literally read off verbatim.
Like some, it's basically like a, you know, like a product safety sheet.
It sounds like because she's literally like, it's like, you know, uh blanky blank,
you know, wood cellulose fibers, blah, blah, blah, this blah, blah, blah, that
and all that.
And they literally will tell me like what kind of plastics in there like, oh,
it's this kind of plastic, it's not this kind of plastic, whatever.
And literally,
I've never spent more than five minutes on the phone to get that list of ingredients.
Be it a shampoo, a diaper anything.
And so they have this process, they have obviously,
and it's clear that this is not like I'm not talking to the company company,
I'm talking to like a service that does this because it's pretty clear that,
you know, they're like, OK, this product this
like they need the exact name. They're like, OK, tap, tap,
tap,
tap, tap and they're like, OK, blah, blah, you know, they start reading it.
They're like,
and so it's clear what's happening here is that the company has,
here's a list of all our products,
here's a list of all the ingredients,
data sheets. And then they, they fired off to some call center service that
sure when people call in, it's like they literally ask like,
what company are you calling for?
Oh OK.
What product are you calling for? OK.
Tap tap, tap and then they just read the thing off to you.
-- So I
-- suppose this is comparable to certain items in
our personal supply chains have
gradients. We say the
bomb is included, right?
Where you can look at like the back of a bag of chips and
see the ingredients list versus I need to go and ask for an S
-- bomb.
-- The
caveat. I know a bunch of people with gluten intolerances or celiac disease
and the problem is they'll list spices.
Right. Right.
I,
I have a friend with that problem actually because he
-- was
-- spices almost always means at least trace amounts of gluten
and thickeners. Thickeners are the other big one
where if it just says thickener, you're like,
maybe no one knows
it's not perfect.
But I mean, well, it's a lot better than the software industry, that's for sure.
I mean, well, look in the food industry,
there was literally thousands of years of no real tracking or regulation
food. It wasn't until really after the industrial revolution and
we made a bunch of people really, really sick and killed them
that the government started to step in and say maybe we should do something here.
And I think if you look at the history of software,
we are an extremely young industry to be getting this
-- right now.
-- Well, but the problem is we've also everything is software now.
-- I know
-- the world is software. Absolutely right.
Like this whole, like, oh, there's this great tweet talking about um oh,
what was it talking about?
Essentially the uh
the Dally and all the knockoff,
like not knockoffs but the other people doing Dally like
systems to like you basically plug in a bunch of text
and it spits out an image.
It's magic and talking about how just completely messed up these things are.
And it's like, and it totally, you know, builds my confidence in self driving cars,
you know,
or like you see that video of Tesla
just running over some little plastic child thing.
Yeah, the kid, well,
I remember they had a video of this from a
couple of years ago and it was kind of hilarious
and they just released another one like a month ago.
And I'm like, it's the same thing. You'd think you'd fix this by now,
but
better
maybe break a little bit. I don't know.
I don't know.
Anyway. So
I think that's part of the problem is like, is
we, we had a food industry since, I don't know, 5 10,000 be
-- forever
-- because humans need food to survive.
-- We don't need software
-- that
the
idea of a restaurant or like
the food supplier is actually sort of relatively recent,
right?
In, in the scheme of human history. Right.
And obviously it's more than last Tuesday.
But software, I mean,
software running the world that's only in kind of the last 3040 years.
Ok. I want to before II, I think we've, I think people get the point.
We don't think this is terrible.
It obviously needs a lot more thought than it's probably been given.
But at the same time, I think one of the important things about
dealing with the government.
I think this is something that happened when we were young.
There's this idea of the government is completely strict and
stringent and if you break any of the rules,
like you lose, go back to start.
But the reality is like, that's,
that's mostly insurance companies in the United States, not the government,
the government's usually like, I've done this with the IRS.
We like you screwed this up.
Here's a new form, fill this out correctly and everything will be fine.
It's like, oh, well, thank you people.
And now granted, I know there's instances where that doesn't happen.
But I think generally speaking,
-- they're not there to screw you over my
-- account.
Made it pretty clear to me like you have to
mess up pretty big to end up in prison for tax shenanigans.
Like
you have to try.
Now, here's how I think we should frame the rest of our conversation
rather than complaining or not complaining about something is,
let's say I want to get ready for this particular piece of legislation
that we know is going to happen in the next couple of years.
What do I do today? Assuming I have nothing in place at all.
-- So first of all, you have to get executive buy in. Well,
-- ok.
-- Yes,
-- because there's literally no, I'm sorry, but there's like this is a problem.
It's a lot of technical people like, oh,
we should go do this good technical thing and they don't get executive buy in.
So
they run a script on their computer and it just never gets done reliably.
Yeah. So step one is actually getting executive buy in that.
This is something we'll have to do once you've got that,
it's essentially you start building a piece.
-- Her. No, no.
-- Hold on. Hold on. I, I think your, your carts too far in front of the horse.
I think
the executive buying is a good point.
And I think there, there is a nist standard that just came out not long ago.
Um This nist 800-1 61
and it's titled Cyber Security Supply Chain
Risk Management Practices for systems and organizations,
which is a very nice title.
They love doing that and this is not a technical documentation.
It fundamentally just talks about how to structure most of
this in a way that an organization can become,
I guess palatable
to what you need to do.
And I think
the executive buy in
is the first step.
But fundamentally the vast majority of these
changes you need to do in your organization
aren't super technical. It's more about getting humans
to accept and be willing to make small changes to what they do.
There are a lot of other standards here too. So for example, there's an iso standard.
I forget the number
literally for taking in security reports and dealing with them.
Well, is that the vulnerability standard.
And so
part of it is like when I say you need to build a P cert, I mean, not just the P cert,
but the stuff behind it in the sense of, you know,
your developers have to start reporting stuff to the P cert,
they have to start listening to the P cert.
And you know, actually
you have to start
maybe prioritizing a vulnerability fix
for a new feature, which
-- again you need executive buy in from that as
-- we, we talked about that last week,
Dustin.
That's a different story.
Here's rather than go into that and,
and there are better places than here to talk about.
Things like P Cert. I think
there's more foundational.
Well, things like S
-- bomb, I see, I would
-- consider S
bomb is going to be a big foundation of all of this. I think
I would consider S
bomb to be part of. I would say PRT
nowadays because
while in my mind, it should be part of what the developers just do like as like
it's just a basic thing that all developers should do.
The reality is we're not there yet as an industry
like
that doesn't surprise me though. If you look at every use case for
today, they're almost exclusively security focused use cases.
There aren't a lot of use cases that
are non, there are things we will be able to do with these.
That's like a whole, that's a very long other conversation,
but fundamentally the vast majority of people when they talk about
bombs, it's to do vulnerability scans
and it's to figure out if I'm shipping something because like log for Shell
just happened.
And I need to know, have I ever shipped this package in the history of time?
Which is, again, it's a very security
-- focused use case.
-- The original use case for S
bomb, which was license compliance
is
quasi
security in the sense of like we're back to the kind of don't do that, you know,
stage of software development, which sounds a lot like security people,
it's risk related for sure.
And so I, well, basically
you need S
bomb, you need. And
the thing is the PRT,
when I say A P cert, it also can't just be like
a person, ideally, it needs to be maybe two or three.
And I get that there's really small software development shops
and open source products or projects that,
that will never have a P cert team
because there's like literally one person working on it.
But part of it is is
it's not so much building the P cert as building
the cultural bits and the sort of the beliefs that,
you know, this could be important. This is something we value.
Well, and, and look,
here's the way I look at this is when you and I got started in all this.
If you wanted to know what vulnerabilities were in your system,
you had to hire an army of people to basically build a custom S bomb by
bomb. I mean, text file, checked into CBS
and then cross reference that with all of
the vulnerabilities that have basically ever been released
-- and there was no automation and
-- then realize
you forgot case sensitivity and do it again
and then some of them
have hyphens.
Yes, I know. I know.
Well, this is, this is a problem today though even with,
with vulnerability data and F bombs is how do you, how do you define?
What is the name of the product? Does it have? Hyphens? Does the
-- company's name is that part of the product is
-- well and product names change.
I know, I
don't,
I know,
I know this is actually where the Spring framework there was uh
there was a back door in spring a couple of months ago
and
Spring has changed ownership multiple times.
And so figuring out what the name of it actually is because
in like the world of C pe they include vendor name.
Well, the vendor name, there's like five vendor names. So it's completely insane.
But anyway,
so I think this is where we have an opportunity. Now.
You don't necessarily need an army of people digging through vulnerabilities.
If you have something like an S
bomb, now you can just like basically scan it.
There's m
there's million scanners,
scan your ass bomb and then you can start saying things like, ok,
what am I affected by?
And then you need someone to say, ok, here's the list of stuff,
here's what we're going to fix right now.
Here's what we're going to fix
before you do that. You also need to start triaging it and see.
Like, are we actually affected because,
-- yeah,
-- that's true too.
My, my favorite story, you know, Jackson Data bind, deserializing vaults,
remote code. Absolutely. And thank goodness that
is it Red Hat satellite?
I want to say five or six, I forget which one
doesn't use the deer
and never will.
So I, you know,
kept arguing with or trying to educate people which devolved down
to arguing because I'm not very good at it apparently.
And then we would just fix it to make them go away, which
I know we did the same thing at elastic.
We had Jackson Data B and Elastic search and we didn't use any of the
-- deser stuff, but people freaked out because it was there.
-- Let me put it this way.
What's
the cost of saying I'm not vulnerable
when the software component has been updated.
Versus the cost of saying I'm not vulnerable
when the software component has not been updated.
And there's this like weird explanation from the vendor, right?
Well, in my favorite always was people would say, prove it, prove you're not
-- exactly like
-- in the case of elastic where our source code was in github.
So we could say, look at this line. This is where we disable this.
That is why we're not vulnerable. But, you know, a lot of people can't do that.
What amuses me is we've trained people that software update equals not vulnerable.
Just accept it because we have made whoopsies in the past.
-- I mean, it's
-- kind of true,
like it's mostly true but not always, not 100%.
-- But uh moving along,
-- yes, triage. Figure out what affects you.
You have to prioritize it because my one complaint about this law,
I will say is they say like, no,
they need to be more clear because there are,
you can never fix all your vulnerability.
I mean, I've been saying this for years and I will keep saying it.
If your vulnerability scan comes back clean,
you either have a broken scanner or someone has done something to trick the scanner.
Like
you just any reasonably sized application these days doesn't come back clean.
It just doesn't.
Well, and that's where the language of it talks about having a plan to deal with it.
And I, I would assume again, I
would think most government agencies are mature enough to go. Ok.
These criticals need to be fixed soon and these not so critical.
Sure, next release or
sometimes
next release doesn't always work. Either if you have 300 low issues,
you're not fixing 300 issues in a release. Well,
generally
you say that
-- sometimes it can happen where you upgrade like one node package and
-- red hat,
one of their log for J updates.
One of their Java pack things was like over 100 they, they, they finally upgrade, uh,
updated a couple of packages and it was like,
it was about five years of CV S
and, and that's fair. It happens. Right.
But, but
that's where I think being overly strict,
but I think this is where this is where the scale we have the issue
of you have people on one end of the teeter totter that are like,
whatever, we just don't worry about any of this crap.
This is where the,
the S bomb for services I think is going to really
be a game changer because before you could ignore it,
that's going to be a tough one because a lot of these companies, like,
that's kind of their secret sauce type stuff.
Like I've, I've talked with a lot of these vendors and they,
they really don't want to give up this
information also because the minute they start giving
up these S bombs then they're gonna have to deal with what you deal with,
which is all these emails going.
Ah, you say you use version X and it says it has a CV S and why?
But if you want to sell to the government, you're going to have to do that.
I'm not saying they're going to publish them on their website,
-- but they want that sweet, sweet government money. So they're going to
-- comply.
Almost every company I deal with will not publish their sock to report publicly.
Which I know it's bizarre to me because I've read
a lot of them and they're not that interesting.
I know. I know, whatever.
Anyway.
Uh,
right.
So,
but then the other side of the teeter totter now is the government people that
I think sometimes they take a purposely hard stance against a lot of this.
Not because they even believe it. But because if they don't,
-- you can't meet in the middle,
-- it's actually simpler than that.
They,
the government 99 times out of 100
has a stick that they can use, but using that stick is a pain in the butt.
And no, so unless you, like, do something to, like, really tick them off, they're,
they're not going
well. No, no. I mean,
I'm saying when,
when I deal with the government as a customer,
they'll often look at a vulnerability scan and say you
have to fix all this stuff and we're like,
we're not fixing all this stuff, we'll fix these things and they're like, ok.
Yeah,
like,
yes, we accept your terms.
Yeah.
If you, if you start in the middle, they're gonna meet you over in, you know,
-- New Jersey instead of
-- in the,
and, and that's my suspicion.
But then
ii I
feel like if you have a, a
moderately sensible
development
kind of culture and environment,
none of this is going to be
that drastic or life changing
is
my
suspicion
change
for mature companies would be the,
the services that will have to start providing bombs
to the government because like Microsoft Red Hat IBM,
like they're,
that stuff's pretty much all public anyways.
You know, there's that one Mercedes document.
I love, that's like 1000 pages long and it's
all the open source junk that's in their car
and it's just this honk and huge PDF.
Right. Here you go. Here's RSP.
Well, no, I mean, like they obviously have that data in a structured manner already.
And,
you know, I, I would hope they give something better than a PDF but fundamentally,
like they've already published this on the web.
So it's, can't be that hard.
Right.
And I, I can't wait.
I,
I wish I would have more insight into what
the services s bombs are going to look like because
I'm,
I don't, I, I legitimately don't know.
Part of me thinks a lot of these services are going to be like flaming bags of poop.
And part of me thinks,
I bet a lot of these services are actually going to be pretty good because
it's just,
it's not when you're running a service,
it's not that hard to just upgrade dependencies with something like depend
aot
because you can quickly roll things back
and move things forward and make minor changes
and it's not like a big event. You know,
well,
again, if you're mature, like uh the, the, the best story I have
-- testing
-- and all that.
The best story I have is, and this is like 1510 or 15 years ago ebay, ebay had
a Java monolith.
That was what ran ebay was this
just honking huge Java Binary.
And I forget what their release schedule was, but it was like once or twice a week,
the train leaves the station,
get your, get your stuff on board if you want it there.
And I don't know how ebay made this work because I mean, Java, 1015 years ago,
making a model with that big work on
a,
like a really high profile public facing website with a lot of moving parts
like, wow, however, like,
so I can't even imagine where they are now probably in the exact same place.
Um Well, no, because like they got to work and like, why would you change it? Right.
It's like, it's like
robot
services. Apparently the whole back end of that sucker is just a big old pile of Java
because
what else did you architect that thing in 1015 years ago?
Right.
Like Python or Haskell?
Yeah,
exactly.
So
like companies have
made this kind of like huge
engineering.
Like it always reminds me kind of like building the Hoover Dam,
like the Hoover Dam came in under budget
ahead of schedule, right? They did some clever engineering hacks
and
I mean, yeah, a bunch of people died and they actually improved safety.
They started making them wear helmets and like tying them to ropes and stuff,
which in hindsight again, seems really obvious, but I guess
whatever, somebody had to go first, right,
to put it bluntly, like, if you're a big mature company, then this,
even if you're not doing this and you probably are doing this,
it's not going to be that heavy of a lift.
The biggest problem will be is if you have a culture of
secrecy or a culture of not telling people what's in your software,
-- that's going to be a problem.
-- That's true. That's true.
So anyway, I think, let's wrap this up because it's been too long.
I feel like when I first read this,
it felt like it was going to be a big deal and it mattered a lot.
But I honestly,
after this discussion, I feel like it's going to be a heavy lift for a lot of people,
but I don't think it's going to be
as bad as I
-- thought it was initially, which is a good thing.
-- I think more so than that.
Stepping back, it's going to be a big cultural change
for the
like, look at seatbelts,
like straight up there is
Senate and congressional hearings where people
are talking about how like just seatbelts
are going to literally be the end of the American way of life.
And there's the same videos for not smoking on airplanes, like, not,
not smoking in general, but just banning smoking on airplanes and, like,
straight up this is the end of American life as we know it.
Yeah. And
so
whatever, whatever
it's gonna be a major culture shift.
But we've done these, like a great example is,
remember when open source was kind of the weird
smelly hippie hiding in the corner of the room
and now it's,
uh,
-- well, it's everything, it's everywhere,
-- it's
literally everywhere. That's
right. It went from
the cancer that will destroy us all
to the thing that is saving everyone.
-- I love it, but
-- there's no other way to do it anymore.
I know. I know. Well, we know that everyone knows that now.
Like I, I keep coming back to you. If you need a web server or a web client, you
-- just can't build that in house server again.
-- That's right.
That's right. All right. Anyway, I'm going to call this one.
I think it'll be fun to see where this goes in the next couple of years. I'm excited.
So, thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening. Go to open
source security podcast.com. Head up the show, not UZ Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag Hit us up on social media. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day. You too.
Thanks everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.