Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Pressers.
-- So
-- before we hit record, the first time we hit record,
Kurt was mentioning how he's tired
and I have a lovely story about being tired from the other night.
So
I'm
asleep. What you should do if you're tired at night is go to sleep.
Well, obviously. Yes. No, no, this was, I'm sleeping soundly like a baby
-- and all of a sudden
-- there babies do not sleep soundly.
They don't.
-- Now that
-- I've
-- had kids, I'm like, no, no babies are like they were sleepers.
-- Ok.
Anyway,
I'm sleeping
and there's this ruckus outside
and it sounds like something crazy is going on. So obviously,
I jump up and look out the window
and it is 415 in the morning
and someone from the city is changing the no parking sign in front of my house,
sorry, like,
like you have like a permanent no parking sign
in front of your house like a steel pole.
-- And yeah,
-- I live on a busy street like I have an alley in the back and no one,
no one can park on the street.
But, yeah, 415 in the morning, the guy's in his boom truck in his boom,
-- changing the sign and it's making a horrible racket,
-- I guess over time, I
don't know.
All I could think of is, I'm like, this can't be real.
And then he gets, he, he finishes,
you know, packs his stuff up,
-- drives to the next no parking sign and they're changing it and I'm thinking
-- like,
changing the hours on it or something.
No, it just says no parking.
They were, the old signs were old and dingy and these are obviously fancy new signs,
but 415 in the morning.
-- Well,
-- but it might be one of those things.
Some places when they do traffic work,
try and do it outside of the hours when streets are busy because, you know,
it's safer and easier.
No, you say that
except
down the street, they've got a big hole dug in it for the utilities.
Yeah. But that's the utility guys.
-- They don't, utility guys don't care, like,
-- whatever.
I don't care what your reasoning is.
Do not change signs at four o'clock in the morning.
I had the same thing happen here at like three in the morning.
I thought there was like a fire outside
because there's like this weird orange pulse and glow
kind of showing through the window.
And I'm just like, you know, oh my God,
is my neighbor's house on fire and I get up and I look, and it's like city works trucks,
the big ones and they were
potholes on one on the street, you know, on the major street behind my house.
And I'm just, like, cool.
Like, I appreciate that because the potholes are getting bad.
Like, there's this one pothole I can still hear, like,
when I'm in the backyard and a big truck comes by and it's like,
good.
That's awesome. Anyway. Anyway. All right.
But, well, it's kind of, you know,
it's kind of the same topic is what we're talking about now,
which is kind of trying to figure out
-- how bad things are so you can prioritize fixing them.
-- Maybe that's a stretch.
But I'll let it, I'll let it go.
Uh Right.
So the topic today, we're going to focus on CV SS,
scores and severity and risk and the threat and what it means to you.
And we got here because I actually started writing a blog post
to kind of throw NVD under the bus a little bit.
So
for those of you who may not know. Congratulations.
NVD, the National vulnerability database,
which is run by NIST here in the United States,
they take all of the CV E data and they enrich it, they add some more information
and it's a very nice feed of data.
And one of the things they do is they add a CV SS score to the CV ES
and
it's never right.
And
see and that's where things go.
We'll get to that. We'll get to that.
Let me, let me set the stage and then we can start bickering over minor details.
-- So they're
-- not minor. That's the problem.
So anyway,
they assign a CV SS score to the CV E and then people use that score like when you
get a scan from one of the container scanner vendors
that we complained about a couple of weeks ago,
that's where they get their severity from.
Generally speaking.
And so I was, I've been getting annoyed by these container scans.
I get that everything is critical and it's like holy crap. No, it's not.
This is nonsense.
And so I started writing a blog post explaining what is wrong with NVD scores.
And in the process of doing this, I thought I should actually crunch some data.
So it's not just me making crap up,
which is basically what the first draft of this blog post was.
-- So I took the NVD data and I thought I can't just use their data. I need, I need
-- more.
-- You mean their CV SS scoring data,
-- correct? Yeah. Right. Right.
And so I thought I'm going to grab the redhead data. Redhead has a huge corpus of data.
I trust
it because I know where it comes from.
It's well done and it's really easy to get, I tried to find the Microsoft data,
but it's behind a bunch of like login pay wally type stuff.
And I thought I, I give up, I'm, I'm too lazy to do this.
I'm just going to grab the redhead data
because it's there and anyone can download it.
So anyway, I grab the redhead data.
I shove it into an elastic search instance and I start
crunching the numbers and it totally changed my perspective on everything.
I, I honestly, I don't think NVD is the problem anymore.
I think they're using CV SS fundamentally correctly. I think CV SS is the problem
just to give a bit of back story on this.
So like because I've been involved with this and I'm very
aware of how NVD operates because I've spoken with them.
But basically, yeah, they enrich the data.
They're what's called a CV E data publisher.
So they don't actually kind of do original research or CV ES.
But what they do, like you said is they enrich the data.
The problem is when you're going to assign a CV SS score, it's very contextual.
And so what the
has to do is essentially assume kind of a worst case scenario.
Well, here's the question, why are they enriching this data?
Well, it's,
it's fundamentally for the US government to consume and
use and other people use it because quite frankly,
managers love.
How do you feel on a scale of 1 to 10? Oh, you feel like a three? OK.
We're going to like we're going to hire somebody with puppies to
come by the office and bring everybody's score up to a six.
Right. Right. Or maybe buy some play doh or something.
I don't know who I do like play doh.
Yeah.
So the problem is NVD, for example, when they sign a CV SS score,
they kind of have to assume like a worst case scenario.
Whereas I know at red hat we had certain, I would say expectations about,
for example, this is how this product is sort of used correctly.
And so thus where NVD might say, like look,
this service is attack over the network like from remote from the internet.
Red hat might say no, no, no, like look if you,
if you run this service and expose it to the internet, that is way out of spec like no,
you this locked down to your local area network and or trusted systems.
And so that that is part of the difference in their scores.
Let's give an example here because I think what you
just gave an explanation that makes sense to me,
but I bet it doesn't make sense to everybody.
And I want to give two examples. Samba being the first.
Yeah, Samba's the classic one where Red Hat's assumption is, you know,
Samba's a file server.
So you're running that on your local network,
you're not exposing it to the entire internet.
-- Yeah,
-- don't do that because if you expose it to the internet,
you're going to have a bad just full stop.
Well, exactly.
I mean, and if you do have to allow remote, remote access to it,
that's what VPNS are for.
Yeah. Right. Right. Now, so, I guess in that instance NVD
claiming something is maybe critical Red Hat might claim it's
important or moderate because Red Hat's going to say,
don't hook this up to the internet.
NVD is going to say maybe it's hooked up to the internet who's for us to say,
and I'm not going to argue who's right here on the other side though.
One of my favorite examples is there are security
in
bin
tis
where
you might run this.
Like, let's say you're running some application,
let's pick on the file application, right?
You run the command file and NVD is notorious for rating those as being critical,
whereas Red Hat would call them lower moderate because in order
to attack that in order to get someone as root,
running the file command against your bad thing
is such a bizarrely complex chain of events.
Yes and no, because there's a lot of work
where you actually are poking files with the file utility to see
what the heck it is to see what to do with it.
-- No way. I don't buy that.
-- I've done this all the time. I have mystery files.
I have to deal with all the time and I quite honestly,
when I have to deal with these mystery files,
-- usually I shove them through virus total
-- first.
-- I mean, yeah, that's the easy answer.
-- Exactly.
And then I, you know, I run file on them to see what is this thing, you know,
and it's like a PDF or an HTML or it's like some office do
that, lost its
-- extension.
-- Ok.
So here's where this starts breaking down though
is you can make the convoluted argument.
Everything is critical
using
-- that line of thinking and I think that's broken. Here's the
-- problem.
So CV scoring has a couple of areas that it
looks at and I'm just gonna read them off quickly.
Number one is the attack factor. This is how do you get to it? Right.
Number two is the attack complexity and I love
attack complexity because you have low and high.
There's apparently no nothing in the middle, you have privileges required,
which makes sense like the,
the the thing that you're attacking kind of like what level of privilege do you need?
You know, do you need a log in or can you just attack it without an account at all?
You've got, is there any user interaction required?
Because obviously that's, that's a big deal then you've got scope.
So the scope of the attacker, does it stay the same or change?
So, you know, there's a big difference between, for example,
breaking into a web server and getting the context of the web server
and breaking into the web server and you know,
somehow getting rude access through that flaw.
Sure, a better example
like with Docker, right?
So breaking into doctrine, being able to mangle Docker is bad,
but breaking into doctrine being able to like touch the system as root very,
very bad.
And then you've got your CIA your confidentiality,
integrity and availability impact and again, you have none low and high.
There's again, apparently no moderate, which always confused me.
But who am I to say?
And then there's two huge areas of CV SS scoring that are always ignored.
And that is the temporal score and the environmental score.
I never touched this either. Exactly because
to get that data is so hard and what the
temporal score is a couple of really interesting things.
Number one is exploit code maturity.
So it's almost always left as not defined because your
options are unproven proof of concept functional or high.
So exploit code maturity for example would be, you know,
oh there's like a there's a zero day out in the wild.
Well, that's bad.
But for example, you know,
there's a zero day out in the wild and somebody you
know figured it out and posted an example of it to github
with, you know, a full fully packaged solution. Well, that's really bad.
Same thing for remediation level right?
There is little bit easier because you can hopefully look at the vendor, you know,
official fix temporary fix work around unavailable
and same thing for report confidence,
you know, unknown reasonable confirmed.
So report confidence would probably be the easiest of these three to
score because basically you look at the source of it like,
oh, it came from Red Hat or Microsoft.
Well,
that's confirmed remediation level again is relatively easy to find
the data for because you go to the vendor site.
But the exploit code maturity thing is basically, I mean,
I worked at vendors where that's what we did and it was a huge amount of work.
The next one is that environmental score where that is kind of takes into account
is this product used? How is it critical?
So like my favorite example here is always DNS servers.
There's a lot of DNS servers,
like the one on my local network that are honestly not that important, right?
You pop it, you can sort of attack, well,
you can redirect my machines but everything's http S now.
So it wouldn't work that well.
And then you compare that to like, oh, I don't know the root level DNS servers,
those are kind of more important than my local DNS server.
And so those two areas are always ignored because the data is so hard to get.
Here's the thing, I, I've actually never met anybody that uses Temple
-- or environmental scores.
-- Well, they don't really exist.
-- So I mean, this is in
-- theory, you could use them within an organization.
Well, that's the intent, right?
I think the expectation is organizations and vendors
are supposed to fill that stuff out.
But yeah, nobody, nobody fills them out.
And in fact, like from my perspective at work,
we publish security advisories and I've just started publishing my own
CVSs scores because the ones at NVD are generally wrong.
So it's easier for me to do it right.
-- And
-- that's the second thing is traditionally, nobody
-- CVS S scoring apart from NVD because it was so much damn work
-- and it still is,
it's not easy.
-- And so
-- some vendors are, and that's one of the changes I helped push through.
What I'm happy about is vendors can also push their CVS S scores now
and NVD can push their score and you can have multiple CVS S scores,
for example, Red Hat and Debian shipping the same software,
but with slightly different configurations by default,
very different CVS S situations.
OK? OK.
There's, there's, we're, we're,
I think dangerously close to rat Holing and there's a,
a couple of other really important points I want to bring into the conversation. So
if you look at the Red Hat data, they have a CV SS scores,
they have version two and version three scores and they also have what they call
the impact and the impact uses something that I call the Microsoft severity system.
And this is low, moderate important and critical are the ratings you get.
Well, technically, there is
-- also a none, you don't see it that often.
-- None doesn't matter.
-- Nobody cares.
-- What? It's because I've seen oracle things with a CV SS score of 0.0.
-- And I'm kind of like, well, how, what, how did
-- that's probably not possible. But
the point is I,
I'll make sure there's a link to this in the show notes
and there'll be a link to this blog post I started writing,
which should be out.
By the time I decide to publish this, the Microsoft ratings are very, very simple.
And if you read them, basically, anyone can score using that scale,
I would say immediately after reading the ratings
where a CV S si bet would take several
hours of reading and then a lot of screwing it up to actually start doing it well.
And in a lot of ways, I think that might be vastly superior.
And I found from a personal experience,
the Microsoft scale is generally more accurate
when I'm making decisions than A CV SS score.
The thing is though I started crunching all this data.
If you look at the red hat ratings versus the red hat CV S
scoring, there's a definite disconnect in those two data sources.
So part of the problem is the fundamental dimensions that CVS S scores on
are horrifically out of date like they definitely made sense 20 years ago.
Yeah, that's probably true. They don't anymore.
Like a great example is this whole privilege is required back in the day if you had a
service that required a login only people who were
supposed to really be there had a log in.
Now,
how does that work for like Gmail or a cloud
provider where you can get a log in for free?
Like there's a lot of services being run where you can just
sign up and get a log in for free with no hassle,
no credit card, nothing.
And so for example,
that throws out the whole privilege required because one of the biggest sort
of separators of moderate from we care about this flaw was ok.
Can you attack this remotely with or without an account?
If it's without an account, we care, but if it requires an account? Oh, ok.
Well, you know,
you only have trusted users in there so that
significantly reduces the threat and scope of risk,
you know.
Yeah,
you have to worry about insider attacks but you don't have to
worry about everybody on the dang planet attacking you physical network.
Ok. Like what does that mean in a data center where shared tendency is a thing?
No, I agree. It's, it's right. Many of these concepts are very old
and
they, they definitely don't always make sense.
Well, they, they assume an on premises network where you run your own data.
-- Yeah, it kind
-- of does. I agree with that.
And so my comparison here actually is, I've,
I've done way more thinking about this than I probably am comfortable with.
If you look at something like CV SS,
it's very rigid and I don't think there's anything wrong with that,
but it also means that as the universe grows and changes,
you have to adapt basically as quickly in many instances.
But then you look at something like the Microsoft
rating system and it really makes me think about
of the US constitution from the respective, it's so vaguely worded,
it can be applied in different ways depending upon the environment it
-- exists in
-- reality has so fundamentally
changed since those documents were written,
right?
-- There's no nice way to put it like it
-- has.
But yet the US Constitution is still applied on a
daily basis by our court system for better or worse.
Well, and you guys have had amendments, you know, like the whole no beer thing.
That was
a,
that was a bad idea. That's OK. It's all better. Now,
the other challenge is that creating this data is
nontrivial.
Now,
I'll be blunt somebody with a good familiarity with
the product and a good familiar with security.
We can usually assign a CV SS score in like 1 to 5 minutes and,
and justify it and explain it.
But I'll be blunt,
the number of people running around with like a
deeply intimate knowledge of the 120 Red Hat products.
Well,
they either work for Red Hat or used to work for Red Hat. So there's like not a lot of us,
you know, same thing with Microsoft,
like I don't know Windows well enough to assign
a score to something that does some sort of
token reuse in the Windows authentication subsystem.
-- Like, I literally don't know anything about that anymore.
-- Sure.
But the problem here is that NVD sets
the scores and then there are lots of organizations
that are now defining policy putting at the CV
SS documentation for 3.1 says don't do that,
but everybody's doing it.
Yeah,
but I have power tools that literally say like don't
use this power tool to cut wood or something.
And I'm like, but it's a wood cutting tool,
you know, like I,
right,
like I have all sorts of things with warning labels
on them where I'm not supposed to do that.
Yeah, the tool is useless without that.
And I mean, that's part of it as terrible as CV SS is, it's a lot better than nothing.
I mean, yes, you know, same thing with CV is CV E great.
No, but having a barcode label for
vulnerabilities
and by the extension,
this is an actual vulnerability is horrendously useful.
Now in, in, in, in my blog post, I write, I basically, II I say this right.
I'm not bashing C DS s. My intent isn't to say this is garbage, throw it away.
The,
the basically what I came up with was the
fact that I unexpectedly I think showed myself that
CBS S it's,
it's probably time for a facelift and bring it
bring it into the modern world which it,
it is like you described.
It's not right. It was built for a different universe.
Well, the modern world is also much more diverse than it used to be. It wise.
I look at what's in my house now. Wow.
This 20 years ago would have been,
I think this comes back to the point of the Microsoft system is vague
and so it's easy to say,
ok, given the circumstances, how does that apply
to this vaguely worded list of ratings?
-- Well, you got more wiggle room,
-- you have tons of wiggle room.
And I think that is funny enough when CBS S started, I was like, oh, thank goodness,
we finally have like some concrete rules to define these things.
And now that I look at it, I think those concrete rules are actually
not good
in the current environment.
Well, ok,
so here's another part of the problem is it's not just that the world
has changed and some of the rules are a bit out of date.
When you build a system with rules, people are going to
use that system and in some cases game the system because, you know,
they have an outcome that they want.
I, I mean, I've dealt with vendors where they were clearly gaming c
-- scores to get them lower.
-- Oh, yeah, that happens all the time.
Or conversely, I've had people try and gain the system. So the CV SS score is higher.
Well, a great example being is some security researchers are like, oh my God,
I found an end of the world flaw and I'm like,
it's a reflected cross site scripting flaw.
-- Like it's
-- every security researcher does that pretty much
-- every
-- one
of
-- them
-- except for the ones like that have a massive portfolio and
-- just stopped caring and just churn out vulnerabilities like to VSO
-- who
was the research company that had put critical in front of everything.
So it's critically low, critically, moderate, critically high.
-- Oh I remember that. I don't remember
-- who that was but
I remember seeing, I thought it was a joke.
-- Yeah,
-- I remember that because I was like, yeah, am I
they're trolling us?
No,
that was legit. But so
the problem is part of it,
it's kind of like doing TCP congestion until you actually put it
out in the real world and use it for a few months.
-- You don't know what the problems are. I mean,
-- I, I do agree with that.
-- So
-- the challenge though is that, do you have a feedback loop to not only say, look,
here's the problems
and to figure out the solutions and then to deploy an update and the answer here?
No, like CV SS moves very like I when did 3.0 come out like that was
-- well, three
-- oh Is pretty old. 31 came out in 2019
but 31 is, I would say an extremely minor update.
-- Oh, yeah, it's 30 came out in 2015.
-- That's a different world, man.
Yeah.
I mean, Cloud was just nascent then and now it's everything.
Um,
so, you know, and that's,
that's the one thing that frustrated me a lot about a lot of these standards is the,
the slowness with which they move.
But something to keep in mind is that
the number of people and the types of people consuming these systems,
-- most of them are not what you'd call
-- agile.
Not exactly. I mean, if you're using a container scanner, which is the new hip thing,
you're getting CV SS scores from MVD as part of your report.
But for example, like,
let's say we totally rewrite CV S S3 1 and come up with CV SS four point.
Oh, well,
now all of a sudden all of these companies that are consuming that data have to make
changes to the software because we came up with a whole bunch of new, you know,
dimensions and metrics and
maybe we added medium instead of just low and high.
That's a nontrivial amount of work for people to be able to consume the data,
you know,
-- their work flows have to change even stupidly simple stuff where like
-- whatever,
that's what's your point though.
-- I mean, if you use that as an argument, the point
-- is that's hugely costly. And so
everything is hugely costly. And if you, if you're going to make that argument.
Like, screw
you. Stay in the past. I have no use for that, that argument. No way, man.
I'm not making that.
I'm pointing out that that is a fundamental problem here is that,
that institutional inertia, let's face it.
Right. The majority of companies are much happier
with business as usual than making rapid changes.
That's just kind of a fundamental thing.
-- That's
-- why they're disrupted out of business.
I'm not arguing for or against it.
I'm just pointing out this is how the reality of it is. We can disagree with that.
-- I have no sympathy for those companies. This
-- is how it is, right?
These companies don't want to change
-- how they consume this data.
-- I don't care
if they don't want to change. Is that my problem? Anyway.
Anyway, look, I'm trying to point out that there's,
there's other factors at play here.
This isn't just, you know, companies being lazy.
It's, they, they have, they have incentives to not change,
which is one of the reasons why this stuff is, you know, I mean, a great example is
why isn't every single CV numbering authority consistently giving out CV SS data?
-- I mean,
-- how do you even give it out though? Right. That's part of the challenge.
-- A perfect
-- example.
When you publish your CV E data to the CV E database, you can push CV SS data,
everybody can do that now, not just NVD, everybody can do that.
-- I I didn't even know you could do that. A
-- great example oracles patched quarterly.
They've been putting in their base score and then the specific, you know,
attack vector attack complexity privileges required, blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah.
They've been listing that out for at least 10 years.
How long has Red Hat been pushing out CV SS data? A
-- long time?
-- Forever.
-- Ish, not
-- forever but not all of them, but a lot of them have at least a decade.
And again,
that's why I was comfortable using the Red Hat data because there is a lot of it.
-- Why
-- aren't vendors doing this?
Well,
there's no real incentive because you start assigning these numbers and
it just makes people angry and they yell at you.
Whereas when you have those kind of nice wiggly room like, oh, it's just a low or, oh,
it's just a moderate.
You have a lot more wiggle room, right?
Because companies do have a tendency to do things.
-- Like if it scores more than a five, we have to yell at the vendor.
-- Yeah.
And that's, I mean, that's my biggest complaint.
We're, we're running ourselves out of time.
So I want to just kind of reframe the whole point of, of all of this.
And this is not where I intended.
I was actually just looking to make fun of NVD a little bit
and that's not where this ended up at all.
So I, I see a couple of pieces to this, first of all,
NVD doing their best and kudos to you guys, I really do think you're doing a great job.
You got to remember often times they don't even have access to the product.
-- They're trying to
-- score. Well, sure, they're doing their best. Exactly.
So, like they're doing a good job,
but then this data ends up going to something like a scanner vendor.
And I think
that the scanner, like, like security scanners today are, I think
negligent to a degree that is unacceptable on many levels.
And one of them is the severity ratings where they're accepting what NBD has.
And they're saying this is gospel and I think they are
misleading many of their customers into believing that these ratings have some
factual bearing instead of saying these ratings should be treated suspect at
best and you should be doing your own research on them.
And I don't, I don't see that today.
I see these vendors are treating it way more seriously than it is.
This is a classic flaw in humans of given even a super terrible weak data source.
We try to imply correlation and causation like, oh,
the bushes rustled over there might be a lion run away and it might be.
And so we have this bad mental pattern of, you know, trying to connect the dots,
right?
And so like, and especially something like, oh, you know, because here's the thing,
a score from 0 to 10 with this, like, scientific backing of, you know, oh,
it's a low severity confidentiality but high for
integrity or whatever, you know. It sounds scientific. It sounds like it's data.
It sounds good.
And so bam, that's it. It's truth now. Right.
What always gets me is, you know,
when you look at somebody who does a survey and it's kind of like, well,
what's the actual sample size?
You know, and if it's done properly, it's big enough to be plus or minus nerve margin,
blah, blah, blah.
But I think, you know,
things where people quote something off of like a Twitter poll and
I look at the Twitter poll and there's like 20 replies.
Yeah.
Right. Right.
Exactly.
And, and this is, so this is something I bring up in my blog post also,
like my sample size right now is NVD and Red Hat.
That is unacceptably small.
I, I need to look for more data now to see like does Microsoft have,
am I seeing the same thing?
Can I get oracle data and see the same thing? Like, I don't know the answer to that yet.
It will be, I think very interesting once I collect more data.
Well, but even if you get Microsoft and Oracle,
the problem is you still have sample buys of, OK, you sampled three companies.
-- Right.
-- No, I agree completely. Well, yes, exactly.
And I mean, this is part of the challenge obviously that we're seeing however,
like back to where I'm going with this right now.
Let's keep moving up the chain.
Now, we have a company making risk decisions based off of data.
A vendor told them was good when it obviously isn't.
And so like part of the reason I'm doing this and part of the reason
we have a podcast about it is this is partially an education campaign for me to
make my life better. It's purely selfish.
But I was saying like, we need, you need to understand what this data is and isn't
because there is an enormous lack of understanding today where I will, for example,
I'll give you, I just talked to a customer that handed me report was like,
we have to get rid of all these criticals.
And I said, Red Hat rated every one of these low, they're not critical.
And they said our security team said no criticals, you have to fix them.
And I'm like, your security team
needs to be educated like I will gladly talk to them and they
said they don't care what you think you have to fix them.
I'm like, then there's nothing I can do for you. I'm sorry.
And that's unfortunately where it ends.
But like that's obviously a security team that
clearly has no idea what they're doing.
Well, see, and, and my goal here with the CV E
JSON data format was to allow a global CV SS score
per vendor per product, even per configuration CV SS scores.
And the reality is that completely failed because nobody wants to do the work
to produce the data.
And very few people would be mature enough to actually consume that data.
And by definition, if they're mature enough to consume that data,
they're already doing it on their own end. Probably.
Well, I've, I've met organizations that do this,
like they consume Microsoft patch, Tuesday
and they also buy threat feeds from various vendors and then they have
their own people go over internally and look at it and say,
like, you know, how does this actually affect us?
-- What does this really mean to us? So,
-- I think there might be some incentive brewing
because I like a great example that I started publishing severity in
CV SS myself because I was sick of NVD screwing it up.
But now what's really funny is I'm getting complaints
because my CV SS scores are different than NV DS
and people are demanding I fix mine and I'm like,
no, no, no, no, no.
-- My scores aren't the problem.
-- Stupid question.
Wait, you're saying that the scores you pull,
not ending up in the CV? Oh, it wouldn't.
Yeah, because they'd go to the CV database but the NVD site publishes them.
Right?
I mean, I'll start putting them there if I can,
-- I don't know how I'll go figure that out, but
-- I don't know what the process for that is,
but I know who you need to talk to.
Yeah, I'll totally do it because I'm, I'm super happy to publish my own scores.
And I think it would also from the first
active of security people who need some education,
they treat the NVD data as gospel.
So if my stuff is in there, like, holy crap,
-- I just
-- want when all you have is like half a
sheet of paper with some vague instructions written down on it.
You know, it's kind of funny to me because almost always,
it seems to me the worse the data is, the more people treat it as the truth,
right?
Whereas when you actually have proper, proper data, number one, you have a lot of it.
And number two, you actually know
you have confidence or not confidence in it.
And so here's where I want to end this because we're kind of out of time.
And I think you bring up a really important point is
I had a lot of assumptions in my mind about this data
and then I started looking at it and I literally had to do a one
on everything that I thought was true.
I think this is true of many people in many organizations.
And I'm, I'm going to kind of throw CVS S under the bus a little bit.
Here is my suspicion is they've made most of
their decisions without data to back it up.
And it was probably gut feelings for people and I
can tell you now that gut feelings are highly inaccurate,
100% of the time.
It's just, it's, it's how it works like we're humans, we're bad at this.
What always gets me is you ask somebody to explain, why did you make that decision?
What data and what thought process led you to that
answer? And a lot of them are like, uh
and there's enormous power in having data sets and being able to look
at them and poke at them and make decisions based on them.
And,
and I, I view that as it every I,
I keep going through this data and like it's making my head explode constantly
because there's so many things I'm finding that I just did not expect to find
and it's amazing
and annoying and terrifying all at the same time,
which is part of the fun.
And I guess so I'm going to
in the show notes, I'm gonna put a link to the blog post that should be out by the time I,
I hit, publish on this,
everything I've done is with 100% public data
and it's with all functionally open source tools.
There's no reason anyone can't go do what I've done.
And I would totally encourage you. I'll have a link in my blog post to my github
project
that does all this.
And it is, it is fascinating and it is a lot of fun if you're a data geek.
All right, Kurt last word, take us home.
I think the fundamental problem is
this isn't a technology or an infosec problem. This is just how humans work.
Given incomplete data. We try to make
the best decisions possible.
I think the problem though is,
is we then assume that we made a good decision on good data,
which is not always the case.
I think that sums it up marvelously and I think that's an important point to it.
Our intent isn't to make fun of anyone. It's to just
maybe point out some truth such as that just because you
made a bad decision doesn't mean you're a bad person.
At the same time. It's important. We give ourselves the ability to change our minds.
-- Well,
-- and that's part of it too is it's not necessarily a bad decision.
It's an incorrect decision. Bad is a moral judgment, not necessarily whatever
the other thing is too is that decision might look bad now.
But 20 years from now you might be like holy crap. We dodged a bullet.
No, seriously, right? Like, yeah, part of the challenge too.
-- So I guess look up Dunning Kruger and go cry quietly while you drink.
-- I like it.
All right. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes, you pound Os S podcast hashtag
to hit us up on social media. Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks
-- everybody. Thanks everybody. Bye bye.