Hello and welcome to episode 79 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Pressers.
I don't even know which thing to start with today. Kurt.
It's
for the best part is the world's on fake fire. Now.
It's,
yeah, that's,
you know, yeah, let, let's start there. Let's start with Skyfall.
So there was a,
well, there was something called meltdown, which happened,
which you may have heard of where, where something affected, like most of the,
the CP US on the planet,
anything
less than 10 years old. Basically,
most of them
-- cost more than $10.
-- Right?
Turns out that was kind of bad.
And
what happened shortly afterwards is kind of
a website appeared called the Skyfall Attack.
I mean, what is called Skyfall attack.com is where it ended up and it kind of said,
you know, stay tuned, watch this space.
There's another attack coming and, and I remember
I talked to a handful of people about this and they were like,
this has got to be fake and I said
it, it probably is, but it's still something we should pay attention to.
And I think also
there are going to be a whole bunch of attacks now on CPU timing
that
we need to be mindful. Now, this one did come out really fast.
But anyway,
what it turns out it was basically a scam and some guy did it and he was like, oh ha ha,
look at me, everybody.
I I put together a fake page to trick you. Aren't I clever?
-- I
-- think
-- what he was trying to get it is he did like, what was it like two comments in the,
in the
comment section of the register and like one
or two tweets that were kind of anonymous.
And on the one hand, I mean, this is also happening in journalism now, right?
Where the problem is that first to publish thing and you know,
it used to be that you had a couple of hours to
research and write a story or even a couple of days,
but now it's like
you have to break the story inside of 15 minutes or somebody else will, you know.
And so especially in tech, right? Like especially in tech.
And so yeah, you don't have time to like verify this and validate this and,
and even if you try, you know, the guy is non responsive.
So what do you do? Right.
But here's the thing, man, this isn't, there's a website, right?
And all you have to say is I found this website, look what's on it.
It's not about validating or anything.
Even in additionally,
if you're a good security researcher and you have something private,
which mind you, you shouldn't make a website like this,
but you're not going to talk about what you've got, even if people catch wind of it.
Right?
And, and so like my first reaction when I found out this was a scam was like,
this is yelling fire in a theater is what this was like.
This is not OK in any universe because
the world was on edge because of me
and you, like you grabbed on to the fear and confusion
and you, you ran with it and like that's not, that's not a social experiment.
Like you're just a big jerk.
What the outcome of that experiment is is that some people will panic.
Some people dismiss it, some people will try and figure out more and waste time
and it's just kind of a dick move.
Um And see what really frustrates me is, is the reality is in security.
There's typically like there are some big
well known entities like Google Project Zero, you know,
that come out with good stuff,
but there are occasionally completely random people who
come out with a really good flaw,
you know, like http Poxy is my favorite example.
It's a bunch of guys in New Zealand that, right? I think it was point of sale software,
right? They, they and they were like, what the heck?
Like what do we do with this, we need some help and you know, we helped them and it was,
it turned out, ok.
But
so there is
the case of just completely random people finding horrible things
that does happen. And that's,
you know, and if that didn't happen, then this would be really easy to dismiss,
right?
Because it would be like, oh, well, it's not from this list of trusted people. So
ignore it.
-- But hey,
-- man, you know what, you know what a better example is even is Dan Kaminsky.
I
mean, Dan was kind of known before he broke the internet with DNS,
but like after that, everybody knows Dan now
and, and that's a great example of, and, you know, granted Dan did everything right.
That could have been done, right?
I mean, it, it was, that was a tough one. But, yeah. No, no, I, I agree completely.
I think,
I think pretending lone wolf type researchers can't contribute
massive research would be a foolish attitude to have.
-- And so anyone who writes off something like
-- that for the
year.
Yeah. Absolutely.
Right. Right.
You know,
and um, and, and the reality is like,
we have a society that
largely runs on trust.
So like my favorite example is I go to the bank to say pay my credit card bill with
money because I have a credit card with a
bank that I can't do electronic transfers easily to.
So I have to be like some 19 nineties stone age person and actually bring them money
and I hand the teller. Yeah, cash. So I, I bring a pile of cash to the bank.
Hand it to the lady
and I get like a tiny little receipt
but
like, I don't know if she faked the entry and printed it off herself,
but it's never been a problem. Right.
Like when you go to the bank and you give them a pile of money,
it like always ends up in your account. It doesn't just go missing.
So
actually I, I have, I have a fun story about that too is I was uh,
I think we spoke some time ago where I,
I help out with the concession stand at my son's swim team
and we had a big meet this weekend
and
I,
at one point I brought uh $1000 in twenties in
to break into change because we were selling lots of stuff
and, you know, I go in and get my stuff and they, they brought out the,
the rolled up or the, the, what is it?
The banded, like stacks of bills where it's like $50 in one,
for example.
And I had,
you
don't have
coins for
once.
I
know we have those terrible bills. But anyway,
uh the lady gives them to me and says, do you want me to count them? And I'm like, no,
even if we're a couple dollars short, like it's totally not worth anyone's time,
but at the same time
I totally get a bank having that attitude of,
if you want to double check us and you don't trust us implicitly, it's ok.
Yeah.
Yeah. And that's, and that makes the world efficient.
It makes the world work, you know?
Yeah. Right.
Anything else?
I mean,
if you had to validate and verify every single
transaction you have in life with everybody and everything,
it would be so time consuming.
You know. Isn't that what the blockchains for?
Well,
yeah, but even then you still need people just not to rip you off.
Right.
No, I, I agree completely. You know, it's one of those things.
Well, my favorite is like when you return stuff to a store,
most stores you literally like Costco is my favorite example.
You bring something to Costco that they may or may not have sold in the
last 10 years and you don't have the receipt and they don't even have like,
because they'll have the electronic record of it, right.
Hooked up to your card.
But even if they can't find that nine times out of 10,
they'll return it and give you your cash,
right? Because they know that like 99% of people aren't there to rip them off
and there's always going to be that 1%. But I also have a suspicion that the 1%
of we'll say nefarious people
if, if you service the the 99% the benefits far outweigh the negatives of that 1%.
But actually
this is, this is a good lesson for security also is as humans,
we love to obsess over the very small group
and, and what they are or aren't doing and,
and we ignore the huge group to our detriment.
Right.
Yeah. No, it's, um, so, so fundamentally, I mean, we
to have an efficient society, you have to have as little friction as possible,
right?
As little,
you know,
extra work as possible. Right?
And so, you know, you look at what journalists do
and they, you know, they'll make their best effort.
Uh but the, the ever common quote of, you know, we reached out to so and so,
but they could not provide a comment by the time, you know,
the story went online or whatever, right?
Because, you know,
they can't sit on this thing for 12 hours or 24 hours
or a week waiting for some guy to get back to them.
Oh, yeah.
No, no, I know, I know, man, I've, in fact, I've,
I've been in that situation where the one where,
where a reporter will send an email and be like, I,
if you can get back to me in the next 30 minutes,
you know, I read the email two hours after they sent it,
sorry guys,
but I
get it and I suppose they, they blast out, you know, send 50 emails,
hopefully four people get it in time.
I
-- get it. I
-- mean, the reporters on a dead,
they don't have a week to wait or a day.
But, um, so anyways back to this guy crying fire, it's like the reality is, yeah,
that,
that will work
for at least some small group of people will get upset
about it and try and figure out what's going on.
Um, and so, yeah, we know the result of what that experiment.
Like, I've often thought of doing like an April fools joke with a CV assignment.
And then I'm like, you know what?
No, because I'm gonna literally waste thousands,
if not tens of thousands of hours of people's time
and that's a dick move.
Yeah,
I absolutely, man. I, in fact, I hate April fools in general for that reason
is you just end up creating a bunch of stupidity.
And I, I think it's a weekend this year. Thank goodness, I don't have to work.
But yeah,
like I hate April fools because there's just so much stupidity going on and I waste
half my day trying to figure out is this real or is this not real?
And, and let's face it. Most of this stuff isn't even funny.
And, and that's what I think of what this guy, like what was proven here.
There
was
for some reason, we picked an
un,
an un embargo date of April 1st was picked for some major issue and it was just like,
oh man,
in hindsight, that was a really bad idea.
Or didn't Gmail debut on April 1st?
Remember like back then most online email providers gave you like
10 megabytes of space and Gmail says here's a gigabyte.
We're like, what? No, that's not real.
-- So
-- yeah, no, I mean,
yeah, I mean, if you want to waste people's time, you, you can definitely do that.
There, there's so many ways to grief and waste people's time. You know, you could
spray paint, bus stops or throw rocks at cars or yell
bomb in a crowded environment or at the airport.
You know, and
if you do that in the airport, man, you're going,
you'll be eating through a straw for a long time, I think.
Well, and see, that's part of the thing too is typically people don't do this
stupidity because there are consequences,
you know.
Um,
and that's part of the challenge with this online
thing is there's really no consequences for this,
this guy who did this stupid thing other than, you know,
we all kind of grumble about him and,
um, I can't even be bothered to find his name, but,
you know, and I don't think public shaming is the way to go.
I'm all for public shaming actually.
Well, it's
a
slippery
-- slope
-- and
there's that really good ted talk, talking about the online shaming and how,
you know, first of all, did we get the right guy
uh in, in this particular instance, we, we know exactly who it was.
The person's commented in public
and I, I don't remember their name and the website's down actually now,
so I can't look it up.
But, but like this is one of those instances
I think,
and, and, and this came up in a side conversation I had the other day was
not using people's names when they behave poorly,
encourages poor behavior because they know they're going to have a
certain amount of anonymity and protection from making terrible decisions.
And like, this is an example of
a competent, reasonable human being made a terrible decision.
Even with that though there's some challenges because there's other people
with the same name who had nothing to do with this.
Right.
There was a Reddit thread about this kind of stuff a while ago where it was like,
you know, people have read it
who share a name with like, somebody who's done something terrible.
What's that like? And this guy is like,
you know, when you Google my name, the first result is this guy who has the same name,
he's in the same state.
He kind of looks like me
and it's like some terrible, like child molester, some, you know,
something that's just not at all socially acceptable.
And he's like, every time I apply for a job,
I have to go through this whole thing to like, prove that that's not me.
I do feel bad for people in that situation.
And I guess
that is one of those examples of
sometimes when you have a functional society that isn't
completely bonkers in terms of identification of people,
you're going to have this and granted it's easy for
me to say this is OK because it's not me.
But even if it was me, I feel like
this is an example of
AAA functional civilized society
is just going to have this problem and you sometimes have to deal with it.
Well, this is why I learned that, you know, the, the,
the internet trope of Florida man does Xy and Z
the reason for that is that Florida is one
of the states that has open reporting laws around,
you know, uh criminal reports, like a lot of states,
criminal reports and whatnot are private, they're not public.
And so the reality is, I think this is probably happening everywhere.
It's just Florida is one of the states where as a reporter,
you can go to like a website and like search for funny things.
And
not only
that,
I think part of it as well is Florida is a place that attracts a lot
of people because it has plenty of opportunity and it has a very unique economy.
And so I have a suspicion between the open records laws
and the fact that just lots of random, like nobody's from Florida, right?
Everyone moves there.
And so you just
crazy hodgepodge like who's legitimately born and lives in Florida.
He was
born,
he left,
-- he left.
-- But no, no, no, no, no, no. You, you have to stay there. Right.
Because everyone born there leaves.
Right.
That's my point. Right.
Nobody's from Florida who lives in Florida.
You either move in or you're born there and you get out like, it's hilarious.
Yeah. So, I, I don't know.
I mean, to me there's, there's, we know the result of this experiment.
It's not going to be very surprising. It's
the part of the question is like, how do we sort of defend against this?
And I mean, the good news is, is there's not,
I mean,
the downside to this is kind of like the spam problem in
that a lot of people's time gets a little bit wasted,
right?
Nobody actually dies from this or has, you know, like a truly epically bad day.
But, you know,
a bunch of people wasted thousands if not tens
of thousands of hours dealing with the skyfall attack,
talking to their manager about it, you know,
calming, ruffled feathers, blah, blah, blah. Right.
And just, you know,
that does add up. It's like the spam problem.
We get these every single day. It, it does become a real problem
actually. That's really interesting.
I bet
if you're a business and you spent time on skyfall,
you could probably make a legitimate case to sue this guy
because he deliberately wasted your time and caused you direct monetary damage.
I mean, let's face it. This was fraud essentially, right? Like
you, you are.
That's a I,
I, well, ok, so definitely on the one hand,
the men's rea like he admitted to it in public, right?
He admitted the intent of what he did in public, which
I mean,
I believe that's the third rule of felony.
So I've decided now there's three rules around felonies.
Rule number one around for committing a felony is don't film it
right? Apparently people do that. Not a good idea.
Number two, don't talk about the felony to strangers,
seriously, folks
or to anyone.
And number three
is like, don't admit,
I guess number two A or whatever it is don't admit to the felony in public
and with intent
because like, yeah,
this makes a court case relatively like here's a printout of his tweet,
uh his tweets, sir.
Oh, ok. Well, there we go. You know,
like,
uh
so and again, we're not trying to give tips and tricks to criminals,
but I just feel like some people are so fundamentally
like, oh, it just blows my, it's like the tide pod thing.
Seriously. What,
what
like as a parent with small Children,
-- they're not small.
-- You know what
I've been thinking about this a lot because you told
me the other day we should talk about tide pods.
And I thought, how can I do anything other than just say like these people are idiots,
but here's the thing. I got to thinking about this and
I don't think they're the smartest people in the
-- world who might be doing that
-- by definition.
If you eat laundry detergent, that's not a
smart
-- thing
-- to get to that. We'll get to that.
So if you're listening and you've done the Tide Pod Challenge, uh by all means,
send me your video, I'd love to
see it.
But
I, I'm encouraging you, please. If you please please, people don't, don't do this.
And so here's the thing, right? Is
this feels like it's probably not very risky because let's face it.
When you were a kid. Did you get your mouth washed out with soap by your parents?
I totally did
so
right.
You say a naughty word or something and all of a sudden you've got,
you get in your mouth washed out with soap to teach you a lesson
and like it's not pleasant but it's not the end of the world.
And so I remember like soap isn't very good, but like I didn't die. It wasn't that bad.
And I feel like people probably have a similar view where they're thinking, OK,
so this is just soap.
I can put it in my mouth and I can bite down on it and
like orange goo flows out of my mouth and we all get a laugh,
we film it and then I spit it out
except that's not what happens because apparently
the chemicals inside give you like terrible
burns in your mouth and you probably need medical attention after you do this.
Well, it reminds me of the ice bucket challenge, right?
If you do the ice bucket with actually just like a bucket of ice,
yeah, you're, it's uncomfortable but you're probably not going to die.
But then the problem is of course, like any online prank me stupidity type thing,
people escalate.
Right?
Because you got to do bigger, better to get the views, you know, than the last person.
And so that one guy did die from the ice bucket challenge because he used
like an excavator or something stupid to dump a huge load of water on him.
I did not hear about that, but I am not surprised even a little bit.
Yeah.
You know, well, the reality is people die in all sorts of ways.
Like, so like I, my favorite is that British phrase,
death due to misadventure as an actual legal cause of death.
Oh, yeah. I, I like to say, uh, poor decisions, make good stories
-- if you live to tell the tale that
-- that is true.
And luckily I've, I've made it through all of my poor decisions so far.
But, but so, so anyway, here's, here's my point about this, right is I think
when as a human,
we evaluate risk constantly throughout our day
and we make decisions all the time about
Cleveland Crossing, the street has a certain level of risk, right?
Eating at a restaurant carries a certain level of risk. And I think
biting down
on laundry detergent
feels like it's probably
a
little risky, but not too bad when the reality is,
it's significantly worse than we think it is because
we're not dealing with chemicals in that thing.
We're used to,
we're thinking hand soap or bar soap. Right.
Well,
we're used to.
So,
and I guess people think, hey, this stuff's fine on my skin. Ok.
How bad can it be in my mouth? And the answer is
quite bad.
Really?
It's not normal soap, right. This isn't normal soap.
And I, I have a feeling or even laundry detergent, man.
I mean, well, now that I think about it,
you're right because this soap is contained in a little pod that when you,
even if you do touch it,
you're not touching it.
Right. Right.
You know,
-- and,
-- and I, how, how often do you touch laundry detergent? I touch it all the time.
-- Like it's in
-- my,
yeah, I have a scoop and I, I get,
I get the powder on my hands every time I use a scoop and then you know what I do,
I just kind of brush it off and in the machine and I go wash my hands and no big deal.
Well, and I think that's part of the challenges is there's a lot of risks that
they evolve over time.
Like a great example being the risk of being online, it used to be,
you could plug a computer in online
and
nothing too terrible would happen. Or you could open up,
remember when you could open up email attachments
safely as long as it wasn't like a dot exe or a dot Bat.
And
it
was it, I love you.
That was the first virus that was like people would send an
email saying if you get an email with the subject of,
I love you.
Don't, don't open it.
And the virus was actually the warning email
because there was no, I love you virus.
But the problem is like,
if something evolves at 5% a year, that means it's completely different inside of,
uh, what's rule of 72 roughly 14 years
or less. Right. Exactly. You know,
um, or even within five or 10 years, it's evolved so much that we, you know,
like the flu every year a new strain comes out and
unfortunately you got to go get a new flu shot.
Well,
a
good example of that because this year, I guess the flu shot is highly ineffective.
The
-- wrong
-- strains.
-- Right. I got the stupid flu shot for nothing is what that means.
-- Exactly.
Um, but yeah, so going back to this, the problem is these like,
soap is a great example, right?
Soap used to be real simple. It's ash
and fat
and lie.
Right. That's, that's basically soap, you know, in a nutshell.
Right. Well,
-- well, funny. Enough. Lye is like, super dangerous too.
-- Well, no, sorry, I was wrong.
It's just ash
and fat
is the minimum. The bare minimum you need to make functional soap.
Right. It won't be good soap, but it will be soap.
Right.
And, you know,
so soap went from something that basically you could eat but it tastes bad to,
you know, now something that's, yeah, full of chemicals.
Highly
concentrated,
you know. And, um,
like, yeah, I mean, the amount of liquid detergent I put in, in a load of laundry.
Now, it's like a tiny, tiny amount. It's crazy,
you know. So I'm pretty sure I don't want to drink that blue stuff.
Um,
you know.
Oh, and here's the best thing I just noticed the other day,
uh, G two Gatorade. The blue flavor is the exact same shade of blue as Windex. I had
a,
I had the two bottles sitting on the kitchen counter and I was like, oh, they're,
they're the exact same color
or what is? There's, there's a, uh, a floor cleaner. Fabu
Loso, I think it's called that has like pictures of fruit on it and it's,
it's orange and red and in very fruity colors
and I guess they do have problems at poison control
where Children drink it all the time because it,
it looks like
fruit on it. It must be
one of my kids tried to grab a ch beer out of the downstairs fridge and I was like, no,
that's not cherry Cola
you can pick
up kid.
Yeah.
You know, but it was like it had,
-- it had pictures of cherries on it. The
-- soda's gone bad. Daddy.
Yeah.
But, uh, no, I mean, and that's the problem. Right?
Is this, you know, I remember as a kid, laundry detergent was pretty boring.
And, yeah,
it wasn't like you had to dump huge amounts of it in to get your clothes clean
and you know, now you, you put in a tiny amount and your clothes are super clean.
Um So yeah, I don't know, it's,
but so back to the, the the the fire yelling fire in a crowded theater analogy. Like
uh do we, how do we defend against this? And, and or even do we need to defend against?
I
kind of,
yeah, because I kind of think about the reality is this happens so rarely,
you know,
that do we actually really need to spend a whole bunch of time dealing with this?
Right? And I mean,
as much as I would love to say,
all of the bases need to be covered and we
need systems and technology to keep us perfectly secure.
And it's the only way like
a significant amount of society security relies upon humans being decent people.
And like this is one of them, it's the only real solution.
But again, this is where I think
things like shaming these people is important because it shows
there are negative consequences for doing things like this.
Right.
Yeah, like, locally, uh, two years ago, yeah, two years ago now
we had somebody who went around
and I guess they think they were using a slingshot or something
and they, like, were firing marbles or whatever at bus stops, you know, which have,
like, the glass panels and breaking them and they did this to, like, 80 bus stops.
Right. That's,
that's a pretty considerable cost,
you know?
And fundamentally, yeah, it's just, it's, it's
just,
yeah, why?
It's just stupid vandalism that has absolutely no upside, I guess,
unless you're the guy making those glass panels and selling them
to the city or to the transit corporation
who
owns those things.
There's some idiotic economic theory called the broken window
and the idea being someone breaks a window, you have to pay to fix the window,
which pays, you know, and there's all this
economic
activity
which actually I think, I think a real economist proved that was nonsense.
But
you,
you do create economic activity but it's wasted.
It's a net negative. Right.
Well, fundamentally, if we wanted to create economic activity,
we would ban bulldozers and make people do use shovels
that would literally solve unemployment overnight. Except
I literally wouldn't be able to afford to build anything anymore
minor details. Uh,
yeah. Well, well, funny enough. No, no, you could afford.
Well, it's complicated because
I,
there's
minimum
wage. Well, it has to be less than that.
So there's this historic house, uh, I went to,
you know, they decorated at Christmas and they've got, like,
their big thing is like Charles Dickens, a Christmas carol and they have people,
like, dressed up in, in character and, and it's fun.
Right. It's neat to go see and that kind of stuff. And I really like it because
it has like, an electricity museum, lab thing.
Hands on type stuff for the kids in the basement because it was
one of the first houses to have electricity back in the day.
Uh It was all DC. It's really fascinating talking to the people
because it was like the power plant was 50 ft away and it was DC driven by the river
and, and yeah, like they, they said that like
the only way they knew if the power was working is the
guy who ran the plant had a light bulb he would look at
and if the light bulb was too dim,
he knew to like turn the power up and if the light bulb was too bright,
you should turn the power down.
And then,
you know, in fairness,
it's not like our IOT monitoring for skater stuff has gotten that much better.
That's true. It's amazing.
Anyway. Anyway, so here's, here's my point though. Right? Is
they,
they were going on and on and talking about how the guy who did
the woodwork in the house and it took him to two years to do,
the woodwork was paid a dollar a day,
which was significantly above the going wage at the time.
And I, I, like, I did the math.
It was like it today, it's something like $15 a day. And I'm like,
-- what, who would work for a day for $15?
-- Well, and especially skilled work.
Like, I've, I've, I've tried doing, like, wood joining
and
the reality is I can't,
it's very hard to do. Well, yes.
Oh,
it's basically impossible because if you're out by even like 1/10 of a millimeter,
you either got a huge gap or the pieces are like sticking out.
Uh, no. What, what you actually do is
so I own an old
house. I do, I do a lot of woodwork. No. No, you don't use wood filler.
You purposely cut things a little large. Well, this is, this is on site.
If you're in the shop, it's easier to do proper measurements.
But like when you're on site you make sure you cut it too big
and you carry a hand planer in a file in your pocket
and then you
constantly adjust as you're fitting it together.
I've done that where I basically cut a piece,
take it back out to the garage and like to shave off half a blade's length.
Take it back in wiggle it. Not quite yet shave off another half blade,
you know, not, not just that I actually, some of the hand tools.
If you have decent hand tools, it's,
you can get away with some impressive quality
and,
and, like, shaving off a little bit
is easy.
I went to buy a shoulder plane because I have to, um,
my parents' cabin is settled a bit so the back door is, like, really sticky.
Uh, basically I got to take like two millimeters off the door at the one end.
Yeah, a proper plane at Lee Valley. It's our sort of local high
end woodwork store. Like, yeah. No, I, I'm not spending 300 bucks on this thing.
You know, you do go buy a belt sander, just buy a cheap belt.
That was Plan
B
Yeah,
I was just gonna,
yeah, because I own a belt
sander. So I was
like,
-- ok, it's gonna be messy but whatever, who
-- cares?
And it's uneven but it's the bottom of the door. So no one cares, like, yeah.
No, I know. I know. I know. But, yeah.
Yeah, that's the thing, these tools and you got to think too back in the day
you had to own these nice tools.
So, I, anyway, anyway, what were we talking about again
in computer security? I think it is
-- just
-- like joining and fixing and,
-- you
-- know,
anyway. No, no,
we, we were talking about the fact that how do we solve a problem like this?
And, and the reality is you can't because we have to exist in a society
with a certain amount of sanity just
period.
And, and this is true of,
of computer security to a degree is the vast majority of people are decent
and honest.
But I think computer security is tricky because you only need like one guy
in,
you know, middle of nowhere ST
or whatever and, and they can attack the whole world.
And in fact, so actually, actually, you know, what this leads into nicely is
there was,
there was some thread on reddit where someone said basically,
I want like a AAA command center view of all of the traffic hitting my router.
And of course, the responses were you have to pay a ton of money to get this and blah,
blah, blah, whatever.
And I thought,
well, no, no, I thought, I bet I could do this with elastic search actually.
And,
and II, I spun up a VM
and funny enough, uh I did in Digital Ocean and they must have been having problems.
It took like five minutes for the VM to get spun up.
So
it took me a total maybe 15 minutes, five of it waiting for the VM.
And basically the VM is only running SSH and I'm done.
Anytime anyone tries to connect to me,
I'm just logging it into elastic search and then I can pull up a map that
updates itself every I can update it every five seconds is the smallest amount of,
of visualization.
But anyway, the point being like
there's crap coming from everywhere which I guess is totally not surprising.
And, and the funny enough, the biggest port right now is the uh Bitcoin test network
because there's real money there.
No, no, just the test network, not, not the real Bitcoin network, the test network.
So I have
an assumption that the IP I have
must have been part of a test net at some point.
So
-- just
-- scanning the entire
because honestly,
you can scan the entire I PV four space for a
port in like 10 to 15 minutes now using something like
uh Z
map or um
what is it M scan?
Oh, I don't even know the name of the tools. I just, I
know
and am scan
and, and yeah, like from literally, well,
I could even do it from home now because I have 100 and 70 megabit up,
you know,
sweet.
It is, it is actually really sweet.
I'm
not a lot.
I don't mean to gloat with everybody else having not as great internet, but no,
really, you do want
it. You want the fastest internet you can afford.
I, yeah, I
have the fastest internet I can buy and it's not that fast.
Makes
-- me
-- sad. That's a very American thing to say.
It is a very American thing to say.
God bless America.
Uh Anyway, anyway,
it is, right.
So I guess thinking about this though is
on one side,
there's civilized society
and not publishing fake advisories
easily falls into that bucket. Right.
And on the other side,
don't be
-- the
-- classic. Don't go out of your way to be a jerk to people.
Yes. That's exactly right. That's exactly what this was.
And, and, but now at the same time,
there's the concept of people all over
the world attacking everything because they can,
and, and there's, you know, botnets and,
and who knows what and they're looking to steal resources and in your Bitcoins and,
and whatever,
and that's where
we need to put our focus on to technology because that
is the place you need technology to solve the problems.
We don't need technology to somehow verify
fake reports coming from random people on the internet.
-- That is a very human problem.
-- Well, I mean, the beauty of a lot of this
is there are really good, simple technical solutions. It's just
they're hard to deploy by default because for example, let's take ssh, for example,
when you spin up a system,
unless you have some sort of orchestration or provisioning thing behind it.
Well, you need to be able to log into it, right?
And so typically sort of the lowest common denominator is of course the password.
Um Now what's nice, for example, uh is for, well,
most cloud providers now when you spin up a system,
you don't set a password, you feed it an SSH key
and let's face it right? Like if your system is only allowing login via SSH keys then,
uh, unless you're, you know,
using one of those Debian generated SSH keys
from back in the day where there were only
64,000 possibilities to open SSL having a bug or not an open sl having a bug story.
But the Debian guys modifying something so that a, like, uh, warning was
stop warning them on something.
The reality is if you're using SSH key based authentication,
an attacker can't get in
unless they like compromise your workstation and steal your key.
Right. Right.
Like that's just it, like it's like two factor authentication with a UB key
unless you can like
somehow.
Well, first of all,
you'd have to trick me into authenticating and then sticking my key in and then,
oh yeah,
the guys that made U two F thought about that
because people like me and everybody make mistakes and we're idiots
that they put the host name in, you know, as part of the authentication thing.
So that even if some Russian dude tricks me,
it's not going to work
end of end of story, right?
You know, and so there, there are these wonderful, you know,
all these people complaining about their web servers being attacked.
Well, yeah,
I hate to say it but you go behind
something like cloud flare or some other protective service
and then you firewall access to your web servers as sort
of far out as you can and only talk to those services
and now the bad guys can't, you know,
talk to them directly,
right. Which solves a whole pile of problems.
It is.
Right. There's, there's really,
there's that, that's how you fix the problem,
you know.
Like, so, yeah, for the, the, for a lot of this technology stuff, we,
we have good solutions.
Um, I remember a friend of my mother,
uh, she bought a laptop
and she didn't have a router at home.
Like she literally just had a cable modem that plugs straight into the laptop,
right?
And she, and this is back like this is about 10 years ago,
she couldn't
essentially when she plugged the laptop in, like it was running Windows XP.
Of course, she couldn't get updates fast enough for it not to get hacked,
right? Because,
you know, back in the day, like, you know,
if you plugged the Windows XP machine and it would be on average,
attacked and compromised in like what five minutes or something,
you know, it is a really low number.
Yeah. And, and so the reality is the solution was, is like, tell her to go buy a $20 wi
fi router
and stick that in between
right there, there is no other solution
I know or take your laptop to a trusted network that won't attack you. But you know,
so let's reframe this discussion now because I feel like
this all makes sense and, and let's think about fishing,
we like to treat fishing as a human problem. And so let's imagine a scale on one side,
spam is a human problem
kind of maybe. And I, I think we get to that.
Uh but I feel like so skyfall is on the purely human problem on,
on the one side of the scale and on the other side of the scale,
you have purely technology problem. And I think SSH keys are a great example of that.
-- And fishing. I feel like, well,
-- it's, it's, it's more so that
you could solve it with humans, but it's basically impossible.
Like you could have everybody choose passwords that have
two K.
No,
no, you can't. That's
never
gonna
happen
like
the reality.
And I think, I think,
well,
no, no,
something important though is
we love to say
you could do this if,
and then if it's some impractical solution of every human picking a good password,
which let's face it
if, if you and I had to pick a password, it would be terrible.
That's why I let my password manager pick my passwords. Right.
So, anyway,
let's think about fishing. Now. Fishing is my favorite whipping boy. Here is
so many people.
I talk to talk about things like, oh,
we need fishing awareness and we need fishing training and let's stop.
And it's like
I have come to the conclusion, fishing is a 100% technical problem.
Yes. And no, there's honestly a lot of fishing can simply be solved with if
it sounds too good to be true. It is.
No, it can't.
What happens when you get a phishing email that looks
like an invoice from the company you just dealt with.
Like, that's not too good to be true. It's the invoice for the crap I just bought.
And sometimes,
in fact, I've even gotten phishing emails that were like,
it was basically the stuff I was looking at.
So these people somehow had insight into like some ad network or something
and they knew the products I was looking for and they sent me an
from a company
for one of the products that in fact I had even bought earlier in
simple example is, you know, we like there's a lot of, you know, uh fishing in uh
for invoices or bank payments and stuff and click like
I constantly about once a week on my phone,
I get a text message saying
your refund from your cell phone company, click this link and you know,
fill out your interact banking details to get the refund.
And that probably works quite a bit in
Canada because we have like six phone companies.
So, you know, if you pick one at random, you're probably gonna get
it,
the one that the person uses, right?
-- Like there's a pretty good chance
-- we have two phone companies. So
yeah,
and so, you know,
part of it is knowing that these guys that's not how they operate.
And part of it is, again, if it's, you know, my,
my phone companies are just not going to randomly give me money,
that's not how phone companies work,
you know?
Right. Like, I remember when I
did have to get my $20 back from them because I, I overpaid my final bill and, you know,
like when I canceled my account
and getting that 20 bucks out of them took three months.
And at that point, it just became a matter of principle.
You spent $200 worth of time
to get $20.
Yeah.
So II I agree on the one to me, fishing is,
I think part of the problem is people conflate fishing as being a separate,
completely unique problem. It's not, it's spam.
Look at spam.
Spam is trying to trick people into doing silly things. That's what fishing is,
is
way more sophisticated.
I
think there's
a range of attacks with even fishing though.
And even spam is if we can put them all in the same bucket is, is some of it is as simple as
I just want to trick you into looking at my product
and you have things that are like, I'm going to literally steal money from you and,
and like, let's face it.
That's,
that, that's basically unquestionably crime and fraud
and no problem there. But then you kind of, you can end up with things in the middle of,
I'm gonna trick you into giving me a password.
Right.
And like that kind of
in
to be the head of the CIA that 15 year old from Britain.
Yeah. Right.
Right. Right.
And, like, seriously he called up the
help desk apparently and pretended to be the director
of the CIA to get access to a system.
Like,
that's not a fishing problem. That's somebody at the help desk didn't.
I? Well, no, I can't say I'm hoping that they have some sort of strong
method internally for verifying identity before you're like, ok, Mr CIA director,
I'm going to give you remote access to your desktop.
They do now
well, or they enforce it, right?
But here's ok.
So this one I'm really sensitive to actually because I know
some pen testers and it's great because the stories they tell
is like anytime they attack a corporation,
they just call up a secretary and they're like, I'm the VP of blah, blah, blah.
I need you to give me this right now, you know, right now.
And they,
they keep getting more and more agitated
when the secretary isn't cooperating and like,
let's face it.
That's an attack on humans and you can't stop that.
Right. Well, not just that, like if you're worried, you're going to get fired.
If you don't help someone, you're gonna help them. I mean, it's, it
is part of the human condition and that we can't fix with technology necessarily,
right?
But
like,
maybe not so much technology but process. Like if
uh like this is a great example.
Uh in Edmonton University was defrauded of
$11.8 million after staff failed to call one
of its vendors to verify whether emails requesting
a change in banking information were legitimate.
So they had a process in place
saying like when a vendor emails you to change their
banking details to be like and it was stupid.
It was like a bank in
hung. It was, it was like, totally not at all what it used to be, right?
And you know, they, they sent $11.8 million to some random bank account.
I when you hear stories of that,
even where people send emails as the CEO to
finance saying I need you to pay this invoice.
Don't ask any questions.
-- You
-- know, I see that all the time with the cloud security alliance is like
uh because you know,
the name of the CEO of the cloud security alliance is
pretty obvious because it's like on one of the web pages,
you know,
the list of people who run this thing
and they'll be like so like some wonky at gmail.com address and it's kind of like,
yeah,
no,
right. Like,
you know,
and we will hit the report button or the spam button or whatever and but you know,
and there's, we're not going to track this down and like beat them with a stick.
-- It's just not worth it.
-- No, it's totally not.
And like, like that is a place process can fix things, right of,
of saying before you pay an invoice, like maybe double check with the CEO, right?
That's not hard to do. That's pretty easy. Call him on the phone.
Say, hey, did you send me this email?
And then I feel like there's the other side of things where let's say you
get a phishing email that's trying to get you to type your password in.
This is sort of things like two factor off
are huge because like two factor off and U
two F basically neuter these type of attacks.
They, they, I mean, yes, someone could get your password,
but without the other half of your password,
it really doesn't matter.
And
even if they manage to suck down your U two F, let's say, for example,
somebody actually manages to execute a man in the middle
attack against my Gmail account using U two F.
They now have access to that session.
Uh They,
they can't,
-- but
-- hypothetically they now have access to that session.
And Google just did a uh a slide deck where they talk about
how they detect
break ins of accounts because there's patterns of usage that are very abnormal,
right?
Like my pattern of usage of my Gmail account basically consists of log in
read email, archive, email, reply to some email,
log out,
right?
And maybe once in a while, change a setting or an out of office setting or whatever.
But the attacker one apparently pretty much consists of log in,
uh, reset, sort of the like phone number and, or backup email, you know,
for warnings,
uh, change the password, you know,
rifle through all your stuff looking for like anything to do with Bitcoin or,
you know,
other sort of electronic shenanigans where you can
actually extract money from the person quickly.
Uh, and then either delete a big pile of stuff or,
you know,
email everybody in your contact book that you're stuck in
Russia and need them to send you 50 bucks,
right?
And, and they can basically
quite like, let's face it.
What are the chances of a legitimate account owner doing that
very low
and more to the point if they do want to change their backup information,
you just poke them again for,
you know, the out of band authentication or the two fa or whatever.
-- And, you
-- know, now that you say this, there have been times I've used
in gmail comes to mind.
I, I imagine, I, I need to start paying closer attention to this now, but
I know I've been like on the road
and
I'll, I'll kind of log in from a weird place and, yeah, the Google says, you know,
you know, you've got to log in again.
I don't, I don't know who you are.
Yeah,
I get it, man. Well, not even just IP because I mean, I do a certain amount of travel but
c if I'm doing certain travels and, and I do certain things, it, it,
now that I'm thinking of it, it definitely makes a difference
depending upon like what I'm searching for and the kind of email
and that's a perfect example of kind of where,
you know, I hate to say this, but part of the frustration is
security solutions that depend on everybody doing the right thing
will always fail straight up.
So security solutions that are more centralized. I,
I think in some ways stand a better chance, right? Like
uh I mean, well, my,
a great example is, you know, my most of my Linux systems,
I get all my packages from the vendor.
Like Red Hat is a great example.
Pretty much everything living on my Red Hat systems all comes from Red Hat.
I actually don't think I have anything weird on them anymore.
And so I just run yum update or DNF update
and that's it.
I don't, you know, whereas I just, oh God, I just turned on the windows, 10 laptop.
It hasn't been on for three months.
Oh,
sweet God.
Uh Anyways, two days later, I had everything updated, including itunes Steam.
Oh, no, I haven't updated Steam. I still have to do that.
You have like a two gazillion bit link to the internet now.
-- Yeah. But
-- more to the point I have to like
the number of reboots to get windows updated.
Right. Like it's at least it was two or three updates
that required reboots because it installed a pile of updates and then it rebooted.
And then,
and I don't think it has the meltdown update. I don't know yet. I, I need to,
I don't even care at this point.
I hate that thing.
Well, no, because,
and then the best part is because I knew my partner
was going to need to use this laptop this week.
And if she turned it on and then, you know,
couldn't use it for like three hours because
it's trying to reboot and install updates.
She's going to throw it out the window and I don't blame her,
you know,
so I, I proactively turn this thing on.
I was trying to get it all updated, you know, in itunes and Windows defender,
Windows updates.
I still got update. Steam. I still got a
VLC, you know, and, and so anyways,
it's just basically impossible to keep that machine up to date because
for sure there's something I installed on there that's not updated.
Uh
You know, there is
totally man.
Well, and something important too. Oh, and then I removed Java.
I don't know why it had Java installed.
Why not?
Why
not? Oh God. So
everything
needs Java
because I don't want whatever their default search
engine is to be my new search engine.
When I do an update,
I don't pay
attention
to
it.
Funny. Enough. I think chrome kind of remove their ability to do that.
So it's,
it will, in fact, now, when I update Java,
because actually elastic search is written in Java.
So I use Java quite a lot now.
But anyway,
every time
-- I'm
-- not
-- opposed to Java, I'm just opposed to Java being hooked up to my web
-- browser.
-- I agree completely in effect.
Now,
it kind of politely asks you to enable Java in your web
browser and when you're done upgrading it and then I'm like,
nope,
no
way.
Yeah. Well, it's like flash,
I disable flash in my web browsers.
Even though it's a chrome flash which is reasonably secure,
you don't need it.
I, I have flash set on, like, click to activate or whatever it's called
and
it is so rare.
I even see that and, and 99% of the time if click to activate flash, it shows up.
I just close the tab
-- because
-- I don't know, I find it's just wonky new sites with video players.
Yeah. Right. Yeah, it's, it's dodgy sites at this point. I mean,
that's all it
is.
There was somebody I was somewhere that I
was actually surprised they hadn't fixed themselves yet
that, that I felt like it was a legitimate site
that should not have had flash,
but I can't remember for the life of me what it was.
Well, yeah, it's
one day we'll get rid of flash. Maybe
never.
It'll never die
-- anyway.
-- But going back to this, I mean, any security problem that generally, like,
like crossing the street safely depends on all the drivers watching.
And, I mean, there's,
there's a couple of crosswalks here on the west end of Edmonton,
like the one on stony plane over by 160 whatever.
Uh, people blow through that all the time when there's, like,
people crossing on the street
because they're just not paying attention or whatever.
I don't know what it is about that stretch of road. But, like,
yeah, I've seen so many people blow through and almost hit pedestrians.
I, I, well, I know what the solution to this is.
It's, you know, self driving cars with computers that don't get bored,
uh, and try and run over people, you know, unless a hacker makes them do it.
Right. Right. And
I feel like
there are
very few security problems that legitimately need humans to solve them
because humans are unpredictable and terrible at solving problems like this.
Well, the other thing I always get is whenever somebody's like, oh, I want to have,
like, this dashboard and monitor what's going on on my network.
I'm like, great. What are you actually going to do with that?
And they're like, what do you mean?
I'm like, so you're gonna see all these attacks coming in?
What are you going to do about? It? Looks cool, man.
Yeah. And more to the point.
So who's going to monitor it when you go to sleep or the bathroom.
It looks cool. I didn't do it because it was useful.
I just did it because it looks cool. Like I'm not even going to pretend
like,
unless there's something actionable you can do then, ok,
logging it is kind of useful.
And that maybe if there is an attack you can figure
out how bad it was or how deep they got in.
This doesn't really apply to home networks.
And number two, because the answer is they, they did everything.
And then number two is, you know,
if you're actually going to be monitoring this and doing actionable stuff with it,
if you don't automate it,
that means you need at least four or five human
beings because there's 100 and 68 hours in the week.
And,
you know, people working 40
hours,
four people, you can't,
humans can't look at logs anymore.
Like, even if you're not doing anything interesting,
the volume of your logs will be so huge.
A human cannot look at them
and
they can look at it with a system of tools to find, you know, like that.
Did you see that cloud flare blog entry on looking at their core dumps?
Yeah. And did you see how few they get?
-- Well, exactly. Yeah. Well, after they fixed a bunch of stuff,
-- right.
But, but I mean, that's a great example of
if they were getting say
300 core dumps a day,
they wouldn't let humans look at them, they would build tooling to figure it out.
But because it was like, less than 20 a week
they could have and let's face it.
My guess is there's a huge overlap in those core dumps.
And so my suspicion is it was a small enough number.
They could justify just letting a person look at
it. And that's kind of logging has reached the point where humans need not apply.
Just
you cannot deal with it.
You have to have automation and,
and I think more and more of our security problems are,
are becoming this.
But I also
feel
it's simply the law of larger like my SSH connections,
the number of SSH connections I get on an IP address.
I don't even know anymore. I'm guessing hundreds or thousands a
day. I don't know. I don't care. I just have
key based off. That's it.
So I ignore the problem,
you know, same thing with spam.
I,
I check my spam folder like maybe once every month or two
on the
off.
-- So
-- I just, I just pulled it up. This is,
this is one of the cool things I love like uh so my machine
that literally like this is a VM that I started
and I'm running something called uh packet beat on it,
which is just looking at incoming traffic.
I have never
actually connected out to anywhere from this machine, right?
It's just, it is a random IP, the only thing running on it is ssh.
And in the last 24 hours, I've had 3000, 173 connection attempts.
Obviously,
none of them are me because I'm not even logged into the machine right now.
So like that, that gives you an idea of in, in effect I 20
four seconds.
That's one every 30 seconds, a
-- significant
-- amount of it came.
It looks like at 9 a.m. this morning for me where I have a huge spike.
And so obviously someone was trying to hack my server with, with SSH attempts.
Right? Like, that's what that is.
Yeah,
it
works.
There's a
lot of default
-- passwords and stuff on things,
-- not on this machine.
Well, that, that's a part of it too. Right. I'm like, I can't,
and part of me wants to, like,
I'm wondering if I turned off SSH
O
or, I mean, key off if,
if the number of attempts I would see would go up dramatically because like,
when someone connects,
you
know,
well, well, they're shotgunning but if you connect, you know, I only allow keys.
Right?
You can figure that out.
That's true.
Yeah.
But anyway, yeah, 3000 just on one port on a, like,
completely insignificant machine.
I'm, I'm confident that I could not parse
those logs by myself and that's not even like a real company doing real things.
Right?
And, and I guess so you say what is the point of having the dashboard.
This is the point. So in the podcast, I can answer your question in 10 seconds,
you know.
So I did read back in the day
one really good reason for having an intrusion detection system.
Now note I'm not saying intrusion detection or intrusion prevention system,
I'm talking strictly about an I DS that
is effectively a dashboard for network attacks.
And the guy pointed out that the, there's one valid reason to have it.
And that is you put one in front of your network and you
put one behind your firewall and all the other stuff protecting your network.
And then you show executives the delta between the reports
and you say this is why we're spending all this
money on these fancy firewalls and all this other stuff.
Definitely.
And that, and I'm literally like, I'm like, literally,
yes, that makes sense because otherwise, like
I get ID P like actively blocking and dealing with tax. That makes sense.
But just like randomly showing you a dashboard of how bad it is.
Yeah, literally unless it's for the executive so you can justify your budget.
I don't see the
point.
No, I agree with you completely. But, but it does look cool and, and I mean,
for
real,
and it's fun seeing real time.
Although the one other thing that I think could be really interesting
is if you have a real time dashboard,
you will like,
it'll light up if someone is starting a legitimate attack against you.
But again,
like if you have automation it's going to see it
probably more than 20 seconds faster than a human.
Right. Which is
so there's still no excuse to not have automation.
Well, and more to the point you still have to react to it and do something.
Yep. Yep.
That's what always gets me is you have to actionable. Something has to happen
-- otherwise it's, it's pointless. Yep.
-- Yep. No, I get it. Wow. I've got
2000 hits on port 23.
But this is, this is crazy and I don't know why this would be
but port 21
20 no, 23 is FTP, right? 23.
-- 21 is FTP.
-- 2121 has 38 hits in the last 24 hours, which is
OK.
I remember when
I remember literally the day of the month or whatever it was the point at which
officially web traffic overtook FTP traffic on the
internet and this was a long time ago.
But I mean FTP used to be, well, if you wanted to move.
Uh
Actually
it's funny. I remember, do you remember Archie for searching FDP,
man?
I remember searching for all kinds of stuff with Archie
because like there was no other way to find.
I only ever used Archie.
I was, I don't know why I feel like Archie worked better for me. So I used Archie
anyway, whatever. Like the young people. Like, what are these guys talking about?
What is
it
that
annoying thing
-- for mainframes? Right.
-- Look it up, look it up. You'll figure it out.
Uh, anyway, anyway. All right, man.
Uh, let's call it any, any closing thoughts on human security,
I guess. Remember our threat model to, you know, quote Bruce
Schneier,
our threat model evolved in the African Savannah and
it doesn't deal so good with the modern world.
Uh,
that, that seems fair and, and my advice would be, uh,
you're bad at security and you should feel bad.
So, there we go.
You're right. Are you talking about me specifically or the world in general? I mean,
both
are true
humans. You, you're in the Venn diagram of all humans. So yes, it applies to you.
So I would agree with that.
So, anyway. All right, man. Thank you. Thanks everybody for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com to check out the show note.
Uh You can find the Pound Os S podcast hashtag on Twitter.
You can join our Facebook group and say hi and chat with us. Let us know what you think
and you have nothing else. Kurt have a great rest of your day.
You too have a good week, folks.
The