Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and I think we're on an almost episode coming up on 400 this year, Josh
-- Reser. I mean,
-- we'll hit 400. I think what I just published 386 or 87.
-- Yeah. So
-- like November
-- ish, I think
-- 20 ish to go.
Who cares? We're, we're monkeys with 10 fingers. It doesn't matter.
It's a sustained effort.
I mean,
-- how many podcasts make it past 10 episodes?
-- Probably not many.
I think I read once that I think 50 is the magic number where like 1% make it to 50.
I would be shocked. It's as high as 1%.
It, I don't know. I don't know.
It's been a long time since I've looked at podcast stats.
That's one of the beauties of not caring
because you don't have to look up data,
which is exactly our topic for today is that sustained effort is different
than a one off.
It's true. It's true.
So, there's been a whole kerfuffle with, uh, Red Hat Linux and, uh, what Alma Linux,
Rocky Linux
or Oracle made a bunch of angry noises.
Susan actually said something intelligent, which is, you know,
we're going to devote $10 million to building like a proper clone.
So you can just come by
stuff which is still like, $10 million isn't enough
ignoring that. What better way to say, we think our actual product is crap.
So we're going to clone someone else's like, just,
I don't even know how to respond to that anyway. Keep
going.
So, uh, there,
so people are beginning to sort of realize,
well,
I don't think they're beginning to realize that's why
we're doing the show to maybe help educate them.
But
so, OK, the long and the short of it is there was a security flaw in I
proof and it's not all that serious.
So it was kind of fixed upstream
like upstream and I
proof, I mean,
and then of course, people are like, why doesn't you know,
uh
Red Hat, what is it called? Red Hat stream sent to us stream. I forget the name of it,
whatever the stream thing.
Like,
why don't you just fix it? And they're like, well, because it's kind of not that bad.
And he's like, but we've developed a patch and merged it like we've done all the work.
And I remember reading that and I started laughing like, I, I'm sorry,
I just started laughing
and Josh is laughing because you and I both know that, that,
that is literally step seven of like 100 and 64 steps
when you do enterprise
source
Cody security update things. Right.
So, without getting into the
details and the weeds,
having a source code patch is literally like step number seven. number one.
Well, before that,
you even need to figure out what the problem actually
is because we've had a lot of people say,
oh, I found a security problem.
Here's a patch and we're like,
we dig in a bit and we're like, oh, no, it's a lot worse than that or
more complicated or whatever.
Yeah.
And I mean, competent people, like, like the, the whole, uh, Kuala stack card thing,
right?
They were like, oh, we came up with a one megabyte stack card page. It'll be fine.
Right? I have a better example than that because you talk about it too much.
And so I'm not gonna let you tell your story again.
I remember there was one time,
one of the open source security groups got a bug report for Fuzzed true type fonts.
And there were
a lot, a lot of reproducers, right?
And I went through a whole bunch of them
and I created a bunch of patches and then I went to upstream.
I was like, here's a bunch of reproducers. Here's a bunch of patches that fix these.
Like, how do we, how do, let's work on this and get it fixed?
They're like, oh, all of these are one unchecked integer overflow.
Like way up here because I didn't know the code
that well. So I didn't understand what the path was
but the authors looked and they're like, oh, yeah,
everything is this one thing right here.
So it was literally one
line patch to fix what I thought was like, 20 bucks.
Exactly.
And it's fascinating when that happens.
Well, and I've seen that happen with a lot of web apps where, like,
I found 100 and 67 crossfit scripting injections and it's like,
oh, yeah, we forgot to escape HTML in this one spot
for sure.
And so like things like that. But then also does your patch break anything.
The thing,
I think a lot of people forget
is Red Hat has contracts where they have said
we guarantee
A B I compatibility
for 13 years.
And as an open source project, you can be like, oh, oops, t he, we broke it a little bit.
We'll fix it on Thursday.
And everybody's kind of like, oh, it happens.
But when you sign contracts in some cases, north of seven figures,
there's no giggling in t he, it's like our lawyers will be contacting you.
-- Uh
-- Right. Right. Exactly. And I think
so, this is an interesting point you bring up because
there are enterprise companies that do open source things.
And Red Hat is an obvious example, Google does this oracle, does this,
all of the big companies do this, Amazon, whatever, all of them.
And then there's open source, which is people like us doing
whatever random thing. And if I,
if I completely break my project,
whatever, it's probably fine.
I mean, pretty much every open
source software license has some version of like if this breaks too bad
in it.
Yeah,
if it works. Is it all useful? Hey, good for you.
But we don't make any guarantees about that.
But the problem is when you start selling open source,
well, that's kind of why people are paying you money for it is to get guarantees.
I have a second angle to this that often annoys me and, and just really grinds my gears
is I think you see some of these companies
pretending
that their enterprise thing
is an open source project when it's not. And so I think there's two angles to this.
There's the angle of
I am an enterprise trying to run a real open source project,
but I also have to keep my enterprise hat on.
And then there's the we are an enterprise company
pretending
our product is open source because then it lets us do certain marketing things
in public that you can't necessarily do
with a truly closed source enterprise product.
Yeah.
Yeah, like that whole uh a lot of companies doing the open core model,
like
there's also a big difference between companies like Red Hat.
I I think part of it is just simple,
what percent are they building in house versus bringing from outside?
And I don't mean just as a dependency chain but like where Red
Hat is importing things wholesale and turning them into an enterprise product.
And also the scale issue because there's a big difference
between having a product or two open source products.
And Red Hat, which like when I left there was over 100 and 20.
Sure. Ok. I feel like we're all over the place on this topic.
So we need to tighten it up.
Problem is that this is, it's a,
what I'm trying to get across is it's a
fundamentally different issue of scale of sustained effort.
Like, like I was saying to you earlier, I can do one push up. Cool.
Now, can you do one push up an hour
for the rest of your life? Because that's what Red Hat is doing.
They're doing that consistent effort.
Like it just came out with the, uh, alpine limits, right? They're, they're
the person who does the most packages and commits
has decided to step down and leave.
And I, and I quote, they said they're going to catch up on a year's worth of sleep,
-- like, more than a year. Yeah.
-- Thank you for the effort. And I, yeah. Wow. Like,
and the problem is
who,
unless somebody is insane enough to take over
that level of effort for basically free,
I don't think
this is
stuff like Red Hat.
Ok.
Hold on, hold on. There's
a couple of pieces to this and I want to break them apart. So, first of all,
I think alpine is probably going to be fine.
A lot of people are picking up these packages. I think it is easy for people to say
an open source project with one primary contributor is a bad thing.
I don't think that's the case.
I think the measure isn't how many contributors you have. It's when a contributor
ends up on
something happening that they can't necessarily do
the work that there are other people
willing and able to pick up the slack.
And I think in alpine we're going to see other people pick up the slack.
And so that is really important.
And I, I, in no way, want anyone to use this to construe that alpine is in trouble
maybe someday. But I, not yet.
Well, and the challenge too is not just pick up the slack but carry it
long term.
And that's what a lot of people forget is like,
every time one of these projects has a problem, they're like, oh,
I'll step up and help
and they're happy to put in a few hours of effort.
-- But it's like, no, no, we need like four hours of effort a month
-- for forever until,
until time ends.
Right.
Ok.
And that is
something redhead has always done a good job of, yeah,
-- because they have money to pay people to do the, um,
-- yes.
Now,
here's the other piece of this that I think is vastly
more interesting and this is the kind of open source versus
enterprise open source discussion
and this is where I want to steer the boat.
So there is what we call open source.
And this is software with an open source license.
The,
the technical definition of open source is just a
piece of software that carries an O SI license.
That could be something you and I do. It's stuff Microsoft is published on github.
There's
many, many things when we think of open source though,
I think we generally think of this community of people building stuff,
right? And it's never done in a silo. It everything has to interact with each other.
Like the Debian Linux distribution or the
Alpine Linux distribution are great examples.
These are communities of people that have come
together to build something big and amazing right
now, when we think of enterprise open source,
this is where you have like a company paying someone to do some work.
This is where like,
and I'm not just saying it has to live under the company's umbrella.
Like Red Hat pays people to work on x.org,
right?
That is their job.
It is why x.org works on a lot of hardware is because of these people,
if Red Hat stopped paying them,
they would stop. Well, some of them would keep doing it.
But the the amount of time they get to spend on it would
definitely decrease drastically as they have to do things to feed themselves,
for example.
Right.
And I think
that is where
we sometimes forget what is going on.
I think
when we're talking about like regular open source, like random people,
this is where we get back to that open source owes you nothing conversation.
Right. Like you can't expect random people to do your bidding.
They don't want to, they don't have to, it doesn't matter.
But now if we have open source from someone like Red Hat
where they're paying people to actually
do this stuff that changes the conversation
because now
you can say person I'm paying, I really want you to add this feature
and you know what?
They're probably gonna listen.
Well, and I mean, that goes to this whole low, moderate, high
urgent security bug thing where,
yeah, we're not gonna fix lows and moderates quickly because
it costs tens to hundreds of thousands of dollars to
-- fix a security flaw and
-- every patch carries risk,
right?
Like,
and some are lower risk like fixing a pro
scripting flos or whatever. But some like heartbleed. Was it heartbleed?
That had the 30% performance CPU hit?
Uh No, it wasn't heartbleed. It was one of the,
one of the, the CPU bugs. I forget which one,
whatever the point is, you can't ship a patch that hammers 30% performance. Like
there's change, fatigue and change management fatigue.
Red
Hat can't
ship a security update every day for a package.
You kind of want to bundle them and patch
them like an extreme example would be Microsoft Tuesday.
Microsoft discovered that the industry is like, you know what, once a month is good,
maybe an emergency one once in a while,
but
-- once a month is good.
-- That's right. I mean, I remember when
Red Hat,
we tried to like cash things up and only release them at certain times.
And it's funny because you, you have both sides of this,
this scale where you would have people saying you're releasing updates too often.
I hate this
and, and then so we're like, ok,
we're going to batch them up and maybe every
other week we push all of our security updates.
Then you have people that,
oh my goodness.
I want these security updates right now. Like why are you waiting to give them to me?
-- And
-- this speaks to Redhead has many different
customers with many different capabilities and maturity levels.
Some and some just
can't. Like if you're running an oil refinery,
you can't just
update the computers,
you know, whenever and just reboot up, it'll be
-- fine.
-- It's probably fine. It's just a refinery
anyway. Ok, we're off track, we're off topic, we're off topic.
But I think the thing people forget is enterprise
software
doesn't have one cohesive set of customers with one
-- cohesive set of capabilities and wants and needs
-- and,
and open source
is exactly the same thing
you say open source
and depending upon who you say it to.
Some people might think of like people in their basement,
some people might think of Debbie and her alpine.
Some people might think of Google Chrome
and they are all technically open source.
Well, Google Chrome isn't chromium is, but they are technically open source,
but they functionally are not
right
because you, you have this huge collection of everything and they're all different
and not just different, different, but like wildly different cultures
and expectations.
So
the problem is,
I mean,
to write even a basic primer that explains all this would be
-- 3040 pages long and nobody would want to read it
-- 30 way,
way more than that.
Like,
it's funny because I'm going through the same thing with A I usage policy
and a lot of people are struggling in their head to be like,
well, is this for just business?
And I'm like, well,
no, it's for business, for schools, for academia, for people, for small companies,
big companies, government.
And they're like, well, what do we recommend? I'm like, oh my God.
Well, it like, it's different for each one of them,
right? It's wildly different.
And so part of the challenge is, is I can't actually necessarily tell you what
they should like what you should be doing,
but I can maybe offer you some options with some what we think the,
the upsides and downsides are
and tying that back into this conversation.
Like even if you have the capability to rapidly patch,
you might not want to because it might introduce more risk and cost than it's worth.
I mean, maybe depending on how you use it. Right. And so
even, even if you have this high level of maturity and the ability to do something
just because a business can do something doesn't mean it does.
Right.
-- Right. Right.
-- For sure. You know, and people forget these things.
So I think part of the challenge is
to put it bluntly, a lot of the people that work in open source, like
at scale on the enterprise and
they're not like talking about it on hacker news constantly or posting
blogs because,
well, when they try to post a blog, it has to go through legal first.
No. Like we, we had this at Red Hat, right.
We'd write stuff and it would have to go through legal and that's
like a fortune 500 is not going to let their co just randomly
spell
whatever's on the, at the front of their head
without it going through legal.
Because, you know,
we've seen what happens when people start doing that and it's just like,
-- oh, you
-- know what my favorite thing ever still is,
is one time I was writing something at Red Hat and I sent it to the legal team
and they,
they said we have to get rid of this paragraph
because it makes it sound like we're offering advice.
And I was like, the literal point of this blog post is advice and like, oh, never mind.
Then it's fine. I'm like, what, like, what just happened?
Like, whatever I know
what to
say it's published. I don't care anymore.
So,
yeah,
like, and that's the thing is there's, there's,
then there's all the competing business constraints and there's all these,
there's,
there's just shipping a patch that fixes the security problem is a very localized
maximum solution because it ignores a lot of other stuff
because it,
it can in the small open source universe where it's if like if someone like me,
I have a multitude of open source projects in my
github
name space
and most of them are abandoned because I like do a clever
thing I want to do and then I never do it again.
But
I have things that are, we'll say slightly longer lived.
And if I submit a patch to that or if I accept a pull request or something,
it's basically zero real effort for me, right? The cost is very minimal.
But now
when a an enterprise is going to submit a accept a pull request to their enterprise
github repo
and you see this all the time where like people submit things to Chromium
or whatever and then there's a lot of back and forth or to go
lang or Python or, or some of these bigger things and like Python's not enterprise,
right? That one is owned by a foundation but it still follows.
-- I think some of the enterprise rules,
-- well,
it's not that they follow enterprise rules per se.
It's, I think that they're aware of, oh, if we do this
-- local maximum solution it has these downsides. Right. Yeah,
-- that's true.
Because, like, if you read the Python has their pep,
I forget what the PEP stands for now.
-- Python enhancement proposal. Is it?
-- Ok?
But they, like, they have amazing discussions about what they want to do.
And it's a similar thing, right? Where
any decision they make any change they accept can have wide ranging consequences.
And more importantly,
they like test the crap out of their stuff. So that testing isn't free, right?
It costs money. I don't test my stuff because I don't care
but they're different,
not just the testing but making tests that are comprehensive.
And
the thing is like there's always 2nd, 3rd and 4th order impacts for doing something
a lot of the time. They don't really matter all that much.
So whatever, you know, just like fixing an html,
special care is missing in a PHP app is almost never going to have much of an impact.
But when you start
fiddling with stuff like Python,
which a
-- lot of the world runs on. I mean,
-- all of the programming languages work like this.
We're picking on Python, but literally if you go to go
or
rust or anything, it's the same story. Yeah.
I love when you see somebody make a proposal, like for c like,
let's add this thing to make it memory safe and everybody's like,
where do we even begin to explain how that breaks? Don't
touch anything?
Like,
like this Python Gull thing blows my
mind that they're even seriously considering the possibility
of talking about changing the color of the report cover to discuss a subcomittee.
-- No, the
-- gill
has to go.
But I mean,
but the fact that they're actually doing it is amazing
for no one knows there are people who don't know what they mean. So in Python
there is
what is Gill Stand for?
It's a global Lock, global interpreter lock, global interpreter lock, right?
And so even though Python has like multi threating libraries and things like that,
there's still functionally
a, a
global locking system
that when variables are what is being written to, I think it, it locks every thread
and it stops them
-- so
-- well. No. Yeah, it's more complicated.
Basically, it's, it's running one thing at a time in about 100
what is it? 100 tick increments
and when something goes to the network or goes to sleep, it releases the Gill,
which means you can actually do some very clever stuff.
Like I had some code I wrote
where it wasn't multi threaded,
but it didn't have to be multi threaded because it was doing a pile of DNS lookups.
And so I basically abused that the Gill exists by doing AAA
lot of DNS lookups in various threads and I didn't have to do any
thread management because they would essentially spend 99% of time out of Gill.
-- Like waiting for network replies.
-- The point is the Gill
is definitely something that affects the performance of Python.
It's so core and fundamental to the
way the language
culture works.
Like not even the technical working of the language, but just the culture around it.
And like, like I said,
I have written code that specifically takes advantage of the Gill behavior to,
to be very quick and efficient,
but regardless Gill has to go.
Right.
Oh, I agree. But I'm just saying like this is so foundational.
It's not even a technical foundation, it's a cultural foundation. It's
-- alright
-- that, that's some nonsense you're making up now.
Well, but the point is this is the,
this is the part of the difference between enterprise and open sources.
Enterprise has a different culture and different foundational.
This is open source now. It's not a difference.
But there is because the people using Red Hat enterprise, Linux
pay Red Hat
to take on that view to take on that.
What about the people running Python who don't
want Python to explode every other release,
which it kind of does.
But
right.
And they could pay Red Hat to keep back porting fixes to Python 3.10 or whatever.
No, no, that's not true at all because
I think if you look at, especially something like Python,
they have been
pretty consistent where you can run what they deliver
and not get it from Red Hat. Now,
I, I think
maybe a couple decades ago you wouldn't have been willing to take that bet.
But I think today a
lot of these like language ecosystems like N PM is a great example. Right?
No one's paying Red Hat to maintain N PM packages. You just YOLO that
-- and it kind of works.
-- That's something that has changed.
Like traditionally we had for a good example. This was post Chris SQL.
They were the poster child for good mature stable,
like it works
like it's good
and you know,
and even they're talking about getting rid of that or they
did get rid of vacuum basically and huge performance enhancements and operational
improvements.
But,
and maybe that's part of what's also happening is
open source is maturing because it has to be because
like we're using it for real work now to run the world.
I mean, right. It's not just the world running some random person's blog website.
It it's ebay, it's Google, it's,
it's all the websites, everyone,
everyone and everything
and, but the problem is it's still you can't.
And maybe that's part of the challenge is that some of the
culture and some of the community hasn't caught up and probably
never will because they don't have to care about it.
They don't want to care about it and if it blows up too bad don't use it.
Yeah. Well, because open source isn't one thing.
I mean, I think we, we, we do this,
everyone does this where I think the world often
forgets that open source is this huge cornucopia of everything
and some of it is enterprises and they're gonna act
like enterprises and that doesn't make it less open source.
-- I mean, it makes it maybe less community focused but,
-- well,
there's not even an agreement on what defines an open source license.
Like, you know, a lot of people,
no, there's an agreement.
It's what the O SI says is an open source license which I don't like. But,
and a lot of people disagree with that.
-- Look,
-- you can disagree with that, but legally speaking,
the open source trademark is quite clear on this matter, like
I don't like it, but that is the technical legal definition.
The thing is that you don't need to use that
to
do open source.
I mean,
you can just go do reasonably or less or more open source or public domain even.
But, um, I think
the challenge is a lot of this stuff,
especially in the enterprise world kind of happens behind closed doors.
It,
there's boring conversations between boring companies that
don't post the things to hacker news.
Boring is good.
Yeah.
And I think a lot of people forget this and,
or they're not even aware of it because reading some of what people have proposed,
it's like you've really never had to keep a system up and
-- running 24 7 because it's doing something important to have
-- you.
It's funny you bring this up because I
had this discussion with someone literally yesterday,
we're recording this on a Monday.
It was over the weekend
and
it is common for us to forget
that
the boring stuff is like what keeps the lights on and keeps society
functioning and that's not the stuff that gets accepted to conference talks.
It's not the stuff that ends up on the front page of hacker news or,
or whatever site we're using now to,
to view news. You know what I mean?
And I think that's one of the things we often forget about is
we live in this environment that's just trying to sensationalize literally
everything and everything doesn't have to be sensational or exciting.
Like it's ok to be a little bit on the boring side.
Well, you know, when I, whenever I look at the skater world,
yeah.
Oh, wait, now we finally have a dashboard and we can see the status of the,
the system or the plant
or, you know, I know somebody that built the dashboard for, um, a large
oil producer. And when I say large oil producer, they're the ones
that basically they have an income equivalent to a large nation state
and they wanted,
they basically now have a dashboard where they can
see the state of all their offshore oil rigs,
which is,
it's a lot.
I mean, that's pretty cool and having that situational awareness. I know. Yeah,
you're like,
you can't just go monkeying with that and start patching it
like it needs to work,
even though it's not a safety critical or even it's
just literally for the executive to see what's going on,
you can't break it
well, and, and
again, this comes to your 2nd and 3rd order effects. What if,
what if an attacker uses your dashboard to then get to the oil rig to that?
You know what I mean? Like,
there's so many other pieces to all of this that you often don't even think about.
But again,
this is where if you're a large company,
you have groups of people thinking about this stuff.
So the person building the dashboard isn't the security team
thinking about how are we making sure that our,
our offshore oil platforms aren't targets of malicious activity?
Yeah, I mean, by definition, to start specializing into security,
you need a group of at least 10 or 20 people probably.
And a lot of open source projects are not
anywhere. Well, they're in the single digits and that's fine.
Look, most development teams
will never reach that point either. And that's ok.
It's,
and that's why people pay Red Hat is. So that Red Hat internally has that. Right.
Right. For sure,
for sure. It's it's why you work with a lot of vendors
because the reality is I mean, this is Tomaz, I am not a supplier, right? Like
you can't make demands of a supplier.
But now if my supplier
is an enterprise
that has an open source project,
I can make demands on that project, right?
Well, and not even that you can make demands,
you can negotiate with them and say basically like I want X, what do you need for
X to be accomplished? And
quite often and the answer is like the pile of money needs to be this high.
Right? No, but that's, and that's how things get done
and it's
fine,
you
know, and a lot of, there's not a lot, I don't know,
but there's a bunch of open source developers that have said similar things like,
oh, you want a
fine hire me as a consultant
and it amuses me when people become offended by that because it's like
if you are working with a company, if you have a vendor,
if you asked me to mow your lawn, I would want money.
Why is software? Why is putting my effort into running software any different?
That's a good analogy. I'm gonna steal that one, I think. But yeah, for real.
-- No,
-- like really, it blows my mind that they ask for free work and it's not just
even, it's not, it's not inconsequential, simple work.
It, it's hours that I could be spending playing with my Children or
doing some
money
to pay the rent or
which I need to do because it rained last night and holy jeez things getting long.
But it blows my mind that these people demand
-- free work and I guess they do because there's no downside like there's no,
-- well, not,
not just that look,
I think the nature of open source to this point has been that
old saying of we've done so much with so little for so long,
we can do anything with nothing.
And
it has been trivial
to just go into the open source wilds
and emerge with the solution you need for the particular problem.
You have be it github
or stack overflow or whatever.
I cobble stuff together all the time where I'm like,
I
had
7 billion parameter llama running on my desktop here.
I managed to shoehorn it into a 12 and a four gigabyte video card
with like
1.5 gigs of VRM to, to spare.
Like I got that working in about an hour and a half,
like setting up his own large language model.
-- That's a I nonsense for those of you playing along,
-- right?
Like this is, it's ridiculous that I can do that.
And so now I, you know, I,
I basically spent 800 bucks Canadian on two video cards so I can reliably do it.
-- But
-- if you're using Lama, are you using github's
data that basically says like you can't be mean to us if you use this data
isn't, doesn't or not, or Facebook, right.
Doesn't Facebook's license have some, like ridiculous terms.
The way, the way the Facebook
and I'm making air quotes here, the open
source license. The biggest point is
I cannot build a project that will have over 700 million users,
which is a suspiciously specific number that I think.
-- Well,
-- isn't there some other nonsense in their license? Yeah.
There's a couple of things that you can't do it for
Schengen.
Like it's not
-- open source and it's ridiculous, but
-- whatever,
it's open source enough and it will be useful to me to get
-- to solve problems I need to solve.
-- That's fair. But it's not open source anyway.
OK. Not legally or trademark wise, open source. But you know what?
It's open source enough that I don't care and more of the point it's free and I like
free because free fits my budget quite well and
even better because it's free and open source ish.
There's a lot of people
using it and there's an ecosystem building up and growing up around it.
So there's tutorials, there's plugins, there's
like, there's all that stuff I want, I don't want just software. I want an ecosystem.
And that's why,
for example, when I run Linux,
I run stuff like ubuntu because there's a big enough ecosystem around it
that most of the problems I'm going to run into somebody else already. Did and
put on a blog that
the search engine can find and so I can fix it quickly
because
I
don't,
I have spent enough of my life being the first one to
find a flaw and then fix it and document that fix.
Like that's how I got my career. I wrote the Linux
Administrative Security Guide because I literally,
I remember I was connected to the internet by a 19 or
was it 14, 4 dial up then? 19? Yeah, it was 14 4 dial up to begin with.
Yeah, because my friend had a nice 600 bo modem.
So, yeah, anyways, I could connect to the internet 14 4 dial up
and I was connecting out to stuff and I
had this sudden epiphany one afternoon where I'm like,
wait a minute, I can connect to anything on the internet.
They can connect to me.
How exciting.
And that's what I realized. I'm like, I need to do something about it. So
again, like there's a lot of people out there.
How do I put it nicely?
I want my computer to you to do useful things and even better yet. I will pay money
for that to happen with less pain.
And you look at a lot of people with
hobbies like there are some expensive hobbies out there.
Like I remember Linus Torvalds talking about his swim flippers where he spent like
hundreds of dollars on these swim flippers that are like 10% more efficient.
But if you're really into scuba diving, that's a massive
-- improvement. Uh,
-- scuba diving gear. Well, not only that scuba diving gear is like,
it's keeping you alive underwater. Don't keep out on that stuff. You know,
like, I mean, you have a proper bike that will last more than a couple of 100 miles.
I imagine it costs more than 500 bucks.
Uh, my bicycle was actually, it's, it's like 10 years old now
and it was about $500 when I bought it.
But now the equivalent bike is, I think, I think I looked at the bike store.
I like going to the bike store
and I think the current bike I have is about $900
and it's a little nicer than mine. But at the same time, like,
I like my bike.
It's, I probably have 5 to 7000 miles on that bike
and I've replaced many pieces of it many times.
But I like the bike and it's funny because I bring it in.
They're like, we can sell you a new bike. I'm like, yeah, I like this bike.
Like, I don't want, I don't want a new bike. I want this bike.
-- So,
-- but I think ultimately,
I think the biggest thing is people need to be aware that
there's more to the world than just what they
see in their village or city or whatever.
II, I think that's not a problem necessarily I think that
-- you
-- can't go visit the Enterprise world without going and working for them.
-- Uh,
-- that, that is,
I think that is a good way to end this.
Yes, I think the enter, it's, it is enterprise, open source. It exists.
It is technically open source but
it,
it doesn't work the way we often think of open source and it doesn't have to.
Yeah, I mean,
the only reason I actually know anything about skater is
my sister's a PM for a large skater firm.
That's cool. Like,
that's
otherwise I would know nothing about skater.
Yeah.
And how would I find, like,
they're not publishing blogs about how I built this cool thing for whatever,
or there's a new technique like those are
-- things that they charge money for. Right.
-- Right. Oh, exactly. For sure. Right.
And also they're too busy to write that stuff and
also legal would never let them talk about it.
Oh, man.
Imagine what like the government would do if all
of the skated details were suddenly being blogged about,
they would lose their minds.
-- Well,
-- like when Schneider
Electric became AC N A CV Numbering authority and started publishing CV,
S for Schnyder Electric stuff, it was like
a lot of people freaked out.
You're not supposed to talk about security flaws in, in hardware dear. But,
like, again,
it's not that I don't want to replace my Schneider electronic relays.
They're, you know,
at the bottom of an oil well, under 2000 ft of water.
Uh
We like,
yeah, not a lot we can do with that. All right. Anyway, I'm kind of so
we're, we're, we're rambling now.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you all for listening. Go to social security podcast.com.
Hit up the show. Not easy.
Podos
says podcast hashtag on Mastodon to get our attention.
Kurt have a marvelous.
Yeah, I deleted my Twitter or I didn't, I, I,
-- I closed up my
-- Twitter account. I deleted mine. It's been gone for a while.
-- I
-- haven't
-- deleted it because I don't want somebody to squat the name.
-- You know what?
At first I thought that but I'm like, you know what?
-- I don't even care if someone wants to squat me. Go
-- for it.
I suspect in six months it won't matter anymore
-- because I think I
-- don't think it matters now
-- is I
-- would, I would view someone squatting my Twitter name as the,
the ultimate form of appreciation we'll say
so.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye bye.