Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner and not working at Red Hat anymore.
-- Josh Pressers.
-- It's true.
-- This one's gonna be a doozy, I think
-- because you were at Red Hat for
12 years
and I was there for, I think seven
-- ish.
-- Yeah,
it's an easy place to stay for a long time. It's a cool company like,
and it was,
it was the cool company.
Well, it was the only cool open source company
for like a decade.
It's still pretty cool. Look, I'm not gonna. Ok.
So. Oh my goodness. All right. Let's just start.
Let's give our, our,
our warning of Kurt and I decided we want to talk about the current Red Hat.
-- We'll say news about Cento S.
-- Wait, you called Sento S?
Oh,
I was pronounced it Sento.
It could be Sento.
I don't care. I don't know.
I, I've called it Sent Os for a long time and that's what's in my brain
and a lot of people I've known have called it that so it is what it is,
whatever. Anyway,
we're not here to crap on Red Hat. We're not here to blame IBM.
-- I
-- definitely not blame Sento
and who I remember when they hired Karen beer and, like, he's an awesome guy. Yeah.
Oh, KB is great
and, well, KB is not there anymore. He, he departed a couple of years ago.
-- I think if I recall
-- correctly, I really have not been keeping track of Red Hat.
Well, and that's just it. Right. We're, we're gone now, so let's do it.
Oh, he stepped down in 2021.
Yeah. Yeah, it's, it's been a while.
I know which I think the first time they changed, sent to us, I'm gonna,
that's hard to say.
Um, the first time they changed,
sent OS to the stream model I think is when he departed,
that is the
right.
Well,
his departure appears to be aligned with the new direction of the Centa
project moving forward around, sent off stream with sent off eight,
going end of life at year's end.
Right. Right.
Anyway, I guess he wanted to spend more time with his family.
Apparently
I always love, like, whenever that I'm like, nobody, no,
like that's the whole point with having a job is so you can get away from your family.
I mean, sometimes,
but it, it's amusing to me.
Yeah, when the politicians are like, oh, yes, I just got caught buying crack.
I'm going to spend more time with my family. It's like, no, you're,
-- you're fired. Like we know how this works.
-- I mean, that's the thing, right. So
in the beginning, there was literally Red Hat.
Linux came in a box cost about 50 bucks. You could get it for free.
Honestly, Red Hat made a living.
No, they didn't, they didn't.
And that's why they went into enterprise Linux
-- where the real money is.
-- I know I have a lot of history here.
Thank goodness, the ND A is long gone.
Well, you were basically there for the whole thing.
I started at Redhead in 2004 and this was after the IP O
and it was
that
I did too. I mean, I whatever, it doesn't matter.
It was a couple of years after Redhead enterprise, Linux became a thing.
It was Fedora had just started not long before I started working at Red Hat.
I remember that. And
in fact, the reason I worked there is Red Hat end of Life, Red Hat. Linux
78 and nine on the same day. And the little start up I work for Progeny Linux systems.
He took over doing security updates for that and they
made me mad and I emailed Red Hat one day.
It was like, are you hiring? And they were like, holy crap?
Yes, like come do literally the same thing you're doing now, just for us.
And that's how like literally everybody I know at Red Hat got a
job on the technical side is like they were basically doing their job
-- and then moved to Red Hat and did the same job.
-- Yeah.
Yeah, that was very common back then, I think.
And, and so anyway, prior to Red Hat Enterprise, Linux,
there was Red Hat, Linux
and Red Hat literally made more money selling hats than they did selling Linux.
-- In those days.
-- They had boxer shorts.
It
doesn't surprise me,
but
for real, they made no money on redhead Linux.
And so the investors obviously were like,
you need to make money. That's kind of how companies work.
And this was, I mean, this was post IP O right? Where it becomes, we have to make money.
We need a way to do this and they created Redhead
prize, Linux.
And the thing that made Red Hat Enterprise Linux
truly unique at the time is the way
they twisted the GP L to do their bidding is how I would describe it.
I think it was, I don't remember if it was Ian Mogan or,
or Bradley Coon who once described what Red Hat did as
they found the line
where the GP L ended
and they stepped
exactly up to it but did not cross it. And so what Red Hat Enterprise Linux
did is they basically had an an A
ya a user license agreement that said
you can take this product, you can take these binaries,
you can take this source code.
And if you distribute any of this stuff without our permission,
we cancel your subscription to our service
which is not in violation of the GP L.
See,
that's me, the GP L just says if I ship you binaries,
I also have to ship you source code.
-- That's
-- right.
And it,
there is some language around, I cannot
uh encumber, you add more licensing terms.
But I'm not,
that's the beauty of it.
That's, and that's the hack if it were,
is they're not actually adding to the license.
They're saying they will actually well revoke
the entire license.
That's right. That's right.
And then, but, but Red Hat did release the source code to Red Hat Enterprise Linux.
And they were, they've always been good about that
once a month, we got an email to sec
alert. Remember saying
I went to FTP dot Red hat.com and there's direct listings enabled
and there's packages what's source code and we'd be like uh huh.
-- That's the whole point.
-- Thank you for your bugger part.
We leaked our source code to the internet.
No, straight up. Like once
work,
it did happen a lot. But anyway,
they made the source code available and you can imagine the clones emerged
and this is where
uh well sent Os is fine,
but the original clones were terrible because here's the thing,
this is not a puppy, this is a herd of puppies. So like
compiling it all once and releasing it. Sure, I could do that.
You could do that in an afternoon.
But then the Death March of keeping it up to date with Red Hat.
Running a Linux distribution is hard to do. Who knew
we do? Especially
if you're trying to be bit
like, compatible with something else. Sure.
Because then you have to do it on their schedule.
Uh. Right. Right.
Right. And
that,
a lot of updates.
No, I know it was Microsoft used to make a big deal about that where they would,
they had a demo, they would do where Steve Ballmer would put like put red hots,
the candy,
like hundreds of them into someone's hands and
watch them spill them all over the stage.
I mean, this is back when Microsoft and Redhead hated each other
anyway. OK. So let's fast forward now to today
where we've got Redhead Enterprise Linux
and
there were the clone makers, they bought Sento S Cento S kind of pseudo goes away.
Well, what they did with Sento
is they made it
instead of literally being, uh I don't want to pay for Rel. So I'm going to run Sento.
They made Sento
the
upstream of Rel. See originally was Fedora was the upstream, right?
They would like just
keep stuff, you know, keep updating it, stuff would break new stuff would go in
and then they basically
pick a time and then freeze it and then like a year, year and a half later,
a reel would be born based on that version of Fedora from like 6,
1218 months before whatever kind
of.
And so then what they did is they put, so Fedora is like the really, you know,
every six months of new release followed by Sento,
which is a bit more conservative and more enterprise.
And then below that comes Rel and REL is the boring stable, it works thing.
And so the idea was now, is,
well, centaur stream is no longer compatible with REL because it's in front of REL.
So it cannot be compatible with R
-- but
-- they still were releasing the source packages. Well, the the source code in in a G
Repo
Loretta Enterprise Linux
and this is where like Rocky and Alma Linux were born
because Cent Os was no longer
like that compatible rebuild.
So you had community projects spring up that are the bug for bug,
-- compatible rebuilds of RTA Enterprise
-- Linux
and even just the effort of like, like you have to remove all the trademark stuff
-- that alone is a huge amount of effort.
-- But Red Hat did that for them.
Red Hat literally removed all of the trademark crap.
-- Yeah, they actually did the work that
-- wasn't in the
repos. I never looked at the
-- No, it
-- wasn't in the Get
repost like they actually did the work to do that, right? Like Red Hat did good
when they did this. So anyway, on June 21st,
Red Hat
released a blog post that they titled
Furthering the Evolution of Sento S stream.
And
yeah, this is where they murdered the clones.
Like here's the thing, Red Hat is not some big evil Machiavellian
company. Like we work, we work with these people. They're not,
they're just not capable of evil.
-- I mean,
-- we were,
we were always being accused of being like evil geniuses
when we worked there and like we were not.
Well, and my response always was if Red Hat is so damn evil one,
tell me one evil thing they've done and nobody could ever spit something out.
And I was like, number two, we'd be richer.
I mean,
no, seriously, if we were truly evil, we'd be richer.
Like look at what son was charging for Sun West and stuff.
If Red Hat could charge that, add a zero to everything.
Oh man.
Yeah, for real. It was still cheap than so.
Yeah.
Right.
Although I remember back in the day like,
so I wanna, I wanna give a little bit of background as well to this.
So when we, when I started at Red Hat,
it was not a job.
It was like a religion
to a lot of us. I mean, I remember when I was growing up, when I was a high school,
I did, my dream was to work at Red Hat someday.
Like we all have that like dream job we want.
When we're kids, mine was literally to work at Red Hat.
Like Red Hat was the company I wanted to work
for because they were the open source company that like,
I could work on Linux and pay my bills and feed my family
and they were like the only place.
And I mean, this is how I ended up working for progeny Linux system because I'm like,
well, they're not Red Hat, but it's Linux, like it's close enough.
And then I realized, oh, this could get me into Red Hat if I play my cards right here.
And I did and it worked out, but
like Red Hat was such a huge deal back then. I can't explain how powerful
and impressive and important that company was. Like,
they
open source.
Like, absolutely all of that. It was, it was absolutely amazing.
And I'm still a huge Red Hat fan.
-- Boy, I'm not going to say I'm not,
-- here's the question.
How much money over the last two decades do
you think Red Hat spent on all those different,
getting involved in all those different lawsuits,
like the skull lawsuit and Amicus briefs and like,
-- not zero? It's a lot, I'm sure
-- it must be in the tens of millions of dollars anyway.
Anyway, that they spent protecting open source.
Yeah.
Yeah. For real, for sure, for sure.
And, and so anyway, ok,
so here is the reason I give kind of that background, right? I think
when, what redhead did
and we'll get to explaining some of the nuance around that. But I, I feel like
they were the chosen one. I feel like that scene in Star Wars where Obi
Wan Kenobi is like, yelling at Anakin like you were the chosen one.
I feel like that's what just happened
where this was the company that like went out of their freaking way to,
to like we'll say do the right thing in quotes
and all of a sudden they
kind of unexpectedly even
they, they, they turned off the faucet
and everyone's like, shocked that holy cow, what just happened,
I'm gonna say something that a lot of people are probably, I
probably going to hate, which is I am
100% OK with this because by the letter of the law
and the letter of the license
and I would argue even the spirit of the license,
they're, they're within the gu they're within the guidelines. They're OK.
Look, they're within the guidelines, but
I'll, I'll skip ahead a little bit.
So, first of all, they released the blog post titled, right?
Furthering The Evolution of Sento S Stream, which
it
had that very like, oh, we're doing this for everybody.
Look at us, which obviously was not and it's not particularly well written.
I mean, Mike mcgrath wrote it. I, I've known Mike for a long time. He's a great person.
He's not evil anyone.
Apparently he's been called Evil multiple times over the last couple of weeks.
Like I worked with him for
actually pretty much my whole career.
Red Hat because he was the open shift guy and I was the cloud security guy.
-- So
-- he's less evil than both of us put together by far like unquestionably anyway.
But then, but then
uh on the 26th, so five days later, he writes another blog post, we'll say that is
more direct and truthful is how he would describe it.
And he basically at the end says, like we did this to cut off the clones. Yeah.
And obviously that's a business decision.
Unquestionably at that point. Now, here's,
here's what I think. And this is me with some background in this space as well as just
some understanding of the market. I don't think
it's going to matter to their bottom line.
I think they did this to affect the bottom line. And I think if
it at best it will be zero
-- and it might even hurt them a little bit. Is my
-- suspicion, my suspicion is that
there are some business people that think it might help.
-- Oh, I
-- have no, I guarantee they think it'll help or they wouldn't have done it.
You know, there's, there's X million number of, of Rocky Linux.
Alma Linux sent
to whatever machines, you know,
and if we get like 1% of them to convert, we'll have more money than all of some country
-- they are gonna convert.
-- No, they're not.
Like if, if you're already running one of these distributions,
you can probably switch to something else pretty easily.
-- And
-- people don't understand
and what Red Hat sells
and Red Hat doesn't sell Linux.
No.
Well,
nobody does anymore.
There's no,
-- there's no market left while
-- ignoring the fact
that they owe over 100 other products.
Right?
I was like 100 and 10 when I left, what Red Hat sells is legitimacy and insurance.
They sell the confidence trick. Yeah.
Yeah.
And they also happen to ship as a, it's like mcdonald's
as a consequence of getting their
leases to pay the rent on the land. They also sell hamburgers.
But mcdonald's is first and foremost, a real estate company.
Red Hat is first and foremost, an insurance
slash confidence trick company, but also happens to ship pretty good software.
Well, and you have to remember that back in 2004, let's say
like running, I'll never forget. So the story I love to tell people is.
So I graduated from college in 2001 and I went to
work for this little life insurance company because at that time,
it was like the middle of the.com explosion.
And I'm like, I just need a job like I have to live.
So I got,
I was an a IX system administrator working for
a company that wrote life insurance software in Cobal.
Like it was,
it was pretty crusty
and that's fine.
It was a cool place and they were lovely people, but I was obviously any time
there was an opportunity I was talking about open source and trying to get us to like,
convert everything to Linux
and we should be using whatever and I'll never forget that.
I had someone sit me down at one point and they're like, look, you're a smart kid.
You are throwing your life away on this open
source crowd.
I
-- told that all the time. Yeah.
-- Get out of here. Like a IX is great.
You know, you should, you should work on that
you should have seen because, like, back in the olden days I actually
went to the
Unixes group meeting locally at the university
and the disdain and the
just general,
like, straight up that here's a nickel kid by yourself. A real computer.
It was like,
it was real, it was legit. And then of course, like,
yeah, 10 years later, ha ha, who's laughing now?
Well, we know how that worked out. But anyway, here's the point. So in like 2001
ish to 2004 people went to Red Hat because they were wanting to do open source stuff,
but they were afraid of it and they didn't know what to think of it.
And Red Hat was basically,
well, we weren't even sure if the legality of it.
Well, that, yeah, that's right. That's right.
Like I straight up had people kind of saying like, is this legal, I'm like,
what do you mean?
Is it like, is it somehow illegal to give this away? For free. And I'm like,
I don't think so.
And you had, you had the fud of, oh, if you had open source,
you have to give away all of your software for free.
And it's like,
yeah,
of course, obviously. And so it was a scary place and Red Hat took away the scariness.
But here's the thing now, let's fast forward to today. 2023.
-- Open source isn't near as scary as it used to be. Well,
-- you don't have a choice now.
Well,
everything is so complicated. You cannot build it yourself.
Here's the second part of that.
I think it's not just that open source is more accepted. The Linux
distribution
has become functionally a commodity like no one
is going to make any money selling Linux
ever again.
-- Like that's just the reality
-- of it.
Like on a worldly map, it's firmly in the utility space of like electricity,
clean water. It's uh
concrete
-- tires.
-- It's,
yeah, it's a commodity
thing that exists now. It just is and you can get like a zillion of them for free.
Well, not even that you can get them for free. It's just baked into everything.
Like you use a platform as a service.
That's true. Unless it's one of those weirdos basing on top of, of free BS D.
It's, it's Linux under the hood like everything is Linux under the hood.
You buy a cheap
network device. It's probably Linux under the hood. You buy a Mercedes car,
-- there's like a whole pile of open source licenses.
-- Oh, for sure. That's right.
That's right. So, anyway, ok,
so let's take all of that.
We'll mix it all up in the pot and that kind of brings us to today
where Red Hat has cut off the clones,
the clone makers probably don't know what they
can do and there's basically no legal way
they can continue producing clone operating systems because
the, the license agreement says you cannot distribute the source code.
If you do, you are violating this license agreement
-- and you get cut off.
-- My one thought.
I remember when we were talking about this uh before a few days ago how I was like, wow,
you know, like red hat turned the knob up to 10.
There's no 11 but there is D MC A takedowns. I,
I
mean, it's, you know, like,
because we were talking about, you know, I was like, oh, well,
-- they could just turn through accounts,
-- they can't do that.
So here's the thing, if
I sign up for a red head
and Redhead has like a free tier that you can sign up for.
So let's say, let's say I sign up for a free tier,
I can download all of the source code to.
I'm not breaking any rules.
I can give it to you. I'm not breaking any rules. They can't D MC Amy for that.
-- I haven't broken any copyright. But
-- if you
but I'm talking like a, like if Alma Linux
has the packages and they're distributing them on a public website anyways.
-- I, I was just, it was a random thought
-- there's, but that's not illegal.
What that says is the license agreement says I get cut off.
It doesn't say I can't distribute them. It says if I do, I get cut off.
Right.
-- That's true. Yeah, it doesn't retroactively revoke, which is
-- why
Alma could if, if they get them. But, but you have to remember
there's still that like legal angle and whoever giving it to them
and is violating the license. That that gets weird.
But once you have that source code, you can do whatever you want with it.
That's how open source works.
Well, once, yeah, once you've been given the binaries,
you have to have the source yada yada, they can't revoke it.
But again,
this is that Red Hat has like they're standing on the edge of the cliff of the GP L
and this is as, as weird as it can get,
I'm OK with it because fundamentally
like, has anybody ever widely deployed sent off and been like, hey,
this is really good.
We should pay for all of it.
Like they might buy a few licenses,
but I don't think so and they only buy a few licenses just to get
that kind of support for the few boxes that they can then apply to sent off
right.
There were people who would buy like one Red Hat license and then deploy thousands
of sent us licenses or machines licenses and they would leverage that one license,
which means they were probably actually a net negative
for Red Hat in terms of support costs,
unquestionably.
Right.
Because the thing to remember is, and here's the thing,
I think most people don't get,
almost, nobody actually buys Red Hat
Linux in the sense of I don't go and buy, I don't even know who makes my two by fours.
I'd have to guess wire hauser just because it's a big company. But
the point is I don't buy Red Hat Linux.
I buy an accounting package that runs on Red Hat Linux
or I buy,
apply. It
is Red Hat Linux
or I buy a Dell Poweredge server that I need to like shove files out or whatever.
-- And my choices are windows are Red
-- Hat.
That wasn't how it worked a couple of decades ago, right? Like
you would buy Red Hat Linux because you needed
a UNIX operating system to be a web server
-- and they had it and they had support.
-- And that was the other trick is
the other trick Redhead did back in the day is
they killed. So,
and the way they killed so
is by driving down development costs so low.
But
well, essentially your choices were,
you can sell this Linux for like 200 bucks per server per year, which
I don't think people understand how ridiculously cheap
that is when you're talking in 2000 terms.
Like these were like $40,000 computers.
-- Like it was ridiculous
-- running
an Os that you paid several 1000 bucks a year for.
Like you didn't just buy it and get updates. You had
a,
a yearly re up. It was so expensive and, and to add insult to injury, even if you
were willing to pay for Sun Os,
you still had to download all the open source to make the damn thing work.
Like to get bash and Apache and everything.
You know, that was the whole point of Suns site, right? All the sun sites.
Oh, sun site. That was the name of that. I'm trying to remember that
there was a local one,
there was a Sunset at U Alberta run by uh anyways and it
also ran the mirrors for a bunch of other Linux distro and stuff.
But yeah, the deal with Sunset is Sun would send you a sun
like pizza box back in the day with a bunch of drives and you'd racket and
given an IP address and boom Suns site dot U Alberta dot C A or whatever.
And it would have a collection of all the Sun software plus, you know,
whatever else you wanted to put on it.
But like, people really don't understand like,
oh,
a
really horrible example. I paid money for Os Two and I paid money for the TCP/IP A
on Pat
was
like, I'm going to forbid you from telling the story. You talk about
it almost as much as
-- you. Do.
-- You think that was expensive? So
Os
A
20, we know it was very expensive.
And so Red Hat drove down development costs to a point where so
os and
all the major unixes died
in the sense of
they're not dead but they're dead ends. They're still running
your, your life insurance company is still running a IX with that
-- coal.
-- Well, and look it, no, it wasn't just Red hat that did this.
This was all of open source because
open source when it started was slow and weird and scary.
And eventually the rate of development eclipsed
the development pace of,
-- of commercial UNIX
-- son's website like glass fish and stuff, you know, like their,
their stuff like so
tried
to, you know, make a Java web server and all these other things.
-- Well, of course,
-- they tried, they had to try like it was try or die and I mean,
they did both but
go to sun.com.
Oh, there's your answer.
But yeah, and that's the thing people forget is like this is,
this was a time when like we literally were building the internet,
but everybody takes for granted now
anyway. OK. OK. So Red Hat cuts off the clones, clones are gone.
Lots of people get upset.
Now,
now
I think it's ok for people to be upset. As well.
Here's the thing I don't get is the vast
majority of open source software I use is like,
it doesn't care if it's on Ubuntu or Debian or Red Hat or Fedora or whatever.
My one thought is what software packages are people running that actually, really,
-- truly sort of need to run on top of rel,
-- well, there, there's,
there's things that are free.
Oh, that are free. Nothing that's free.
See, and so here's my thought is like, if you're willing to, like,
these are not cheap applications by and large,
like this isn't like you're buying $10
applications and be like,
oh, I'm the
same with buck by running, sent off instead of real.
And that's the thing I don't get is this
like idea of it's like penny wise pound foolish.
Like I worked at a place they, they had,
it was a construction company. So the accounting system is like, so bizarre.
So there's all sorts of strange accounting magic in there,
like holdbacks and all these
ways of charging money and not charging money anyways.
The point is it runs on Skull
UNIX back in the day.
And I'm like, oh, we could run it on Linux with the skull emulator.
And then I realized, or
Kirk could not be yelled at on
a Friday afternoon because paychecks aren't printing.
So we're gonna, we're just gonna pay the vendor for the,
for the accounting package and everything
-- that comes with it.
-- You're talking about a different universe. Right.
-- That's not how things work anymore.
-- Well, no, no, no.
But that's,
that's my kind of thought is that's the market where sent off
and all that stuff came from and it doesn't exist anymore.
-- No, it doesn't. Exactly. Right.
-- And
that's what I'm getting at. Like, this doesn't matter anymore.
-- No,
-- it, it, it's, the world is so different now and I think if you're a company,
like Red Hat,
it's really about building like an ecosystem and an infrastructure
and an experience for the people using your stuff.
Right? No one is going to pay Red Hat for enterprise Linux.
They're going to pay Red Hat because they have a problem to solve.
And Redhead has a collection of tools that
will solve their problem because like you just,
I mean, you said a little while ago, Redhead has what, 100 and some products,
probably 200 products or more at this point because that was cris we left there for,
I mean,
I left Redhead in like 2016. That was
a million years ago at this point.
-- And
-- the other thing is people forget is Redhead
has expertise because I remember my favorite bug was
essentially this.
It was something like once every couple of days,
the server slows down for a few seconds and we can't have that happening.
And I'm like, what?
And it was a high frequency trading system.
And so they're like, yeah, it can't be slow for a few seconds.
And so there was some spin m text that would, like,
every 50 or 100,000 iterations it would not lock or unlock properly.
-- And like Red Hat fixed it in like two days. Yeah,
-- because they could,
you know,
I mean,
and this is why the likes of Intel and a MD
would partner with Red Hat because Red Hat had the ability
to do things No one else could do.
They have some of the best kernel talent in the world.
Well, remember with the Intel hardware bugs to like,
make software patches that didn't perform or hit a what?
30% performance
degradation.
Right. Right.
-- That
-- was,
yeah, this patch is sponsored by AWS.
Yeah,
I think part of it is anybody that is still relying on
like a bit for bit compatible free Red Hat Enterprise Linux,
like they're, they're probably also using
-- coal or something like they're just so old at this point.
-- No, not necessarily.
There's lots of reasons people would want Cento S because part of it as well.
-- Red Hat does bring a certain amount of stability.
-- Ok. Fair.
If I'm going to run
-- something else, it's going to be much less stable.
-- That is true.
13 years of support is a long time
and, and so here's, here's what,
here's what you're going to end up with now is I can either basically
incur the cost and deal with it myself or I could pay Red Hat
and I don't think people are going to pay Red Hat because I think
anyone capable of getting to this point can incur the cost and it's probably
going to be cheaper than paying Red Hat if you have a reasonably sized fleet
-- that we're talking about here.
-- Right.
Or, you know, they'll do what I do. Which is, I ran Fedora,
I ran one version of Fedor
in production for like four years.
Don't do that
to do
it end of life after a year
for
-- months of support. That's like a quarter of the way there.
-- I run it on my laptop.
Every, every release I'm like, I'm not gonna upgrade on the day it comes out.
And actually the last release I did not upgrade the day it came out.
I did it for the first time ever. Do you know why?
Because I was in California and my laptop was powered up in Wisconsin
because they released a week early and I wasn't ready.
But anyway,
no, I think, I think there's going to be a lot of kerfuffle about this.
But you know what this reminds me of is,
remember when I think it was Oracle was the first one to do this where they were like
they added to the end user license agreement that
you can't benchmark our stuff and release the benchmarks.
-- Uh
-- the dot
-- Clause, I think we call those
-- and I just checked and like Sousa does that now.
-- And like, a lot of software vendors do.
-- I
bet a lot of people have those duet clauses and why not?
If you have a lawyer writing your, your
ya just throw it in. It doesn't cost anything
well, more to the point. If, if you don't do it and your competitors do,
then they will benchmark your software and maybe make some mistakes,
making air quotes here as possible and then release that data and be like,
ha ha we benchmark this and like, look how terrible it is compared to our solution.
Yeah, I mean, that's fair. That probably does happen.
-- And I, I hate that kind of stuff. Oh,
-- it happens all the time.
We had that problem. Um Well, I'll tell the tale
in open shift. So part of being security at Red Hat is we would assign CV ES to
issue
the moment.
We figured out it was a security related issue
and
the vast majority of our security bugs were public
like we didn't hide them. They just weren't worth it like they weren't that bad.
And I actually got told off because
there was a rival company that was basically saying,
look at all these open security flaws and openshift,
they've been open for X number of days.
Our stuff only has security flaws for a few number of days because they were one
of those vendors that only assigns a CV
identifier like the minute that they release the pass
-- one of those,
-- you know, and keeps everything hidden.
And I was like, ok, well, sorry,
I mean, ok,
so I want, I want to use that as a good example, action.
This is still something Red Hat does.
Red Hat has been ridiculously open, especially around security to the point of
just hilariousness sometimes
and a lot of competitors would never do that.
I remember like, this always got under my skin.
You
can't.
And, and it just,
it always irked me when you'd have the likes of Microsoft and Sun and Oracle.
-- And I'm like, oh, you know,
-- look, redhead has 3000 open security box.
-- I'm like, yeah, I know I filed them all.
-- I know I hated that.
All right. I feel like we're just telling tales of redhead at this point.
-- That's part of the thing that is how, that's how we got here.
-- It is.
It's totally how we got here
and look, here's, here's how I will end this.
Here's kind of my parting thought on this is the first blog post. Red Hat released
was a little weaselly and kind of crappy.
And when I saw Mike mcgrath had a second blog post, I was,
I opened it fully expecting it to be declaring how this is good for open source,
right?
And when I saw at the end where he basically said we did this to cut off the clones.
I was like, well done,
Mike like that is the only thing you could have said
in this to do the right thing and well done like
100%
and more to the point. I like,
I'm sorry, but this is a massive free rider problem.
Part of it too is to remember is not just missing revenue for Red Hat, but like
there's this, I think to some degree, there's some perception issues as well,
which I, I know at Red Hat, I was always a bit frustrated.
I want to stop this conversation right now.
We literally a few minutes ago just talked about
how this probably won't increase Red Hat's revenue.
I don't think this is a free rider problem.
I think this when it boils down to, it feels like an issue of fairness.
It's not fair when someone takes Red Hat's hard work and uses it
sometimes against them, which was what Oracle Enterprise, Linux for a long time.
-- Well,
-- what I was about to get to is like the,
the having these clones actually incurs a cost to Red Hat
in some ways because I've had people complain about Centa stuff and I'm like,
I can't fix that.
I work at Red Hat. I don't work at Sento.
Here's
back
before. No, no, I don't think it matters. I think this is one of those issues.
There are many times that something doesn't feel fair
and
we as humans like to take actions that we feel like
levels the playing field and this is like one of my favorite
examples of this is when you see like public assistance for the poor
saying you have to take a drug test or you have to
try to find a job and you have to do this thing,
right?
And at the end of the day, it actually ends up hurting everybody,
but it feels more fair and, and, and that's what it comes down to.
And I think this is what that is.
This feels more fair to the Red Hat people,
but it's actually going to hurt everybody.
It's going to hurt Red Hat and it's going to hurt
the not Red Hat people.
Well,
and the one argument I saw was that I think
is about the only argument against this that holds water is
people stand
on the shoulders of Red hat,
-- not fair, blah, blah, blah. Well, I mean, Red Hat, no,
-- we all stand on Red Hat.
-- How much freaking open source does Red Hat contribute to? And
-- Red Hat
also stands on the shoulders of Giants.
And one thing that really annoyed me is somebody was like, oh Red Hat doesn't,
you know, write the Linux Colonel.
-- I'm like, actually, yeah, like 13% of it,
-- like, strange contributor to the, every
year, like, consistently, about 10 to 13%
is from Red Hat.
Like that's,
that's massive. So that really annoyed me.
But the,
but that's kind of the only argument that even holds a little tiny bit of water.
But
I would say to that argument of like, there's a huge difference between
taking a bunch of open source and just reshipping it bit for bit versus actually
adding a whole bunch of value, putting your heart into it,
paying literally thousands of people to fix the software and to produce,
to produce security patches on a Saturday afternoon and
-- not hang out with their kids
-- been there,
you know,
and I, I think that's a big part of this is like,
the people really have no idea about the amount of work.
No, I, I think this is the fairness argument again, Kurt, like,
I don't think it's a matter of,
is, is this good for Redhead? Is this bad for redhead? It feels unfair.
And so a thing has been done to make it fair.
And I think I, I, my suspicion is it's going to hurt everybody
because that's what fairness often is.
-- Yeah. Well,
-- people don't like something
that they had for free being taken away from them.
And that's part of it too.
Look, it's not just that I really think like the chosen one perspective, like Red Hat
doesn't feel like the chosen one anymore.
Another company.
I, I think you think, and that's the thing, right?
Compared to literally every other company, they're still doing better,
I think for open source than many other places.
But again, the chosen one, right?
It's like when we look at the Jedi, like, there's probably a bunch of dirt bag, Jedi
and we're like, oh, whatever. But you, you were the one you were going to save us all.
And then you
-- entered everybody.
-- The one thing that's always kind of wild to me is like
Sousa just sort of kept a low profile. Right. Like
-- they're still around.
-- Oh, no, they're still around. But like, when's the last time
you kind of heard about them or thought about them?
And that's goes to the point of the chosen one. Like
there are other Linux companies like
ubuntu.
Well, uh huh.
I, I know,
but Red Hats, the one, they were always the one
and now they're just like everybody else.
Yeah,
that's it.
Maybe that's why everybody's so upset is Red
Hat is just another software company now.
-- It's the
-- end of an era, you know,
and,
and it is what it is and Red Hat is a company and they're going to do what they think is,
right?
-- And there's nothing we can do
-- about it.
I mean,
maybe that's part of the problem is Red Hat is a company that is now
going to behave like a company and not behave like a bunch of open source
zealots. I mean,
-- which 20 years ago it was,
-- it's been on that path for a long time and
in 2004, like, we would have burnt that place down.
They
have something like this.
I, I remember my induction for Red Hat.
There was me another technical person and then a bunch of, like,
15 sales people that had just been hired
and they had to teach them about the GP L and open source.
And of course, me and the technical person are like, oh,
ok. They don't know what this is fair.
Yeah. Right. And, you know,
they really didn't understand open source and they really didn't, like,
get it because it,
yeah, I mean,
we didn't have to do that when I started because it was just a bunch of tech nerds.
Everybody else.
I mean, would have sat through it and be like, oh, it's a,
it's a multilevel marketing scheme or a cult.
I'm out. Right.
And maybe that's, maybe that's what's really poking at people.
Is it, is the end of an era. It's the end.
It's been two decades and Linux one, it's boring. It's a utility.
It is that, that's just it. Linux one. It's boring.
I'm sitting here
on a Windows 11 system with, I think. How many open Linux?
A bunch of open Linux
VM?
Si mean, I still run Linux because every time I try running windows,
I make it a couple of months and then like, I rage quit
but I mean, I'm not even running VM. So I'm running Windows subsystem for Linux
-- version two. Like, it's baked into the Os. It's technically
-- a VM.
Well, no, my point is it's not a third party. App, it's baked into Microsoft.
-- That's true. That's true. They, they, you had
-- told me that 20 years ago
the Linux would be baked in.
Oh. And if you go to the Microsoft store, they also removed all the fake Linuxes.
So, when you used to go to the Microsoft store
five years ago and you typed in like sento s
there was a bunch of scammy ones that came up that cost like 50 bucks or 100 bucks.
And I was like,
I remember they're all gone now.
It's just, it's clean and pure.
As far as I know,
that's the way it should be.
And which, which variant of Linux
do you run in your WSO
-- open
-- to LTs
and
two? OK.
-- I'm just, I want to be boring. I want it to work.
-- That's fair. I get it. I understand.
-- And
-- what I love is I can type things like X clock and it just pops up on my screen now.
I know. Right. Like, it's amazing,
-- dude, 20 years ago, I couldn't even get that thing working on Linux.
-- That's true.
That's
actually why I ran Sousa for a while.
Remember because Sousa had the X config program and I didn't have to
guess at the values that may or may not break my monitor.
I remember.
Yeah, because if you did it wrong,
your monitor would do scary things and make weird noises.
You could overdrive the, the, the V sink or the H sync and that's right. You could,
you could make the magic ker
chunk, stop k
chunking.
Yeah.
That was the, the days of C RT monitors and people have no idea how good we have it now.
It
was so bad.
I can just tell my monitor to display stuff and I probably won't break it.
I have, I haven't thought about configuring a monitor
in so long I can. It, it's not even funny.
Yeah. Anyway. All right, I'm gonna call this one.
We're getting long winded and just telling stories of the days of yore.
Like I have a different podcast for that.
So,
thank you, Kurt. Thank you for listening. Go to open source security podcast.com.
Head up the show notes, Su
Podos
Podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks, everyone. Bye bye.