Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast
episode 80 with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought crime. Josh Bresser
80 seems like a big number to me when I think about
-- it.
-- It's,
I'm very aware of that number because that's basically the age of my parents
and that I think 80 qualifies as old.
Uh, just like us. So
it, it's the new 60 or something. I don't know.
Whatever
an is hard.
Cool.
Speaking of, speaking of hard things, do, do you by chance,
run or exercise outside at all?
Kurt,
uh, the skiing downhill count
maybe. Do you, do you have one of those like GPS Fitbit tracker
Deos
downhill ski?
That would actually be interesting. I wonder what that does anyway.
I
might get
a,
you'd be surprised actually. So I, I've seen them before.
Uh I've got someone I bike with.
They have, uh, I think Garin makes it and it has a gps in the watch
and like before we start a ride,
he hits a button and then it maps our
ride and it tells us like elevation and average speed
and you can look up like exactly how fast you were going on any part of the ride.
It's really cool actually.
But of course, this happens after it uploads the data into the cloud,
which I guess kind of brings us to the topic of the day,
which is, uh,
yeah. Did you hear about the fitness tracker that they used
to find army bases?
Well, and it's so,
I guess it's kind of two fold and I just checked and
there are a pile of fitness watches that track your skiing downhill.
I have no doubt.
-- And I bet they know when you're on the ski lift even, which is cool, of
-- course,
because you're going up very fast.
I mean, no offense if you can walk or run well,
run up a hill that quickly you wouldn't be
wearing a fitness tracker because you'd be like,
you'd make Dwayne the Rock Johnson look like a lazy
guy.
Yeah, that, that is true. That is true.
What gets me about this is,
it's kind of a two fold thing and number one is tracking the data is one thing,
but then sharing that data
with a company that then may or may not expose it in a quote
anonymized manner
which
could protect you directly.
Uh, but then could also put you at risk, for example.
Yeah, if you're on one of those secret military bases in the Middle East,
but I have no doubt people don't think about this kind of stuff very often.
So, you know what it reminds me of is, is the old argument of metadata doesn't matter.
And it's like
it kind of does and it's actually way more important than you think it is because,
because I guess, you know, you know what it is
is one singular piece of metadata is probably irrelevant by itself.
But when you have a treasure trove of metadata, it is incredibly valuable.
Well, from what I've read,
there's is quite often when you have about somewhere between
six and 10, either different pieces of metadata
or you have six or eight occurrences of a piece of metadata.
Um So for example,
if I could randomly select six or eight times during the week to
know kind of where you are to say within a 10 block radius,
I would basically know where you live.
Yes, especially as I work from home and I probably spend 90 plus percent of my time,
but also things like where you go, where your kids go to school,
you know.
Um
so it,
and, and well, this this sort of anonym
and sharing of data that you know, doesn't directly impact me is typically true. But
yeah,
apparently there's a lot of common edge cases like military bases that
people don't necessarily want everybody else to know exactly where they are.
But
we should, we should also explain
how they, how this was found, right?
I'll let you do the honors.
Well, so
there's a, well, there's about a million companies at this point selling, uh what
looks like a wristwatch and tracks your fitness activity, tracks your location,
elevation speed, heart rate, blah, blah, blah.
-- And
-- in this case, location is what
matters, right?
-- And
-- so what this company Strava did is they
released a global heat map of athletic activity,
-- which sounds really cool and, and it
-- does
sound really cool and, and I imagine like a city, like we'll say,
-- oh,
-- you can see Edmonton when you go to the
beach,
you can see Edmonton and Calgary because it's the two bright blobs in Alberta.
Nice. Well, and not only that, I bet you could reconstruct a city map really?
Well.
Yeah, they did that. The local military base shows up very beautifully.
Um
We'll get to that,
you know.
Um So basically, yeah, when, I mean,
when people typically go running or jogging,
uh quite often they, they jog on streets, especially on military bases, right?
Because you're probably not gonna want to run through the firing range,
you know, or the tank range or all the other ranges, right?
So, yeah, typically they, they,
you stick to the streets and so it's kind of like the um, oh,
what's that open map?
Is it open map, the project to, you know, create like a Google map of the world.
But using open source data,
that's open street maps. Open street maps. Yeah. And so
open street maps, you know,
originally had just like all the major highways and cities and, you know,
now it's getting to the point where they have footpaths and all the small stuff
and
having a heat map of where people were,
even if it's aggregate data and not identifying a specific user.
Yeah, you can basically map out streets and running trails very, very, very easily.
Right.
Well, and not only that,
I think one of the things that's interesting about
data like this also is what isn't there where,
you know, like there, let's say there's a building
nobody is going to or where building might be a bad
example because you can go through buildings in some cases.
But like
if they're say an impassable object,
you'll know because there will literally be zero, pass through it.
Right. There's no way to get through that.
And it would be nice if somebody told Uber that because I live next to
a major road and there's this giant sound wall that's like 10 ft high.
And Uber seems to think that the Uber drivers can just stop on
this major road and we go through our backyard and hop in their car
except there's this, well, number one, you're not allowed to stop on that road.
It's a major road. And number 2
10 ft wall.
So that's
the funny thing is Google knows about the wall,
right? They know about the foot.
So,
uh, when people use Google Maps, they get to our house, no problem.
But when every time we've ordered an Uber, now
we've had to wait an average of between five
and 15 minutes while they drive around lost,
trying to sort of get
there.
And then we have to call them and explain to them where we live and they usually flub
that up and go to an address about two or three blocks away to the point where it's like
they tell me, I'm in front of your house and I'm like, no, you're not.
I can see you, you're two blocks away, please turn to your left and proceed.
You know, so I've, I've learned now what it's like to be a GPS
and I can't even imagine how frustrating it would be for these.
This is why I don't think we'll ever have artificial intelligence, gps.
S because they will just get pissed off and quit
because trying to direct humans is even when it's something as simple as like,
please turn left and proceed two blocks down
and you're headed straight for me, you know, keep going, keep going. You're good.
You're good. Ok, please stop. Why didn't you stop? Ok, I can see your tail. You know,
I can see the back of your car now going down the street. This is awesome,
right?
This is why we need self driving cars,
self driving cars with good maps though.
Right.
So anyways, but yeah, so you would definitely also you can infer a lot.
Um because I don't know if the heat map data has any time
data associated with it.
Like,
so if there's a slider where you could see like say 3 a.m. versus 6 a.m. versus 9 a.m.
but if they were to release that, you know,
you would have even more data to then infer what's going on around this place,
right. Oh, man.
Could you imagine with, well, in, in, I have a suspicion, normal people can't,
can't look this up.
But obviously if you could look up the heat maps for
say 2 a.m. or whatever time bars close where you're at
like,
yeah, you're going to know
and,
and I guess ironically you could then resell this
sort of data to advertisers and whatnot to be like
this is the popular bar in town, right? This is where everybody goes.
Where do you think the real time traffic data comes from?
That's on your Google maps, right? The cell providers resell bulk
movement data.
You don't say,
you know, this is a huge income stream for them.
-- Oh, yeah. Right. Right. Totally,
-- man.
And, and quite honestly,
I love it because it's allowed me at least once every month
to avoid some route that's all jammed up from an accident or
Lord knows what?
Oh, seriously, man.
I mean, anytime I go on a road trip, obviously you map out your route, right?
And you start driving it and then every hour or two,
I like update the route just because sometimes there will
be a traffic jam or a car accident on the,
on the interstate or whatever.
And it's huge when you can get around it. And, and again,
I mean, I just keep thinking about all this and it's like
there's the old mantra, you know, metadata doesn't matter. And
it totally does.
I would say metadata is almost more useful than regular
data because it's much easier to parse and extract from,
you know,
because you can do much more statistical analysis of it versus with real data,
you know, I'd have to comb through your actual content of your emails
-- to find my incriminating stuff.
-- Well, not only that, like
if you tell me, you have all my emails, I'm going to freak out.
But if you tell me you have my fitness tracker map data, I'd be like,
I probably don't care.
Right.
Well,
I I would care but most people probably don't care because
they're thinking who cares if someone knows where I've been.
And it's like
-- people,
-- it reminds me of this a
few years ago, the the city deployed, well, not the city,
the companies that own the infrastructure deployed,
smart water meters that are wireless
and
uh smart power meters that are wireless,
which uh obviously saves them a ton of time when doing actual meter reading,
you know, because they drive around in a van now.
Um I literally remember as a kid, the Atco gas guy would be running around,
you know, in his shorts in summer,
he knock on your door and you'd like, let him in,
he would like run down to your basement,
look at the meter, scribble it down and like, say thanks and run out.
And that would happen at least once a summer.
See, I never, I never had that,
but we would have people come, there were,
there were meters outside and people would walk around.
In fact, I had a friend who did that.
Uh in one summer home from college is his
job was walking around reading meters and he,
he lost a lot of weight that year
just because it was, you know, he probably walked about 20 plus miles a day
and they did that here where they started installing
meters on the outside of houses. But let's face it, that's really expensive.
Like if you have to move a meter from the inside of a house to the outside,
that's a significant cost
and more to the point by just making these wireless ones boop problem solve.
You know, so for gas, for electric and for power now they're all, you know, wireless.
Obviously, they know when I'm showering, when I'm running the dishwasher,
when I'm washing my hands,
washing the toilet.
I wonder, I wonder what the granularity is on, on those things.
It's whatever they want it to be.
I suppose
that's the reality
and the beauty is there was that article where this guy was,
they did some research into the power meters,
how they monitor the power and they found out that they really don't work
with the new Led lighting and some of the CFC lighting and they totally
get very confused and will over bill.
And so of course, this is a known problem that nobody's fixing because, hey,
when you over bill a customer that's ok.
All right.
Under billing. No,
no, under billing is a problem. Right. But overbilling and we can live with that one.
-- Yes, exactly. Well, people aren't going to notice or care by and large.
-- It is true.
It is true. I wouldn't notice if they were overbilling me a couple of bucks.
And how do you prove it without buying a lot of expensive equipment?
Uh,
that's true.
Actually, I couldn't prove it if I wanted to,
but not only that if they're overbilling me, say a dollar or two a month
is buying $1000 worth of gear
to prove I'm paying $1 a month too much worth it. Like, no,
there isn't.
So this extra
thing goes back to, you know, there's a lot of open source data
and this is a really beautiful example of,
you know,
you can infer if there's like this one
little heat.in the middle of literally nowhere,
especially if it's in a,
in a Middle East country or a poor country
where people generally probably aren't buying $500 fitness trackers.
But, you know,
maybe that's a military base because military people do
tend to spend a lot of time running around.
I, I have a suspicion also. There's probably certain products that are, we say
more, more American, right?
Where you might not show up anywhere else in the country except in one place.
But I think even more than that is, I, I
bet some of these guys are wearing these things,
like, as they're doing, say mission type work. Right.
And, and so I imagine there's a certain amount of,
of metadata leakage in terms of just field operations these guys are going on,
which is
crazy.
I kind of wonder. I mean,
I, I would personally from an operational point of view, I would, you know,
force everybody to sort of strip down their electronics and only use approved stuff
and, and I don't know if they do that or not. That would be something.
Well, remember when they banned Furby from the NSA.
Yes.
Right. So, ok, for those of you that don't know, Furby is this
cute little toy that if you take the uh the fur off of it?
-- Is this like robotic nightmare?
-- It's
a demon.
-- Yeah,
-- it's amazing. And you can hack into them and program them to say bad things.
But regardless
um part of the cuteness of what Furby did is Furby would
listen and then sort of recycle phonetically what it heard and essentially
speak gibberish that sounded cute and that counts as a recording device
for the purposes of what the NSA counts as a recording device.
So they banned these things from the NSA campus, you know,
and all facilities.
But now, I mean,
the amount of stuff that has a microphone in it or
an accelerometer and apparently some of these accelerometers
are sensitive enough to be a microphone.
I have seen that actually. Yes.
Uh yeah,
using MEMS accelerometers as acoustic pickups in well in musical devices easy.
Um
But yeah, in theory,
you know,
even your smart phone accelerometer is getting to a point
where it's sensitive enough to also be a microphone.
-- That's pretty cool, man. I'm not gonna lie.
-- I mean uh uh
yeah,
I
that's the thing, right? Well, it reminds me of the whole Tide pod thing.
You know, microphones used to be microphones,
but now microphones are well a great example is, you know,
these road podcasters that we're using,
they have a built in sound monitor, right?
And there's a little volume dial on the side.
And if I crank mine up like all the way to six, I can literally hear
like my heart beat from 10 ft away.
You know, these things are insanely sensitive. Yeah.
Yeah, I I know what you mean. Uh
We should, we should keep going.
The other story
I love that you posted it kind of related to, to warfare in the modern age
is in the Western United States
-- there's not going to be GPS for a little while. There will be
-- GPS. It's just
not
for
us.
And
GPS always amazing to me because
it,
the GPS signal is so weak, it is
barely above
the noise that you would just
like if you put an aerial out listening to, you know,
the random background radiation, noise, radio noise, whatever
the GPS signal is just barely above that.
And so the tricks that they do to interpret this signal,
especially when you're thinking about civilian gear that costs like 50 bucks
is pretty magic
in my mind.
I agree with that 100%. It's, it's crazy
how sensitive GPS is but, but I think not, not just that
the signal is incredibly weak and the clocks you
need to make it go are insanely accurate,
which is even
better than that.
They actively have to skew the signal to account for things like weather
relativity. Yo
they have to account for relativity because the clock is so sensitive
that that's wild.
But this really drives home that
sometimes the only way to test something is to actually test something.
-- And so
-- why don't you explain what's going on?
Because I imagine there's some people listening right now who are like,
what are they talking about?
So essentially the United States Air Force uh holds
a air war exercise called red flag where uh
it's the US and several other countries that
are invited to essentially have war games,
practice, tactics,
practice new things, you know, have maybe some experiments, see what works,
what doesn't work, new weapon systems, new doctrine,
all that stuff.
And as part of their testing now
they are jamming gps for quite a large area. Uh, like
it's a pretty powerful transmitter from what it looks like.
So,
I
jam it though.
I have a suspicion what's happening and, and this was tested some time ago.
So there's civilian gps
and there's military gps,
basically the same satellites and the military has the
ability to turn off civilian gps over select regions.
Yeah.
Well, the, the encrypt, the, the,
the military GPS was simply an encrypted signal
and that was the whole premise of like that James Bond film,
the one with Pierce Brosnan, you know,
with the GPS receiver thing that could have the encryption keys and
was all technically wrong. But regardless it was a fun movie.
Um,
well, so the deal is too though.
Jamming gps is not hard.
I mean, it's illegal as heck, but you can go to,
there's a bunch of Chinese websites where you can buy GPS.
Jammers.
Um I've
maybe played with one. Maybe not, I'm not gonna be specific, but if you do turn on a
low power gps jammer to see what happens to say your smartphone or whatever,
some really bizarre things can happen.
Um, like at the simplest level, it can just lose the GPS signal and be like,
I'm confused.
I don't know what's going on. I give up.
In other cases, there was a device that basically started drifting at about 6000
MPH westward
or something like it was just flying across the globe.
I, that failure case was very bizarre. But,
you know, and
for you and I,
our car gps doing something wonky like that doesn't really
matter that much because we're obviously going to be like,
well, that's not right,
you know,
but for something like a missile system
or a drone on approach,
there have been stories of people who listen to their
GPS and like drove off a cliff or something.
I mean,
-- we're not that stupid, hopefully. Well,
-- I
I'm not going to say that
I'm not willing to claim anything.
-- So
-- one aspect of this is that to test certain things,
you actually have to go test certain things.
So what is the effect if your enemy jams all the GPS,
right? Do your weapon systems crap out or decide not to work,
you know.
And so from that perspective, it makes really good sense to jam gps
all of it for quite a large area
and,
and literally see what happens.
Uh you know, this reminds me of Chaos Monkey and Chaos Gorilla by Netflix,
like Netflix,
right? Net like
Netflix runs in three Amazon regions.
Um They run those clusters at 60% use the theory being if one of the clusters dies,
the other two clusters go from 60 to 90% utilization
and nobody notices.
And how do you test that? Well, the answer
is you turn everything off in one region
and you hope it works
and if it doesn't, then you do a post mortem and fix it. Hopefully.
-- No.
-- II, I agree. I think that's amazing to test like that.
I think it also says something about the resiliency of the systems you're
building because if you're unwilling to do a live test like that,
you know what you've built probably sucks.
I mean, let's face it.
This always is what reminds me when people complain about reboots.
I'm like, if you are complaining about reboots,
you're doing it wrong because your system will either need a reboot at some point
or it will fail and reboot or die.
So if you can't even do a scheduled reboot,
you are so far up the creek without a paddle,
-- but I, I actually can't help you at this point.
-- No, I know, man.
-- I know.
-- And
I get that. It's tough but it's something that just happens.
So
what's
the good news is because of the way the US is laid out.
This is happening in the Western US where a lot of the land is federal land.
Like my understanding is Nevada is owned like
90 some percent by the federal government.
I can't answer that, but it is very,
somebody did a map of the US and it was the state and then the
states were shrunken to show how much of the land the federal government owned.
And of course, on the eastern coast,
it's like very little because that was settled first and it's privately owned.
But then when you get out west, states, like Nevada, New Mexico
are just
massively big chunks of it are just federal government land for parks
or for, you know, military bases or whatever.
And so that's kind of the good news is that
this is, you know, this isn't like jamming gps in New York City,
although that actually wouldn't be that bad because you have
enough wi fi signals to figure out where you are,
whatever gps is basically jammed in New York City.
I mean, the buildings,
um,
so in some ways,
this is happening in a good place because there's not that many people out there,
but it's also a place where people really do rely on gps because there's, you know,
you don't have dense wi FI data to figure out where you are, right?
So it'll be, I'd be curious to see what happens with this.
If there's any news reports of people doing stupid things or whatever,
it would not surprise me
if there are.
And, and unfortunately I'm sure we'll never know the outcome of the testing,
the military does if their, if their systems and processes stand up to no gps.
Because when you think about it, man, even what, probably 3040 years ago,
there was no gps. Right. It just, it didn't exist in many instances.
And so
the
biggest
reason it really took off is the US had,
had to switch.
Uh, so traditionally what happened is when they deployed GPS,
you have the civilian channel and the military
channel and the military channel was very,
very accurate.
Right? Because bombs and stuff
and the civilian channel, if my memory serves had something like 10 m resolution,
which ain't bad,
you know, if you're a cruise ship or something.
Um,
but during the first Iraq war, they didn't have enough military receivers.
So they literally had to make the civilian channel
accurate because they literally no,
there's pictures of people like driving an A 10, you know,
warthog with like a civilian GPS, duct tape to the front.
That's
hilarious.
You know, because you're flying over a desert, there's not a lot of landmarks.
Right.
Again, you know,
a lot of this doctrine was developed in western Europe where you had landmarks,
churches, you have stuff
when you're flying over a desert. It's,
oh, there's a, there's a straight road over there
like all the other roads or, you know,
-- sand dunes and some camels or whatever.
-- Well, not just saying
-- things like sand dunes move right. Sand dunes don't stay still.
-- Exactly.
Um,
so yeah, they ended up making the civilian channel accurate and of course, that
made
the economic benefit of having accurate GPS.
It's in the hundreds of billions of dollars a year easily.
Oh, my goodness.
I, there's so many things, I mean,
think about every construction project on the planet now.
They all use GPS.
-- Uh,
-- well,
we were talking before the show when I used
to work for the government for flood forecasting.
But that's how they measure dam movement.
They have these metal plates, you know,
built into the dam and they put the transit on differential GPS
and they can measure, you know, two millimeter and slightly better accuracy. Now.
And I imagine
in the day it was what surveys, right?
They had a guy with the little survey, what I don't even know what you call the thing.
Well, the challenge is the dam
might not have moved relative to your survey point.
That's true actually.
-- And
-- that the case,
that could be a problem, you know,
if a whole chunk of land is moved one or two millimet,
that's probably something you need to know.
So, anyways, so, yeah, we ended up with the benefit of now, you know, everything,
having
really high quality GPS and even better.
Now, we have the European system, Galileo and we have the Russian system, GLOS
and a lot of modern Android phones.
As I understand it have two or three of these systems.
One thing that's not mentioned, I just googled.
Nobody can say whether or not the US is also going to be jamming Glo
-- Naz and Galileo for their exercise.
-- It seems like it would be foolish not to.
Well, I'm also wondering at the same point,
I'm going to guess that most of the US military systems with GPS built into them.
I mean, I have no idea if they also support Glonass
or Galileo, I would assume they don't because most of these systems are, you know,
they take 1020 years to develop and deploy
and
Glonass. Is it even finished yet?
I think it's, the satellite coverage isn't complete yet, or is it? I can't remember.
I know, like five or 10 years ago it wasn't,
it is done now. Oh, there we go. Yeah, last launch was in 2016.
So, yeah, it is now finished.
But yeah, no, I, I would be curious to know what would happen if you
jammed all of these because right now, you know,
Android phone users with more recent phones will still have Glonass
or Galileo to, to rely on, you know,
-- when their GPS fails.
-- Right. Right. Right.
And I, yeah, I feel like to have an effective test. You'd have to block them all,
you know,
reminds me of is, is putting my security hat on
is imagine like the internet disappearing for a day or two, which,
which you could think of is in the denial of service aspect right there.
How many businesses could function with no internet?
Like I couldn't,
I couldn't do
a
vastly lowered rate.
I literally could not do my job without internet. I am comfortable.
Here's the
thing is it's not just the internet that would disappear, but for example,
so my local telephone company tell us
they don't have a phone network. They have a single data network. Right?
They were the first phone company to do this. They have a single IP network.
That's fax, phone internet.
So, and that's the thing, right? Is how many companies now have a phone system?
No trick question. How many companies have a sip phone system?
All of them, how many actually have an old timey mechanical pots, phone system
answer
none of them because they're just stupidly expensive to maintain an obsolete now.
-- Yeah,
-- I hope the answer is none.
Because if you're using a pot system, you're getting ripped off.
Don't use that.
Yeah.
So that's the thing, right?
Is the internet disappearing would also be, well,
remember when the denial service against DNS happened and like Slack went offline.
And so all these companies that were
essentially part of their implicit uh, plan was, you know, we,
we communicate via Slack and suddenly Slack has gone.
Well, how do I contact my ops or my engineers? Do I not
remember for these guys?
Right. No, I, I know, man. I know exactly what you mean. It was, it was crazy.
-- So
-- it's tough to build resiliency when
you don't know necessarily what your, your dependencies are.
Uh, I'm reminded of all those people that get like two internet connections.
And it turns out they go over the same physical fiber, you know,
and it gets dug up and all the internet dies.
Yeah, I love that.
But, you know what? So, so, here's the thing though,
is
in this, this kind of harkens back to the beginning of the conversation is
if you're not actually testing your resiliency, you don't have resiliency. Right.
-- If you can't shut off the internet,
-- well, it goes back to,
you don't have backups until you restore for them.
That is true.
Right.
Until you restore from your backups,
you don't know that those are actually backups.
It's like Schrodinger's backup. Right.
Yeah,
I've had that happen.
I had a tape drive that would write happily, but turns out it wouldn't read,
uh, that was really common with tape drives though.
And in fact, read and write heads were different on many of them and,
and even if they were the same,
you could have issues with alignments. It was, it was very strange.
And in fact, I remember back in the day
when I, for some reason there was a time I was doing a lot of backup work.
I think that this is one of those things like
people I became known as the backup guy.
And, yeah, you'd have two, basically two tape libraries
and
you'd,
you'd bring the tapes from one to the other and you'd back up on
one library and then you would verify on the other one because you can't,
you couldn't back up and verify with the same drive
you had to use different drives.
And there was a, an article written about this how, you know,
until you operationally test stuff, you don't know that it works or not.
And I think that's one of the issues that a lot of these companies have is
so Maersk, uh, you know, the shipping giant had this happen with, uh,
which cryptovirus was it?
Um,
I want to say wanna cry.
-- It
-- was
not
pia, right.
Oh, not Petya. Yeah, that's the one.
And they had to, like,
shut down all their systems and they had like a global
reinstall reboot effort that took something like 10 or more days
and they had to do everything via like paper
and fax and apparently it was just a nightmare
and,
but there's a lot of companies now that literally can't do that.
Like Amazon can't go to paper and pen
and I'm not even talking about their, their, their,
it services and their cloud stuff.
I'm talking about like, just shipping that stuff to you that,
that can't work without computers.
I know.
I know exactly what you mean. It's
think about this one. I think it's, this is a tough one just because
it's like the modern electrical grid we can't live without
-- it.
-- That's a fair point. If, if, if electricity is down.
And in fact, I've,
I remember working places where you lose power
and they basically just said go home with,
you can't work.
And that's internet now, right?
When internet goes down, like, go home you can't work.
Well, funny story.
That's, I,
I know a place where that happened and the supervisor made everybody stay because,
and, like, you know, we're all in this together and,
but it literally was like, yeah, nobody could do anything.
Why would you make people stay?
Like, what's the purpose of that?
-- Oh, my goodness.
-- But yeah,
well,
this happened in Canada a couple of decades
ago where a small town lost their water source
and it basically ended up killing the town because
the water source was gone for long enough,
you know, kind of like, well, I guess the modern one would be Flint,
Michigan with their lead tainted water, right?
And this MP member of parliament wrote an open letter talking about essentially,
how do you kill a town in Canada?
And one of the quickest easiest ways to do it
is not have a water source,
you know, especially when people we're used to having one, right?
Like it's one thing out of my parents' cabin, we don't have running water.
So we, you know, we bring in containers of water,
ok? It's a pain in the ass, but it works.
But like my home here if I didn't have running water all of a sudden, ok,
I can't use the toilets.
I can't wash my hands. I can't prepare for food. I,
you know, what do we do? Right.
Go to the cabin and rip out the waterless toilet and bring it home.
-- I guess
-- every, everyone gets cholera. That's what happens.
Typhoid and dysentery.
Interesting.
-- And that's the thing.
-- We,
we,
some things you just have to rely upon because to not rely
upon them and to build a system to not rely upon,
it is so expensive.
Like to build
a waterless house in the middle of the city could totally be done, you know,
water
on the roof.
It is actually illegal to not have the water hookups. No, that's actually a thing
where if you're not essentially hooking up to the local utilities,
your your domicile would not be, it wouldn't pass inspection,
right? The city would not pass it.
Alright. So
basically, it's just not economically feasible now,
at this point to live without internet,
right? So, so you,
you raise an interesting point. I think this is something for us to think about.
It may maybe talk about next week, but is the fact that
there are certain minimum expectations
in any system. And, and I have a suspicion at this point.
Internet is kind of one of them. But,
but
where do we draw some of our lines in saying
this is something we should care about and we
have to test for because like for example,
uh a data center might test a power outage, but like,
I don't test them at my house because that would be dumb.
Right.
Uh I did, uh, what I would do is actually
I would do it not to test, but to make sure I plugged everything into the right thing.
Right.
Because occasionally, for example, I had, when I, back when I had a workstation,
the workstation was plugged into the search or into the power,
uh providing like the power,
providing part of the UPS and my monitor was plugged into the surge.
Only part.
So, when I tested it,
I was like, oh,
I can't log into my computer and turn it off because the monitor doesn't work.
So, what I used to occasionally do is I would go down to the basement,
flip the main breaker and then wander around the house and
make sure I could actually turn off all my computers.
And I quickly discovered that I had a bad habit
of plugging the monitors into the surge only port,
not the battery protected port.
So,
testing it does make sense. But now I don't bother because they're all laptops.
-- It, it depends. Right. We'll just, we'll leave it there and it's
-- an easy enough test.
You go flip a main breaker five minutes later you turn it back on and
also, then you get to go reset clocks. Right. Because your stove, your microwave.
Yeah, I do hate resetting clocks. All right.
Anyway, I'm, I'm gonna call it and I think we should, we should maybe think about
some of this, what, what services and, and kind of things do we do we need
that we can test, or rather rather,
I would say let's reframe it from the security perspective
of what makes sense to test and what doesn't.
So, and, and maybe it's everything, I don't know. I don't know.
All right, I'm, I'm calling it. Uh Thank you, Kurt. Thank you
for listening.
It was fun.
If you want any of the show notes, you can go to open source security podcast.com.
Uh,
if you know the answer to any of the questions
we couldn't answer today about kind of some of the,
the things going on with the military, uh, by all means, you know, you know,
let us know.
Don't, don't get yourself in trouble, but,
uh, we, we'd love to know the answers.
So, so hit us up on Twitter maybe, or Facebook. There's a Facebook group.
You can use the Pound Os S Podcast hashtag to get our attention.
And yeah, if nothing else, I guess Kurt, you have a fabulous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks
the