Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner Josh Pressers.
I'm not your partner in Thought Crime anymore. Are we done with Thought Crime or?
-- What's the deal?
-- We'll see thinking of something new,
something better than Thought crime.
It's getting a little too real.
This episode doesn't really lend itself to thought crime,
-- does it?
-- I don't know. What are we talking about?
Well, put it in the notes.
-- Project Zero news and updates from Project Zero team at Google.
-- Yeah.
But the audience doesn't know I put it in the notes. This is how it works.
It's the magic of a podcast cart.
Yeah. Yeah.
So anyway, there's this report that Google put out and it got me a little,
a little wound up.
We'll say
it's,
I
-- guess it's a report.
-- It's a blog post. Well, look, my,
my bar for what I call a report is very low. OK.
I was going to say it's a blog post but actually is based on some real data.
-- It has
-- data in it. It has cve
I in it and I don't care about any of that stuff.
It basically the thing I want to focus on is the last couple
of paragraphs of the whole report because I will summarize what happens is
so Google Project Zero does phenomenal work.
I don't think anyone will deny that.
And one of the things they've done is they've uncovered
and researched a number of old days in the wild.
So this, this blog post,
they publish kind of focuses on the fact that
there were a handful of these that were discovered
and then fixed and then Attackers figured out again.
-- Right.
Well, they fixed the bug but there were like slight variants,
-- shell
-- shock. Right.
Yeah. Right.
Where
-- that's such a story
-- and it, and it's also not just slight variants,
but sometimes it's, the bug
was caused by some sort of underlying assumption about reality or
about how stuff works and that assumption was also made elsewhere.
Right. Right. So, yes, exactly.
So, anyway, they, they basically kind of lay out, they explain, you know,
here was the original bug,
here's what was found and they go into an amazing amount of detail.
I think
there were a couple of things that hit me on the data itself is number one,
it's almost all web browsers
-- in fairness. That's what matters nowadays.
-- I do agree with that.
That's what's remotely attack.
-- And that's what, how else do you use a computer?
-- Right.
And it's like the old, you know, why do you rob banks?
It's because it's where the money is, right?
I mean, obviously you could, you could write an O day for, I don't know,
-- something bash or whatever
-- solar winds.
That's a, that's a different story.
But
you know what I mean? This is a situation.
Duh,
obviously web browsers are going to be attacked
because web browsers are where the opportunity is.
Well, and especially the big two IE and Chrome
and Firefox is in there. Yeah.
-- And
-- so Safari kind of, but
it's look, it's all the web browsers, right?
That's just the reality of it is the bad guys are going
to put their money and their effort into web browser expo.
I get it makes sense. Right. Right.
Now, the thing that has me wound up is kind of at the end
they talk about when you build your patches,
you should make sure you're doing it right.
And you should pay attention to all this other stuff and you could
work with us to make it better and all this and all that.
And I just kept thinking this is literally some of the worst advice I've ever
seen from security people because the answer is quit using effing c full stop.
-- Well, but we can't sunk, fallacy costs.
-- No, no, no sunk cost. Fallacy is garbage.
How much do these things cost the universe versus how much
would it cost you to start rewriting some of this crap?
But here's the thing. How much does it cost the universe?
Versus how much does it cost the company? One of those is a number I don't have to pay
-- and there's your answer,
-- you're not wrong.
And this is part of what has me annoyed is, there's like I feel like
in my mind there are 600 levels of annoyance at everything going on here and
it's everything from the people saying just
security harder to the people saying whatever.
-- I don't have to pay for it. It's not my problem.
-- Well, and even if, even if you try
is security harder and smarter and do things like, oh you know, we found this bug,
let's do a proper root cause analysis and squish all the instances of it.
Yeah, I mean, if you're looking at this, it's all, it's C code where
managing
memory, managing pointers, managing,
managing all this stuff constantly,
people get it wrong and this isn't like throwaway code or simple code.
Somebody wrote on a weekend. This is,
you know,
this is stuff in chrome and IE and Safari and Firefox
-- that has been through how many code reviews
-- all of them.
And it's had a gazillion.
People look at it and it's been fuzzed and
put through static analyzers and all of the things and
the reality is we still can't make it secure
because it's C and that's just how C works.
Yeah. And then my question is, well, so what is that good enough? Well, clearly not.
Well, no, no, no. No, but what I mean is ok. So we have a big pile of cvs and
all the web browsers.
But does it really matter? I don't care that much.
I mean, I browse the web on a, yeah, it's a windows machine
using chrome
and I honestly update when it flashes that green thing or that
red thing when I let it go for a day or two.
And I really,
honestly, I don't care. I, I spend,
I probably spend more time thinking about cheese
than I do about my web browser security.
That, ok, so that is kind of a different problem.
And this is in my, in my mind house of madness here, this is also part of that.
Is there is the angle of you could say, well, I don't care.
Well, no, no,
it's I'm actually saying I don't care because I have objective proof
that as terrible as it is over the last 20 years of we
b
the world keeps working.
Yeah, there's, there's a lot of external, it's like potholes. Yeah, I hate,
there's three potholes on my way to my kids' house that are really hard to avoid.
Fundamentally as terrible as C is and as terrible as these web browsers are,
you know, the world keeps working.
And I think here's the other thing is,
is part of it is it doesn't matter because there are
so many people that can't or won't upgrade their web browser
or operating system or whatever because they have something
that's certified to work only with XY and Z
and they're stuck with it because it's, you know,
it's a cell counting machine or AC NC Mill or a piece of medical equipment.
-- I mean,
-- ok, look,
-- that is a corner case and I'm going to no longer let you corner case
-- me.
-- It's a corner case with millions of instances.
-- It's not enough to matter.
We're talking about trillions and even if it's millions,
I don't care, I'm not talking about this. It's a corner case.
I don't care about the corner cases don't obsess over it. It's not a helpful,
it's not helpful to the conversation.
So
you are not incorrect in saying that the world continues to work.
I think you could sort of make that argument. But I think the problem is that
the failure scenario in many of these cases is catastrophic.
What do you mean by catastrophic?
So like solar winds will be what I pick on where
a lot of when you're talking about an O day,
you're also talking about a very targeted attack.
Someone is going after a very specific thing.
-- Not always,
-- the web browser, zero days are quite often used in, you know,
a drive bys or whatever or especially once they're not 00 days.
-- I mean,
-- maybe, maybe there's, there's going to be some of that.
But I think generally speaking, right,
we're talking about a target with value for some reason and some of these
we will never learn about for obvious reasons and some of them we will.
And so I think
there's an aspect of that is you and I
don't matter,
right? Or as some of these targets do. But more importantly, and the thing
that, that just consumes me from the inside is that unless a lot of people get killed,
no one's ever going to care.
And that's the other thing that just drives me bananas sometimes because
like a great example of this is we are recording this.
I think what, like a day or two after that whole incident in Florida,
the water treatment place where some hacker tried to like poison the town.
-- I tried
-- to increase the lie levels in the water from 100 parts per million to 11,000,
100 parts per million.
It's very specific that, you know, that I like that.
-- I literally just read the article
-- because it didn't work.
-- I guarantee you nothing will happen.
-- Well, no, no, it worked.
They saw him do it and they flipped it back.
-- But
-- I mean, he didn't kill anyone unless like he literally killed the town.
Nothing is going to change is my prediction.
We're going, we're going to whine and complain and gnash our teeth and then
that's it.
Human beings have always had a million things that could
kill most or all of us at some point,
you know,
uh and food safety is a great example of the outgrowth of this, you know, chicken,
you know, listeria salmonella and all those horrific bacteria.
You know, we're currently going through a pandemic.
We had mutually sure destruction when we grew up as Children.
And so I think part of the problem is there's always
this huge laundry list of stuff that could kill us all.
You know,
the, the animals could escape from the zoo and eat us all or, you know,
self driving cars could rise up and kill us all.
And sort of where do we allocate those resources for things
that are kind of a problem because let's put it this way
in the entirety of human history.
How many times have we actually gotten together and
actually gotten rid of a significant risk to us?
And the only one I can really think of that's a super success is a smallpox, right?
Humanity got rid of smallpox, we can do it and once in a while we do,
-- but measles and polio are making a comeback because people, I
-- would even reframe it.
The way I like to think about this all the time is automobile safety.
If you look at automobile safety
before things like seatbelts and airbags and
all this other safety equipment was mandatory.
A
ridiculous number of people died because cars were unsafe.
Well, we keep going back to that, the Bel Air crash, the new and the old one, you know,
the Bel Air
-- is just horrifying.
-- Yes, exactly.
It is difficult for people to say I care about this
thing when it doesn't necessarily have a direct effect on you.
Like if I for example,
am in a burning house saying get out and put the fire out is of immediate need.
That's easy to understand.
There is a lion looking at me across the field that is an immediate need.
I understand that saying that
the web browser I'm using has security vulnerabilities and
maybe someone could steal my bank account information.
Like
what? Well, and you know what?
I was just thinking, it's worse than that because it's,
it's a combination of a centralized and decentralized problem in that you have
this massive centralized organization that has to make the changes to the code,
test it and ship it and that's a ton of effort and money.
And so they kind of don't really want to do that,
but they have to,
if they do that, that's not enough.
That's
the start.
Now you have to convince 100 plus million
or billion people to actually install the update.
Well, that,
that's another problem and that's why like
automatic updates need to exist because people
are just never going to care and they're never going to do it.
It's not even that they're not going to do it, man.
I have automatic updates enabled on every single I device I have on most
of my computers where possible and the other day about a week ago.
So I'm on my Windows 10 computer and I
went to the Microsoft store to look for something.
I forget what it was.
And I noticed an update tab and I'm like, oh, that's interesting. I clicked on it
and I had about 20 apps that were not updated.
I have automatic updates enabled for that.
So I hit the update all button and it basically started downloading all the
data on the internet because there's a whole pile of stuff that needed updating.
But I was like, I, I wanted you to automatically update.
This computer is turned on pretty much all the time.
It's hooked up to Gigabit Ethernet to Gigabit
internet.
So it's not like I don't have enough bandwidth but just
something somewhere went wrong with the automated updates and it wasn't.
So I had a whole pile of un updated
apps, some of which I used to connect to the internet and do stuff.
-- Let's say that's a corner case.
-- No, no, no.
What what I'm saying is even when you want it to go, right?
And even when you want to automatic update and even when you like,
I desperately want to keep my computer as up to date as possible.
So that if there is a problem with an update,
I encounter it as quickly as possible and I know why it happened.
Oh, I updated X and something broke first is a
month from now.
I update everything and something breaks and it's kind of like, well,
what broke it because it was, I updated everything.
And so even in that case where I want everything updated and I try to make it update,
it fails. It doesn't always automatically update. To put it bluntly, this, this
problem,
you have that centralized problem where you got to convince some big org to do it.
You have the decentralized issue where you have to convince everybody
to vote or to tie their shoes or to look both ways
when they cross the street and even when they have a
good computer that's up to date and on a good connection,
it still doesn't work.
Right. And how many people
have cell phones with no data plan and only have
access to good bandwidth when they're out of Starbucks.
I'm going to stop you.
Do you've fallen in the very typical trap of
security people of instead of talking about one problem.
Now, we're talking about 50 problems and we can't solve 50 problems.
But, and that's part of the problem.
It's an ecosystem of problems and we can't just solve them one at a time.
We have to, ideally,
I keep coming back to this markets and incentives if we can incentivize and
get people to want to update that solves a whole bunch of these problems all at once.
Maybe.
I mean,
that's part of the discussion I think is we fall into this trap of telling people to
security harder or throwing our hands up and saying it's too hard or just being like,
I don't care really whatever.
There's been examples of subtle or major incentive
changes that have essentially completely fixed problems.
-- Yes.
-- And that's something we don't understand how to do. Like, if I tell you, Kurt
here is infinite money.
Go fix the auto update problem. You probably can't.
-- I would buy everybody a new iphone.
-- Although
I will take infinite money if someone has it. Like I will try really hard.
The interest alone on the float would be worth it.
But like this is,
I think this is part of our problem
is our issues aren't necessarily resources or saying,
oh, we can't do that because we don't have the budget for it.
Like there are problems that revolve around budget don't get me wrong.
But I think in many instances we just like, we don't even know what to do sometimes.
Yeah. Well, I think the problem is these are interrelated.
It's like, it's like traffic safety, right. The city I live in Edmonton has this
zero vision,
traffic safety thing where essentially nobody dies in
traffic accidents at some point in the future.
And it's kind of like, yeah, maybe, hopefully,
but I'm pretty sure we're never going to get there,
which is a sort of a depressing statement.
But at the same time, I'm not saying we shouldn't work towards it,
but it's so many different things.
Right.
It's,
it's things like maybe having people actually
respect speed limits around school zones.
-- The
-- solution to, I bet 90% of those problems is self driving cars.
Oh, absolutely.
That will, that will solve 90% of it.
Humans are bad drivers. Like, you know what it is?
I just realized this, like,
complaining about humans writing C code is the same as letting humans drive.
Like it is the same problem.
You think you're good, but you're not
-- like that is
-- all
-- the
-- other and you can
solve specific problems.
You know, the city, for example, puts in traffic abatement, you know,
they put in speed bumps, they put in the little zigzag
things, you know, to, to reduce speed in certain roads
and that'll solve maybe, you know, it's basically a CV E patch, right?
We, oh you know, there's a lot of traffic taking 95th ave between 142nd and 149th.
So they put in a little tiny traffic circle that makes it kind of more awkward.
But the flip side was they had people doing donuts
around it for a while when they built it.
But uh well,
paved
circle,
that's just the equivalent of using like unnecessary C pointers.
You look cool but don't do it, you know.
So there's this constant sort of trying to patch if
we put in enough marked pedestrian crosswalks with flashing lights,
maybe city buses will stop running over old people,
if we maybe enforce speed limits, enough people will stop dying in, you know,
speed related crashes.
-- No,
-- that's ridiculous.
You can't say, how do you enforce,
saying enforced speed limits is just saying security harder.
Yeah, exactly.
And, and that's the thing, right?
Traffic is an ecosystem and the solution to the ecosystem is
a completely new thing which well is self driving cars and,
ok.
Ok.
For example,
everybody works from home and stops commuting that would cut down traffic a lot.
-- Although,
-- although not quite so in Wisconsin where I live in the United States,
obviously a lot more people started working from home
and the amount of traffic on the roads decreased substantially,
but the number of fatalities remain the same.
Yeah.
Here they found people uh
driving faster, right?
And that's exactly what they think it is, is people are more reckless.
So the like less, there are way less cars on the road,
but just as many people are dying because the people on the road are like, oh,
I can do whatever I want. But again,
humans like this is what humans do. Humans are humans and whatever,
but
so, ok. Ok.
I want, I want to bring us back to earth here because that's enough traffic talk
for a while.
I don't think you're wrong in saying
this is an ecosystem and saying this is a big problem.
But I think I don't know how to even talk about this.
Necessarily,
I don't feel like we have the language to even describe what our problems are.
And that bothers me greatly
and I was about to say, ignoring the vocabulary issue.
Do we have actually any strategic policy or even a simple statement
that actually defines what we want to do? I mean, food safety is a good one.
Food safety, you can basically summarize us.
Well, let's have food that's safe and doesn't make people sick through, you know,
various bacterial and viral contaminants.
Boom.
Done that pretty much covers all your, your food heating,
cooking issues right there.
Done food storage, food safety, you know,
don't have the chicken dripping on the vegetables.
Cool.
Right. What do we do for
security?
Flavored juice?
Uh, I,
I agree with this.
I, I feel but so here's, here's the other thing that I'm wondering now is,
is this because computer security is
too hard or is it too big
-- or is it just not, are we not even thinking about it in the right way?
-- You want to say?
Too hard, too big? I mean, we had
nuclear deterrent, you know,
they built things that cost hundreds of billions of dollars.
You know, the dew line, the pine tree line, you know,
these radar stations that the missile silos, the bombers, the submarines, you,
the whole space race was basically a giant measuring contest to prove that, hey,
I can put this heavy thing in orbit and land it on the ground somewhere.
I want to
-- wink. Wink.
-- But let's even go.
Well, no one knows why.
Uh, let's even go further back though. I feel like sometimes
you, you, the solution is food safety. Right.
But I'm talking about,
oh, that chicken was infected by a demon and when you ate it, the demon killed you.
Like,
no, it's not a demon.
And I feel like in, in the security war,
we're talking about chicken bones and evil spirits and that has nothing.
You know, like those aren't problems, those aren't real things.
-- I
-- keep coming back to, you know,
we can't really just replace all the sea code bases because sunk cost.
But at the same time, we clearly can't secure them.
And from a manageability point of view, they're a disaster.
The sunk cost fallacy says, don't say that
-- since they do say that for
-- example, infrastructure, you know,
we had an old bridge here in Edmonton.
It was an old rail bridge,
it was converted to roads or to be a road bridge and
it was literally falling apart because it was over 100 years old.
So we built a new bridge and destroyed the old one.
And the new bridge is actually quite nice, much wider, much safer, you know,
better pedestrian access, blah, blah, blah.
And
I part of the challenge is I think with computing,
we're not sure we, we haven't built good safe tools yet.
I mean, things like rust are starting to get there.
You know, it's, it's not like civil engineering where here's,
you want to build a bridge from A to B, here's how you do it safely.
You know,
software is still very much getting people to agree on which language to use,
bringing up things like bridge building is an
interesting comparison because to build a bridge,
you have to be what's called a, well, in the United States,
we call them professional engineers where you basically, like,
you have to sit for these tests and you have to basically get a license
and then you can
build a bridge because like, if I built a bridge, I'm, I'm not qualified to do that and
like, it would probably kill people.
And then they'd be like, why did you let this idiot build a bridge?
You know, like, obviously,
well, and not just, it's worse than that.
It's, it's not just building the bridge, it's designing the bridge, like locally,
our bridge was designed quite well
and then apparently the welds on it were not up to spec and so the city was like, well,
it's not our problem, you know,
let the subcontractors sue each other and sort it out.
But as long once it passes inspection, it passes inspection.
Here's the really interesting part though is I can't just, well,
I could basically build a bridge on my own if I owned property or something, right.
Which I'm sure some people might have done and like, if you've done that,
send me pictures, I'd love to see them.
But
software is completely different because anybody can write software.
Anybody, like, there's no limitation. There's no, oh, like to build a bridge.
You need millions of dollars. Like no, you need what, a credit card and five bucks.
-- And you've got an internet website, you know,
-- one thing I've never understood is why
there is
so much software. A perfect example is skater
software, right?
I checked once and there's about 1000 companies globally writing skater software.
You know, ranging from really big ones,
like say Schneider Electric down to five guys, not the burger chain, but actually,
you know, five people writing skater software.
Uh sorry, I need to qualify that for our American listeners
and I,
I get that there needs to be different
sk of software for different hardware platforms and
for different sort of industry verticals like mining is
different than say chicken processing to some degree.
But fundamentally do there actually need to be 1000 companies doing this
globally and replicating that effort and
replicating those mistakes and problems.
-- I mean,
-- maybe who's to say you're right or wrong?
Well,
I can't feel I can't help but feel like that's part of
the problem we have is that we have so much replicated effort.
But is it, I mean, are you saying that there should be six restaurants in the,
in the world and all these, all these little places.
-- They're just duplicating effort.
-- I'm not saying there should be
-- restaurants, but there's only six ways to build a bridge.
-- I mean, that's not true.
There's a bazillion ways to build you.
-- There's an infinite number of ways to make a bridge.
-- No, no, no, no.
There are six basic designs, cantilever arch. Um
Anyways, I can't find the list right now, but
there's basically, there are 60 trust, trust is the other one.
But anyway, the point is
there's six ways
six fundamentally structural ways to build a bridge.
And yeah, there's a million variations on it.
You can paint it pink, you can paint it brown, whatever.
But fundamentally, you know, it's like building a road.
There's, you know, we can use asphalt,
we can use concrete where we could maybe use cobblestones if we
want to look at an old timey thing or gravel and dirt.
-- I mean,
-- I don't, I don't know if this is a valid comparison to software.
-- For
-- example, why do we need Internet Explorer and Chrome and Firefox and Safari?
When ironically,
aren't they kind of basically all based off
the same underlying engine at this point.
-- Safari is still its own thing,
-- right?
Well, Safari and Chrome share a common ancestor in what used to be called K HTML,
which was a KDE HTML library, which was,
and then they kind of diverged in their own direction.
Firefox was its own thing.
Internet Explorer had its own engine as well,
which eventually turned into edge and then eventually Microsoft was like,
screw it Chromium one.
And now they're using the Chromium engine
but I don't, I don't even know if this is the right
conversation to be having because saying well,
-- but
-- this is an example of now we don't
have four completely separate built from scratch engines.
-- We have sort of a more common engine that's still
-- written in C
exactly
like,
well, but at least we've agreed on the internal combustion engine and we're,
we've stopped trying to put raccoons and gas tanks in a formula one race.
Maybe, maybe I, I don't, I don't know.
Well,
would you agree with the statement that it would be
harder to secure multiple code bases than less code bases?
No. And the reason being is that
it is still a giant pile of sea code.
I would say if, if there is a line of,
let's say a couple of 1000 lines of sea code that once you surpass it,
it doesn't matter how many lines you have,
you just have a mess and having four browser engines or having one browser engine.
You think of it as if you lump all of the code into one place,
you cross the line almost instantly
and I think one or four is unmaintainable. It doesn't matter.
Well, I I'm talking more about it from a high level view.
For example, with one general code base,
you could at least get some decisions made on
it that affect most of the world rather than,
you know, chrome decides to go and make zero days harder.
I hope Internet Explorer and Microsoft did as well.
-- And I would like to think Apple and Safari are doing that.
-- Everyone's trying.
But the only right answer is quit using freakin C four or one.
-- If they're all in c it doesn't matter because it all sucks.
-- I agree.
But I'm talking more about a perfect example.
It's the whole Cups thing that I tweeted about right where cup
is dead
and open printing is
supposedly taken over it except open printing is not mentioned
on the Cups website meaningfully or on the cups,
github at all.
I don't even know what, what is open printing. I don't even know what that is.
It's a fork of Cups.
OK. That's it.
It's a fork of Cups that's actually being maintained by the community.
I have no idea how well that's nice, good or bad it is. But whatever.
But the point is like, for example, Google Fuzz,
there's an issue where Google Fuzz filed an issue saying, hey,
we'd like to Fuzz Cups and like come play nice with us.
And of course, it's been ignored because Cups is dead.
I checked the open printing github
for that.
It couldn't find that issue.
Like,
I don't know if Google Fuzz doesn't know about open printing or if
they don't think it's important enough or whatever because it's a fork.
But the point is if Cups was still alive, for example,
it would be getting that Google open fuzzing
stuff.
Whereas now, because there's two code bases because one died and one is active.
Now, we kind of have to replicate that effort and it's more,
there's more friction and there's more stuff to do to kind of get the same result.
-- I,
-- I don't like this example because like cups is just dead full stop.
Like everyone should be focusing all their effort onto the other thing.
What I'm trying to get at though is we've never had as far as I can tell.
The only industry that's like software with
all this ridiculous replication is cooking,
right?
Every restaurant has a chef that makes this slightly different version of recipes.
But the difference being it's just a slightly different taste in curry,
not something that like you said is going to be possessed by demons and make you die.
Let me, let me, I can do one better. And I think this is a great comparison.
I think it's a great way to bring the show out on is cooking is a marvelous example.
And if you have a restaurant,
the health department is going to come and inspect you.
And if you're serving rotten chicken,
they're going to shut down your restaurant and tell you
you can't be open anymore until you fix this problem.
And now I'm not suggesting we should
have software inspectors because that sounds horrifying.
But we have software inspectors.
Source code fuzzing and it's awesome and it works perfectly.
No, it doesn't.
Anyway.
That was sarcasm.
Yeah, that was,
you're a little too serious. That one was too real. But, like, I mean, I think this is,
this is one of our challenges is
we have software. Anyone can build it.
But if I write terrible software,
no one gets sick and dies. So no one really cares you like.
The only reason health departments exist is
because if the restaurant makes bad food,
I might get sick and die and people freak out about that.
Well, but even when people do get sick and die, metaphorically speaking,
like this whole solar winds thing, it's not like they stop using it.
I mean, I just got a letter from service experts, Canada,
this giant organization that basically kind of runs the
back end for a bunch of HVAC companies,
you know, heating and ventilation.
So they had a data breach with ransomware and I got a
letter with a 1 to 800 number I can call to,
I guess, complain about and they're giving me this useless advice like, you know,
make sure your credit score is good and don't,
you know,
don't basically fill out credit forms online that were
sent to you via S MS text or email,
right?
Just useless stuff. And it just makes me angry because
I did not have a direct relationship with service experts,
Canada and I cannot do anything about this.
I'm stuck with their crappy data security pretty much.
And in the software world it's the same,
like I have bought this software because they have some sort of security flaw.
It's not like I'm going to throw it out and buy a different
one because it's not like the different one is going to be secure.
Right.
And, and, but you said something really important just a minute ago.
And I want to kind of end on this point as you said, you know,
solar winds of metaphorically getting sick and dying,
metaphorically doesn't count like people have to litter.
I die before anyone cares and not just a couple people,
it has to be thousands to millions of people.
And I'm going to like this, this bothers me to say,
-- I'm
-- not even sure man because I'm looking
at the COVID situation and it's like that hasn't
actually gotten people to just wear a mask
-- and wash their hands
-- that has active disinformation,
working towards it.
So
-- the software industry
-- and I think it does.
And so this, this makes it because obviously, if I suggested that
we need government regulation of all software sold to the public, I can only imagine
the the the hate that would come raining down upon me and some of
it would be would be real and some of it would be manufactured.
But even then you think about the labor
movement where they were advocating for worker safety,
there was enormous disinformation coming from these
industries who didn't want to change.
I mean, when you can externalize costs like that,
right?
And look,
they have almost nothing to lose with
disinformation because that's going to add cost and
suffering on their part even though it will make like society in general better.
And so, but again, at the same time, like you said, at the very beginning,
the world goes on like, is it that bad?
Not really is having a web browser that sucks better than having no web browser?
Absolutely. So in summary,
after our discussion, I have no idea.
-- I
-- just, I'll leave us on two depressing notes.
In late 2018, Toyota recalled nearly 2.5 million
vehicles after finding a software glitch, blah, blah, blah.
In 2019, a jury ordered the company to pay a $15.8 million in damages. Ok.
Whatever $15.8 million is their coffee budget.
Here is the one thing I will end on and,
and this will tie it back to the Google part
is if your advice is ever just security harder,
you suck.
-- That's all.
-- Yeah, I,
I don't know what to say at this point because I've seen people
try security harder and I've seen people like Google Project Zero is,
is actually security and harder in
a
I'm not sure it's effective
to
put it bluntly. No, I'm really not sure that it's truly effective.
-- It makes for cool reports. So I'll let them go.
-- They're fixing Cve.
But again, does that, is that really?
We should talk about this someday because we're out of time?
But I have a suspicion, Google Project Zeros is more about
attention
than
actually fixing things. But that's another story. So anyway, I'm going to end this.
So, thank you, Kurt. Thank you, everyone for listening.
Go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up the show note, Suy
Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag Do you hit us up on social media? Kurt?
You have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody. Please hit like and subscribe.
Sure, thanks. Ring that bell.
All right, thanks everybody. Bye bye
the