Hello and welcome to the open source Security podcast episode 75
with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime. Josh Bresser.
What is New Kurt?
Uh, just getting ready for Christmas?
Oh,
I should start getting ready for Christmas.
All I can say is thank God for Amazon.
Yes, I agree.
Amazon is amazing because you go into a store
and you spend an hour not finding anything.
And then by the time you walk back to your car you've ordered
the thing you went looking for.
Amazon.
I've actually started doing that when I'm at Home
Depot and they don't have the thing I want.
Seriously, man. I, I know exactly what you mean.
There,
there are a handful of items I really like to
touch and make sure I understand what I'm getting.
But for the most part, I've, I've given up, I just ordered off Amazon.
It's so much easier.
Yeah.
No, I just got a new mattress for, you know,
and they ship it via UPS and it gets here in like three days and
you have 100 days to sleep on it if you
don't like it because we're actually getting rid of.
We, we previously bought a mattress and it was,
it was just honestly too squishy and I love the reviews of all these
mattresses online because the people that bother to leave reviews it boils down to
49% say it's too squishy and they hate it.
49% say it's too hard and they hate it and 2% are like, it's ok.
So
we had this mattress for about a month and a half tried it. It just too squishy.
We got a different one and yeah, we're much happier with it.
Great.
Now, now, can you just keep it for like 90 days and then return it
-- and then get another one from someone else?
-- You know what?
You probably could because there's enough companies doing this now.
Uh, but the problem is that the refund takes quite a while to recycle.
So, like it's, you know,
I'm not going to get my money back for like a week or two or three.
Um, so you'd essentially be carrying the cost of like two mattresses at any time.
So, I guess you might as well just buy one.
Right. Right.
I suspect not only that the pain and suffering of having to
deal with changing mattresses on a regular basis is probably
not worth.
Here's the interesting thing is they have a charity come pick it up and the
charity is happy because now they get like a big pile of nice new mattresses
and I'm happy because I didn't have to schlep this thing out or like,
try to attach enough postage to it to send it back to wherever.
So, does it come in like a mattress size box or do they, like,
it's like vacuum
compressed and sealed? So
the new one came in a box. It's about a foot.
Uh, it's about a foot and a half by foot and a half by about 4 ft tall.
It weighs about 100 and 21 pounds.
So the poor ups lady was just end over end.
It was like good thump and then she'd, like, raise it up on its end and, like,
pitch it over a thump.
Right? Because it's just too bulky to carry. Right.
Unless you're like, Andre the giant.
Um,
but I was just thinking it's, it's interesting because, like I was,
I asked the mattress guys, like, have you seen a lot of these?
And he's like, yeah, we see about one a week. So
it's,
you know, it's a source of really nice mattresses for these charities, right?
Because there's absolutely no way you can ship this thing back
for less than like 1000 bucks, right? Because it's,
it's
a,
you know, it's a mattress,
you know. But, uh, yeah, so, no, I'm, I'm really, again, it's like, how do or not?
How, but why would anybody go buy a mattress in a regular store where you get to, like,
lie down on it for five minutes and then you,
you're expected to spend like one or $2000
and if it doesn't work out for you, you know, my experience with trying to uh
return expensive things to stores because I don't like them,
especially something like a mattress is a nightmare.
You know,
versus these online guys where you just send them an email and they're like, oh,
we're sorry,
like, and that's it.
That's literally the return process and then a guy comes and picks it up.
Right.
So,
but it got me thinking. So Christmas is coming.
And what's something much like Thanksgiving in the US?
What's something we all end up doing at Christmas?
Uh fixing all of our relatives, computers?
Yes. Right. Exactly.
Uh
So,
so with that in mind,
I came across this thing called security planner.org.
Yeah.
Uh,
it was actually mentioned on Bruce Schneier's blog
and his disclaimer was he's involved in it.
So he's obviously pro security planner. But,
um I opened up the website. I haven't tried it yet.
And so what we're going to do today is the, the premise seems to be,
improve your reading from the website here,
improve your online safety with advice from experts.
Answer a few simple questions to get personalized online safety recommendations.
It's confidential.
No personal information is stored and we won't access any of your online accounts.
Let's do it.
Um So with that in mind, Josh and I are going to walk through this
to see what the advice is. You know? Is the advice good. Is it ridiculous?
Is it actually useful?
Because
I,
I think we're kind of getting to the point where a
lot of people have computers that are reasonably well behaved.
You know, it's not like, well,
hopefully it's not like running what malware bites for six hours.
Um, but, you know, hopefully you've got some relatives who's,
maybe you can help them with their online security
maybe. Or we're going to get a good laugh because this site's maybe terrible.
-- Let's, let's find out. Right.
-- So I'm
clicking the orange button.
All right.
-- Oh,
-- ok.
Can I
choose all that apply?
-- I like this because it separates iphones and ipads from Android.
-- You
have
to
tell people what you're seeing. So,
the
first, the first, oh, I thought you were going to read, uh,
the first question is what do you use to handle your private information?
Choose all that apply? And your options are iphone or ipad.
Uh, next option, Android phone or tablet.
Next option, Mac computer, next option, Windows, computer, next option, email,
uh, next option, social media accounts.
-- Next option, online shopping and banking and next option, other. So my,
-- my question
that there isn't Linux computer on the
list.
Well, yeah.
Um, well, Android.
But, um, my one thought here is shouldn't like email and sort of social media
be like pre-elected because how, how does anybody avoid using email.
So, if I was going to guess, I bet
people don't associate social media and email is the same thing,
which is why they disconnected them.
Yeah.
Right.
So,
I'm basically selecting everything except for android phone windows and other,
-- I'm assuming others like PS four and stuff,
-- just click them all.
Kurt, click them all.
Ok. Clicking it all. And then you click next,
click all your top online security concerns. Choose all that apply.
Uh So your options are unauthorized. Access to my online accounts.
Yeah, that's definitely a concern.
Accidentally downloading viruses, malware or other harmful software.
Yes.
And to wit, I'm always shocked when I download a piece of software,
run it through virus total.com and I'm like the first person to have done.
So
I find that rather sad.
Um
You know, uh third option protecting my data if my devices are lost or stolen. Yep.
Uh number four, better privacy for my web browsing. And I like the icon.
It's a little laptop with like some window shades,
right? I was just gonna say that it's very nice.
Yeah, the graphics on this are nice, very accessible. Um
better privacy for my communications. OK.
Uh People around me can see my screen now.
This is literally my one nonconcern because I work from home.
-- No, no,
-- you, you work from home
but
you, you do travel every now and then
and
I, I travel a fair bit. So I got a screen protector not protector privacy filter.
I think they call them
because.
Right. Right.
And so you basically can't see my screen except if you're directly behind me,
which I know isn't perfect, but it doesn't.
Right.
So,
this is a reasonable concern, I think,
yeah, I've noticed on airplanes,
especially when people do have a good screen and even sitting next to them,
I can't see their screen.
So I would say that they do work because quite frankly, if somebody's like up
right in behind you being a creeper,
hopefully you'll notice.
No, they, they work great. It's definitely worth every penny.
Uh One here,
I'm not super clear on it says accessing blocked websites and I'm
assuming that's more for maybe people in other countries where stuff gets blocked
uh
could be,
I don't know. I'm gonna
tell
us
and then I'll click. I'm not sure because I'm not sure.
Oh, if you click, I'm not sure it deselects everything else.
So,
yeah.
So it's,
this is, this feels very,
choose your own adventure where I feel like we're going to have to go back
and do things again.
And hopefully we don't make the wrong decision and get uh you know,
killed in a landslide or something.
All right, clicking next. Finally are any of these statements? True.
Choose all that apply.
Number one, I would like information about being anonymous online. Yes, I would.
Number two, I am dealing with an urgent digital security issue. Ok.
I'm curious about that.
I assume that means somebody who's getting doxed, like, online or something
that's, or, or it could be a matter of like, like,
people know when their email gets hacked and then
they don't always know what to do about it.
In fact, I had,
I, I can't remember. It was, oh, it wasn't that long ago.
Um,
a neighbor calls me and it is basically telling me what's happened
and it's clear someone's taken over the computer and I said,
like,
just turn off the internet and turn your computer off and then I'll be over in an hour.
And, yeah.
So, so that, that might be good advice to, to have that option.
That's true.
Um, next option. I'm concerned about online harassment.
Yeah, I've been on the receiving end of that and it sucks.
I think we've given far more of that than we received
in our younger days. I will say I'm a reformed internet security bully.
So I've never been so rude that somebody got us or
that somebody sent a cease and desist letter to me.
That is,
no, that's a ridiculous bar.
If you have to wait till someone sends you a cease and desist,
like you're well past the point of being a giant a hole
anyways. Uh, I want to know more about how governments are accessing my data.
Uh That's a really good one because, like, remember, like, 10 years ago,
if somebody had brought that up like, oh the NSA and the CIA and blah, blah, blah,
we would have all been like, ok, crazy person go take, you know, go.
And
I remember when people would tell me I'm crazy when I
would tell them the NSA is basically listening to everything you do
and then snow didn't happen. It's like
I told you,
well, it's even better than that. It's not, the NSA is not listening to everything,
the NSA is listening to everything,
using a computer to transcribe it and shoving it into a database.
You know,
because I think part of the problem is
people think of old timey wiretaps where you're
like inherently limited by how many people you
can pay to listen to these things versus.
Well, actually in true lies, remember in true lies,
they had that scene where they're, you know,
the thing is automatically transcribing and printing it out and
the guy is reading it and punches a hole in something
and, and remember that was like crazy science fiction.
Now it's like
real.
Yeah.
Ok. Uh Fifth option I feel like I face additional risk because of who I am or what I do.
Ok, I like that.
And uh option number five is not.
So I think if I click that. Yeah, delux
everything. So
OK, there we go. Get results. Ok.
Oh I like this. Your top priority enable two factor authentication.
If that doesn't show up like for everything, no matter what you pick.
I don't know what else could be there.
Like that's a no brainer.
And just to warn people,
your action plan includes 38 tips to help you better secure your online accounts,
phone, browsing, computer, internet connection and connect with specialists.
So this
right? So
you
have,
how
many, how many did you say? 38?
38? So I clicked the, the two other options that did everything.
I forget what they are now even. And I have 19.
So I have a feeling the list has significant overlap.
So,
uh so the number one is get two
factor authentication and I completely agree with that.
And, you know, people will argue like, for example,
phone based S MS authentication is not totally secure and it's not right.
People can hijack your S MS messages and they can hijack your phone and blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah.
But it significantly raises the bar from having to get your password of, you know,
Mr Snuffles 2000
to, you know,
having to get that password and then hijack your phone or take off your phone or,
you know,
whatever this one
is,
if,
if you're using S MS as your second factor and someone comes after you,
it's because you were
specifically targeted
and if you're specifically targeted,
you're probably gonna lose no matter what you're doing.
And
that's a big difference
than drive by.
It might make a difference because with bank fraud, they will target you
but they will spend a reasonable amount of effort.
Only because quite frankly,
I'm not like you're not gonna spend 50 grand to rob
me because I don't have 50 grand in my bank account.
-- You know, and
-- that's fair.
I think there's, there's potentially some bars, but at the same time.
So my assumption is for like a bank, everyone has a form of two factor
oath.
Uh, most Canadian banks don't unless you count it. They have the secret questions
which are passwords, which are the same as
the primary form.
So, no,
actually a lot of Canadian banks don't have what I would call real to fa they have,
well, you have two factors but they're identical.
They're both passwords.
That's not two factor.
Anyway,
it has to be
two separate factors.
We
can,
we can,
we can revisit two factor
o another day because I know we could speak probably for
an,
we'll put
a link in the show
notes. There's a website. What is it two factor off
something that has a list of like all these banks
and online services that either do or don't enable to Eva
kind of how to go about enabling it, which is
quite useful.
So,
yeah, two factor
off.org
and it's like
thousands of services. It's awesome. So we'll put a
link to that.
Um
All right, I just lost the tab. There we go. So, uh now here's some stuff. Uh
Safeguard your online accounts.
Best practice. Learn to check suspicious emails,
learn how to protect
-- yourself from emails with harmful links and attachments, whatever
-- that,
that advice is.
BS.
Well, you can't do that
not reliably. Right.
Because at three in the morning you're going to get an email from somebody saying,
oh my God emergency,
please check the spreadsheet and you're going to be tired and you
think it's from your boss and you're going to open it.
Um, what I do here honestly is, I hope and pray that like Google's
email filtering catches most of it.
And then
because I have literally gotten an email from my bank in all caps back in
the day because they had some like
terminal based system that only talked capital letters
and I actually thought it was a phishing email because,
right, my bank had never emailed me before and it's all in caps and it looks all wonky
and I go into the branch and like, oh, yeah. Yeah, that's, that's legit.
And I'm like, oh, really?
You know what else I love is when a company uses some,
like third party domain to email you.
-- And it's like you can't do that
-- or better yet. They use a third party
service that's like, also used by a lot of other people.
You know, like,
it's one thing to run mailing lists on
mailchimp and announce new products and specials,
but like, don't run your, like, account recovery process through them.
Right. I've, I've seen stuff like that where it's like, literally,
you know, this is one of the problems I have with outsourcing,
uh outgoing email for services like mailing list is that,
um, I found a lot of them,
they use like a set of outgoing servers that
everybody uses so your reputation and stuff can suffer.
And more to the point,
you can't use things like sender protected framework or other, you know,
deacon to restrict who can send email because
a whole pile of other people can send email
unless that provider locks that down and not all of them do
it.
We're going to rattle ourselves. We can,
we
can,
I think we could turn everyone
one of these into a show.
Uh
The third one. Ok. The third one I like get a password manager.
Ok. So that one is my second one on my list.
But I agree if I was going to list like number one and number
22 factor off in password manager would be my number one and two,
unquestionably.
Well.
And even just for things like if I get hit by a bus, you know,
hopefully my family can get into my passwords,
you know.
So that's the other thing I see about password management is it's
not just about me managing my passwords to be more secure,
but it's about managing my passwords.
So there's actually
an accessible copy of them somewhere for my family.
Now, did you hear,
uh did you did you see Tavis found that
Windows 10 automatically installs a password manager for you.
And I guess it had a flaw that any website could
read any password you had stored in the password manager.
I'm not surprised.
This is one of those things that I have a suspicion.
Password managers will continue being crappy for another couple of years.
They, they're getting better and they're going to get better.
And, and really,
I think the problem is the password manager. That's a simple problem.
The password manager integrated with a web browser.
That is not a simple problem.
Same thing.
Yep.
No, absolutely. And this is actually where
having someone like Tavis,
like going to town and these people makes me happy because he's going to,
he's going to make them better whether they want to be or not.
And that's awesome.
Yeah,
I think this one's a no brainer. I don't think anyone's going to argue about it.
What else you got?
Uh, these are, uh,
get emergency support from experts and get specialized advice for high risk users.
And, um,
oh, wait, I'm
the
top two results from every category. There's more options that I skipped.
So we'll go through those sub options later or do you want to go through them now?
I don't think. Oh, you know what? Ok.
No, we're going to go through. So it's, uh, check your account privacy.
And so I guess what that's referring to is like a lot of websites, like,
say if you go to google.com/account, it'll, that's your account on Google.
Like once you've logged in and
they have like a security check up thing that will walk you through,
like where have you logged in from which applications can access your account?
And it's, I like that because for example, I do once in a while,
but once a year go through there and kind of clean out my,
like,
which computers are allowed to access that account because it changes over time.
You know, or I stop using a
machine or whatever,
um, or, you know,
online services that are tied into my Google Drive that I no longer use.
So I, I get rid of those so that if they get hacked, I don't.
But the problem there is is I have to go through, well, like, you know,
you'd have to go through linkedin Facebook, Google Drive,
like dozens of so like every social media and data storage website you use
and that just doesn't scale.
No, I, I know I, this is one of those things that I feel like
these, these large corporations are
that they're purposely taking more from you than they need
and you can dial it back
but you shouldn't have to
and, and normal people are never going to do this anyway.
My favorite example of this is Google Drive where
I want something to talk to my Google Drive,
but really only one folder
-- of stuff, not everything you can do
-- that.
Can you do that? Now?
I'm, I'm trying to.
-- So
-- I,
-- I
-- have Google Drive
but I know like for example, with, with Dropbox, I believe you can do that.
Ok?
Because I can't,
with Google Drive because there's a couple of services I'd really love to use.
But they're like, they just,
they need blanket access to my Google Drive and I'm like,
uh
no,
no.
Uh the second one is check your account security
and that falls into the same category as this,
check your account privacy, which again, I mean, they're well meaning,
but it would be super nice if there was like, I hate to say it,
if there was some standard to describe sort
of the account features and privacy features and then
maybe in my web browser or, you know,
something set my preferences and my web browser, for example,
could warn me when I go to linkedin and says, hey,
your account is out of sync with what you want.
Maybe that's OK, maybe that's not OK
because honestly,
I've looked through privacy features and like Twitter and linkedin and Facebook
and I think I've dialed them down and locked them down, but like
a, I'm not sure I've done it right.
And b every time they change something,
they have this tendency to reset everything.
Oh I hate that.
You know, you get that email saying we've changed our privacy settings.
You might want to go in and fiddle with them some more and,
you know, invariably they've wiped all the privacy protections I enabled.
Right.
No, I know. Or, or my favorite is
the, the Twitter app on Android.
I don't think it's doing it lately, but for a while there, every time they,
they updated the app
they would undo my,
quit bugging me with every freaking update that's going on on Twitter.
And then, you know,
I knew when the app was updated because it would start like doing all the crappy
little icons at the top and then I'd have to go back in and disable it.
And it's like, come on guys, you know what you're doing? This is not an accident.
I thought you could change those note anyways.
-- But
-- you can, well, actually what's really nice is in the newer version of Android,
which I'm sure.
I, I think I OS has had this for a while.
You can just like blanket block apps from doing any sort of notifications.
And basically,
and
that
if, if I install an app and you give me a notification, odds are very high,
I'm just going to uninstall it.
But if it's something I kind of need, like Uber is a great example.
Uber loves telling me crap I don't care about. So it's like, no, you're blocked Uber.
If, if I need you, I'll go look,
I've noticed a lot of kids games,
uh, do this now, like a minion rush will randomly at like,
three in the morning and be like,
hello, blah, blah, blah.
-- And it'll, like, talk for 30 seconds to, like,
-- every game on the planet.
Does that when you install
even adult games?
Well, you know what it is, it's those games that want to entice you to play more
so they can have you buy their pretend money with real money,
buy.
Right. Whatever. I hate that crap. Anyway,
let's keep going.
Uh So the next one is get a security key.
Uh So what they mean by this is like something like a UB key or a two factor,
like a hardware token
for authentication. And I totally
agree with this because um
it sets the bar quite high in that you have to like come mug me for my key,
like my physical key ring in my pocket
at which point you can just threaten me with a gun or
a lead pipe and I'll probably give up whatever you want.
Um Secondly, they're super easy to use.
Now, I, I love explaining to people how to use a UB key because it consists of
you
uh plug it into your machine unless you got the newer one in which case,
just put it near your machine
-- and then you touch it. That's it. Like there's no step three.
-- Yep.
No, I know. Well, and I really like U two F for, for two factor
because U two F uses the web address
as part of the kind of key or I don't, it's,
I forget the name. Right. Right.
So basically if you're on a fishing site,
U two F will not work.
You have to be on the real website.
U two
F protects me from myself.
Which no, seriously.
And when it comes to like losing passwords,
I am my own worst enemy because actually this next one,
I do like add password alert to Chrome.
And what password alert is
every time you plug in a password to Chrome, it kind of
uh, it,
you know,
checks basically that you're not accidentally typing your password into like a
Google document or something
and like exposing it,
right. So it checks what you're typing.
I'm hoping it hashes it and then compares it to the hashed database, right?
So it doesn't have to like,
you know,
have access to your clear text passwords.
Um,
but basically, yeah, I mean,
and because there have been instances where I
cut and paste like the wrong password into something
and sometimes that's ok. Like if I'm logging into Google and I'm,
you know, accidentally log in with the wrong account, the password. Ok.
That doesn't matter so much.
But, you know, if I go to some third party service and use my Google password there,
then it's gonna be like, oh,
I need to change that right now.
You know, you know, this always reminds me of is, and,
and this is a great security lesson is
a million years ago, I worked at a little Linux company and for some reason,
they decided to give every workstation the same root password
and then they just gave that root password to everybody.
So we could essentially log in his root in everyone's computer.
And you can imagine the hilarity that ensued.
Right.
Where every morning you'd come in. It's like, I wonder what they messed up tonight
and, and we of course, play ridiculous practical jokes. But anyway, one time,
uh,
one of the developers accidentally pasted the
password into like the Debian channel on free
node and tell anyone for something like two days.
And also all the machines were internet connected
when we found out. Oh, my goodness. It was the wrath of the security goons
and we were really
well. Ok. No, no, here's the thing. It's, this is a double edged blade is on one side.
He was afraid to tell us because he knew we were going to do this
and by not telling us it, we made it much worse because then we were super angry.
The
whole data breach thing. Right?
It's the data breach thing is the, the,
the spilled can of coke on a rug.
Right. If I tell you I'll get in trouble.
If I try and cover it up with paper towels, I might get away with it.
Uh, you never get away with it.
That,
that's one of the lessons I've learned over all of my years is you never get away.
You might get away with it for a little while,
but you're never going to get away with it forever.
So, ok,
the next set of recommendations is around connect
to resources that can provide additional assistance.
Um And they are get emergency support from experts.
Uh get specialized advice for high risk users,
get help dealing with online harassment, learn more about an
anonymity, online
uh and check out transparency reports. And then if you click on the learn more,
for example, with online harassment,
you get coping with online harassment and oh
links to connect to specialists at online.
So ss which I assume is like some sort of
anti
cyber bullying thing.
Uh Check out a guide for staying safe online and get support from other survivors.
So that's cool. I like that.
And then, oh, tell someone, number two,
tell someone many forms of online harassment
can
consider reporting your issue to the police and or
someone you trust who can help keep you safe.
And
that's a perfect example, like honestly how much security advice
really boils down to tell an adult,
right? Which is the equivalent of 4911, like tell somebody who can help you.
Uh
Yeah,
you know, that's, that's generally good advice.
I'm always reminded of that Minecraft streamer
uh guy in Japan that burns his house down
and like at no point, does he like you see him calling 911 or whatever,
the Japanese equivalent of it is.
-- Right. He tries to put the fire out himself.
-- Right. Right.
And it got caught on video. Thank goodness.
And I think a lot of them anyways.
Um, so, yeah. No, this is good in that.
Like, that's part of the problem too is even if like,
if somebody started doxing me,
I wouldn't know what to do. I'd have to like literally Google search.
I am being doxed. What do I do?
-- No, like, because I have never dealt with that. Hopefully, I never have to.
-- I,
yeah, I know what you mean.
It's one of those things that I've never had to deal with, I guess at the same time,
this is also a reason I made a decision a long time ago to not hide who I am
and finding various contact info on me isn't very difficult.
And I kind of did that with the thinking.
You can't, again, if someone is targeting you and they want to dox you, they will,
you cannot beat them.
And so I guess I, I kind of treated this as
let me help you out with that
and, and it's just something I don't
worry about very much, but it's also never really been a problem
and that works for some people for some things,
but for other people who maybe have a different, you know,
religious or sexual orientation or whatever
they, they don't have that option of being open about
it.
And, and you're absolutely right there is,
I acknowledge there are definitely reasons
to want a certain level of anonymity
and
I don't have many of them,
which
not that saying I'm anti
anonymity. Mind you, I think it's very important we're allowed to do that.
It's just I made the conscious decision to be lazy and not care.
So I, I like this because, you know, uh,
hooking people up to organizations if they're going through, this is definitely
needed because quite frankly, if somebody came to me and said I was being doxed,
I, I would have no idea what to do
or, you know, I'm being bullied online and let's face it being bullied online.
Oh, well, don't use Facebook. I mean, that's not,
you know,
that's not the most helpful of advice. Right.
-- You can rent my botnet and knock him off on it.
-- Right.
Yeah, exactly.
Um, you know, and I, I do worry about this because I have, you know, Children who are,
uh, you know, they're in grade school, you know,
and at some point they're going to get to junior high and high school and I assume
like all people that age group they're gonna be
with and around some people who are not so nice
and are bullies.
Uh, you know, and it's, yeah, I, I literally, this is all my,
-- to do list of things to learn about as a parent
-- sweet.
Now you got somewhere to start
this one I really like.
And, and this is one of those I know I, I harp relentlessly about.
You have to build it into the tools and expecting people
to be proactive and people to make their own decisions.
That is not an acceptable excuse.
In this case,
I think having this kind of information available
is quite reasonable and it is awesome.
So,
I don't even know, do they teach this in school now?
Because I, I think back to so in, in Alberta, there's this thing called Cal
10, Career and Life Management. 10 means it's
a, well, it's 1/10 10th grade course. Uh anyways,
and they taught us
uh
amongst other things like how to balance a checkbook.
And I remember thinking like this is so pointless because like the ATM tells you
what your balance is and it updates your like this is how old I am.
I actually had a passbook that I could feed into the
ATM and it would print on it and tell me like,
update your transactions.
That was a thing
we're talking about 30 years ago.
How would you, how would you make sure it, it on the right line
or did I just print per page or something? This sounds like the dumb.
I
kept a record of where it was.
Anyways,
the point being is I actually had like a physical passbook
that showed me how much money I had in my account,
I remember having
little
books.
In fact, I still have one that I keep in, like,
the crappy little plastic checkbook they give me
because if I don't put it in there, the checkbook doesn't close. Right.
So I
leave, I never write in it, but it's always there.
But, yeah, so I'm, I'm hoping and assuming, you know,
courses like this in school are, are, they're covering some of this.
although grade 10 is a bit late.
Like by that time, you know,
-- you've probably had to deal with online
-- bullying already.
You know, here's the deal man is, I don't think they can
not because they don't want to but because the world is changing too.
I mean, so here's a great example,
let's say you were
going to
set
up.
Yes.
Ok. Yes, that is good advice
like that. But
you know, that's never how these classes work.
They get overly specific and if they made it today,
they would probably focus on Facebook and the, the youth today.
All the young people I know
Snapchat man, they love Snapchat.
And so you could focus on Facebook all day long when the reality is,
most of the young people aren't getting harassed on Facebook,
they're getting harassed on Snapchat,
right?
Yep.
You gotta love it. However, like you said, like, tell an adult talk to people,
like for example, it's not
really appropriate for randos to ask you for naked photos or photos of your drunk.
You would
and sending that to them, you may really regret it. Actually,
you've, you've put a thought into my mind, not because of that comment.
Uh
but that, that also added some thoughts. But anyway, the point being uh
telling like young people, for example,
it's OK to ask for help about this stuff is
similar to the many of the other problems of,
many people don't know who to ask.
They don't have anyone in a lot of cases because let's face it.
The world isn't teeming with security professionals
but like when they do know them
and this is true of saying an organization that has a real security team.
Uh A lot of people don't ask for help because they're
afraid to or they don't feel safe and let's face it.
This is the same with young people. If they don't feel safe, they don't ask for help.
This is
the
same
deeply personal embarrassing, right? Like I sent my photos to who I thought was
whatever, right?
Um
You know, this reminds me of two. I remember there was a long time ago,
I was uh
I was a Cis Edmund at a small company and
there was this 11 of the employees, the Cis Edmunds,
there were like four or five of us we really got along well with, with this one lady
and
I forget what it was, but one day she comes in and it's like,
is there something wrong with the email.
And we said, what do you mean? She said, I don't think some of my mails went through.
We said, oh, do you mean the one where you mailed out your resume?
And she got like white as a ghost?
Like, wait, we made that up. Are you leaving?
She really did. She was mailing out resumes from work email.
We're like, all right, number one,
we're gonna sit down and teach you how to not
screw this up because do not do this from work.
And of course, like, you know,
we were good sports about it all and we helped her learn how to, like,
she set up a Gmail account.
Well, I don't think gmail existed back then but you get the, you,
you get the idea like we set her up, we're like, this is what you need to do.
Do not use work email for this and we're not going
to tell anyone what we just learned because we're nice people.
But, yeah. Yeah, it was,
oh, you gotta love it.
Yeah.
So moving along next area is keep your phone's data secure. And, and
I think this is something that's really
underappreciated because for a lot of people,
especially young people now that the phone is their computer
straight up. Right?
A
lot of people, like
my kids have tablets and it's funny because my one son calls the, um, the ipods, um,
baby ipads or he calls them iphones.
But he doesn't make a distinction.
And, you know, I, I don't think that they'll necessarily ever have, like, a laptop.
Like I had one where, you know, I loved it and cherished it.
They'll probably have a phone that is more powerful than my laptop.
Ignoring your kids.
If, if you gave me a choice of, of losing my phone or my laptop, take the laptop
in a second.
Yeah, I would put the laptop in the garbage disposal myself. If, if I had to, to keep my
phone,
like I would cheerfully sacrifice it.
So, what's the
advice?
-- So
-- number one is text and call privately with signal which, um, I, I, well,
we actually use it and actually,
I think a lot of people in the security industry use signal now because, well,
two reasons, one is secure and two, it's actually really easy to use it.
Actually, I, I've started using it with a bunch of nonsecurity people. I know
because I found in
it, it seems like I don't know why this is, but as of late,
I feel like sending text messages has become less reliable than it used to be.
And, and for some reason, certain people,
I interact with the text messages just aren't getting to
where they should be going for some reason or another.
Maybe,
maybe
I'm being spied on, I don't know.
But whatever,
uh, you,
you, I'll tell him, I say just download signal and put it on your,
your phone and then I'll use that to contact you and, and signals.
Even I really like signal because it also has the two little checkmarks.
So for example, I know if they got the message.
Yeah.
And so the one thing I love about signal and the one thing
I hate about signal is that it relies on your phone number,
which let's face it, your phone number,
especially now that we have number portability in most of the world,
your phone number is your
identity. Really? That's the best, you know, that's kind of the best way to,
you know,
push a text message to you to prove that you are who you are sort of claiming to be,
you know, online
uh and to hook up something like a hardware token to
your account or whatever.
Um And on the flip side, I hate, you know,
because I don't like giving up my phone number because, you know, if
somebody calls me at three in the morning accidentally wakes me up,
that's really annoying.
-- Um
-- That's why I just don't leave my phone near me at night.
-- Yeah.
-- Well, unfortunately I have kids so I have to, you know, and they don't
anyways.
Um, that's not an option for everybody.
Um,
number two here uh is protect your iphone's data with
encryption and what I especially love about that is it's basically
the default
and it just works.
Yeah. Apple's done a nice job with that and they keep it safe.
Yeah. And then the, just below that is protect your android data with encryption.
And,
sadly, I have no idea how that works and I'm assuming it's not the default
or is it?
I don't, I think you have to turn it on.
I don't, it might be default in some of the new phones.
Maybe the new Google phones, almost.
Certainly not like your, your $100 phone you're buying
from, from whoever.
Yeah, it's good advice though. I'm
uh uh yeah,
I buy it.
What else you got? Yeah.
And then the next one I'm gonna roll up again is protect or back up your iphone's data
and
also, you know, use Android's Google account backup. Yeah, for the love of God.
Back up your data, especially your account data
because I, I have been in the Apple store once or twice, you know,
like one time my ipad did something funky and
turns out it just literally needed like a hard,
hard factory reset,
which they wouldn't tell me how to do over the
phone and I forgot that you can Google it.
So I took it in thinking it was like hardware messed up. Did they charge you for this?
No, it's free. Ok. Ok. Anyways.
And so I'm sitting at the table, you know, I made an appointment, I'm sitting there,
I'm there like 10 minutes early
and there's this lady there
and so the guy has to reset like, hard, hard reset my ipad and he's like,
have you backed it up?
And I'm like, yeah,
like, when did you back it up last time, like, last night before, you know,
I brought it in or whatever?
He's like, ok, great. You know,
and this lady crossed the, the table is like, wait, how do you back it up?
And I'm like, uh, you
log into icloud and,
yeah. No, there's no step to
and she
had no idea and she had not backed up her ipad and that they
were trying to back up her ipad before they had to hard reset it,
right?
Because let's face it.
99% of tablet and phone problems are solved by turn it off and on or turn it off,
like with a hard reset and then turn it back on and refresh it.
Um, like, literally unless hardware is broken, that's, that will fix it. So,
yeah, I mean, she was just amazed at how
you could just back up your device so easily.
And I was like, and, and my first thought was like,
yeah, yeah. How did you not do that? But um
that's one thing I am glad to see is, and,
and that's another thing where I think laptops and
desktops have really fallen down is like by default,
backing up a desktop or a laptop is much more difficult than backing up a phone
in
general.
I mean,
unless you have like a Mac and you just
log into icloud and it backs it up automatically
assuming you purchase enough free space, right?
By default, you get five gigs, which
is nowhere near enough for anybody nowadays.
And I feel like this is,
this is again one of those instances where telling people to do it isn't effective.
They just need tools to make it.
You need to make it,
you basically need to make it
not necessarily on by default,
but like you get prompted by default and it needs to be one or
I would say less steps to enable it
basically,
right?
Um And that's one thing I do like is that Apple has made
the the icloud experience kind of this cohesive whole
where I want to log into my icloud account regardless of the backups because it does,
for example, my contacts and everything get synced, you know, I get
my key chain synced. I get like all these actual benefits
that make my life easier, let alone the backups which I do really appreciate,
you know, when a device dies or when I buy a new device and literally the
you log in and then an hour later it's your device.
I know, I know we got to keep moving man.
So the next one I'll roll up again is track and protect
your Apple device and track and protect a lost or stolen Android.
And
um
again, these are, I know in the I OS world this is, you know, you enable,
find my iphone, uh, which is not enabled by default, but again, it's like one step.
Um,
and then,
uh what I especially like is you can't disable it without putting your password in.
So it's not like somebody can steal your device and just disable that.
-- Right. They'd have to have your passcode or whatever or, you know, your
-- thumb.
Well, I, I would envision this is less about
theft and more about, uh, I've, I've lost my phone
and I don't know where I left it and it's like, yeah,
-- it's at the grocery store and then you go that
-- ping function
where you can tell an iphone or whatever to make a ping noise
because one time my son helpful, you know, put an ipad away in a sock drawer.
Right.
And we just,
for the life of us we're looking at all the
usual places like in the couch and stuff and,
ok, you know, it's not working. Uh, it's still online. It still got lots of battery.
Thank goodness.
So, like start making it ping and it's like everybody should be quiet.
Right.
And you're like, slowly moving around the house trying to listen for this ping
-- noise. You know. That's
-- great.
All right. What else? Let's keep going.
-- Uh,
-- well, then that's basically
it.
That's it. That's it.
-- That's
-- it. That's, I'm at the end of the list, uh, done with these.
You could also better secure your browsing computer and internet connection.
Ah, now there's a second set of stuff
so browse more securely
learn to spot a suspicious website. And that one
annoys me a bit because,
uh, well, some of it's simple, like paypal
one.com
or not having http si get that. But
the problem is like, let's face it.
Like with, let's encrypt,
anybody can get an SSL C or a TLS certificate now for their website.
Um, and trying to explain to people, you know,
domain validation versus extended verification versus what's the third one?
DVEV?
I can't remember.
So that's proof that it's kind of a pain in the butt to explain.
It's, I agree again, this is where tools
and I guess funny enough, uh,
suspicious websites are less dangerous if you have a password manager
that uses the URL and you're using U two F,
if you put those two things together,
you're going to cover like 99%.
Yeah.
Every single phishing,
email and text spam phishing thing I've
gotten goes to some website that's been compromised
and is like
the thing in Canada is the interact where there's like, oh,
you have like a $27 refund from like a phone company
because statistically like,
that's like 30% of Canadians probably use that
phone company because we don't have many.
And so, you know,
they go and they plug in their account details and their intact stuff, which is like,
you know, that's a huge step forward to ripping somebody off bank wise,
you know.
Um, and one thing that helps there is, is some of the, uh,
providers are better and when I say providers, I mean,
like the credit card and debit card providers,
some of them are pretty good and
aggressive about shutting down these compromised websites,
you know, talking to the provider and being like, hey, there's,
you know, you have a compromised wordpress site serving out fishing blah, blah,
blah, please.
For the love of God, turn it off before anybody uses it, you know.
Um, and that's, that's a pretty big thing now for some of these larger providers, um,
of course, there's no way to know how well they are doing at this.
So the next one is, uh, you'll love this, stop prying eyes with a privacy screen.
So that's one of those uh,
polarized filters that you put on your laptop. So
you have to be like right in front of it to see the screen. And
yeah, as we discussed previously, hopefully,
then if somebody is like putting their head on your shoulder to stare at your screen,
you'll notice that.
Right.
Um The next one.
So prevent tracking with privacy badger, uh privacy badger is a,
an add on from the eff the Electronic Frontier Foundation.
Uh
I like it
but I have had it break one or two websites,
uh, in a way that's
painful to figure out because
uh, like a lot of stuff on websites.
Now you'll like,
click a website and you get cycled through three or four year old
very quickly before it kind of like logs you in or whatever.
And it had privacy badger break that and to kind
of unwind and figure out where it was breaking,
took a little bit of effort.
Um, now having said that
it doesn't break too many websites.
-- So I would say in general, the cure is still a lot better than
-- not only
the, I know
I've used privacy badger a little bit and you can easily disable it
for certain sites.
So if there is a site that it's super wonky with, you can just turn it off.
However, I will say in nearly every instance,
the sites it didn't actually work with,
I didn't want to use it for real anyway because it's like, yeah,
I'm not going to this dodgy site after all.
Yeah.
No, I remember,
I specifically had one website where the login went through sort
of a third party website that it blocked and it broke
inappropriately. And like I said, it was a pain to find out.
But literally that was the only instance of a problem I've had with it
and I've been using privacy badger basically since about a week after it came out
in a few years now, I think.
Yeah.
Well, it, it works and it's minimally false positive and, and intrusive, you know,
which is nice
you know, it's like all these people that say use no script.
I just wanna like gouge my eyes out because using no script
on a web browser in the modern role is so painful.
-- I
-- I so want to use it but yeah, I I give up every time.
Alright. What else?
Yeah.
Uh So the next one is install HTTP S everywhere.
And again, that is a, I believe it's also eff did that one.
Uh But anyways, it's a little extension that basically
if a site has an HTTP S
version, it'll like force your browser to use that. So it's kind of like
using uh the HSTS Secure.
It basically kind of implements HSTS security
headers without the server actually implementing them.
Um And so the nice thing is because like, for example, a lot of banks will have a
non secure and a secure website because they want to
support older browsers or people who are not so savvy
and just turning off HT TT P and you know,
using HSTS and preload and all that would break
everybody using windows XP or whatever, for example, you know,
so all the grannies would not be able to bank online.
Um
And so yeah, this basically gives you the best of both worlds. Uh
Yeah. Um
Moving along, we have installed the Tor
browser now this now we're getting to the part where well, no, no, no.
Like because we clicked all the options, remember.
So I'm assuming normal people don't get this.
Um And so I'm assuming this is more, for example, with, you know,
dealing with blocked websites,
right? Because didn't you click an option?
That was something about, uh avoiding censorship or what was it?
I don't remember what it was called even.
Yeah, basically.
Um,
now in fairness, the Tor browser is really, I've,
I've tried it and it literally as you download it,
it,
it is easy. I guess my, my concern with
Tor always is
most people don't know what to r really is. They think it's magic.
And in fact, I, I found a link uh last week,
I think it was someone put a link up on Twitter where someone running a Tor
exit node
was sniffing plain text credentials and they had like a Twitch live stream.
-- This is a live stream.
-- You
watch
them in real time and it's like
people don't realize that
Tor isn't magic encryption. It's just kind of,
it makes it
if you do it right, it makes it harder to track you if you do it wrong, it makes it much,
much easier.
I remember there was a bunch of Tor
exit nodes that were doing things like for example,
blocking port 443 but allowing port 80
or you know,
they were blocking the encrypted versions of protocols
and allowing the non encrypted versions of protocols.
Right.
Now, the good news there is again, a lot of these major websites have,
you know, gone to HTTP S and with something like HTTP S
everywhere, you know,
you,
it wouldn't be as much of a problem.
Um, but yeah, I would say in general, the, the main use case kind of for Tor
is, yeah, you want to browse stuff and it's either blocked or you really, really,
really,
you have like a hostile network or a nation state.
Here's
what I'm going to say to this.
If you are say at the library and want to look at, I don't know, let's say Craigslist,
assuming maybe that's blocked.
OK. Tor browser,
if you are trying to evade a nation state spying on you,
uh you need to educate yourself and if you're relying on this website to,
to give you advice, you're probably going to go to jail.
That's
uh well, it actually, I mean, it does talk about how the Tor browser is not AAA
be all end, all
right.
Like it does talk about some of the downside, well,
not downsides but the limitations.
I mean,
if you click on the learn more.
Yeah.
Uh
So anyway, it's moving along.
The next one is I like this install Chrome or
-- Firefox.
-- I'll agree with that 100. Although
this is one of those things too that, that kind of
Firefox just had the incident where the Mr robot people paid them to put, you know,
essentially spyware into the browser.
And, and I mean, Chrome,
I love Google for, for certain reasons.
But let's face it guys at the end of the day, chrome is funded by
internet advertising,
right?
It, it is
probably,
well, so is Firefox?
-- Firefox is
-- si mean, realistically, Firefox gets a big check from, you know,
being Google the default.
Yes,
that's, that's fair.
It's, it's one of those things that I, I think chrome is still on, on the side of good,
but I'm always
ii I keep an eye on things because I, I have a feeling
there these browsers walk the edge of a knife and now I will say also Google,
not Google,
Firefox, Mozilla,
they did the right thing and undid their, their silly
Mr robot thing.
So that's good at least.
But this is kind of one of those things we need to be eternally vigilant.
Yeah.
Well, and what always gets me is when these cases do come to light,
usually it's something really stupid and like,
yeah, it's like that Mr robot thing.
It was what it was replacing keywords or making it search or some,
some ridiculous thing
to do with the TV. Show to try and
advertise it, I guess. I don't know.
Um
moving along.
So the next 10 I like this. Uh So they're labeled as a built in option.
Uh oh I didn't notice. So on top of these tips, they have things like advanced or
uh quick and easy. So like install Chrome or Firefox is quick and easy. But like,
you know, using the Tor browser is labeled as advanced.
Um This one I like these are labeled as a built in option.
So it's, it's using the data encryption in, in
uh
Mac Os and Windows to encrypt your data, right?
Uh And again, yeah, I would just
uh back in the day when you know CP US didn't have like built in encryption support.
Yeah. No, this was a nightmare. It made it so slow.
Uh Nowadays, you know, every intel and a MD,
whatever CPU has built in AES encryption.
So when you enable disc encryption,
there's literally no
performance.
It's,
but, but again, I guess
this is one of those instances where
uh tablets and phones I think are, are offering a vastly superior
uh kind of just environment.
Yeah.
Um And the biggest thing for me,
the reason I use data encryption is two reasons actually is number one obviously.
So my, my data doesn't go walk about if somebody steals my laptop.
The other big thing is, is to deny use of that laptop. If somebody steals it.
Because you know,
think about this, if every single device that got stolen wasn't usable, then
you know, there would be no resale market for these things and that would be great.
So I actually have a secret option three
is when I'm getting rid of hardware
and you have an encrypted disk, you only have to wipe the,
the first bits of disk because that's where the keys live,
right?
And then
basically the rest of the disk is essentially
random if the key is no longer available.
Well, and I wrote about this 17 years ago,
I did a presentation on why data deletion is not data deletion.
And and for example, a great example is, you know, hard drives, remap bad sectors.
So if you'd written plain text to bad sectors,
your hard drive might be like, oh, it'll be on the safe side.
I'm not going to let you touch that sector but you know,
data recovery software easily can,
well, in like S sds basically can't be wiped.
I mean, let's face it.
Yeah,
exac well, not reliably
because you can't actually like,
yeah.
Um
yeah, so it's, it's better just and realistically, like I said,
from a performance point of view, there's just, there's no excuse not to,
not to encrypt everything everywhere.
Now at rest,
um I get key management. It's not always easy but
sorry folks. That's how it is.
Um The next one I do like is use Microsoft free Antivirus.
-- And when I have had Windows, uh I believe yes, it was introduced
-- when I
say
-- I've got a handful of Windows, I think, I
-- think for sure it was in Windows.
Defender was in Windows seven anyways, it's in Windows 10. Now
their antivirus, I will say two things about it
almost never breaks the system
which a lot of Antivirus does occasionally, you know, like,
takes out some poor accounting package or just you reboot and you, you're hooped.
And number two is it's lightweight enough that it doesn't, like,
mess up all your performance.
Which again, a lot of antivirus software makes machines.
Most antivirus software is terrible.
-- And I've been running
-- well and then you look at, like, um,
again
or
-- in research into antivirus software
-- and it
is not,
they're no better. But I guess the one thing I like is it's, it's free.
Right? Why am I going to pay for crappy software when I can get it for free?
Yeah.
Um, so the next one is, is a classic backup,
your Mac and back up your Windows computer and in
fairness backing up a Windows computer is a lot easier.
Now,
um,
-- you need an external hard drive or something, plug it in and pretty
-- much
just with the tablet
through it.
I mean, it's a no brainer.
Yeah.
Yeah. Uh,
well, but the thing to remember too is, I mean,
part of the problem is having off site backups
because for example, like, you can back up all
the laptops you want,
but if your house burns down and all your backup hard
drives and laptops are in the house when it burns down,
you know, you're absolutely, you're done. Use the cloud.
And so that's one thing where I do, like, a lot of the, like, file services,
like Dropbox and stuff where you can keep,
again, it goes,
it's kind of more of a feature like keeping files in sync with that is super useful.
But then by virtue of having your files in sync, you having them in the cloud,
you know, you now have an off site backup of your stuff.
All
right,
let's keep going.
Um
Yeah.
Uh The next one of course is update your Windows software and update your Mac.
Now, having said that I just recently finally factory wiped some,
I bought some Windows 10 tablets that were super cheap
and I got rid of them for the simple reason is that I was spending 1 to 3 hours a week,
updating them,
the antivirus and the Os and everything and they were just,
the update was so painful and these tablets were so limited that
yeah, I ended up factory wiping them so that I can give them away to charity.
Um,
and even Mac, I find is now, like,
not as great as it used to be.
Some of these updates are pretty horrifically large and I mean,
Microsoft office is a great example.
Right. It's on average every month now. It's over 500 megabytes of updates.
So if you're not on high speed internet, I don't know what you're going to do.
Right.
Like straight up, if you're on dial up, you can't update 500 megabytes.
I know. Actually
I did,
I wrote a blog post some time ago.
Where I like used uh uh firewall to artificially lower my speeds
and the internet is unusable at dial up.
I'm,
I'm comfortable saying that it is unusable near the
only website that was almost usable is Amazon.
And they do some clever things where the first time you go there, it'll be really,
really, really slow
and then they purposely serve content in a way that makes it very, very fast
after the first uh,
visit anyway. Anyway, let's keep going. Yeah, we get
it.
Ok. So moving along now we have secure your internet connection and,
uh, the first one is use a VPN.
Uh, again, this is like if you're dealing with blocked content or,
and one thing to keep in mind with blocked content, for example,
if you're on a corporate computer and they have content blocking
-- and you bypass it,
-- there's
a
chance they have like three things spying on you at the
same time and so you're not going to evade them.
Yeah.
So, I mean, using a VPN, um,
well,
you know, sad to say actually with the repeal of net neutrality in the US last week,
using a VPN might become a much more popular thing
because if I SPS start throttling certain types of traffic,
like
competitors voice services or online gaming or whatever, or Netflix,
you know, unless they then start throttling the hands which
there's some of them that are definitely evil enough to do that.
Um,
you know, and give you the whole, like, oh,
you should upgrade to a business connection if you want a VPN.
Um,
the nice thing about most VPN S is, is that
if you start blocking VPN S,
you're going to annoy a lot of business
customers which they generally want to avoid.
Um,
so, yeah, I mean,
using a VPN you're going to be paying about five or 10 bucks a month for a VPN service.
Um,
but yeah, there's definitely, uh, a valid use case for it now, especially in the US,
with the repeal of net neutrality.
Luckily, I live in Canada where it's enshrined in law
that we have net neutrality, uh,
along with a lot of the world.
Um,
next one is I've never even heard of use glass
wire for windows and it's a firewall program for windows
and then enable your Mac firewall. And I would,
I honestly thought Mac Os,
that's
crazy by default.
So, if it's not enabled by default, shame
that
because I just got a Mac,
uh,
about a year ago
for, for work.
And yeah, I,
I was poking around at the security settings and the firewall is not on by default,
which I was, I, I almost didn't believe when I saw that.
Well, in fairness max by default don't have a lot of services
like you have to enable them.
So, but at the same time, really that firewall should be enabled,
um,
moving along
and that's it. So what do you think?
Uh Well, honestly, a lot of the stuff that is uh difficult is labeled as advanced,
you know, and stuff like the built in option of using data encryption or
um you know, backing up your computer. Uh I think there's a good,
it,
it always comes back to that kind of return
on investment and more importantly for normal people.
Is it actually achievable?
Like let's face it, I am, you know, you and I are,
I would say hopefully somewhat advanced security knowledge people
and I would definitely say I cannot
with 100% certainty, say that if you send me an email, I will definitely.
Yeah.
Um And so that's why I use things like
that.
I think what these guys are trying to do is really good.
I, I think they asked the right number of questions up front.
I like the way the interface is set up, but I think they give,
they give too many options
like let's face it if, if I was a person that didn't really know anything,
I don't want 30 things I want, you know what I want.
My advice should be the advice should be
two factor off in a password manager and that would be,
that would make most people probably 500% better.
I was gonna say
if I had to pick one thing from this whole list, I would say honestly,
my number one would be get a password manager.
Number one,
because that applies to all websites regardless.
And then number 22 factor authentication because like I said, a lot of sites don't,
still don't offer
factor
authentication.
And, and
no, I know, I know. II, I agree with you. I guess
two factor
on would be number one
or I'm sorry. Pastor manager. Number 12
factor
O is also really good.
And then backups would be my third.
And I think if you did those three things, right? And
egos are huge and, and
the way I always think about this stuff is
you can give people a list of three things and they might do one of them.
If you give people a list of 30 things, they will do none of them.
And that's just the way people work.
It's, I mean, the good news, you know what I am noticing about this list though,
more of this stuff is now built in,
right?
Because I remember when this conscription and stuff you
had to buy third party software for that,
you're right.
Like the world is getting better. Like Windows has honestly passable built in,
right? It's not amazing and great, but it's OK.
All antivirus is terrible.
And I know lots of people like to argue with me about this, but
it, it sucks.
I mean,
well, no, I would say antivirus at the client level is terrible at the server level.
It's actually quite appropriate
for a whole pile of reasons and you can do stuff at
the server level that you can't do on the client side.
Uh,
yeah.
Well, like behavioral or, you know, spotting trends, like, you know,
suddenly if somebody from Russia sends, you know, 10,000 people the same dot Exe.
Yeah. You know,
you should block that probably.
But, yeah, it's, um, I also like that they do give you links to actual people that
it's a good
start
and
organizations that can help you because
honestly, I didn't know half of these existed.
Ok. So, I guess all in all this is very nice. It's very well done.
I, I, my only real complaint is the list is too long at the end.
But again, I don't think there's any, you know, here's what I would do.
I think if I was them is a long list isn't necessarily a bad thing,
but they don't really organize it in the,
these are the three most important things to do.
And if you're doing these, then you should look at doing this stuff. Where is it?
It's kind of arranged in a more hodgepodge manner
where if I didn't know what I was doing,
I wouldn't know which,
like which one of these things is the most important thing I should do. Right.
Yeah.
Well, here's a real question. What would it take?
Honestly,
let's just pick the two top things that you can
do without actually having to buy hardware or whatever.
What, what do you think it would take to do to get,
say 90% of people using a decent password manager and backing up their computer.
-- Uh
-- You have to just make it default with the computer.
I mean, let's face it. This is one of those things that the reason
anyone uses many of these tools like for backing up that,
that ipads have is because it's just part of the ipad.
Yeah. Yeah.
And I think the good news is well and this comes,
I would say maybe 1/4 recommendation is using cloud services because
a lot of them are quite secure and by definition,
hopefully are properly backed up.
So like Gmail or Dropbox or you know, whatever.
And so there, you know, you're just,
you're getting your cake and being allowed to eat it like it just
in theory, I've, I've never, you know,
the number of people that have complained about loss of data from Gmail is
vanishingly small compared to the total number of people
-- generally like human error.
-- You know, there have been one or two incidents.
Well, no, there's there. If you Google it, there's one or two incidents that
like where Google had like a pretty whoopsy moment.
Uh and you know,
same like with git lab where they knew
what a production web database server or something.
So it does happen. But,
but realistically, you know, I kind of hate to say it but it kind of gets you into that,
it's probably safer to have one super
tanker that's hopefully managed well versus like,
you know, 10,000 people in kayaks with
oil.
I think all in all this is actually a useful thing.
Um,
I would probably say that I wouldn't even
bother going to this unless you've already got a
password manager and backups going because until you do
that doing the rest of the stuff is kind of
not
fair.
All right, man, I'm calling.
Thank you, everyone for listening. Thank you, Kurt.
You can go to open source security podcast.com
and we'll have links to various show notes including
uh the little test here. So, you're welcome to take it on your own.
You can hit us up on Twitter with the Pound Os S Podcast.
Hashtag You can hit us up on Facebook with the
open source Security Podcast group, which there's a link to from the show notes.
-- So, yeah, nothing else. Kurt, you have a fabulous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks.