Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in bedding crime.
Josh Bresser.
-- I don't even
-- want to. It's Groundhog Day
-- as we
-- record this for
-- us.
-- I
mean, and here's the best thing.
It turns out the groundhogs are wrong more than half the time.
No,
humans are wrong more than half the time because
this is all just made up human nonsense.
But what the point is, they're betting on a simple binary.
-- Spring is coming or spring is not coming. They're not,
-- they're not at all.
The groundhog doesn't get to like come out or hide. They predetermine all of this.
They talk to the Groundhog in made up Groundhog language and then the
groundhog tells them what it decides which of course is all ridiculous.
No,
but my point is you're betting on a yes or no
item and if you're wrong more than half the time,
then the best solution is to just
bet against it because they're consistently wrong,
-- I guess whatever Groundhog,
-- it's like fund managers versus monkeys,
throwing darts at the paper.
The only redeeming
aspect of Groundhog Day
is the movie, the
movie
the
same,
like
everything else is ridiculous.
That was one of his best works.
I would agree completely. Now, I will say this.
So I think the concept of Groundhog Day as a,
we'll say way to divine the future is clearly nonsense.
And I think the people who have created this spectacle around it, whatever.
I love the aspect of just like humans coming together in the middle
of winter to have some fun because we need more of that.
Well, and there's some truth in it. You,
when the birds fly south for the winter,
there are animals that can sense the weather coming.
You know, the horse has always got real nervous before a storm
except we don't use those animals. They have a marmot and they talk to it.
Well, and also the horses are predicting something like an hour or two out
and you can just sort of look at the sky and be like, yep, thunder clouds.
This is, I, you know what I just realized
the way we ascertain the potential future from a
groundhog is not unlike most of the security industry.
Well, except it's more accurate.
-- Let's
-- take these chicken bones and throw them on the
-- ground and then decide what to do
-- pretty much.
Yeah, I, there was that Twitter thread about, you know, what's,
what's your biggest unanswered question in it?
Security? And
there's a bunch of technical ones that, you know, somebody had an answer for,
but there's a couple of us that were like,
we just want data on what works and what doesn't work and of course nobody has that.
Right.
It's, it's hard, it's a hard problem.
I mean, I'm not, I'm not going to knock people for not having it.
I'm going to knock people for pretending they do
well or pretending it doesn't really matter or that I can
make decisions based on my lack of knowledge and that's fine.
You can make decisions based on lack of knowledge. They're just not good decisions
and, but more even better,
they're not willing to change those decisions when data does come up.
I know.
So, I mean, well, this is, I mean,
what we're going to talk about today with Pseudo and Lib G
-- Crypt.
-- That's right. 2021 keeps delivering.
-- I mean,
-- I'm sorry, but it's,
how many decades has it been that we've proven developers can't write?
And I'm not going to say secure code because that's that we're not even close to that,
but code that can manage its memory properly or do something as simple as ch
own a file safely.
No, I'm serious.
I know.
So here's what all of this comes down to. I think.
Number one, these are two things written in C
and C is impossible for humans to get right.
But then number two, all of the things you just said sound easy
and it's like that Dunning Kruger thing where
you think it's an easy problem but it's actually a really hard problem.
And not only is it a really hard problem because it's secure related,
it doesn't come up until somebody attacks it.
Right. Memory management
problems.
Generally,
sometimes they come up and you get a program that
just has weird crashes as a part of life and
then somebody investigates it and finds out there's a buffer
overflow that just once in a while gets triggered randomly.
But
the majority of security flaws don't get triggered until
an attacker very consciously attacks and triggers it.
I mean, I agree with that. Well, you know, the infamous examples,
things like that one Microsoft engineer that wanted to, you know,
track down like some random handful of random crashes in an internet
explorer thing that were reported automatically to Microsoft and found out,
you know, there's a zero day in the wild.
I love that story.
I just at this point again, people pretend like, oh, well, we plugged this one hole.
We're back to being ok.
Well, we are ok for the moment until someone finds another problem. Ok.
So why don't we explain what
heck is going on because this is actually some really complicated stuff.
Which one? Because they're both,
there's OK. So there's three problems that we're going to talk about.
Two are in pseudo, one is in Lib
GPT. Let's start with pseudo I guess because PSEUDO is a set
UID application on a UNIX system.
So the idea is this is a way for a normal user to do something as root.
Well, no, no.
If you corner case me,
I'm seriously going to drive to Canada and beat you with a stick.
No, no, it's just you can specify a user other than root.
You can give somebody print privileges or
that's true.
You can do as,
-- as let's just pretend root because that's what we care about
-- elevated privileges.
Sure.
And so the beauty there is, for example, I can give a user access to reboot system.
Yes,
I can give them access to change the network config or
I can give them access to interact with the mail system.
OK.
Look,
let's just say the only real reason this is ever used on a shared
system is so the support people can change the passwords of the other people.
-- That's usually what it is. Right. Yeah.
-- And again, that sounds like a simple thing.
-- Oh, just, you know, let Bob run reboot us root.
-- No,
that's,
it's horrendously.
-- I don't even know how many lines of code pseudo is
-- anymore.
It's probably a lot I should have done this before we hit record. But it's a lot.
We'll just say that
anyway, probably tens of thousands to hundreds of thousands. For sure.
-- Well,
-- and it relies on external libraries.
-- I
-- don't know how many actually. Anyway, that's a good question too.
It's, I feel I thought I was prepared.
The thing I like about the pseudo attack is
a lot of these pseudo attacks are exploitable,
not just by the users listed in the Pseudo earth file
-- by anybody on the system. Right.
-- Right.
-- So let's explain there's two pseudo problems. Well,
-- there's the Baron same edit.
What's the other one?
There's the,
there's a buffer overflow and then there's also one that affects
pseudo only when Se Linux is enabled in permissive mode,
which is absolutely hilarious
because
el
so, OK, so the first one is a buffer overflow and this is kind of your classic case of
uh this is qis
I'm anytime I use the word Attackers in this instance,
it's actually security researchers but whatever.
So
Kace figured out
that there is a,
-- we'll say one of the checks for
-- the argument parsing.
-- It
-- is, yeah, it's coming from, it's coming from the human typing kind of.
And they found a corner case where if a, if a, if a command line ends with a slash,
-- which is technically impossible in shell, it ends with a slash, apparently
-- not.
Well, anyway, there's, it ends with a slash.
Then basically one of the checks kind of fails.
You don't get your string terminator, which is a null character in the Seaworld.
And then you can end up writing nonsense onto the
heap and then eventually you can make pseudo do things that
pseudo shouldn't be doing.
And it's basically how it executes the command that it's been given to run.
And the reason. And this is like this is just a huge pile of holy crap
because you can't just use it with pseudo,
you have to use it with a command called pseudo edit.
And ironically pseudo edit is meant to only edit files.
And it's just like go,
I will put a link to the advisory in the show notes
because the advisory will do a far better job than I am.
And the details are unimportant.
-- There are exploits out there to go after this
-- and there's a,
there's a more reliable exploit that came out a few days after the original stuff.
Right. Right.
And so basically what this comes down to is just kind of classic buffer overflow.
It affects the heap
and just given the way it works, the technologies like address space layout,
randomization and position independent executable and all that stuff.
None of that matters here because of how
this exploit works because basically you're just overwriting the
buffer into the buffer of the command you're
going to execute and then you control that so
too bad.
It doesn't matter where is on the on the heap.
But anyway,
the point is this is an absolutely fascinating bug because these are
literally some of the best security developers in the world they made.
What would seem to be a very trivial mistake like if
you would have showed this to me and been like,
oh look, if you, if you do this, you can overwrite 11 character basically.
I'd be like, eh, that's probably not that bad, you know what I mean?
But like Wallace did the work.
I actually remember the first time that sort of, you can overwrite. What was it?
Like, four bites of data in some.
It was either it was either windows or internet explorer flaw
and of course, everybody's like, you know, medium, it's bad. It could be bad,
but like, 24 hours later, it's like,
yeah, we've upgraded this to like super critical.
Oh my God, you need to patch it right now. Important.
Actually with the lib G crypt flaw,
I can explain why, why that matters because that one is fascinating in what it does
and we'll, we'll get to that.
But anyway,
then the second problem that was found in pseudo is basically
pseudo has special code that says if I am running an E
Linux do something different when you run pseudo edit and it turned
out what it basically does I think is that what it,
it moves the file, it changes some permissions,
it edits the file and then it moves it back, I think is what happens.
And basically it's just your typical race condition where
they say, oh we're going to put the file here except
they don't make sure the file doesn't
this before they start changing some permissions on the file.
And so an attacker can basically create the file first and then do scary things.
Well, between the time of check and time of use, there's that
-- micro gap.
-- It's, yeah, but on computers now it's like seven years of execution time.
-- Right. Because they're so fast
-- and the thing is there are, we're going to say safer.
I'm not going to use the word safe definitively.
But there are safer ways to avoid these time of check
time of use things because I don't want to say it's a
problem, but it's a problem that we are well aware of,
but you have to know it's a problem.
I bet a lot of developers don't know that this is even a thing.
Yeah. Well, I, I think a lot of it probably boils down to the classic.
Why would they do that or they don't think it's possible to exploit or something?
It's forbidden knowledge,
I think for developers like it's just not something you would know.
I mean, so explain the bug because it, when you,
you can explain it in a way that makes it,
I guess more obvious.
Well, in simplistic terms, all these times of checks,
-- times of use bugs boil down
-- to make up a crappy example.
So I want to write a temp file. Does
temp slash
Kurtz
temp
file dot txt exist? No.
OK. Good. I'm going to go create that file and then write data to it
except between the time I checked that it exists.
And by between the time I actually started writing to it,
-- an attacker created a symbolic link there that points to etc password,
-- right?
-- You're catting garbage of password.
-- Exactly. Exactly.
Or the favorite, actually this is, I don't know if they fix this yet,
but the favorite used to be to cat garbage into the Cron tab.
And Kron was super happy to be like, oh, there's all this Gobby
*** in this file.
I'm just going to throw that away till I hit
something that looks like a command I should run.
And it's like what?
Yeah, but in fairness how many people messed up those first few star, space star,
space five, space star, right?
Like it just works.
-- We made it work
-- except it's like a super reliable exploit vector now like
-- no, just like when something is wrong give up, do not try to
-- recover.
You know what it boils down to if you see something, say something.
So if something doesn't look right, like stop and say something, report an error,
don't just keep
along.
It was a different time because I remember back in the
day when I was but a wee lad doing development,
there was this concept everyone would talk about which is be very stingy on what
you send and be very accepting on what you receive with the intention being.
-- Yeah. No, those days are over. Right.
-- Right. And
-- those days are so
-- over.
No,
if you don't receive exactly what you expect
like you give up because something horrible.
Well, and you tell the other end
-- that.
-- Right. Right.
So, I think, you know what? That's a good point.
That is something that can no longer
essentially be.
Yeah. Right.
Yep. If you get garbage just quit, don't, don't even try to parse the garbage.
It's not, it's not unless, although I say that
and html, like web browsers, those people are champions. I don't know how they do it
because they like, they will parse any garbage,
-- you know what they do it, they do it one patch at a time. Yeah,
-- that one patch at a time.
That is so true.
That's why web browsers are just like a constant onslaught of security updates.
I love those
CS S HTML.
Five compatibility tests where it's like you're supposed
to see like a rubber duck or whatever and
you know, they,
they run it in some brows and it's just this mangled piece of looking like gray to art.
I know. I know. Ok. Ok. Anyway, anyway,
so here's the lesson I would say we can take from everything pseudo related.
You cannot write memory safe code.
-- I don't care who you are just, you can't,
-- it's worse than that
because you cannot write memory safe code and
see and systems like Python or Rust that essentially
coalesce all the memory required safe code into a small core that, you know,
hopefully only a few very competent developers work on.
Certainly reduces the risk but doesn't eliminate it,
-- but even they can't get this. Right. Oh. Right.
-- Right.
And there are obviously still security vulnerabilities in
rust applications in Python applications.
It's just, it's not going to be a one bit buffer overflow.
Well,
what I'm saying is just by using Python or
Rust doesn't make you immune to buffer overflows.
Right. There's still potentially those in the run time, not your code.
It is possible.
It is unlikely.
But you can also execute Rust code in an
unsafe way where there's a decorator you can use.
That basically says like,
don't worry about memory management here. I got this and it's
like,
don't do that.
I feel like if you know that should be in your C I CD pipeline for like, no,
you're not allowed to do that,
right?
And I think we talked about this a while back where there
was some like web baring library in Russ that basically was like,
yep, I got this,
don't worry about and it was just like a train wreck of memory management problems.
You know what? It's actually not.
I just plugged in Python buffer overflow into CV database. 29 records.
There's only literally about a dozen in the last decade.
And is that because of Python or is that because of some weird binding? Yeah.
Yeah, that's like that's like a buffer overflow in PC
underscore
Rer
in C types call proc dot C blah, blah, blah, blah blah.
So that's like in the language core.
-- Interesting,
-- but there's literally a handful in the last decade.
And my
is to actually exploit those. You have to write Python code.
You don't just run code and interpret data.
That's usually how that works.
Yeah. So, but basically that's a lot safer.
-- I mean, that's, that's orders of magnitude better,
-- unquestionably.
Now, art,
do you think the pseudo people are ever going to rewrite pseudo in a safer language?
-- I don't think they can because I
-- don't
-- think
-- they are.
Well, you're in that classic trap of pseudo has so many learned lessons,
applied lessons that are embedded in that code.
But to extract all those lessons and ideas and implement them safely in a new
language is essentially it's not just your chances of doing so securely or zero.
Your chances of doing so successfully and getting it out
the door in a reasonable amount of time are zero.
Well, and here's the better question. Would it be a valuable use of resources?
I think the answer is no, because the correct answer is just stop using pseudo.
And now there's probably a bunch of people that
just leaped to their feet and said what?
But here's the reality, we don't live in multi user
systems anymore. It's just, it's not how it works.
And so like, for example, at, at, at elastic,
we have a bunch of containers we ship and none of them have pseudo in them
because why would you? Right. That'd be madness.
I've come to the, I came to the conclusion, actually, I think I want to say about,
well, about almost 10 years ago now. But yeah,
the only really truly safe sort of interface from one
privileged level to another is probably a network socket.
I mean, maybe I'm not, I'm not even concerned about that.
Well, but if you have,
if you have privileged code and unprivileged code running
in the same container or VM or whatever,
as soon as the attacker, it gives attacker a very clear way.
V
the LINX kernel or via pseudo or via whatever to get to that privilege goes.
Whereas over a network socket, because it's a network socket,
we're already making assumptions about the bad guys being able to try and talk to it.
And so it tends to be,
I think the mentality tends to be is it's a
lot more hardened and a lot more secure by default,
you have no data to back that up. I'm calling BS.
But, well,
but this whole multi user system clearly hasn't
worked from a security point of view.
I agree. And I think the only way to win not to play, right?
Just like microservice is microservice, the crap out of everything you can
and don't try to transition from low privilege to high privilege in the same,
I guess, like name space, we'll call it, right?
-- Just don't do that bad idea.
-- Basically. Name space process.
Well, not even process, space,
execution, space.
Just
you get the idea. I want to talk about LG
Crip because I think this one's way more fun actually. So this one is from Tavis
Tavis Ori,
who if you, if you listen to this pods
at
all, we talk about it.
Like, I guess frightening Tavis fan boys would be my description.
Well, I would say he's a top 10 researcher on the planet. That's true.
-- I mean, it's hard not to
-- like him like that infamous, you know,
does anybody at Claude Flair?
Can they reach out to me? It's Friday.
-- That's right.
-- I
think
I found something bad.
But anyway,
so Lib
Gryp is the cryptography library that GP G uses, which is the,
I guess we've complained about
at length. I won't rehash any of it here.
-- It was a beautiful piece of software from a different time
-- from,
from the early nineties.
But anyway, basically,
what it comes down to is Tavis found a one byte buffer overflow in Lib G
crypt.
And this can be exercised prior to checking
any check sums or signatures or anything,
which is like the worst possible problem you can have
in a crypto library because think of it this way,
let's say I send Kurt
some malicious encrypted content and his,
his web app decides, oh, I'm going to decrypt this and it loads it up and now if it's,
if it's pre checking anything,
it means just sending it, say an email.
And if the web app tries to decrypt it, you're going to trigger it immediately.
Whereas what happens in, let's say it's going to verify the signature,
meaning like I would have to sign
that content with my key and then send it to Kurt.
So it would be absolutely definitive. It came from me.
Whereas an attacker who doesn't have my key could not exploit that,
which is obviously far less dangerous.
Now, here's what makes this one so fun. It overwrites one
bite
in AAA heap structure
and that doesn't sound that bad, right?
A lot of people will be like, yeah, whatever, who cares?
I love that as a security person, I'm just like,
but here's what, here's what makes it so fun is in the intel world,
there's a concept called little Indian en Dia N.
So what ends up happening is part of that pointer,
the part that is we'll say less dangerous because obviously,
if you imagine when you're, when you're parsing data, the higher bits,
if you change those now,
you're moving from say memory in the we'll say one
megabyte page into memory in the 16 megabyte page,
right?
Where you could make these great leaps
in the process space.
Whereas if you affect the lower bits,
now you might only be moving, say, you know,
tens or hundreds of bytes forwards or backwards
depending upon what is happening in the application,
right?
-- Stuff
-- can still go bad, but it's a lot harder to make it go really bad. A
well, it's, it's what you want though in this case.
So what ends up happening is you overwrite one bite, right?
And that one bite is happens to be used as part of a function pointer
in a structure
that is then immediately called by the library, which is if I was going to create
the worst possible exploit
to show up a heap over of vulnerability in 2021. This is literally what I would do.
It's like the perfect storm of how not to do this stuff.
And it's, it's absolutely brilliant and it's absolutely hilarious.
It just gets me.
So how many more of these are lurking in this code?
See, that's what always gets me if somebody finds a CV in the code
and it's code that has
definitely had more than one CV found than it.
Like this isn't the first time they've ever found a flaw in Lib GIC Crypt.
Well, how many more are lurking? 1000 a million?
Well, probably not that many, but I'm sure it's not zero.
Well, there's so there's 15 cvs in Lib GIC
-- Crypt going back the last 12 years.
-- Yeah.
Probably be a lot more than that.
I feel like there's more than one security flaw roughly every year in Lib G
crypt. Interesting.
See, and that's what I see is the sense of scale is it, should it be 10 a year, 101.5.
I bet it should be more than one. I mean, it's C code parsing
encrypted content which is already pretty dicey work to begin with.
And I mean, again, like the developers who write this stuff, they're not slouches.
These people aren't bad at what they do.
Well,
and to be fair about a third of
these flaws are really complicated side channel things,
you know, where you can kind of cut Lib G some slack on that because it's like,
oh because the CPU does Xy and Z
that lib G
didn't anticipate until some security researcher spent
six months poking away at it.
-- Here's
-- part of the problem. So if a normal person found this bug
and they reported it,
there is a high probability the developer would be like, yeah, whatever.
Because a one bite buffer overflow on the heap, you would naturally assume oh,
address based layout randomization is going to save us.
It will be fine. Nothing to worry about here.
But then when someone like Tavis looks at it,
he obviously has a deeper understanding of
what's happening literally in the hardware.
I mean,
this kind of goes back to the last episode where we're
talking about using eight bits to really understand what's happening.
Like Tavis gets that in 64 bits, which is amazing.
Well, it's like anything where you have domain specific knowledge, you know,
I've done enough home renovations now that I look at
certain things around a house and I'm just like,
oh boy, that's bad.
Right. And, and it might not look that bad.
But, you know, in my brain, I'm just like, uh, oh my breaker panel,
all the breakers were different.
That's a good sign. Like they were the same brand,
but they were clearly spanning about two decades. And I'm just like, oh boy.
So I had them all replaced. That's a good idea.
And,
and the other thing I discovered when I was changing out
the light switches in the garage with motion sensor ones,
which is lovely.
I walk into the garage boof, the lights go on
and I accidentally touched the term uh the terminal to the, to the junction box,
metal junction wash with
screwdriver.
And luckily I have like quite nice screwdrivers, so I didn't get zapped,
but I got a nice big bang spark and uh
the light stayed on like the breaker didn't break.
So, and that's when I went and looked at my fuse box and actually paid attention to it.
And I'm like,
and I'm looking at it and I'm like, oh, ok.
These, these breakers are, some of them are probably original from 1981.
And so like I said, I had them all replaced and now if you do something like that,
the lights will go out and, you know, the host won't try and kill you.
But that's the thing like it's, that is a, not like if I,
if you tell that to a normal person,
oh, you know, you, you spark it and the lights stay on. They'll be like, ok.
Right.
Whereas every electrician is going, oh my God, go,
proceed immediately to the breaker box and turn everything off,
you know, and call an electrician.
So, and that's the thing. Right.
-- And this, this stuff is way more complicated than that.
-- I mean, I would agree.
I think it's, it's very difficult and there isn't, I mean,
I feel bad because I know I've explained it terribly, but
it's just
what is, what is happening here at a low level is so mind bogglingly weird.
And I feel like this,
it is one of those things you could probably make
a 25 minute youtube video explaining why this is happening
and
it would, it would be long because this is super complicated.
Here's a thought. What if we just,
and I don't, I get that this isn't for every piece of software on the planet,
like say Greer
said, but for security
sensitive code and I think we could all agree that pseudo and like
lib G crypt are, would, would be classified as security sensitive code.
But shouldn't they also strive not just for
quote unquote security but for code
correctness in general because code correctness
in general will also a help the code be more understandable and readable
-- and B prevent other problems.
-- I mean, it probably is though.
And that essentially what I'm saying is we,
we triage our software and hold certain pieces to a
higher standard which some organizations have tried to do.
I think this already is though.
Kurt, I mean,
this is the kind of code that is going to get
an enormous amount of scrutiny from a lot of people.
-- And yet here we are with legit crypt.
-- No, I agree.
But there are also, these are extremely esoteric bugs that only
the,
I guess I would say some of the top end researchers are going to be
able to understand or even create exploits for it just because it's so complicated.
So question then is that does that maybe not inherently
imply some sort of failure in the language that
was used if to truly understand the failures.
Here's the thing, if you have a
system
right built out of components that is so inherently complicated and difficult to
understand that understanding the failure scenarios
and properly addressing them is basically impossible
then.
Well, you know,
this reminds me of is all the old nuclear reactors from the 19 seventies
and eighties had about 3 million moving parts that turns out they don't need,
right?
I remember reading this reactor design from
Westinghouse where Westinghouse straight up said,
like we looked at our existing design and then
told the engineers to remove everything that wasn't needed.
And they basically ended up with a simplified nuclear
reactor with a giant pool of water above it.
And like,
-- you know, three valves in parallel.
-- Right.
I mean, yes, that, that's exactly correct
because gravity almost never fails.
No. Seriously. That was the reasoning. It's like pumps, pumps fail all the time.
So let's put the water tank above the nuclear reactor.
And the, and the managers are like,
oh, that makes it a lot cheaper too. They're like, yeah, no more pumps.
And, and I mean, I agree with this.
I think this is,
these are fine examples of the old saying what
I think it was as Brian Kernigan who said,
you know, it's twice as hard to debug code.
So if you write code as cleverly as possible,
you by definition are unable to debug it.
And this is the same thing like when you are
dealing with some of these issues in C code now,
it is probably 10 times harder to understand these
security bugs than it is to write them,
maybe even 100 times.
-- Oh, easily.
-- No, no, no.
It's provably hundreds,
if not thousands of times easier to write the bugs than it is to understand them.
That's fair.
How many security researchers on the planet can properly explain this, not us.
No, I and I, you know, I would put us in the top percent and I,
but I know I'm not smart enough to explain this properly.
It's super difficult just because it's,
you have to, I mean, it comes back to like that whole Feynman thing.
Can you explain how magnets work?
You know, and I'm going to tell a story about slipping on ice and then, no, I can't.
It's like what just happened
pretty much. That's, that's what my response is.
I,
I use Python.
-- That's my solution to this is I'm just not smart enough to write anything and
-- see,
I would disagree with that.
Like,
it, it's just, it's so, it's,
I feel like
someone says, how does this bug work?
And it's like, do you understand the Von Neumann architecture of computing?
And they're probably like, I
don't know what any of the words you just said are.
Well,
yeah, even that is a great point. You know, we have this
the infamous schism of, well, maybe we should separate data and control.
-- It seems complicated. It's
-- expensive. This is much easier.
I
know,
know, I know
it's just this is
and this is not even, I'll be blunt, these aren't even the truly complicated bugs.
Like when you start looking at side channel
stuff where you have hardware branch prediction,
interacting with crypto
code, it's like
just I'm going to believe whatever the security researcher wrote because I can't,
it's not that I can't even validate it. It's I'm
smart enough to know that I probably don't fully understand it.
-- And
-- this is already crazy complicated.
And these, you're right, like the bug Tavis found just because of how it works.
It is an infinitely more simple heap overflow than some other stuff.
But it's still crazy complicated which now, now I have,
I guess two things to add to that is number one,
they goodness we have progressed
the technologies we use to the point that
you are basically, we're in the realm of like ridiculous, crazy bugs, right? Where
-- the simple ones are gone because we fixed,
-- most of them are gone. Well,
most of them.
But you know what I mean?
Like we fixed a lot of these problems through
libraries and compiler options and all this stuff.
And that is amazing and fantastic.
But now I think on the second side of it is like,
we also have better languages for this stuff.
Like honestly, some of this stuff needs to go.
It just, it does.
What's really fascinating to me is you look at the writing on the wall where,
well you read the tea leaves with Microsoft and
Rust and it's pretty clear that they're tired.
They're just as tired of Mac
-- of patch Tuesday as we are.
-- Yeah, seriously.
And not only that, I mean, I honestly,
I bet there just aren't a lot of c programmers around anymore.
-- Well, at
-- that level of expertise needed because that's the thing, right? I mean,
to, to have somebody come in and start
interacting with the window, like a source space,
like the Linux kernel or the Windows
kernel or the Windows user space.
That's, I can't even imagine how many years of education and training,
you need to properly understand that code,
let alone make changes to it safely and correctly.
-- It's hard for sure, for sure.
-- And they're all getting old and dying and retiring.
Thank goodness, finally get something nice.
All right. Anyway, I'm, I'm going to call this.
We've been, we've been rambling on, I guess
I will end this just with the,
don't you? See,
that's all
like,
-- just don't
-- and consider maybe using something like
rust to start to replace your c co
-- literally
-- anything else. Cart, the answer is literally anything but c
because, and I'm not talking about from a security point of view,
but from an actual sort of project management,
if you can do a renovation of your house
by slowly replacing things rather than having to rip half your house apart,
-- that's probably going to be more successful, especially in software
-- terms.
The house of
Theseus.
Yeah, exactly. The House of Theseus with respect to say something like rust and see
where
it's actually,
it's achievable to do this kind of rewrite.
Whereas you pick a different language
and start a complete whole new rewrite something
else.
That's your,
I mean, remember when Mozilla Firefox, you know, they almost died.
Every major rewrite I've ever seen has,
has either killed the company or organization or been
life altering,
-- terrible
-- for them. Yeah, I mean, you are correct.
II, I do agree with that,
-- but maybe
-- that's part of the answer is to
have these languages like rust that are not only safer
but give you the ship of Theseus
because here's the thing,
we're asking you to fix the ship while you're underway in a storm.
And I'd like you to swap the engine out for something better, please.
And the engineer is kind of like he's not Scotty.
Right.
-- You know, if it was Scotty, we'd be fine.
-- It's true. It's true. We would.
That's right. Take two hours. All right. Anyway, I'm calling it.
That's, this is a good one. Thank you everyone for listening to you, Kurt.
You can go to open
social security podcast.com head.
It's Suzy Pound. Oh, it says podcast hashtag do hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks everybody. Bye bye
the