-- A recording, recording,
-- recording. It's December 22nd. Hooray.
Yeah, we're getting there. So how to report a singular security flaw.
-- I guess you just do it right.
-- Pretty much.
Um,
yeah.
No, it's, it's like Nike says, just do it start by looking for how to report the flaw
to the project because some projects have a bug bounty,
some have an email address.
Some have, you know, they just want you shoved in their bug tracker
and then following that you give them as much information as you can.
I would, I would say you missed a crucial step, which is, have a security flaw
-- step one.
-- Well, that was sort of assumed, but you're right.
Not necessarily.
No, no, but you are correct. You are technically correct, which is the best kind.
I've gotten enough security reports to know that that is an often misunderstood or
-- next step.
-- I'm actually going to disagree with you because
sometimes you have something that you're not sure about and as a vendor,
I would much rather get those, not sure reports.
I do agree with that. However,
-- if I get a, not
-- because those are typically the worst ones,
but but
I've never gotten a not sure report.
I generally get a, I have found a critical security issue in your product
and it's like,
-- no, you didn't. This is literally documented functionality.
-- Yeah. Well,
and again, there, the thing I've seen is the way they want to use the product.
It does become a critical flaw for them because how do I put it nicely?
They kind of want to use the product wrongly or in a way that makes their life easier.
Sometimes, sometimes then you educate the customer and hopefully they take to that
a
sometimes,
-- I mean, so
-- I didn't say it works.
We
have a security vulnerability now we need to tell somebody.
And I think what you hinted at at the beginning is really important
where every project in every company is a little bit different here.
And now going back to the topic of bug bounties, we talked about what,
a couple of days ago, if you have a bug bounty,
-- it becomes much easier for researchers to contact you.
-- It's a very strong signal.
-- This is how we want our security books,
-- report ignoring the signal.
You have a standard application
to do this, right? Whereas if I, if I email security at
cried.org,
-- what, what happens
-- next
-- to my
-- inbox? Well, I know that, but I'm saying, you know what I mean? Like
I have emailed companies.
Well, first of all, I've tried to contact them and you can't even find them.
But you end up on Twitter like, hey, does so and so.
Well, look at Tavis Ormandy half the time. Oh, my goodness.
And it's always Friday night, which is the best.
But so let's say I contact a company right now.
What kind of information should I be including
-- in my report to this
-- company? Definitely at an absolute minimum.
-- The product and version.
-- Yeah, that's huge.
Well,
and I've seen people not include the version quite
often or they say it's the latest one.
And I'm like, no, I want a number.
I, I, you know, I, I need this explicitly because I've seen situations where
they report something in a product that's no longer supported
or end of life or about to end of life.
It, it does happen
and in which case it's, you know,
unless it's truly terrible and there's enough customers demanding it.
Well, it's gonna die next.
Like I literally remember we had a pretty bad flaw coming in on a product that was,
you know, end of life in a week.
And I was like, I'm just gonna put this one over here till Monday and then, oh,
look at that
right.
I actually replied to them and said, you know,
this thing EOL is in a week and more to the point, please.
For the love of Peter upgrade to
-- the newer version of the software, it's much better.
-- Ok.
So we have a version, we have an application,
we have to include you need details though to say this is what I did
and the more details, the better because I can always,
ok, there is the potential for chasing down false rabbit holes,
but without information, there's no rabbit holes.
Yeah. Right. I mean, I've had that before where someone sent a report.
It was like, I can't figure that, you know,
you need to give me more and often they never reply again.
It crashed. I made a crash.
Ok.
You know what this really comes down to honestly,
at the end of the day is there is a vast corpus
of information on the internet about how to report good bugs.
It's just a bug, right? How do you report a bug? Like what, what did you do?
What happened? What should have happened?
The one potential difference being is that you might want
to be able to report the bug secretly and again,
having a bug bounty or specific security
or a whatever accomplishes that.
So we can basically ignore that part of the argument.
-- But
-- now I will say there is nothing wrong with reporting a bug in a public bug tracker.
If there is no other way you can find to contact a project,
I would go even one further to say while I prefer and I'm making
big air quotes here responsible disclosure and trying to work with a vendor.
At the same time, the vendor shipped a product with a flaw why
I found the flaw.
-- Am I now supposed to do a bunch of work to make the vendor's life easier?
-- Yeah, I agree.
I think from a researcher perspective you have to set a ceiling
for the pain you're willing to suffer and don't let them,
don't let them take advantage of you.
I think that's the single biggest takeaway I would,
I would give for this particular bit of advice.
-- And
-- I've also seen situations where people who are not at all,
security researchers stumble across horrific things.
Yeah, it happens and they just don't want to deal with it.
-- And that's
-- fair. It is. We will see you on December 23rd.