Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast.
Episode 131 with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
What's new man?
I ran out of decaf
coffee. Decaf.
Why is that a problem? Like it's decaf, you could drink water.
Apparently when I drink real coffee, I talk too fast on the podcast.
You do talk fast but running out of decaf
just like stir some mud in your water or something and it's
pretty much the same thing. Right.
-- Well,
-- here's the weirdest part as far as I can tell my Costco doesn't sell decaf
coffee.
I don't know if I've ever looked Costco's coffee selection,
-- I think is quite bad and I generally don't purchase
-- coffee.
There,
there's,
you have about 10 choices.
Half of them are pods and half of them are beans and most of the beans are Starbucks.
So.
Right. And I don't look at the pods.
I,
I actually had one of those pod making coffee things once and the waste was horrific.
And then I started using it to make, uh, noodles
because I could get hot water very quickly.
And then I realized why am I using a very
expensive coffee maker to make hot water when I can
use my $25 tea kettle over there. And it actually gets hotter and better. So
I got rid of it.
I grew up with one of those German instant hot water taps that has like,
basically a little boiler.
Oh,
those are the best man. Yeah.
And so I just, I, I took that for granted and now it's, it's II,
I really do wish I had one.
I got one of the electric kettles when from, you know, various trips to Europe,
they always had the nice electric kettles.
-- Now, granted, Europe has 200.
-- Those things are a fire hazard.
200 and 40 volts, they're not a fire hazard.
They've got 240 volts.
So the ones they have work like scary fast and
the one I have is obviously plugs into us.
Voltage 120 volts.
It's still acceptable. I can get a pot of hot water, a liter of hot water in
probably two minutes, which I think is acceptable.
And I really like it because
I can put as much as I want, obviously turn it on and it is way faster than my stove was
and it is made of glass and clear. So it amuses me that I can watch the bubbles. So,
there you go. That is always fun. It is. It's fantastic, man. I, I love it and,
and it also amuses me that it only has leader markings on the side of it.
-- So it's clearly this was not built for the US audience.
-- Oh, right.
Because, yeah, sorry. Yeah.
See, that wouldn't have occurred to me as a problem, but as a Canadian,
I speak fluent metric and
material. Right.
You use the good way to measure things and not a ridiculous,
you know, all of our building supplies are, are imperial.
Uh, That doesn't surprise me.
Everything.
Half inch copper tubing,
four by eight sheet supply wood that are
actually 49 inches by 83 inches because yeah,
well, that's the beauty of it too.
Like,
like none of those sizes of building materials are
actually the sizes that they say they are,
which is hilarious in its own sad way.
And it actually is a nightmare because my house was built in 1919.
And so the two by fours in my house are actually two by four.
So anytime anyone has to do any sort of work on anything
you have to accommodate for that, which is
-- funny and sad at the same, you have to
-- go by a four by six and clean it down.
I
put in a regular two by four and scab it out with f
it's way easier, man.
It depends what it is too, right?
Like when, when I put in a door and I had to like muck with a load bearing wall.
Yeah, that one got two by six is all cut up.
So that's actually a perfect lead in for this, which is um
zero. Patch.com has just released three micro patches for three Windows.
Zero days.
Yeah, you need to explain this to,
we'll say to me what you actually just did a little while ago
because I'm certain there are some listeners that don't understand and like,
I don't run Windows anymore, so I don't even know what's going on.
So basically when you have
a
bug, be it security flaw or otherwise in a piece of software,
the typical thing you would do is well with open source, you'd
update that software or add a patch to fix the behavior recompile and deploy it, just
-- ignore it forever,
-- which is
um or you know,
in the case of something like a proprietary piece
of software where you only have the binary,
typically, you, you wait for the vendor to
issue a fix and for them to do it on their end, right?
They patch the source code, recompile
Q A it test it blah, blah blah and ship it out,
which is what Microsoft does every patch Tuesday.
-- Right. Yes,
-- exactly.
But the thing is you can for certain types of bugs actually
modify the binary typically in
a
relatively small way like several
statements or several um essentially several assembler commands can be replaced
to
patch that bug.
And this is binary patching and some vendors actually do, do this.
So um Google's Courgette, I wrote an article about this probably a decade ago.
Courgette. The idea was,
well, we need to replace this binary, like chrome
your web browser.
We need to update this binary, but we,
we actually only need to make a change to like 1% of it
for this, you know, update, right? We're not, right.
We haven't completely changed and rewritten the program from scratch. We've just
added support for this and fix that. And
the actual difference in the Binaries if you build them correctly is like maybe 1%.
So that meant they could chip a patch for your system.
That was a megabyte instead of 100 megabytes, which
you know, when you have many, many millions of end users using this,
that really adds up and, and it creates a much better user experience because, well,
not to throw Microsoft under the bus, but every Microsoft patch, Tuesday,
I don't even run windows.
I just have a Microsoft office installed
on average. I would say it's about two gigabytes of download
which thank goodness, I live in the city and have high speed internet.
But I'm thinking if you live out in the country, you know,
with five or 10 megabit internet,
which is pretty good by country standards in North America
-- that would take all day.
-- Well, Linux
patches are similar where you generally have to download a whole new package
and you just rip and replace and I'm sure Windows does similar things.
And I know
as part of Microsoft's SDLC program,
they added, they basically made the statement that,
like if you're modifying code in a function,
we're going to rewrite the whole function because
it's quite likely there's other problems in it.
And so they're replacing probably quite a bit of code on a regular basis and I,
I doubt they're monkey patching. They're probably rip, rip and replacing files.
Yeah.
So, anyways, uh I guess the premise of zero patch is that kind of like, well,
very similar to uh what were those network protection,
uh IP S intrusion protection systems.
I'm
trying to think of the vendors that used to sponsor P
to own.
And so they would get these zero days and then they would write these,
these uh what was it called?
Like network DNA scripts or something that
the attacks
uh tipping point. That's the one,
right?
So the premise was basically, it's like,
rather than having to patch 10,000 windows machines,
you have this thing sitting on your network that like
blocks
attack X.
That's it. It just magically blocks attack X that
we solve the problem.
And so zero patch
takes that to the,
well, the machine level where OK, we've,
there's CV E food, there's no patch from Microsoft for it yet.
So here's a small binary patch and in this case, they've released um three A SM files,
you know, a similar files.
So, what is this? Like three maybe four dozen lines of text.
So the patch itself, you can, you can look at and see
what it's
attempting to do.
Part of the concern though is this is not, you know,
applying a source code patch to source code.
This is applying
a small binary patch to a really huge and complicated binary, right?
I mean, most Windows binaries,
um I've met people who disassemble them and,
and try to understand them for a living and it's a, it's a nontrivial task,
but it is doable to be clear.
This is absolutely doable and it can be done in a reasonably sane and trustworthy way
assuming this zero patch company is doing a good job. But I don't know.
So anyways, they've released these three micro patches,
you can apply them to your window system and in theory,
they will address these 30 days
and you're good to go.
Uh, they probably do. I mean, so here's going to be my complaint.
Well, I shouldn't say complaint. Here is the explanation I would give around.
This is
a long time ago. People would say things like
open source is less secure because anyone can
see the source code and they know what's happening
and
it is quite clear that just because something is in a binary only format,
it does not make anything more secretive or safe.
Well, you don't even need to look at it. You just fuzz it nowadays, right?
American fuzzy loop or something and you can find tons of bugs,
you, you fuzz it.
But then there's people who will look and say, well, here's what's wrong, right.
There's missing a length check is missing on this
line here or this line here is doing something.
It shouldn't, it's obviously missing
one of the, the parameters for copying memory is wrong. The math is wrong, whatever.
Right. There's, there's a million things it can be
and
the, the tools and the people are so sophisticated now
that
it
honestly binary code is as good as source code in, in many, many instances.
I was just about to say the thing.
It's weird to me that people ignore the fact that binary code
is, it's just machine readable source code
that's been
and sometimes it's, it's mangled a bit like um CS S MIN,
you know, or uh sorry javascript min,
you know, which packs takes out all the white space and, and smashes the,
the variable names and makes it a, you know, kind of painful to understand.
But
fundamentally
the
the intent and the code is still there.
You know, you can, there, I know people that can comfortably read assembler,
you know, you give them a file full of assembler and they like the matrix.
You know, I see a,
I see a dog and I see a cat and I see a whatever and it's just like, wow, your,
your brain is something different than mine.
That's for sure.
You know, and we need people like that. But
man, they scare me sometimes.
It's fundamentally it's machine readable code.
And if it's machine readable code, that means a human being can also understand.
It might take a little longer, it might take a little, you know, a few extra tools.
But we've had those tools for 20 or 30 years now.
Uh Yeah, the tools are pretty good. And
if you're used to assembler,
it's not that hard to figure out what's going on in a lot of cases.
My fear or my amazement is that they can hold
the, the
concept of what the program is doing in their head, you know, holding a concept with,
of, you know, thousands of branch statements and hundreds.
Have you ever seen those people that do
the disassembler and create those flow chart diagrams
of like of an application, right? And you end up with
-- make
-- those, the disassembler makes them well.
Yeah, exactly.
And you end up with this thing that has like 4000 boxes and 3000 lines and
is just like a something a cat would cough up.
But that's what your program looked like before you assembled it.
It's just the assembler does a nicer job of turning it into the spaghetti.
It is because
in a lot of instances, if you take your program
and you try to kind of do that, the code execution tracing like you end up with there.
Uh it'll skip over things like system calls which let's face
it. They're actually really important.
-- But once you're dealing with kind of, some of the assembly and
-- some of them are deep,
like some of them are
something that, like a single statement that, you know,
that's thousands and thousands of instructions.
Ultimately.
Oh, more than that, I bet, I bet most Libs
calls actually, I should look into this. This would be a fun project.
So I just ran into a, I have a small Python script.
I used to validate email addresses and I use the Python email validator.
And one of the things it can do, which is quite handy is
it takes the domain name and actually validates that there's an
MX record or valid IP for it and next to it,
right. So
you plug in google.com and it's like, yeah, google.com has an MX record.
I talked to port 25 on it. It worked great
and
I haven't run the script in a long time.
And apparently at some point in the last few weeks,
my ISP blocked my outgoing access to port 25.
So I run the script
and I get this just weird trace back error in Python saying, you know, I just,
it can't, it doesn't work, it doesn't, it's not working.
My first thought was, oh, I've enabled I PV six across my network, maybe I PV six
broke, you know, is my Python compiled with IP P six support. I don't know,
you know, it's whatever came on my Mac machine from X code or whatever.
So I, I check into that.
No, it doesn't seem to be that and,
and I finally like five minutes later try tail netting to
port 25 because let's just see if it's actually responding.
Right. Nope,
it's now blocked by the ISP. So, you know, that single line of Python that
results in Lord knows how many system calls and
calls
to go out.
You know, do an MX look up, connect to a port that's got to be, I
don't know, not a million instructions but more than 1000.
Oh, I
-- wouldn't be shocked at all if it's a million, it might even be more true.
-- So,
see, I'm, I'm not really sure what to make of this micro patch.
And because my one thought is somebody who's paranoid
enough that they need to fix their zero days and
be invulnerable to them and can't wait for Microsoft
at the same time, I imagine
is not the kind of person installing binary patches from some company that I, I,
I've never heard of before.
I, I don't know what I think necessarily. I guess I would view it as
in the open source world.
There are,
there are times when someone might post a patch and say here's a patch for this issue
and it is conceivable.
The upstream project hasn't patched it yet and people will take it and use it,
but it's very much a caveat emptor.
Right. You're, you're on your own
and it's not our problem. And this is basically the same thing, right?
If you can't wait for Microsoft,
that's your prerogative.
But if you, like, end up, you know, nailing your foot to the floor, well,
that's also your problem.
Right.
I don't know. I don't have a problem with it if people want to do it great.
If, if you feel like the risk of not patching is
greater than the risk of using
this, this potentially dodgy patch.
Ok.
And I mean, I, yeah, I, I don't, I don't have an issue.
Well, my other concern would be is,
is what it does warranty wise when you call Microsoft Support.
And they're like,
so have you made any changes to this system?
And your, your response is, well, funnily enough.
We, uh, we did apply a binary patch.
I, I suspect first of all,
the Microsoft support people aren't going to know what that means at the top,
at the front level.
Um, and once they do understand,
-- I, I,
-- in all seriousness my guess.
And I mean, I remember I've, I've,
I work at a place now that even does this and I've done it in the past is
it's often run this tool and, and send me the output and then you'll get the output.
You're like, yeah, you changed a whole bunch of stuff.
You're gonna have to install the original stuff
and reproduce it and then I can help you
and that, that's almost certainly what's going to happen.
So, again, that leads to the, you know,
I don't really understand the market for this.
So, I mean, if somebody out there is using zero patch,
please reach out to us and tell us I, I'd love to hear your use case,
but as I said, I just,
I have a hard time understanding the risk profile that would want this
and, and let's face it. There might not not be a market for this, right.
This could be a start
up.
That's a problem looking for a solution.
They've been around for a few years or a solution looking for a problem.
That's what it is.
I don't know. And maybe they're wildly successful.
And now I guess, I guess however, here's one thing to think about is
there are many organizations that don't like
applying the Microsoft patches because they're gigantic.
And so there might be an appeal to saying, well, here's like a literal one line patch.
I'm gonna choose this rather than install this pig of a Microsoft patch.
And then once a year I'll install the Microsoft
Giganto patches
and then deal with the outcome.
Well, the classic LTs model of we only fix what's absolutely needed to be fixed.
We didn't improve anything. We just,
-- we're keeping this thing from running off the rails.
-- Right. Right.
Yeah, I don't know, maybe. Yeah.
So, anyway, anyway, let's, let's continue our, our news roundup episode.
Well, I guess the next big thing and,
and here's the,
it is
for you and me it would be a large amount of money.
But I suspect for Google,
somebody pointed out that if, if essentially Google was a person earning a wage,
this would be less than one hour's wage,
you need to introduce a headline before you start talking about this.
Nobody knows what you mean.
-- Yeah.
-- So Google was fined. Well, I wanted to give some context for this number.
So Google was fined 57 million by French data privacy body
for failing to comply with the E U's GDPR regulations.
And at first I was like, oh God, data breach, what the heck happened, ah,
uh, having read the article, it, it's not that bad.
What it essentially seems to boil down to is that Google
doesn't really inform people
well, if at all
as to what's going on privacy wise with their data.
So it was pointed out that you need to click through
multiple screens and you need to hunt through multiple documents.
And ultimately for you to understand what Google is
doing through data would essentially require a law degree,
probably several 100 hours of free time
and you still wouldn't know exactly what's going on.
Yeah. Oh, without question,
uh, they got fined for 57 million, which like I said,
that sounds like a lot of money to you and me.
But to put it in context, if Google was a person that would be something like,
less than an hour's wage.
Right.
-- It's probably seven
-- minutes of, you know,
my last speeding ticket was more than that.
Like, my last speeding ticket was like, two hours of my wage.
Photo
radar. Oh, no, it's not that bad, but it's just, it's photo radar. Right?
Like they set up in zones where everybody goes a bit quick.
That's great.
Google's business model depends on them basically selling your information.
And I know the, the information is worth a comically low amount.
-- It's
-- selling the information to third parties either directly or indirectly.
Right.
And
they have minimal incentive to make drastic changes.
Now, if the fines continue to increase
and look, they without question, have accountants that are saying
this is how much money we're making with this ridiculous policy.
This is how much the fines are.
As long as the amount of money they're making is larger enough than the fines.
They don't have to care.
Plus they can just spend a few 100,000 or a
million dollars fighting this in court to drag it out.
Right. And right. It'll be in court for, I'm sure 20 years because
they can, right. Like you and I cannot afford to pay lawyers for 20 years.
I probably can't afford to pay a lawyer for 20 minutes for something like this.
And, and this is I think about this all the time is just
some of these Gigantor companies, they, they don't have to follow the same rules.
You and I do because in some ways they can make their own rules. And
-- I think the intent of, well, there
-- is regulatory capture is a real thing.
Sure.
You know, that that's a, that's a sad fact of modern life in,
in a lot of western democracies
and well, countries in general
and I have a feeling that the purpose of GDPR with their,
their potentially ridiculously large fines
is to deal with this exact problem.
But I also have a strong suspicion that it isn't going to work
because until we have 20 years of case law
that says this is how this is going to work.
They're just going to drag this stuff out forever and
by the time the case makes it to court,
like the world will have changed so much, it won't even matter.
Yeah, I,
the one thing I've seen consistently when
talking about crime and punishment and rehabilitation,
one of the major deterrent to crime
is that people have to be consistently caught and
punished quickly
and reasonably,
you know, if your kid or your dog does something you don't like, you don't,
you don't bring it up 10 hours later or a day later,
right? They've forgotten about
it or it's just, it's not connected enough for them to understand.
This is also true of people in companies.
And so my concern is these companies can drag this out for months or years.
I don't think they're gonna quote unquote, learn their lesson.
-- Uh,
-- no, I don't, I don't think they will. And, and this is,
this is kind of fundamentally
going to be the problem with regulating cybersecurity someday, which, you know,
is something we talk about.
I go back and forth constantly. I'm, I'm back to thinking regulation won't work.
Uh, I'm sure that in a couple of hours I'll change my mind.
But
it's,
let's say you do start just fining these companies to death.
It, it's gonna have to be a comically large fine,
but you actually have to collect the fines.
That's the problem.
Right. Right. You have to move fast.
It's not, even if the fine is big or large, you actually have to collect it.
And one thing I've been looking for in GDPR terms is I've been
looking for companies that have been fined under GDPR and we have,
now we have Google,
there's that Canadian firm, uh,
that was involved in Brexit and did some shenanigans and got a fine,
but they're appealing it.
So,
one thing I've been looking for is places that have had to
actually pay meaningful fines and I haven't really found anything compelling.
I haven't heard of anything at all because I know this is,
there's some people I'll talk to every now and then and they're saying, oh,
we got to take the GDPR stuff, seriously,
or we're going to be fined a bazillion dollars.
And it said, show me a single company that's been fined this, right? Like,
-- because here, so, and I guess here's the other half
-- of this,
show me a company that's actually paid this fine,
-- right? Ok.
-- That's fair. You know, this reminds me of all these environmental laws.
Here's the other half with something like GDPR is
the goal of the regulators isn't like they're not out to get you,
they're out to help you do the right thing.
And so as long as you pretend to like you care,
they're, they're on your side fundamentally. Right.
And
that's,
I'm sure Google is pretending to care.
But my, I have a suspicion
there, there are,
there are definitely people who do carry Google so don't get me wrong there.
I'm not going to say they're super evil, but there's also a bunch of people who don't.
Well, the problem is Google's 100,000 people.
It's a country. Exactly.
And I'm sure they have a lot
of internally inconsistent views on everything including,
uh, well, ok, to bring up something utterly ridiculous.
Remember the discussion at Red Hat about the removal
of the paper towel dispensers in the bathrooms.
Yes.
And I mean, how many
-- people got involved in that discussion?
-- Everybody.
It was,
and OSHA was invoked and
just, wow, it, it was a big deal. So, I mean, and that's paper towels in the bathroom.
It was epic.
And so something like privacy on a global scale. Like,
-- sorry. But
-- I,
I know, man,
it's,
I know, I know. And I don't think we ever got paper towels back. Did we?
I feel like I feel like no, maybe, maybe in a couple offices.
That was that? Oh, that's right.
I remember that was the amusing thing is I'd go visit our
offices in Europe and they got them but the US offices didn't,
uh,
for
-- probably GDPR or something.
-- I don't know.
And there's probably some European directive on Hannah washing that involves
I, who knows, whatever, whatever it was
anyway. But, but yeah, you're absolutely right.
-- It's big companies are,
-- it's no, it's, it's groups of people. It doesn't matter.
-- You've played
-- D and D has your party ever agreed
consistently?
No,
I'm trying to think of an instance and I can't.
So
there is, there's always, but it's, it's any group of people.
There's always lots of people who are just
anyway, people are people that's,
let's keep moving. We've got one more fun story to talk about, uh, Mastercard.
Why don't you explain this one?
Yeah. So this one I really like, it's
when you sign up for a free trial, a
lot of them require credit card number.
Uh,
ostensibly,
ostensibly the reason is to make sure you're a real
person or that you're not abusing the free trial,
you know, one per customer kind of deal because most people don't have more than
I'm hoping. Two or three credit cards.
Right.
You sign up for a free trial
and you're either satisfied or dissatisfied with it.
So then you try, well, if you're,
if you're satisfied, you continue, you pay
whatever,
but if you're dissatisfied or don't care,
sometimes
unsubscribing or getting them to not bill, you can be
impossible
in fairness. Uh, especially with some of these multilevel marketing scams
where, you know, I'm going to send you a free promo gift box of
essential oils or whatever garbage they're peddling
and
you get that and implicit in that is, you know,
you've now signed a contract that you're committing to buying
like 250 bucks for this stuff every month or whatever.
And you're expected to flog that on to your friends and family or whatever,
getting out of those things can basically be a nightmare.
So it looks like basically Mastercard is making it possible to
cancel more easily because here we go to help cardholders with that decision.
Merchants will be required to send the cardholder either by email or text
the transaction amount, payment date,
merchant name along with explicit instructions on how to cancel a trial.
So hopefully it's easier for people to cancel these stupid things
and these companies that prey on people for getting to.
Well, a great example, the cable company has been selling my parents
the same 15 megabit down one megabit up internet for about a
decade now and they're paying 70 bucks a month for it and
for $55 a month you can get 300 megabit symmetrical now, locally.
That's fantastic from another company and you can
even get a better deal from that company.
So,
you know, I'm going to name it. Shaw. Shame on you. Shaw. My parents trusted you
-- and you dick
-- them. I'm, I'm shocked a cable company would do this there. I know me too.
Beacons of honesty and integrity in society. Kurt.
Yeah, it's uh
-- not that the phone company is any better but whatever
-- the phone company is worse.
-- Look,
-- it's a different flavor.
It's right. They're, they're all terrible and
it is, man. II, I like the fact that Mastercard is doing this because
this is problematic and I think
it's especially problematic with the older generations
where
I have, I have seen, I'll use my parents as the example I have.
I have more than once said, like, why do you have this?
They said, oh, we don't know how to cancel it. We gave up
said that's not the right answer.
You call the credit card company and tell them
what's going on and they will deal with it.
And
I, I guess here's the thing. I keep thinking of
what's the angle for Mastercard here?
Is it just that customers like them more or,
or do you think there's some sort of other business?
Mastercard isn't really technically doing anything other than forcing
a certain level of transparency onto the merchant.
So they,
so I'll put it blunt,
Mastercard is taking a cost center handling charge
backs and angry customers and Externalizing it.
So something might be right
because I bet chargebacks are,
well, it would,
it wouldn't shock me if there's a lot of additional costs
we don't see or understand in that industry around charge backs.
It's not just saying
of, uh, you know, merchant, I'm taking money away from you.
I I think that transparency is good because quite frankly,
what's that famous quote?
You know, if you're doing something that
you would be ashamed to do in public,
maybe, you know, that's not the right thing to do and,
and obviously society changes and things that used
to be shameful or no longer shameful like
uh
well or things that were
OK are now shameful, like say smoking in the car with your baby.
But I think in this case,
forcing merchants to provide a degree of basic transparency.
Like I mean, come on the transaction amount, the payment date
and the merchant name, come on. You can't argue against that
and the explicit instructions on how to cancel a trial. Again,
that's a basic level of transparency and honesty that II I
think should be required.
That's fair,
that's fair.
And it also makes it easier for Mastercard probably to handle charge backs when
they don't do this because now they're
in violation of their card processing agreement.
Yeah, that's, that's a good point.
So, actually I, I have a story to tell about this as well. So my daughter has an ipad
and
I got an email over the weekend that said,
you congratulations on signing up for this service.
And I looked at her and I said, what did you sign up for?
And she goes, oh,
I downloaded this video editing program because she's like she wants to,
she's working on her youtube channel intro, right?
For
the youtube channel she's going to make
and I said, well, you know,
they're going to charge you five bucks a month
right after the first like 12 days or whatever.
She said, yeah, I, I uninstalled the app and I said that's probably not enough.
And, but it was really nice though because you, we went into the
wait. She has a credit card.
Well, no, but she has itunes credit,
right? Like I
assume the
your credit and then just like magically cancel.
But at the same time, it's like this is actually really nice because Apple has made it
like there's just a, there's a tick box or not a tick box.
So it's like a section in your account that just says
subscriptions and you click it and say unsubscribe and it's gone.
Right. That is
awesome.
And it's,
and, and I guess at the same time
when you have like that walled garden environment,
they can get away with that because Apple can say you do it our way or screw you.
And the thing to remember too is a lot of, well,
especially for subscriptions with software.
The marginal cost of me servicing one extra customer is basically zero.
So it's just
free money.
And
yeah, Apple has a market and a brand worth protecting.
Same, same as mastercard.
I,
I have a Visa and a Mastercard and I've actually started
using my Visa and I've stopped using my Mastercard pretty much
because Mastercard was difficult to get a hold of for something.
And I started using Visa and I actually had to do a
charge back on a couch because we bought a couch and they
never delivered the damn thing. The couch saga,
we paid for this thing back in October.
And so when I phoned Visa, it was
somewhat annoying to get a hold of them.
But once I finally did the charge
back process literally consisted of which transaction,
which date?
Ok. T
tap, tap, tap, tap, tap, tap. Let me put you on hold for a minute
and then she came back and she's like, ok,
the charge back will be issued on your next billing cycle.
Thanks. Bye.
And I'm like, that's it.
Like I, I assumed I'd have to send in a piece of
like a copy of the receipt or something.
-- But no, just
-- boom, I've had no trouble with Visa.
I've never tried to do a charge Act of mastercard.
It's,
but no, no, here's,
here's something to think about.
If, if Apple or rather, if, if the, the subscription my daughter signed up for,
if she got charged that I would blame Apple.
But when I use my credit card to sign up for some scam thing and
I get like a charge for something I didn't know I was signing up for,
I don't blame the credit card company. I blame myself and the other company. Right.
Well, and Apple too. Uh, let's face it. They,
it's, it's worth it.
I suspect because the cost of hiring humans to answer the phone and deal
with angry customers would be a lot more than just providing those check boxes
without question. So, II, I really like when companies
accidentally or intentionally even
make our lives easier because they want to cut costs and I'm ok with that.
-- Yep. I, I agree 100%. You know,
-- unfortunately, it goes the other way sometimes. But
I think in this case
that basic level of transparency
I, I think should not just be for trial offers. I think that should be for everything.
I mean, shouldn't your receipt say
well, because you've been in this situation,
no doubt where you get a charge on your
credit card and you're looking at and you're like,
what company is that?
Yes.
Like tech Savvy Internet goes by T si. Ok. That makes sense
when you say it. But
you know, my friend is looking at her credit cards
and
she's like, what the heck is T si,
you know,
I can't handle. T si, it's a three letter acronym.
I, I had many things that their,
their credit card merchant name is nothing like what they are
and
yeah. No, it'd be nice but
-- I
-- love it.
I get an email now every time I make
a credit card purchase that's processed outside of the,
it's processed from outside of Canada.
So some of that I expect like say Amazon,
but some of it when I'm buying from a Canadian company and then I get this alert email.
I'm like, where is that coming from over there? And
what is this, you know, the merchant name on it is just,
I mean, it's the same amount as I literally just 30 seconds ago, bought online.
But it's
like,
you know, if I had to reconcile these a month later,
I certainly wouldn't know who that is.
Oh, definitely. Yep. Yep. Absolutely.
Ok. Well, anyway, anyway, we should wrap this one up. So,
yeah, I guess. Good job mastercard.
That's,
that's all I'll say.
Yeah, I, I hope all the credit card companies do this.
Indeed. Indeed. Well, we probably only need one.
I, what isn't mastercard the most used card in the world?
I think I have no idea.
-- Might be. I thought Visa
-- was by transaction volume. The highest is it? It
might be.
I don't know, whatever my guess though.
Is, there are very few shops I've seen that don't take Mastercard.
I can't think of a single one.
So
I have a suspicion. This will,
this will catch on for everybody whether you want it or not. Which, why wouldn't you?
Oh, wow. Mastercard is
debit cards with the vi oh no, it's a visa is definitely bigger than Mastercard.
But the two of them are like 56% of the whole industry.
-- I thought they were more than that. I'm surprised at that
-- level. Globally.
You gotta remember. There's a lot of non visa, non Mastercard stuff,
smaller stuff in other countries or even in Canada.
Well, and then there's, the whole debit card is a blank thing and
-- all sorts of mix and match things.
-- Now,
that's fair. That's fair. All right, so cool. I'm,
I'm calling it, man. So thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to
omit
our Security podcast.com. Hit up the show notes.
You can use the Pound Os s podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media.
Yeah, Kurt have a great rest of your day.
-- You too,
-- everybody I guess,
don't forget to check your uh credit card statements for weird charges.
That's right.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the