Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 115
with myself Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
-- Hey, Kurt, and
-- we have a guest today. We have Brian Hajj Jost from Steel Cloud.
Say hello, Brian,
hello. So Brian Haj Jost, I'm the President CEO of Steel Cloud.
And what does Steel Cloud do?
Steel Cloud is a soft security software
company that builds technology around compliance specifically.
Uh the DSA
stig
and CIS controls. Uh D
A is the US federal government organization
that is charged with writing the,
the manuals for implementing um implementing
systems and security controls on systems.
Uh CIS is a not for profit out of upstate New York
that does basically the same thing,
but they involve um state and local governments uh commercial organizations and
other organizations throughout the world to build their security controls.
Ok, cool.
So this is,
this is one of those topics that I guess is kind of near and dear to my heart is because
I, I deal with this and the stig on a regular basis and I guess
why don't we start kind of at the very beginning and, and let's explain
the, the concept of kind of compliance in this us federal sector. Right.
Like, why, why do we have these rules and what does that mean?
And I guess we could, we should even give some of a history lesson because
they've evolved immensely over the years. Right.
Sure. There was somewhat of a war game that went on inside the federal government to
determine how computers, uh, this was probably 20 years ago,
how computers were set up and managed.
And from that, it came, you know, the basic requirement that there,
there needs to be some conformity
and that someone needed to take a charge to determine
how uh computer systems can be effective,
effectively implemented
and how they can be secured. So
um the security technical implementation guides or the
stig s uh grew out of that activity,
the dfso or the um
uh their security office was charged with
creating a set of rules basically
um to uh implement and maintain computer systems. And there are sts
for almost every piece of technology you can imagine from routers and switches.
There are sticks for copying machines, there's sts
for
significant applications
plus the cocoons in which applications live. So this would include things like,
you know, uh Red hat uh +56 and seven
windows server, uh all the workstation uh components, firewall browsers,
databases, iis Apache.
So almost all of the components you can imagine there's a stig for
and there's also on the CIS as a corresponding
a set of controls that have been developed by that organization that,
that pretty much parallel the stags,
right? You just said something that I'd never realized before.
The copy machines have stig.
That's crazy.
Well, they're computers now.
It, well,
well, if you can imagine, let me, uh, that's an interesting story. Um
You say, why would a copying machine have sts?
Well, most, you know, copy machines are printers
and you send a print job to a printer and it's, it's multiple people send them,
they get cashed on the hard drive.
So, um those get uh deleted uh once they're printed,
but think about why they're being stored,
there is a need for them to be encrypted. So in case a uh
um a repairman has to come in and replace that
hard drive when they walk out with the hard drive,
we wanna make sure that they don't walk out with any information that they can view.
And so,
and so the other thing is once um a file is deleted off that hard drive,
there's very specific
uh you know, triple wipe, industrial
um deletion of that file.
So those are, those are kind of the stig that come into play with, with a copy machine.
That's awesome.
Well, I would assume fax machines too.
Now, since it's all sort of the same organism, blob of printer and scanner.
Sure. And, and again that the,
any of these controls, either stig or cis basically look at the vulnerabilities,
look at how a bad actor uh might be able to take over the device and access the network
um or access data on that device.
So if, if you, you think about or imagine how these would
uh grow over time.
Um throughout both the federal government, the commercial organizations,
they look at vulnerabilities, things that they've experienced
in the recent past. they look at
their operating systems and the operating system components and say,
how could we manage these or how could we harden these
so that that particular thing would be hard to do
uh or, or we could prevent it all together.
And so there's a constant march toward looking at vulnerabilities,
looking at hacks
and determine if there are things within the operating system that
may be,
you know, fully reasonable for
uh you know, a gas station or someone's bookstore, but unreasonable for, you know,
a government computer or a large corporation that has sensitive data on it.
And so, um the stig themselves, they come out
um uh every 90 days, they are a new set of stig which correspond to something like um
10 or 20,000 individual controls.
Now, what, what do we mean when we say controls?
Because I have a feeling there's some of the audience
members who aren't quite familiar with some of this lingo.
Yes.
And,
and one of the things that exists and it
doesn't matter whether you're deeply embedded in the it,
uh,
organizations within the federal government or you're
a complete neophyte in this area,
there's a real fog around the stig and what they mean. So
a simple example would be minimum password length.
So minimum password is, it's in the federal government.
That's, um, I believe 15 characters now.
So you can have a password, a computer that is less than that password complexity.
Uh The most interesting ones I think that that uh most people can relate to are
there's over 1000 controls just in Microsoft Office across
Excel and Word
and basically those controls
uh control how Microsoft
Office operates,
they'll gray out menu selections that they're viewed as dangerous or could be
uh hacked or taken over.
So it's very detailed esoteric things down
to a very understandable things,
but there are literally on an operating system level somewhere, right?
Around 300 different controls for a
Microsoft operating system
on a ST a little more than that on CIS and, and
about the same for Red Hat.
So here's a random question because coming from the cloud space
has stig looked at sort of cloud providers yet
and started making maybe recommendations or adding controls.
So for example, like Amazon web services, right? They have like
good Lord several 100 services now,
you know, is there a stig for kind of graying out some of the more dangerous things or,
you know, maybe
people should try to avoid, you know, um like with the S3 buckets, you know,
now Amazon has a policy where you can,
you can set a global policy so that your
S3 buckets can't be made publicly available because apparently
people have been doing that, you know, banks and what not.
Well,
probably what I should try to and we're kind of getting deep in the weeds here.
When you look at compliance, it happens at multiple levels. So,
stig S and CIS flow under
uh nist uh 853 and 801 71 controls.
So you have higher level organization controls,
you have high level kind of network controls like how networks are administered,
locked rooms, um
um and other types of things. So when you look at uh Aws and Azure,
they have fed ramp controls.
So there's a whole set of federal us, federal controls that determine whether a
hypervisors and a cloud service
um, is uh protected. You know, one of the things that,
um fed
ramp calls for is that all of the endpoints,
all of the OS s the instances within the cloud
um are hardened to a recognized standard which generally is stig or CIS.
So it's kind of one paragraph and a very large, very large document.
So when you look at most of the cloud services,
um the cloud providers responsible
above a certain altitude. So
they're responsible for the network, they're responsible for the hypervisor.
They're responsible for the basic operation, the cloud,
but the customer is responsible for the hardening of actual
endpoints and that's not the responsibility of uh of,
of any of the cloud providers.
So,
um, we have worked extensively in the commercial cloud.
We, uh we, our product was used to harden the first
department of Defense application to get an authorization to operate,
meaning the
authorization to actually go live in the Amazon cloud and back in 2014.
So
that application assumed all of the controls
that existed within the AWS environment.
But each of the end points in that application had to be hardened to, to the sticks.
So hopefully that clarifies it a little bit.
So it'd be fair to say the stig basically apply to sort
of the actual hardware software that you're running on your end.
Yeah, it's actually the cocoon that the software lives in
and then there's again, other compliance controls that rise, you know,
above that as an umbrella over that.
But at the, at the Coalface,
uh ST
es are the
-- lowest level operating system controls that have to be implemented.
-- Nice.
No, that, that's perfect. I, I love the cocoon analogy
that I'm gonna steal that.
So.
Well, when you, when you,
yeah, when you think about it, that cocoon is made up of a whole bunch of components.
I mean, it could be antivirus, it could be
a browser is database and operating system,
all of those components probably have their own stig
and so to be compliant, each of the components within that cocoon
or that app stack,
uh have to be have to be hardened and, and literally,
you know, in many applications,
there's over 1000 controls that have to be individually done.
Now, now you mentioned there can be over 1000 controls and a long time ago,
a human literally sat down and verified
all those controls.
That's not quite how it, right?
That's not quite how it works anymore. Is it?
Well, uh actually tradition, when I say traditionally, that's how it's still done.
I mean, the
uh I believe there are estimates the the US federal government spends about $4
billion on stick hardening and the initial hardening is typically done by hand.
I say, why would that be
the issue with, with the controls?
And I'm, I'm gonna use, I use sticks a lot,
but it's synonymous with CIS too because of the, the,
the types of controls are almost exactly the same
sts
break applications
doesn't matter whether the application is custom built for the organization
or the app
or, or the application is a, is a large, um
you know, a large software company,
um their applications have not been developed
or tested in these hardened environments.
So when they get into a hard environment, they break
and every application breaks in a different way.
Um If you could just harden
to the stig book
an environment
and that was it, there would be no reason for our software because it would be
a cookie cutter operation where you just harden everything the same.
Unfortunately,
every application reacts differently and all the state controls
have to be hardened around an individual app stack.
So not just the application that's running, but the complexion of, of other support
systems that, that are on are on that app stack.
And so
the real issue starting what you have to do
is you have to be able to determine which controls have to be turned
off which ones have to be adjusted and which ones could be implemented,
then you have to waiver those controls or
provide documentation as to why we're not uh uh
enacting that control
manually. Which, which again is the, the vast predominance of how this is done
across the US federal government
um
that's done by hand
and for an APP stack,
it would normally take between two weeks and two
months to do that for every single application.
Um
with the average being around a month,
um that same work can be done using config Os in 60 minutes.
Um
The other benefit to using an automated tool to
do this hardening work is when you are done,
you have a secure signature that you can replicate
that work in 90 seconds anywhere in the world
versus doing it manually. When you are done, you have a pile of notes
that you have to write work instructions,
maybe you're going to develop custom scripts
or do something else with you aren't done.
So there, there may be another week's worth of work to do
just to take your output and put it
into some form that's useful for the organization.
Sure. OK. OK. So, so I guess I'm, I'm curious then
what uh how does XC CD F relate to all this and kind of to fill people in?
So the stig these days is transformed into an XML format called XC CD F
which then defines a lot of text but also rules
that can be kind of run against a system,
right, to kind of the check fix text to say that this, this is,
this is configured wrong or this is configured, right. Right.
Right. There's, there's two types of um
open standards for compliance testing.
Uh XC CD F is one of those and SAP is the other one.
Scap is a language that was defined by NIST.
Uh
and it's for
vulnerability scanning. The shortcoming of both
XC CD F and cap
is that neither one has any content for remediation
or neither one has any content for fixing.
So, whereas there are
um
a plethora of scanning technologies that exist in the Cyber world,
Steel Cloud in our config Os system, we are the fixers,
our value that we provide um
our customers, the fact that not only do we scan
but we fix things. So we have enhanced um
our content,
our security content to include all of the rules for detailed level fixing.
So I can press the button,
I can fix an app stack, all of the controls that need to be fixed.
Um I can skip all the controls that would break that app stack
and I can produce all the output from everything I just did.
So the the the real differentiation there is
um
you know, pure scanning that we're checking for things versus
remediation where I'm going in and I'm fixing the non compliances.
So just for our listeners to put something in perspective, so for example,
like SC or XC CD F can make a statement like
the password must be.
Well, like you said,
F is it 15 or more characters long now for the federal government?
Right? For the US, federal government.
And so for example, that sounds pretty simple, but then you have a Linux machine
and for example, how is it actually processing, you know, passwords?
Is it a local password file? Is it using LDA? Is it using?
Oh God forbid Nis or NS plus, hopefully, you know, and so there's,
there's different ways for the remediation to happen
depending on how that system is configured.
And
so I'm assuming that Steel Cloud is able to deal
with this to some degree or fully in some cases.
Yes.
And, and usually the compliance, you know, the base level compliance documents
species specifically what has to happen
and es especially scap is very sensitive to
um the order in which things happen. So you can have a compliance system.
But if you didn't do in the exact order that scap
is expecting
a will read, a compliance system is non
compliant.
So not only do we have to tune our content
to allow systems to, for us to remediate systems,
but we also have to do it in a way that any other tool
that the customer use might use to double check
or to validate that they will get the same results that we do.
Um But yes, in the, in the
uh in the
Linux
world
compliance is typically cracking configuration files
and doing very detailed editing,
starting and stopping Damon's loading and unloading software.
So that's kind of the
the job that uh if you look at bringing a system in compliance.
Those are the things that you have to be able to do
on the window side. Um a little different um because you have a registry.
So for many systems,
uh um the
the security controls are kept in registries. So it is
creating or updating registry entries,
but it's also local audit policy and local security policy.
Um
in databases, it's data specific database queries and updates
in things like uh IIS.
Um There are other configuration files as well as registry keys. So it's ver
it can get quite complex, especially
when you're doing remediation, which is why
um every other,
every other vendor has really shied away from fixing systems.
They just want to produce reports.
Sure. Sure. And, and I know, II I don't, I think it was maybe answerable scripts.
There was,
there was somebody I knew that had kind
of developed their own remediation scripts to like,
deploy an instance of Linux
that would be Sted. And every time they, they ran it, it, it broke the system
because
it did a bunch of crazy things. Like, like you're saying, you can,
anytime you have a deployment, you can turn on some things and,
and you can't others because it either doesn't make sense or it,
it breaks it for some bizarre reason, which, I mean,
that's kind of one of the challenges, right?
When you're dealing with this insane,
just list of controls, you have to figure out what matters and what doesn't.
Well, I mean, I don't know if anybody remembers, but even going,
like while going back a few years, we have, you know,
Se Linux and trying to craft se Linux policy that didn't, you know,
break your system horrifically,
uh going back even further, you know, firewalls, even state full firewalls,
you know, it's still very easy to break stuff and,
and before when we had stateless firewalls, like,
I don't know if anybody tries to remember
making passive FTP work through a stateless firewall,
but it essentially involved taking a sledgehammer to your rule set.
You know, it's, it's, uh the the
thing to make this, you have to start from kind of the right position
understanding that everything breaks, everything needs to be customized.
It has to be easy and simple.
If you start from that point and you develop software around that
you recognize.
So we have built in roll back anytime we update a system,
we build a synchronous rollback file.
So in one mouse click, I can roll everything back
because this process, when you look at the entire DEV
ops process,
you it is it is hunt and search break and fix. There are lots of processes along the way
that aren't really contemplated in,
I'm going to write a script
because the only way you can write a script
is if someone's already done the break and fix,
if somebody is already
uh defined at a very detailed level,
what needs to be done and all you're doing is translating into some language.
Well,
that's about 5% of the job.
You know, you, you have the 90% prior to that
and then these things change every 90 days. So then you have a sustainment issue.
As software applications are updated,
they may react differently with the security controls.
And as new sts
are released, they have to be tested and released
and all this has to be done easily
and quickly.
And
you know, most many of
the many of our customers are people that have tried writing scripts
or tried managing their own GPO s and they've just found that
the work is, um,
it is, it is
unsustainable
-- and, yeah.
-- No, I've run into this.
So, for example, if you take something quote unquote,
as simple as a PHP application like wordpress,
you can very easily write, you know, a security lockdown for it
and then you try and update it and it has to
do a bunch of new stuff that it didn't do before,
you know, so you fix that and then
you want to, you know, back it up
and then all of a sudden that's doing a whole bunch of new stuff. So
yeah,
that's something I think a lot of people forget is when
you write these sort of security policies to wrap around apps.
Uh ideally, you need to account for every action that app needs to do
to live.
And, you know,
obviously there's longer term things that are not
day to day like backups and updates.
Uh And I've, you know, I inevitably people seem to forget about that
you mentioned.
Uh Wordpress,
Wordpress was probably the hardest application that we had to harden around.
Um It took about 70 minutes as opposed to our normal 45 to 60 minutes.
Reason is there are three
uh contingent controls. You could set any two of the three
in the application would run, you set all three of them
and it would not run. And
so the, the job
I sorry
that makes
no sense.
-- So
-- the job is out of the 300 controls in the
operating environment to find those three controls and set them correctly.
And
without our application
that literally could have taken, you know, weeks or months
and it took 7 70 minutes.
Um,
as an aside, we, we,
we did the same thing for Webex for a federal integrator
and they wanted to see the hardening in front of them.
So we'd never done it before. We did webex in front of them. It took
45 minutes and there were six controls that had to be adjusted to allow Webex to, uh,
operate on a dod computer.
Ok. So can I ask when you say it took 45 minutes?
Do you mean it took your staff 45 minutes to write the rules or it takes 45
minutes kind of from the time you click like deploy or Harden or whatever until it's,
it's done?
No, the, the deploying harden takes about 30 or 45 seconds.
No,
the,
so it's building the profile.
You have to test, you have to, our application breaks the sticks down into pieces,
it applies and roll back the,
it rolls back the pieces
so you can find the pieces that are causing the application not to operate.
You adjust those you test and,
uh, basically that uh, 45 to 60 minutes allows you to step through every C
one C two and C
three, which are the,
the levels of severity with inside of the state controls
and determine which controls have to be adjusted.
Once you have that done, once you've spent that 45 or 60 minutes,
I can replicate that anywhere in the world in, uh,
30 to 90 seconds
because I have the rules built. Then I know what's waivered.
I've documented the waivers and the reason
so that I push the button,
nothing breaks and it sets up the machine exactly
what would be necessary to run that application.
Nice. That's really cool.
Good deal.
OK. OK.
II I like that. I, I keep thinking of, I've, I've written Stig before
and
it doesn't take 45 minutes,
you generally measure it in days or weeks in, in many cases just because it's,
it's a ton of work
to go through all of the rules. And I guess there's, there's one other thing that,
that we should probably clarify is
so I, I know we talked about kind of all, all these different sts
and if you stick a database to an operating system,
but really a lot of this builds on each other
also where you have to deploy the operating system,
you stig that,
then you deploy the application on top and you stig
that and if you have something on top of that,
even you might have to stick that.
And so it's not even just like one stig in some cases you
can be talking about dealing with three or four of these things.
Um, generally best practices would be that you get everything loaded and running
and then you stick around it.
Yes, you describe the traditional thing where the,
it department gives the organization,
here's the end product.
We want you to deliver a fully sticked image, load your application on it
and, and give it back to us.
Uh, the problem with that is, um, some applications won't even load.
So starting with something that's already pre hardened
that you have to tear it down
just to get it to load
and then you have to tear it down and build it up and test to get it to run
is, is, is counterproductive. Let me give you an example. We had a customer,
uh navy customer
uh that we had just, they just implemented our system
and they stood up a new app stack and it didn't work.
Um They got it loaded but it wouldn't work. And they said,
you know,
Steel Cloud told us this technique
and they called us up and we said yes, use the unstick signature.
So we have signatures specifically to
if your it department gives you a presti
image
to unstick the image
because again, you wanna get the software loaded,
you don't wanna be wrestling with drivers,
install programs and stig and not know where you're at.
So they unstick it, it still didn't work.
So it had nothing to do with the stig they
would have spent 2 to 3 weeks wrestling with the stig
when it wasn't that they reloaded. The endpoint security took them 10 minutes,
reapplied the stig everything's up and running. They're 20 minutes.
They were done. They would have spent weeks on that kind of thing. So,
best practices, get the software working, all the components, databases,
applications, all the other, get it working and then stig aro around it.
That is best practice.
And that's kind of the philosophy that we brought to the market.
Yeah,
I think that's something a lot of people forget is there's a lot
of software out there that doesn't actually easily work out of the box.
-- It's
-- like none.
Awesome. So, I, I think it's time to kind of wrap this one up. So
I'm gonna give you the last word Brian.
Do you have, do you have any parting thoughts for the, the audience?
Yeah, I, I do.
II,
I think a lot of the audience may look
at this and they're not in the federal government.
It hadn't been dictated by any of their industries.
And they said, well, this is kind of nice to have. And
how does, how does this affect us? Um
II, I think it's coming, I mean, we see it,
the FBI is enforcing compliance and stig on state and local governments.
We've seen the IRS do a flow down to state and local governments
and the state and local governments have done a flow down to tax preparers
that their environments get Sted up.
Um So whether it's from DH S,
whether it's the SEC, the banking regulators,
um The Nuclear Regulatory Commission,
I think all of the major infrastructure in America eventually gonna be failed are,
are going to be uh required to comply with standards
and also public companies. It could be, the SEC comes out and says that uh
um if you are, um
if you're going to be on these exchanges that you have to like they did with,
with Sarbanes Oxley, that you have to be compliant.
So, uh it is coming uh Steel Cloud, certainly preparing for it. And um,
we're gonna be ready when our, when our customers, future customers need it.
Um Thanks so much today.
Ok, cool, fantastic. So, I guess thank you, everyone. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you, Brian.
It, it has been a fantastic conversation. I really appreciate it.
We'll have to have you back someday to
talk about the new and exciting
things happening.
So I guess if, if anyone wants to show notes,
you can go to open source security podcast.com
where you can hit up links to.
We have links to some of the things Brian talked about as well as kind of
some of the information on the stig you can use the Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag to hit us up on social media
-- and you two have fantastic rest of your days.
-- Ok. Thanks so much. Bye now. Thanks.