Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime, Josh Pressers
-- and I miss that crime.
-- I, I think it's time for us to embrace real,
probably white collar crime. I feel like that's more our thing.
-- I don't think you and I would do very well at real crime.
-- Although
now I think you are implicating yourself where if I do legitimately commit crime,
then
there is going to be countless hours of evidence of you claiming
-- to be my associate in said crimes
-- or it's a double bluff.
Kurt's
who would,
who would be exactly five D just who would be stupid enough to claim this in advance?
Have you read
any police report ever?
Oh, my God. I love
honestly, my favorite isn't police reports.
It's watching the border shows where these people come to the
border and basically they try lying to the border agent.
And, you know,
it always reminds me of is car salesman where the car salesman sells a car,
like three times a day and people coming in to buy a car, buy a car,
like once every five years, you're going to lose.
Right.
The border agent has seen and heard your story and every single variation of it
seven times this week already.
Yeah. Exactly. And I love when the stories get real complicated though.
This one guy who's coming to America, but he's not visiting family,
but the guy is his father in law or his godfather, but it's not his godfather.
They're going to be adopting him,
but he's not their son yet and they're not adopted yet
and he's going to be staying with them for three months,
but he's not going to be working and he doesn't have a lot of
money and it's going to be fine because he's also going to travel.
And of course, you know, the agent's just like, yeah,
his story doesn't really hold together, right?
And I feel bad for the guy but
-- like, oh man, just some of these people, you know,
-- my,
my favorite example of that is I have a friend who is a police officer and he said
when you pull someone over and ask if they've
been drinking and they say they've had two.
-- It's always
-- two beers. It's two.
-- You know, anyone who says two needs to be out of the car.
-- I kept a count.
I was watching, we were watching,
you're under arrest and cops and a couple others and I kept a tally
and it was literally always two beers with the one exception of one guy said one beer,
several people of course, said I haven't been drinking at all. And the cops, like,
but that I can smell it on your breath,
right. You know,
and then of course there was the one guy who's like, yeah,
I've been drinking all day and the cops, like, what?
And the guy was honest with the cop and the cops, like,
I'm still gonna have to bring you in for driving under the influence.
I was like, thank you for being honest.
So, you know, funny enough,
this ties into the discussion we want to have today of the fact that there are
when you do something only every now and then
it feels different.
And I think even worse, this ties into the law of large numbers because there's like,
doing something once a week or once a day.
But when you do something
seven times a day and you practice and get good at it and optimize it. Like,
I once actually arranged with a butcher to go butcher chickens with him.
And unfortunately the deal fell through.
But because I wanted to learn how to properly butcher
a chicken and the reality is to do that,
I'm gonna have to carve up like a couple of 100 chickens.
I, I can't afford to do that at home
or eat chicken every day for the, you know, next few years.
Right.
I mean, I love chicken but, you know, a little variety but, you know,
that's the point.
Right. Like this guy, you know, the butcher shop I go to,
they can carve meat better than I ever will because they do it for eight hours a day.
-- Right. Right. It's like any
-- skill. Like, it's a family butcher shop. Right.
They've all been doing it since they were 16.
-- Yeah,
-- exactly. Man.
Exactly. And same thing with, like, security stuff. Right.
You and me. How many vulnerabilities have we read?
-- More than 10,000?
-- How many, how many today?
Yeah.
You know, I once did the math and I at the two companies I worked previous to Red Hat,
I think I handle something like 30,000 vulnerabilities
-- over a period of like seven or eight years.
-- I believe that once you spread it out,
what's a couple a day?
Yeah.
Anyway, anyway, OK. So let's explain.
There are two news stories that kind of piqued our interest
and
I will let you explain them.
-- How about,
-- well,
so the first one is the ever classic targeting developers
with your sort of not quite mission impossible style attacks,
but more like a spearfishing a developer so that you can like inject some code
either into the repo directly or the more likely scenario.
A dependency of a dependency of a dependency.
You know, you go down the chain and you get that,
that famous XKCD comic from a few weeks ago where you know,
the whole internet rests on like some random library written
by a guy in Arkansas in his spare time.
Like, I remember working a XML hash do
bug. And the guy
was, like, I have a free weekend in, like, five weeks to fix this.
I can't do it before then. I'm busy.
I have a life, I have kids and we're like, ok, we,
we're actually going to do it for you because we need this sooner than in five weeks.
There's a ton of these things, you know, there, well,
there's infamous cases where people have essentially
hijacked
libraries online using either, you know, social engineering or just outright,
you know, some sort of process to, to hijack it, you know,
account retrieval type deal and then, you know,
inject like a a what was it Cryptocurrency, wallet theft software, blah, blah,
blah.
-- I,
-- I want to set the table here and I don't think
worrying about this, like if this keeps you up at night,
you have very broken priorities is how I would describe this.
Yes and no, there's a few people who do need to worry about it,
but there's a really easy solution.
And I know, for example, Google did this where
Google has a bunch of software.
They open source software that they really,
really rely upon in various ecosystems.
And so they just pull a copy of all of it into their own servers,
like their own source code servers and manage
it themselves and they manage what comes in.
And so to put it bluntly, they've reinvented Red Hat.
Right. And, and
-- not everyone can do that.
-- Yeah.
And that's not bad either because Google's like, well,
we need the software to do XY and Z, we don't need the latest hotness.
We just need it to work reliably and have all the security patches.
And Google is at a scale where they can do that, you know?
Ok, we're gonna have 10 or 50 people do this. Cool. Like who signs the check?
Let's explain the second half of this story, which is the the other
news story.
And ironically, they're both from the register which like was not on purpose,
but I love it.
Well, they are a good news source. The reality is I would say,
and I'm just making up numbers here
probably between half
and 80 to 90% of all security flaws.
And I, when I say security flaws, I mean, not like the big important ones.
I mean, like all security flaws
basically
can either be handled publicly
and are or accidentally sort of
become public because, you know,
literally a developer commits the code patch before the issue is public, but it's,
you know, looks innocuous and it's nobody pays attention to it or in some cases,
I've seen them commit a code patch that literally says like fixed buffer overflow,
you know, a week before the official thing goes out.
And quite frankly, like
it really doesn't matter that much. It's
Attackers
in theory,
they could be monitoring this and use this as a
supply of security flaws that haven't been patched yet.
But generally speaking,
most Attackers are using security flaws that are well known for months.
Right.
Right. Right. Ok. So the second half of this, which your description
I feel like is more vague than I like. So I'm going to, I'm going to fix it, right.
I'll patch it.
So, back in the day, millions of years ago,
there was
the concept of a security embargo where a project, for example,
would have a patch ready to go when something went public,
the patch got committed into the public repo and everyone was happy
these days. Everyone's using github, github. Basically.
I don't think they have private issues still.
They do not.
-- Yeah. Remember they added it, we talked to the guy.
-- Oh, that's right. That's right.
Ok. That's right. That's right.
That's for, well, it's different though because that's for security things.
It's, yeah.
And, and to be fair, like, that's relatively in the last 12 months or less.
And for, especially for me and Josh, that it breaks our worldview a bit.
But in a good way,
-- this
-- is what month, 37 of this year. So
anyway, anyway,
so basically,
what happened is these researchers realized you could basically mine
github
-- and, and get like, the Linux kernel is their example. That
-- used to be my job.
Like when I worked for very security firms, when everyone knew it.
Like literally, when we worked for very security.
Uh when I worked for various security firms, at least, you know,
we would monitor all the public sources.
We basically had a thing that sucked in change logs and looked for the word
security in other terms.
And we were starting to look at, you know,
like actually looking at commit streams and
there's certain projects that when a certain
person commits a code that's a security fix nine times out of 10.
And my favorite always, for example,
is like internet software consortium did this all the time where they
do a bind or a DH P release with a security fix,
but they don't clearly label which part of the code it
was and they would do a bunch of other fixes.
So you'd end up with like a one or 200 kilobyte patch file.
And on average, it took me something like five minutes
to find the security patch.
And like, I, I wouldn't even call myself a programmer, but, you know,
you learn to read patches.
And so like five minutes later, I'd be like, oh OK,
it's this function doing this thing and
you know, based on the description, it's like, yeah,
if you can force a recursive query to a server, it'll do this look up and it'll,
you know, eat a reply.
That's way too big and blah, blah, blah, blah, blah. Right.
And so, you know, I
was trying to obfuscate this and trying to, you know, release the patch, but without
details.
And yeah, like literally half an hour later,
I'd have written up my report and we'd have released it to customers.
And now the, I think the most interesting example of this is,
I think it might have been meltdown or one of those CPU type bugs
where the patches went into the Linux kernel like months before it was known.
See, here's the thing. Now we start talking about culture
and world view. So there's people that view the world
in security terms of, you know,
security is special and it needs to be handled differently and embargo and blah,
-- blah, blah, blah,
-- we are not those people.
Well,
I would say part of me still is because I
can see that there are corner cases where that's suitable,
but they are very, very limited, like three times a year limited
across the globe.
But then there's the more sort of and,
and that camp also speaks to sort of the red
hat style of corporate and industrial software user where it's like
I want to install software on this thing and make this thing work,
but like basically never have to run the risk of doing
something to it that breaks it because it's an oil refinery,
you know, and you don't want to break those things, they're expensive.
And then there's the second camp which is
more developer driven and focused where they're like,
just run the latest greatest,
which, you know, if you're running something on your laptop and playing games,
cool.
You know, if it, if it breaks you just fix it.
And so a great example of that camp would be like the
open BS D group or project story and the Linux kernel group,
right?
The Linux kernel group is like, security isn't special.
They're just bugs, we fix them, we move on, you run current or else, Well, you don't
-- too bad for you. Well,
-- you pay someone to, to care and feed it.
I mean, this is kind of, that was Red Hat's whole thing basically.
And there's people that want that. I mean, we do this all the time in life.
-- It took me like 20 years to accept Peck's plumbing. What
-- that stuff's awesome, man.
Well, now that I've used it, yeah, I would agree because basically it, oh,
so I just cut the pipe, jam, a shark bite, fitting on it.
And I just basically play like, you know,
keep your toys with my plumbing and just jam them together.
Oh, well, like, and I don't have to like solder upside down.
Oh,
yeah. No, this is a no brainer.
Well, and, and so actually what, what got me into pecs
is so
back in
man, this would have been like, 06 or eight ish give or take.
The cost of copper had become
obscenely expensive.
And now Peck was relatively new in the area. I was in
and buying a crimper. I remember the crimper was, like, $300 back when I bought it.
But the thing is I did all the math and the
cost of the copper for the project I was working on
was going to be about $600. Whereas the crimper, plus the, the crimper was 300
like, everything else I needed was maybe 20 bucks.
Well, that's what gets me.
Yeah, the crimper is still like, yeah, 100 bucks it'll last forever.
As long as you don't like soak it in salt water
is like, so rusted now because it's so old, but it's still fine. It doesn't matter.
But anyway, anyway,
the point is it was one of those situations where I could buy $600 worth of copper
and the time,
-- the time of like, soldering a joint.
-- Yes,
I didn't understand that.
And so I sent my wife and kids away for the
weekend while I was basically doing a bunch of plumbing,
work on this bathroom.
We were getting remodeled
and I was like, go away for the weekend.
I, I, I'll hopefully be done when you get back. And anyway, my wife goes away.
-- It took
-- about 20 minutes, right?
It took about 20 minutes. Yes.
What gets me too is like, you gotta cut the pipe. You're just like,
like, literally that's how long it takes to cut pecks.
Whereas cutting copper properly, you got to cut it and then you got to score it out,
you got to do the ends.
Like, it's five or 10 minutes
-- for
-- joint,
right?
And it was funny because my wife calls me and says how
plumbing going. I said, oh, I'm done.
And this is like, you know, like noon on Saturday
and she says, oh, ha ha, like, really? How's it all this going?
I'm like, no, I'm completely serious. I am 100% done with this project.
Like, you can come home whenever you want.
Well, I have to replace both my outside water taps because they're like 40 years old.
And if I do it with copper, it's going to take easily about 4 to 6 hours each one.
And if I do it with, you know, replacing it with packs, it's going to take about,
you know, 15 minutes anyway.
Anyway, we are,
this is not a plumbing podcast.
Well, but the point is so, so there's, there's new and better ways
and so,
yeah, not everybody can, can stay current, you know, you're,
you're using the Linux kernel for automotive
software support.
Well, you can't just be like, hey, we're going to ship you a new kernel every day
and hope that it works.
I mean, and in theory, you could, but you'd have to have a really crazy C ID build,
process, testing, process,
whatever and that's just not going to happen basically.
What it always comes down to really is people grossly
overestimate the value of the majority of security flaws.
I would agree with that
because when you look at what security flaws are actually being used,
it's not these ones.
Let's explain that statement because I bet you there
are more than one listener who is like,
what?
-- Now it
-- kind of reminds me of when people start theoretically going over, like,
for example, the use cases of drones and terrorism and people are like, oh my God,
you shouldn't give people ideas.
And it's like you seriously haven't had the thought of like strap a hand
grenade to a drone and fly it somewhere and drop the hand grenade.
Like if you think a terrorist can't come up with
that on their own after it's been in the news,
like
that's how the Russians blew up, that Ukrainian ammo dump with one hand grenade.
-- I'm sorry. But this is not rocket science,
-- right? Ok.
So here I want to, I want to tie all this together now. Ok.
So security people have a notorious history of
talking about how the world is going to end
doom and gloom and it never does, right. It just doesn't because
-- we, we always overestimate. I
-- think we just keep rescheduling it for next Thursday.
That's right. It, it feels like it's getting closer
anyway. We always overestimate the importance of this stuff.
But I think part of the challenge is we are
buried in these issues in ways normal people aren't.
And So we don't,
we rarely have the big picture view even though we like to think we do.
So there's obviously the security people are always doing this.
There is the fact that when you look at Attackers,
I think that the way we think
about Attackers is evolving substantially where historically,
I think it was just
a lot of pranks. Right. It was like kids with too much free time.
-- Well, there wasn't
-- really, it was really hard to monetize a lot of these attacks.
Yes, exactly.
-- That
-- has changed. Oh, boy. Has it ever?
Well, you've got, like, bug bounties now, right.
Oh, I meant more like, you know, crypto mining on people's hardware.
Well, ok, there's, there's that angle too, but I don't like,
so that was a really big deal for a while.
I don't even see that. Like I used to.
Yeah, because it's horribly inefficient and it's
way more efficient to just steal people's crypto from their wallets.
And so it's a vault.
-- And
-- so here's, here's part of the story though is we are building a market where
you're going to make more money being a legit
security researcher than you are being a criminal.
Generally speaking, I look at what I earned versus what I've read.
The Underground earns and unless we do some really crazy pons,
there was a recent Blockchain related crypto scam
2.5 million. And I'm like, that's it.
Like, that's all these guys manage to pull off with a Ponzi scheme.
-- That's actually not good and
-- that's not normal, right.
That's the Black Swan of the, of the, the, the scammers.
So, anyway,
I have no doubt that you would make way more money
and here's the thing like to do this kind of work,
you gotta be smart and you're going to be smart enough to say Holy Carol, this isn't a,
you know, I'm gonna,
I'm gonna do way better just doing a bug bunny over here than I am trying to, you know,
scam old people out of Bitcoin or something.
And, and so now we, we look at our environment, right?
And you've got the state level actors who in all seriousness,
they are unstoppable because they have like the best example is there's this,
this blog post that's basically
when you look at the tax,
there's Mossad and not Mossad is the way this guy breaks it down.
And like he talks about the fact that like if Mossad wants your, your stuff, they'll,
they'll like, you know,
put uranium in your phone and have you die of brain cancer and then buy your estate,
-- you know, in 20 years or
-- even simpler.
Like, you know, I always tell people at the, the CS A,
if somebody snatches you and threatens to beat your knees in for your crypto keys,
you give them their cry,
your crypto keys,
-- your knees can't be fixed, man, especially past the age of 40
-- right?
But anyway, anyway, so, so the point is I feel like we, we try to frame security
in a world that doesn't exist.
-- And I think it is not particularly useful.
-- Has there ever been a research
or a study looking at actual
which vulnerabilities are being used,
are being used for what and how and what the
outcomes were when I looked at the crypto stuff,
for example,
you know what the number one attack in crypto
is for actually getting money phishing sim swap.
So I basically hijack your phone number and then
I reset your account and I take your money.
That's it.
-- Yeah,
-- that's why don't,
don't use your cell phone as your second factor for your crypto account,
but don't use a phone number, right?
-- And, and that's it. It's just that
-- simple. That doesn't shock me in any way yet.
How many,
how many people are taking down is the
most serious threat to the Cryptocurrency universe,
right?
Probably not many.
Well,
it's funny actually because some are like Coinbase now has a thing where it actually
warns you if you choose S MS two fa it says this is moderate,
it's ok,
but stronger is using a software two fa and even best is a hardware two fa like a token,
like a UB or whatever.
And I'm like, it's nice.
Yeah, they do a good job because I have a Coinbase account.
That's where I sold my $50 worth of Cryptocurrency.
Way back when I was looking to see, like, can I turn Bitcoin into money?
And I did and then I paid my taxes on it and nobody audited me.
Thank goodness, you're on a list now for, you know, 10 years from now.
Well, no, honestly,
my taxes are super boring and I purposely make sure I'm
not like trying to mess with the system just because like,
the cost of the audit is going to vastly outweigh like
the 100 bucks I might scam out of the government.
-- So I'm
-- like, well, and that's a perfect example, right?
All these people trying to do, you know, financial scams and outside of, again,
like good
honest white collar crime
when you try and scam the tax authority for money, like they're going to win
eventually and right,
because they have infinite time and how much am I actually going to get by,
by lying about my deductions?
100 bucks? That's not worth it.
I used to get like GST rebates because I, you know,
primarily contract for American firms.
And so I get, you know,
between one and $2000 a year back from the government. And of course, they audited me
and it came out to within two cents of what my account said. It shouldn't.
They cut me a check the next week, I
guess what it boils down to most people vastly overestimate the competency.
And I think they also overestimate the reward
like people seem to think robbing a bank,
you're going to get, like,
you know, a giant bag with a million dollars.
Oh,
no.
Like the average bank robbery, I think in Alberta at one point was like,
-- between two and $3000
-- and you can't spend any of
the money because it's all marked up the wazoo.
-- I mean, as soon as you spend it, they're going to
-- find
you.
I mean,
we talked about that one where the guy actually did rob a bank and got away
on a bicycle and which I thought was kind of awesome because I never heard that.
Yeah, but still two grand.
Yeah, exactly.
Well, and now there's, you know,
that there's that security footage and all that stuff out there for.
Right.
Go to get a job, like,
anyway,
ok, we've explained, we think that there's obviously
a certain amount of, I guess, unnecessary alarm here.
-- And so, like, let's, let's frame this.
-- It's fun.
It's way more fun than the real stuff because the real stuff is boring.
Yeah. Yes, I'm getting to that.
So let's frame that conversation in the context of say, watching the Linux
public G
repo for fixes that don't follow the standard procedure and saying
this is probably a security fix and it probably is,
does that
gain any substantial benefit to the universe
if you can do that? And my argument is that
-- probably
-- not substantial. No, it's one of those 5 10% things.
But the thing is if you are a mossad, then you don't care,
you just pay for that 5 10% advantage.
They don't need a Linux kernel vulnerability either. They could.
There's a million other things they can do to attack. I would view it as
they will add this their toolbox, but they don't technically need. It.
Always got me is of all the pen testers.
I know and I know quite a few, not a single one of them has ever really failed.
They never fail because so this is one of the easiest examples I give in this space.
And this was,
I actually learned this talking to a lawyer a long time
ago about some Microsoft shenanigans around the open document foundation.
But fundamentally
when you are the red team,
the red team only has to succeed once they can try a million times,
they have to succeed once.
Well, and they get to pick the playing field, they get to pick the timing, right.
-- They have no rules.
-- Exactly. Well, they get to pick the game.
Well, it's Kelvin ball for them, right.
When you're the blue team,
you have to win every time and you have to follow the rules.
Like by definition, you will lose 100%.
Well, this is what always gets me about the whole hack back thing where I'm like,
um,
no.
Yeah.
First of all,
you're just going to be attacking some poor schlub who's being used as a bounce,
like a grandma
in Nevada
or
my first thought was when I,
when I saw that seriously mentioned in the US politics like years ago, I was like,
wait, you know, what I'm going to do is Russia, I'm going to like,
hack a bunch of Chinese servers from America
and hack a bunch of American servers from China
and like, just get them hacking each other.
And then at that point, how do you know it's like the hackers or the hack backing?
And how do you, how do you deescalated? Right. And that's the thing.
-- There was no talk of deescalating ever given.
-- There's a simple solution to this.
Kurt,
we'll pass a law that says it's illegal
for Russians to use American computers to hack China
-- problem
-- solved.
So,
there we
go. Right.
No, you absolutely right.
This is the same story here where we're talking about,
let's attack the supply chain, let's watch github.
Let's, let's do all of these activities in all seriousness.
I think outside of like the bizarre world of like security academia and research,
I'm going to say these don't like, this just isn't practical to focus on this.
And if this is your focus,
-- you are wasting opportunity all over the place.
-- It has happened a few times, but
there's just not been a big deal.
I mean, and even things like specter and meltdown I've never seen
or heard of an actual major incident stemming from it,
my guess is they're all Massad type events where we'll never hear about
-- them because it's like special ops type stuff
-- and the people that are actually
really affected by it are just like, ok, well, this sucks,
but we'll pay to use our own computer, like a dedicated post.
-- Right. If you, if you actually care, but most people probably don't care.
-- Yeah.
-- And not do multi-tenant. Right. Right.
-- Exactly.
And, and the thing that always kills me is so
I will know people that obsess over things like, oh,
we've got to worry about our open source
dependencies because someone might attack a third level dependency
and they might put a back door in our software and they might do this and that,
and it's like, but your freaking servers haven't been updated in two years, like,
what the heck is wrong with you?
I mean, I remember there, there was actually,
there was a person I was dealing with that was basically doing this of, of they were,
I would call them
plot threats and the container images they were running literally
had not received a security update in five years.
And I'm like,
holy crap. This is bananas.
-- Well, it's, but the thing is doing the real work is hard
-- and it's not fun.
Right.
Like I would say if you can't update a service or a software product in,
depending on the size and complexity of it, you know,
like something like windows 10 cut Microsoft, you know, they get more than a week
but in an emergency,
but basically what it boils down to is if you can't fix something in, say,
between one and three weeks and I don't count
like heroic effort 24 hour days for a week.
I mean, it has to be just sort of a normal business level of activity, not, you know,
the end of the world activity.
If you can't do that, that reliably,
then you got way bigger problems than worrying about security.
Yeah, exactly. Exactly. And
I guess part of that is that the industry is maturing.
-- Well, it
-- reminds me of cars, you know, like the way we do car recalls and stuff. Now,
I remember the first big, uh, Michelin tire recall.
It was,
you remember those suvs that would roll over and the tire would pop and all that
and, you know, and I remember the, the,
the news would put on like two affected tires and two non affected
tires on a car and then take it to a variety of shops
and, you know, they'd be told anywhere from, like,
all the tires good to all the tires are bad to like,
these two tires are bad and these two tires are good and it was completely wrong.
And, you know,
and as a result we got RF ID tags and tires now so that
we can actually track our supply chain and say this tire is good.
Or bad or it was actually made by this company on this date.
-- And,
-- and I mean, that's a boring supply chain issue.
-- Putting a serial number
-- on
-- stuff.
-- Security should be accounting.
I'm going to, I'm going to keep saying that that's like my new thing.
-- We
-- had that thing with red onions that have, I want to say salmonella or something.
We don't know how it happened, but
they're like, just basically don't eat red onions.
And I'm like, well, which ones and they're like these brands. And I'm like,
for example,
I bought a Greek salad from Costco and ate it the other week that had red onions in it.
Like, uh,
I seem to be ok,
whatever, you're young enough to make it through salad,
-- it's fine.
-- I've read about it and it sounds horrific. It does.
-- I've never had it, but I don't want it for sure. But
-- that's the thing, right?
Like, just simple stuff, like knowing what your, your supply chain is.
Step one and then, you know, being able to actually execute on updating it
once you can do that, then
worrying about security
makes sense because you can do something about it.
Otherwise you're just, it's like me worrying about somebody ram raiding my house,
like, with our car. It's like,
what am I gonna do? Put up
-- boards and block off the driveway? You could,
-- but that would be stupid.
I mean, really?
And, and so, ok, ok, so we're running out of time. But I wanna,
I wanna bring this all home. I'm gonna say if you're a researcher working on this
good,
right? This is important research and this is important stuff.
However, one of the challenges becomes
obviously part of doing research is you want recognition for what you do.
And so the hard part is how do we have
research being done on what is essentially a scary problem
that doesn't end up sensationalized or misrepresented.
And I don't, I don't know the answer to that.
I'd say that's not possible
and maybe there isn't, I think human nature just computer says no.
Well, and it's like you said about, you know, putting,
using a drone to attack things is
there's people doing research on that. There's people trying to understand it.
There's videos of a guy who's hooked up a handgun to his drone and
I was like, I checked and it's like, no, the FAA that's really illegal. Is it?
I don't know. Yeah, it's super illegal in the US. And, well, most of the world.
But anyway, anyway, and I guess this is,
this is part of the challenge is, is there,
there is very interesting and amazing security research to do.
There's going to be phenomenal things to discover.
But we also have to make sure we keep everything in context
and we don't just scare people for the sake of scaring them.
And how do we do that? I have no idea.
Yeah, because I do see research into stuff where it's like, cool.
Is there anything actionable we can actually do about that?
-- And that's a good point too. You know,
-- it's like
the whole meteorites hitting the earth thing.
I, I, part of me is like,
we should spend more money monitoring for meteorites that might hit the earth.
But part of me is like, but why we can't do anything about it, like,
-- we can't redirect them
-- space force.
Yo.
Oh wait, they don't do anything. Um But anyway,
I'm not really clear on them either. Yeah,
but you know what I'm saying?
Like part of me is like, yeah, we should,
we should have more monitoring of meteorites.
I might smack into the earth and cause problems. But
again, like, what are we going? Do you guys have some secret armored space shuttle?
We don't know about that. That
would be
-- to nuke on it. I feel like the answer is
-- no.
Also I'm going to apologize in advance for everyone listening.
Who's a space nerd and carts misuse of the word meteorite.
-- So,
-- oh shoot, you're right. I apologize
for
asteroids.
-- Well, no, wait, wouldn't. Which
-- meteorites hit the ground, right?
Meteors are flying through the air. Meteorites hit the ground.
Asteroids are in space.
I was technically correct because we worry about the ones that hit
by the
when they are meteorites. We're all dead. So we don't care.
We care about asteroids. Those we might be able to do something about.
I feel like spacex
doesn't have some plan for that yet. Maybe give them 20 years.
-- This
-- might be a good thing.
I'm going to think about this a little bit
because I think you might be onto something.
But at the same time, let's say we knew an asteroid was coming.
I have an answer and that is,
it's good to know sort of the logarithmic scale of a problem.
Is this a once a year thing or 10 times
-- thing or 10 times a day thing or once a century thing? Every
-- 30 million years?
So, and that's what I, you know, with a lot of these security flaws, I'm like, well,
how
bad and how often do these actually happen?
Like I want to get a sense of,
I don't need specific numbers but at least an order of magnitude.
So I can say it's, is it like a 10 or 100 or 1000 problem?
Yeah, because how we handle that, if it's a 10 problem,
we can just handle them one off.
But if it's 1000 or a 10,000 problem,
then we probably need some automated tooling to handle it
and we should invest some time and money in making it go away.
Yeah, I agree with that too.
Alright. Alright, I'm calling this,
this is and I need to think about this
aid thing. I like it. I like it anyway. All right. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. Go to open source security podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes. Yz Pound says podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too, thanks everybody.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye bye.