Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 95 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser
and the world continues to burn.
Right.
Pretty much. Which story should we talk about first?
-- How
-- about the simple one
that, that's not helpful?
Is
-- it Twitter,
-- Twitter,
Twitter, Twitter.
So, your, your Twitter password is in log file somewhere, apparently.
Yes. And I
changed it, which
was nice and easy because I use a password manager.
Right. I, I don't know what it was. I don't know what it is now,
one of the, one of the interesting things. So I changed it right away. Right.
And then maybe a couple of hours later, the Twitter app on my phone, like,
basically said, go change your password.
And I thought, oh, that's interesting.
They,
they're not paying attention if you change your
passwords when they send out this notice.
So they just, like, probably blanketed
the world.
Um, I, I didn't change my password immediately because it's, well,
it's a single use password
and I think I have some of the two of a stuff enabled.
Right.
So, but yeah, I got that big honking notice saying, like,
go change your password and I'm like, ok, whatever.
Yeah. Do it. And of course,
now I'll, I'll give them
11 of the cool things that password notice said was, oh, and while you're at it,
double check the linked
applications.
-- Yes, that I appreciated. Yeah,
-- that
-- was
-- awesome.
And I took a look and there were a couple of
things I had listed that I'd forgotten about and weren't,
I wasn't using them anymore, so I took them off.
So, I mean, that was, that was cool.
Yeah, I do a periodic review of my Google account for that because obviously,
you know, once in a while I'll want to generate a PDF or read a PDF or, you know,
do something like that and it's like this application wants to like,
and I get it that it needs to, like,
touch everything on your drive because that's how the security model works.
But it really,
so, you know, in that case I'll try typically, what I'll do is I'll,
I'll give it access for like an hour and then take it away
if it's really amazing.
But in general,
-- I've stopped that because so many of these apps just need way too much
-- access a lot,
right?
We must be able to send emails you
-- to edit a
-- PDF.
My favorite was, yeah, the,
the ones on Twitter that want to be able to send tweets as me or,
or the linkedin ones that,
like just want all the access to my linkedin
account and to scrape like everybody else's account.
It's like, no,
seriously, man.
Although, although I, I found there's a PDF,
uh I use it to highlight PDF S because uh so my, my son is a swimmer
and in the swim meets, there's like hundreds of events
and I don't like to print off like 700 pages of crap to carry around.
So I take the PDF and I highlight his particular events
so I can easily just scroll around and find them.
And there's an app on Google, I forget the name of it.
That,
that does this where I can take the PDF and then highlight it and then it re
saves it and actually the permissions only give it
permission to files I open with that app,
which is like, that's awesome.
Like that's totally the way it should work.
But anyway, anyway, so back to Twitter and, and here's, here's my,
my quick thoughts on this is there are some people, not a lot, actually,
people are pretty good, but there are some people that are, you know,
complaining about Twitter.
-- Of
-- course, there are, there's people complain about everything.
That's true. That's true.
But here's the thing,
I'm pretty sure Twitter didn't have to tell
us this because this isn't really an incident
depending upon how you define it. But I mean, it was under their control.
They don't believe these have been lost.
-- And so
-- what's interesting is there,
there may have been an incident and they may not be telling
us or they may not know because one thing I'm curious is,
do they?
So, for people that don't know exactly what happened or maybe don't use Twitter,
Twitter accidentally logged passwords in clear text to an internal log file.
Ok. That's a bad,
apparently 300 million of them.
So I'm assuming it's like,
yeah, basically everybody, yeah, everybody who used Twitter and like, oh,
the last forever.
Anyways.
Now, my, my concern would be like, what the permissions and access to this log file?
How, how is that constrained?
Now, obviously,
a log file of this size is not just some text file sitting on a file system, I'm,
I'm guessing.
So I'm guessing it's in some back end kind of storage thing which may or may
not have strong access controls and strong logging
plus then replication of that system plus,
then,
you know what underlying systems is this thing sitting
on that other people manage plus backups plus,
you know, just empty gazillion
chains of, you know, where this stuff ends up, right?
Because that's just how data is,
right?
And it sounds like it was going on for a while because, I mean, if it's everybody,
if it's 300 million affected people, that's, that's a lot of passwords,
you know, that's a lot of activity over, over some time.
Right?
And now I'm,
I just pulled up the blog post here and it does say we have no
reason to believe the password information ever left
Twitter systems or was misused by anyone.
So I, that that's a pretty concrete statement.
I think along the lines of this was not,
-- it, it would, it wouldn't qualify as an incident by most standard definitions
-- of an
incident, not an external incident.
Right? And, and generally speaking, it is all about kind of the external incidents
that people are expected to report on. So I think Twitter doing this,
it's a very difficult decision but I applaud them
for, for what I would say is doing the right thing
and I'm hopeful that many other organizations will follow suit in the future.
Yeah. And, um,
no, II, I am happy that they reported this. It, it,
the problem is I'm paranoid enough to not completely trust them and be like, oh,
they reported this, they must be doing fine,
you know.
Um, but I mean,
the good news is now external incidents do tend to
end up in the news pretty quick because they're,
they're quite
-- obvious
-- because Brian Krebs posted
all
of
that.
Yeah, exactly.
My one piece of, uh,
sort of frustration though is that they're
not pushing two factor authentication more.
Right.
And I mean, because really there's, there's two answers to the password problem.
Number one is password managers,
right?
Because the reality is there's so many systems that
will just only ever have passwords and not two fa
and, and also one thing to keep in mind too is
there are some cases where I'm not a big fan of two fa because, you know,
maybe I don't want to have to schlep my phone around
with me all the time or rely on that phone,
you know,
whatever you get a U two F key.
Well, I have those too, but at the same time, you know, what if I lose my key ring
or what if my kid chucks it down a sewer hole?
Like if you've left your, if you've lost your keys in your phone,
like the least of your problems is going to be logging through Twitter.
Yeah. True.
And, and so
I do like tu of
a and I think I wish more places would use it.
But again, you know,
that so that we have this dual sort of
two pass password managers and two factor authentication.
And then the third thing that we've largely ignored is account recovery.
And I would lump password resets under account recovery because that's
sort of a form of password or of account recovery.
And what worries me is, I've, I've never seen a really,
uh good account recovery with one exception being Instagram, uh,
a friend lost access to her Instagram.
And so what they did is they had her, basically, they sent her like a numeric,
uh alphabet code
and she had to write that down on a piece of paper
and take a picture of herself with that piece of paper.
And, because,
well, and, but see, here's the Catch
Instagram is one of the few services where they Instagram
typically has one or more photos of you.
Right.
Like, I, I don't really have that with, say Twitter.
Well, no, there's my profile pic, I guess. But you get, you know what I'm saying?
-- Right. Like that's
-- mine isn't me.
Well, exactly. Yeah. So I'd have to get my kids to re stage that.
And so, yeah, I mean, it's, it's interesting because that's, that, that,
to me is a very clever way of dealing with that.
You know, it's like for the sake of argument, you know,
90 some percent of our real accounts post pictures
of themselves so we can use that as authentication.
Yes,
I
-- think that's actually pretty
-- smart.
I'm gonna, I'm gonna end this just because we've been rambling on it.
So, I guess fundamentally Twitter, good job, guys, two thumbs up
everyone else.
Pay attention and, and I guess also as kind of a side note,
if you're running an organization that has, will say more than four servers
or for services, you have passwords in your logs, go look for them, you'll find it
anyway, we'll keep going.
So, speaking of things and logs and things that shouldn't exist.
Uh,
I wanted to talk about name spaces today because that's a
thing that we don't really think or talk about enough,
I think.
Uh Yeah, you, you said this earlier and that seemed very
kind of cryptic to me because when you said Name spaces,
the first thing that popped into my head was like kernel name spaces
just because I was so involved with those when they came out.
Well, that would be a kind of a subset of this.
But what I'm talking about broadly is more of the global name spaces.
So, as a simplistic example, DNS is a great one.
I go to Walmart dot
something.
Well, what is that?
I don't even know
if it's walmart.com.
Yeah, exactly.
So like if it's, you know, and, and so for example, it's a great example,
there's an expectation that if it's something.com, it's, it's quote unquote legit
ish
probably.
But if it ends in like dot And then some wonky, you know,
country in some place I've never heard of.
-- It's like maybe that's not the real Walmart
-- Walmart that totally not hackers.
-- Right.
-- Exactly. Walmart dot uh what is it um
dot Museum?
-- Right.
-- Right. Like, I don't know.
So
um other things are name spaces like for example, in Python, when I type
import
f
well, where does that come from?
Man, you just hit on a can of worms with that one
and see,
and some of them like Python and Ruby Gems have sort of an established name space.
But some others like uh
go is a great example. Go
uh went with, instead of relying on a central, like single service,
like say Ruby gems.org or something,
they use DNS as their name space.
And then
um essentially a path that is optionally there.
So like, you know, something something.org/and, then that if that's get
repo, that's the repo where this code lives or it can live down the tree a bit.
Um
And so they went with DNS as their global name space.
But then part of the challenge becomes, you know, I,
I know the name of the library is LDA.
Well, which one is it?
Right? There's a bunch of those,
you know,
so hopefully the person specified the total like the full name space, you know,
and, and I'll be blunt,
chances are I'm going to go with the one on github because
that's the one that will show up in Google results first,
right?
But so this came up. Uh Well,
you mentioned this was the uh the N PM.
Uh somebody made a malicious module.
The Get Cookies.
Yes, this is a fascinating story.
Apparently several other uh packages with similar names, express cookies,
http fetch cookies.
Uh Oh,
sorry, those are the ones that depended on those.
Right.
Right. Right.
So,
yeah,
and so this is a great example of sort of,
I guess you could call it name space pollution in a way because so
what happened here is somebody wrote a malicious N PM module called Get Cookies.
Well, awesome. How do you get people to use it?
The answer is you don't you get other software to use it
that people do use? Right?
So essentially the chain was he got get cookies
to be used by Express cookies and Express cookies.
In turn was used by http fetch cookies.
And http fetch cookies in turn was used by
a very popular module called mail parser which well,
parses mail
and I'm not 100% certain why
-- needs cookie support.
-- Who knows?
My understanding was it? There's a new,
the mail parser that, that ended up being updated to use. This was old.
It was deprecated essentially by something newer.
The whole story is, is super weird
in, in the way it reads and it sounds like this could have probably been done better.
But fundamentally, the fact that we kind of got to where we are today is,
I'm, I'm not gonna say
the supply chain is, is bad
in, in the way this stuff works in like N PM and whatnot. It's just,
this is an interesting problem that has it.
It feels like it's happening more and more often
and I have a feeling it's going to continue
to happen more and more often and we don't have a really good answer to it today.
Right.
Yeah.
Well, I mean, part of the answer would be, is being able to upgrade your, well,
having rapid response when something like
this does happen because here's the reality
does it,
if it's a back door,
then that's kind of bad because somebody intentionally put it
there and chances are they're going to intentionally use it.
However, if it's just a simple coding mistake,
that results in a security vulnerability.
Well, again, now when the bad guys find out they're gonna start using this,
this was totally new
-- coding mistake.
-- Well, yeah. No, this is a back door.
But, um, you know, there's,
there's been coding mistakes that have been
equally like remote code execution very easily,
level of terrible.
Um I mean, one, well, the best example of this that's old was, you know,
member shell shock,
right? That code got put into bash in 1995. And then
as it turns out, why is my, you know,
my web server needs to process environmental variables.
So they use ba
I,
you know, when I first learned that I was like, what, like what
like literally, I don't understand what's going on. I have to, you know,
I thought somebody made a mistake, explaining it to me.
And
yeah,
so backdoors are definitely a problem because backdoors see
the problem is there's threats and threats are bad
but
uh sorry, risks are bad, right? And security vulnerability is a risk.
But then there's threats, you know,
where you actually have somebody or something who's going
to have a reason
to exploit this
and you know, the the means to do so,
right?
And, and, and by definition, you don't accidentally, well,
I'm gonna say by definition,
typically you don't accidentally put a back door and stuff.
But then there's been those manufacturers that have
just really done boneheaded things or accidentally left,
you know, development code in production systems
and, and they're always gonna do that.
And, and this is actually where when you said we should talk about name spaces,
I kind of got excited because
uh a lot of the name spacing we see happening kind of on,
on a low level is all about segregating
resources where let's say you have a malicious package
and it is going to start running arbitrary code.
Well, if it only has access to a very limited amount of data
due to, you know, various technologies, obviously,
there's like kernel name spacing being one of them. And like
in Kernes, you've got your pods and, and whatnot, but you get the point is
that's really the future of everything is making sure that once somebody gets in,
they can't move laterally because in, in most networks,
there's the corporate firewall.
And if you get past that, like it's done,
it's
done.
Yeah.
And, and even tying this back to our earlier discussion, for example,
why can't I set up a folder
in Google Docs that I can then give that app permission to?
And that app thinks it has access to everything.
But in reality, it only has access to a, you know,
a very specific subset of what I want to give it access to.
That would be great. You know what I mean?
Um I've looked at, you know, I,
I really wish I could set up sort of these fake roots
and fake environments for these other apps to have access to.
Um,
unfortunately, you know, I, I just can't Google doesn't support that,
so I'd have to set up other accounts or something.
Um, but tying back to this is
there's a lot of assumptions made around name spaces, like, for example,
a, a lot of name spaces are
somewhat curated in that they're not 100% curated,
but, you know, like sort of the important stuff is curated.
There's healthy security teams maybe behind it, there's,
you know, it, it's healthy.
Um But the problem is,
you know,
you end up with something like this where maybe mail parser was well
curated and then it kind of depended on H TB fetch cookies which,
you know, you get these chains of dependencies
and eventually you end up somewhere that's probably not the best part of town.
Right. Right.
Um And I've seen some pretty crazy dependency chains where
I mean, like my favorite is always, you know,
like R PM dependencies whenever I install some package.
And it's like, why, why are you pulling in like this random,
like library for image parsing?
Like what,
like just why, you know, and it turns out
that something depends on something depends on
something depends on this thing and it has
image parsing as an option,
right?
And, and this is a huge problem, especially in,
in places like N PM because once you start pulling in N PM modules, man,
it's turtles all the way down
and things get out of hand.
-- Yeah.
-- And I like, I mean, and then the other concern too with these
is not even from a security point of view but that that whole like
left shift situation where somebody removes a package and breaks half the world.
Yes, like straight up. Right.
So, you know, even at this point,
we don't even have to worry about like militia security actors, just somebody
delete something or decides to kill a project. And,
and then the problem becomes, what are the rules around the name, space ownership,
right.
You know, can I go take o can I basically, for example,
could I create a company with a name of
a popular module and then bully that name space manager
into giving me that name space? And the answer is, well, that's happened.
You're right. Right. It, it can totally be done.
And that's,
that is less concerning to me because that's a very public and open process.
What we saw here with get cookies.
This was clearly meant to be malicious in secret.
And, and I think that's the difference, right?
Is there is openly malicious in some cases, which is generally easy to see
and, and I actually I, I say openly malicious,
but it's generally just like stupidity that that is the result of much of that.
But then there's like the sneaky stuff
and the sneaky stuff is what's really concerning
and you must get cookies thing, man.
It is super sneaky and the things these people did, like
they knew, like these are pretty smart folks that put this all together.
Like, like I've, I've been looking at some of the files for this and
there is
to my knowledge this was not on github anywhere, there was a user account on github.
But, but the actual Get cookies source wasn't there. It has a change log
that goes back to 2015.
So I don't know if they like found something
called Get cookies or they found something that they,
they took and, and changed.
But like that was really fascinating to me. So it's essentially a forged change
and let's face it. If I was looking at a project, I would,
I would look at the change like, oh, this has been around for a couple of years.
That's legit.
No, sure hasn't. It's been around since March, you know.
Yeah. No, I've taken a look on Google for this and, and even the, the user name is very,
I got three pages of Google results.
This is,
this is pretty clearly
a beautiful setup
and, and I guess at the same time
they made enough of mistakes
that they got caught,
but it would not surprise me if there
are smarter people that aren't making mistakes.
Right?
And
one of the,
one of the beautiful things too is if you look at the timeline published by, you know,
in the N PM Js guys,
well, people, sorry, uh you know, the initial report
to unpublished it
two hours, three minutes.
That's pretty solid, right? So,
and, and now we don't know, you know, the
how many people
uh we're affected by this, right?
-- Because they
-- kind of do it says up earlier that the mail parser
received 64,000 weekly downloads and it sounds like it was there for a while
where, where this was an
like a month or more.
Yeah,
but
we don't know is that some developers workstation doing
builds or is that like a production system?
Right?
That's what I mean by we don't know how many people are affected because that's
measuring this is like I've literally seen case. Well,
there are some major companies, for example that they, they download these things,
put them into an internal repository and then use them,
you know, things like that.
Yeah.
No, I mean, this also speaks though to the to the health of the community, right?
Like two hours and they
dealt with it.
-- I I really can't ask for much more than that,
-- right?
And, and the the thing I keep thinking about here is
as much as people want to rail on open source sometimes
and, and it's funny because I, I see more attacks as of late than I did for a long time,
which is
whatever.
But, but here's
-- where
-- the money is now.
Let's
face it. Right. Like, no, no, no. Think about it. Like let me put it this way.
Is there any major
cloud service built? Not using open source?
No.
Look, man, even the people I see
talking about how open source is insecure.
Like you go to their website and you go to
the like included library section and it's full of stuff
and it's like you guys are just a bunch of
annoying hypocrites that don't want to compete on level terms.
Like that's what this is.
But anyway,
yeah, I challenge anybody at this point to write
-- anything nontrivial in house like a web server or, or like, you
-- know, don't do that,
please please don't roll your own
crypto. It's easy, right?
Says
anyway,
-- that was, that was a joke, by the way.
-- Yes, please don't,
don't write your own crypto unless,
unless your last name is Rivers Shamir, you know, like somebody like sneer
-- or somebody like that
-- dude,
-- I wouldn't trust any of those people to write crypto anymore because
-- they,
-- they would be smart enough to say no,
-- that's true too.
Anyway, anyway,
here's the thing I keep thinking about
is
there are
hostile insiders
at any large organization.
This is, this is a known fact just statistically speaking,
if your organization has more than probably 10,000 people.
You certainly have one or more hostile insiders,
meaning there are certainly closed sourced applications
that have purposeful backdoors.
Well, there,
there's, there's like, search the CV database. There's a ton of these
and, and some are quasi
like, oh DEV code slipped out. Whoops. A dod.
But like some of them are pretty clearly malicious
but, and, and malicious from, and in some cases it's worse. It's not even an insider.
It's clearly not an insider threat.
It was pretty clearly
that the actual maker,
-- like, this was a sanctioned back door.
-- But here's, my point
is
the open source community took
a little over a month to figure this out.
Right.
Well, it's more that it's like a lot of things, you know,
a lot of things people don't notice, like, we, like,
literally driving around the city and, you know, my partner is like,
when the heck did that thing building get there.
And I'm like, uh, that's been there for, like, ever.
Like, I've never noticed it and I'm like,
and then I check Google street view because now I'm getting paranoid.
I'm like, yeah. No, it's been there for at least 10 years. Right.
It's, it's actually legitimately a weird looking building and I'm like,
how have you not noticed that?
Right. I've done that.
And so
part of it is, you know, we don't,
people, people generally,
if they see a little bit of weirdness they generally ignore it
if it's not immediately dangerous to them. Right.
That's how we're wired because if we reacted to
every single thing that was potentially weird and dangerous
dude, I wouldn't be able to get out of my chair.
Right. Like, seriously.
And so that's just part of the human psyche. Right?
Is we, we have some really great filters for danger.
Like, think about when you're driving.
How many potentially dangerous things are there?
Well, by definition, every single other car
and you just sort of tune them out.
If they're not swerve
-- around,
-- you're getting a little more philosophical than I hoped.
But
fundamentally, it's, it's from the time what I've noticed in the open source world,
at least from the time of somebody actually spotting the weirdness and raising it
to it being dealt with is, is getting increasingly short.
They're, they're moving very quickly.
And that, that's one of the things I've been thinking about now is so
if you look at the source code and I, I found the source code to get cookies and I'll,
I'll maybe throw some up on the show notes,
but I don't see how I can do any harm. I mean, I
don't like
no one's gonna use it
anyway anyway,
that
no one's gonna use it, please don't use it anyway. Anyway.
So the point is though that if you look at this,
it's really weird what it's doing
and
a normal person would look at it and be like, oh,
that's just some weird cookie processing.
No big deal there.
But it's the sort of thing that makes me think
normal applications don't look like this.
And so I bet you could take, uh, what, what's that? What's that thing? Uh Truffle Hog.
That, that looks for entropy in your, your G repo?
I bet you could use something like that
to look for
SATED code like this.
So, anyway, something I was thinking about for this weekend is to take Truffle hog
and to look at this particular source code,
which appears to be high entropy to me as a human and,
and see how it compares to other things because I have a suspicion
that
when someone builds a backdoor,
the code is going to be weird in ways that normal code isn't because
obviously the goal of a backdoor is so a human doesn't see it,
right? But we can build machines to see this stuff. And so
it's, it's just my, my brain has kind of been racing about this just because like,
I feel like we have a huge opportunity here to build some
tools to help make this not be a problem in the future.
Yeah.
Well,
what I've noticed about code in general is code that is cleanly and simply written
tends to be more understandable and thus
more maintainable and less prone to errors.
Yes,
the the probably the biggest problem I would say is
where people start fiddling with code logic and not the,
not the syntax or the form of the code
but sort of the actual flow of the law
itself.
Yeah, because that code can look completely correct.
And then the logic is like you actually chart it out and it's kind of like what?
Oh man, you know what I'm gonna,
I'm gonna yell at Python for lambda functions here because man,
some of those lambda functions people write.
It's like you're either a crazy person or you, you just guessed until this worked.
Like I don't know which it is.
It's, it's but, and, and I agree with you and I feel like
the, the way the universe is heading and this is funny enough.
I don't know why I remember this but I was thinking
about this while I was brushing my teeth this morning.
Is that if I created a language today,
I would make these syntax super simple, like to a point of being hilariously simple
and make the ability to plug things together
like one of the fundamental features because let's face it.
Like what, what didn't the last XK CD talk about that?
My new job is just gluing things together and I've known
you can name them work like that's totally what's happening.
Now.
I, I'd even go one step further. I would, I would forcibly make every single um
thing wrapped in a little web container and everything would be a rest api
like at the function level.
Exactly.
Hyper,
what's smaller than micro
nano
services? There you go. Nano
services. You heard it here first we better we should copy our data
or trademark that, I mean,
but uh you know, because clearly the future is gluing stuff together
because it's just, well as open source shows, it's faster to glue something
than to recreate it and then glue it in.
Uh Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
Well, in all seriousness,
I think gluing things together has been pretty hip for a while.
It's just, it's becoming an art form whereas before it was
like, it was external libraries
and that was, that was more work, right?
And then they randomly changed.
That's,
that's what the versioning was for, right?
Which totally always checked out.
Yeah.
Yeah. So,
no, I think this is a, like you said,
we're seeing more of these attacks but we're
also seeing better response to these attacks.
And so fundamentally, I'm ok with that.
I, yes, I, I don't think there's a way around it.
I think this is just part of the, the evolution of,
of open source and security and development in general and,
and there's gonna be some,
some weirdness that happens and I think we're gonna
see more backdoors and we're going to see more attacks
and, and here's the thing, right? Is
as much as I would love to say, oh, well,
we just have to design our processes to deal with this or we have
to design our tools to deal with this or we have to do.
Here's the thing,
you're never going to design something an attacker can't circumvent.
So the, the absolute best way to deal with this is to move fast, which M PM guys can do
and then make sure whatever happened doesn't happen ever again. Right. I mean,
make it hard definition
or yes, that's fair. Make it, make it hard enough.
They go, they go to Ruby Gems or somewhere else. Right? Like that's,
that's the plan.
It's, it's like the old saying. Right.
I don't need to, I don't need to be able to run faster than a bear.
I just have to run faster than you.
No.
Right.
And, and this is one of those things that,
that I think about constantly is the fact that we love to talk about.
We're, we're building our defenses and we're,
we're doing all these mitigations and all this stuff.
But if you look at
like the really good security technologies
and even processes that, that exist,
they exist because they basically reacted to things from the past.
I don't know of any of them that were, were forward looking and said,
we're going to stop these things from happening in the future because again,
well,
and I guess it's twofold because let's say you do
build a technology that stops something in the future.
That's great. Now, they're just not gonna do that.
They're gonna attack something else. Right.
It's, it's just, it's the,
the cat and mouse game that never ends and that's what we're stuck in it.
It's
our, yeah,
where everyone's on their hamster wheels and no one's going anywhere
anyway anyway. All right, man. Any, any last parting thoughts before we go,
uh, just, you know, be aware of what software you're actually using,
maybe take a look at it once in a while.
Look for weirdness and, and
-- more importantly, if you see weirdness, tell somebody don't just
-- ignore it.
-- If you see something, say something. Right.
-- Exactly. Like file an issue on github
or wherever it lives
anyway.
Alright, sweet. Thanks, Kurt. Thanks everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com to catch the show notes.
You can use the Pound Os S Podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media
and you have nothing else. Kurt, you have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
Thank you. Bye bye.