Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 24
and the first of the new year in 2017 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime, Josh Bresser.
Oh, man, 2017,
the train wreck that was 2016 is finally behind us and everything is ok again.
Right.
-- You know,
-- my personal thoughts on that are,
if you look at history every single year is a train wreck.
-- You know, at least it wasn't a super volcano last year
-- yet.
I read an article actually in the newspaper today with yes,
I read like the dead tree newspaper every day,
but they said there's a volcano in Italy. I think that is getting ready to erupt and
it's in a, a densely populated region
which
that's pretty much Europe, by definition.
That's true.
And it's not like we've ever had a problem
in the past of densely populated regions near volcanoes.
Right.
So, yeah. So I think this year
we should, maybe we should lead off, I think with some predictions.
I love predictions.
-- Yeah, I think we should do some, a nice set of predictions for 2016
-- and
17.
No,
no sadly, I don't.
-- So I think we should do the predictions for 2016.
-- I, I love it.
This is a brilliant idea because we can laugh at everyone
else without having to actually do any real work ourselves.
Yeah.
And we can just pair at them, which is a
-- winning strategy.
-- I love it. I love it.
So I guess to, to start off then let's say this.
If, if you want to look at what we're looking at,
you can just head over to open source security,
podcast.com and all the links we refer to and all these predictions we have there.
And so if you wish you can play along at home, dear listener.
Yeah.
So I'd like to start with my favorite prediction of 2016,
which is also essentially my favorite prediction for
the last probably 10 or 20 years,
which is passwords are going away
right, right next to the paperless office. Right.
Yeah.
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
I mean, and, and what gets me is, um, I have a lot more,
I was gonna say, apps,
but it's more websites that now support two
factor authentication primarily through my phone because,
you know, S MS or, or the Google Authenticator app or whatever,
which is awesome. But they all pretty much primarily go by password,
you know,
full stop.
And
what really drives me nuts is how few of them will allow me to log in, say,
using a Google or a Facebook or my linkedin account
so that I can just use one password for many sites.
But yeah,
I don't think passwords are going to go away for probably another 50 to 100 years.
They will never go away. Let's face reality.
There will always be passwords in some capacity. However, however,
I
think what's going to happen here and this has been
referred to kind of like water on Mars or Voyager leaving the solar system.
How many times have we found water on Mars in the last five or 10 years?
What, like 20 maybe, maybe more.
And, and I think passwords are kind of like the, this is, this is like boiling a frog
where
eventually it's going to happen,
but it's been take,
it's taken so long and there have been so many incremental
changes along the way that when it does finally happen,
nobody even notices.
And I, I suspect
it's gonna be the same thing like when we find, you know,
extraterrestrial life where we send out these probes
to these moons and planets and stuff.
And
we always find like on Mars, how many signs of life have we found?
You know, a whole bunch and one day they're gonna be like, oh, we finally found,
you know, life on Venus and like, didn't we do that like 10 years ago?
You know, I mean, that's just how this stuff is.
Yeah. Well, it leads me to one thought is, you know, we still have coal
and FORTRAN apps that are 4050 years old, grinding away on data,
you know, so much so that
Amazon and the Amazon cloud now actually has like a batch data processing service,
right? Like explicitly aimed at like banks and whatnot because they're like,
they're like, let's face it, right?
You wanna move this stuff to the cloud,
but you're basically just forklift a mainframe into the cloud, right?
So we have to support batch processing because
that's how that world works.
And I'm, I'm thinking like password based apps. I mean, they're,
they're the rule, not the, you know, I,
I can think of so few applications that don't require a password,
you know, it's, it's at least another 50 100 years for that paradigm to, to change.
Well, but, but so, well, let's use Cobalt as our example here is
there's not a lot of Cobalt or FORTRAN
in actual production anymore. I mean, the, the stuff that exists is quite large but
it's just been a slow death
and it's gonna be one of those, you know, kind of
what, what do you call it with? The,
not a Parabola, you know, but the other way where it's, it's going to,
right? It's gonna always be approaching zero but never actually getting there.
And it's the same thing with passwords, right?
We're going to continue to approach the universe where there are no passwords,
but we will never actually touch the line.
Well, but see, here's the dirty secret.
We'll always need some form of password because what happens when you wash up,
you know, with, without your wallet or phone or anything.
And you literally only have what you remember in your head and maybe biometrics,
right?
And the problem with biometrics is you need sensors on everything, which
what happens
today,
I mean, OK,
-- so let's say you have your
-- secret question to like, you know, change to, to uh,
to recover your, you know, account, right?
What was your first high school teacher or?
What was your favorite pet or, you know, things like that? So
the reality is like the, the one benefit of passwords is, you know,
barring head injuries, you always have your passwords.
That's
true.
And in theory, you know, as
you
let's face it,
it has one.
Yeah. And so, you know,
that's the dirty secret, right? Even if we replace everything with really good,
you know, biometrics or really good, um,
like token based authentication or whatever,
you know, something you have. Well, you know, you can always lose that,
right?
Or you go in a steam room
and uh, and with something you are, you know, well, I mean,
people do get their limbs and eyes and stuff injured, you know, what happens then,
right?
Yeah,
that's, that's very true.
You know, there's, there's been, you know, there's those cases of, well, I mean,
there's double amputees out there.
So, what do they do? For fingerprint based authentication systems,
you know? I don't know. That's an interesting question,
you know. So,
anyway, so, yeah,
I think passwords are gonna be here to stay for a couple more decades at least.
And, um,
but my hope would be is that we
supplement them with two factor authentication so that,
you know, by shoulder surfing or sniffing the password, you don't just
-- basically hijack somebody's life right away.
-- All right.
So this, this one came from the uh CSO online top 15 security predictions for 2016.
So let's,
let's stick with these guys for a few minutes and see what else they had to say.
We've got, uh let's see, IOT for ransom.
So when they say for ransom, they mean, like, you know, give us a Bitcoin or we,
-- you won't get any
-- coffee,
they're discussing ransomware to a degree and then
they're trying to tie it into iot.
Well, I mean, I've, there's that comic,
you know where that guy is in his kitchen and every single device is showing
some variation of like give us money and we'll make you coffee or cook your,
you know, open the fridge or whatever.
And my, my problem with that is, is by definition,
the people that are like susceptible to be being
hit by ransomware are typically not that sophisticated.
So how do you make them pay you?
It, it is true and if you disable all of their devices, they,
by definition cannot pay you
and, and well, ok, so ignoring that, ignoring that conversation.
Have we seen any instances of IOT ransomware?
Not, I've heard of nothing public yet. And I kind of have kept an eye out for it.
I haven't TV. S maybe I think we'll see that
with the IOT attacks.
D
do
is easier to monetize.
Right. Because like, if I hijack, say a million TV.
S and I send out a million ransomware notices,
I then have to, like, basically train and educate
enough people to, like,
pay me in Bitcoin because realistically Bitcoin is
the only way to do this anonymously.
Right.
So, you know, I'm only gonna get a minor subset of those people and more the point,
you know, it's like those people that have like,
virus infested laptops and it's gonna cost like 200 bucks to, to wipe and clean it.
Well, you can buy a new laptop now for 300 bucks.
Yeah. Exactly. Exactly.
And, and that's, that's always gonna be the challenge of ransomware. Right?
Is ensuring that the ransom is less expensive than the alternative.
-- Well, not just less expensive but less hassle.
-- That's true too.
That's a very good price
because you and me, we could,
we could go get a hold of, you know,
you and I could follow instructions on how to buy
a Bitcoin and ship it to somebody with relative ease.
But you're dealing with people who, like, can barely check their email
-- or don't know how to reset a password
-- trying to even explain what Bitcoin is to.
My parents
is a horrifying thought.
I, I would, I would just call it magic money.
Like, I can't even think of anything else I would say.
Yeah. Yeah. So, I don't think we're going to see IOT ransomware
because quite frankly it's just, it's,
that's
a foolish thing to say.
I
was,
I think on the higher end we might, but here's the reality.
If someone ransomware is my $3 light bulb. Oh,
ok.
I, I go and buy new light bulbs.
It's less hassle than paying the ransom and it's probably cheaper.
So, you know, you mentioned that and I know we,
we laughed about this a couple of episodes ago, but I was at a store yesterday,
I think it was,
and there was a $12 light bulb that was Bluetooth enabled and a speaker
and part of me wanted to buy it so bad
just to have it and say I have it.
Another part of me is like, no, there's no reason to have this thing.
Like no good will ever come of this purchase.
Yeah. Yeah,
I expect in a couple of days I'll go back and buy it.
Yeah. See, and that's the thing, right. I mean,
I,
I think at the higher end you'll be able to maybe hold a medical device ransom.
You know, like an MRI scanner that cost a million bucks
but yeah, at the low end I just can't see it
being MRI,
like, working and more to the point, I can't see
an attacker getting enough people to actually pay
-- to make it worthwhile
-- regardless of that.
We're just picking on 2016 predictions here. It didn't happen. Right.
-- No.
-- Well, there's not enough IOT deployed yet. Right.
Yeah. Sure.
And the thing to remember too is, I mean, as bad as IOT is the reality is
99 point whatever percent of home internet connections are behind
a net device because your ISP will only give you one IP,
because we haven't done I PV six yet.
You know,
and so how do you infect those devices?
Right. They have to be if they're directly connected to the internet. Yeah. Sure.
They all have default passwords and stuff. So, no problem. And,
and that's where things like those video camera systems come in. Right.
Because businesses put them online so they can check them remotely. But, you know,
as far as most of these light bulbs are like nest cameras, they,
they go through like the Google mothership or the manufacturer's mothership.
Right.
And, well, granted those things are probably not as secure as they should be.
I just, I don't think, I, I think it will happen at some point,
but probably not for a few years until we really get some more
widespread availability and
easier ways to get money from people anonymously online.
Yeah. Yeah. That's,
I'll, I'll agree with that.
All right. So let's move on to the next one is about
chip, credit cards
about
it says your card is safe or you aren't.
Yeah.
Well, it's funny because the, I just took a course on, uh,
cybersecurity economics and they actually used this exact example
from Britain back when Britain introduced chip and pin,
the card not present fraud rose dramatically, especially from foreign countries,
right?
Um, Because the reality was like in Britain,
you could no longer easily clone a card by copying the make stripe,
but you could still clone the card and then use it to make an online purchase.
So this isn't even a prediction. This is just
what happened in Europe.
Well, it's how it works, right? You,
you
make one type of fraud harder. So of course they move to a different type of fraud.
So, I mean, yeah,
that's not even a prediction that is like that is
a historical fact used in an online cybersecurity course.
I know. Right. Right. That's great. Well done guys. Well done.
Uh So, so moving on then now this one
shows up in a number of places in all the 2016 predictions I reviewed is,
do you remember in 2015 where these groups like anonymous, for example, were, were
essentially breaking into people's online accounts and they, they
the same
stuff.
Yeah. Right. Right. Exactly. The doc
or the
stuff
where you,
you're stealing basically someone's private information and then you're,
you're either trying to ransom it back to them in
some cases or just using it to hideously embarrass them.
And
a lot of people said this was gonna get worse in 2016 and I don't think it did.
I think this actually decreased substantially.
Um, so my experience of it is, uh,
a couple of the major sites like icloud
and stuff definitely tightened up their security.
Um,
you know, talking passwords. It kind of goes back to that.
A lot of places have really good account security,
like passwords and two factor authentication and all that.
And then they have really terrible account recovery and like setups,
you know, like, um, like there was those famous cases with, I think it was um,
well, it was a large online retail. I'm, I'm not gonna name because I might be wrong
where basically it was the last four, it was the classic,
last four digits of your credit card could be used to recover the account.
So all you needed was somebody's email address and
the last four digits of their credit card,
which let's face, it are not hard to find.
Um, so things like that.
So I think a lot of them uh improve their account recovery procedures, which,
you know, again, that becomes a problem, right?
Because if somebody legitimately loses all their stuff,
how do they get back into their account?
Especially when, you know, they,
they're goofy and forgot their passwords or whatever
their secret question answers. Sorry. Uh, not a password. They secret question.
Um, so I think that side of the doc
and got, or that side of the, you know, the break into your data got a bit harder.
And I think the reality is, you know, people
like you, you can only use a blackmail once and then it's like, well, ok.
Yeah, you, you, you shared my
deep, terrible secret.
What are you going to do now? Right.
Yeah. You know, and I didn't die. Nothing too terrible happened.
You know, I didn't get fired or whatever.
So, you know, and I think that's part of it is the reality is,
I mean, the dirty secret is everybody has dirty secrets. You know,
we all,
we all have things that we are embarrassed and we won't say we
won't tell our mother or our coworkers or our boss or like,
put on our, you know,
web page
or our Facebook profile.
And I mean,
you know, but the vast majority of things are just not that terrible
and you're just,
nobody really gives a care.
You know,
I remember one time a person was so embarrassed to tell a
group of us that she had been divorced and we were like,
uh huh.
And then what happened? And she's like, no, that's it. I was divorced and we're like,
yeah. Ok. But like, what's the, what's your deep, terrible secret? I'm divorced.
I we're like, I don't get it. Like, how is that a terrible deep secret? Like this is,
what year are we in again? Like,
you know,
and, but in her mind it was the most terrible shameful thing, you know,
coming from her cultural background.
And that's,
I mean, that's just part of being a human is we assume
people care far more about details like this than they really do. And,
and it's kind of like, always where, you know, I, I get this, my, my, my son is 10
and it's always like, oh, so and so doesn't like me and I'm like,
so and so probably doesn't care, you know,
that's the reality of it. Just don't worry. All right,
we're lucky that people actually know we exist
-- whether they like us or not.
-- Exactly. Exactly.
So, oh man, anyway, let's keep going.
The next one, I'm gonna skip over a couple here on this list because they're just,
they're boring.
But there is
the cloud wars talking about
that hackers are going to use public cloud as a major attack vector.
-- And I don't, I can't think of any good examples of this from 2016.
-- It
has not really happened yet.
And I know for a fact like some of them like Amazon web services is a great example.
You do a port scan from an EC2 instance
and you get a nasty email within like two minutes saying like you
better explain what's going on or we're probably gonna shut your account down.
So I shouldn't like scan the internet from EC
like I did. Uh, what was I doing?
Oh, yeah, I wanted to, I wanted to verify my firewall configured home.
So I just fired off, you know, n map
with like uh no options
pointing out my home IP address.
And like literally three minutes later I got this nasty email from
Amazon web services and I'm like I typed in a reply saying,
you know, well,
I scanned my own IP address and please for the love of God don't turn my account off,
you know.
Um but the reality is like uh a lot of
these major cloud writers are really good at egress,
detecting the attacks, blocking them, filtering them, you know,
just in general dealing with them because that is a significant
cost on their side if they have to deal with people complaining about these attacks,
right?
Because
people who are being attacked will be annoying and they will manage to find like
that phone number for one of your humans and like phone them and harass them.
Well, I guess not only that you,
these IP addresses in a public cloud are heavily shared
and if one of your IP S ends up on a blacklist,
I mean IP D four addresses are they're worth their weight in gold these days.
So if your, if your address is on a blacklist, you're going to be in trouble.
Yeah,
I had to deal with this one Swiss company that they block
all incoming email from all of Amazon's IP ranges and I'm like,
well, I guess you're not getting our email.
That's crazy. Why would you do that?
It would stop a lot of spam, I guess. I mean, but,
you know,
I mean,
in theory I shouldn't be sending email directly from
an E two instance I should probably be using,
you know, Amazon's simple email service.
Ses. Ok, that's fair.
But, you know, it's uh why bother setting it up just have post pic,
you know, post,
spit out the occasional email or whatever, right?
But yeah, I mean, so, you know, and
so the reality is this guy is like, well, I can't receive email from you and I'm like,
well, yeah, no, you can't go get it, go get a gmail address
and like sign up using that, you know, like I,
I'm not going to rejigger my entire email infrastructure, you know, to,
to do one person.
Um So I,
I think we're gonna see some of that eventually but I think it's
gonna look a bit different in the form more of like account hijacking
and then trying to use those that account's resources,
you know, to do something nefarious. Um
But it's probably gonna look more boring, like, probably like Bitcoin mining,
you know, because again, it goes back to the question of how do you monetize it?
So, I've hijacked your account.
Honestly, the one big way I can think of to monetize it is to resell it. Right.
Like, you know, cheap web hosting,
just go to this virtual server, you know, for the bad guys, right.
For bulletproof hosting or whatever.
But again, that stuff gets detected and taken down relatively quickly.
Right. I, I just, I don't see that as having a future because,
I mean, if you're spinning up any number of systems,
people are gonna notice when,
when the number of systems they have running went from, you know,
-- 1000 to 25,000 or so, or,
-- you know, they use the serverless stuff like LAMBDA.
And the thing is, um, a lot of people don't set, like, uh,
you can set on most of these cloud providers, you can set warnings, let's say, like,
look when I
hit a certain amount of billing, warn me, right?
Like, say, I normally spend 2000 bucks a month,
you know, warn me when I hit, say
2500 in case something goes haywire. Right?
I don't think a lot of people set those limits.
Um,
what's interesting is like a lot of these cloud providers do limit
how much resources you can use and spin up by default.
You know, I think with Amazon it's like 10 instances and you gotta ask nicely for more
or whatever, you know.
Uh, well, and I had like, first, uh,
simple email services I needed to send like 100 emails a day.
So I sent a nice, you know, I sent, filled in the form, like,
can I please have 100 emails a day?
And they're like, you can have 50,000 a day.
So I'm guessing that's like their, their sort of floor entry level. But yeah, I mean,
I, again, it comes back to how do you monetize this stuff?
And I can't think of a lot of good ways to monetize this, especially,
you know,
with these providers wanting to filter and prevent outgoing attacks so
that people don't block their IP S and like you said,
then,
you know, then they become much.
-- Well, they, they will lose business.
-- Well, and let's face it too.
And in all the predictions
I looked at last year,
I mean,
none of them really mentioned ransomware in any significant way and
let's face it 2016 was like the year of ransomware.
I mean, this is where cybercrime learned how to monetize what they do.
Yeah,
definitely.
And that's just the reality of it. I mean, in, in, in all seriousness,
I don't see it getting any better
next year
because I, I mean, I remember
almost certain,
I, I remember 2015
and ransomware just started coming out and it was kind of a
joke and it didn't work very well and we laughed at it.
I remember laughing at it being like this is stupid, you know, whatever.
And you look at it now and
it still has problems.
It's not great because I've read a number of
reports talking about the fact that in most instances,
the ransomware fails due to either backups or it
just doesn't encrypt the data correctly or whatever,
there's a reason.
But give them another year.
I mean, these guys are, they're innovating at an alarming rate
and
I, if, if it, if 2017 isn't the year of ransomware, 2018 probably will be
where it's like a huge problem unless we do something drastic to stop it.
And I don't know of anything
out there
that's ready to stop it.
Well, I'm kind of wondering.
So, for example, uh I keep a lot of my files in icloud right from my, you know, I devices
and I don't know exactly how icloud works on the back end with keeping snapshots.
But for example, if icloud transparently keeps like,
say snapshots going back forever or, you know, to whatever my,
my one terabyte limit is,
I can just roll back before the ransomware
without too much hassle
and, you know, and I won't bother paying them.
So I suspect we're gonna see a lot of innovation in ransomware.
You know, obviously they're gonna get better at actually encrypting the files.
Um, I suspect they're also gonna maybe get a bit quieter,
you know.
So for example,
they encrypt the files and decrypt them on the fly for say
a week or two to make sure that they're everywhere and then,
you know, flip the switch and say pay up or else,
you know, conversely then, you know,
maybe hopefully people can recover the decryption keys and stuff. But, um,
yeah, I suspect they will get better because, yeah,
it's been proven to work and generate money.
It's huge.
And what gets me is like, and I still haven't heard.
Um, so there was what the San Francisco, what was it called again? Not the
system?
-- Was
-- it Bart? I think it was
the,
it
is the Bay area rapid transit. That's the trains,
the municipal bus service or
service.
That's the one.
And so they got infected and they, they at the time had to pony up.
I think it was Bitcoin, whatever it was worth it was like 73 grand or something.
I mean, it,
it's got to have cost so much more to recover it manually.
-- So
-- rumor has it that they were, well, they, they stopped taking fares because they
still
need
to
confirm
and rumor has it. It was like half a million a day
they were dropping.
-- So
-- how did they ultimately resolve this?
Did they pay the ransom or did they get somebody in
to fix it or because that's what I haven't heard,
-- you know,
-- I don't know.
So maybe make a note we should check on that. But um
yeah,
because I'm kind of wondering like honestly part of me if I was running that place,
I'd be like, part of me would be like,
let's just pay the ransom, get back up on our feet and fix it.
You know, the old part of me was like, no, you know, you do not pay the kidnappers.
We don't negotiate with terrorists kind of deal.
But the reality is like, as a business,
you know.
Yeah, it would be great if everybody didn't pay because these people would stop.
right. If nobody paid, they would stop doing it.
Um,
but on the flip side, you know, the tragedy of the commons, if you know, well, I don't,
if I pay then I'm, I'm out of here and I'm, I'm done for the day.
You know, I don't have to spend like a month fixing everything.
So, according
to this, this website, I just found
the Muni folks restored from backup. They refused to pay the ransomware.
Glad
to hear that
man. So, I,
I'm really torn over this because
they lost probably millions on this attack and for 70
grand they probably could have made it go away.
Well, stupid question though.
But isn't the whole point of having backups that A,
you have backups and b you can restore them quickly and painless.
So, you know what, when I was a youngster,
backups were one of the things I got stuck with
because you always give the new guy the crap job.
And I learned a ton about doing backups and it is in
it. It reminds me of key management in a way where it's really easy to do wrong
and almost impossible to do. Right.
I
think it's worse than that because even when you're doing it wrong,
it looks like you're doing it right until you actually have to do a
proper recovery. Like, not a test recovery but like a legit, like
-- something went wrong.
-- And
I mean, so, so you say that and like,
that's one of the things I did is I would do bare metal
restarts of,
you know, critical systems and things like that.
And of course everyone I worked with is like a stupid new guy.
And I'm like, no, no, like this is, and
it saved her behind
more than once or,
or the other one nobody realizes is when you do tape backups,
you need two drives because you do the backup on one
drive and then you verify the backup on the second drive.
Because what happens is the way tapes work.
If the, if the reader right head becomes misaligned
now, no other tape drive on the planet can read or write that data correctly
because of the way it is
your,
well, that's just it, right? If you lose the tape drive
and in another tape drive can't read your tapes. You now have a box full of plastic.
Yeah.
No, when I worked for the government,
they had uh 50 or 100 years of historical data on these, uh, tapes,
they were like 100 megabyte tapes.
And I believe there was one tape drive in the
province that the government owned that would read these,
man, you've got to get that stuff
off
if you're lucky. Right. Assuming the drive still runs, I think
you didn't like NASA,
someone have that problem where they had all this data and they're like,
we got to get it off because, you know,
in 10 years this stuff just this gear isn't going to exist.
Yeah.
Well, it's like five and a quarter inch floppy drives.
I mean,
can you imagine having to find a working five and a quarter inch floppy drive?
And then the big question is, what do you plug it into?
I'm pretty sure I can't buy a computer with, um, an isa interface
-- or with a five and a quarter floppy drive interface
-- anymore.
I would go to a local grade school
to see their equipment.
Yeah. Go basically computer mining in the, uh,
please let me into your basement.
I need one of your old computers.
Yeah.
-- So, no, seriously,
-- seriously.
But that's because the reality for me is like, you know, if,
if you get hit by ransomware, it should literally be like, ok,
we just have to figure out when this ransomware hit and then
ideally it was recent, you know,
so we're not losing a week of work or two days of work or whatever,
but we can just roll back to pre ransomware.
And then also more importantly, you know, prevent it from getting in again,
which I guess mostly in these cases, you know, means
preventing Janice from accounting, running dancing.
-- Hamster dot exc, which some nice Russian guy emailed
-- her
whatever dude. I want to see that hamster dance,
which I guess this kind of leads us. So let's, let's keep going.
We don't, we don't need to burn all our time on this. But
so let's move on to the Gartner stuff because Gartner their, their predictions are,
are interesting because they, they're multiyear predictions.
And
the number, the top one here is that through 2020
which is
closer than we think. Now
it says 99% of vulnerabilities exploited will continue to be ones
known by security and it professionals for at least one year.
-- And I think ransomware ties into this.
-- I have to agree
with that.
That's totally true. And I think it's always going to be true.
Well, the economics are simple, right? A zero day is going to cost you 50 to 100 grand,
right?
And then it will for sure, let you get into like almost everybody.
Although, you know, some subset won't click on it or won't download it or,
or will have some, you know, extra security that prevents it.
And you get basically the exact same infection rate using the known vulnerability.
It's
just spam it out, you know,
just take 10 million people instead of 1 million people.
And this is obviously, I mean, I mean, this is totally,
this comes back to all the economics of
the bad guys have to run their business as well.
So they're going to pick the cheaper option. Right.
Well, and also the easier option, right?
Like the level of skill needed to use an existing flaw is uh well, basically zero,
right? There's kits or there's, you know,
there's meta
um,
versus the, the expertise needed to find a zero day.
Like, you know,
you have to be at least this tall to get on the ride or at least this tall to, you know,
have 100 grand to go buy one.
Oh, seriously. Well, yeah. But even if you had it, what do you do with it then, I mean,
it's nontrivial to actually use this
stuff correctly and more importantly is protected
because as soon as your exploit gets out, it's worth $0.
Well, yeah, I mean, especially, uh, the big guys like Microsoft and Apple, you know,
they are like, very actively monitoring, you know,
all those telemetry systems that send back data, crash data and stuff.
I think the reality is, is that these zero days
exploits are gonna mostly be used by state actors.
Right?
Because they're the people who are like 100 grand to go, you know,
mess with some journalists. Yeah. Sure. Whatever.
They have infinite money. Exactly. They, they, they don't care how much it costs,
you know, and especially in some of these parts of the world where, yeah,
they have quite a bit of money that they've historically been willing to spend on.
-- Not very nice.
-- We'll get to the, the state level. One is,
I don't,
one of these predictions talked about the election
and which was, yeah, which election?
So it was dark reading
in their predictions said a cyber attack
will impact the 2016 presidential election.
And I think
in 2015,
I would have accused them of being a bit tinfoil hat to say that.
And in 2017, I'm like, I won't say that's a hard, yes. But it's probably a holy crap.
I think that might be. Right.
Well,
so I've done a lot of reading on election machines.
-- No, no,
-- not, not the machines, not the machines,
the machines are untouchable because they're so crappy
and they're so different
that it would be like you would need to literally hack
millions of completely different computers that are all terrible and,
and you probably can't even get any exploits to
work on them because they're just going to crash.
Right.
So my,
my fear has always been that they're not gonna
go directly after the machines even though they could.
But that,
you know, there's, there's subtle things you can do like there.
-- I mean,
-- either the, one of the parties
-- or,
-- you know, voter registration list. Right.
Because for example, even a 0.1 or 0.2% shift in the number of,
say Democrats or Republicans registered in an area.
-- Some of those races were tight.
-- They're all tight, man. It's basically,
well, I mean, some of them were decided by less than 1000 votes.
And
so even a minor shift there of like, just somehow getting those people not to vote
-- could be the deciding factor. It would,
-- it would be very significant.
But I think regardless of that,
there were events around this election involving
cyberattacks.
-- Well, the,
-- the, the DN
the Democratic National Convention Party, uh, you know, what is it?
John Podesta got hacked
with a targeted phishing email link where, yeah,
it was basically go click on this link to reset your password and he,
he sent it to the it guys and the it guys
meant to say, do not click that it's
a illegitimate link
and accidentally put
like it's a legitimate link. And so he clicked on it and entered his stuff and whoops.
Well, there you go. His email got hacked.
So, you know, it, it comes back to a lot of that.
Like, I'm worried more about these subtle influences where you don't,
you don't need to hack all the voting machines and like, be like, oh, you know, uh,
you know, co
boast the alien won by a landslide.
You know what
I voted for
king.
Yeah, exactly. I voted for the lesser of two evils.
But yeah, these, these more subtle hacks, like voter registration lists, uh,
things like, well, you know, like the republicans and the democratic conventions.
I mean,
there are some major choices being made there, like, which, you know,
candidate they're going to run,
which obviously are going to have a huge impact on the election, you know, like,
yeah, that's right.
And I think that's what, so, so, you know what,
this always reminds me of is metadata matters.
We, we obsess over,
I guess what we'll call the target where there's the one big thing we worry about,
but in reality,
that's not that important. If you can start doing things all around your target,
you can affect that, be it metadata or in this case,
releasing information, uh, about one party when let's face it, like they're both
terribly
releasing.
-- Right.
-- Exactly.
Releasing information so that people only get one part of the.
-- Right. Right. You know, exactly.
-- Like they're, they're all terrible. None of
them. One of them isn't way better than the other.
-- Oh,
-- I mean,
the reality is you go through anybody's email spool and you can find at least
one or two emails taken out of context that are going to get them fired.
I
have no doubt you could do that.
Absolutely.
It's, yeah, these, and, and the reality is though, I mean, the,
like I live in Canada and so we have, you know, it's nice.
We have a federally mandated election system that consists of,
here's a piece of paper with names on it and circles next to the names,
you make a cross in one of the circles, not two of the circles, not a check mark,
not a smiley face, not a poop emoji, but just an X.
Then you fold a piece of paper and
put it in the ballot box and you're done,
right? And that's
-- hard to hack, especially of scale,
-- remarkably efficient.
It is super efficient. It, voting is very quick typically.
But where things do fall down, for example,
is quite often students have trouble voting
because, you know, do they have ID that's local to the area, right?
They might be from out of province or, you know, and do they have like,
so then they're like, oh,
you can bring like a utility bill but like if you live in student housing,
you don't have a utility bill.
Voter ID, we could fill
hundreds of shows, especially in the United States around that topic.
Yeah.
So basically what it boils down to is pretty much every election
system is going to have this problem where there's all these like
extra systems that happen sort of before the voting
that, like I said, I think one or 2%
changes in them could seriously throw,
you know,
especially local elections that are hotly contested like that one we
had in Calgary where it was a one vote difference,
like the literal definition of democracy.
Oh, yeah, they had so many recounts.
Oh, my
-- goodness.
-- Because, like, yeah, they were like, we just, we can't believe this.
And, um,
you know, personally part of me likes, uh, what was it?
I think it was they do in some Middle Eastern countries
where basically you vote and you dip your thumb in ink.
Yes.
Right. Indelibly.
And it's like we don't care who you are, where you're from.
Just, you know, one person, one vote
on
time.
That type of voter fraud basically doesn't exist.
Well, but
in the sense of you could then get rid of all those extra ancillary systems.
-- They're now not needed. Like
-- we don't
need
to do
voter
registration.
No registration. Now, the, the downfall you
that is for
people to lose their minds. Right.
-- Right over someone carting people in from somewhere else to vote,
-- which again,
barely ever happens.
It would be more democratic to let anyone vote and dip their finger in ink.
But I think due to politics that would never catch on and let's face it.
It's all about politics. Right.
It's all about the politics which now this brings us to the next point
on the dark reading list
is they talk about balkanization of the internet, which
I don't think that even came up last year.
But I'm,
I'm wondering if the, the RNS um or if the DNC hack by, by Russia is going to
bring this conversation to the top,
I think. Yes and no. So there was a couple incidents of
countries taking themselves offline, uh, for whatever reason,
like they were rioting coup elections, that kind of thing going on.
But the majority of them came back online because I, the, the reality is you can't
not be on the internet anymore if you want to be part of the world,
if people want to take and give shipping orders, right.
Forcing them to go back to phone
lines.
This isn't exactly the same thing.
It's one thing when you have a essentially dictator,
government cut off the internet to prevent dissent.
But this is more
where governments try to pretend there's borders in the internet and you want like,
like the United States wants to keep out Russia.
Well, so for example, things like, um oh
jeez, I keep forgetting, I keep referencing it, Google's project.
Um The one with no,
essentially they,
they accept that their network is even their
internal networks are like essentially public networks.
And so they,
they stop pretending like they have a network perimeter
and they put the perimeter down like the application level
beyond
-- Corp,
-- beyond Corp. Yes.
Um You know,
things like the cloud security lines does uh
has a project too called software defined perimeters.
And the idea is
uh let's say you have a, a large application running in the cloud, right?
It's gonna have for the sake of it's gonna have a database, a middleware layer,
a presentation layer, a
logging piece you know, all, all that standard stuff that makes up an enterprise,
the app,
well, you don't control the network anymore. You know, it's in the cloud
so you can't really just stick a firewall in front of it.
So the idea is that you bring the firewall down to the
application level and essentially sort of create like an application level,
virtual private network so that the various pieces can talk to each other
and only to each other and anybody else trying to talk to them
doesn't have the right certificate or prime number key or whatever essentially.
And you know, just can't attack it until they
get through that first layer of encryption and authentication.
You know, and of course, if you deploy this properly,
it solves a whole bunch of problems.
That's not the balkanization of the internet.
That's like you, you're just segregating every single system.
Yeah. And I think that's what's going to happen is, you know,
-- smart companies like Google have already accepted this.
-- Yes. But, but
you're talking about a smart company and I'm
talking about what happens when some politician from
the middle of nowhere who thinks the internet is a series of tubes decides to say that
we shouldn't allow immigrant packets into the country
and that's just not gonna work.
We know that.
But the thing is, it's just, here's the thing, even if,
let's say for the sake of argument, we build the great firewall of America
of you know, the USA
and we block for the sake of argument. We block Russia.
Well, there, how do you deal with all the VPN providers?
Yes,
-- it is. Definitely. Right.
-- II, I pay, I think it's 10 bucks a month for who is it?
I think it's tour guard over,
like,
every plant, like, they're in every country on the planet.
You know, I think they have something like 1000 end points.
I don't even know or care to be honest.
And so
that's the thing. Right? Like, um, are we going to start, like,
you have to label packets
or, you know, by their geographic region
for the evil bit?
Yeah.
You know, well, we already have geographical IP databases but again, you know,
VPN providers, like,
and are you gonna block, you know, what's Amazon gonna do?
Right. Like
Amazon gonna
look, let's face the reality.
It can't be done.
And luckily it hasn't been talked about yet and let's hope
it doesn't get talked about because anyone with any freaking sense knows
it's completely ridiculous.
Right.
Well, it's not just ridiculous. It's,
and this is what I find really offensive. It's not cost effective.
There are better ways to deal with this. Yeah, definitely.
You know,
if it could work then I'd be like, well, maybe we should talk about it.
But the reality is even if you spent the money trying to make it work,
it wouldn't work.
Now, now
that actually leads to the, the one dark reading point I wanted to
get to in this discussion is,
it says a shake out of security industry, snake oil sales people.
It's not gonna happen, it'll never happen. Every industry is one of these guys.
It's just, it's how it is,
it's going, you know, again, that,
that security course I took on economics has been really
interesting because they actually cover this point a lot.
And basically what it boils down to is there is a huge level of information asymmetry
in the security product market,
you know, like uh antivirus is a great example.
How many viruses do you detect? That used to be a meaningful question?
Now, that question doesn't even mean anything because these guys are, you know,
auto
generating new viruses on the fly,
you know, or um and then, you know, Tavis Ormandy starts looking at the anti
virus
scanners and he's like, oh my God, you know,
these things have like unpack running in the kernel,
you know, because speed
or one of them used, what was it? Um
They changed some string operation to be the insecure one because it's faster.
-- Yeah.
-- Yeah, it was uh they used string copy instead of STRN or no string.
Was it string copy? But yeah, it was the STR versus the STRN variant
because it was like 1% faster.
Yeah,
and that is something that does get benchmarked on antivirus scans
is speed of scanning, you know,
so the reality is, and,
and the second problem too is you don't find out that the product is garbage until,
well after purchase.
Yes.
And, and let's face it too. I know. I, I read, I just read a thing the other day.
I don't remember where this was, but they were saying that
this, this group was recounting
the process of investigating purchasing a security product.
And they said at the end of the day, they just pick the sales guy, they like the best
of backup software, right?
Like until you actually do like a full disaster recovery level backup and restore,
you don't know if it works or not.
Right. Right.
Absolutely.
So,
no, the reality is, and, and even if you know, people get shaken out,
there's always newcomers with new products and
new technologies that are just garbage.
Like,
-- all
-- right. So no, let, let's, I'm gonna use this as a transition point.
Speaking of shakeouts and new technology is trend micro.
One of their predictions was ad blocking will
shake up the advertising business model and kill
mad advertisements.
Yeah, that's a big old
-- weird
-- to me. Is that
what I find the weirdest is that there's still
people who don't browse with an ad blocker,
but,
but it's not just that is the solution to
ad blocking wasn't to clean up the ad business.
It was to create ad blocker blockers, right? Like that's just,
and now,
now we all run ad blocker blocker blockers. Right.
And it's just gonna, like, it,
it's like insane section where we're just gonna
keep going another level deep where we're just,
they're going to get another level of ad blocking detection and
we're going to get another level of blocking their detection.
I, what's interesting to me is, I mean,
this whole advertising model basically exists because we
don't have micro payments or micro transactions to,
you know, so that the newspaper can make money when you read it. Right.
-- So
-- they computer with ransomware and I'll pay you. Yeah,
exactly.
It's fine.
You know.
And so I hate, I mean, part of me wants, for example, a good strong free press to,
you know,
dig out the nasty things politicians do and embarrass
them so they don't do it so much.
-- But this is
-- why I get the newspaper delivered to my house every day.
-- Yeah.
-- But I can't help but think that that might be a dead business model
and
it's totally dead business model. I would,
I, I don't know any young people.
I'm the only person I know under the age of like 50 that gets the,
the like dead tree newspaper brought to their home every day.
So, I don't know, maybe the future is more things like wikileaks or something I,
I can't say.
But, um,
yeah, I, you know, it's, I, I think like many people, they mean, well,
just their execution has been less than perfect.
It's,
it's very hard to do some of that stuff correctly.
And so I'm at least sensitive to that.
Right.
But, uh,
no, I think, um,
yeah, like the ad blocking thing, I mean,
like even mobile devices now support ad blockers like that was recently added
in Apple's IO si think last year the support for ad blockers and,
um,
I don't think Android is quite as friendly there for some reason.
Weird. Why would Google? not? Huh.
Weird.
But, yeah, I mean, because, and part of it for me now is I don't want ads on my devices,
not so much because of the ads, but just
the, the, I have a very finite amount of attention span.
Well, not only that they're so intrusive,
they take up so much space and they always
slow things down when they load that stupid ad.
Well, and the best is like right now on my ipad, because I have an old ipad.
I cannot put ad blocking on,
I get two youtube ads
and only two,
one is fake.
You know,
one of them is the government of Alberta ad on sustainable energy
and how great the carbon tax is and all that stuff,
which I actually agree with.
So, like, you can stop showing me the ad. I'm in favor of this
and the second ad is for some sort of
online financial service that, and I quote,
it's like having a bank in your own house and I'm like,
how else do you do banking anymore?
Like, of course,
it's like having a bank in your house because you have a laptop or a tablet or a phone.
And, like,
that's how people bank now.
Like, I paid the rent yesterday with, like, I was, like, on my phone.
I'm like, oh, I should go pay the rent.
Maybe the system has decided you're like, in your eighties
to
online
-- banking.
-- Yeah. Maybe, I don't know, maybe looking at,
yeah.
But, and, but the thing that kills me is I only see those two ads. That's it.
I don't see any other ads for last month.
It's funny you bring that up is so,
my wife and I were watching funny youtube videos one night on the couch and on our,
our smart TV, connected to the internet
and
they kept showing ads for, like,
really old people and it was clear that
the targeted demographic here was probably 60 plus
in the various products that
it was like 11 o'clock at night. I mean, it was pretty
late
and I just looked at her. I'm like, I have no idea what's going on right now. Like, why
Google knows who we are, right. Like, they know,
and
I will never purchase any of this crap that they're showing here.
It was, it was crazy.
Yeah.
No, I mean, it's, I've been reading about this because there's a lot more, you know,
people are looking at, like, brand influence instead of like, outright, you know,
getting you to click on it and buy something. Right.
So, putting that like ID in your head and,
and, but, you know,
the dirty secret is we have no idea how well this works if it works at all.
-- Right.
-- Well, you know, it does work. All right.
So I actually I told this to someone the other day is, I am doing
research
into a security topic and part of it has involved
me watching episodes of Star Trek the next generation.
Ok.
And I know this sounds hilarious.
Terrible security on that show.
Yeah, I know. Anyway. So it's part of it. Right. When I was a kid
I would watch Star Trek obviously on broadcast television
and they do the intro
and then they'd play, you know,
the little music and all that stuff and then it would go to a tide commercial
every single time.
-- And I
-- still,
when you say a tide commercial,
like
the laundry detergent,
a tide commercial.
And even now it's been like,
probably 25 years since I watched Star Trek on broadcast television.
I still wait for the tide commercial to play
when the intro. I'm, I'm totally serious. Like,
I, I understand the power of this stuff. Right.
Because, like,
I am now brainwashed that when I watch Star Trek
there's going to be a tide commercial after the intro.
Like, seriously.
Yeah, it works.
Yeah.
So I, I just,
I think the whole advertising model is gonna have to
evolve a bit and become a bit nicer because it,
it reminds me of, you know, every time I travel to America,
one thing you guys have that we don't is those giant roadside billboards
are
terrible. And we have big roadside billboards in Canada.
But they're not like on this, like,
like one or 200 ft tall poles.
You know what I mean?
-- Like those really tall ones, like,
-- like everything America does it best. Right.
Yeah.
-- And I just find that so bizarre and ugly. Oh, they're
-- terrible, man.
They're so annoying. I hate them all. So.
And, um, yeah, I mean,
what really gets me going and curious about the future is with augmented reality.
But we have ad blockers
because that would be lovely. Didn't,
it's already been done in the lab, essentially.
Some guy in Toronto was doing it. I think
there, well, there have been a handful of, of movies and, and TV,
shows that kind of deal with this where they
show augmented reality ads based upon who you are.
I didn't, didn't
we already see that?
There's, uh, the L CD billboards that, like,
look at kind of how old you are and stuff like that?
Sure. Yeah. And that's just real reality. Even
-- crazy, man. So
-- that's happening.
I mean, but, you know, I like the idea of having, like,
augmented reality and never seeing a mcdonald's again in my life.
I, that's
that would be interesting. You could,
yeah, you could block out a lot of things. Couldn't, don't show me fast food.
I don't want to see poor people anymore.
Or homeless people or that, that could be crazy.
Yeah, it'll happen. I mean,
oh, man.
Yeah, it'll be,
oh,
I, I could see a lot of bad coming of that because you could,
you could legitimately just hide the things you don't want to see.
Like, like you don't want to see hungry little kids begging for money.
Yeah, they look like park benches now. No big deal.
That's
right.
That's right. They're dogs jumping around. Uh,
they, man.
Yeah. No, thats
when I started thinking about some of this stuff, it's just like, II,
I have to stop and just
take a break from life.
They, they kind of covered this in. You ever watch Black Mirror?
I
do
the new, the latest season that just came out on Netflix.
They've got the, the war episode.
That kind of covers that where they use augmented
reality to make the enemy look like monsters.
I, I actually skipped that episode because I found it rather disturbing.
-- I still need to watch it. It's pretty
-- messed up. I'm not gonna lie to you.
I
saw where they were going.
Yeah,
that's one thing I like about Black Mirror.
It's the only show that legitimately makes
me feel uncomfortable watching it where,
especially some of the episodes where I'm like, yeah,
that's actually we could do that today.
That, that social media one. It was the first episode of the new season.
I'm like, that's like real, that's,
that's today.
Right. They just,
they basically just took what's happening now and they
-- added a little bit of a twist
-- to it.
Well, it, it's going on in China, right? With the, uh the, the,
the, the citizen,
right? So it's essentially that score of like, how good of a citizen are you? Are you
online?
You know?
So it's uh yeah, I mean, well, I mean, look at, you know, the US Customs, what is it?
Immigration, customs enforcement agency wants, you know,
access to people's social media profiles.
Y
yeah,
that's right. And currently it's just noncitizen but I mean, give it time. Right.
Boil the frog man.
Yeah. So,
yeah, like I know returning to Canada,
the Canada Border Services agency has every single
right to go through all my electronic devices and
ask for my passwords and if I don't give it to them then that's a problem.
Uh What,
what they can do is they can just be like, ok, you don't get your devices back,
you know, because we want to know what's on them,
-- you know. And so like, yeah, I tend to wipe stuff or
-- I don't, I don't
very sanitized.
I purposely,
I,
I've got clean gear anytime I go through an airport
because I know that this is certainly a risk.
Oh, yeah. My traveling laptop is so boring.
Yeah.
Right. Right. Yep. Exactly.
But again, with the way cloud works now it's,
it's not like it used to be.
I mean, I guess funny enough the,
now that the authorities care about this kind of stuff, it's kind of irrelevant.
Well, yeah, I mean, the, the reality is like, I mean, oh, a great example is my, like,
my photos, I don't keep my photos on my devices anymore.
It's, they're not big enough,
-- you know,
-- I have
is I have my photos backed up in several locations because
one of my fears is I've heard stories of like Google
deciding you're a bad person and they just kill your account
and like it's gone and you don't get it back.
And so that's one of the things I obsess over is
making sure I have good backups of that kind of stuff.
And
that's where II I don't know what the Apple policy is,
but I imagine it's similar where you could just lose it all.
I assume there are things you could do to get Apple angry at you. So
quite honestly, part of it is I try to, I make sure I don't do anything naughty or,
you know, that could be perceived as like evil and quite honestly with Apple,
that's pretty easy because they don't like sell compute services or anything.
So,
yeah,
so, but yeah, no, I mean, that, that is a good point.
Like if Apple decided I was a non entity that would be very, very inconvenient for me.
Yeah.
Yeah, totally, man.
So, all right,
I guess here's the point is let, let's kind of bring this one home.
Now is I looked through this list and I'll put the, the,
the links to these lists in the show notes.
Um, open source security podcast.com again,
but
a remarkable number of these just didn't come true.
And so I think
the thing, the takeaway here and this is something to think about for 2017
is the fact that we suck at predicting the
future because the future is so incredibly unpredictable.
And so I think the things we expect to happen in 2017 are almost certainly
things that will not happen in 2017 and that's almost terrifying to think about.
Well, I think a large part of it too is we,
we look at making predictions from like a technical
perspective and we just ignore the economics of it,
you know,
like fundamentally all behavior boils down to is there's got
to be some driving motivation to do this behavior,
right?
Ransomware, get money. OK. Clear, simple, clean, effective,
you know,
um cloud flare, you know, prognosticating the DDOS
attacks in 2017 will like hit a terabyte.
Well, that's just a linear extrapolation fit of a graph, right? That's
not,
that's literally taking a ruler on a piece of
paper and drawing the line and going like,
oh, we hit one terabyte,
you know.
That's, yeah, it's a prediction, technically speaking,
but it's like saying the sun will come up,
you know, it's pretty safe. It's probably gonna happen,
you know.
And what I'm really curious about is like, sort of what of, you know,
of these criminal business models,
what new criminal business models and things are gonna come up
in the next, you know,
year or two years or three years because
that is what's gonna fundamentally shift things.
And
I'm really curious about things like with the IOT, you know,
obviously
ddos that's gonna work. That's boring. You know, that's a
known
problem
right there. There's no bit of
money
to do it.
Not a lot of money. Right.
And so, you know, they're gonna,
but somebody is going to find a killer app for it and go with it
-- and that's what
-- I'm really curious to know.
You know, if I want, if I want to have a prediction here is I will say
we are not going to see
ddos monetized.
We're going to see someone figure out what they can
do with all these zombie devices because let's face it.
The, someone wrote a clever botnet that can just use these devices to D
OS,
but I suspect people are going to find something
they can do with these that will generate revenue
and they're going to do it and it's gonna be crazy when they do.
Yeah. No, I agree.
I mean, uh, some things would like, maybe drive up power consumption.
I, you know, buy shares and energy companies.
It won't be that subtle. I think it'll be more direct. It'll be very ransomware.
Ask where you get immediate returns because let's face it too.
When you're dealing with criminal activity,
you need fast returns. That's not the long game. I mean, you need to get in,
get your money and get out. Right.
And, and because you're, you're going to either get arrested or shut down,
that's the reality of it.
It's not a long term growth.
What I wonder though too is I always wonder,
are there these criminals taking a long soft
approach that we just will never know about?
Yeah, they're called Wall Street executives.
But
two
1008 housing crisis was a giant redistribution of weal
given the nature of, of criminal activity.
I, I just don't see anyone having the foresight or patience
to have any sort of long term criminal business model.
Right.
It's, I could see it being very rare if at all.
II, I don't like speaking in absolutes, but I think in this case, I,
I don't think they exist.
I just don't.
And of course, now we have someone listening, laughing because they've been,
you know,
running their criminal enterprise for 27 years under the radar.
But it's like I said, it's just, it's like start up culture, right?
Get in, make your money, get out. That's the only way to look at
it.
All right, man.
2017. Here we come. Right.
And I think it's safe to say that,
that it was very easy picking on all the 2016 predictions.
I cannot wait to mock the 2017 predictions next year
because why not?
Yeah, I guess if nothing else, everybody thank you for listening again.
The, the website is open source security podcast.com.
We'll have all the show notes there and you can hit
us up on Twitter with the Pound Os S Podcast.
Hashtag
And
if nothing else, you all have a fantastic year.
Let's hope we all get enough rest after staying up far too late. And
Kurt, you take care of yourself.
You too.