Hello and welcome to episode 122 of the open source security podcast with myself,
-- Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh
-- Pressers.
What's new man?
Uh Apple has some nice shiny new products.
They, they do.
Actually, there was,
there was an announcement about some of their new stuff and we decided we
should talk about their T two security chip which while not open source is security
and
not even
close to open.
However, however,
the one thing that, that I'm telling myself uh potentially is a lie,
but I don't think so is that this is technology we're going to be
seeing all over the place in a couple of years because I think what,
what Apple's doing here will change the game enough
that it's going to make a difference.
Now,
all of you people screaming T PM at your phone or whatever you're listening to us on.
No, no A T PM sucks. And this actually looks like it might work. So all
X
why,
why don't you start us off by just kind of
running through a brief overview of what this thing is.
So the T two security chip is an actual, like,
separate physical chip that is on the motherboard of your, um, new Apple air.
-- And I believe we
-- should also specify. It's, it's a custom chip.
-- It's
-- only Apple has this. Like, they, they,
they built it
-- and, and yes, it's the airs and the,
-- well, they didn't build it.
They, they designed it and they had it built for them.
Well. Right. Yes,
nobody builds anything anymore. Right. You design things.
Right. Right.
And, and yes,
you are correct that this is on the Airs and the pros
and for what it's worth some of this functionality already exists today
in iphones and even things like the surface tablets from Microsoft but not,
not on this level.
Well, and part of it is because those things slightly different attack vectors.
But regardless, so the T two security chip
I think is pretty nifty.
The old style was, oh, physical attacks came over. Right. That was always the man
if somebody physically controls your device game over. Well, you know what?
That's not good enough anymore because I have a computer in my pocket, my phone
that has my entire life on there. My last pass, my Google everything
and, you know, at some point I probably will lose physical control of it.
I'll get mugged.
You know, if somebody points a gun at me and says, give me your phone,
my answer will be yes.
-- Like here it is. Take
-- it from,
you know,
um And I still want that damn thing to be secure.
I think that's fair.
So the T two security chip essentially covers
sort of, well,
two really important things which is encryption of the local data storage.
So the uh well, whatever the SSD or whatever it's called now on a, on a Mac
and the secure boot. So essentially, uh if you have the secure boot enabled,
even with physical access to your device,
I can't monkey with it. Right.
I, I must have your biometrics or I must have your password
to get this machine turned on and, and decrypted and running.
It's even more than that.
You can, you can make it so you can't even boot off of external media
because I mean, so like today,
the evil maid style attacks that are talked about is basically someone shows up,
they boot your computer with a special flash drive.
And let's say you have an encrypted hard drive.
Well, they could monkey with your bios still and maybe have a bad bios
that could, you know, steal your passwords or even some data later.
And, and there are things like T PM modules and secure boot
that can do this to a degree,
but making them work correctly is a freaking nightmare.
Yeah.
And, and for those of you saying the evil maid attack is theoretical.
So back in, yeah, here we go 2003 Poker sharks laptop owned by evil maid attack.
Professional poker player, Jens K,
I'm sorry, I butchered that
learned a lesson about
security earlier this year.
Don't leave your computer unattended without securing it first.
Not even in your hotel room.
Now, realistically, I, when I travel,
I leave my laptop in my hotel room all the time because like,
I don't want to carry it when I'm going to,
-- you know, an evening function where there's, I
-- almost never leave it behind.
In fact, I have a chromebook I travel with for this purpose.
If I know the laptop will leave my site,
I bring the chromebook.
Whereas if I know I will have it on me at all times,
I might consider bringing my Macbook.
Yeah.
But so this basically the T two in theory, assuming it works as advertised,
basically solves this
to a degree,
it makes the attack significantly more difficult.
Um like nation state level difficult.
So, well, why don't we start? So the first thing the T two chip does
is it has what's called the secure enclave.
Now, we've heard about this in the iphone and elsewhere.
And the secure enclave very simply put is the computer chip has
uh a small
area that is, well, it's a secure enclave,
like that's where the encryption keys live,
they're generated securely.
So this thing has a really, apparently a really good, you know,
cryptographically secure random number generator which, you know,
we've talked about in the past.
It
is.
Um
And so it'll generate the keys
and more importantly,
it stores the keys in a way that also makes it very easy for it to delete those keys.
So,
you know, if you do lose physical access or physical control of your laptop,
you know, you can do the,
find my iphone or find my uh my apple air and tell it to a remote wipe, right?
And all that device has to do is not churn through all the data on the hard drive,
but simply delete a couple of very small A es encryption keys.
You know, in the secure chip, this chip
makes it very like essentially extracting those keys from the
chip would require a physical attack against the chip itself,
you know,
which
possible. But we're talking nation state
level attacks, not a mugger.
It's, it's even man, even if you're a nation state, it also means you have to,
it's the sort of attack that's going to take a significant amount of time.
So you can not
during trying to do one of these sort of operations,
you also have a very high
probability of just like accidentally breaking everything
and
it takes days to weeks to mount.
This isn't one of those sneak into the hotel room quick through this attack and then
like
your
computer
at this point,
it's probably easier just to kidnap the guy with his laptop and
beat him with a stick until he puts his thumb on it.
Exactly.
Not that we're advocating for that.
But uh yeah, so, so the T two has a secure enclave with the encryption keys,
the encryption keys, theoretically speaking, just cannot be removed.
So that essentially means now that if you encrypt your
data,
uh you know, at the volume level
on your ma
air,
it's tied to those keys in that T two chip. So even if somebody, you know,
steals the media out of your laptop,
they can't access it because they don't have those encryption keys.
And that means also that, that,
that data that's encrypted is now tied tightly to that T two chip.
Like you can't,
you can't get access to that data without that T two chip.
And the T two chip itself has protections.
It's worth pointing out that the flash storage
on the macbooks is soldered onto the board.
So
you can't steal the hard drive
it out,
right? It's,
-- it's pretty much, this stuff is all connected.
-- Yeah.
Well, and, and so this is important to keep in mind, you know, if your T two chip fails,
then you're, well, I hope you had a backup of your data.
That's right.
But it's OK. It's on an unencrypted hard drive in my desk, right?
Don't tell anyone.
Yeah.
So,
so basically that secure enclave is what allows the chip
to do a bunch of magic with encryption keys.
Very, very, very securely.
One of those things being
storage, encryption,
something that isn't clear to me on this secure enclave is like the
Intel chips have a
similar function. The SGX
which is
meant to
SGX is not, well, SGX is a form of secure enclave, but it's actually for
processing not for
pure key storage.
And
that's
very
much what
I I have a suspicion that T two chip doesn't allow arbitrary code execution.
It
-- is important.
-- Well,
so the, the way APPLE uses the secure enclave is they're referring simply to
key generation storage and management.
As far as I know, that's all their secure enclave does.
The Intel SGX
is
allowing code and data to be executed
um free from disclosure or modification. So a great example of this
is uh there's a, there's a Blockchain from the Hyper
Ledger uh consortium or whatever it's called called uh poet proof of a lapse time.
And it's very efficient because essentially
the way it works is all the nodes in the Blockchain
run this little bit of code in the SGX that
waits a random amount of time and whoever waits,
waits the shortest amount of time,
wins the election and gets to generate a block.
And you know, there's protections against people
having like a fake SGX and always winning and cheating.
But fundamentally, this means that you now have a Blockchain technology that's
like really efficient because
it's the shortest waiting time.
And it's, you know, you're typically measuring that in milliseconds,
you know, whereas with Blockchain, you're like,
you're what is it the, the Denmark?
Now, the the electrical version of Denmark
is churning away on, you know, shot signatures.
Um So
-- with this electricity turned it into pretend money.
-- Yeah.
So, so Apple's secure enclave is a very
specific limited use case, which I
think is
it's not that Intel is doing it wrong,
it's that Intel is solving a completely different problem and just
right,
and there's a more important aspect of this is by by making it very specific,
you've reduced your attack surface by several magnitudes.
Whereas Intel's attack surface and SGX is infinity, right
versus
apple, which has a finite attack surface now.
And so having these,
these keys that allow you to be very sure that these keys are unique to this chip and
secure allows you to do obviously data encryption,
but it also allows you to do secure, boot very securely.
Um And the T two chip also apparently has some magic to,
you know, enforce the boot process.
So yeah, even if you boot off of some external thing,
you know the T two chips like Nope, that's not allowed, sorry, you,
you're not allowed to do that because I control access to
the USB or to the whatever, right.
And so looking at this, sorry.
So basically you got your boot ROM evaluates the ibot signature.
The ibot evaluates the T two kernel cache
signatures,
the T two kernel cache
uh evaluates the UEF I firmware signature and then the UF,
the UEF I firmware
uh happens and those four steps happen in the T two chip,
like they physically occur in the T two chip,
then it hands it over essentially to the, the CPU
and hands it the UEF I firmware,
you know,
um
and it, it boots,
right? So essentially
the T two chip is evaluating and
uh validating the security of what you're asking it to boot off of,
you know, if you've,
here's one of the interesting things about the way this all works is they
say here in their document which we of course link to in the show notes
that the T two chip has an immutable boot rom embedded in it.
And that means that it obviously starts up and executes this ROM and it can,
it can never be changed because obviously having
the ability to change it would be and it
an attack.
And right.
And so that's the trick is if anyone, if any researchers ever find a,
a problem with this boot ram and let's face it, I think they will someday.
Now most of these T two chips depending
upon the attack could be rendered completely useless,
-- which
-- is
hilarious,
is super simplistic and all it does is check
the signature of a larger blob that can be updated.
I'm not going to claim anything is perfect and
even that can be
-- smart.
-- Yeah,
even that can be screwed up. But,
but the beauty is
to remind everybody,
your T two chip has the encryption keys.
If you encrypt your hard drive, so that T two chip is tied to that laptop.
So if you take that T two chip out
and monkey with it and break it,
that laptop is dead
and it's not like you can take a T two chip out of one laptop monkey with it,
put it into your,
you know, victim's laptop boot
and access the data. Right.
That's the beauty is the T two chip and the data are, if you do the,
the drive level encryption,
-- that T two chip and that data are now tied together, you don't
-- have a choice.
So the way they've done this, that's really cool
is the T two chip sits between the, the regular processor and
your, your flash memory.
And what happens is even if you don't set a password for encrypting your disk,
your disk is still encrypted with a random key inside of that T two chip.
Meaning
like literally if you pull the T two chip out, put a new one in which I don't, I,
-- I suspect that's not possible, but let's just pretend
-- to
sure.
But anyway, like your,
your computer doesn't work anymore because the new T
two chip would have a different key in it,
which is freaking awesome.
You just have to reinstall the US and everything.
-- Right.
-- Right. But
here's the thing and this,
this is the thing that has me most excited.
So today, the way disc encryption works
is
on the first bit of the hard drive,
you'll have a special key and then your password unlocks that key.
But all of these operations are happening in CPU and in regular memory.
And so there's always like the cold boot attacks
and all these other things where you can easily acquire
the key that's being used. And likewise,
if you have the hard drive, like the key is there,
you just need the password to unlock it.
And in this instance,
now this is kind of like the equivalent of two factor authentication.
Well, and that's the thing that allows brute force attacks.
Right.
-- Right. Exactly.
-- Exactly.
Defeat
it does because you can try what 90 times essentially and then it just cooks itself.
-- It's a
-- little, there's so my understanding was uh blah, blah, blah. Here we go.
You get 10
attempts to log in
to prevent malware from causing permanent data loss
by trying to attack the user password.
These limits are not enforced after the user has successfully logged into the Mac.
So,
um but will be reimposed after a reboot. So, but basically,
uh then you get, you get 10 attempts, then you get like 30 more attempts
and then you get 10 more attempts through Mac Os recovery.
Uh And then you get 30 more attempts
for each uh thing.
So if you have file vault recovery enabled, you get 30 more attempts.
So if you have icloud recovery enabled,
you get 30 more attempts and 30 more attempts.
And if you have file vault recovery key enabled
and institutional key,
you get 30 more attempts for a maximum of 90 possible attempts.
And it's also important to note
that there's a delay between the password attempts.
So attempts one through 14, there's no delay
attempts.
15 through 17, 1 minute, 18 through 25 minutes, 21 to 26 15 minutes, 27 to 31 hour.
So,
and I assume past 30 it's an hour. I don't know. But regardless it's, it's that,
yeah, you have a, a finite number of tries
to get it right.
And then the device is like, sorry, no.
And,
and
again,
you know, short of like, somehow pulling the T two chip out of the system
and doing some sort of physical attack on it to reset that counter.
You can't,
if you can, if you can reset the counter, you can probably just read the.
Exactly. Exactly. So,
you know, at this point now we're back to the whole, well, yeah,
just pull the T two chip out of there and, like, get the data out of it.
This is a,
you know, this is a nontrivial task.
It is theoretically. It is definitely possible.
But,
-- you know, if I had to bet money, I wouldn't bet for it.
-- The bar gets raised so high
that
it is an
impossible attack for,
for most Attackers and here's the thing that I always keep thinking of.
The purpose of all this technology isn't necessarily to 100% stop Attackers.
The real purpose is this technology is just to know you're being messed with,
right? If your laptop's gone, you know, you've been messed with.
If there's someone like literally trying to force
you to touch something to unlock it,
like, you know, you're being messed with, right?
The danger is the unknown of leaving something say
in a hotel room and coming back and saying
I didn't leave it there. What just happened?
Well, fundamentally this raises the bar to it's less effort to just kidnap the guy
or girl with their laptop.
-- Stop telling people to do that. But
-- that's the thing, right? Is at that point,
the open
-- source security podcast does not condone
-- kidnapping.
But basically at that point, Apple can say they've done a reasonable job.
I, you know, I, I would,
-- I, I,
-- I agree. I agree completely.
Yeah.
So the other thing they've done that I really like and well, I,
I don't want to argue about this because you
have a differing opinion of how this works.
But fundamentally when you close the lid on your Mac Air, now,
the T two chip or something associated with it
because it's apparently not 100% clear in the document disables the microphone.
I'm going to say they don't use a T two chip and, and this is why
because first of all, if the microphone is connected to the chip,
that seems like a stupid over engineering and more importantly
is the way this is written and here it is,
it says all Mac portables with the Apple T two security chip feature,
a hardware disconnect.
They don't say
that the T two T two chip is a disconnect.
And I would also argue that if, if it say,
say you do have a wire going to the T two chip and that's expected to do something,
I would not say turning it off via using
switches in the chip counts as a hardware disconnect.
Whereas a literal switch
in the lid that when you close it, a magnet opens a switch
-- that is a hardware disconnect
-- regardless the point is that
is no argue this with me.
Come on,
I'm just more impressed that they've finally done this because,
you know,
I've seen also reports that,
you know, the accelerometers in some of these phones now are sensitive
sensitive enough that they can put the vibrations of your voice.
Definitely. Or, or the I read one about our keyboards
where using the accelerate because let's face it like my phone
is literally sitting what two inches from my keyboard maybe.
And, and using the accelerometer,
you can measure how I'm tapping the keyboard to
guess what the keys I'm going to type are,
which is very cool.
Yeah, and I'm wondering do the Apple Airs have
accelerometers and motion sensors. I know like
the stuff with physical spinning hard drives used to have those like drop sensors.
But
-- right,
-- II,
I did try to research this actually before the
show and I couldn't find any references to it,
-- which leads me to believe they
-- do not, they definitely have a sudden motion sensor.
That's like the drop sensor. But again, how sensitive that is?
Oh,
it is a tri
-- axle accelerometer. So. hm. Yeah. Well, which
-- is not sensitive enough.
You need a gyroscope to be that sensitive. Do you?
I don't know, man, some of these things are pretty crazy sensitive. Now,
all the research I've seen relies on
gyroscopes. So I'm going to stand by all the research I've seen
and I imagine
it I'm wrong and if I'm not wrong, someone will find a way to do this soon.
So actually you can just apparently type in PM set hyphen G
as root
and it will tell you
if you have a sudden motion uh S MS
and my IMAC does not, which would make sense.
Hopefully you're not dropping your um or sorry, my Mac mini
does not have one but my Macbook or my Mac Air doesn't
-- no weird.
-- I
I wouldn't expect them to anymore just because
new systems don't have spinning disk,
right?
And,
and really the drop sensor was so you could park
the hard drive heads is all it was really for
and, and it doesn't matter anymore. Because it's all solid state now.
Like, drop away.
-- In fact, that's funny
-- because, and again,
we're not advocating people drop their computers.
No,
no, no. You know what the problem is though?
So, like, my wife had a spinning disk in her old Mac
and at least once a year I was replacing it because she was notorious for dropping it.
Never far enough to break it, but always far enough to ruin the hard drive.
And yeah, like even with the drop sensor, it clearly didn't, wasn't doing its job.
And now she has a solid state drive, uh, everything is fine and the case is dented.
So I think it's been dropped from even higher,
but at least the drive is fine.
Oh, yeah. No, my, my Mac here actually
has like a really solid crease dent in the edge of it.
I, I don't know what I did to it, but I must have been
like,
yeah, it's, uh,
anyways and here's the beautiful part too for all the
people like yelling about T PM and like secure boot,
you know, they're locking and in fairness.
So you can only use the secure, the secure boot with Mac Os and with windows.
So if you want to run Linux with secure boot, you're, you're out of luck,
but you can disable the secure boot if you want to run Linux, for example, on your Mac,
I want to clarify something about secure boot though before we go on is,
is.
So in the Windows world,
there are two C A keys they use because you could like Fedora and Ubuntu are signed.
You can, you can boot them with secure boot enabled hardware.
There are two Cas Microsoft has,
there's the C A Microsoft uses for Windows and
there's ac A they use for everyone else.
And apple is explicit in this document that they
only support the C A used for Windows.
They don't support the partner C A.
So,
yeah. Yeah.
All you people thinking but, but Fedora's got, it's signed for secure boot.
It is, but it won't work out
well. And realistically, the number of people that's going to affect is
not a lot. And
I
talking about a company that made a phone and told people they're holding it wrong.
So, quite frankly, you know, the entire Fedora community could try and
-- pitchfork mob them and I don't think I will care.
-- Right.
No, I don't think they will. And, and my, my suspicion is you can't even run Linux
on the brand new macbooks
because goodness knows they probably have
some incredibly wonky hardware inside that,
that just not enough people care.
But uh no, overall I'm happy with what this T two chips is doing because also,
uh they've made it easy,
right?
I mean,
I remember diddling around with secure boot and UEF I
and whatever when it first came out and like,
oh my goodness,
it's terrible.
I turned it
off.
That's
what I ended up doing when I had PC si just ended up disabling it because
stuff would just randomly break or not work.
Um,
oh, and there is one more thing the, um,
the, the T two chip does,
uh some of the stuff now with the touch ID sensor.
And again, so this is nice because it means for example, that, you know, you're,
the problem with biometric data is you generally
can't change it that easily unless you're like
really hardcore committed to like burning your fingertips
-- with a soldering iron and changing
-- your fingerprints,
you can't change it.
Just say you can't change it. Actually, you know what's funny?
I burnt my finger really bad on my 3d printer the other day
and, and II, I wonder, I actually, it's one of the wrong fingers.
What I, what I need to do is add all my fingers to my fingerprint reader on my phone.
And next time I, I like horribly burn myself,
I can see
badly burn your finger. It'll be fine because, you know, it's looking up
like you can because you can get like little cuts and
stuff on your finger and your fingerprint reader don't care.
Like because I,
I'm not gonna say which fingers I've registered but, you know,
I don't have all my fingers fingers registered
and yeah, you know, like my hands get beat up and
my phone seems happy with it.
But, um,
the nice thing is, you know, this is
again, the T two chip is
storing and processing this data.
So it's not hitting
the main CPU or the main memory
unencrypted,
you know.
Uh Right.
And it,
it sounds like from reading it and I must also interject at this point
that I feel like we've said the word T two chip a lot.
But anyway, uh right, it sounds like what happens is you scan your fingerprint
and then it kind of uses that data to decrypt a different key
in chip and then that is used to do stuff in that way.
Your fingerprint isn't like you said, going into ra M where
potentially be sniffed or stolen.
And well, and more of the point, you know, it can't be replayed, right?
Because talking to the T two chip only, well,
I'm going to assume the T two chip is smart enough to go.
I only take fingerprint data from the fingerprint sensor, right?
-- I would hope so,
-- you know, whereas if it's coming into the CPU, the CPU is kind of like,
yeah, whatever data is data.
I, I would, I would hope that is true.
I,
I don't like to assume anything just because we've seen it all.
But that, that does sound like it makes sense. Yes.
Well, more to the point Apple is not a stupid company and
I think they fully understand that, you know, if they make,
if they screw this T two chip up, that's going to be expensive
for them to fix
probably, you know,
because it'll be a case of bring your laptop and swap it for a new one.
Uh,
and then all the old ones go back to China to
be de soldered and a new T two chip put on them
because that's the failure mode for a T two chip. Right, as well. It failed.
Sorry about your data. Say goodbye. Have a good cry. Here's your new laptop.
Right. Right. And, and actually that's,
that's going to happen, right.
Some,
some number of these will fail and you're going to
be left with a brick if it does because they,
they've integrated this so deeply into the hardware, which is,
that is interesting.
And that's one of the things I know, like with TP MS, you can replace T PM
and fundamentally,
although you're kind of in the same,
for example icloud backup is so easy. Like you, you log in,
that's it, there's no step to it.
Uh like unless you're like me,
you maybe need to go buy more storage because you have more than five gigs of stuff.
But fundamentally, you know, for people's core data,
like their address book and you know, their favorite photos and stuff
by default, all that stuff is safe and you know,
the extra storage is not that expensive or you just get
an external hard drive and do your time machine backup.
Right.
Right. Right.
I wonder if this will let you do external drive backups or, I mean,
external drive encryption,
but still rely on the functionality of this chip because if it does,
that would be really freaking cool.
Uh That's a good question. I
don't know.
-- I
-- bet it doesn't because from the thing is I've read,
it sounds like it's not in a position to be doing that.
And additionally, that means you'd have to basically feed USB through the chip,
which
the key storage on the chip.
Uh And that might happen, right? You could do something like that.
Although then the key is still going to be in memory
at which point you're not really gaining anything for yourself.
This
is a
S encryption and
it might actually, it does do a
because
each chip has a 256 bit AES key
that's burned into each process for manufacturing time.
It can't be read by firmware software and used
only by the T two chips hardware AES engine.
So yeah, it has an AES engine. So
you, you just shove your AES data through that T two chip up. What is it like?
Usually there are 10 gigs per second now for an AES chip.
I'm, I'm sure it's pretty fast,
right?
So,
no, that's cool. That's cool. And, and that's,
again, I'm, I'll be excited when this comes to all of the hardware,
which I think it certainly will and you don't think it will
I think it'll come to Apple,
obviously. I think it will come to chromebooks
and it might come to more business laptops.
-- I bet the surface season. Yeah.
-- And I was going to say that the
surface are pretty good.
Um,
the, the
Microsoft Mobile,
it is conceivable
and you might not be wrong because I know if you look at
a lot of the consumer hardware, it's, it's pretty bad
and their goal is actually to not have to help you.
They don't want you to call them and ask for
help and putting in a security chip would certainly,
we'll say, create a situation where you probably need help
where something like a chromebook or even a
surface book and special Apple's products are in
insanely walled garden.
Right?
And that, that makes it a little different with respect to
kind of how things work.
You don't, you don't have options, you do it their way or you shut up and leave,
which is
not very open source friendly, but
on the other hand, my fonts display correctly.
Yeah,
we talk
about that.
We were,
I was complaining to Kurt the other day about trying to use a high DP I screen in Linux.
And let's just say he laughed at me a lot
and, and my solution was to just turn my resolution way down.
So
I, I'll let I'll let the listener figure out what that all means.
Ah,
I think it also shows it's possible to do this at scale. Right.
Because I've seen a lot of,
there's oftentimes a lot of security hardware stuff where people are,
like they poo poo it because, oh, that's nice.
And it's too expensive.
We can't do it widespread or we could do it widespread but it's too hard to use or blah,
blah, blah.
And this clearly shows,
no, you, you can do it
right.
-- It's possible.
-- Yeah.
Yeah.
It, it, it is. It, well, I guess we're going to find out if it is.
I,
I have a feeling it's gonna work out. Ok.
So anyway, I guess in summary, well done Apple,
I can't wait to see this everywhere else
because I think these are awesome features and they
will definitely make a computer far more secure.
And I'm also glad
that I've not bought a new laptop recently because
this definitely makes me rethink buying a Mac.
Like II,
I hate Os X for the most part because I find it annoying for a variety of reasons.
-- But this might make me ignore my hate
-- that, say what you will about.
Like I'm, I'm, I use Mac Os daily, whatever it's an operating system.
But the hardware man,
like my hardware now is all six years old and it just still keeps chugging along fine.
You know, it's like it's fast enough, especially now with the cloud, right?
Because I can move all the heavy lifting into the cloud.
That's, that's not because of
that just because Moore's law has failed us.
Right?
No, but I mean, the apple build quality, I mean, a great example is Nintendo, right?
I pulled my Nintendo wii
it was sitting in a box in the garage for like 10 years,
like in a plastic box bin, whatever you call it.
And I basically just pulled it out, kind of blew the dust off of it, plugged it all in,
uh, realized I needed to buy that HDM. I adapter thing because like
TV, S in the last 10 years no longer have the um
is that the stupid thing with four cables,
the,
the, the four cables that's R GB with four cables and most TV s have those.
But the, the Wii doesn't do HDM.
-- I, the wii U does HDM
-- I for 23 bucks, you get an adapter that makes it do HDM. I,
-- but
-- does that give you too much lag?
So, so here's the problem. Actually, I can, I, I have,
I know more about this than I want to.
So I bought my first flat screen TV. I plugged my wii into it
and I went to play guitar hero
and like I failed
and I'm like, what's going on here?
And it turned out that uh L CDT vs have a certain amount of lag
to them and you can obviously
on game mode then and everything would be fine.
But my concern with trying to convert from the Wii to HDMIS,
you're going to have some on a leg doing the conversion
from what's essentially an analog signal into a digital signal.
I, I literally
spent like 23 bucks on this thing. And
-- now,
-- ok. Yes.
But now I want you to spend several $100 buying guitar hero.
-- And then tell me if it works,
-- I
mostly
play
that.
I
play Wii sports with the sword fighting and yeah, any leg there and you're hooped.
That's fair. And I do love wii sports. But
no, I do agree with you that,
that the Nintendo build quality is very good and being an enormous Nintendo fan.
Boy, that I am.
It, it,
I still own every Nintendo system I've ever bought and
I still use them ironically and they all work.
And in fact,
I've never even replaced any of the batteries in the stuff that has rechargeable.
I have like one of the old Nintendo
gameboy Advance SPS. It looks like an Nes. It's very nice
and like the battery still holds a charge for it.
Slightly less than it did, but still a respectable amount of time.
And that thing's well over 10 years old.
-- And
-- that's another thing. My Apple Air, I still get eight hours out of it.
I don't get the full 10 hours I used to get, but
eight hours, six years later, that's
like
six years ago. I wasn't,
I wasn't getting eight hours out of.
So. So anyway, anyway,
in summary.
Uh well done. Apple.
Everyone else copied these guys because they're onto something cool
and, and that's, I guess where we'll leave it. So I guess thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com.
You can find the show notes there.
Hit us up on social media with the Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag
And, and yeah, if there are any fellow Nintendo fan boys out there, like,
like hit me up, we can maybe play some Mario Kart or something someday.
-- So, yeah, Kurt have a great day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody. Thank you.
Bye bye.