Hello and welcome to episode 71 of the open source security podcast
with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime. Josh Bresser.
I am so excited. Kurt.
We actually have some good news to talk about, like for the first time ever. Maybe.
Yeah.
Well, probably it,
it's not the first time ever but,
but we, we do tend to talk about bad things and, and we'll get to some more bad things.
But no, no, I'm excited about the github
security scanner.
Yeah.
-- No, that's actually really exciting. It's
-- super awesome.
So, would you like to explain it or shall I?
Uh Well? Ok. Um I can.
So as you know, github hosts a lot of code,
like a lot, a lot, a little
bit
and more to the point.
Github
encourages people to uh fork code,
right? Uh You can basically take a project, fork it
and then monkey around with the code on sort of your own side
for your own need.
Uh And if you want, you can also, you know,
uh do a poll request or merge it back into the upstream one
and make code better for everybody.
Um
And a lot of modern
languages and code uh especially things like go no Js, you know, those guys
really have a heavy model of
uh libraries that you
import and use
um quite often for like really, really core stuff.
And so like a lot of these projects kind of really end up
basically being just a bit of glue with a whole pile of imports,
which is
we should clarify that when we say import,
we mean basically copy the code into your own project.
Yeah.
Yeah, sorry, like a literal,
like not an import space something but an actual like cut and paste or copy of the
the the raw source files in.
And so the problem becomes then is if you have a
flaw on a piece of code that is widely copied,
forked, imported, whatever,
how do you tell everybody?
And the answer is traditionally we don't,
-- it's a simple solution.
-- It is and, and you're absolutely correct,
right?
I mean,
because part of the problem was until recently
figuring out where did that code go is,
is really quite difficult, right?
Because a great example is like um
Gzip, right? Very nice little compression utility
not available by default on windows.
So a lot of UNIX programs that use J Zip has ship a copy of it
with their source code so that the copy like the code will build on Windows.
So the problem becomes when there was like that Fla
gzip that resulted in a denial service, whatever, you know. How do you mean Z
Lib?
Uh,
no, some of them just actually tossed in the whole G
and that's fair.
Yeah, you, you would hope that they, I think a lot of them,
these people actually don't even know Zed Lib exists,
right? They just think of G zip the command line and they're like, cool. Grab that.
Right.
Um Anyway, so, yeah, long story short, they either grab
Gzip or
Zed
Lib or whatever,
jammed it into their source code so that, you know,
now you can have your VPN decompress and compressed data or whatever, you know,
data,
you can make data smaller easily.
And um you know, it's quietly forgotten about and how do you detect this?
Well, you know,
do you Google search for strings in the code and like try and parse all of Google?
Do you download everybody's source code? And
uh there's a um there's a text searching stuff, uh Google, text search shingling.
And the idea is that you, you kind of create shingles,
like you take chunks of the code and kind of hash them or
otherwise analyze them and then compare it to other shingles and see how
similar they are, you know.
Um it's, it's basically just,
it's a borderline impossible problem because of
not so much the complexity but the scale
and this is where github
comes in is that when you use github and fork something, for example,
github knows exactly what happened, right.
They have a log,
like Kurt went to CV project slash CV list and created a fork of it into slash,
you know, Kurt Siegfried slash CV list.
Right? So that is now a fork of the,
uh master, you know, the, the miter one.
And so
github
knows kind of where all the code went.
So there's,
yeah, so if there's like a flaw in something popular like,
uh, no GS library, for example,
they then know kind of where that stuff went.
Um And they can also search, you know, their g
relatively easily for it, right? There's, you know,
using shingling or just even straight up good old timey grip, whatever.
Um You can kind of find where it all went. Now that's kind of useful except
github actually went and did something actionable, actionable about it
in that quite simply
they warn people,
which is a huge step forward. It,
it's amazing to me and I've already experienced
the power behind this.
And so I'll tell my story is
there's a library called Math dot Js, which is part of the whole node ecosystem.
And at work we're looking to use it. And actually, I've got kind of 22 fun
to, to talk about here.
So first of all, uh someone shows up and says, hey, we want to use this library.
What do you think of it?
And so the first thing I did was I go to
the, the Miter CV E database and I search for math dot Js. Nothing.
I'm like, it can't be that bad. Sure. Let's use it. Right.
And then of course, someone else says, uh,
I search for security in the change log and there's a whole bunch of stuff.
Maybe we shouldn't use this.
And I said, all right. Uh, number one, I didn't look there but good job. Right.
Because that's something I didn't even think of, like, in my brain.
I figure if it's not in the whatever, no CV ES it's probably ok.
And I should have known that, that, that's actually bad.
But, yeah, like these guys are actually fixing security issues.
So I said the fact that they have security flaws in their chainsaw, that's really,
really good.
Right. That's,
-- that's
-- not bad
stuff. Yes.
Correct. Exactly.
And so,
and, and again, I should have known when there were no CV I DS.
Nobody has no CV I DS right
there.
It hasn't been covered yet.
That's fixed now.
But then, so I emailed these guys and I said, basically, hey,
uh, can I work with you to assign CV I DS for your security issues? Right.
And they said, well, we don't know what CBE is, but ok, that sounds fun.
Right.
And of course, my usual, like, how does someone know what CBE is kicks in?
Which is fair?
And then what's funny is shortly after that, they emailed me back and said, hey,
Github
just told me, I've got a bunch of CV ES in my dependencies.
Like, what is this stuff?
And I'm thinking this is amazing, like these are people that,
that at the beginning of the week didn't know what CV ES even were
and now they're not only getting them, but they like,
have a very acute interest due to these github
warnings. So
the vision I have here is that
github
is going to raise the awareness on CBE in a way none of us could have
on our own
over 9000.
Well, and this kind of slides into
the next topic.
So there's a lot of people like Linda tools
who essentially look at security bugs and say,
why are security bugs so magically special, right?
They're just bugs, fix them, be, you know,
deal with it. Yo,
security is not some magical special property.
It's, you know, it's about correctness, right?
If the system is correct and we designed it correctly
and it behaves as expected, assuming we didn't, you know,
design some system that's designed to let somebody in or
designed to allow somebody to do something they shouldn't do.
Um, you know, it'll be fine and,
and this kind of feeds that in that, I think that
one of the problems is, you know,
security bugs do have a slightly special property in that.
Uh, some of them can really result in very, very bad things.
Right?
A great example being right now,
you can now search the CV database and, and plug in the term medical device or airbag
and there are CV S for those now.
And that's a little scary. Right.
Because, you know, like worst case scenario,
my laptop does something terrible or a piece
of software on my laptop does something terrible.
It's not going to kill me.
Right.
Might bankrupt me by cleaning up my bank account, but it's not going to kill me.
Whereas, you know, um,
a remotely exploitable security flaw in like the system
that controls the air bags in my car,
that's bad
that, you know, that can kill me literally. Right?
And so
I think at a minimum,
we need to understand how bad the security problem is,
right? Like
how, how bad is it really? And part of, and that's a big part of where CV comes in is,
um, CV is about, you know, telling people, hey, here's a security flaw.
You maybe need to pay extra special attention to it.
But something we often forget is that,
you know, we also need to get some data going so that we know, like
is
software package a actually objectively better than software package.
B for security properties.
Which library should? I
-- like?
-- 10 topics
that you've been on
here? Let's, let's start here.
II I, you've got me thinking about this to a degree is so
you say security bugs are sort of special, sort of maybe, right?
-- Some of them are sort of special.
-- So, so let's think about it in this way.
Let's pretend
that, that security bugs are just bugs.
Are there,
are there bugs
that
could kill a person? But not get a CV ID?
Uh, there are, and have been the Thor
Radiation machine
that had that, um, oh, it's not a, a security flaw because it's not really trigger,
but it was like
a programming error.
So, instead of using a hardware safety cut off for the radiation dosages,
they decided to do it in software
and there was a flaw which, well, you know,
it would get a CV because it was user triggered now that I think about it.
Um, but for example,
um, a software flaw that prevents the airbag from working at all,
right, the thing is just completely defective
and those sort of things happen where like randomly an airbag will fail
and, and it may not be trigger, but they would also trigger
-- a recall.
-- I suspect it could be just a simple manufacturing defect.
So, so this is, this is where my brain sits now is
let's say we call security bugs just bugs.
Then we're going to say that some
bugs deserve a thing called a CV E ID.
I think one aspect that does make them slightly special
is that they can be intentionally triggered
in
and then they can result in some
uh
negative thing like additional access or deleting people's data.
And so it gives people
control over a system that's simply put, they should not have. Right.
I'm always reminded. So I've been running Linux for
going on 2324 years now.
And I remember running like Slackware 1.0 or 1.1
with like uh the Linux kernel 0.99 patch level.
And it was like, it just went up to some ridiculous number. I remember
and I remember one of those patches
fixed my network driver
and, oh my God,
it was glorious because I went from heavy network utilization would cause
the system to just lock up weirdly after 10 to 15 minutes,
pretty much guaranteed
to. It actually ran for like a day or two before crashing.
And it was fantastic because now I could use NFS.
Right. NFS was previously unusable
in that.
Well, I could use it and every 15 minutes I'd have to reboot my system, which,
you know,
it's a workstation, so
bearable but not great.
And so, you know, should something like that get a CV.
Well, it's not user, like it's not
trigger,
it's, you know, an attacker doesn't really cause it, it's just,
it's a,
it's a product of the system because there's like a defect in kind
of how the software is talking to the hardware or whatever it was,
you know, I forget.
And, you know, and, but like I said, though, once it was fixed, holy cow,
this was so much more usable
And so, for example, if, if somebody introduced a flaw in the Linux kernel,
it caused it to reboot every five minutes like clockwork,
that wouldn't necessarily get a CV. Because it's not,
you know, it, it can't be triggered by an attacker.
It's just a, a defect in the system,
you know.
Yes. And
I agree with this,
but it, it, it's one of these things that I keep rolling around in my brain
and
ask the question.
So, so let's say we do say that there are certain bugs are special for some reason.
Then we're back at the point of, well,
they're not just bugs,
right? They are special.
And the second aspect though is most software bugs propagate relatively easily.
Like, for example,
if you have a network driver that poops out after
say 10 or 15 minutes due to whatever reason,
like a counter hits the end or, you know, something, whatever,
it's going to propagate itself quite reliably like it's gonna be in your face.
And the thing is a lot of security bugs are not really in your face.
They, they quietly sit there
and it's not until somebody takes some specific action to exploit them,
but they then become a problem.
Right? Because let's face it.
If you have a flaw that causes your system to reboot every five minutes
you're going to notice and take action.
But there are, there are different levels.
Well, yeah, agreed. But
that, I think that's one of the other aspects of a lot of security bugs is that they,
they don't trigger
typically until an attacker specifically triggers them.
Ah,
yes, I think, I think you might be on to something now is right, because there's,
there's accidental bugs and then there's attacker oriented bugs. Right.
Yeah.
Um,
you know,
and so, like, and like I said,
the one aspect of security flaws is that security flaws tend
to not really be up in your face as much.
Um, for example, a great example is like a buffer overflow nine times out of 10,
if you don't exploit it right.
-- The, the process or whatever, just crashes
-- or keeps running sometimes.
Yeah, that too.
But every once in a while
the person triggering the flaw remotely now has control of that thing.
Ok. So I, I think we're in agreement here and,
and in, in Linus's email, that is the root of this discussion.
He says security bugs are just bugs but I think,
-- but
-- he's also not wrong. I think,
I think that particular argument is wrong
because
because security bugs
are well, yes, they are bugs, they are bugs that have
serious
results from them being exercised, right?
And they, they, they, but they have to be maliciously exercised for those results.
I think part of it simply is
is that
people live in different
kind of versions of reality with different cultures. And
you know,
where Linus lives with kernel development versus where a bank
lives with having to make sure customers are protected versus
an IOT device maker who is literally going to make an IOT device that
will be installed in a well casing at the bottom of the ocean,
right?
They live in very different worlds, right?
-- Linus can literally say run current
-- or or they're making a light bulb for $1.
Yeah.
And that's part of the problem is I think to some degree,
Linus is not wrong. He is actually completely correct in the context of his world.
But then for example, you go and talk to a bank and a bank is like,
we can't just run current on our system because it's, it's for sure,
something bad will happen every other week and we're gonna get, it's fine,
it's fine.
They just, they put everything in the Blockchain and it'll be fine, right?
It will happen. That's all you have to do.
And so I think that's part of the problem is we need to
uh in a way it's a form of empathy in that. I, I look at security from say Lin's
point of view and you know, also like the open ssh and open BS D guys
who have this culture of a bug is a bug fix it, make the system correct,
run current. And
I agree with them, but the problem is run current doesn't work for everybody.
That's not even the core of this argument though, from Linus either,
I think it comes down to the fact that a lot of the security
is, is first of all, it, it ends up being very fundamentally low level, right?
Where we like the hardening issue in question from case cook
is
super low level.
And anytime you change something kind of in the bowels of the kernel,
you run the risk of, of literally breaking everything.
And in this particular patch,
it sounds like was designed to literally break
things because when it detected a problem,
it just, you know, murdered the process instead of
letting it maybe continue on. And, and
I would argue killing the process that is acting incorrectly is OK.
But Linus disagrees.
-- And now at the
-- same time, it depends how you define incorrectly, right?
A
buffer overflow, right? Let's say, let's say a buffer overflow gets triggered.
And in
this case,
the colonel would kill it instead of letting it
basically kill itself eventually by doing something insane.
Right?
And
I would side with case on this one in saying something bad has happened,
if there is a buffer overflow and you should almost certainly kill what's going on.
And, and Linus disagrees. Now, at the same time, this is also Linus's project.
So he's allowed to disagree and have his own opinion here. Right.
Well, I would say part of it is it kind of,
I I suspect part of it goes back to Linus's argument of we don't break user space
and, and I think that is a good argument and I also suspect that's
part of the reason that Colonel has been so successful
right now.
Now we take this idea about not breaking things and what
is a security bug or what isn't a security bug?
And how do we, how do we fix these low level things? And then we think about
github
and the things they're doing now where they're going to start pointing
out a lot of this stuff and they're going to point out problems
and now we, we end up in a weird place,
interrupt you for a moment because I think that's
also an important part of security bugs is that
pointing out problems.
For example,
any piece of software you import is going to have a change log with a ton of changes.
And
fundamentally again,
a lot of them you're probably not going to care about.
And then essentially typically kind of one of three things will happen.
Either one, the library will do something like they'll,
they'll add something to the library like a feature that is so awesome.
You will definitely want to upgrade it because it's just so much more cool. Right.
So that's easy. Right.
Number two,
the library has a problem that manifests itself
enough and is problematic enough that you're like,
I need to deal with that and go fix it.
Right. Like it crashes every five minutes.
But then number three,
the security problem there's a security problem in the library.
You as the person importing it and using it aren't
going to notice typically until an attacker triggers it.
Right. And that's the problem
and that's why I think we sort of need,
I'm not going to say so much special treatment of security bugs,
but special notification of security bugs.
And that's a
big part where CV, and what github
is doing come in and
-- makes it so much better. I
-- think, I think that's an amazing argument right there.
I, I love that because you're absolutely right
because
-- of those three things. Why would you upgrade the library? Yes,
-- I, I agree.
And this ties back exactly to what I was trying to bring. This is github
is going to start telling people why or,
or rather if they have security problems in their,
in their library, well, in their product, I guess, or project because it's,
it's using someone else's code
and you're right,
this, I like this because really now the
github alert
is the same thing is having a, a latent bug or crash or whatever from a,
another miss feature
that you might be looking for
a fix for when you, when you upgrade your dependencies. So,
so I guess ironically
now we're kind of back to the argument about their, they're just bugs.
It's just, it just so happens that
it's, it's a bug you probably need to care about. Just not in the same way.
You care about a crash.
And I think part of the problem is the visibility of security flaws tends to
be lower than like other crasher bugs or a bug where half the screen is purple
because, you know, the people running the code,
are they going to notice a security flaw,
by definition, they're not going to notice a security flaw
at a minimum until it is exploited.
And even then if it is exploited, they may not notice.
-- I bet the Equifax people would disagree with you.
-- Yeah.
Well, and that, but, well, no, because they,
apparently somebody was in their systems for a few weeks or months.
That's true. Right.
And that's the thing, right?
If you have a user interface where half of it is an annoying shade of purple,
nobody's going to miss that flaw.
Like that's going to be in your face,
you know?
But like I said, like by definition,
a security flaw doesn't propagate until somebody exploits it.
And even when somebody exploits it,
there's a good chance you're not going to notice
because how many of these massive data breaches,
massive companies that spend massively on security spending.
It turns out the attacker was in there for weeks
or months or in some cases years before they noticed
it. It's very
common
and that's why I think,
like I said,
I'm not so sure that security flaws need special handling
from a fixing point of view in so much as,
like any security flaw needs or any severe bug needs to be dealt with
sooner rather than later. But I think they need,
you know,
that better notification because just otherwise people won't notice this stuff.
You know,
a great example is this weekend or last week
rather I upgraded from Fedora 26 to Fedora 27
and I ran into a relatively simple bug in that the updater wouldn't go
because I had X
Chat installed. Right. Good old time IRC client
because X
chat is no longer present in Fedora 27.
So somebody filed a bug saying, you know, blah, blah, blah, the update breaks.
And it's like, well, yeah, it does.
And the solution is you remove X chat and you install hex
chat.
That's it like, and they use the same config files. It's actually not too bad.
There's no way you're going to miss this flaw because everybody who
tries to upgrade Fedora is going to run into this flaw.
And, you know, it's going to be really obvious. Right.
But a security flaw on the other hand,
uh, you know,
I just upgraded my kernel and it fixed a bunch of security flaws that there's
the only way I would notice those is if somebody exploited them
and then hijacked my machine and then I noticed it and then I
somehow forensically determined that they exploited CV EF
in the kernel, which
even as a security guy that would be very hard for
me to do and for a normal person basically impulsive,
it is impossible.
It's not basically impossible.
Yeah.
And so I think that's why at a minimum
security bugs need better
-- sort of tracking and notification.
-- No. II, I like this though.
I think,
I think you're totally on to something and this is absolutely the right
argument is when you have other kinds of bugs you see them.
Yeah.
Like a cross site scripting flaw isn't typically going
to accidentally propagate until somebody does crazily say,
like, hey, I wanted to call that system,
you know,
javascript, take blah, blah, blah, which
typically is not going to come up as an issue,
right?
You know, or how many times has stuff broken because they're like, oh, I,
I stuck this weird character in,
I mean, it's happening more now because people want to use unicode.
And for example, I was,
I was playing with some websites and I was like,
I wonder if I can put unicode in my user name?
I mean, can I make my user name a smiley face? Because that would be kind of awesome.
I,
yes. And it turns out at some sites you can and at some sites you can't.
And at some sites I'm pretty sure something went horribly wrong in the back end and,
and you need to use the unicode snowman.
Snowman is where it's at, Kurt.
Yeah.
You know.
Yes,
I, I love doing that. In
fact, I think
anyway.
And, and part of it too is with respect to special handling of security flaws.
We,
we can't even really have that discussion until
we actually know about the security flaws.
Right. We can't have a discussion. Do security flaws need special handling?
Because for example, for all we know the Linux kernel
has 90% coverage of all their flaws with CVS or
more likely in my opinion, has a much lower coverage of all their flaws by CVS
and they are accidentally or otherwise intentionally fixing security flaws
and not getting them CV S because either
they don't even realize it's a security flaw,
right?
They just fix some correctness behavior that
may or may not be exploitable,
you know, because there's a lot of stuff where it turns out that code change, hey,
totally improve the reliability of the system
in a way that could be triggered by an attacker. And oftentimes it
improves it in a way that like straight up the attacker has no influence over that.
It's just
how things are, you know, and like I said, we can't
really have these discussions until we have an idea of the scope of the problem.
And so, for example, for the sake of argument, you know,
maybe the Linux kernel has CV S for all the really bad stuff that we need to care about.
Great or maybe it doesn't,
you know, if we assign all this stuff CV S,
then we can have a data set we can look at and we can say, hey,
maybe this subsystem maintainer is terrible
or maybe these, you know,
every time you add a new driver it takes a while to shake down.
Right? Or maybe every time you add, I, I, the reality is we don't know.
Yes, I, I agree with that. And this is
where I'm super excited for the work github
is doing because
I have a suspicion
that as awareness goes up,
the number of security issues is going to increase exponentially,
which I guess it'll be really funny too because we
had how many CV ES came out last year?
It was more than
10-K, right? 12 or 13
or 13,000. And, and I'm sure that will be broken this year, but
it already has
it
already.
We're up into 15 or 16 already and
not all of them are assigned mind you.
So like, you know,
Microsoft has a block that they're going through an oracle and whatever,
right?
But
we are on track for more.
This is one of those things I just think about is
so
the dream has always been, let's give every security issue A CV E ID,
but it's also going to be a nightmare because how
are you going to deal with that volume of stuff?
Well, uh this is, for example, part of why I pushed a
JSON format for CV,
that includes an affected section where you define the vendors and the products.
So that, for example, you can say I only care about Xy and
Z and I can ignore the rest of it.
Right. And, and that's the reality, right? Like
for example, um I,
at one point tried to figure out how many skate
of vendors are there globally that write their own software.
-- And the answer is at least 1000.
-- You'll never know though.
-- You can't answer that question.
-- Exactly.
Well, so anyways my point, I'm just trying to get some scale numbers here,
usually within an order of magnitude, right?
That would be good enough for my back of the envelope. And so
I figured out there's at least 1000 skate of vendors writing software
and some of them are huge like Siemens and Schneider and those guys
and some of them are like literally 10 man shops. Like um I remember a
friend of mine worked for a company that literally started out as two guys got to 500
then was sold to I think like Honeywell or something, you know,
and it was a customer acquisition essentially, right?
They didn't care about their technology or software because all
skater software is basically the same at this point,
you know, you got a web gooey with a bunch of stuff. Anyway,
point being
like five of these skater vendors are CNAs and do CV S.
So like on the skate upfront alone,
we have thousands of companies making like like software that matters,
this is stuff, running power grids and
all that stuff.
And then, you know, you go to look at medical devices again,
there's at least several 100 vendors probably between 1000 and 10,000 globally,
that kind of matter, you know, they have more than one customer.
And so I was trying to basically get like essentially how many entities on the
planet are building software that we kind of care about the security flaws in.
And the answer is
if I had to guess I'd say between 100,000 and a million
and I don't mean just like companies but also like a great example curl, right?
That, you know,
Daniel from Sweden wrote a really useful piece of software as it turns out
and it's now embedded,
I think in all the UNIX operating systems like Apple
now man.
Is it?
Yeah,
exactly.
So, you know,
and he's a great guy for security because he, you know, fixes all security flaws,
he gets CV S, he patches them quickly, he sends out pre notifications like it's
the guy on, you know, he's doing a great job.
And so
my back of the envelope estimation says we need at least 1 to 10 million
CV S per year for stuff we care about and by stuff we care about,
I mean, kind of stuff that more than 10 or 20 people in the world
-- to
-- 10 million is a completely ridiculous spread
like it's an order of magnitude,
you know,
but it is a completely ridiculous spread. But at least
it's, I'm beginning to get some approximation of how big is the,
-- it
-- is in the millions. And I, I agree with that and, and that's,
and remember folks that's per year, that's not the overall number that's per year.
Right.
-- And,
-- and so anyway, the, the place this conversation will end,
which I'll get it there quicker is
people can't pay attention to this stuff because people don't scale. We need
automation.
And this is where I think things like what github
is up to is a huge first step.
It is going to be enormous long term, I suspect
because of we raise awareness, which is going to raise a number of CE I DS,
which is going to raise the amount of work,
which means we're going to have to automate because we don't have a choice.
Right.
It totally reminds me of, of how we used to deal with attacks.
We used to deal with attacks by having a human,
read the log file and chase everything down.
-- You know,
-- man, I remember,
I remember knowing people whose job was to read I DS log files
and, and,
ah,
I
just, I can't
ban them. That is a job.
I mean,
and anyone who did that, I, I apologize if I'm picking on you, but it just,
it sounds terrible and it's totally automat.
Right.
Yeah. And, and I mean, that's what's going to happen with.
This is part of it is we're beginning to understand the scale
of security flaws
and the fact that, yeah, Attackers do use these to do bad things.
It's, it's gonna get ugly before it gets better.
But, you know, the same was true of online attacks. And now, quite frankly,
you know, being online is normal, being attacked a million times a day is normal.
It's just, it's like the spam problem, right?
Remember when spam was unmanaged and I remember my inbox just
literally didn't work because I had so much spam in it.
And now honestly, it's a non issue. I got one or two spams.
No, that's because you use Gmail, which I do too.
And the reason I use it is because I used to run my own mail server
and I dealt with the spam and one day I threw my hands up and said,
II I give up like you win spammers,
which I guess, ironically by, by them winning,
I switched to Gmail and then the spam went away.
So,
and that's part of it is,
you know, we're going to figure out what parts of this can and need to be automated.
Uh The notification is definitely a good step because again, you know,
um how can we have people fixing this stuff if they don't even know it exists?
Right. Right. Exactly. Now, now let me ask you this
is,
do you what do you think this is going to do to some of the existing, like,
security scanning type
companies and products?
Well, ideally they should move up the food chain just as like firewall vendors did.
Right? Like no offense.
But looking at firewall products,
I remember when like non state full firewalls cost real money by real money.
I'm talking like five or six figures.
And now that stuff, well, that stuff isn't even built into anything because it's so
terrible.
You know, you have to at a minimum,
have a state for firewall that understands protocols to some degree.
And that is built in by default into everything
because everything runs Linux or BS D or,
well, uh, uh,
what you might call it, uh Minix as it turns out,
you know? Right.
And, and that's just a given. It's like having a TCP/IP stack that's reliable.
Right. It's just, that's,
that's how the world works.
Could you imagine an operating system without a firewall or a TCP/IP stack today?
Like you'd be laughed out of the room.
Yeah.
Well, remember the, the, the,
the Blackberry playbook that came without an email client
and when I heard that I was like,
yeah,
this thing is doomed because how do you get a device
out the door without an email client after the year 2000?
-- Uh, no,
-- you know, you know, that's actually a fine example.
And that, that's probably a discussion for another day. But like
that is a company that doesn't know who they're building the product for.
Right.
I mean, it will not only that, like,
that's even more confusing because Blackberry basically they,
they, they existed
because they gave people mobile email. Like that was the only thing it did.
Yeah.
But uh back to this. So, so essentially um
what's going to happen is like every other technology is
the simple stuff gets so ST
so simple. It's just baked in by default, right?
Like secure web servers, I spent 500 bucks buying one.
Now they're in my bathroom scale,
right? Maybe if you
ssl certificates used to cost real money. Now there's lots and crypt and cloud flare
and it's basically free.
And so that's what's going to happen with these companies.
They are going to either have to move up the food chain or perish.
But here's, I guess, yes.
And that's my initial thinking of this is you need to find a way to add new value.
But I feel like github
is,
they're coming in really early here.
I feel like because this is like security scanning
has really only been a thing that isn't it. And it still kind of sucks.
But, you know, it's only been a couple of years.
It's not like this is 10 years,
although maybe that's just the way the industry is going to move now is,
is a couple of years, the
beginning of the S curve for scanning. Like because there are people.
It is, it is actually reasonably widely used, you know,
a lot of stuff like license compliance,
make sure you don't ship something you shouldn't,
um, making sure you're not shipping stuff with like known CV S, make sure you,
you know, a whole bunch of other reasons.
And I feel it's kind of like antivirus right now.
You know, we're at that, like,
people examine the malware and handwrite a signature for it
and you know, plug it into the database and that's cool. But
you know, that kind of stuff is going to get heavily automated.
So for example, you know, the discovering of security flaws,
people are working on automation of that and
working on the automation for remediation for fixing it
on that.
This was at black hat, they've got a Blockchain based machine,
artificial learning intelligence that, that can scan the mal
before
I
downloaded.
Like, right,
actually,
that was one of my favorite things is like if
you ask a legitimate question to many of those vendors,
they don't know what to say.
And so,
you know, and, and part of it too is what is actually useful
because for example, for a lot of projects,
they don't really need source code scanning because they're like just
whatever we ship whatever is the most recent stuff this week.
You know,
like if you update your software every 24 hours to whatever the most recent stuff is,
I don't think most people know that, I think in
the
great
idea, but it's,
but
what I'm trying to say is there's different use cases and
no, no,
no, we need to talk about this actually because this, this,
this was a point that came up with the math dot
Js guy when I was talking to him because he said,
well, why don't,
why don't you guys just update to the latest instead of worrying about
a version that might have a security flaw?
And
so from my perspective, there's kind of two sides to this and,
and I think that the conversation is bigger, but
there is kind of older versions you have to support for a length of time.
And, and this is like the, the Linux kernel has the, what do they call it?
Do they call it LTs
the
stable, stable?
Like the Linux kernel basically has two versions.
There's the new version that they're working on today
and then there's another version they keep alive for like a year or two, right?
And
I think it's even simpler in the people.
Forget for end users, there is a real cost to update churn.
Yes, there is a real cost update even ignoring. And this ignores the fact
-- that sometimes the updates will break stuff.
-- Well, in that, that's right.
That's the second part of this is
even if you want to follow like like master or
whatever you want to call it for just like super DEV
ops let's pull things in every hour and rebuild and test and all this.
Uh, someday
the API or something will break and you won't be able to
pull in the new version until you patch and patching takes time.
Right.
And it might take five minutes, it might take five days, it might take five months.
It depends what's happening.
And so I think
in, in a perfect world,
everyone upgrading quickly and always running the latest version,
like is a great idea
and maybe someday we'll get there,
but we're not there today.
-- We,
-- we won't because even for example,
Apple doesn't support their devices forever.
Right? I have an ipad. Um
I had a gen one ipad that, wow, that thing's like dead.
I had a GEN two ipad that's stuck on I OS version. What is it? 9.3 0.5 or something?
Like you should
really
old version
basically.
Yeah,
I'm looking for somebody that just needs like a web surfer for their four year old.
Um And then, you know, I have some more ipads that are,
they're four
years old now, so they're stuck on I OS 10 point whatever the last 10 was.
And so now I'm, you know, having to upgrade ipads mostly to get a better CPU for the,
you know, the Augmented Reality and the 3D games and stuff.
But also so that I can keep an up to date I OS.
Yeah. You know,
um,
and it's not so much, I'm not so worried about security flaws,
so much as that the apps themselves
don't,
you know, the,
the app developers aren't going to support version nine and 10 for a long,
long time because like
supporting two or three streams of software is a lot of work, especially if,
you know, you're talking about a mobile app where most people are updating
relatively, you know, consistently.
Um And so part of it is, you know,
uh, just performance wise and, you know, software compatibility wise,
like I already ran into, I, I ran a software update and, um,
one of the apps broke on I OS 10 just flat, like it
turns on and you get a blank screen
just doesn't work awesome.
Right. Try explaining that to a seven year old.
I, I, have
you say it's broke and I can't fix it, do something else.
-- That's what
-- you said. I think that was word for word what I said,
you know.
And,
yeah, so I,
I love the run current argument but the reality is there's
a huge cost associated with that and like I said,
that and that's assuming everything goes well and you don't brick stuff,
you know, and then the cost just shoots up astronomically
and some stuff. Like
people, I think a lot of people forget because outside of niche industries,
you know, satellites run software and it's, as we learned from the Hubble, you know,
space telescope repair emissions,
that's really expensive,
uh, you know, or
like,
-- and wells or pipelines that are underground,
-- making sure you can update your,
your satellite from Earth is important.
Actually,
didn't one of the Mars Rovers have some sort of problem with the file system.
And they had to, like, it had
a, it basically put itself in a,
like safe mode and they were able to upload a new operating system which is
an integer
overflow or something,
-- something
-- really dumb. And
that's like, that's awesome. Right. That, that's where it's at right there.
But, but at the same time,
uh, this is a multimillion dollar thing. Maybe even in the billions.
I don't know how much it costs.
So there's a certain incentive to make sure it can be remotely update.
Where is your, your $1 iot light bulb? Yeah. Nobody cares.
And there's also that incentive though, it's working. Don't touch it.
Right.
That's a huge incentive for people with software.
That's a huge incentive for everything. Kurt. I have so many things in my life that
it's like, I, I, this is working and I know I could make it better,
but I'll probably just make it worse if I touch it.
So I'm just going to do nothing. Like, nothing is easier than maybe breaking it.
In
fact, I feel like this. I've got my, my website, I have a website called breast.net
and
I've had it forever, like, like longer than I could remember.
And it's running on a AVM, like a VPs somewhere
and
I keep meaning there's like, it's just serving static content at this point. I
mean,
that's
the
thing.
Right. Like
it's enough work that it's,
it's easier for me to just pay the five bucks a month for this VP.
Like, I even have it, it's set on, on Cron to do,
like an auto update every day at midnight because I don't even care.
Like, I figure
whatever comes to distribution is probably secure enough.
But no, I, I right in here. This is exactly the point though. Right? Is
my life would actually be easier and I'd say five bucks a month if I dumped it into S3,
however,
it's enough work to change it and like it's working today. So
why should I care? Right. And that's
the,
and, and like once a month, I think all right,
today is the day and then I start doing it and I'm like,
I can, I'm gonna go watch this
comes
back,
you know, people,
whether they realize it or not will do a cost benefit analysis and
a return on investment analysis for everything they do to some degree,
some, you know, consciously, some unconsciously.
Um
And again, though, you know, you can't make those decisions
until you sort of know what the problem is in the scope of the problem. Right.
So there's a great example, like a
lot of security bugs are not really that bad.
So hey, you know, we'll get them on the next major update
and then some security flaws are bad enough that no,
we're going to fix this in the next 24 hours
so that the world doesn't hopefully burn down a bit.
That's fair,
you know,
but we can't do that until we have the data to drive those decisions.
And the good news is now is that,
that's starting, you know, CV, we have the
JSON format, which has much richer data than the old CS V format,
which had like a description in URL S
and a CV ID.
And that was basically it,
you know, now we'll have richer data with what's affected, how is it affected?
You know, you can have sub containers. So vendor A is maybe strongly affected.
Vendor B is barely affected because of some decision they made or change they made,
you know,
and then that second part is have people like github
notifying everybody
that needs to be notified,
right?
Because that's the other problem is our notification
systems are typically incredibly coarse in that.
Here's a data feed. Good luck,
you know, that's it basically or
somebody selectively consumes it and, and you know,
they have to build something on their end to selectively consume it.
Whereas with github,
it's like I'm going to tell you just about the stuff you imported
Ergo, hopefully the stuff you should be caring about.
-- You know,
-- it's, it's awesome, man.
Now, I guess here's, here's the one other thing and we'll kind of,
we'll close on this one because I, I don't have an answer to it,
but this is going to cost github a lot.
This isn't cheap and it's not free.
So, what's the, what's the incentive here for them do you think?
Well,
I think the reality is they have to start doing stuff like
this because this is part of them moving up the food chain,
just like every single web server on the planet now
comes with SSL TLS support. Whereas that used to cost.
I remember when a local company in Edmonton bought one,
they had the first secure web server in Edmonton.
That was
um actually, technically, it was the second one.
The first one was the running room, had a secure web server. God knows why.
But the second company, it was an ISP that had one, they spent $15,000 on Netscape,
whatever it was secure server things.
And so to sell access to it, they were actually,
they seriously looked at like charging people a percentage
of what they were selling online because they,
they could not
like if you told people, hey, to set up this web server,
you need to pay 5000 bucks upfront or whatever they know.
Right.
And like I said, now,
secure web servers are kind of the default rather than the exception.
And I think that's with a lot of the security stuff. It's just like everything else.
You know, how many people actually properly support I PV six now.
And the answer is actually quite a few.
Right. Whereas five years ago,
I literally was talking with hosting providers
and they're like, what's I PV six or? Yeah. No, we have no plans to support that.
Like straight up. I was running a six bone tunnel for a while
because my VPs host did not support I PV six.
And that might not be the best example because I think I PV Six has a ways to go still.
But
it's
-- all the mobile phones now
-- and it's coming, it's getting there.
I think it's getting close.
Yeah.
Yeah. I,
I don't
think
Six is.
It's,
and like, a lot of the security stuff,
-- a lot of the security stuff that people do won't be super noticeable
-- and,
and it shouldn't be, security should be boring.
It should be like fixing bugs right where if you're fixing security bugs,
you should just fix them and it's,
it's not like the end of the world and some people might care.
Some people probably won't. It's kind of,
I know every time there's a new change log and something I run, I just, I,
I skim it looking for the one or two things I care about if I don't see it, I say, ok,
neat.
You know, don't care.
And, and security is the same way.
It's,
it's just a bug
and, and I,
I like this. I like where we ended up here where, where CV E is just,
it is the, in your face example of
the, the bug because we don't see him otherwise. So I love it, man. That's great.
All right, Kurt, any parting thoughts,
try to look at things from other people's perspective.
Once in a while, it's not easy.
But honestly, it's, I think something more people need to do more of,
if they would only agree with me more, everything would be fine.
Right.
Well, that's one thing I,
I say that freaks a lot of people out is I often say that I know I'm wrong.
-- I'm always wrong.
-- I just don't know which
part I always assume whatever I thought of.
Like that's, that's the wrong answer.
So let's look for other things that aren't that,
you
know,
and then hopefully you find out you have the least worst,
the least worst.
I never
do. I let a smart person fix it.
It's just I know that whatever I've thought of, we can at least cross that one off.
So, anyway, anyway.
Right.
All right, cool. Well, thank you, Kurt, thank you, everyone for listening.
You can go to open
source security podcast.com to hit up the show notes
for the various odd things we've talked about today.
Hit us up on Twitter with the Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag
join our Facebook group.
Yeah. Otherwise send us messages. Let us know what you think. Kurt.
You have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too.
Thanks, folks.