Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime.
Josh Bresser.
Oh, we're back to crime again, huh?
Well, I think technically we might,
we're going to be borderline skirting with Libel.
And
are we?
But I,
I'm pretty sure what we're going to be saying is truthful.
-- So I believe the truth is a defense in Canada and the US
-- in
-- the
-- United States.
As long as we classify ourselves as entertainment,
I think we can say whatever we want.
Right. Right. We're probably fine.
At
least I am
about that.
Yeah.
Well, so, so the context here,
the Canadian Federal Government has a Canadian Center for cybersecurity
and it's run by the communications security Establishment,
which to put it bluntly is our version of the NSA.
So it's, it's a real organization. It's not
some
five guys in a room doing random reports. It's, it's a legitimate,
you know, really funded, well funded
government agency that occasionally does do some good public work
and occasionally does some really
terrible
wrong stuff.
So I wanted to preface this episode by also talking at sort of the high level of
I'm sure we've all been there where we
see something that's just fundamentally wrong and,
you know, you feel like you have to speak up because it's so wrong.
Like you see somebody punching a puppy
or pretty much any multilevel marketing
and, and I feel, and, and there's no money in this. There's no,
not a lot of benefit, but I, I think it's important on occasion
to call out something that is grossly wrong. And I,
and I really hope that this is wrong and not in like intentional lies.
-- Of course,
-- it's not intentional. It get on with it.
So
they talk about open source security,
-- security considerations when using open source software
-- except they
took the talking points from Microsoft in 2005.
Not even, they're worse than that.
I, it's, it's pretty, it's the usual,
everyone be afraid.
Well, yeah.
And the part I love here is they have a statement, you know,
78% of companies run open source software
that actually is probably, it's probably more
-- it's 100%. But
-- here's what I love, but less than half are managing it properly.
Well, yeah, nobody manages their software properly.
It's 100%
-- and seven companies are managing their open source properly. That's my
-- estimate.
What gets me,
look at all the software designed to help
you manage your commercial software and I don't
even mean esoteric stuff but just stuff to keep you up to date on Microsoft patches,
right.
How much effort and time do people
and patching their windows machines and fail at it,
as evidenced by all the ransomware attacks
that go stomping through these organizations.
I mean, even ignoring the ransomware,
there's various compliance standards that have requirements on reporting and
looking for missing software patches and things like that.
And
the first of all the systems that track this stuff
are atrociously bad and they're obscenely expensive and yeah,
everyone is basically just bad at this.
So
anyway,
open source is created through voluntary collaboration of software developers.
-- Uh
-- We'll give that 1 50% true.
That's sort of technically true of
-- all human activity. Not
-- necessarily.
-- I mean, well,
-- apart from slavery, everything is sort of quasi
-- technically voluntary like you could quit your job.
-- No, it's not. I'm getting, I get
paid to work. I'm not doing this for free.
-- Like if they make it miserable enough, you're going to leave. I
-- mean,
that's not voluntary though,
voluntary. Ah but you're conflating voluntary with being paid.
I think you're splitting hairs.
No, I'm not because this is kind of an important point later anyways,
the original authors license the code so that anyone can see it,
modify it and distribute new versions of it.
That's
-- generally
-- true. I'm OK with that. I'm OK with that.
This allows developers to extend open source code to create new stand alone product
or add new functionality to existing software products.
Generally true.
Os S is very common.
Yes, it's like the default.
Now folks,
you are probably already familiar with several open source
products like Google Chrome and Firefox web browsers.
Due to the nature of publicly available OS S
anyone can make changes to existing open source code.
Well,
and, and I hate statements like that because they,
yes, anybody can make changes to the code,
but it's not like those changes are going to be incorporated and used by anybody.
-- You
-- have to accept my back door because I'm giving you
-- pull request.
-- Yeah, exactly. This accessibility makes it easy to customize
OS to suit your business needs.
-- Sort of if you know how to build it and get it working
-- right in
the same way that owning a tree makes it easy to build a house.
Right.
Well, yeah, I mean, I,
I suspect we actually do have show listeners who have
built and run a copy of say Firefox or Chrome,
but I'm also guessing we can count them on one hand with my fingers making a fist.
It's pretty bad. I have built,
I have
Firefox from SARS more times than I wish to recount
and I can tell you now it's a terrible process.
I have access to a Napa auto parts. That doesn't mean I can go build a car. Actually.
That's a good question for a future, future thing to think about.
It's like, can you, can you build a car by buying parts from the auto store,
I doubt that they have engine blocks but an electric car
-- maybe, maybe, or the frame but
-- whatever.
Yeah, and then capabilities can be added removed or modified as needed.
-- Well, again,
-- the
same way owning a true
and no offense.
But if capabilities can be added removed or modified as needed that easily, I mean,
the whole software world would be a lot better off
regardless. So, I would say that they're about
60 to 70% correct on what open source is.
But they,
like you said, this whole, oh,
I'm going to make a change to the software and everybody has to use it ha ha.
And then they talk about the risks and these are, these are just dumb. It's so bad.
Yeah. So risk before you implement OS S in your organization. Ok. Hint.
It's too late. You already have.
No, you are.
Ok. Here's the thing. Are you running windows?
-- Well, then there's open source embedded in windows.
-- Are you using a computer
-- that
-- you didn't hand build and wire it yourself?
If you did, it's going to be full of
open. I bet your firmware is probably running open source.
No, no, no, I'm talking about that guy that made a custom eight bit CPU on like a bunch.
-- Remember? It's like a room full of breadboards.
-- Did he build the whole CPU?
Which one are you thinking about?
The guy who used the Motorola 6502 to build his own, like custom a bit computer.
-- No,
-- no, no. This was, this is like a room full of bread boards.
It's
beautiful. It's, it's like all the spaghetti wiring in the world.
-- We'll
-- put it
in the show notes because I want to see this too. This is totally my game.
-- So I look forward to watching that
-- excessive access.
Open access means the code is available to all.
Well, ok, there is open source that's not accessible to all but whatever.
Let's ignore that
which creates opportunities for cyber threat actors.
-- I've actually never heard that term used like that.
-- I like it.
-- We should, we should normalize that term
-- to manipulate code maliciously.
-- Yes, they can manipulate the code maliciously.
-- Look, this point is just dumb.
My view on this,
my suspicion when I read that is this reeks of Microsoft the early
two thousands and my guess is whoever wrote this hasn't gotten the memo
that all of these claims have been debunked and shown to be ridiculous.
And more importantly,
I think history has shown us that closed source is
probably more vulnerable to these problems and open sources.
Well, if you look at this from the term of,
I think what they actually are maybe meaning is manipulate cold ma
means I can find and create a buffer overflow concept using OS S
can give threat actors opportunities to gain
access to your networks and information.
Well, that's true of commercial software. I mean again. Right.
I've worked with people whose job it was was to take Microsoft patch,
Tuesday bin Diff run it through all the DB G.
Do a bunch of magic and 24 hours later have a working exploit.
Ok. Number two is a great one. Lack of verification.
And I'm like,
does commercial software have a lot of verification because from what I've seen
anyway,
this is my, well,
see there are no guarantees that qualified experts conduct
proper testing and quality assurance throughout the development of
OSS
or that those who review the code thoroughly check its security.
Yeah, that's software. That's the software world.
This lack of verification can make your it infrastructure vulnerable.
-- This is true of all software on the planet and
-- houses, people build houses,
the building
passes the house and then the house falls down
the next week because they did something horrific.
There was a, there was a giant condo complex up in Fort mcmurray.
The whole thing was framed wrong and they built this thing and it
was around for a couple of years and then massive cracks started happening
and that they literally gave everybody something like an hour
to get out of the building and they were,
they were removed from the building for months
and the whole
because it hasn't fallen down or burned down.
The insurance situation is a complete,
but the point is this was a building something we're supposed to have
an understanding of how to build properly and it was completely screwed up.
And software is more complicated than buildings. And
we don't have software inspectors. No.
Well, we, we do, we have those automated code scanners that do a great job.
Oh, my goodness.
Don't get me started. So. Ok.
And then here's the third one I love because you and I both work for Red Hat.
So I read this. So I'm like, lack of support.
I'm like, huh most Os S does not have dedicated support.
-- Well, but that's also true of software in general.
-- It depends what you're doing.
I mean, you can run, I mean, you can pay Red Hat for support,
you can pay Microsoft for support.
You can, you can run close source software
and not get support. I mean, that's io
-- this is dumb.
-- A perfect example.
Let's pick an app on your phone at random and try and get you support for it.
That's
let's say the Facebook app or the Twitter app.
Has anyone ever in the history of either of those applications gotten support?
-- The answer is
-- no.
And then the second sentence is just even stupider without a
support team updates and security patches may not be available.
-- So again, this is true like this is software,
-- this has nothing to do with support.
I mean,
there's plenty of companies with no security teams and
they never provide security patches to their stuff.
There's plenty of
open source, it never gets security patches to its stuff.
And, I mean,
this is a hugely complicated problem and there isn't
-- a good answer to it
-- and it's hugely complicated
across the whole software industry. Not just
-- oss,
-- it has nothing to do with open source.
It's just a hard problem for anyone who has to publish security advisories.
You live in a historical house and you basically had to effectively
fix the equivalent of some pretty major bugs in your house.
I literally replaced the foundation on my house.
Yeah,
like I've seen that photograph of a guy in a bobcat under your house driving around.
Yeah, like that sounds like some pretty intrusive bug fixing.
That's one way to look at it, I suppose.
-- So
-- if vulnerabilities are discovered in the software cyber threat,
actors can exploit these vulnerabilities.
Yeah,
that's how vulnerabilities work to gain access
to your organization's network systems and information.
I mean,
yeah, that's also true of your front door and the lock on it.
-- You know, the lock picking
-- lawyer, I think again, this comes back to the,
this sounds like a talking point for Microsoft in 2005.
Yeah,
-- basically, let's just
-- scare you by saying something that you can't.
Here's, I guess here's part of the challenge you can't really prove it either way,
whether it is or isn't true, which is, I mean, it's true of all software.
I can prove it's true of all software by pointing at the CV database.
Especially by pointing out that the only commercial vendors
represented are ones that really want to be represented.
So it's survivor bias.
These are the guys that deeply care about security and
are pumping out hundreds of security patches a year.
The ones that don't care about security
-- CS are probably worse.
-- I have no doubt. I think that's completely true.
And then I love how they flip it around. Not all
oss carries the same level of risk.
In fact,
most commercial it security products have open
source components worked into their code.
For example,
consider companies that manufacture it security
products that offer cryptographic functionality.
These manufacturers embed the open source open and
sell cryptographic library in their product lines.
So all of a sudden somehow you can take open source,
shove it into a commercial product again.
Boop it's fine, I guess.
Right.
And that's what I really hate is not only are their talking points wrong,
their talking points aren't even
-- internally consistent.
-- No. Right.
I, well,
so documents like this and attitudes like this always
lack internal consistency because if they had some,
you couldn't make these talking points and look this.
Like I said,
every every time I look at this document and I look at it a lot
more than I should just because I don't know why I suddenly must have inner peace
and I need to rid myself of it.
But like every time I look at this,
it's just like it feels like Microsoft
wrote this where there's just inconsistencies,
there's fallacies, it doesn't make sense.
And anyone with even the tiniest hint of a clue
looks at this and is like this is ridiculous.
Well, but the problem is there will be people that don't have a clue looking.
-- I know
-- tons of them. Absolutely.
What also gets me is, is,
it's not like this report was say true 20 years ago and now it's not true.
No, this report was also wrong 20 years ago. It was all wrong.
And
this is what really gets me is,
I don't normally like to punch people metaphorically in the face and say
you're stupid and you should feel bad about this work you did.
But in this case, they are stupid and the work they've done,
I hope it's not malicious, but
-- it,
-- it's wrong. I want to be really clear here and they should feel bad.
I'm comfortable with that point.
Here's the worst thing they actually ran this by for sort of
public comments on a couple of mailing lists because this was actually,
this document was brought to my attention by a local listener who's like, Kurt,
have you this document.
It's bad and I read it and I'm like, wow, it's really bad. Have they updated it since?
Right? Because this is from July of 2020.
And he's like, well,
they actually ran it by on a one or two mailing
list and got a bunch of obviously hugely negative feedback.
And I'm like, oh cool. So is there an updated version?
He's like, no, this is what they ran with.
And so they, they chose to go with this, they chose to, you know,
coat the floor in slippery stuff and tell people to run on it.
-- So
-- here's, here's my suspicion.
Number one, not stupid. Ok.
I think it's really important to be careful calling people stupid because
I think this is an example of good intentions gone bad.
And my guess is somebody put together a document that gave them warm fuzzies.
I bet if you asked for sources to back any of this up, there's none.
-- Well,
-- yeah, there's no links to sources in this document.
Well,
we know there aren't any if there are sources they're
all going to link to like Microsoft blogs from 2005.
So there's no real sources. This is warm fuzzy
-- and my guess is they showed this to
-- people.
Well, it's not warm fuss, it's fear, uncertainty and doubt. It's classic fuzz. OK?
It is.
But whoever, but the person who wrote it probably was like, oh,
I've done a great thing.
Look what I did.
They showed it to someone their baby got called ugly and I bet they doubled down on.
No, this is right.
And the,
the fact that these stupid hippies won't agree with me
means I'm more right than I thought I was before.
-- That is my suspicion.
-- I mean, because the second page is basically all these awards.
It's things like considerations for using OS S blah, blah, blah.
Before acquiring new software,
your organization should determine the level of risk
that is tolerable and can be accepted.
That's true of all your, that's risk management.
-- That's true of buying lettuce like, yeah.
-- Yeah, you don't,
you don't buy the brown
-- squishy lettuce.
-- That's right. My lettuce is covered in manure.
-- Let's buy that
-- lettuce before installing new software.
Your organization needs measures to detect
and mitigate vulnerabilities such as logs,
audits and incident
processes. Yeah,
I
like that.
You know, like when using OS S,
you should manage all Os S using the same
procedures and tools that you use for commercial products.
Yeah.
Like, I mean,
-- ok,
-- I think you're right in that somebody wanted to, yeah,
write something about Os S open source security and yeah, they got it really wrong.
So the other half of this, I bet is you and I
have a great deal of background in dealing with security people. And
I would be willing to bet a pint
that the feedback they received was
difficult to read. We'll say, I bet it was harsh and, and not wrong,
but it was probably, I mean, this is one of the challenge with it with humans, right?
Is if, if I show you something and you're like, that's the worst thing I've ever seen.
I'm not going to listen to you anymore. Yeah.
I'm
be like, well, I think Kurt's an idiot even though you might be right.
I'm not going to listen.
Well,
they've done those studies that show that people who hold factually incorrect,
I guess opinions would be the word, whatever,
factually incorrect beliefs that if you hit them with actual facts,
-- like provable facts, they just dig in harder
-- and,
and what's even better is there is a number of studies that both
prove and disprove that point and you get to pick the one you like
based on the fact that this got published under, you know, their official flagship.
It's got like an its
APP number and all that other stuff.
This is part of their catalog of documentation
that they've published on their website that's official.
And now like we haven't been particularly kind to this document already.
And I guess here's the challenge now is let's say we run across this, which we did.
How do you possibly
open a dialogue with a group like this and say, let me help you.
And this is the thing they literally say need help or have questions,
want to stay up to date and find out more on all things.
Cybersecurity.
Come visit us at the Canadian Center for cybersecurity at cyber dot gc dot C A.
And did you do that?
Well, yeah, and it's, it's a government website, GC dot C A government of Canada.
I mean, good luck submitting a bug against their document.
That's a good point.
-- Actually,
-- there's a contact information and it is contact at cyber dot GC dot ca
and a toll free number and then a media relations link.
Good luck going in through the front door and trying to get them to understand that,
you know,
there's this grossly factually incorrect document on your
website that I think you should update.
-- So
-- actually, that's, that's a really interesting thing.
You just said, you said it's factually incorrect.
Could we prove it is wrong by providing alternative source?
This?
I believe so,
I don't think we can other than our
entertainment podcast posing as a security podcast potential.
You know what I mean? Like,
I think there's,
there are a lot of opinion pieces that talk about this,
but do we have actual research we could point at and say this is wrong because of this?
-- I think we'd struggle to find it,
-- we could point it.
So for example,
the CV database to point out that the closed source
has just about the same level of problems and,
you know, zero days as the
-- open source.
-- What do you point at though?
If I'm someone who doesn't know what that data is?
I can't say, oh, here's a data set of prose descriptions.
Go mine it and find out that you're wrong. OK. True. I mean, you can't do that.
Part of the problem is that kind of work and data would be horrendously expensive.
And difficult to do correctly.
Like what I keep coming back to is with this whole COVID thing
is we still can't figure out if vitamin D is really important or,
and it seems like it's really important.
But every study I've read that says it's really important is not super great
-- and perfect in the sense of like vitamin C and scurvy
-- in that context.
Usually a research paper like that in the medical field,
they'll spend like five years working on it,
-- right? COVID is like a year old.
-- Yes and no.
Because for example,
some of the studies have taken mass sampling of vitamin
D levels in patients and looked at hospital outcomes.
And is there a correlation, right,
have specific branches of statistics and math and
medicine to do that kind of data analysis,
correlation doesn't mean causation.
But there are specific branches of medicine
-- and biology and statistics to determine
-- that
whatever I'm not talking about COVID COVID is depressing and I hate it.
But the point is that in our universe, we don't necessarily have data either way.
-- I
-- would
-- say we probably don't have data either way because the
whole thing is just such a train wreck and tire fire.
And but here
thing is if you explain to someone that here are two products, one of them,
you can look at all of the source code and evildoers can find out what's wrong with it
and the other one is secret and the evil doers can't find out what's wrong with it.
-- Which one feels more right. You know what I mean?
-- Oh, yeah.
Well,
and especially if you don't have an understanding of
open source security or open source in general.
Exactly.
And it is a very difficult problem and, I mean,
you and I obviously are huge fans of open source and
we talk about open source security more than is healthy.
I wouldn't say I'm a fan so much of it as it's just,
it's an acceptance that like sidewalks and roads.
It's just how life is.
I am a fan of open source.
-- I'm not even going to pretend I'm not,
-- it's like saying I'm a fan of electricity.
-- I'm also a fan of roads and sidewalks.
-- I love electricity. I love it.
I love it so much. Um, but anyway, that's, that's neither here nor there.
I'm not talking about whatever bizarre hacking project I have in the basement.
But the point is we are very opinionated on this topic. And so we get riled up.
I guess I see this two ways.
There's the angle of how do we describe this
using data to prove our points or alternatively,
like open source one who cares?
-- Shut up. You know what I mean?
-- Well, that's, and that's a very valid point.
Open source is that is well past the tipping point,
like we don't have to fight for it anymore.
Microsoft is, oh, what did Microsoft announce they were shipping in windows,
-- everything,
-- basically.
I mean, I'm honestly in all seriousness, I am shocked they haven't
like open source windows at this point and then, like, screw it. There you go.
There's some, well, there's a bunch of legal reasons they can't, that could be,
that's probably fair.
You know,
there's a bunch of IP and patent and intellectual stuff
that really sort of prevents them from doing that.
-- And
-- I bet there's enormous quantities of code they didn't write because
-- they either bought or acquired from somewhere
-- more to the point.
-- Who cares?
-- Yeah. Right. Exactly. Exactly.
They're not being super evil this decade and I can, I can live with it.
No. Really? Right.
Like they're, they're, I can't speak for them next decade,
but this decade appears to be on an upward swing for open source support.
I agree.
I've had,
I've had so many conversations about this where people are just every
now and then you'll run into someone and they'll be like,
oh, Microsoft Evil Empire.
It's like, actually
I know it's a sample size one but I am reasonably
happy running windows 10 on my main desktop and I am pretty
diehard Linux supporter fan, whatever you want to call it.
-- So,
-- well, it runs Linux
better than some Linuxes do.
Yeah.
Yes.
-- Anyway, anyway, part of it
-- though,
I worry that if they got this something and I'm
not going to say simple because it's not simple.
But if they got something that is reasonably simple, this wrong.
It also makes me wonder what else they're getting wrong in their other documents.
-- Everything
-- look
just because it's a government organization and
just because they might be in theory,
the experts on a particular topic, it doesn't necessarily mean they're correct.
I mean, this is why when you read a research page,
the last 10 pages are links to other research
papers because if you don't provide your sources,
like, is it actually a researched paper or is this just some crap, someone made up?
And my guess is this is just some crap, someone made up? Yeah.
Well, like you said, it's recycled talking points from 20 years ago. Yeah.
And my guess is it was, I don't know, someone
who knows what the inception of this was, but absolutely, there's,
there's no data behind this.
This is nonsense talking.
And I mean, unfortunately, refuting this other than, you know,
whinging on a podcast is, is going to take enormous effort for zero gain.
Like, really and more importantly, let's face it.
How many companies are going to read this and be like, oh,
maybe I shouldn't run open source.
It's like, no, they won't. They'll be like, yeah, whatever. This is stupid.
-- Somebody is probably consuming this. I hope it's not many people.
-- I doubt it.
-- I seriously doubt it. Well, no,
-- no, no, I'm just thought experimenting.
So,
assuming people are consuming this and their technical
people are most likely going to say,
well, this is true of all soft.
Yeah.
Like it's not specific to open source. And also that ship sailed.
And my thought on this is if somebody in management reads
this and then overrules their texts with respect to open source,
those texts were doomed to begin with.
I mean, I absolutely,
this feels like if someone said 50 years ago telephones are bad, stop using them,
we'd all be like you're an idiot.
-- No,
-- the letter will never die.
That's just what I feel like here, I, I don't,
I don't think anyone's going to take this seriously.
And my suspicion is this is going to make the group who's,
I've already forgotten in the Canadian government.
It's just going to make them look dumb and it's going to damage your credibility.
That's all this is going to do.
Yeah.
Yeah. It amuses me still to, to read topics like this just because
it is,
I have a feeling we're going to be talking about this
until we die and then the next generation will talk about this until they die and then
hopefully the machines take over and then we
just don't have to talk about it anymore.
-- We've still got, people won't wear their
-- seatbelts.
I mean, I
think I keep looking up, seatbelt compliance percentage wise.
Let me just pull this up. But in Canada there are some shockingly low numbers.
-- What do you mean by shockingly low?
-- Ok.
So the highest is, ironically, British Columbia at 96.9%.
So that means 3.1% of people aren't wearing their seatbelts.
-- And the lowest is if you go to the Yukon, it's 78.1%. I mean,
-- that doesn't surprise.
So, so many of our listeners probably don't know the geography of Canada. Right.
British Columbia
-- is British Columbia the most populous part of Canada.
-- No.
British Columbia is not the most populous,
but essentially the majority of British Columbia
lives in and around Vancouver metro area.
Yeah. It's the very west coast of Canada, very west as far west as you can go.
And, and most of them are very south west and south in that particular province.
-- Very close to the United States.
-- Yeah.
Well, cause the top half of BC is just mountains and trees.
Now the Yukon is, there's like, what, 30 people who live there?
-- Probably
-- no, no, no, Bob moved. So it's 31
but,
-- but it's, it's not populated hardly
-- at
-- all.
-- Well, there's white horse basically.
And then there's some people living out in the boonies.
It's definitely a low population level.
And now like,
I know people in so I live in Wisconsin and northern
Wisconsin we'll say is a pretty wild region of the country.
It's very densely forested.
Well,
and the Yukon is quite a bit larger than Wisconsin and
I just checked the population is like 36,000 people in total.
And if, and if you were to remove white horse,
then that would be pretty much most of them.
Right. Right. And, and the point is
I found when you have these very low population areas, like,
I have family members who live in northern Wisconsin
and they don't wear their seatbelts because they're like,
there's nobody here.
I don't care.
And it's like, I'm not going to disagree with you,
but you should still wear your seatbelt.
I remember being a child and they had that car safety thing where
it was like a car seat with the seatbelt and they put you in it and then they basically,
it went down a little ramp and slammed you into a stop bumper.
So you felt the,
it was simple,
like a five or six mile per hour
impact. It's simulated and holy, geez. Right. It,
that was a lot of force at five or six miles an hour.
You know,
they slide you down this 10 ft ramp basically
and just wham you stop and you hit the seatbelt
and it was a shocking amount of force to me as a child.
And, and I really took home the lesson of, yeah,
wear your seatbelt because if you crash a car at 3040 miles an hour, you know, and,
and the reason I'm speaking in Imperial is to
out of sensitivity for Josh and his people,
you know,
it's, yeah,
it's even a low speed crash is a shocking amount of force for that human body.
It is. It is. But, but people are bad at risk management.
And so people assume if I'm the only person on the road for
thousands of kilometers or miles or whatever.
Yeah, you can still drive into a ditch.
Well, I know that's the thing,
right is you're probably going to a moose is almost definitely more dangerous
than another car in that context because if you hit a moose,
you're going to stop
up abruptly.
Well, a few months ago there was that Moose that actually got hit by a car,
killed a bunch of people in it and then got hit by
another car and killed one or two people in that car.
-- And I was just like, these things are horrific. I mean,
-- they're enormous
until you see a moose. You don't understand how big a moose is. It is ridiculous.
-- Imagine a small minivan on
-- stilts. Seriously enormous stilts.
You could walk under the, it's like, it's completely ridiculous.
But anyway, anyway, anyway, the point is humans are bad at risk management.
People in an unpopulated area and they think, oh, I'll, I'll be fine. Right.
It's the same thing on the internet where people are, like, oh,
no one's going to find my computer.
I don't need to install those updates and then, oh, ha ha. Yeah, you did.
It's just human nature, man. And then,
and then I guess we end up in a situation where somebody writes
a report that has no data that can back it up but whatever,
nobody cares.
And, and I guess ironically now that this exists,
someone could point to it as an official resource,
you know what I mean
in some other report? Because now it's technically like real data.
It's,
it's like those people who update Wikipedia to point to a news
article at Wikipedia and then update the Wikipedia with the news article
to point out that this is real now.
Yep. Yep. I do. I remember that. Anyway. Anyway, we are, we are nearly out of time.
I will, as this is a Canadian report, I will give you the last word.
Be kind to each other, please. It's, you know,
isn't that just the Canadian way?
No.
-- Have you seen what we've done with our indigenous peoples?
-- Ok.
All right. That's, that's true.
That's true.
You've just smashed the image of friendly Canada for every
-- look up orange shirt day at school.
-- I maybe I probably don't need to do that.
I don't want to. I have enough bad news. All right.
Anyway, I'm calling it before we depress anyone else further. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you for listening. Go to massage
security, podcast.com. Head up the show note, Suzy
Pound To us
Podcast. Hashtag Do hit us up on social media. Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks
-- everybody. Bye bye.