Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 87 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
-- Josh Bresser.
-- Kurt. I'm excited today. We have a guest.
We have Josh Os from Let's encrypt. Hi, happy to be here. Thanks, Josh.
So why don't, why don't you tell us a little bit about kind of yourself?
And let's encrypt, which, which I must admit, Kurt and I are huge fanboys of
great.
So my name is Josh Os.
I'm the executive director and a co-founder of Lots and Crypt.
Although lets encrypt is actually the name of a service, the company behind it,
the nonprofit is internet security Research Group.
And we started this all up in early
2013 mainly because I was working on uh networking security at Mozilla.
And it was really frustrating the slow pace
at which sites were transitioning to htps.
And from the browser side, there's not really much that we can do about it, you know,
sites either
make the switch or they don't and we just
have to accept whatever they do in the browser.
So I started thinking about with some colleagues, you know, what,
what needs to happen
to
help sites switch to HPS at a faster pace.
And we talked to a bunch of people about
what the hang up was and there, there are a bunch of complications.
But the biggest thing that we, we heard was
that people had a really hard time getting and managing certificates
that the process was really difficult. It also costs money.
It was hard to figure out exactly what you should be doing.
So we started focusing on this question of
a,
you know, how can we make getting in managing certificates easier?
And another way in which this really came to the fore for us was that we were
at the time working on standardizing HTP two.
And there was a big debate in
the U BC
working group about whether or not the protocol would require
TLS.
Ah Right. Right. I remember that.
Yeah,
the obvious answer on the face of it is that at,
at this day and age knowing what we know,
we should definitely not be making any new protocols that aren't secure.
That seems like an obvious piece of wisdom one would think.
But at the time,
there was a really great objection raised to that and I was,
I desperately wanted them to require CTLS.
But there was an objection that I just couldn't shake,
which is that if you require TLS, you will make htps.
Well, you, you'll make H TB two
much more difficult to deploy
and you'll make it pay to play,
meaning you will not be able to deploy
HB two without paying someone for a certificate
-- if you
-- want to talk to the world. Yeah. No, that's
true. Right.
And you're a very unequal playing field
around the globe
in terms of access, price,
things like that and in terms of education
and knowledge about how to deploy TLS properly.
II, I think that's super fair and I guess for some historical context here, for,
for anyone who might not know is
prior to let's encrypt
getting a certificate was fairly expensive in many cases.
I mean, you're generally talking
50 to $70 a year in some cases, which
it doesn't,
right.
I mean, that doesn't sound like a ton of money necessarily, but I mean,
let's face it like when I was a broke college kid, I didn't,
I didn't have a TLS certificate.
Yeah, TLS certificate
just because like that was, that was beer money. Right.
And so in
and Right. Right.
And then I,
I remember when L and Crip came along
and you guys were talking about free certificates,
I thought like, how, how on earth are the, are the Cas gonna let this happen?
And thankfully it did because your, your service is amazing and obviously the,
the price is right.
And so
I guess why, why don't you tell us for, for a few moments, kind of
what is the fundamental model of how let's and crypt works because it,
it kind of deviates from the traditional universe of CAS.
Right.
Yeah. So
we wanna make certificates
easy to use primarily.
And although sometimes people think of us as a free C A
free is really in service to ease of use, the reason that RC A is free
has less to do about not being able to charge some
very small amount and more to do with the fact that
if we start charging people for certificates, it really complicates
getting and managing certificates.
So imagine your,
you know, it's just admitted a small company or let's say a huge company, right?
You're in a fortune 500 company and you want to set up
a little web server to do something that's not gonna be very important. Right?
But if you need to pay anything for that certificate, even if it's a penny,
you gotta go find a credit card, you gotta get approval from finance,
you gotta plug that card in.
You know, you're gonna have to pay attention to when that card expires.
So your cert doesn't stop and your site doesn't come down.
You've now taken what could have happened in one second with no thought whatsoever
and turned it into what a 30 minute
endeavor here if you're lucky. Right.
Yeah. If you're lucky. Right.
I can relate to this because previously with the cloud security line.
So I ended up actually,
basically it was
not only cheaper from the number of certificates we needed.
But it was way less hassle to just get one
wild card certificate and use that on every server which,
you know, from a security point of view and compartmentalization,
sort of least privilege is terrible.
But from like making my life a whole pile simpler,
like only having to deal with one certificate every two years,
you know, it was a no brainer
so I, I can very much relate to that pain.
-- Yeah,
-- the options people had before sort of forced them to make
unfortunate decisions.
Um
So free is so like I was saying, free is really in, in service of ease of use here,
right?
We'd like to get
our goals to, to get to a point where
you barely even need to know that you have a cert or even what a cert is, right?
So
you should just be able to start up your web server and it gets the cert
installs it properly,
configures it properly and just handles the
whole thing without bothering you about anything.
You shouldn't even need to know that the cert exists, right?
-- Um
-- I, I, I'll confirm that that's where we want to go because I'm,
I'm using let's encrypt on my personal web server.
And I actually was, I, I found some other service was,
was handing out very inexpensive certs
and I had to generate my own certificate and, and get the CS R, right? Which took me
longer than it should I embarrassingly admit?
And then, and then got it and put it in place.
And then once a year I had to remember how to do this.
And then you guys came along and I literally, I have a script,
I run that's running in Cron
and I don't, it's magic, right? Like it's amazing.
It's amazing what you people have done.
Yeah.
From, from an ease of use point of view,
even using the acronym CS R let
alone requiring your customers to actually generate one
is craziness, right?
Like
that's, that is so hostile to use of use.
It's, it's,
I guess we should also clarify CS R as a cer certificate signing request,
which is kind of the thing you send off to the C A and, and they sign
and then give back to you. And it was, it's a terrible experience.
-- Yeah, it's really difficult to generate
-- that.
What I love is, it's so terrible that some cas
will let you generate the key and CS R on like via their web server
to make it easier.
And then of course, as we discussed last week with uh was it Trusco?
Yeah. Right. Right.
And the breach of 23,000 private keys, I mean,
yeah, this, this clearly is not a great system and not very fun.
Yeah, that's kind of taking it too far in the other direction.
You don't need to generate people's private keys for them
just to get rid of CS RS, right?
So, and one thing I'm not 100% clear on is, so what's the relationship between,
let's Encrypt and cbot?
Are they the same thing or different?
So initially, when lets encrypt started,
we had a client called Let's Encrypt
and we distributed that client
and it was developed partially with our developers,
but a lot of developers from eff as well.
And after some number of months of doing that, we realized that
we're never going to be able to produce
a client
that works for everyone
or even the vast majority of people.
There's software deployment environments, you know,
different types of web servers and web server,
software operating systems architectures
there, there's a huge diversity out there.
And the only way that we're gonna build clients that work for everyone is
to depend on our community to build the things that matter to them.
So
the second issue we have is that we wanted our client, you know,
lots of crypto is built around an
open protocol called
ACME
automated certificate management.
-- E stands for environment.
-- OK. Can I interrupt for one moment and ask, is that a
acronym because I'm like a huge looney tunes fan. And when I saw
Acme, it made my day.
Yeah, all of our stuff is named after like a road runner.
So the software that we use to build our, that we used to run our C A is called Boulder.
It has a smaller
smaller cousin named Pebble.
Um
We use it a lot internally too.
That's
ok. I'm, I'm sorry to interrupt. So, so back to Acne,
no worries.
So we use this open protocol ST standardized by the ITF,
you know, we, we started this protocol,
but we moved into the standards process and our
hope is that many CAS will use this protocol.
So we want all the clients that work with Lots and Crypt to also work with other cas.
And the problem with having a client named Lots Encrypt
as you run into a bunch of trademark issues,
when you have a client named, that's
Encrypt getting certificates from AC A that's not lots encrypt.
That's fair. So for,
for two reasons, we decided to, to stop producing a client. One is that
we were not going to get the coverage that we wanted.
We wanted our community to decide what's important.
And also this trademark issue would require us to at least rename it anyway.
So given these challenges,
um we talked to the folks at eff who are
doing most of the develop development at that point anyway.
And we said, hey, why don't we just make this an eff project?
You guys take the client rename it,
run with it
and that's what we did. So
CBO
is the new name for the client
and it is owned by Electronic Frontier Foundation now and they do a great job with it.
That's awesome. That, that's very very open source. I like it.
Yeah, I guess my second question would be, are there any other CAS that support the
Acme protocol right now?
I have heard that some do, I don't have direct experience with it.
Um Often for automated certificate, certificate protocols.
For, for like a large commercial C A, you'll sometimes need to be a
enterprise customer or something with access to their API, you set up a contract,
get access to the API.
I have heard that some large CAS offer ACNE
as an API option. If you're an enterprise customer,
there's also one or two other smaller CAS that
have at least been talking about doing it.
I think, I think one actually does maybe
a Norwegian C A called bypass. Um
I'm not very sure on the details of that though.
Nice.
-- Yeah,
-- because I was, I was wondering my,
my understanding of the ACNE protocols is just purely the technical side.
It doesn't, for example, have like payment stuff built into it.
It has the ability to connect to a payment system.
So we made sure to do that so that commercial CAS
could also use the protocol. So
commercial CCAS are a really important part of the ecosystem.
They provide a lot of things that we don't,
they're really important part of the ecosystem and we want to make sure that
they're also doing things in the, in the best way possible
and coming up with a certificate issuance
and management protocol is really difficult.
It's, it's really hard to secure those things.
Um, we've had a lot of industry experts. Look at our protocol.
We have paid for formal validation, cryptographic validation.
We've paid for many audits of the protocol. This protocol is, is pretty,
pretty well vetted about, as about as well as you can do. Right.
I mean, there's always a potential for a problem but it's, it's a really
well developped protocol and
it would be better for everybody if we all just used
Acme instead of inventing our own
proprietary protocol,
that doesn't get that kind of community review and industry review.
So
we'd like to see standardization on ACNE for security reasons.
But also because it makes life much easier for people who are
getting and managing certificates, right?
So if all software works with Acne Cas,
then you can just pick and choose whatever C A you want to get a cert from
aim your software at that and go.
So interoperability and security are really important reasons why we
would like the C A industry to standardize an Acne.
That is fantastic.
Now,
you said something that's kind of spiked my interest
a little bit is you mentioned about having a
healthy C A ecosystem with kind of traditional commercial players that exist is
I, I guess I don't understand some of the goals of your organization.
So explain to me kind of what is the vision you see in terms of of
the let's encrypt service
with, with existing, you know, kind of four pay cas.
Sure.
So our goal at let's encrypt is to provide a free certificate to
people anywhere in the world in a really easy to use way.
I think that's an essential part of moving forward with the web.
If you want to have 100% encrypted way web,
you can't require everybody on the web to pay for a certificate
and you can't require everybody on the web to be an expert who can, you know,
bre easily generate CS RS anytime they
want.
But you also need to support
people who, who
have other needs.
And at less encrypt, you know,
we work really hard to work at volume and keep things simple.
But
people have means that lots encrypt doesn't satisfy, right.
So for example, we have one certificate lifetime, 90 days
if you want another lifetime.
So I talked to a Fortune 500 company the other day that said
we would actually like lifetimes to be five weeks.
And at the moment, we don't support that. We're not able to
tailor what we do to particular individual subscribers.
But that company is able to go to one of
a number of commercial cas and say here are my needs
and they'll cater to them.
Another thing that we don't offer directly is direct support. So if you,
if you really want to be able to call someone up
two in the morning and talk about your certain issues you're having with it.
We're not, we're not going to be able to do that. We have,
you know, we,
we help secure something around 70 million websites and we've got a staff of
12 people full time. That's awesome. So,
support is not really
direct support is not really something we can do.
We do have great community support.
So we have community forums and we have a
huge community that does a great job answering questions
and that works really well. But it's not,
they're not people that you can call up,
you know, whatever you want and talk about sort,
whereas commercial providers
provide really great support
or many of them do.
So if that's something you need, you know,
commercial provider can make a lot of sense.
There's other cert types. Um Ovev,
we don't do that.
Those are, are just,
there's three basic kinds of certs we offer DVOV and EV are different,
different types of certs.
We don't offer those if that's what you want, commercial providers can do that.
The main reason we don't offer them
is because they can't be automated
so they don't scale very well. But if that's what you want,
commercial providers are happy to help you. So
there's a lot of, you know,
we talked a lot about diversity of deployment environments already.
That also means that people have different needs for CAS and, and we need
a number of different cas out there to fill those needs.
So, just a quick note for our listeners.
So the,
the three different kinds of validation are DVOV and EV and DV is domain validated,
which is literally a fancy way of saying,
you know, this site claims to be cre.org and
it is
cre.org as far as we can tell
OV is organizational validated and there, they're actually validating, you know,
the organization that's getting the
certificate that, you know,
that organization is actually Walmart or some bank or something.
And then EV is extended validation.
And, uh,
I'm not really clear on how it's that much different than OV, to be honest,
I don't know if, you know,
um,
but fundamentally for like 99% of the world,
we use domain validated certificates.
And, uh, I mean, a great example of this is Amazon,
like Amazon doesn't even bother to use the fancier certificates.
They just use a domain validated certificate.
And, um, so that I guess leads to my next question,
which was so obviously let's encrypt and, you know, CBOT
will work for public facing websites that have a, a public name, right?
Uh Is there any plan support or is there any way to get, you know,
free certificates for internal facing websites that,
you know, may not have a public name or may not even have a name at all and maybe just,
you know, an IP address of, you know, 10.0 0.0 0.1.
Yeah. So
there's one thing that people can do today, which is
we can validate your domain using DNS records.
So one option you have today is to create a public DNS record for your server
and then validate by putting the validation information in the DNS record.
And then we don't actually need to connect to the server to validate.
So
let me take a step back here and say that there's three ways that, well,
two ways that we can do domain validation right now,
one is that we can contact the server and
have the server do something special to demonstrate that the server actually,
you know, is controlling the domain.
The other way is we can
check your control the domain by checking DNS records.
So the advantage of DNS records is that we don't actually have to talk to the server.
So you can make a public DNS record for a server with the domain.
And then
we don't care what IP address is pointing at because
we don't actually need to talk to the server.
We have, you do special things with the DNS record itself.
The downside of that is that it's harder to
automate management of DNS than it is to automate
certain things about the web server itself.
So that's the solution that's available today is to validate
with a public DNS record for an internal server.
And we know a lot of companies
that do that
we have heard a lot of demand for
the space in general to make it even
easier for people to validate for internal servers.
It's a difficult problem. We are
thinking about it and
I wouldn't be surprised if it's something we
try to work on more in the future.
That, that is fantastic. In fact, I just had a conversation about this the other day
because one of the challenges you get when you're doing some internal TLS
is your options are basically give a user ac A
that they have to somehow import into their client,
which let's face it.
Most people just end up with like a root C A that trusts
star which ends up making you substantially less secure if you do that
or we train users to click the Yeah, everything's fine here.
Go away http S warning, which is also not good behavior.
And so this is, this is a super annoying problem, honestly.
Yeah, we, we talked to some,
some large companies about this including large financial companies and they say,
you know, we're really trying to secure our networks,
but we've got 5000 internal servers that don't use TLS.
And
that's a, you know, that's a tough problem to deal with.
So I'm curious, what do you think? Because uh so actually uh what is it?
April 30th chrome is making one change where
they're going to require certificates to be in the, you know,
in at least two of the certificate, transparency logs.
Uh and then Chrome uh Google has also said that in uh what is it July of 2018.
So this summer build 68 of chrome
is, you know, rather than labeling http S websites as secure,
it's going to start labeling http websites as insecure
sort of flipping the the default as it were from, you know,
being secure is good to being insecure or being HTTP is bad.
Uh So I'm curious what you think about this.
That's a really important step that chrome is taking to label
playing HTP sites is not secure.
When I think about,
you know, the biggest day to day security disasters, we have
one of the biggest ones is that right now when you visit a web page
in a web browser
and it's not using
htps,
the browser just acts like everything is totally fine.
-- That's
-- everything is fine, right? Nothing to see here. Move along.
Yeah,
all of the web browsers are really,
really take security seriously, right? Like they've got
engineers who are constantly making security
fixes thinking really hard about security.
But then when we visit a site that's spraying
your information all over the web with no security,
the browser really just says nothing about it. Everything is fine here, you know,
so it's really important that browsers start seeing something about it.
In addition to keeping people more informed,
it has a it's going to have a big impact on
how many sites use htps,
you know,
the availability of something like lots and crypt that makes it free and easy
to get a certificate will motivate a bunch of people to do it.
Well, not just that, I mean, I think outside of motivation, if you guys didn't exist
Chrome and Firefox couldn't take these actions, right?
Just because I, I think the bar was unnecessarily high prior to let's encrypt.
Yeah. So the game plan all along has been
for us to do as much as we can to deliver the browsers,
the numbers that they need to make this kind of thing possible.
They don't want to create warning fatigue for their users.
So they don't want to show a warning on every single
web page because then people just start ignoring the warning.
So the warning has to be rare enough that people don't start ignoring it. Our
job is to give the browsers that
the numbers that they need to start turning in on those
warnings and then make them more and more severe over time.
Well, and one thing I noticed too with chrome was that they were going to um
with the uh the transparency log stuff in April. They said basically
the main page will if it's corrected a load and if it's, you know, not
corrected will you'll get a warning but be able to click through.
But that the
third party elements embedded in that page,
which let's face it as a fancy way of saying like ad networks and stuff
simply will not be loaded.
And that struck me as a really kind of good
decision because, you know, you're no longer sending an alarm to the user.
It's just like, you know what this,
this third party element that the page wants to load, it's not secure.
So, or it's not, you know, in the transparency logs.
So we're just not going to load it right?
We're not going to tell the user we're not going to bug the user.
Um
And I'm wondering maybe if that's part of the way forwards is, you know,
to essentially just
uh
not bug the user and just not load the content.
Yeah. So there's, there are a lot of things that can evolve and how
web browsers behave and display information to users.
I think it,
the more they do to not load not secure content. The better
I think,
you know, the first big step here is to label plain HTP sites
as not secure.
I think another important step that's gonna have to happen down this
road is that the lock icon is gonna need to go away.
So right now you see a lock icon
when a page uses H gps,
that lock icon really overpromise things for users.
So when you see that lock icon, you might think, oh, this web page is secure,
it doesn't mean that it's secure or safe necessarily.
It doesn't mean that the contents of the web page are safe.
It doesn't mean you're not gonna get scammed.
It doesn't mean you're not gonna get malware.
It doesn't mean that,
you know, the people operating the site aren't criminals.
It just means that you have a secure connection
to whoever's on the other end of the line.
And I think people really don't understand that point.
Yeah.
Seriously, man, I, I, that comes up all the time when I talk to non technical users.
Is there
like, oh, it has a lock, it's fine and it's like,
yep, sure is.
It's not even worth trying to explain it to them because it's so complicated and,
and I feel like
what, what you're talking about is totally correct of just,
yeah,
stop showing it to people because it provides a
false sense of security which is super dangerous,
obviously.
Yeah. H gps shouldn't have a lock. Htps should be the new normal, right?
What you see today is your browser looks normal when there's no security.
When there's no htps, we need the normal state to be secure
and get rid of the lock icon because I think it's really confusing to people.
I agree 100%.
That's, that's awesome.
-- It'll take some time, but I think we'll get there
-- because I,
so I was looking at htps adoption and it's um from all the sources,
I found it's essentially
a
pretty
like steady line headed up, which is good,
but like the slope on that line is not what you would call steep.
And I'm wondering, um, like, what's the adoption you've seen?
Has it been sort of slow and steady or have there been upticks as these things change?
Like, are you expecting basically this summer to get hammered when you know,
all the site operators
have their users freak out on them?
I do expect our traffic to grow.
Um I, I expect it to grow pretty significantly as a result of,
of this change in the chrome U I.
Once people see their site label is not secure,
they're probably gonna start running around trying to figure out
the fastest way to get a certain.
And I think for a lot of people that's gonna be less encrypt.
I think the the really important number though is not
how many certs we issue because
that
doesn't have a ton of context, right?
It it matters for our capacity planning, but the really important numbers
and I think
these numbers are really impressive is that
when LUTS and crypts started
just under 40%
of page loads on the web.
So every time someone loads a page that's a page load, just under 40% of the time
page loads used H gps.
And that's
I think December 2015,
so late 2015 and that's 20 years of progress. So
SSL had been around for about 20 years at that point
that 20 years of progress. So on average
2% points a year.
That's how things were increasing
since then in the two, in, in a little over two years.
Since then, we're now passing 70%.
So we're doing around 15% per year right now
in increased htps usage in terms of page loads.
And now do you guys know what percentage of that is? You?
It's hard to say, right?
A lot of people put a lot of work into promoting a gps, you know,
browsers play a big role.
Come on, man, I just gave you a huge opportunity to take
up
here. Right.
Yeah,
I mean,
I think there is a big uptick in that number literally the day LS Encrypt launches.
So there is no question that we are a major driver of that growth.
Exactly how much I can take credit for, for lots encrypt,
you know, I, I'm not totally sure, clearly, we are a major driver of that.
Right. Right.
So we're doing about 15% improvement per year on the web. And that's crazy. I mean,
I, I don't think that anything else has ever changed on the web
at 15% per year. That was so fundamental to how the web works, right?
Like you're changing all the bits on the wire and
you're moving the web at 15% a year right now.
That's crazy.
I mean, compare that to something like I PV six, right?
Which is a really, another really important thing that the web needs to move towards
and that kind of adoption is really slow.
It's really hard to change the internet how it works. Right.
There's a lot of legacy stuff out there.
It's expensive to change stuff at scale,
15% a year is a stunning rate of change and we're doing it
and at this pace, you know, we're going to be almost at 100% soon.
I, I think I would blame the web browsers for a lot of this because I mean,
look at web browsers today,
you you install your web browser and it
basically just takes care of itself after that,
right?
All the care and feeding is magic and
users are almost always running the latest version.
And I mean, heck man,
how long did IE six hang on where sites were concerned about supporting
it just because so many people were using it and it was,
it was embarrassing,
right? Whereas now
I feel like with the way what you see with Safari, Firefox and Chrome is, you know,
you're along for the ride whether you want to or not.
So you can start doing some of these interesting things because you
don't worry about people being stuck on some obscenely old version anymore,
right?
Yeah.
Well,
browsers are actually a relatively easy way to move things for the
reason that you said they can quickly update many millions of people,
right?
The problem is when you need to take it make a change to
the web that requires action on behalf of people who run web servers
because that's not on the auto update train. Right? Like, yeah, that's fair.
That's fair.
There's tons of different kinds of web servers and web server software.
If you need everyone who runs a server to act, to make change on the web,
that is really difficult to do.
Well, I'm curious what's because that I've,
that used to be definitely 100% true.
But now, you know, for example,
with cloud flare or actually I just noticed um
a few months ago when Amazon web services,
they have the certificate manager now
with well effectively free certificates. A similar model is less encrypt.
You have to register your domain and kind of prove that
you own it and every what is it quarter roughly.
So I think it's 90 days,
you know, they reissue the certificates.
So it's definitely some of the large providers are definitely addressing this.
And I mean, is that a general trend
you're seeing in the industry or is that kind of
limited to a few of these large players that,
you know, are typically a bit ahead of everybody?
Yeah. So centralization in terms of
how web servers are managed
definitely makes it easier to make change, right? When,
when Amazon has
control over so many web servers, they really have the ability to promote change
relatively easily, right?
You're not talking about a million individual assist
admins running the server under their desk.
Now you're talking about everything centralized in
one platform where you can sort of
apply medicine relatively easily.
So, centralization in web servers, you know,
does have the upside of making change easier.
So
we see big uptakes, for example, when
a large provider like, you know, squarespace or Wix or something like that,
there's many millions of websites on those platforms and they have the ability to
push a gps on those websites relatively easily.
And that's great. You can get 4 million websites
by working with one provider.
That's crazy.
So I I just realized something that when, when Kurt mentioned a quarterly,
quarterly refresh is,
so you said that your
expiration is 90 days, where did 90 days come from?
Well, the exact number of days,
I don't, you know, we picked 90 seemed like a good number.
It's a quarter, right quarter of a year.
The issue is that
long, so long certificate, lifetimes have some problems associated with them.
So,
an important thing to understand before we get into why 90 days
is
that revocation doesn't work.
So there's this kind,
there's this concept of revocation that you can
revoke a certificate, so you can take a valid certificate and if something happens,
you can revoke it and then people will consider it not to be valid
that doesn't work very well at all.
The main reason that doesn't work is because some web
browsers including Chrome don't check revocation status on a normal basis
except for a short list of revocations for really important sites.
But almost certainly,
you know,
sites that you and I are running are not important enough to be on that list.
So
if,
if you revoke a,
a certificate in general
chrome, for example, is not gonna see that revocation,
it's just gonna consider the cert to be valid until the cert expires.
So
that's the first reason that revocation is broken.
The second reason is even if you have a browser that does check revocation status
using a protocol called O CS PO CS P is a fail open protocol.
Meaning if you get no response,
it's considered a good response.
So there
the
is not a very effective way to deal with compromise
once a cert is issued, the reality is
you're stuck with that cert being valid until it expires.
Now, do you remember uh this compromise, the security issue called Heartbleed?
I vaguely recall it,
right? So
heartbleed was a security issue in some software that leaked
a lot of private keys around the world. Right? Suddenly, a lot of people
were concerned that their SSL private keys have been leaked
and the action that was recommended was while everyone
go revoke your certificate and get a new C.
Right.
Yes. And
I think that is still the right thing to do.
But I think we need to be honest about how effective that was, which is not very much.
It was terrible.
I remember after heartbleed, I,
I was using Firefox and I told it to hard fail on O CS P failures.
And like the internet stopped working for me for the most fire.
I think I lasted 15 minutes before I turned it off. It was just embarrassing.
I looked into it and the majority of the CS running O CS P responders
apparently had something like less than 90 like 9 0% uptime
on their O CS P responders for requests or whatever.
Like it was
the failure rate. It was,
was just absurd. Like it's unusable at that point.
Yeah,
there used to be these horror stories about CS that had poor R CS P
responders because they didn't want to spend money on more ra M for the server.
Um It's a historically under invested thing, although
a lot of CASU use big C DNS now and the availability is much better.
But anyway, when heartbleed happened,
everyone rushed out to revoke their certs which didn't really do much
and get new certs. So if your private key did leak during heartbleed
and let's say you went out and
you know, paid a lot of money for a three year cert, right?
And you did that last month.
Now someone has your private key
and a cert that's valid for three years,
right?
And there's really nothing that you can do about it.
You're just stuck until that cert expires
Right. And that situation is why we,
we do 90 days certs. So that's encrypt
in a heartbleed scenario. All of our certs clear the system
in under 90 days.
So
if heartbleed happened again,
all lots and crypt certs subject to something like private key compromise
would clear out of the system in less than 90 days.
And the incident would essentially be over for those people. I think.
So.
That's,
that's the reason to have a shorter cert
lifetime in order to enable short lifetimes.
Right? Nobody wants to go get a cert every 60 days, which is what we recommend.
But the whole point here is automation,
you can't have ease of use of that automation.
Yeah,
I was gonna say because part one of the things I run into is by buying like
two year certificates is I basically have to like
relearn the whole process every two years because,
you know, I've forgotten it and, you know, having it.
Yeah, every 90 days either.
Yeah,
I'll automate it or I have to do it often enough that chances are I'll remember it.
Although,
hopefully, yeah, it would be automated.
And I think that's something really important because, yeah, these things,
you know, it's like people updating their
web browsers and antivirus, they do that regularly.
But how often do people update their, you know, their operating system? Right.
Because that only happens every
couple and also people forget to renew their cert
in two years Right. Like who makes a calendar entry for that?
And then suddenly your c expires and your site goes down.
I'm totally guilty of that.
Well,
it just happened with the Oculus Rift apparently
yesterday or the day before,
apparently all the Oculus Rifts on the planet stopped working because they,
and there was an expired certificate.
Yeah. So the answer is automation. And if your certificate
issuance and management is automated,
then it shouldn't matter to you how often it happens. Right.
Doing it every 60 days doesn't matter to you. If it's automated,
you can do it every 48 hours
and it doesn't matter. Right. Please don't do that though. Right.
I, I mean, I think we may get there someday. Right.
I think 48 hours is not a reasonable amount of time for a cert to last,
but it only works in a world where, you know, environments are very automated.
Right. Right. Absolutely.
We, that's actually a problem with, uh, some of, you know, some of our red hats,
cloud products, like infrastructure stuff.
We do want very short certificate lifespans potentially because it basically,
yeah,
basically makes a whole pile of security problems
either go away or become very minimal.
And that, yeah, if this site or host or whatever is compromised or somebody goofs up.
Yeah, it's valid for like, 48 hours.
No big deal, you know, not a year or two.
and so personally I do think, especially for a lot of internal stuff. It,
it really does make sense to have very short lifespans because,
well, going back to your, you know, your,
your fortune 500 with 5000 internal servers.
Stupid question.
But like, do they have, you know,
when they decommission a server is part of the process,
they're doing the certificate revocation, which, well,
as we've just discussed is basically useless.
You know, if your certificate is 90 days that's less of a problem.
And if it's 48 hours then it's, well, it's effectively not a problem at all.
Awesome. All right. I, I think, I think I'm gonna call it.
This has been a fascinating conversation, I guess Josh.
Do you have any closing thoughts
for the audience?
If your site is not, uh using htps,
make it, use htps
can help. We're happy to help.
If not, there's lots of other cas out there.
Awesome. Yeah, and the,
-- the clock's ticking.
-- Well, thanks for having me. It was nice talking to you.
It was fantastic. I, I appreciate the time and yeah, definitely.
Anytime you want to come back, you let us know we'd,
we'd love to hear what you guys are up to and, and what's going on,
that's encrypt is definitely one of the, the good ones
out there. So. All right. Awesome. So, so thank you, Josh. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you audience for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com and hit up any links to show notes,
we'll,
we'll link to Josh's Twitter and probably some,
let's encrypt things for you to check out and if you want to get a hold of us,
just hit us up with the Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag And yeah, nothing else. Thank you guys. It was an awesome conversation.
-- Thank
-- you.
Thanks
the.