-- What show on 165
-- one 65
-- looks prime.
-- It might be quasi prime. I don't know.
-- That'll never get old.
-- I agree.
Hello and welcome to the open source Security podcast.
Episode 165 with myself, Kurt
Siefried and my partner thought crime. Josh Bresser.
-- Oh,
-- what's new man?
-- Uh,
-- snow? Lots of snow.
-- Yeah.
-- You live really far north and it rains a lot where I live now.
And if, if it was snow I would have like, 4 m of snow,
it would be insane.
So, I'm glad I don't,
we've only had like light flurries that melt as soon as they hit the ground.
But, like south of us in Calgary where they get a lot more humidity. They, uh,
they got foot of snow or something yesterday.
You live in Canada? Aren't you supposed to use the metric system?
Well, I use the metric system for most things,
but if you're asking me my height and weight
and sort of day to day measurements, I tend to default to feet and inches.
But also, well, part of it is all our building supplies are imperial,
like a sheet of play it's four by eight.
-- That's probably because you get them all from the US and
-- we export to the US.
But like IKEA ear
shelves are exactly a foot wide. Like, not about a foot wide, but like
exactly a foot wide.
I
don't know,
I measured because I was measuring them because I wanted to put up some sides on them.
So stuff wouldn't fall off
and I measure it
and I'm like, oh, it's, it's exactly a foot like give or take a half a millimeter.
But I'll use, I'll use millimeters for like that fine,
half a millimeter because I'm not going to be like 1 32nd of an inch
or whatever because I have no idea what 137 2nd of an inch is.
I mean, I mean, it's
about 0.8 of a
millimeter. But,
but, so what I find interesting is depending on how much meat I'm ordering.
If it's a small amount of meat, like one or 200 g of meat,
like enough to make a sandwich or two, I'll order in grams.
But if I'm getting like ground beef for dinner, I want a pound of it.
Like I'm not going to ask for 450 g or 454 g of ground meat.
I'm gonna be like, can you give me a pound of ground beef?
-- Now, can you order either or?
-- Oh, everywhere.
Yeah, we all do this or my classic at Ben's meat deli.
I'm like, give me about a fist of, you know, raw beef.
Like, that's about how much I want
advanced, like, so volumetric. Right.
-- And I'll hold my fist and we'll be like, I want about that much raw beef.
-- Right. Right.
That's awesome.
-- Oh, my God.
-- So,
well, this, this ties into what I wanted to talk about today and it's, um, it's
about Microsoft. So
let's set the stage here. So you would agree that Microsoft is a big company.
I think that's an understatement.
They've got to be in probably what the top 20 or 30 of giant companies on the planet.
Uh, probably shockingly not because there's some really, like,
well, like, like some of the oil companies like Exxon Mobile and stuff. Yeah.
But anyways, well, by tech standards at a minimum, they're big.
Right. Of course.
So,
and we would agree that they're a mature company in
the sense of they've been around a while and,
you know, they, they sell to enterprise, they sell to consumers, they're,
they're sort of everything to everyone.
Right. Right. Yes. So in general, if Microsoft is able to make a decision,
uh,
like a major decision that changes something they've historically done,
it's probably worth listening to and looking at for other people as well.
Maybe. I mean,
so, II, I have a, I
don't exactly know what you're going for here because you won't tell me again.
But I think if you look at Microsoft historically, they have
generally made decisions with their own best interest in mind.
I won't necessarily say
they make the right decisions, but I will say
their decisions are worth investigating and understanding.
Yes. Ok. Ok, perfect.
So a
big one this week, well, last week,
by the time this podcast comes out Windows 10 had an update KB 4516071, you know,
Bit Locker, right allows you to encrypt your hard drive in Windows,
which is something everybody should do because, you know,
if you lose your laptop or somebody steals your desktop,
you don't have to worry quite as much.
Right. Right.
So Bit Locker kind of did something that five years ago I would have said,
sounds sensible,
which is if the underlying hardware it's running
on like the SSD it's running on says,
oh, no, no, no, I, I support encryption.
Like
I can do that then Bit Locker would be like, oh, ok.
I don't need to encrypt all the files in the file system. I will just use you to encrypt
all the data on your,
on your device.
-- Ok. I'm not a fan of this, but,
-- well, Microsoft reversed this decision this week.
They explicitly if your hardware says, oh, no, no, no, I can do encryption.
Bit Locker goes. Aha. Yeah, I heard that one before
and Bit Locker then goes and does all the encryption because I mean,
to quote Microsoft,
uh well, not quote Microsoft specifically,
but there's a lot of S sds out there that have encryption with, you know,
backdoor accounts or, you know, default passwords
-- and so on. And so
-- I would not trust a hard drive maker to get this right.
And the thing I always think of here is Schneier
has
a blog post.
It's very old now, but it's based,
I think it's titled The Security Market for Lemons.
And he specifically picks on a
USB drive that claims to be encrypted, but just like,
wasn't at all to a level that it was ridiculous.
And he points out the fact that
it's really hard to refute this. It's really hard to test for this.
And so there's actually
you're going to make more money selling garbage that
doesn't work than you will actually doing it,
right.
I mean, so I just
checked that article from 2007,
but it's actually worse than that.
As I did some testing of file wiping programs. I found this is way back in the day.
Oh, my goodness.
Um This is going back to 2004.
So Windows has this thing called alternate data streams in a file.
Basically, you have a file
and in the command line, you can append, what was it? A full colon.
I want to say, yeah, you
append a full colon and then more text and it
kind of creates like a sub file within the file
and the ntfs file system is like no, no, there's a text file here.
But if you know about alternative data streams, you be like, no, no,
give me the alternate data stream called like file name,
you know,
full
call and metadata.
Like you could put your metadata in it or something.
That's
kind of
right.
Exactly.
And
so I found a whole bunch of these file wiping programs
just and antivirus programs just didn't know about alternate data streams.
That does not surprise me. I think most people don't know about them.
I, I haven't had anyone ask me in a while,
but for a long time I remember people would say, oh, did you, did you know about this?
It's like, well, yes, didn't everybody.
And ironically, the only reason I learned about them
was I worked in a window shop back in probably 2001 give or take. And
we used to
pull pranks on each other by just like
doing stupid things with alternate file streams.
And
yeah, I just assumed everyone knew.
But no, no, no, I bet there's lots of people listening now that, that don't know
what.
-- And
-- here's another clever thing the ntfs file system has,
um I think I want to say a four
kyte block header size to kind of store data about the file.
But if the file is small enough for the, for the,
the file metadata and the contents of the file to fit in that,
like four kilobyte block or whatever it is, it basically stores it.
And
this thing is called the master file table, the MFT.
And the deal with the master file table in NTFS
is if you touch the master file table in NTFS,
you probably have a dead file system.
Like you don't touch it right.
You let windows touch it,
but you do not touch it because there's also no documentation on it.
Like I actually a Microsoft person looked for me and wasn't even able to find it.
It's just black magic and yeah, and so that's from 2002.
So the reality is, yeah, I
think what it boils down to is if you have a layer below you claiming. Oh, yeah.
No, no, no, it's all cool. Everything's encrypted here or handled properly.
You probably don't want to believe them.
I'm 100%
in agreement with that. I would not trust
any. In fact,
this happens all the time where I'll see an encrypted
disk or an encrypted thumb drive or something and think,
oh, I should get that.
And I'm like, no, and I slap my hand away and I keep thinking this is,
this doesn't work.
Don't waste your time and money because they're always expensive.
Well, every time I see them at RS A or Blackhead, I'm like, well,
how do I validate that?
You know, because they have some really slick ones now that have like,
um it's like a hardware USB device with like a little 10 digit keypad on it that you
p
and they look really slick and I mean, if they were cool, great. But
for example, like,
do they have like a secure enclave so that I only get like
10 attempts to enter the pin number before it wipes itself or,
or can I like crack?
Can I shuck the package open?
Just,
you know, because I don't care how big of a pin number you set with a 10 digit code.
-- I can brute force that.
-- Right.
And it would not shock me if most of these devices,
if you like cracked it open and basically chopped off the encrypted
keypad part that you could probably just read the disk behind it.
Like a
-- lot of these
-- suck. Well, and that's assuming it's even encrypted.
Right. Well, that's what I mean. Right. I'm saying.
I bet in, in some number of them the data is probably not encrypted at all.
And there's like a secret blocking device between
the USB port and the data.
And in fact, I remember this when, I mean,
I don't remember if this is in Schneier's article or if
it was just related to things happening at the time,
but there was an encrypted USB drive
that you plugged it in,
you had to type in a password and then you can
access your files and it turned out that the password prompt
basically was all on the computer and there is actually nothing
physically happening on the USB drive.
So, if you just didn't have the software installed,
you could just read the drive and it's like this is the dumbest thing ever.
Yeah. Well, I mean, the, the challenge being is if you give me
one of those encrypted hard drive things,
how do I validate that it's actually
properly secure without basically tearing it physically
apart
and, you know, reading directly from the US from the memory chips and being like,
oh yeah, so that looks encrypted and then
you know what I mean? And working your way back, like is the secure enclave secure?
Like do I only get 10 pin attempts before it wipes itself?
-- You know, things like that?
-- Right.
-- I mean,
-- so look,
normal people shouldn't be expected to do this.
-- And I mean, this is one of the reason there's, we
-- shouldn't be expected to do this.
-- Well,
-- well, I mean, right.
But I mean, there's things like I'll pick on Phipps 1 40-2
where the idea there is you submitted your security thing
to a lab
that did exactly what you're talking about where they, you know,
tore it all apart and they really looked at
it good and they asked lots of questions and
they're willing to say we did a bunch of work on this and we verify it's real and
some of that maybe. But even then
I,
I don't know if a lot of these labs have
the actual expertise needed to truly analyze this stuff.
And
I, and a lot of these companies, I'm not saying they're malicious necessarily,
but a lot of them don't know what they're doing.
I think it's done in Kruger. Right. They, they, they know a little bit about it.
So they think they know a lot when in reality
they really don't know anything and what we're going to,
uh,
in the show notes,
there's a great video of the lock picking lawyer
picking a lock that consumer reports couldn't pick.
And it's a really
simple technique to pick this lock.
Like it's not some fantastically complicated magical thing.
It's actually just, you just need to know
an additional technique.
That's it,
-- you know,
-- and
consumer reports
probably isn't the best at measuring security.
I'm guessing they may be like, I'm guessing they don't have
the lock picking lawyer style of person and staff.
So they either call a locksmith in or
they have somebody who's pretty good at it because
I was watching a video, I think it wasn't consumer reports.
It was um uh I think it was underwriters laboratory.
The guy that breaks into safes and he's like,
so like this say says, you know, 15 minutes with tools
and then like, but the video is only five minutes long.
Is that because he broke in?
Yeah, because he, he like,
he just side grinds off a triangle piece and then jack hammers the bejesus out of it.
-- And then he's like, yep. I mean,
-- that's an example actually of a really easy attack.
We can understand as a human, I understand taking an angle grinder to a safe,
I know it needs to be done.
Right.
Grind off the hinges and if that doesn't work, just like,
start grinding the wall and something's going to happen.
Whereas you talk about how do I
analyze the security
of an SSD that does on board AES 256 right? Like
99% of humanity doesn't even know any of the words I said after SSD
-- pretty much,
-- I
mean,
I get it.
It's hard and I think Microsoft is totally doing the right thing in this instance.
It is unquestionably good for them and good for their customers.
What's really scary is there's all those people running around with
Bit Locker enabled that are not protected unless this thing,
you know,
unless they make this change and kind of
re encrypt everything because there's a lot,
there's dozens of S sds out there that have, you know,
a default backdoor password or a hard coded password from
the manufacturer or whatever stupid backdoor type thing exists,
right?
I would be shocked if Microsoft re
encrypt someone's hard drive without them knowing
that sounds super sketchy.
It's well, I mean, you, you hopefully prompt the user, right and say, hey,
I noticed you have this potentially dodgy bit of hardware.
-- You want me to do something about it.
-- I, I think that's potentially fair.
Yeah.
So then the next piece of news coming out of Microsoft, which is,
I'm really not quite sure what to make of this.
So when you install windows, traditionally you create a user account,
this is normal.
This actually is pretty normal across all barbering systems for the last 30. Right.
Well, 2025 30
not even
like five or 10.
Linux
back in the day.
Yeah, but Lin
has always been bizarrely non mainstream.
Well,
and Windows even Windows 95 you created a user account
and granted it was not really secure per se.
-- But what
-- you didn't create a user account, Windows 95
I did
-- what I need to revisit this, I don't
-- remember moving along.
So
traditionally you in most of these operating systems, you can create, you know,
an offline account because, well, to put it bluntly,
that's all we had back in the day, right?
You create a local account, Bob or Josh or whatever
with a password and that's how you log into your computer.
And
now with more modern computers in the cloud and everything, you know,
you can choose.
Well, for example, with a Mac,
you can choose to log in with your icloud account versus a local account, right?
Well, Microsoft is now by default, getting you to log in using
an online account, not a local account.
And apparently there are ways around this, like you can kind of
enter a fake phone number or whatever, enough times to like,
sort of air out and let you do a local account.
But it's, uh, shall we say it's, it's kind of that dark ey pattern of like, no, no, no.
I want you to do it this way
and I really want you to do it this way and I'm
not going to make it easy to do it any other way
of, you know, logging in using your, well,
essentially an online Microsoft account.
Did they give a reason for this? I do remember seeing this story.
I haven't, I was looking and I haven't,
as far as I know Microsoft hasn't made a statement as to why they've done this,
right.
That's the impression I have as well as of the time we are recording this episode,
which generally how these things work.
Now in 15 minutes after I hit stop,
there will
be a statement,
but that's ok.
Ok. So I've actually been thinking about this one
and I'm gonna say bad Microsoft and I'm going to agree.
The reason I'm going to say it is because
I think
the world of P CS and when I say P CS, I'll pick,
I'll say Windows specifically and I'll maybe clump Linux into this a little bit.
But there is a culture of choice
in that universe where historically speaking, by the hardware, you want,
install the operating system, whatever you want.
And things are the way you want them to be. And that's great.
And on the other side of that coin is Apple
where they're like, you're going to shut up and do what we tell you to do. Right.
And if you try to ask a question,
-- they slap you in the face and that's the apple way
-- because you're holding it wrong.
That's right.
We didn't build it wrong. You're not using it. Right. And
in the Microsoft world,
I don't know if that's going to fly because that's just not the culture they have.
Now. Conversely, I can understand
when you take the apple like approach,
you can create a very refined user experience that can make it much,
much nicer for people.
But I don't think that's their universe.
And I mean, they tried to do this with, remember Windows eight
like that monstrosity where they were trying to do some magic tablet.
-- Everyone loves everyone sort of operating system. And it was awful.
-- Oh, the tiles.
Yeah. The whole thing of how do I even log into this or log out?
And I remember
-- using it once and, and I was confused.
-- Right. Right.
And I feel like this is another attempt of theirs
to impose their rule on the users.
And I am 100% confident they're going to roll this one back.
I will bet money that they do not.
I think overall that they're wrong,
but I suspect or at least I hope that they're doing
this for what they think are good reasons such as,
oh, you know, now we can back up your important data to your Microsoft Onedrive.
Yeah, it's not the worst thing in the world,
but this also assumes that people have enough upload bandwidth for that to happen,
which not everybody has. I mean, you until recently,
you know,
really terrible upload bandwidth, I can do it and, and, and you,
we live in the first world, you know,
nothing to say places with much more terrible internet.
I would be shocked
if this is the reason they're doing it.
My guess is the only real reason they want to do
-- it is so they can track what you're doing
-- there.
Is that for sure?
But the reality is there is the potential for
a much better user experience in the sense of,
you know, auto
magical backups,
account recovery. You know, how many,
like I used to have a burn CD with, what was that windows?
Password reset thing called?
I
-- don't remember, but I know what you mean. Yes.
-- Yeah.
You know, and like, so unless the hard drive is encrypted, basically, it just,
you boot up the computer off the CD and it rewrites the, um,
the NTS a security account manager database to reset the password.
You know,
because how often did people forget their password
and they're just locked out of the machine?
And I'm like, well,
unless you've encrypted the hard drive. No, you're, you're fine.
Like, if nothing else, I can just read all the data off the hard drive for you.
But
normal people by and large were like, I forgot the password. I'm, I'm screwed.
I did that more than once where I would actually, my problem was always,
I would set up the computer and create the default account that would auto log in.
And then for some reason in a year,
it would like not auto log me in and say you have to type in your password and I would,
I have no idea what my password is.
I probably said it to something really clever a year ago, but
no idea.
Yeah.
See the other thing that they announced that maybe ties into
this is Microsoft Windows virtual desktop is now generally available.
-- I don't
-- know what that one is. It's exactly what it sounds like.
It's a virtual desktop.
It's like Amazon workspaces where you get an instance of Microsoft
Os and productivity apps running in the cloud and you log in remotely to it.
How do you know how expensive it is?
-- Because the Amazon one is actually fairly pricey.
-- Uh Amazon workspace.
I think we're paying,
I have one instance of it that is costing me about 30 bucks a month,
which is ok.
I should say if you're a business that's cheap when you're just some weirdo who wants
a really cheap desktop in the cloud
-- that's
-- without office and some other stuff, like, if it was
an actual proper desk,
-- I think it's more like 70 or 80 bucks a month it works out to about,
-- and, and,
but with Amazon you also have to pay for storage, which gets expensive as well.
-- Sort of with workspaces, it's, you get storage with it. Oh, do
-- you? That's new then?
-- Because when I looked you didn't,
-- I don't know how much
the, uh, the virtual desktop cost. But
what I'm guessing is that they're trying to move
to that model of if anybody remembers. Oh, what were those Java terminals called?
-- Where you just stuck your card in and presto? It was your
-- desktop?
-- Oh, the Sun fires, right?
-- Yes. Sunfire.
Those things were freaking awesome, man.
Because for those of you that have, have no. OK.
First of all, Sun was a company back in the day.
Let's back it up here a bit.
Uh And then Oracle bought them. They made awesome gear.
Yes. So made awesome hardware and software and then Oracle bought them.
-- So that's why you've never heard of them.
-- It was, man, I remember
I was in college.
It would have been about 1999 probably when I used the Sunfire for the first time.
And they, they worked really well.
You basically plugged in a card and then it gave
you like a remote desktop to another machine somewhere else.
And our workstations,
they were ba basically ended up being split in half where you could,
a human could sit at it and use it and another one could
like, sunfire in whatever they call their, their remote session.
It was awesome. It was really cool.
And, and to be clear when we say card, we mean, like, just like a plastic smart card,
like nothing big and bulky, like it goes on your, in your wallet or whatever.
It's nothing, you know. It's, yeah, it was,
it was, I never used one, but it looked like a really good system because
you could do it
for hot desking or anything.
This is kind of before laptops were generally available.
Well,
what we needed them for actually at the university is a Sun workstation was very,
very expensive,
whereas the remote terminal was not.
And so basically by buying one BV workstation,
-- you got two out of the deal is what happened,
-- Sunray,
not Sunfire. Sunfire
was
sun
fire,
was it?
Yeah.
So the idea,
and I suspect maybe that's kind of what the idea of what Microsoft
is going for here where you log into a Windows machine with your Windows
online account and then
your desktop and all your data,
which for example, Apple does, right? If you log in
to Apple and you either have your icloud tied into that
local account or you're just logging in with your icloud.
Like your, your, your documents directory is
your documents directory.
You know,
it's just magically synchronized.
Yeah.
But if you don't pay them,
then you fill that up because they give you like seven megabytes of space,
like five gigs for free.
Just honestly for free. That's not bad.
-- It's
-- not, it's not enough
but for free.
Whatever, man, I just paid them a bucket full of money for a computer.
They can give me some freaking free disk space
-- that recurring revenue
-- back when, back when I had a Mac.
-- That was of my many complaints about the
-- system.
I don't know with what they charge I got over it. But
I think more to the point,
this is the inevitable way forwards.
Yeah, probably. I mean, look at chromebooks.
-- That's basically how chromebook works.
-- Exactly.
Well, chromebooks are a perfect example of that.
Yeah, you, you can't even log in with a local account. Can you?
-- I don't think you can create a local account.
-- I don't think they exist.
I think you have to, it has to be a Google account and I think you have to be online
now.
There's also going to be that complaint about
Microsoft about what about people who are offline.
But
my argument basically there is going to be,
there's nobody left offline.
And if you are offline,
you are a one off for these organizations and they're just going to
increasingly not care which is right or wrong is the way it is.
If you're not willing to pay for internet,
you're probably not willing to buy their stuff.
-- That's
-- probably also
true. Right. Like,
literally the only places I know that are offline now are, like,
-- because I've gone camping,
-- I would not camp anywhere.
I didn't have cell reception
just saying.
Yeah.
Well, in the mountains,
I think fundamentally it doesn't matter if we agree
or disagree with this because this is what's happening.
And, I mean,
you look at a Mac or an Apple product.
Yeah, you can log in sort of locally without
using icloud. But the experience is limited, shall we say?
And a lot of stuff doesn't work and you
wouldn't be able to download and install any apps,
right?
-- So it basically would be broken.
-- Uh Maybe, I don't know.
Well, you have to log into the App store with an icloud account.
I don't know if I ever installed apps out of the App store, I think might be.
So this is again where I am not their target audience.
I think when I had a Mac,
I pretty much installed Homebrew and then pretended it was Linux
for the two years. I used it
and then I got rid of it for Linux because it
wasn't Linux enough for me because it's a Mac and,
but at the same time, so here's the deal though.
I recognize I am not Apple's target demographic and I
don't argue that they should change things to benefit me.
-- I just say not mine and that's good enough.
-- Right.
Yeah. So
I don't know, we'll see where this goes,
but I can't imagine Microsoft Backpedaling on this.
-- I think they will. I still do what,
-- what are consumers going to do? Not use windows?
Right.
-- But everybody who gets broke enough has already moved to Linux or a Mac.
-- Maybe
there's a lot of users of Windows for specifically, I'll call it games
and that's a weird group of people and it's
probably a very noisy group of people as well.
And so I think they'll be the ones to watch.
And in fact, I mean, I remember when Windows eight happened,
that's when Bell started pushing the steam boxes,
which was essentially let's play games on Linux.
And that I, I mean, unfortunately, never worked out.
I would have loved to have seen more games on Linux.
I read an article, one of these game developers published about kind of their
AAA year of Linux gaming or something like that.
I forget the, I'll, I'll try to find it. I'll put in the show notes if I can.
I don't guarantee it though because it was obscure
and they basically point out that like 98% of the
crash reports they were getting were coming from Linux.
And I
remember
like 2% of their users.
Yeah, I remember this and they, and they said sorry,
we're not going to do Linux anymore
and I don't blame them at all. I would do the exact same thing.
And I get that too because I played a lot of games on Linux with Steam
and I think I had 100% of them crashed at some point on me, like without question.
So, I mean, I guess this is the inevitable March forward.
Everything is online and because everything is online, everything
-- will be online.
-- It is true.
It is true.
I, I don't know, I guess we'll see where this, where this ends.
I, I still, I bet you Microsoft ends up doing some backpedaling here.
What you can to be clear, you can still log in with the local account.
You just have to basically, you just have to
fight the U I.
I've seen this with other providers where, you know, um, well,
it was an authentication provider where
they want you to use their authentication app to do the two factor authentication.
And I'm like, oh, I don't want yet another one.
So I, I basically
made it air out and then it actually presented me with a, oh, you know,
this seems to be broken.
Do you want to try Google authenticator or some
other
standard totp authenticator? I'm like, yes, that is exactly what I would like to do.
-- You know.
-- Exactly.
We have standards for a reason.
-- This is
-- why everyone should be using
Webo
then
everybody.
Yes.
Absolutely. All right, man.
I, I feel like this was an interesting hodgepodge of information
and I guess fundamentally, Microsoft would do what Microsoft does
-- and that is the way it is. I
-- think that's a safe bet.
That's right. All right. Well, that's fair. All right, cool. So I'm going to call it.
So, thank you, Kurt. Thank you for listening.
Go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up the show notes.
You can use the Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag Do find us on social media.
-- Kurt have a fantastic rest
-- of
-- your
-- day. You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks
everyone.
Bye bye.