What is it now? Day 862 of January 2020.
Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
So, what's new and exciting with you?
Well, I, I'm actually going to watch over the next
month or two, the highest grossing franchise movie of all time.
I don't even know what it is anymore. It used to be Star Wars but,
well, no, not anymore. I know it's not. Then it was Titanic. What is it now?
Sharknado?
-- They made six of them.
-- Wow.
-- I
-- know.
-- Right. I'm like
-- what I mean? I appreciate when trolls win.
And this is a fine example of that when it's harmless wins because
there are dangerous trolls and there's hilarious trolls and this is hilarious.
Yeah, we're not going to talk about your elections.
But what I love is the Sharknado budgets for these
films are like between two and 3 million each.
I mean, I believe that, I mean, this
reminds me of what was it called Cubed? The movie Cubed.
-- It was made in Montreal for like 300 grand.
-- I, I don't even know what that is?
It's like a horror film that's stuck in a cube. There's puzzles. Yeah. Sorry. Cube.
Not cubed.
And, like, it cost a couple 100 grand to make and it, it grossed
hundreds of millions of dollars. So, you know, 1000 like, what is that?
1000 times what it cost? You know, and, and, yeah, like,
I don't want to call it a troll, but like, at the same time,
Sharknado does have a slightly trolly element to it.
I think
I would agree.
Yeah, I'm fine with that.
But, you know, I think it boils down to if you find a formula that works
and it's like, ok, so we make this crappy film for 3 million bucks and then, like,
it makes several
hundreds of millions at the box office. Like you kind of be saying not to,
I, I agree. I like pet rocks, man. Pet rocks.
Like, if you want to argue against Sharknado,
you have to argue against pet rocks
and Pokemon cards and all sorts of stuff that's not needed.
I mean, I'm always torn over
deciding what is
good or bad when it comes to things like entertainment,
especially because you always get people that are like, oh,
-- like reality TV is garbage and like video
-- games are not art
well, actually. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, they kind of are now,
that's hard to argue now.
I mean, I think you could make some plausible arguments, like 3040 years ago. But
what, what I always come back to with all of this is,
it's, it's, it's also subjective. Right.
Where, like, I think one thing you think another, I'm sure we have, I mean,
I know we have many, many tastes that are in common and we have many that,
that aren't necessarily,
but the
superior alternative, they're so good. I need to find, I wish I could buy them.
Actually, I'm glad I can't buy them here.
So, for anyone who doesn't know cheesy are these like Canadian Cheetos,
except they are so good.
And if I, if I could buy them I would like, we
million pounds because they're like, so good. And I eat way too many of them.
They're actually better because it's, it's this company called Hawkins,
the Hawkins Family.
And they make cheesy. That's all they make their websites from like 1990.
It's like three or four pages
-- and
-- the packaging looks like it's from the seventies because
it is.
But,
and it's funny because there's some subtle things like
the front of the package is yellowy plastic,
the back is white.
So that the cheesy look more orangey.
I don't know. They're amazing. They're so good.
And it was funny because, so Kurt at one point sent me this huge box of cheesy and
some other candy, but I can get the, the other candy you sent me, I can get.
What were they?
Uh, I think it was, um, I'm totally spacing out. Now. What's the Canadian one?
You guys? Coffee Crisp.
-- Yes.
-- Coffee Crisp. Thank you.
The cheesy I can't get here. But the, the other things I, I, they, I can get at stores
and
it was funny because you sent me this huge box and I opened the cheese and I'm like,
holy crap.
These are like the best things I've ever had
and then my kids come home and they're like, what is this?
I'm like, Kurt sent us some stuff and they looked at the box,
uh the package of the cheesy.
They're like, I'm not eating those. Like
you need to eat these. These are the best in hindsight.
I should have let them not eat them because then I would have more for me. No.
Yeah, I do, I do this all the time with my kids where it's like, oh, you're,
you're probably not going to like the Swiss chocolate.
It's pretty,
I know.
I know, man,
I used to have that with my kids where they wouldn't eat
a lot of the snacks I like and now they like them.
It's like, I'll like open a bag of chips or something and,
and an hour later they're gone. I'm like, what happened?
I ate three chips and now they're gone and the kids are like, oh we, we were hungry
goodness freaking parasites.
Anyway. Anyway, we have a real topic we're talking about today.
Forest and trees, forest and trees. Kurt forest and the trees,
forest and trees. So, ok,
so
some history, some background first. So I was at
the
Open Source Summit
last week
which due to the magic of podcasting,
we still released an episode even though we didn't record an episode last week.
And now we are recording an episode the week after.
And funny enough, I'm also on vacation next week.
So there will be an episode released even though
we're not recording anyway.
So
one of the things at the Open source summit
was something called the Global Security Vulnerability Summit,
I think is the name of it G SBS.
And
we talked all about vulnerabilities and obviously,
uh Josh Bucher and myself talked about the GSD,
-- the Global Security Database project at
-- GSD dot ID.
That's true. We is that domain live now.
-- It will be by the time this comes out, I'm sure it was
-- live like two days ago.
Oh, ok.
-- Well, I pay attention, you
-- clicked on it and complained and then I fixed it.
Oh, that's right. I did, I did complain. See, I, I'm old, I forget things, man.
I have no regrets anyway.
Anyway,
so
one of the things that kept coming up
was this how we deal with vulnerabilities today.
And
there is, I think this obsession with individual ideas where we focus
for
JB
BB,
that one's special,
but that's the problem is people then
apply that to everything.
-- That's
-- right. Exactly.
And so I think especially in the vulnerability space.
And we have some examples because this open SSL thing that just came out
and there's even a comment in there from the vim people.
-- The one that has a CV, or the new one that does not have a CV, as of this time,
-- the,
the new one that does not have a CV,
that they're claiming is maybe not a vulnerability,
but that's part of the discussion,
right. So anyway,
and, and part of the discussion that came up is like in the, in the GSD,
I think it's like he's a bit
confidence.
I want to bring up one thing for you.
One thing for us.
So like in the GSD project,
we file all of these issues from the Linux kernel where
Sasha Levin sends us a mail that's basically like I ran,
he has an ML job that looks at kernel
commits for things that are maybe security related.
And so we take all these I DS from him,
we do zero verification and we assign them a bunch of I DS
and then those go into OS V and Google does whatever Google does.
I like how you say we do
zero verification. Like it's a new thing. Like,
I mean, a little hint, folks,
I didn't assign 6000 CV S by actually researching every single one of them.
We admit though that our data has zero verification instead of pretending it does.
-- That's
-- actually
-- not true that one the QR code for Android and iphone, I did verify
because only because I had my phone sitting on my,
-- no,
-- not the kernel, not the kernel stuff, the kernel stuff get zero verification,
right?
I don't look at any of these and say, oh,
maybe this isn't a vulnerability because I don't care.
The point is the purpose behind this isn't
to identify like individual literal security issues.
It's to gain
a corpus of data
that you can then use in a data analysis like environment to make decisions, right?
That's the intent.
And what I boil this down to is is log for JAY is
a good example of something like you should definitely pay attention to this.
Like this specific issue warrants all of your cognitive function at this time.
Versus let's say you have a random node package that has 17 low vulnerabilities.
Do you care about those individually? Absolutely not.
Well, let's, let's be more specific. You have a Linux kernel.
What are you going to do? Like patch it yourself and test it and deploy it?
Well, Google will, yes
and like literally what they do. But that's the thing like, so there's like
a literal handful of organizations that do that globally
actually. No, that's not true.
There's quite a few organizations doing custom Linux kernels,
most of them do not do it very well.
I think you would agree.
Um And we worked at Red Hat. So we've seen the sausage being made for many, many years.
And the reality is like for a Linux kernel, unless you have
millions to tens of millions of dollars per year to
spend on keeping that Linux kernel up to date,
you just use somebody else's.
That's right. That's right.
And, but, but so I think the kernel is a bad example in this context.
I want, let's, let's pick on a note package,
but everybody runs it.
-- It's a great example because it's so universal
-- what they can't do anything with it.
Exactly. So this kind of proves our point. It's a forest.
Well, I mean, in that case, yes, but, but I, I don't,
you're ruining my talking
point.
I agree.
We violently agree at that
point.
OK? So I want to focus on, let's pick on a node package, right? So you could have uh
no, let's pick out Java because log
for J is Java, right? So you've got log
for J, right?
And
you're going to say log for J is
a very important thing and it, it,
it is something I'm going to care about and I'm
going to individually like go seek out and pick on.
Now, let's say you also have 30 other Java libraries
and
there's a variety of vulnerabilities affecting all of them.
And Java actually Java is another good example because upgrading Java
Jars, Java Jars, that's a word.
Um That's hard to do sometimes because of the way
dependencies are kind of intertwined in the Java ecosystem.
It's not quite like node where you can kind of yellow it a little more.
Well, you don't necessarily have access to the original stuff like as
well.
Le let's be real, like at Red Hat,
we shipped a lot of jars for which the source code for that jar.
Like no, that jar got pulled out of some maven thing somewhere. Like
that's true.
No one does it. right. No one does it outside a red hat. No one does it.
So here's where I think things start getting weird.
So I've got this collection of, of
jars.
I have a collection of vulnerabilities
and
upgrading any one of them takes a certain amount of effort.
So now I have to decide
which ones do I care about. What one should I put at the top of the list?
-- It's
-- actually worse than that,
I think. No, it's not worse than that.
This is where I think data analysis becomes important versus saying I'm
going to look at each individual CV E versus saying I'm going to
collect some data.
I'm going to process the data based upon a certain group of heuristics I
care about. And then
I'm going to make my decisions based on the outcome of that.
Well,
and what I was gonna say is it's worse because it's a variable amount of work and risk.
Like you might update one jar massively and like, oh cool,
just works and another jar,
you might like tweak one little thing and the whole thing catches fire
and you have no idea what's gonna happen until you try.
You know, because, and, and to speak to what is important, like, we've had many,
you know,
uh attempts at which of these packages are important versus not important, right?
Like,
you know, there's things that run the internet and things that run on
end points that are not as important.
And then as I always say,
it's kind of the final coffin in the nail or nail in the coffin.
You and I have combined like going on
40 or 50 years of experience handling vulnerabilities
and you and I
given a vulnerability
cannot say if it's going to matter or not.
Like there are vulnerabilities that I like when I worked at Red Hat that I was like,
oh my God, we're going to spend the next six months dealing with this
and it was like a two day thing and gone.
And then there's other things where I'm like,
this is the stupidest thing ever and it ends up eating like two months.
Yeah, I mean, ok, so let's, let's shift our conversation to this open SSL issue now,
which the one that doesn't have
a CD E ID,
we got to back it up a bit because Open SSL three is like a massive rewrite, yay.
And so it is backwards compatible and that they have like
these massive remote code execution and remote command execution flaws,
right?
Like open SSL one hat. Yes, I'm throwing open SSL under the bus a bit because
like
it's open SSL, it should be better than this
really.
You know,
it's not like it runs on public facing internet
everywhere. Yeah, like all of it and your TV.
And so
they released 301302303303 is found to have
a command injection flaw like really bad.
So they released 304 to fix it.
Cool
has
a heap buffer overflow and more fun doesn't want to compile properly.
And people can't, basically, people can't ship 304.
So now you have a situation where not only do you have
a new flaw in like you have a flaw in 304,
that's exploitable,
but people aren't shipping 304 updates to fix the 303 security update,
right?
Because it's broken. So I would actually argue at this point.
I'm kind of thinking it needs
two.
Maybe like I already assigned it one vulnerability identifier for the
heat buffer overflow because it's pretty clear that it's probably exploitable.
Well, ok.
And I love that people like, oh,
it only affects systems with a VX support and I'm like, cool, I look it up.
-- Yeah, that's everything since like 2013.
-- It's, it's a lot.
Well, they've discontinued it.
So the brand new things don't,
-- but it doesn't matter
-- because we all have brand new servers.
Yeah.
But here's,
here's where I think this gets dicey is I will
put a link to the register story that's very good.
And the actual issue from open SSL and one of the developers basically said,
I don't think this is a security issue
with no
evidence at, at
all.
It has no CV E because UPSTREAM said we don't think this is a security issue
and I think that's problematic. What, what is the saying?
Extraordinary claims require extraordinary evidence.
Yeah, I, I don't know why they haven't assigned it A CV because in my mind,
if it gets a CV E and it gets some attention,
then
I mean, it's open a cell.
It is one of those sort of special packages because it is so public facing, right?
Like it's,
it's,
you can't hide it behind a proxy because while your
proxy is going to be running open SSL probably.
Exactly.
And so I get, you know, um
without going into detail, we kind of know how the open SSL sausage culture is made
and they kind of don't like these things, you know,
they want to have a nice crypto library that's secure and
doesn't have a lot of CV S.
You know, I come from
like,
OK, to put this in perspective, I have a list of like 200 projects,
home renovations to do around my house, most of which will probably never get done,
but I've documented them and put them in my, to do system
so that I don't forget them and that they're there. So I kind of have an idea.
Like, oh, fun fact.
Last week I learned because I had all my lines marked, my power line
goes straight under the big tree in front of my house.
And Josh, of course, is very helpful. Like, oh, don't worry about it.
It's at least 8 ft down and the roots won't touch it. I'm like, fun fact.
That's not what the line marker guy said.
It's only four feet down.
I mean, trees generally don't break.
No, no, no, it's, it's my
-- line go under the tree also,
-- but it's plastic.
But the concern was I might have to at some
point remove the tree because it's not doing very well.
I had it trimmed. So hopefully it's a bit healthier.
It's the one that the pickup truck hit. Right. So the tree took a lot of damage,
you know. And so anyway, it's like I would rather
know,
like I have a list of like all these stupid niggly little details.
Like there's cracked grout between the transition of the bathroom and
the floor that I need to fix at some point.
Like all these stupid little things
that I'll probably never fix, but I know about them and I, I don't have to like, like,
I don't have a lot of mystery and unknown problems in
my house because I've basically found them all undocumented them.
And that's kind of how I feel about software.
I would much rather you come to me and be like, Kurt, here's a list of like, well,
like the Linux kernel people,
here's a list of like 5000 possible defects versus like, that's probably fine.
You should just run it, don't worry.
And, and I, I agree with that.
People have successfully ignored this stuff up until now by definition.
OK?
I think
they have ignored it. But the why is where we will probably disagree a little bit.
I think,
I don't think people are ignoring this stuff on purpose.
I think there is a perception
that the quality of existing vulnerability data
is a very high bar
and it somehow comes with
some sort of, I guess assertion of truth.
And I think anyone who's done investigating into
this data understands that's definitely not true.
So many people seem to think of
the e means miter validates it in some way and it's like, right
or no. Right.
Well, I mean, there's, again, this is, I think part of the,
the, the legend turns to myth sort of problem where
over the years there's been a complete lack of transparency in education.
And so a lot of this is taken on myth like qualities.
Yeah.
So let's first a myth
number one,
-- you can't test all the vulnerabilities.
-- Ok?
Look, I don't want to talk about vulnerabilities.
I think there's a better conversation here instead of
hashing out why everything we do today is terrible.
So which it is.
But
OK, so here's where I think it gets really interesting, right?
So open SSL says, I don't think this is an issue, no evidence.
And then there's a comment in here
that says this is from uh a vim developer.
I believe it says I'm gonna read it verbatim.
Actually,
I don't like the idea of marking every
heat vulnerability overflow as a security vulnerability.
Them has started to do such thing in this year.
Actually, he might not be uh a developer. I don't know, I I shouldn't say that.
Anyway,
di has started to do such thing that's like as as written such thing in this year.
Now we are being noised
about 10 high severity vim CV ES per month without any exploit in practice.
I think we shouldn't mark bugs as security vulnerability unless we have
some evidence showing it can or at least may be exploitable.
Well,
and we have some evidence and some suggestion
of exploit ability by the fact that somebody reported
AAA
heat puff overflow.
I mean, but
overflows are
they very likely don't matter?
True and well, same thing with null point or D references. But you know what?
There's also,
I remember there were all these classes
of vulnerabilities that could not be exploited.
And then somebody invented like what,
you know, return oriented
point or D references, you can do anything with those
like or I remember this one again, you know, there was this,
it was a Microsoft vulnerably probably 1015 years ago.
I think it was an internet explorer
and it was like, literally you could write one or two bytes of memory. So like
we fixed it,
we can't do that,
like really come on
and like, oh no, like 24 hours later we had exploit code for it.
Uh Tavis did that once with a vulnerability in something where I think
it was a one bite buffer overflow and we were all like whatever,
this isn't exploitable and he was like challenge accepted and he totally hit it.
Did get Lotus 123 running on Linux. It's
true like the guy is he's a legend for sure. But, but anyway,
so
I think there's two pieces to this conversation specifically in the
github. One thing I don't understand is
when they say being noised that like so OK,
so there's like if I get 1000 CV S pouring out for stuff I use, how does that matter?
More than 10? Well, that the implication is I'm handling this manually.
Well, right. OK. So here's, here's how this happens.
Let me explain how this works because I,
I literally am in the middle of this all the time.
And
so
this person is probably running a
vulnerability scanner against general often containers
and it's going to report all the findings and
they're using usually the CV SS scores which
are hilariously wrong for a million reasons.
And
so I've got this list of vulnerabilities and it is very common for customers or your,
your security team or whoever to literally show up with the list,
the verbatim list and say, fix all of these issues.
And then as a software developer, you're often just fix them because like,
uh if you can upgrade components or whatever that,
that quite often makes the problems go away
versus saying
here is a list of vulnerabilities
and I'm going to use this data to
make intelligent decisions about what I should be doing
with my underlying dependencies and no one does that today.
But that's like that's what we need to do. And so instead
we end up in these situations where you have people saying,
oh, we should only be filing vulnerabilities for things.
We can 100% prove our vulnerabilities versus saying this is like a dial of risk,
right?
Where if, if I have
100 buffer overflows and no evidence of exploit ability like that dial isn't a 10,
but it's probably around
five, you know,
it's worse than that because there are vulnerabilities that
are provably exploitable like Jackson data bind data de
serialization, like those things are always exploitable.
And for example, red hat satellite server uses Jackson data bind but does not.
And my understanding is probably will never use that de serialization stuff.
And so that's where I would spend time
trying to educate customers as to why we didn't have to immediately fix this.
You know, I'd be like, I'm like,
like we number like here's the function that's affected, here's our source code,
we don't use that function
and
it was often easier to just be like with the devs like, yeah, we're just,
we're gonna have to upgrade that because man, like these finance people are just
they, they got all the CV, they got like the hole.
And I think this also speaks to how people fix security flaws, which is
they don't have good management systems.
They can't say, oh,
we for sure have this configuration setting enabled to cross the board 100%
because there's been a lot of bad vulnerabilities where
it's like a simple config change of boop.
You're done.
Like a great example being that windows, remote data, telemetry, MS DT something,
something, something where you know, you have like you click a URL and
like code execution or command execution, sorry, command execution.
And there's you remove one key from the registry hive
that
provides that protocol handler and just,
well, you're safe, right?
So I ran that on my computer, my son's computer, my son's other computer
and I'm like, cool, we're done.
But I have no idea if that register key is like magically reappeared. I hope not.
I should check, but most people can't do that.
So their response is the only way the only tool I have is to, I
can check software versions.
So. Right. Right. All I got is a big hammer. Everything better be a nail.
And so they can't,
they can't do these clever,
like how much traffic on Twitter do you see where they're talking about?
These clever GPO fixes where you can change group policy
objects and windows to close all sorts of security flaws.
Right.
And
people just can't
like they just don't have the tooling or the process to do that at their company.
And so they have to update software or buy third party software to do it or whatever.
And I think that's a big part of the problem is
the industry traditionally
like management and orchestration tools are only really available
in the last 10 years
prior to that.
It was all commercial stuff that was horrifically expensive,
complicated and terrible,
right?
But stuff like Kubernetes, Anzel Salt Puppet,
that's all kind of recent in the last 10 years.
And a lot of people still don't use them.
-- I mean, but I, I don't think this is necessarily,
-- well, it's,
it's the culture of how we got to, why do we,
why is the only solution to fix a vulnerability to upgrade the software?
-- I mean, in because in a lot of cases it is the only solution
-- true but not always,
always,
not always, not always. But again,
I think this is where we come back to
that whole concept of forest versus trees where I think
when you're looking at a tree,
a log for Jay
like there were mitigations for that, right?
And I'm perfectly comfortable saying go deploy these mitigations while we wait for
an update because there's a million reasons you can't update something right away
like this is where always like it takes time,
right? I mean, right.
It, it,
it's not instantaneous or you have to go to your vendor or you have to do your test,
whatever there's a million reasons, right?
Blog for J is a tree and anything that deserves a mitigation is kind of it,
it needs to be important enough to earn mitigation,
not everything does not, everything will in upgrading is the only answer.
But again, this is where I think we come back to this concept of like zooming out
looking at the data and saying I'm going to use this data as part of a
risk calculation to decide what packages should I
update first and what packages will I up?
I mean,
in all seriousness, we did this at Red Hat when we were working on
all of the Linuxes because we had more
vulnerabilities than we could fix just because of resources.
So we would rank them in order and say
this is the stuff we're going to fix now,
this is the stuff we'll probably never get to.
But
but if we do
-- it will be
-- last and like, it would be funny too because once in a while, like a,
a DEV team would bump a component like
a lot because new features and stuff
and,
you know, they'd be like, well, Red Hat did this.
If you look at the Red Hat log for Jrh Sas,
there's a couple of them that have like over 100 CV ES
because they bumped some Java component, like from
basically from 2010 to 2020
right?
Like it had like 10 years of security fixes all of a sudden applied
and
well, obviously it didn't matter that much because it,
but that's another great example, right? Of where
if you bump a really old component that had a lot
of really lame problems or problems that didn't even affect you.
But then Red Hat would do the right thing and add them to their advisory.
But then they'd look like crap because people were like, oh my goodness,
Red Hat just fixed 500 issues and 11 advisory.
What a bunch of clowns it's like, no,
they're just giving you the metadata. You need to understand what's going on here.
Like they're not bad,
they're actually doing the right thing and they're getting punished for it.
And I feel like all this vulnerability stuff,
if you assign enough vulnerabilities to your product for things that are maybe
you will be punished versus someone who
purposely hides vulnerabilities today and that's wrong.
Look, at how
you were on the receiving end of all these scan reports.
And the problem was less the scan reports and more the solution they wanted,
which is I want a clean CV scan,
right? They want to clean scan. And II
I keep telling people if your scan is clean, you're either lying
or the scanner is broken.
-- And,
-- and but, but that's a very immature way to view security.
Like a great example being your your home inspection story,
you know where it's like,
no,
like we're not fixing like you buy the house. We don't
and, and that's the
like I had a house inspection. Well, and now I have a list of 200 projects.
Some of which are like
my roof leaks
like the roof,
that
one. Ok. Leaky roof like that, that's
a
-- tree
-- when I had,
when I had the roofing guy go up there.
He's like, oh yeah, so your shingles aren't sealing properly like, yeah,
I noticed a couple of them flapping in the wind,
but I didn't realize it was like three rows of shingles, right?
It's like really bad. And I'm like, again,
house inspector, like
how did you miss that?
Because he literally he stuck his hand.
I mean,
some of them are incompetent. Some of them just miss it because they, they miss it.
And,
and that's part of the game though, right? Is
any time you're
trying to look for really any sort of
data and this is true of vulnerability landscapes
like you're going to miss things or going
to be false negatives where they get missed.
You know, I just realized here's, here's the challenge.
-- Proving a negative is basically impossible.
-- It is logically impossible.
But
it follows that proving that you found all the positives,
like all the real positives proving that you found all of them, meaning thus
proving the negative of there are no more remaining ones
is basically impossible.
Impossible.
Yes,
I I think it boils down to a lot of people don't
have mature management of their it systems and by mature management,
I mean basic stuff like inventorying like what all do you have?
Because for example,
something very simple like doing SPF center
policy framework for your email servers.
That should be trivial because you should know
every single system you have set up to send email like from your domains, right?
You should have that as part of your it
inventory
and
most people don't.
And so they have like a tilda all or even
a question mark all policy of like whatever man,
like just let
it like if you don't even have basic inventory,
if you don't even know what systems you have all.
But how can you secure them?
It's like, oh that building in my backyard is, oh, it's mine. I'm responsible for it.
Whoops.
Like that's literally where a lot of it is.
They have entire, you know, shadow it Right. That's a phrase because it's a thing.
-- I,
-- OK,
I think you've gone too far down the path for this conversation because I think I,
I want to focus on, like, I think the big problem today we have in the,
the security space specifically vulnerabilities is that
we don't have this concept of,
of risk as like a floating point number between zero and one.
We have this infantile view of risk often as binary of risk or not risk.
And that that doesn't, that's not real, right?
And also how it applies to different parts of your systems
in
different aspects.
You know, like the CS A is a great example.
We have some sensitive pi I in sales force and I,
I do my best to make sure that it's only in sales force and it never goes anywhere else
because then I only have the one system to worry about
or like a great example. If I have a system on the internet running
open SSL three R four,
that's a very different story than if I have a system in my basement
running open SSL three da 0.4 like both have risk.
But
if you just treat it as binary risk, they're even, they're both one.
But the reality is the one on the internet is probably like 0.9
and the one in my basement is going to be like a 0.3
I care. I'll get to it eventually.
-- So with CV
-- SS scoring there is that
aspect of temporal and environmental risk that you're
uses. And that's my question.
Does anybody actually apply that internally to get the full score?
-- I
-- mean, I'm sure there are,
there are probably organizations that you're going to have to be
comically mature to do that.
Well, at a minimum, you have to know what you have, what versions.
Right. Absolutely.
-- Absolutely.
-- Already put you in the 1%
-- 1
-- percent.
It's
probably like 0.1% is my suspicion.
And, and so, I mean, I guess
all of this,
this whole conversation and the reason I even wanted to talk about this
because we actually were going to talk about something I've forgotten already.
But,
and, and we kind of threw this one out um a a day or two ago. But
it's just like, I think in the security space,
we have to start putting significant effort into
getting away from this binary one or zero risk concept.
And this, I mean, this is so true of vulnerabilities where like
vulnerability does not equal bad.
Like you have to look at the data and there's a lot
of pieces to this and just vulnerabilities isn't even the whole story
because
there's so many other pieces to this.
Like how many components are in your application?
How are you using your application?
How many developers are using your application?
When was the last time things were updated? I mean,
one of my favorite examples is when
someone's like, oh, can I use this component? They're like, oh, there's no CV ES.
It's fine. I'm like this actually, I just, actually, I just had this conversation.
I forget who this was with now.
Uh
Like no CV. S that's the,
well, there were no CV ES
and I looked at the github
history. I'm like, this hasn't been updated in seven years.
I
don't care if there's no CV ES. We should not run this thing.
I don't remember who I was talking to about that, but it was like, oh, my goodness,
no part of the prompt too is, is
the scale has crept up on people without them realizing it.
Like, if you have a web application with 1000 dependencies,
you're now into the scale of 1000 packages times between probably
one in 100 vulnerabilities per year are being fixed in them.
You're into the suddenly thousands to 100,000
vulnerabilities per year for your web app.
You're not though
because, well, you're ignoring it.
-- It's, there's no CV ES and you're just not
-- even that
there's node has like 2000
CV ES for the whole node
system ever of all time, like 2000 out of 1.9 million packages. Like,
hm,
maybe we're missing
-- a couple of million
-- per year. Well, I'm not saying it's a couple million per year.
Probably. It's, it's a terrifying number for sure.
It's, well, and that's the thing. And it's terrifying. So people just
put their hands over their ears and ignore it.
We say this is too much work, it's too big
and we have no way to deal with this data. So we're just not going to
versus saying we have to start thinking about this different.
And, and I think this after the, the Global Security Vulnerability summit G SBS,
like I think this is the thing I want to start
hammering home is we need to stop obsessing over individual CBES
generally, not always usually.
And, and it's more about
looking at the data in aggregate than it is about looking at individual flock.
You need to start having data
to aggregate and look at and that's,
we're working on that and that's exactly what the GST is doing.
We're trying to make it easy enough to
like we want to have a corpus of ham.
Exactly. Exactly.
Well, yeah, I mean, there's varying degrees of ham, like some of it will be ham in a can
that was made from grinding up scary parts of, of meat,
-- but at least
-- that's better than delicious.
Well, the, the current system is here's N PM Js or here's github.com.
No, that's it.
Like go, go read the issues and the, the change logs and,
and some projects do great change logs with, you know, security full
and space bla bla
bla
and some just sort of sneak them in or, or
don't really like in the issue it might be mentioned. And it's,
yeah, we have no idea. And it's,
yeah,
and I, I think again, it kind of boils down to, is that Dev,
sort of implicitly know that stuff is getting fixed silently
and hence, again, back to this mantra of keeping stuff up to date and not, you know,
because what else you're gonna do? Like, it's just, it's like
you're crossing the road blindfolded.
That's what
it's
like.
Ok.
No, no, I, I think that's, that's too simple and, and we need to cut this off soon,
but I think just saying, keep it up to date,
no one thing is they don't have like, what are the choice?
-- Like they have no other strategy. Currently,
-- I
understand what you're saying in many instances. You're right.
Like this is one of those cases of we're just going to like update things as,
as fast as we can versus saying,
I'm going to build a strategy
and part of the strategy is making sure that we obviously want to reduce risk
and like, like application churn and bugs are risk.
Like that's something you have to think about like jumping from open SSL one to open
SSL three is going to generate a lot of work and probably bugs in your application,
right?
Versus so you could say, OK,
I need to make this jump because there's these security vulnerabilities.
But then you also have to say, well,
what are the odds of introducing bugs and breaking my app.
And now let's compare those things and say,
what should I do in the me?
You know, which one is more important right now and,
and it's very hard to answer that today.
You know, one thing I've just noticed, sorry,
I was at N PM js.org just looking around,
I did a quick search and it's,
it's suggesting packages that haven't been updated in 10 years.
That's bananas.
And this one still has a weekly downloads of 3830.
I have all this data.
Well, and that's, I'm kind of like, I didn't realize,
like I knew there'd be stuff in there that's stale,
like an even one or two years stale or like American date, like very stale,
but like 10 years,
there's probably some older than that.
I could, I'm sure I'm not, I can't do it at this moment,
but I could definitely find you something way older than that, I
thought.
Well, but way older and in use
and I'm looking at some of the stuff six years. Ok.
Four months, a month, a year, two months, but six years, you know,
there's stuff that's more than half a decade old
and this sort of also goes back to the forest trees argument of like,
uh what was it?
The Apple App Store was getting rid of apps that hadn't
been updated in like two or three years or something.
And people are losing their minds.
I kind of agree because like,
there's a lot of games in there that my kids like that haven't been updated forever
and they're not like a security risk.
But on the flip side, like N PM, gs.org is a little different, I feel.
And
for example, there's,
there's a conversation that we can't really have
because we don't have good data for it.
But like, kind of what are the metrics around?
When should we maybe remove stuff from N PM, js.org and make it break?
Because like,
it's widely used and hasn't been updated in five years
or 10 years or something or is that worse?
Like if we like left shift, like we suddenly break everything on the internet,
left
hand, left pad, sorry. You know, and, and that's kind of where like
you have the state of like, oh, you know, this library is used,
it's pulled down like 10 times a week.
So if we break it probably not the end of the world versus, you know,
it's used 10,000 or 10 million times a week
-- and
-- there's some that get like literally millions of downloads a week. Like it's,
I agree and, and
you know what though, here's, here's the thing and here's what I want to end this on is
like, step one is always just like admitting you have a problem. And I feel like
I feel like we're getting closer to understanding the problem exists.
Not even understanding the problem.
But I think for a long time
it was just, oh, open source is free. I'm just gonna take what I need and run with it.
And now we're starting to say like, OK, this is like a living breathing organism.
It needs food, it needs care. And if we don't do any of those things, it dies.
And now we have this horrible rotten animal living inside of
our product and we don't know what to do with it.
Yeah. Ok. There's an M PM Js
uh thing called safe dash buffer.
82,690,778 weekly downloads
hasn't been updated in two years.
Interesting
and it, it does buffer, it does some buffer handling stuff like supposedly safely
buffer. It's no J si
know but still man, it's,
I
don't know. I mean we should look at it and see like it but is it, is it two lines of code?
I don't know. It's
uh
how do you see the code?
But again,
there there should be a link to get out.
There usually is not always,
but again,
this is where we have to start collecting this data and using it
as part of like the meat grinder of data comes in, risk decision comes out,
but it's also different for everybody. So it's complicated,
you know, it's 60 lines, it's a bunch of buffer handling.
It's just whenever I see buffer handling, I get nerve
because you know, only in C I know, but still,
well, no, if you, like,
if you look for Python buffer overflow and other language buffer overflows,
-- there have been stuff in the back and
-- that's, that's different though.
It definitely,
maybe this library is done. I hope it's done.
Maybe
that's the thing we don't know.
We don't know.
How do you tell
it'd be great if there was a tag that was like, functionally complete.
Like, I'm never updating this again unless someone reports a terrible one.
Well, and,
and there are ones like I remember looking at
one that was called American Date and it literally,
all it did was take a date and spit out the stupid American month, day, year format.
-- And I'm like, cool and it was
-- like five months ago,
right?
Sorry,
is functionally complete until someone finds bugs in it and then they fix bugs.
But it's not uncommon for Z
lip to not get updates for a decade. And that's great.
Like it doesn't need them. Well, except for that last thing we talked about.
But anyway, I'm ending this,
I'm ending this.
That was, that was another Tavis bug. No, no. Tavis did Tavis do that one.
There's been multiple,
I don't remember. Anyway, it doesn't matter. All right. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. Go to up on social security podcast.com.
Head up our show
at TZ Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag hit us up on social media.
-- Kurt, have a lovely rest of your day. You too.
-- Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye
that.