Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 162
with myself Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime,
Josh Bresser.
Awesome. Thank you, Kurt. And I am very excited today.
We have a guest,
Alan Friedman who is the director of cybersecurity
Initiatives at the National Telecommunication Information Administration.
That is a mouthful Alan welcome.
Thank you. Yeah, I'm
used to having to try to spell out the acronyms.
So from now on, we will just refer to your employer as the NTA I, right.
That's correct. Ntiantia. I apologize.
We're a
tiny part of the US Department of Commerce.
Awesome. Very, very cool.
And you are here to talk to us about a topic called software Bill of Materials,
which is something near and dear to curtain
I's heart and we speak on it often, but I will let you
explain what that means because you will do a far better job than either of us could.
Well, you know, it, it's not a new idea.
There's an international standard for a safety data sheet and in most of the world,
those barrels have to come with this list that says
here's what's in the barrel and here's what you do.
If it falls over and start and gets people wet and the term
bill of materials comes from industry, it's decades old.
And if you're building a product, you need to know what parts you need.
And if you sell that product, you give an industrial context,
you give that bill of materials to the business that's downstream of you.
So if I buy
a 10 ton diesel generator today,
it will come with a list of every nut in every bolt so that
I know how to plan for owning it for the next 20 years.
But chances are if I buy that generator today,
it's going to be connected to the internet
and
I have zero insight
into what's in the software stack or what
are the third party components that are used?
And are they
the freshest and latest ingredients
or are they old and rotten and may do you know some harm to me in mine?
Yeah,
I bought a bunch of iot stuff with the explicit
understanding that I have no idea what's in this garbage
like straight up,
you know, and at one point while Josh had talked about this, but I had to basically,
I had to hard reset all my light bulbs in my house to get them working again.
I,
I remember hearing about that story, long time listener, first time interviewing.
Awesome. Awesome.
I guess my question is, yeah, I've noticed in life.
Everything I buy that I either put in my body or like on my body,
like skin products or whatever, you know, diapers for my kids back in the day.
Either the, yeah,
there's either an ingredient listing on the package that is comprehensive or
there's like a 1 800 number I can call and they're,
you know, pretty much immediate with.
Oh, ok. It contains and then they start reading.
How did the software industry avoid all that?
Well, I,
you know,
we you can spend a lot of time and you guys
have uh talking about the challenges of the software world,
but I think there are a couple of reasons
that are pretty evident about why we don't have this today.
Uh The first is actually comes out of the open source world
which is licenses.
I don't know
how many companies around the world until
quite recently could honestly say that they
knew all of the licenses that they were shipping and that they in fact,
were up to date and had the right permissions to use all of them.
I think that's in 2019. A much better understood risk,
right? That's something that
uh in the enterprise level,
every corporate risk officer thinks about very few folks in the start up land.
You know that if you go to exit, someone's going to be asking you for this.
There are tools that will do this automatically that can scan binary
and can scan reposes and sort of look to map licenses.
The open source community itself has become quite aware of this challenge, right?
You've got a lovely little project that you're working on and
along comes someone who commits some code to help out.
And it's wonderful until you realize. Oh wait,
that was GP L code. What do we do now?
And I think that's now a much better understood.
One of the other reasons that we don't have this today is right.
Transparency makes people uncomfortable. Folks.
Given the option of sharing more data or sharing less data.
Most people are going to share less data, right? You get less risk by doing nothing.
There are a couple of ways that we can think around that. One of them is
no one has ever said I want less data, right?
Everyone wants to share, everyone wants the data themselves,
but no one wants to share it downstream.
And so we've tried to frame this issue
as a supply chain issue
and most of us are actually in the middle of the supply chain, right?
We take software from other people, we do stuff to it, we add to it
and then we often send it downstream and no one really knows where they are, right?
If you make an operating system, is that going to be used by
the customer itself or is it going to be folded into a
device that then that's going to be handed on to a customer.
So we're trying to help people appreciate that.
We're all in the middle of a supply chain and if we want the information,
we can sort of share it downstream as well. Nice.
I can totally relate to this, especially the licensing piece,
Kurt and I were both at Red Hat for a very long time.
And
obviously when you're shipping an open source operating system,
the licenses that were contained within it were a huge deal.
And that's something we paid an enormous amount of attention to now,
I guess from your perspective.
So we, we kind of understand the problem and I think
there aren't a lot of people in the industry today who don't get this,
which is great because I think even five years ago, people were like, what now,
what who I can't just use this stuff for free, what's going on?
So I guess from, from your angle. So what are you doing about it now?
Because this is a monumental problem. I think in a lot of places
and I like your, your term monumental because I think it helps capture the scope.
This isn't just a problem for one corner of the ecosystem.
This is something that affects us all.
And so our approach was to say, you know, let's let's swing for the fences,
let's try to capture the entire ecosystem as part of this discussion.
And we did that for a number of reasons. One because it faces all of us. But also
we saw that different corners of the digital world
were starting to advance this idea.
And one of the things that we at the Department of Commerce were worried about is,
oh, look,
there are some folks in the healthcare space
talking about doing a solution for health care.
Oh, look, some folks in the national security community which you know, works in,
in that vertical are interested in doing in that space.
And oh look, there's some open source folks that have their own solution
that's going to segment and fragment and that will lead to all of us being worse off.
And so we said, let's try to get everyone around the same table.
Now, us department of Commerce is one of the parts of the US government that
likes markets.
We, we like uh sort of open and productive ecosystems.
We like that magical word innovation,
but we also recognize that sometimes markets fail, right?
We talk about a security failure or market failure in security.
And so one of the things that I try to do in my role is to say,
how can the government catalyze solutions to market failures without regulation?
My corner of the government tends to try to say,
let's let's try to avoid regulation if we can.
So,
you know, and, and by the way, even if I wanted regulation,
no one gave me any legal authority to tell anyone to do anything.
So I don't have that power even if we wanted to. Now, no one gave me a budget either.
So if I can't
tell anyone to do anything
and I can't pay anyone to do anything,
the solution that we came up with is trying to
bring enough people in the room who want to make progress
and who believe that progress is better than the alternative, which could be
more dangerous regulation down the road from the US government,
from another government
uh that they said, let's try to do this on our terms, on the community's terms.
And so we have this thing that we call the multi stakeholder process.
And if you roll your eyes hearing it,
I'm the guy who has to say it day in and day out. But I think it the spirit behind it
is valuable, which is
let's convene and try to let the experts in the community
open source software, commercial software embedded devices.
And of course the end customer, you know, in this case, I mean,
the enterprise customer and talk about how this data can be useful to all of us.
Awesome. And now you guys run kind of day long workshops.
Noticed.
Yeah, here and that you do,
you're very good about allowing remote individuals to participate,
which is really cool.
So why don't as part of this? Why why don't you let, let's go the next step.
Now explain kind of what that means and how you've implemented it.
So our process starts with trying to
identify the problem. I I
I'm not trying to look at all of software security.
We're not trying to solve all of supply chain security. We're looking at this one
quote
unquote narrow problem
of what is transparency look like for third party software components.
Now, obviously, folks who know software know that's a big deal,
but we've tried to scope it well.
And then we work very hard to reach out to the broader community to say, hey,
we're having this conversation come play in our pool.
And if you can't make it to a meeting, we try to webcast,
we have a live call bridge so that folks can weigh in.
And from those initial meetings,
the community itself defines
how they want to approach the problem.
The analogy I like is, is we push but we don't steer.
I work very hard to make sure that this is a community led initiative.
And my job is to help make sure the the conversation moves forward
that we're not ignoring the minority voices.
But at the same time, any public process you have
uh you know,
outspoken is the generous term I think for the certain type of voice that's great.
And we try to make sure that those people don't
derail the conversation that we can continue to make progress.
So one question I have is so as a as a consumer, like an end consumer,
not even a very big one.
How can I find if the vendor publishes this data or you know, has it available?
Like is I, is there a registry of vendors that do this or is there some,
you know, standard I can look for on their website, some key term or something?
Oh, this is, this is a great question and I and the bad news,
I don't think we're there yet.
Right? We were talking about why
we don't have this today.
And I think one of the challenges is a very old chicken and egg problem, which is
no one is asking for it. So no one provides it,
no one provides it. So no one is asking for it.
And so a large part of this
is to shape
what do we mean by this and create
a market expectation.
And so to do that, we've had different working groups,
tackle it from different angles.
So one of them is just, hey, what is an S bomb?
We had this idea in our head or at least most of the people
who have been thinking about this all had some idea in their head.
But actually building out
the white board model, the shared vision took a while.
It took, you know,
69 months to figure out which part of the edge
cases we want to explicitly include which parts we don't,
what is a minimum, viable look like?
What are the things that we're going to save? For further down the road.
And so today we are now in a position where if you say I want an S bomb,
I have a much better chance of knowing what you mean.
I want to interrupt for one moment for those of you who are slow like me uh S bomb.
It took me longer than, than I'm proud of
SBA
is software bill of materials, right?
That's correct. And thank you for
a
couple of points on S bomb. One.
If you're on a bad phone connection,
it sounds like the other person is talking about F bombs a lot.
That's awesome.
The other thing I've learned is you've got to be very careful talking about
this particular issue while you're pacing around in an airport because you know,
talking about delivery of the bomb and how we're going to make the bomb.
That's just you. Yeah,
-- you don't want to go there. That's epic.
-- So as well.
Here's a question then what exactly is an S bomb?
Because like I'm thinking of it from the open source world of, well, I mean,
like a Ruby or Rails application might be a
good example where you'd have like a GEM file
saying no
Gary or whatever, you know,
equal to or greater than or approximately version X
and then you build your software and you actually
get the gem lock that actually shows what you
ended up with.
And
I mean, is that an S bomb?
-- An
-- S
balm is the dependence component, the dependent components
and in graph form. So
what do we mean by that? So first, let's take a look at what a component is.
Component is a unit of software
that I use to build software that I didn't write. And again,
trying to cover as broad a terrain as possible but still limited.
So we're not talking about standards that you're implementing,
we're talking about things.
We, we use the verb include a lot.
Now we talk about a component,
what do we mean by a component unit of software that is definable
and identifiable.
Now, that gets us to one of the first challenges here, which is that naming
is a hard problem
in, you know, 3040 years of digital world.
We've solved naming
pretty much only once
and I can
has a budget of tens of millions of dollars to run the DNS, right.
DNS is how we can actually guarantee
that something is uniquely namable and reachable.
Every other solution that you come across in the naming world
involves.
Oh, this is easy, everyone just do what I do and of course, that doesn't scale.
So I'll give you an example of the naming problem. Are you using com dot sun dot Java
or com dot oracle dot Java?
Well, depends on when you started keeping your records.
There are so many different churn variables
in how we think about the organizational structure of software companies get
bought and sold uh projects get renamed projects get folded into other projects
that
saying
that we have a definitive name says that's a hard problem.
Not one I want to add that we are solving today.
The ultimate solution
is going to look something like federation ruby, you handle ruby names,
node, you handle node names this project or you know this open source foundation,
you think about names in there and then we have some sort of federation
to have unique regions
and then also rely on a number of canonical sources of aliasing, right?
This project is also known as this project is also known as this project.
So we've got our component
ideally, well, it has to have a version number.
Ideally, you've got a hash as well. That way I can verify that. Oh Yep,
we're talking about the same piece of software.
You didn't go and grab something from github
that had been back doored. We, we're talking about the same piece.
Now we have to put it in our graph
of dependencies, right? So my software uses this component,
it includes this component.
That component in turn includes the further on component,
this gets to the first question, which is how deep in the graph or the tree
do we want to go?
Obviously,
-- we want to go pretty deep, a stupid
-- question. Don't you want the whole thing?
I mean, I know, for example, with, um there was one product I was dealing with which,
you know, pulled in Kubernetes and one or two other things,
which meant it had something on the order
of 2000 software components being pulled in.
Now, you know, whether or not they're actually being used
by the ultimate software pulling them all in.
I'm, I'm not 100% certain, but don't you need to know all the ingredients kind of,
even if they're,
I don't know what's the word I want to use like inert or not being used,
but you need to know they're there, especially from a licensing point of view.
-- So
-- uh you know, I've had one security expert who said,
I want to know what's in my product all the way down to the sand.
That is an admirable goal.
One of the tradeoffs that folks made early on
was this
tension between completeness
and adoption,
especially when you're dealing with the commercial domain, right?
If in open source,
it's a little easier to be complete because depending on your build environment,
right? This is just make with a couple of extra flags,
github will do a lot of this today
uh automatically. And that's great. The challenge.
However, is if you have a choice between
completeness or adoption stakeholders early on
said I'd rather adoption and recursion.
So I
asked for my supplier one layer down
and ask
them
to get one layer down and so on.
Now there's going to be tension there just be some times where
I don't have the market power
to say, hey, I want this or there's going to be levels where it's opaque.
And the important thing is to acknowledge, to explicitly build into your model,
what you know and what you don't know.
And that's the final piece that we've tried to define
is
explicitly acknowledging
when
a component is a leaf in the tree, it has no further sub components. And when,
hey, I'm using this component
and I simply make no assertion about what's in that component.
So basically trying to turn all your unknown unknowns into at least known unknowns.
And then I guess shooting for what's practical over what's perfect.
Which, yeah, I know, I,
that makes a certain amount of sense there,
there's even a term good enough for government work.
But uh no,
in all seriousness, I think a
lot of the things that we are caring about if we're trying to staunch the bleeding,
a lot of this is, you know, what are the high level things that I'm worrying about?
You know, if, if it's a medical device, what's the operating system?
Right? If, if, if you know there's something that's keeping
someone alive in a power plant,
we should have a good idea of if we know for a fact that it's been end of life,
now,
there's a lot of important stuff that is going to be deeply buried,
right? You know, what is the next left pad
that you and your organization need to worry about.
Well, that involves going pretty deep in the tree.
Uh And so that's the tension
of the minimum versus what we can hope to expect
either because we've got
people who care about security
or because we've succeeded in pushing adoption.
-- So
-- one question then have you worked with?
Um,
because I know this is something that's now kind of
finally coming into C I and CD BUILD systems.
I know some of the security scanners obviously
will try and figure out what you're shipping,
what version it is and warn you if it's out of date.
But more in general,
it seems to me like if you're going to build
an S bomb, you know, the,
the compile time is the place to do it because you
would actually know what's going in and what's not going in.
Yeah, a number of them are, a number of them are, you know, are,
are bigger proponents in this space.
And I think, you know, especially in the C I CD approach,
it just knowing what you're shipping,
not just at time of build, but at time of, right, that's been a big emphasis.
I think you're hearing a lot of folks
in the in the tool vendor space talk about left of boom, right?
How do you or shift left?
I think there's even a company by that name,
right? How do you empower people as their writing to know what's in there?
If your if your process involves blacklists or banned software or even, you know,
white lists for certain types of software,
then yes,
you absolutely need to be tracking this as you're writing and integrating
-- it into a process
-- because the one thing I'm realizing is I,
I don't,
there's no easy way to do this. It seems right.
It requires quite a bit of maturity in the software process
and having, yeah, those automated tools to make this happen.
And I mean, my understanding of most of the industries,
most of the industry is not that sophisticated.
I mean, the whole,
the fact that C I CD is still a new thing for many people.
-- No,
-- I think you're exactly right.
This is going to require tooling because it has to be done in an automated fashion.
Part of it is understanding the differences in who we're dealing with.
This is one of those areas that if you're
a newer organization and you've got a more modern process,
you're a smaller company,
this is actually going to be much easier for you.
You're using some of these up to date tools. I've mentioned that, you know,
github
will not only, you know, build your dependency graph, but they'll flag thing,
they'll flag libraries against which there's a CV E.
So that's great. If you're an older company, if you're an enterprise
and you know, your build pipeline has 18 steps
and it's, you know,
there are 18 different parts of your company that need
to sign off before you go to Gold Master.
Yeah. There, it's going to be a lot harder to shift this.
Fortunately,
those are the sorts of organizations that are realizing
that they need to get ahead of it at
the commercial level.
It's quite interesting to think how few companies in the
world who make software can actually answer the following question.
Do you ship Library X
coming from the CV world?
It was funny because there were always the three cases of number one,
the software so obscure, probably nobody ships it.
Number two,
everybody ships it like it's g
lipsy or open SSL libraries.
And then of course, the third case, the more common one where, yeah, we,
we have no idea.
And you know,
I think there's some really great high profile examples recently of VX works used in
just a huge number of satellite uplinks and medical devices and I CS tools.
One, how many people know that they have
in their organization? Right?
It's, it's,
it's buried deep in these things that are in turn buried deep in other things.
But two, some of the vulnerabilities in that
that were identified in VX works are actually open source
components that are in related products elsewhere in the industry.
And that's really the vision of trying to get visibility down into that.
What we do with that data,
how we use it is going to depend on where we are.
So let's compare, you know, a, a hospital
and a cloud deployment from a cloud deployment perspective.
It's not even clear what
your enterprise customer can do with this data.
I understand what you as a service vendor can do with it, right?
You need to be able to answer that question yourself. You know, what could
G suite
or sales force tell you that would help you make a risk based decision.
And at the other end of the food chain, if you're someone's, you know,
you're using an outdated web
app.
So the supplier has just
laughed the thing eight ways from Sunday,
but the whole thing sits on struts. What do you,
what do you communicate
to
your customer
so that they can make a good decision?
-- So
-- it's funny you mentioned this because I'm just
actually in the process of writing a report,
the CV for cloud services interim report,
which has we have the exact same questions, right?
So, ok, so I
there's a vulnerability in this cloud service, what can the
end customer actually do about it? You know, what do they care?
And I think at a minimum, it boils down to going back to transparency,
then they can make a decision about whether or
not they're actually going to use this product.
And I think also,
well,
if I have two providers and one can and is willing to tell me what all
is in their service versus one who either cannot tell me or will not tell me,
you know, that speaks to the maturity and their capability.
Right?
Or even a case of where, you know, you,
you maybe have a third party auditor confirm that they know what's in it.
You know, I don't need to know what's in the service, but I need to know that, you know,
what's in the service you're publishing.
I mean, if I was going to bet money,
I would bet a large amount of money that there
are cloud service providers out there that don't actually know what's
-- in their services
-- agree completely. And I think you, you hit the, the,
you hit on our vision,
which is this has to be driven by market forces,
uh especially if we want to try to avoid
uh some regulation. So
today we're seeing it in a few organizations.
So for example, one of the biggest banks in the United States
already asks
for an S bomb. Now,
they don't care what format you give it to them.
They've just found
that if you can't produce it,
your development process is probably shoddy enough that it's going to
increase their costs of using your software and maintaining your software.
So
there and again, this is in the commercial world, they're gonna take 5 to 10%
off the top of your asking price
just based on the fact that you cannot produce
an S
bomb.
And I love that approach because it's sort of really driving home.
Hey, this is a good signal of process.
And I think the same is true in open source if I am building a project
and I'm trying to choose between two components
and one of them has the internal governance to say
yes, these are all components. We're making sure we're looking,
we're looking upstream,
we're making sure that whenever one of our components that we depend on
is updated, we're, we're doing
the refactoring. That's, that's a good, a sign of good quality.
And we're starting to see more and more organizations look
to that when they think about open source security.
So I guess my question would be why?
Well, I, I don't want to say you don't sound like you're against regulation,
but it sounds, would it be correct to say you sort of
-- regulation is a last resort?
-- I think that's a great way of saying it. Uh
I, my view and I'm going to make it clear, this is not speaking for any,
any governmental agency.
I think that we think you can think of it as a bell shaped curve
where you've got the leaders
in security, like leadership and security is never driven by government action.
So what we're trying to do today
is get the folks who are on the forefront of security to start thinking about this
so that we can understand how it's done.
We should
at
all costs,
try to avoid regulation when we don't know what it is that we're asking for.
Then as we sort of get into the middle of that
bell curve and more and more organizations are adopting it,
then we start to think about standards, draft contract language,
making it easier and cheaper for folks to adopt climb that adoption curve.
For me, the best approach to regulation is when we don't see that massive adoption
or when you just have some recalcitrate laggards at the end of the curve,
then you go after them with a stick.
I like that. That makes a lot of sense.
As you've been talking,
I keep thinking you're dealing with the best of the best regulation
is kind of how you tie them up and drag them along.
I know, I know so many orgs and you're, you're filling me with hope.
But I think back to the,
some of the things I've seen and these people are only going to
get on board if you force them to and drag them along.
Well, my other thought is we talk about regulation, but I
we're making sort of an implicit assumption that
it is good regulation that there's no,
for example, Gamification of the system or,
you know, uh unintended consequences that result in, you know,
everybody breeding more snakes and rats
-- to, to get the bounty on them or whatever.
-- Love, I love that story, right?
Perverse incentives are,
are a big part of it. You know, my, my phd is in, in applied economics.
So something I'm very aware of is is mechanism design.
But I think the, the other part of it is
if we're going to be asking everyone to do something,
we've got to be able to tell a story that it's turnkey
or at least cheaper and easier.
And so now that we've sort of fleshed out, this is what it is.
The next pivot is talking about tooling. How do we generate the data?
And you guys already talked about the importance of
thinking about the different your different build processes.
And then of course, how do we consume this data? Right?
The goal is to make sure that it's actually useful.
We're not having transparency for its own sake.
And so
if you know one of the things we're doing
is talking to the vulnerability management solution providers,
you know, rapid seven
q less tenable folks like that could actually
use this data to better protect their customers.
And once we know that this data can be useful,
then more and more people I think are going to start asking for it.
I love it. OK? I think we're nearing the end of our time.
I have one last question for you, Alan that I think everyone is wondering
where on earth did you get that fabulous jacket you wear at conferences?
Uh That, that started from the, the
the answer is quite boring.
I it was, it was just a lucky Amazon find,
but it started off because I wanted to start doing more policy discussions at
hacker conferences
and most policy discussions are really boring.
One of the things that I've never understood is
Washington DC is supposed to be full of,
you know, all of the,
the extroverts and the class presidents who are supposed to be good communicators
and events in Washington
are really tedious, even for people who love policy. That is really boring.
Whereas you go to most hacker conferences,
the introverts who don't talk to anyone all day, just give spectacular talks.
Right?
I think we don't appreciate how good quality most of the presentations we see are.
So I was trying to make policy panels interesting and I came
up with the idea of doing it as a game show.
And so that's why I got the shiny gold game show host jacket
and it's since become a way of making sure that people
who want to find me at a conference can find me
and that people aren't too afraid of the fact that
just because some random guy works for the US government,
he doesn't take himself too seriously.
That is absolutely fantastic.
So for those who want to get involved in the
bomb is what's the best way for them to get a hold
of you or to look at what the work you're doing is,
-- it
-- would be spectacular to have more folks, especially from the open
source community
involved in this process. It is open.
Anyone can join the easiest way to do it is to first check out
the documents that are already published on our website and then shoot me an email.
My email is on the website and I'm happy to bring anyone who's
interested up to speed and I can tell you about the different working groups
and how you can get involved. Ok. So let's wrap this one up.
Thank you so much, Alan for joining us. It has been an absolute pleasure.
Thank you so much for having me.
So, thank you, Alan.
Thank you Kurt and thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com. You can hit up our show notes.
I've got notes on all the things Alan has talked about today.
You can use the Pound Os S podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media and yeah,
-- Alan Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day. Thank
-- you.
Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye.