Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast
with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner in building software. Josh Bressler.
Ok.
So we were originally going to have an episode where we
talked about the security of the matrix as in the movies
because a new trailer just came out a little while ago.
And Kurt and I were like, oh, this would be fun to talk about it.
We made a bunch of notes and stuff and,
and then this week happened
where there was what a a Travis C I issue where
Attackers could acquire credentials.
Well, we'll go more into detail of that because
-- I'm just going
-- to high level, high level. There is a Travis issue.
There was an Apple update that fixed a bunch of zero days and
there is a Google Chrome update that fixed a bunch of zero days.
And it's just,
I look at this and think
I remember when fixing an issue in 90 days was considered
fast and now I feel like 90 hours is too long.
-- Uh
-- 90 business hours would be too much 90 hours hours.
That's what 344 ish days. I don't know, 96 hours is four days.
I would say that's borderline acceptable.
I walk around with the calculator in my pocket all the time.
Now, let's see, 90 divided by 24 is 3.75.
So, if that was like days maybe, but business days, that's absolutely,
that's almost a week now.
-- And that's not acceptable. I
-- mean,
I just,
-- I don't even know what to say about
-- all part of the problem too. is, is
something like Travis is
how do I say this?
There are certain pieces of software that are
just incredibly important in how they're used and
what they touch and build systems are sort of the one of the pinnacles of that.
Yeah. And we ignore them
like,
ok, let's,
oh, I, I, I'm laughing because I don't know what else to do.
If I didn't laugh, I would cry.
All right, let's, I'll let, do you want to explain the Travis problem?
I'm just gonna read the wishy
-- washy statement they made and then we'll pick it apart.
-- Theirs is pretty,
it's
pretty
lame.
-- But no, no, no,
-- it's not pretty lame. It's borderline lying.
It's
through a mission.
Ok. So what Travis said? And
so this security boltin only got issued about a
week and a half after the whole thing dropped,
they basically got forced into doing this by people holding them to account.
So
it says, hey, all according to a received report,
a public repository forked from another one could file,
they pull request standard functionality gene could help it bucket assembler
and while doing it, obtain unauthorized access to secret
from the original public repository with the condition of
printing some of the files during the build process.
In
this scenario, secrets are still encrypted in the Travis C I database.
This issue is valid only for public repositories, not private repositories.
In the case of private repository repository owners have
full control of ability somebody to fork the repo.
Um
Travis C I implemented a series of security patches
starting on September 3rd that resolved the issue.
This issue, sorry.
And uh as a reminder,
cycling your secrets is something that all users should do on a regular basis.
If you are unsure how to do this, please contact sport. Travis C I team. Ok.
Well, I want to start with that last part as a reminder.
Cycling your secrets is something that all users should do on a regular basis.
So I'm just going to remind all of our show owners that periodically spraying
your house down with water is something thing you should do just to ensure,
you know that it's nice and wet and fires don't start.
That's the same level of advice. It's like saying
Josh, you know, have you replaced your windows recently?
Because, you know, just in case somebody were to throw a brick through them,
you should be, you know, well versed in replacing your windows.
I don't, I don't think that's
a reasonable comparison
at all.
Like we've done the
-- password rotation, cycling secrets.
-- Well, C I is special.
The thing with C I systems is that it's, if you have a properly running C I,
it is going to be
conducting authentication or potentially conducting authentication
against some sort of infrastructure,
you know, maybe hundreds of times a day.
And so it's,
we think of it in the context of typical authentication where you
might have a token or a password or something like that.
But that's
basically a broken way to even think about this because the issue being
you have to store the password or the
token somewhere and you have an automated system,
which means basically eventually you're going to
have authentication credentials ending up in plain text
somewhere that potentially an attacker could find,
which is kind of what happened here.
And I mean, the right way this needs to be done is basically you have to have ac I system
that say calls out to some authentication server
with like a one time URL gets back a credential that's only good for like
10 seconds or whatever you need,
you know, does its business and then moves on, but unfortunately, no one does this.
So
it's, it's complicated.
So,
um,
I, I mean, in my opinion, the, the cycling your secrets, it's,
it's not something you should do on a regular basis.
It something you either build into your
system that happens automatically or it doesn't
exactly like that.
I should have been more clear. That's my concern of this
where they say that all users should do. No, the users should never do this.
The system should do it.
Well, it's, it's hard anyway,
we should keep going because I don't want to dwell on this and I
think there's some bigger high level concepts we should talk about on this show.
Well, like the fact that they tried to ignore the security vulnerability report and
do it for a week.
-- Yeah, that's part of it too.
-- The other challenge is it's not clear
that the attacker has to sort of,
there are security vulnerabilities where the attacker has to have
sort of actively done something and then exploited it.
And there's other security vulnerabilities where the attacker, you know,
can end up with leaked information
that they can then later use and it's not at all clear here.
So like does every public repo that took poll requests during this
last week and a half have they leaked their secrets and stuff?
-- I
-- mean,
that's what happened.
That's what it sounds like because what my understanding, I don't,
I don't have all the details and I feel like we're missing a lot of pieces.
It sounds like what happens is I fork your repo,
I make some changes.
I submit a pull request and this is not
uncommon at all that a pull request gets submitted
and then the C I runs to see like is it green, is it red? What's going on?
And while that runs me as the person who submitted
the pr can generally look at the bill blogs and,
oh, look at that in the BUILD blogs.
We've got some secrets.
Yeah, exactly.
So here's the problem. It's kind of like the
um
well, the situation here is that rotating your secrets
while helpful doesn't make that previously disclosed information go away.
-- What
-- I mean? If you rotate them, then the old ones don't work anymore.
I mean, not hopefully that's literally the definition of rotating secrets.
-- Disabling the old,
-- this is where I come back to the users can't do this.
The system has to have already been set up to do this.
This is what I'm getting at, right?
Like to have a human, you're saying to a human,
please go forensically examine these logs and make sure everything got tidied up.
We're talking about software projects that barely managed to
set up Travis and just get it running.
They don't have some sort of security maven that can do this,
right.
That's what I'm saying is this, this cannot be done by users.
It has to be built at the system level to be just a normal part of it.
-- Yeah. That's right. That's right.
-- You know, and
my frustration here is that they're basically dumping this on users.
It's just not going to work.
Well, they don't have a good solution because this is,
this is an ecosystem problem. It's not technically Travis's problem.
Travis is just part of the problem.
All right. So let's go. Let's keep going. What happened at Apple?
We talked about the N SS O group, what like three or four episodes ago?
-- Apple because that's where the money is and
-- well, yeah, whatever.
But the point is the NSO group was going after Apple devices.
Everyone knew this was happening
and they released some fixes that
as best we know citizen lab has some documents about this that basically
it sounds like they caught at least one of the NSO group.
-- They actually found it in the wild. Yes. Yeah. Yeah.
-- Yeah.
And, and they have it and the citizen lab folks have it.
And basically
so there, I think there were 20 days patched in the latest I OS update that came out.
So if you're listening,
I hope you've long ago updated because this will come out like a week or more after.
But the point is
Apple releases updates, fix zero days.
They have fixed, I think 12 or 16, 0 days already in the year 2021.
And
that should scare us all to our bones.
This won't end until the NSO group decides
to stop spending money on finding these vulnerabilities,
ignoring the NSO group.
Even if the NSO group goes away.
There's, there's a line
that is
out the door
of people doing this research and looking to sell
what they found to various entities because it works
and there's cash money.
I mean, you're talking millions of dollars for some of this stuff.
What really scares me is that at least with apple
products essentially you're either in support or not in support,
there's, there's no in between ground.
Right.
Whereas with Android.
Yeah, exactly. You've grown. Yeah, I can't get a Google phone here in Canada.
So I'm in that indeterminate. I buy something and maybe get software updates.
Maybe it doesn't, maybe matter. Maybe they don't.
So I, I did some research into the,
this was a while and I hate saying the word do some
research because I feel like the current state of like COVID.
Anyone who says, oh, I did research. It's like, no, like reading crap from me
on Facebook isn't research,
but
we'll say I read some papers
that we're discussing the current price of various
exploits and it sounds like Android exploits that
can affect the Android ecosystem are actually going
for more than iphone exploits right now.
The trick is
that
there are like, if you think about Android, it's really like 100 ecosystems.
It's not like a ecosystem.
Yeah.
Which is,
yeah, that's its own story. But anyway, anyway, uh yes, you are correct.
The Android Universe is
dicey. Let's call it dicey.
But anyway, anyway, OK, so, and lastly
Chrome just released an update that fixes a couple of zero
days that they know are being exploited in the wild.
And I feel like, again, what is going on, why there's all these zero days,
it,
it just the thing I keep wondering and this is kind of the question for us talk about.
Are we getting better at finding this stuff
-- or is it actually getting worse? And I don't know which it is.
-- I would say it's both,
it probably on the one hand, we definitely have better tech,
like, citizen lab.
What they're doing out of University of Toronto is flat out amazing.
Like, it's, it's basically nation state level stuff.
-- They're the heroes we don't deserve.
-- Yeah, exactly. And they're Canadian who
are,
-- um,
-- that's right. That's right.
And so,
like, they're doing stuff that if you told me that a universe, like,
if you told me 10 years ago that somebody was doing that, I've been like, yeah,
of course, the NSA does that?
Not a university group?
I think Google and Apple are much more cognizant of how
the phones are being attacked and that it matters now,
like,
without getting too grim. I mean,
there's a guy named
Khashoggi.
Right. It's, no, I know, I, I couldn't imagine being a journalist these days just
being a journalist that's doing any sort of investigation into
the rich and powerful now has got to be just terrifying.
Well, or, or certain nation states,
I consider those as the rich and powerful. They're powerful and rich, I guess.
But, you know, what I mean? It's, it's mind blowing for sure. I mean,
and, and I think on the flip side too, is that, well,
10 years ago, well, ok, 10 years ago we had smartphones but
we didn't use them like we do now.
Right.
You know. No, no, I think that's an important point. This is something I was,
I was thinking about on my bike ride for,
I don't even remember why this came up in my mind.
But 10 years ago the iphone was like, brand new.
And you think about how much the world has changed in 10 years. Oh, no.
You know what it was? So, you'll love this.
My kids played this game called Genshin Impact
and they, they've been hounding me for months to play with them.
So I'm finally like, fine. Now, the one thing I will say, like, anti
cheat is clearly a huge deal for this game.
It's, it's a Chinese company that makes it.
And
when you run it now, mind you,
I'm running this on basically like a Ringer Windows computer.
It, it, the game runs as admin because of all the anti cheat crap that
I
know. I'm like, oh my goodness, my Children are running this on computers.
It's like, I'll just never touch those computers again
because I don't want anyway anyway.
And I was thinking now you can play this game on a PC.
You can play it on a Playstation and you can play it on your phone and it's all the same.
Like you can play the game, shut it off on your computer, pick up your phone,
open the game and you literally come where you left off.
And I'm thinking like
a decade ago, if you would have told me this was going to be reality,
I would have been like, no way you're completely making this out.
-- There's no way that could happen.
-- I accidentally kicked the plug out of my computer,
plug it back in, turn it on and Chrome's like, do you want to restore it?
And I'm like, God, yes, please, please, please. And all the tabs came back.
Actually. You know, it's really funny
when I reboot my Linux computer and I have a lot of stuff going on in Firefox.
I'll do a Kill Dash Nine, which is just like the kill, you know,
like kill it now with fire.
Don't, don't, like, let anything shut down that way when I restart Firefox again,
it's like, oh, I must have crashed.
Let's just reopen all the tabs,
you know.
-- Anyway. Anyway.
-- No, but that's the thing. Right? Smartphones matter now, like our
i it's,
you want to get government service, you want to order a meal,
you want to do your banking.
It's a smartphone thing.
Seriously,
you know.
Uh,
and so I, I think we're getting better but I think conversely,
especially if you want to do something at a distance.
Uh, what better way than to hack the guy, the person's smartphone. Right.
And attribution is impossible because here's the best part too.
If you get caught it doesn't come back to you.
It goes back to, oh, the NSO group is, you know, at fault effectively for this. Cool.
-- That, that's not my problem.
-- Think about
everything going on in the world today. We're online more than we've ever been.
-- There's real money all over the place. I
-- would argue that are we ever offline?
I mean, if you're carrying a cell phone, you're online. 24 seven.
I, I, everything I do. I mean, you think I wake up in the morning,
I use my phone to download podcasts while I'm on my bicycle
doing my ride. I come back, right. I sit down and start working
and
that's obviously all online.
I might play some video games again. Most online I'll watch youtube or Netflix or
even even my, even my broadcast TV. I have set up is a flex client
that talks to my Flex server that is
-- streaming the television to me or a network. You
-- go offline to read a book.
-- And well, how did you buy that book though? You bought that book
-- online?
Actually, I, I love my Ereader.
I am one of those people that I think E readers are vastly superior to real books,
please.
At me, I love this conversation,
but like I have an infinite number of books on an Ereader I, I now I,
I don't care for the DRM and everything and that's another story.
But yeah, like
everything I do
is online.
-- It's madness.
-- We are seeing some really interesting advances in
like
real security where they're squishing entire classes of problems.
We're making things fantastically better.
I love how all the major cloud providers now are
doing secure enclaves in silicon for the last few years.
Right. Amazon's nitro stuff like that.
you know, Apple has their secure enclave processor.
Uh Google is doing it on the Android phones, right?
They have that thing where they can now do um,
voice to text or whatever for subtitles and it's done in like a little stand alone
thing so that the rest of your phone doesn't know what's going on and it's private and
it's, it's, I find that really intriguing.
Now,
now I want to interrupt you though because I know we've
talked about a lot of this technology in the past.
I think we did a whole episode in the Apple T two chip back when it came out.
But so there is that
kind of defensive perspective of let's make technology better,
let let's focus on some of this and that's hugely important.
But I think the thing we don't talk about very often is the days of taking
the data,
the, the time of taking days or weeks or months to patch things
is
I think dead.
And this is one of those things that
matters. Right. And the problem is everything matters now, basically.
Right. Right.
That's just it.
Like, if I'm a company making a product and people are buying my product, be it an app,
be it a thing?
You download a game genshin impact on my computer.
Like this thing runs as freaking admin.
I,
I guarantee it's full of security vulnerabilities
because it's a freaking video game,
you know?
-- Well, the anti cheat stuff is probably full of flaws.
-- Oh, my goodness. I,
yeah, guaranteed, guaranteed.
And you get the idea of the ability to update
a lot of this quickly is becoming hugely important.
So there's the angle of the company needs to update their products,
but then also the person receiving, it needs to be able to update as well.
And I mean,
I always talk to enterprise people and they're like, oh,
you don't understand this is an enterprise.
We can't just update in a day. And it's like, well, if you don't,
you're screwed and I, I'm super sensitive to this and I,
I am truly sympathetic to the plight of the
people in, in large enterprises trying to manage all this infrastructure.
But it's like,
I feel like
you're, you're right
and I'm right.
And now what?
Well, and now what honestly,
a lot of people outsource their stuff to the cloud and just, they're like,
I'm outsourcing this risk.
I'm done with it.
That's,
that's quite often what happens.
Things. Sure. But you can't do that to everything.
-- Yes, you can if your risk appetite is willing. I
-- mean, no, you can't like
imagine.
-- Let's, let's pick on Microsoft because we can,
-- dude,
-- there's entire banks that are pure cloud based, but
-- they're still running window.
I mean, they might be in the cloud,
but I guarantee you they have windows servers running that need to be
updated on a regular cadence and their cadence is probably 30 days.
I don't know.
I, I
do know,
I
guarantee
it.
There is no bank, there is no company over,
let's say 1000 employees that is going to be running in
a clearly cloud environment the way you want to define cloud.
It is just the honest to God reality of computing.
I am going to respectfully disagree with you because there are
reference studies of banks that are essentially 100% cloud based.
Do they have something outside of the cloud?
No, no, no, they can be cloud based.
I'm happy to admit they are cloud based, but there is a difference between Sass
and
running essentially a bunch of Windows computers in the cloud. You know what I mean?
Well,
there's this one famous case of essentially this one lives in Aws and uses all
-- the Aws services like LAMBDA and stuff
-- and you can use all the services.
But I I would there is no way
they aren't running
a server. You know what I mean? A Windows server in that infrastructure.
-- Uh
-- The one reference case I saw it was all Amazon services,
but you can be an Amazon service and run
-- a windows server
-- curtain.
I don't know,
but they had like a complete architectural diagram of
their bank and it was all Amazon services.
-- There were no what you would call classic
-- servers.
I'm going to be willing to eat crow. I want you to look this up and send it to me.
But I will be completely shocked
if they aren't using
E two as part of that infrastructure.
And if you're using easy two, by definition,
you're functionally running servers and, and again,
those servers need to be updated.
Right? That's the challenge. Yeah.
Well, and, and what the real challenge though is,
how often do you have to update a server every year?
Well, ballpark at least 12 times once a month. Let's say
that
I would say that's a normal cadence once a month,
at
-- least once a month plus, you know, zero day drops. So
-- it's
-- a
-- handful more
apps. Are you running on it?
You
know,
-- and
-- so you then take, let's call it 20 updates for a round number
20 updates. What, what is the chance that one of them will cause breakage?
Probably 100%.
Probably at least one or two. Yeah.
And then you handle like the thing with and
then you look at the security and it's like,
well, what are the chances we actually get hit by a security attack.
What compensating controls have we got, you know, ensure that this doesn't happen.
You know,
if I'm running a server on a virtual private cloud and it's got a really well defined,
you know, web interface that's protected by a WF and cloud flare and stuff like that.
You know, I might, I might worry less,
you know, I might take that risk. Right.
And, yeah. No, it's, it's, um,
it's a difficult, it's,
it is hard,
you know, cost benefit. Risk analysis is hard. That's
why
this is hard.
This is not an easy job
to do, especially at scale. Right.
And that's the other thing people forget is like, I mean, I
manage a literal handful of servers.
I manage two servers now,
my own little pie box and we have one little VPC running wordpress left in the cloud
and that's whatever easy.
But like wordpress.com.
Right. That's a whole different level of scale and operations.
You know.
Now you need to have somebody whose entire job it is,
is to deal with parking issues and building parking
lots for the staff that runs the computers.
Right. Right.
Well,
they probably automatic has been good about work from home.
But you
know what I'm
saying? Like at
some
point you
have,
yes,
you got to have a parking lot person.
You gotta have just all sorts of crazy
things because you have so many people working,
doing stuff
are mind.
Well, that's it, it's logistics, right?
Like I remember reading this quote that, you know,
fundamentally every large problem becomes a logistics problem.
That's right.
Well, that's, I mean,
I love the description noise of Amazon is like Amazon isn't a technology company.
Amazon is a logistics company but they
needed technology to support their logistics.
So they built
it. I mean,
anyway, anyway, we've gone,
I don't even know what to say. I keep thinking about this.
I've been thinking about this for a lot.
I think the only way out of this is automation,
it's being able to, to apply a patch whack a button
and 30 minutes later you have a build that is completely tested
and I know saying completely tested,
easy to say those words
and in practice, basically damn near impossible.
Right?
And then another button,
you hit another button and it pushes it out to the content delivery network
and people get the update right away and having said that again,
there's people on slow internet.
They can't get a half gigabyte update,
right? Or, or what about?
I have my parents turn their computer off
and then they don't use it for a week, which is like mind blowing to me. But
then they turn it on
and then they get mad because it takes an hour to turn
on because every freaking thing they have installed needs an update now,
you know, and it creates
a silly, I, I just tell him. I like sleep. This stupid thing on it goes to sleep.
It uses like no power. I mean, you get the idea,
you know?
Yeah, there's no good answer to this. I don't
-- where we're talking about a problem with no solution,
-- I think.
Well,
the one of the few answers is to look for
vendors that actually provide support and do patches quickly and
that is becoming more and more apparent who does and who does not.
And the good news is for a few things that matter.
Most of the vendors are doing it.
Like most of the web browsers are pretty responsive now.
No, I agree. And now you know what? This is a good example.
I think,
I think you've actually hit on the story is if you look at the web browser universe,
probably 10 plus years ago,
it was pretty dicey. I mean,
I would say you had browsers that didn't really care about security.
You know, Microsoft for the most part,
you had Firefox, which I think was doing a pretty good job on features.
But I think some of their security was definitely lacking and then
kind of Google shows up with their sandbox
10 years ago. Nobody really cared about security like they do now.
Well, some of us did. I mean,
so fun, fun fact.
I remember arguing with the Mozilla developers at one point.
I'm like we, you need to assign CV I DS to all your security issues like we don't care.
And I was like, if I just assign these,
will you put them in your advisories and they're like, yeah, whatever nerd.
But, you know,
and these days that's unthinkable for the most part of
not assigning some sort of identifier to your security issues.
And yet here we are with the Travis C I issue and no, Cve.
Well, that's because Cve is fundamentally broken.
This is a cloud problem and they don't deal with that.
Now, there's, there's thing obviously,
there's things happening to help fix this in theory.
But
Cve isn't, isn't it? I mean, that's just reality. That's another story.
CV is pearl.
-- No CV is straight up pearl.
-- It is.
Anyway, I'm not, we're not talking about that today.
All right, the web browser though,
I really like that comparison because web browser technology has come a long way.
It's gone from, we need the ability to sandbox things,
we need the ability to harden things.
I mean, Google created a special library to deal with true type fonts
because most people don't know this.
But you can actually literally include true type fonts in your website
to download and render and the true type font libraries
will say weren't the best written things ever.
Well, I mean, historically, we've just assumed you could trust them, right?
-- So like Google wrote special libraries for this. Well,
-- who would serve a bad font?
I mean, come on.
-- True type fonts are turning complete. Did you know that I was
-- just about to say? Yeah.
Fun fact.
I think all the fonts are though, like postscript, everything printing has been.
-- I know, I know. Postscript
-- is.
Yeah, because there's that really nice chess engine written in postscript.
Well, my favorite was there was a postscript file.
When I was in college you could send it the printer
that would actually calculate the value of pie
on the printer and then print it. It took like 10 minutes. It was hilarious.
It was weird denial of servicing the printer. We thought it was a joke.
That's actually why I had to buy new printers.
My, my old printers CPU it was an HP laser jet four. It was just too slow
to render certain PS and PDF files.
It just literally couldn't print them.
It just would sit there and stare blankly at the wall.
That's awesome.
That's awesome. Anyway. Anyway. OK. So,
but the web browser universe, right,
there was all this technology that showed up to help make vulnerabilities harder.
There were, you know, hardening essentially.
But then also there was the aspect of
like, let's just stop telling people what's going on.
We're going to build auto updates into this.
And I think part of that auto update system means you also
have to be extremely aware of what could break for users.
How do we make sure this is a painless experience? Because
if you're a web browser vendor
and my browser just breaks one day.
I'm going to be mad. I'm just going to switch browsers, you know.
Yeah.
Well,
I have to say Chrome especially has gotten much better
at bringing all my tabs back the way they were.
Be it,
I turn off the computer accidentally or restart Chrome
for an update because it used to be,
you know, you restarted Chrome for an update
and you got a blank slate.
right? Well,
you didn't restart for an update. You had to go download the new version
and
then install the new version
and it maybe blew away all your bookmarks. Who knows?
And yeah, I mean, it was definitely a weird time.
Well, there were times where I just, I had too many tabs open and I just, I like,
I literally would be writing a security report about the flaw in the browser.
And I'm like,
right, I need to restart my browser, but I can't until I've done this work.
-- It's very
-- meta.
It was a living.
I mean, but, but I guess here's the thing is I feel like browsers are ahead of the game.
I think phones are getting better. I mean, like an easy example is
why on earth can you use
iMessage to root an iphone? I feel like this is a total no brainer.
You need to rewrite this freaking thing in something that's memory safe.
Well, and they're doing that with blast door and having stuff contained Well, yeah,
-- I
-- mean, they're getting there but I feel like, you know what I mean?
This is, this should not exist.
Well, look at the, look at windows and all the traditional, you know,
when we found out there's a bunch of font processing in the kernel.
-- Yeah. And they fixed it.
-- Yeah.
Well, but I mean, you know, it took how many years for them to fix it
longer than it should have. And, but that's the thing, right?
I feel like Apple is operating on a timeline from 2005. Not a timeline in 2021.
-- Yeah,
-- I, yeah,
I, I like this stuff needs to be fixed now.
Not like, oh, we're working on it, everyone. We'll have it done in a couple of years.
Like no, you have two months go
-- well.
-- And
I think part of the brutal reality too is, is
playing whack a mole with vulnerabilities
no longer works. There's no, it's, it's untenable.
You need to reengineer stuff very fundamentally
so that
you essentially build it so that yes, the bad guys will get in,
they will get code execution.
But because, you know,
we're running it virtualized in a sandbox inside of a thing with a gun, you know,
a metaphorical gun pointing at it
that, you know, if it steps outside of its memory boundary at all,
we shoot it in the head.
Well, ok, now we're maybe sort of safe.
Yeah, that's part of it. It's all of this stuff piled together, I think. And,
and unfortunately I feel like
I feel like we always just keep switching
our conversations to something else instead of saying
-- it's all the same problem.
-- Well, I mean, fundamentally, as I see, the challenge is
economically,
how do you incentivize companies to spend a ton of
-- money on products that they've already sold
-- well in?
-- Right. That, that's obviously part of the issue as well,
-- right?
And traditionally with cars warranties and stuff,
but that's not gonna work with software
and, and look, man, the world is functioning for the most part
and until there's some sort of incentive,
be it regulation or financial pressure from customers or whatever.
I don't think we're going to see drastic changes. I mean, let's face it.
That's why Apple can spend years fixing
iMessage because no one's saying if you don't do this right now,
we're not going to give you any money.
The reality is apple products are selling like hot cakes
and they're going to keep selling like hot cakes.
Let's be real
vulnerabilities in iMessage that are exploited by the NSO group
don't directly affect probably 99.9% of iphone users.
Like my kids both have iphones.
I,
I doubt very much somebody's going to use the NSO
-- group to attack their phones even if
-- they did,
what, what's gonna happen to them?
Nothing noticeable.
Now,
do I worry about stuff like the NSO
group being used to steer national conversations by,
you know, killing journalists or by,
you know,
that kind of stuff.
That, yeah, I do worry a bit about that because as we're seeing right now, you know,
it's been a bit of a rough week in North America for some, you know,
sillier people protesting sillier things
in a way that I,
if you told me about this even a year ago I would have thought.
No, that's just, no, that's like bad.
Like, that's a bad story and you're being lazy with your writing.
Like that's just not possible, but apparently that's,
and so
I just, I keep coming back to the fact that like Russia will happily spend a few,
like for Russia to spend a few million dollars on Brexit,
they basically broke a major NATO partner.
That's
-- right. Like, they have food shortages in Britain
-- now. It's probably the,
the best investment they ever made.
Yeah.
I it's mind blowing to me this whole
Brexit thing and then now you've got Scotland looking
like they're going to vote for independence and
probably rejoin the eu because they're not stupid,
which I just, I love the fact. Yeah. Oh my God. The maps are going to be so complicated.
Those Venn diagrams of what is the UK and the British Isles and everything is
complicated.
I mean,
but
I think I'll try to dig it up. I think C GP Gray made a nice video.
But like what is the eu and it's mind bogglingly complicated
anyway. Anyway, I think we need to call this one.
I guess the, the parting thought and the thing that would give me hope in all of this
is
I still feel like we're on the right path. At least
-- I think
-- better.
We are actively getting a
better ecosystem and better technology that enables more
technology and more automation and more ecosystem.
And it's one of those things that becomes a self reinforcing cycle.
The reality is you could set up AC I system now on your own probably in less than a week,
20 years ago. That would have been physically impossible.
You can do it in like five minutes and
exactly, and 20 years ago that would have been something,
a fortune 100 company might aspire to.
That's right. And, and I think just all
this all sucks,
but knowing about it is the first step.
And I think for a long time
we just didn't know
and
well, or we didn't realize how important it was.
Like,
I am so grateful for all those people that spent all that
time working on those MRN A vaccines for the last 10 years.
Thank goodness,
-- no
-- joke
-- turns out they were right,
sadly.
Alright. Alright. Anyway, I'm adding it. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. Go to
Security podcast.com Head
Podos podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media.
-- Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye
the.