Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
-- Josh Bresser.
-- After the show last week, when we recorded, I went and got a COVID test.
-- It was a fascinating experience.
-- Did they tickle your brain?
They did not.
I was shocked by this.
I was expecting that because I've had the weird
brain tickling test when I had the flu.
No, I, so I was feeling extremely bad and in the last episode, my voice sounds ok ish.
But
I was not. Well.
And
so it was like the whole thing was crazy though. So I call my doctor
and they have a recorded message that says if
you think you have COVID go to this website.
And I thought,
ok, that's fair because I was, I was experiencing some of the symptoms,
we'll say not a lot.
And I didn't have a fever and a fever supposedly is the biggest one.
So I go to the website,
I fill in their little, tell me about your symptoms
and then I click next and it says, oh, you should get a COVID test,
schedule it by clicking here and I'm like, oh, this is, this is, you know,
like I'm getting all excited because I'm thinking this is really cool.
So I click next and I scheduled it for like 10 minutes later, right? Because why not?
And it's literally down the street from where I live. So I thought
I can do this. It's a drive through testing place. I schedule my test.
I pull up and it's got a big sign that says,
call this phone number to check in. You have to register before you come. Right.
-- Which? Ok, that's great. Well,
-- so, so here locally I know, like, something like
between 10 and 30% of people weren't showing up for scheduled COVID tests.
Oh, my, that's terrible.
Well, but it's a bit different here in Canada too because, like, well,
this is also when they were testing asymptomatic people.
-- Ah,
-- gotcha. Gotcha.
And, and in fact, if I didn't click the right buttons,
you can't get a test. Like you have to,
you have to be sick. Right. Exactly.
So, anyway, I called the number and the people that like, oh, is this you?
And I'm like, yes, this is me.
They're like, ok, and they asked me literally all the same questions again.
And I'm thinking, ok,
I understand this because some people are confused or
they lie or whatever and you're just double checking.
But it's no, no, no. But it's, it's how
hospitals and medical stuff operates
right. Every time you go to the hospital. What's your name? Ok.
Can you spell that out for us? Tap, tap, tap. Ok. Here's your record.
When's the last time you were vaccinated? What's your date of birth?
Is this your current address? Are you still allergic to killer bees?
Like, because, well, no, because medical records get messed up. And that's fair.
And, you know, one of my kids is allergic to penicillin and it's like that's a major,
that's a, you know, that's an important thing for the hospital to know.
Right. And, yeah. Ok. Ok. So, anyway. Right. Call him up, get the thing, wait in line.
And then
it was just a, like in a barn basically that they had people driving through
and, yeah, they, they, of course, read all my information to me,
made sure it was me that people were wearing like, hats,
mat suits who did the test and they just, like, swabbed the inside of my nostril
and it was, it,
and then I waited, what, six days for my not positive test and then it, I, I feel,
I feel fine today.
It was, it was just a head cold or whatever, but it was,
it was definitely an odd and unexpected experience, I guess.
And I'm glad I went through it just because
I love learning new things like this and this is one of those
strange new things that I hope I never have to do again.
-- Yeah.
-- No, I've, I've had two COVID tests and, well, I suspect,
you know, with the way things are going,
I'll probably end up getting tested again and
-- on to happier news.
-- Burning down a house. Yeah,
apparently.
So ring doorbells are
basically long story short.
It's a little box with a camera and like Wi
Fi and then there's two main sort of differences.
There's the ones that have batteries
and there's the ones that you like, wire into that 12 volt circuit,
your doorbell runs on.
Right.
I personally will never use the ones with batteries
because they're only rated to work to minus 20.
-- And I live in Canada.
-- Right.
I have a similar problem where I have,
I briefly investigated getting a video doorbell
and they need the batteries or hard wiring and one of my doors,
I don't have a doorbell wire to yet and I could run it there, but I'm kind of lazy.
So I'm like,
that's a lot of work running
that one stupid little wire.
Like, because I had to look at this at my parents' house and it's,
it would have been at least a 10 to 20 hour project to run a wire.
I guarantee I can do it in two hours or less.
-- I have, I would have
-- to take down part of their ceiling in the basement.
-- See,
-- I don't have, do anything like that. And in fact, I, so my, my old back door
is not my back door anymore because we put like a
little addition on the back of the house to be,
we had no entryway.
And so it was very frustrating because there's like shoes everywhere and stuff.
Right. Exactly. So, we added a mud room
and
the doorbell is on the inside door so you can see it through the door.
-- It's the old door. And I'm like, I need to move that. 00,
-- I thought you put that there.
And I'm like, yeah, that's no, no, no. Somebody explained how doorbells work to you.
And the thing is when they, when the people did the work, it's like,
how did none of us realize the doorbell needed to be moved and like,
none of us realized it till it was done.
Have you thought about maybe just drilling a hole
in your door and having a poking stick?
That sounds totally practical.
No. But anyway, anyway, the wire is basically like in the basement.
I know where it is.
And I literally just have to kind of sneak a wire around the outside of
the house and then drill a hole into the side of the wall and it take
like an hour maybe. But whatever, whatever. Anyway, ring doorbell.
-- So
-- basically you've got the, so if it's the battery version, whatever, it's,
it's easy.
But, you know, it only works in California.
Right.
Probably south of the Mason Dixon line in the United States is my guess.
Yeah, pretty much like it's rated to minus 20
people are showing pictures of their things that, you know,
like just the battery is free solid at minus 3040 or
worse at like minus 20 ish or towards minus 20 ish.
The stuff gets pixelated because the power output gets kind of wonky. Got you.
Right.
So, anyways, I went with the wired ones and then, like,
pretty much anything you have to attach it to your house.
Right. This is reasonable. And I've actually seen doorbell products
attached to your house with like double sided sticky tape.
You know, like the little, the little cheap, like $10 wireless ones,
sticky tape is terrible.
-- It never works. The
-- gorilla
double sided sticky tape works. But that stuff's expensive.
That's
also three M makes one that's really good.
But yeah, the generic stuff is garbage, don't use it.
So obviously, you know, a ring doorbell will cost like 200 bucks.
You're not going to sticky tape to the side of your house.
You're going to,
there's like two screw holes and you put like two screws in to hold it on to your house.
Right? And apparently
if you use two large screws on a couple of models
of doorbell that have the batteries in them that will,
I guess damage the battery enough.
But
no, you didn't read the, you,
you sent me a link to the Canadian recall website and you clearly didn't
read it because it actually has a link explaining what was going on.
And this is fascinating.
So what happens is the ring doorbell, you mount a thing to your house, right?
And then you like, put the doorbell on it and there's a screw on the bottom
that like screws it into the mount
and the screw on the bottom is very short
and I assume the battery is right there. And people were putting wood screws in it.
Yeah, you puncture it
and they were, they were screwing into the battery then, like screwing straight up.
-- Like, that's fascinating to me.
-- Sorry, I was thinking of my doorbell.
Not the battery one.
Right.
Yeah, basically the way it works,
you can mount a plate and then mount it to the plate or you can, like,
just obviously you can just go through the two holes on my doorbell like it,
they just go straight through and you mount the plate and then
you attach the doorbell to the plate with that small little screw.
It should be a small screw.
Not ok. And we should be clarified. It shouldn't, it's not so much small as short.
There's a difference if you're into screws. If you puncture
-- a battery,
-- a lithium ion battery specifically.
Yeah, then bad things will happen.
And, you know, it's funny,
I was actually just watching Lena's tech tips and
he was talking about how the old radiators,
you know, for your computers, for whatever reason they would have.
It sits in like behind a plate and the plate
has screw holes in it to attach to your computer.
And the radiator grill is in the middle.
And, well, where are you going to run the hose for the radiator?
Well, you've got some spare space around the outside, run it there,
except that's where the screw holes are.
And so apparently on a lot of older radiators,
like if you drove the screw in too tight, you puncture the hose for the radiator.
You know, I'm a kind of an amateur fix it.
And I, for example, electrical screws are all flat on the end.
So that if do hit a wire or something, it squishes it instead of puncturing it
and you hopefully don't have as bad of a result.
Obviously, if you drive a too long screw and it's just got to go somewhere.
Well, and I will,
I will find a video on the internet to put about people puncturing lithium
ion batteries. It is like, it is like a firework.
-- Yeah,
-- I tried that with one I thought was lithium
ion. It was labeled and I punctured it and like, nothing, it just kind of
it a bit but nothing really happened.
-- I was sad but it was like, also, like, 10 years old.
-- Did you have it fully charged?
-- It has to be fully charged. Oh,
-- yeah.
Probably wouldn't fully charge because it was like 10 years old.
Yeah, because so, I mean, you have to imagine when you charge a batter,
you're adding energy to it.
And then like when you puncture it, you're causing a runaway thermal reaction,
the energy comes out.
Yeah, exactly.
So, anyways, yeah, it's what's interesting to me is like,
I get that there's construct
in this device because it's physically small.
But at the same time,
I feel like a mounting system where you're
driving a fastening device towards something that,
well, when punctured gets angry.
Well, ok. Ok,
let's first, let's,
let's call back to the last episode we did where we talked about old android devices,
right?
And now we're talking about something new that has a different sort of problem.
But I think fundamentally
what these all boil down to
is
tech. People
are bad at designing physical things
and that is my takeaway from this.
This is more interesting though because when
like your android phone breaks the liability,
there is almost non existent just because of the way liability laws work.
But if your doorbell lights on fire and burns down your house,
that's a liability issue because someone built an unsafe product.
Well, and also we have lots of case law. Here's the thing.
If my android phone breaks, I go to bat for my Android phone.
If my house burns down,
my insurance company goes to bat and my insurance
company is massive and hateful of people who cause
-- houses to burn down and make them pay out money and
-- they don't want to pay you,
-- they want someone else to pay.
-- Exactly. So, it's,
I mean, well, and this is how, you know,
we got the whole fire department's fire safety thing was, you know,
people's houses burning down and then literally you'd get a
plaque on your house and you paid your insurance and,
like, you know, if your house starts burning down,
people show up with buckets and put it out.
-- I don't
-- know if you remember we recorded an episode of,
yeah, a long time ago.
Well, it was like years, I'll find it. I'll put a link in the show notes.
-- But
-- yeah,
so the long and the short of it is what's
fascinating to me is because it's burning a house down.
That's something we understand
and it's something that's covered by this larger company.
Like a large insurance company can go up against Ring or
Nest or whoever.
And, you know,
they're big enough to scare them whereas you or
me going up against Ring or Nest or doorbell,
whatever.
-- Who cares
-- we can though?
-- Because the way the laws work is you have to show physical harm,
-- right?
But I mean, they can just drag it through court for five or 10 years. Bankrupt you.
That is, that is a very good point, right?
And that's, that's what I mean is like if you go to IBM and threaten legal action,
they're like, yeah, so what?
But you have no standing I'm saying in general, the way companies work is if,
if an individual goes up to a fortune
100 company or something and threatens legal action,
they don't care.
But if a large insurance company goes and says we have a problem,
then we have a problem.
Right. It's a meeting of equals. Not David versus Goliath. That is true.
And I think thats interesting here because having a large
organization to go to bat for you is great.
You know, that's like food safety.
There's all sorts of things where if something bad happens to me,
it's not that I have to deal with it.
It's I go tell somebody who then deals with it on my behalf
-- and that somebody else is much, much larger and more powerful.
-- There's also law
that surrounds this, which the world of technology
-- has nothing. I'm going
-- to disagree slightly.
-- There law is important, but also we still have cigarette companies
-- and
that is a special case because they have
been specifically exempted because they let's face it.
They just bribed all the politicians to get off the hook.
But I'm just saying like having the law on your side doesn't mean you're going to win.
-- And I, yes, I will agree with that.
-- Right. It helps. It certainly helps
it.
Well, if you, if you don't have legal standing, you have a 0% chance of winning.
If you have legal standing, we'll say you have maybe a 50% chance of winning.
I understand.
You know, because I have a lot of products that have like,
little flaps with screws and stuff.
Right. And none of them have where you drive, like,
none of my children's toys have a situation
I've ever seen where you're driving a screw
into a hole where if you drove it too far it would touch a battery.
It's always off to the side.
Yeah. You know why?
Because the people who did that got sued and they learned their lessons
well, and it's just also generally cheaper to manufacture that way.
You know, because you have a flap with a latch on it.
And I'm kind of wondering like I, because I've bought a couple of, you know,
various IO
products.
And what's interesting is the nest products actually came with
a custom design screw for mounting the nest fire alarm
to either wood
steel studs or into drywall.
And the way the screw does this rather cleverly is
it's got like a fine thread and then a coarse
thread so that it will grab into like drywall or
it will grab into a piece of wood or whatever.
But it's got like these magic screws because they basically, to be blunt,
they're selling to a lot of people who have
trouble like putting a screw in their wall.
I, I get that
and that's a really clever screw and a really clever solution.
What I don't get though is, I mean, I guess one of the challenges here. Is there
such a custom screw? Because if you look at the screw, it's a very odd shape.
Like it's, it's like a t, I guess I would call it.
Like,
it's a flathead screw with an Allen key and it's got a shank that's got thread
on it and then it's got like a little piece that sticks out from there.
Right.
Like,
it's got a little knob on the end and there's no
way you're going to be able to buy that screw anywhere.
Right? So what are you gonna do?
You're gonna use a screw of approximately the
same size that goes in which is probably,
let's be blunt.
A number eight wood screw will fit in most things and you can jam it in there.
It fits in everything.
You just turn your screwdriver way up to
fast and it'll make it through about anything.
Also,
what's fascinating to me is because it's an American thing they show that they
show the woods screw here with the Phillips head and OTA Robertson's head,
which is, you know, the superior woods screw head.
-- It
-- is superior.
So, actually funny enough,
I watched a youtube video just the other day about this as to why
the Phillips head basically took over in the United States in the Robertson head.
For those of you who don't know Phillips head looks like a kind of an X
across and the Robertson screw is the square hole in the head of a screw.
But now I will say
having done a lot of work with screws in the last probably couple months,
the Star drive is the superior screw, unquestionably.
Oh, the power drive.
Yeah, the deal is Robertson being a Canadian wouldn't license his patent.
He wanted to make the screws and sell them.
Right.
And obviously that's going to be more expensive
and conveniently enough too. Phillips head actually has
a design flaw that actually is a feature in manufacturing,
which is where you overdrive it, your screwdriver slips out.
-- So it's harder to overdrive.
-- It's called camming
out caming out.
-- I know that from watching youtube
-- videos
and that's actually really quite useful when you're building something
like a car because you can have like a powered
screwdriver that just like smashes that screw in and cams
out as soon as the right torque is reached.
-- Exactly
-- magic. So you can't overdrive it and mess up the hole.
And so funny enough, you know, I'll just put the, I'm not going to talk about this.
I will put the link to the marvelous youtube video in the
show notes and anyone interested in screws can go watch it.
It sounds boring. But it actually is very, very interesting.
Here's the quote, why do we steal a flathead screws?
Because those things are slit,
they slip and they're dangerous and they're horrible.
I
know, I
know,
regardless, whatever.
But so I would say there's actually, I would say there's two failures here.
Number one is that they use such a weirdly custom screw.
And number two that obviously if you put something in that hole,
that's long enough it,
choose the battery.
Look,
I think you can't say it's a weirdly custom
screw because the reality is people use whatever,
right?
I mean, this is, so this is human nature and this, I think is something that,
that makes the design experience of products.
And this is true of any kind of product, be it software, be it a physical device,
whatever humans are notorious for doing weird stuff.
But I would argue this isn't weird.
This is I need to put a screw in this hole to hold my doorbell together.
-- I lost the custom.
-- I don't care how you define weird. It's irrelevant.
The point is people do things that are unexpected by
the designers of the systems and like in software,
we're notorious for saying, oh, we just don't do that.
And in the world of software that kind
of usually works in many instances because whatever,
but in the world of like real devices,
if doing the weird thing ruins the device or burns down your house.
Now, it's a different sort of problem.
Well, now you have an insurance company involved, right?
-- Yeah. Or whatever. Right. In
-- my, in my life, what I've noticed is
there's problems and then like there's the kind of problems where your accountant,
your lawyer, your insurance company is involved and those are real problems.
Right. Everything else is easy.
But, I mean, from our perspective, dealing with software all the time,
we're used to telling people just don't do that well.
But also we can, we can retrofit the software,
-- we can retroactively issue a patch to fix it
-- well.
And does it burn your house down
-- generally? No.
-- Right. Like, don't click there?
Ok.
-- That's all.
-- I mean, I don't know.
I'm kind of wondering because I also had
a conversation once with somebody who was saying essentially
that there was like some product recall where
if you recharge something it could catch fire.
And I'm like, well, that's dumb because, you know,
people plug stuff to recharge it all the time and leave it unattended.
-- That's literally the point of recharging.
-- Yeah.
You know, I don't,
I'm not going to like plug a battery and then sit there
and stare at it to make sure it doesn't catch fire.
And he was arguing that no,
like you should listen to the manufacturer and you should keep an
eye on it and build a safe space to recharge your batteries.
No, that's ridiculous. Well, yeah.
And I was like, that's, that's literally the most insane thing I've ever heard.
You're saying, I literally can't like plug a battery into a recharger.
Like got a Ryobi battery charger with Ryobi batteries that I bought at Home Depot.
So they're not from like some dodgy Amazon online.
Reseller that they're not actual Ryobi batteries.
And I'm saying like that thing
that should work without burning my house down. Seriously.
I think that is a perfectly and I mean,
so one of the things that happens in the world of law, at least in the United States,
I don't know how this works elsewhere,
but there's this concept of like a reasonable person and
I think it's safe to say a reasonable person would
expect you plug the battery into the charger and you
walk away and your house doesn't start on fire.
Like that is a reasonable expectation.
You know, now I'm looking at the ball in this battery to reduce the risk of injury.
A user must read operator's manual risk of fire and
burns do not open crush heat above 40 C.
Wow.
40 C, I mean, like there's places in the world where it gets above 40 C all the time.
So actually I looked into this because
I enjoy going into the sauna back when I used to go to the gym
and
the sauna was
your Apple watch. I don't have an Apple watch.
So I did this because there was a guy in the sauna using his phone
and the sauna was, I want to say probably 50 ish C maybe it, it was pretty,
it was pretty warm.
It was over, it was well over 100 degrees in Fahrenheit scale.
And anyway, I was curious like, when do these batteries fail.
Like,
do I need to sit on the other side of
the sauna from this person in case his phone explodes?
-- And was it like one of those nice cedar saunas?
-- It is, it's very nice,
so,
-- like, very flammable. It's
-- lovely.
Maybe, I don't know, whatever.
But the point is the actual temperature at which
these things fail is well above 100 c,
but they just put these warnings on, I think so, people don't find out,
you know, like,
you know what I mean?
Well, and that's the thing, you always want to have a safety market,
you need some buffer in there.
And so anyway, I,
it was obvious at that point that while I'm sure using your
phone in such a hot environment isn't the best thing for it,
the battery will not explode.
I,
I killed my iphone accidentally back in the day
or rather I killed the charging circuit on it.
The battery was fine, but if it was plugged in, it would go all wonky.
And as soon as you unplugged it, it would, it would operate fine.
And while it was charged,
it would reboot every five minutes by having it on clipped
in my car in front of the hot air vent.
And so over a period of about three weeks, one winter, it just,
there was enough temperature fluctuation between like being outside in minus 20
then being cooked in my car
that II I basically
the phone worked great unless it was plugged in and it wouldn't charge properly.
Interesting.
Yeah, it was kind of fascinating because it was a very odd failure.
I can't help but think the reason that this
is different is because insurance companies are involved,
like,
because houses are burning down because it's not that there's
not real loss in other software issues like there's been,
but there isn't.
No, no, no, no, no.
Like the Phoenix pay debacle here in Canada,
literally thousands of federal employees had to take out like home loans to make
ends meet because of this pay system that was supposed to be done by IBM
or you know, there's been, there's been payroll software
incidents that have really cost time and money
and had provable losses, but they're kind of, they're at that business level.
I'm,
this is interesting to me because this is a consumer level device
where you have the insurance companies going to bat for you.
And I can't think of anything else like that's not going to happen with your,
I guess maybe those, oh, you know what,
those Amazon essentials or basics or whatever cables that
caught fire and like we're burning people's houses down.
-- Yeah,
-- same thing because you burned the house down. So I there is a presentation
that I will put a link to in the show notes from
there is a person Wendy Knox Everett who I follow on Twitter.
She is a lawyer who does cybersecurity work and she's phenomenal.
I'll obviously link to her profile as well and I listened to
-- her talk about like a 100 years
-- in the before time.
But anyway, the thing, I didn't totally understand that, that she clarified,
I think marvelously
and I've since discussed this with many lawyers is
when you're dealing with liability,
it comes down to proving you actually lost basically money or life in some way.
And the problem with like,
let's say someone hacks Facebook and steals all your information.
Can you prove you lost money? No, you cannot, can you prove you lost life?
No, you cannot so that you have no standing in those kind of cases.
And whereas like if you buy a ring doorbell and it burns your house down,
did you lose money?
Well, yes, your house burnt down. Did you lose life? I mean, let's hope not.
But you know, you know what I mean?
You can connect that event to something bad happening.
And I mean,
this is where our legal system is unable to deal with
the current environment of just like technology and the internet.
And this is, it is a very difficult problem and things like, you know,
as bad as they are,
but the GDPR privacy law and like what California is doing
while flawed are the first step in this journey for sure.
Well, I mean, pretty much you look at any regulation or law,
it was written back in the day and a lot of
-- them are just comically terrible now
-- and that's how it is.
But now at the same time,
I will say what you pointed out what Tim Berners Lee started
a company trying to control your data or something like that.
And I'm going to tell you, we cannot solve this problem with technology.
This is a legal problem that has to be solved with laws.
I was looking at his product and it's like, well,
how many websites have you run into where it's
basically we want some information on you or something
or you need to use your email address and we need to
send an email and confirm it before we'll let you in.
Otherwise you just don't get to use it.
And I'm thinking, like, do I want to deal with that type of question constantly
throughout the day?
As you know,
all these organizations need to use my pi I legitimately
you're already clicking OK for cookies on every site.
Like, why
not?
Yeah, if there's one,
I was actually trying to figure that out the other day is how many
humans has GD are killed through the collective loss of time of clicking cookies.
You can't prove it.
-- So, the answer
-- is, well, what I'm saying is statistically right, like,
if everybody spends a minute a day clicking cookies away, you know,
we're killing basically a,
probably a Titanic's worth of people every 15 minutes or something stupid.
-- How many
-- coal fired power plants is GDPR supporting. Right.
Yeah. How many is that in, you know, banana slip incidents?
Watching techs design these things and build these things and especially, yeah,
this intersection of the real world, like,
like a perfect example here that I don't get is why have they issued a recall notice
and asking people to check the numbers when to install a ring product and use it?
You have to have an account and that account has to be hooked up to an email address.
Not only could they reach out to you via email or probably
phone number which is registered,
they could overlay something on the display saying this ring device, blah, blah,
blah,
I'm not a lawyer,
but I may have a reason for that is so over the
course of I talk to lawyers more often than I would like.
I love you all.
But what what can happen in situations like this is you want to do the absolute
minimum whereas you want to push as much
responsibility onto the other party as you can.
Because what happens is let's say you display a
warning on devices and let's say someone's house burns down
and you're like we put a warning on your device and they say I didn't see a warning.
No, you didn't. Did they see a warning? Did your system fail? You know what I mean?
And so you can actually increase your liability by doing something like that.
So that is my suspicion again.
I don't know for sure,
but I've encountered situations very similar to that where in my professional life
we had to not do the right thing
because the lawyers said it could get us in trouble,
which of course is sad and annoying, but it is what it is.
One thing I'm beginning to wonder is, you know, Apple, for example,
a bunch of Apple phones were stolen in some protests or something.
And they literally sent text messages to all the phones saying, you know,
these phones are stolen, we're going to remote brick them, please return them.
Don't be a jerk. You know, that's possible with essentially every IOT device.
When you buy a firestick from Amazon, you turn it on
says like, are you Kurt
Seri? And I'm like, whoa, how did it know that?
And then I'm like, oh wait, of course, I'm like, of course,
it knows because I bought it.
It's on my account. It knows the serial number of the fire stick. It sent me.
So when I plug it in and turn it on, it's like this serial number reached out to us.
Let's see whose account that was bought through are you Kirk or you know,
did Kirk give this away as a gift?
And I'm kind of wondering at what point do we get to this remote bricking?
See most devices don't have the ability to tell you they're sick. Like my light bulb,
I guess it could start flashing. Maybe that would work.
But, you know what I'm saying? Right.
Like, unless it has a screen, maybe something audible.
-- You know, how's it going to communicate? To me?
-- We've never had to do this in the past.
I mean,
you could, you could maybe make the argument that, like, a circuit breaker
in your basement
is similar to this where, when, when something bad starts to happen, it just like,
and especially if it keeps popping, then you're like, oh, maybe, you know, we,
-- yes,
-- something is wrong. Exactly. And you could potentially argue that.
But I think fundamentally the vast majority of products we've ever
had to deal with have been a get product use,
product,
eventually,
product breaks and things now like devices like what we
talked about last week where these devices are basically,
there's nothing technically wrong with them.
They just don't work anymore because some outside force has caused it to be. So,
-- yeah, with the Android phones and the certificates.
-- Right.
Well, and it's not even that they failed, fail.
It's just you can't use it to surf most of the web.
Yeah, that's true. And I would argue that that basically renders it unusable.
-- I mean,
-- I agree, but it is definitely a different sort of problem for
sure.
It would be like having a skateboard that you
can only write on 10% of the city streets.
-- That's how most city streets are these, well,
-- you
know what I'm
saying?
Yeah. Well, yeah, where I live it, between the snow and the cracks.
It's so much respect for those, especially the people who bicycle here in winter.
I'm just in awe of them.
I, I have looked into biking in the winter and let's say it is
not a pleasant experience and I'm too lazy to do it.
And more importantly is everyone you talk to, keeps telling you, oh,
you're going to fall a lot.
And I'm thinking,
I don't like falling and I'm old. So that's dangerous and bad.
Not counting the $400 bike tires.
I have to buy,
I also just keep coming and I can't help but think it's not about just showing loss,
but it's about showing loss and then having a large
company insurance company to go to bad for you.
I feel like that's a critical component here because otherwise
it's just going to be one person.
Like I've had to return my nest smoke alarms twice and get new ones
because they malfunctioned in a weird way.
And luckily Nest just swapped them out. But I'm,
I was beginning to kind of like,
do I trust these things?
Right.
Because if they keep malfunctioning to this degree and I would actually test them,
like,
I'd take a candle to light it on fire and blow it out
under the smoke alarm to make sure it detected smoke and like,
freaked out, you know, at some point,
I'm not beginning to trust these devices as much and
I'm not beginning to trust this company as much.
Right, based on my experience,
and there was an incident of Mercedes cars
just randomly catching fire here in Canada.
And of course Mercedes at first was like, oh, you're, you're,
you're parking it wrong or, you know, it's,
it's not us or squirrels
or whatever.
And it, and so somebody started a website and because the thing is transport,
Canada wasn't really tracking this in a spreadsheet or something anywhere.
And then it turns out when they figured out there's like, been like,
tens of these fires, it's kind of like, ok, well, that's not normal, you know,
one or two Mercedes just randomly catching fire.
Sure, whatever, it, strange things happen.
But, you know, when it's tens of Mercedes,
it's like, oh, maybe there is an electrical fault and that's the other thing is,
you know, how do we spot this trend? Right.
Because, like, one house burns down and it's related to the ring doorbell.
You know, they do a fire investigation. Ok. Like me, you know what I mean?
Like, maybe it's a problem. Maybe it's not. But, you know, once you get 10 or 20
I think that's the other aspect here is how do we,
how do we track this stuff so that we can know when there is a problem?
We don't, I mean, so what happens is,
I think it's up to the manufacture to keep track of things like this.
-- Well,
-- but
I mean, the manufacturer would have to find out like, you know, like,
for example, is there some national database of, you know,
when they investigate a fire,
they write down the cause of it and put it into this
national database so that people can see a correlation of like,
oh, you know, oh perfect example.
I remember this guy was talking about these shop vacs, this one brand of shop vac.
And I'm talking like a big shop vac for like a permanently installed sawdust system.
And it turns out these things will catch fire when they're turned off.
It seems,
and I'm like, that's really not
to
happen to an electrical device.
There's like a fault in it where like some oil and
some stuff builds up in a part that gets hot,
you know, and, and well, oil flammable heat,
that's a fire.
And so it would smolder and then they would catch fire like,
at some wee hour of the morning.
I mean, I guess if someone out there knows the answer to this, like,
is there some sort of like, like, how does, how does this kind of stuff get tracked?
-- Did the insurance companies do it? Did the fire departments do it?
-- Yeah.
-- Does, I, I don't think it gets tracked.
-- I don't, I don't know.
I have no idea.
My suspicion is, it doesn't, but let's hope I'm wrong because I enjoy being wrong.
Uh, I don't know. I don't know, man, I guess we're, we're pretty much out of time.
Why don't I'll give you the last word on this one.
I don't,
I don't have super strong thoughts because you're the one with the ring doorbell.
Uh,
oh,
we, we solved it back in the 19 fifties. LP Z LP zero on fire.
That's
on fire. Just bring that code back. We're, we've solved the problem.
A job well done.
Anyway. Anyway, it's so funny enough.
I'll rally up before we go is if only we
had a centralized place to store security details from software,
-- for example,
-- so some sort of vulnerability database or incident database maybe
if
that existed
anyway. All right.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to opens sources Security, podcast.com. Hit up the show,
not
a Podos
podcast. Hashtag to hit us up on social media. Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye
the