Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 68 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
I feel like
we don't even have anything to talk about this week.
-- Nothing lit on fire that I
-- know
of.
Nothing technical lit on
fire.
Just
ignore
the real
world. Right. We can, we can pretend
everything is fine.
Everything is fine
as it is.
Yeah,
nobody's gone to jail yet.
Not yet. Give it to him.
Oh, man.
Right.
Anyway, so what's new with you?
-- Uh,
-- I got a raspberry pi behaving nicely.
-- The poor little thing is very high system load, but it works,
-- man.
I love those little things. They're,
you know what I always think of is
a raspberry pie. Is, is what are they? Like? 30 bucks? They're super cheap
and
it is magnitudes more powerful than the first
computer I ever bought for myself some,
you know, 20 years ago.
And,
yeah, it's crazy, man.
and they're super cool and they're fun to use and they're easy
and they're cheap and I don't feel bad if I break it.
So
I love it.
Yeah,
I was just buying new batteries today for my UPSS.
Uh,
because, you know, you got to change
-- every 34 years, probably
-- buy new UPS.
You know, there's like, stuff inside of them that doesn't go bad.
Yeah, I had one
actually
not
just
that
they will still run
but the, the things that, that trip and prevent the,
doesn't matter,
jolts
electricity.
Um,
yeah, that's fair. Then. Why didnt have a UPS?
Well, it's,
it's mostly just so the internet doesn't cut out if
there is a little glitch for like one second.
There
you go.
Right.
Because like, literally,
I've got this huge honk and ABC 1200 Ups running two raspberry pies,
a cable modem,
-- uh DS L modem and uh a little um Intel Atom Firewall.
-- That's great.
So
they run for like two weeks.
Yeah, I mean, I think the whole setup is drawing something like 20 or 30 watts.
So it's not even an old timey light bulb.
No, no. Let me ask you this though. Is,
are your raspberry pies running straight off DC? Are you using AC to DC?
So, really, you've got AC or rather you got DC batteries converting to AC,
converting back to DC.
And then actually there's an instruct
I found once that shows you, you can put uh USB ports
on the
UPSS that way you don't have to worry about converting back and forth.
-- Yeah, that
-- would work
if I
walk
in.
And
anyway,
I
know.
Well, and here's the other thing.
Right is I used to worry about, like,
say lightning hitting and zapping all my equipment
and, and that would suck.
-- But, like, it would cost me less than 10 grand to replace
-- every,
it's gonna cost you like, 50 bucks.
I
mean,
so I have some,
I have a real nice monitor that I love
that.
I would cry if that got fried.
Well, no, I wouldn't because I'd just claim the insurance. Get a new one.
There you go.
And it would be better.
So, yeah. So, yeah. No, it's, the world has not really been too utterly terrible.
Um,
so I was thinking, why don't we talk about some sort of existential,
not really existential but some sort of looming long term
type threats.
Like, like robots taking over and killing us all or
even better. One of my favorites is we're running out of sand.
Yeah.
Yeah. Well, we're running out of a good kind of sand.
-- Is there
-- bad sand? I don't know. Yeah.
So there's like, there's lots of, it's like any kind of rock.
There's lots of different kinds of sand
and the kind of sand we want and like is the kind from the ocean
where it's been sitting there for, you know,
tens of thousands or millions or whatever years, uh,
rubbing up against other bits of sand and it's nicely rounded sand and it's,
you know, nice, it's not porous,
you know, it's, it's really awesome for building
cement,
you know, concrete buildings rather.
So
did you know,
I, I love watching documentaries
and I learned that white sand, beaches, white sand is uh, parrot fish poop.
They eat coral and then they poop. White sand.
So, yeah,
that's fun. Fact. Everybody,
white sand, beach fish poop.
All the phosphorus mines in the world that are basically economic. Are bat poop?
Are they still, I know they used to be,
uh, well, generally speaking, the ones that are, like,
really economically viable are still that.
But, yeah,
actually, do you know, I, I learned that because I was at, uh, in the US,
we have this cave called Mammoth Cave, which is named, such because it is huge and,
and it was when I went there.
But, yeah, I, I learned that actually they, they found the cave
and then it was converted into, yeah,
phosphorus mine was kind of its first lease in life when they
ran out of phosphorus and it turned into a tourist trap.
-- So, yeah, there like bat poop. Right. It's crazy,
-- man.
Yeah.
Well, you know, it's like any, technically these are renewable resources,
just sort of on human time scale.
That's non renewable, right? Like renewable is something like a tree
maybe,
right? Or, or the sun, the sun comes out every day for now.
And so life is good.
Yeah, much like the helium thing.
Everybody's like, yeah, there'll be more helium generated by uranium decay, but
-- it'll take a few million years.
-- I hear we can just steal it from the moon.
Right.
That's
three.
And, uh, one of my favorite science fiction writers,
Charles Strauss has written extensively.
Why? That's
an incredibly stupid idea.
That's fair. Everything is stupid.
Well, more of the point we can just, if you can build a working
fusion reactor,
chances are,
you can build something that'll run on something other than helium three.
There's, there's a whole bunch of different fuel sources just
as I understand it, helium three is sort of, in theory the easiest one to get to fuse,
right? And we're, you know,
sort of still at the banging rock stage of fusion
as it were still only like five years away.
I will admit I have no idea.
So I'll take your word for that one.
Yeah.
So,
and then here's my absolute all
time favorite one
is um
the cameras that are everywhere now
and doing facial recognition
or
they're not doing facial recognition and they're also not doing face blurring.
Yeah.
You know, I this is one of those things I think about a lot and, and it's not even just
the cameras everywhere. It's also,
there's all this like social media
and, and there's pictures of people everywhere and, and,
and like a great example is if you search Google for either of us,
it's like a cornucopia
of just pictures, right?
And, and
this is kind of the new normal and I wonder sometimes what, what is,
what is the eventual outcome here?
Because I know
there's places like the European Union that's trying to kind of
rein some of this in with like GDPR which is coming
and,
and to a degree, I think that's noble.
But at the same time I feel like it's completely impractical
and I don't know what the end game is.
I don't know what really interests me and
I'm not sophisticated enough yet to have one,
but apparently there's a lot of cameras, uh, now that take 360 pictures,
like 360 degree
pictures. So using some sort of a
combination, I guess of some fish eye lensing and of course,
like when you take a panorama shot, you just basically turn around and it
computer magics the picture together to make it look nice,
you know.
And so, for example, Google is letting people take these pictures because, uh,
well, if you do, uh, Google, you know, if you go to Google Maps and look up a business,
a lot of businesses now will
take 360 view pictures of their
business and put them, you know, online, right?
So that you can see what the business looks like inside, you know,
which is really good if it's like a,
there's this one chain of, uh, it's like a place for kids to play, right?
And you can see how cool it looks.
Um,
but, uh, the Google specifically points out that
So street view that, which is where Google takes the pictures,
they have software to blur out the faces and everything.
-- Yeah. But
-- here's the thing,
-- the 360 view stuff
-- doesn't,
-- people are uploading.
-- Ignoring that though is
even though Google might blur the pictures we look
at like I guarantee they have the originals.
Yeah. No true. But also I'm, I'm more likely to notice a Google street car.
I've actually seen them locally,
uh, that I am some, just some random, taking a picture that, you know,
also happens to be uploading it to Facebook or Google.
And, yeah, I was wondering about this and some things that really come to mind are,
you know, going back to those people on Facebook that, you know,
due to search algorithms were kind of being outed as, you know, whatever,
um, sex workers and stuff.
But one thing that I was kind of thinking about was, you know, undercover policemen,
right?
Because
how are you going to find people
that you can put through police training
-- that don't have a ton of pictures of themselves online?
-- That's a really good point.
And actually I could see a whole, like, criminal economy erupting
that that's essentially doing like background checks to prove this person
isn't a cop and they are actually a fellow criminal.
So
the good news is, most criminals aren't nearly that sophisticated.
But, um,
I mean, it, it really does. Yeah, I mean, you, you just can't hide your past. I mean,
uh, I was watching some fail videos and no doubt at some point, you know,
somebody's gonna be trying to get a job or, you know, maybe trying to get insurance
and that video of them,
like lighting themselves on fire while on a skateboard is gonna come up.
And quite frankly, if I have like five people
and four of them did,
were smart enough not to light themselves on fire
on a skateboard and put it on youtube.
And one of them wasn't smart enough to, you know, figure that out.
Chances are I'm gonna hire one of the four.
I don't know, man. That sounds like a cool story.
Yeah. But like what if he does it in the office?
What's the saying? Poor choices, make good stories.
No, I totally get this. In fact, I remember this when I graduated from college.
This was kind of the birth of people putting pictures on the internet.
And
I remember like many of us who graduated and we told, you know, our friends, like,
get those pictures off the internet, right?
Like I do not want these showing up when people search for my name on Google.
Well,
that's one thing I ran into is is I have a Facebook
account so that when people do tag me in their photos,
I'm notified otherwise they would just take me
in their photos and I would never know.
Yeah, that's true. That's a good point.
-- Right. And it drives me nuts because there's nothing I can really do about this.
-- No,
no, there isn't.
You're stuck with it.
But at the same time, so
I know people who will,
like, anytime you tag them they will go in and un tag themselves and they,
they do all this stuff and they talk about, oh, you know,
I don't want Facebook spying on me and it's like
you've already lost this battle,
right? Like, they're
totally
taking
the computers can figure it out pretty quick now,
right? Yeah,
that's always terrifying too.
And Facebook is like, I think this is so and so in your picture. And it's like,
yes,
yes, it is
really great Reddit posting about this.
Some guy lost enough weight that Facebook didn't recognize him
and he was like, so proud of himself. And I'm like, legit, that's
except Facebook, of course, you know, five minutes later figured it out.
Thanks to Reddit and came over, dude.
I actually, you know, what else this reminds me of is I,
I don't remember if it was Reddit or somewhere
else I saw but there was someone showing off.
They, they don't have a cat
and they kind of took a video and they took their cell
phone and they talked about cat food for a whole day.
And
what do you know, Facebook is showing cat food ads like the next day
and it's like,
Facebook says they're not listening to your microphone. Uh That's probably a lie.
It's looking like
-- I
-- was thinking what was actually more interesting about that.
Uh So Facebook is or maybe is not listening in
on your microphone and suddenly you targeted advertising on that.
That's regardless
what's really fascinating to me about this
is that I can't
prove it one way or the other
because part of it is if I have like the Facebook app on my phone,
it's sending so much encrypted data to and from Facebook,
how would I know?
So, actually I'm going to give Google a plus one here is on my Nexus phone.
I can, I went in and I turned off the microphone for the Facebook app.
So
in theory, Facebook is,
although the other thing I was thinking about this is what if Google
is spying on the microphone and then selling the ad data to Facebook,
which totally could be the case.
But what's fascinating to me about this is that we,
our cell phones are sending and receiving so much data on a daily basis.
Now, it's not like, like in the olden days,
it was really easy to see what an application did because you'd basically turn it on,
on your computer,
you know, turn on TCP dump
and wait for it to call home,
right? Like it was really simple and easy because they basically wouldn't,
like applications didn't really need to talk to the network unless you told it to,
right?
But now, applications like say Facebook, you know, they, they
must talk to the Facebook mothership to be of any use
so you can't block it,
you can't filter it because it's all SSL and TLS encrypted.
And it's typically, you know, those guys are pretty paranoid about it.
So they're, they're having their applications set to be, you know, not like, oh,
hey, the certificate whose name is a little wonky.
But sure, go ahead Anyways,
you know,
actually you bring that up and I just read
that Google Chrome is going to remove certificate pinning
mostly because it's a giant pain in the ass. It doesn't really help.
I know.
I mean, honestly, I looked into it and I was just, basically,
there was about a nine in 10 chance.
I would lock everybody out of our website
and about a one in 10 chance. I wouldn't.
Kurt, there was a 10 in 10 chance you were gonna have people out of your website,
let's face it,
you know. So, yeah. No, I absolutely not.
And well,
and then the other thing with the key pinning is how does that
work with things like lets encrypt or cloud flare all those other,
you know, uh services that do relatively short list certificate.
It
work for those at all.
And I would argue, you know,
the world would be much better off if like
everybody had like 30 days certificates instead of like
two years or I think I can actually buy. Uh,
what is the
longest sort of cheapest
SSL certificate I can buy? I wonder.
Well, ok, but you're only half right. I think,
I think for, for a normal website, yes,
many short lived certificates are superior to one pinned certificate.
But I think if you look at something like Google, for example,
I can understand why they want Chrome to pin their search because there are,
there are literally hostile organizations
that attack people connecting to Google.
Well, the thing is there, it's, it's,
you don't need to pin the actual Google certificate,
you just need to pin which C A is allowed to issue,
right?
And that solves 99% of your problem, right?
Because there's,
there's a current kerfuffle uh today or yesterday about the uh there's a,
a Dutch certificate authority like it's,
it's their National Dutch certificate authority, whatever.
Uh that's been in
browsers, like probably basically forever
uh except Holland
or sorry. Is
-- it the Netherlands is the correct name
-- of the country?
The Netherlands
Holland is the province,
the Netherlands is the country. Yeah. NL Netherlands.
So the Netherlands has passed some new legislation
that comes into effect on January 1st 2018.
So
couple months
basically saying that the security services are allowed to use
like fake keys to intercept data and you know,
do surveillance on people which
well,
yeah, probably means that that local C A is going to be strong armed or paid or
whatever
do you
know? Is this C A, like a Star Wild Card or is it only for the.nl?
-- No, no, no,
-- it's
everything, everything. All right. So, yeah, like,
are there any C A that are actually locked
down to like a.nl or.jp or anything like that?
-- I don't really think there are, you
-- know, I, I don't know the answer to that.
And,
I mean, this is a great example of
the, the law enforcement organizations. Well, I'm sure they have good intent
in doing this. They're, they're,
if they're allowed to do it,
which I'm sure they won't be because I imagine that cer it's going to get yanked.
But if they do it, they, they make us all less secure. Right.
This isn't like, oh, we're doing this for the good of humanity.
It's like, no, you're ruining the internet
pretty much.
Uh,
oh, by the way I can buy easily up to three year certificates.
And how much is a three year cert,
$14.97?
It
-- sounds
-- crazy.
Oh,
my.
I remember when certificates were hundreds of dollars and it was like,
really hard to get them and you had to fill out like,
real paperwork and fax it somewhere.
Oh,
-- dear.
-- But, yeah, no. So back to that. I mean, that's,
uh, yeah, the certificate pinning. I, it doesn't really matter.
Especially my understanding is Google is now ac A and I think they've
issued, their C A has issued their own certificates. Have they? Not,
I have no idea.
But like when you, when you own a web browser, you can just become ac a, right.
It's fine.
But, uh, yeah, so basically, I mean,
what, what we really need is ideally is that DNS pinning of, you know,
which certificate, authority or authorities
are allowed to issue certificates for your domain and
subdomains because that's kind of really what matters.
Right? Because typically people have,
uh, you know, a reasonably long term
relationship with their certificate authority.
You know, if nothing else you fall into a rut and just kind of stay with the guy,
you know,
even if they're terrible because
actually there's, I know there's many large organizations that
they, they purposely use one certificate authority for all of their certs.
And the reason being
when they scan their infrastructure, if they see a cert that isn't from that C A,
like they know there are shenanigans be it.
Generally speaking, it's just someone like
a let's and crypt cert and they're doing something dumb. But, but
there's also the possibility that you have like a rogue actor in play here and,
and that
should not be there.
Yeah.
So I think the pinning certificates to ac A
to which C A or C A is plural that you use
makes a lot more sense than pinning the actual certificate because,
yeah,
if you ever have to roll that certificate over which you will have to do at some point.
I mean, it's just, it's a disaster.
Yeah.
Yeah, hopefully we'll see more of that.
So,
-- um,
-- well,
did you want to quickly discuss the 152 different things
-- that you can do to keep yourself safe
-- online?
That
crazy thing.
It's not.
Well, ok, so here's what happened.
Google did a survey of security pros and I don't remember being asked. Were you?
Goodness. No,
I think calling us professionals is a stretch,
right?
Anyway, so they did a security survey of about 231 infosec pros worldwide,
basically asking them, you know, kind of what,
what can you do or what should you do to be safe?
Um And some things
came up commonly.
So for example, patch your systems and software, 90 people mentioned that,
you know, on that or for example, use unique passwords, use strong passwords,
right?
Some very
generically good advice.
Um I'm gonna disagree but
go
on well. Ok. But what was interesting to me
was that basically the majority of the stuff is very difficult to do
remotely well and reliably let alone get it. Perfect.
So for example, like telling a human being to use unique and strong passwords
is impossible because they,
they're gonna have like 100 passwords and they
just physically can't remember that many different things,
right.
So, you know, what they probably should do is
use a password manager. What a great idea.
And you know, and I'm kind of looking at this and I'm thinking like, oh,
here's a great example, browsing habits use http S well,
I don't really get to use it either it's there or it's not
right. Like it's not really up to me.
Um, I don't get much say in the matter
-- and then my favorite was be careful slash think before you click.
-- Oh,
my goodness.
What does that mean?
No,
that is.
I want to scream when,
when people talk about that where you hear people say things like, oh,
-- look at the link before you click out
-- every
single link on Twitter is T dot
-- C.
-- Yes,
I know exactly like that. That's ridiculous advice.
And not only that
we need to be able to trust our web browsers. Right?
And, and we have to find a way to make it.
So these web browsers aren't serving malware and we aren't.
So you, you,
you should be able to open up any web page
and any email
and not have it on your computer.
Just that's it. That's all I have to say.
Because if, if, if that's not possible, we're up the creek.
That's a reasonable requirement I would say.
And the only exception I would say is for some reason if you've given that web page,
I don't know.
I actually know. I can't think of any exceptions.
The only exception I can really think is
if you download an executable from that page,
then run it locally then, you know, that's not your browser's,
that's,
that's fair.
Yeah.
But fundamentally anything my web browser or email
client suck down from the internet and,
like, try to display to me should not result in my system getting hosed
completely. Even with an ad blocker and a bunch of other stuff, running
my web browser and email client by definition have to
like, go grab all sorts of weird wonky stuff and there's no way
it can be ever safe because I mean, a great example that, you know,
the front page of cnn.com is over a megabyte.
Now
there's like how many elements in it?
I I don't know several 100
you know,
um or for example, you pull in something like Google ads and all of a sudden boom,
you're pulling in like 20 or 30 different things,
you know.
So yeah, no, that whole click uh think before you click or whatever. No, no, just,
I mean, think before you put your user name and password into something.
-- Yeah,
-- probably, maybe again, this is where a password manager kind of helps you.
Well,
-- actually
-- this is where two factor authentication with something like a
key comes in because
the host name is part of the authentication request.
So even if somebody manages to man in the it,
you, it's no good,
right?
And,
and so here's my take on this and you showed me this and my first reaction was like WTF
and then I read it and my reaction was wtf and,
and the reason though my reasoning changed at first I thought 100 and 52 things.
That's insane that anyone would be expected to know them.
And then I read it and I'm like, oh, ok.
So it's not that any one person is expected to know 100 and 52 things.
It's that our industry is so disorganized that you ask
a bunch of people and you end up with a
list of 100 and 52 instead of a list that
is six things because everyone is telling the same thing,
right? Like
this is crazy.
Well, more to the point, we don't
really have anything truly useful to tell people by and large because for example,
Josh, how do I use a web browser securely?
Right? And the only answer I can think of that makes any sense is like
use Chrome,
maybe Firefox
just like
IIII I curl up in the corner and cry
and that's,
that's the best advice I got.
-- And like
-- the only advice I would have for email security is use the uh don't use
like don't use an email,
-- like
-- use gmail. Look, that's the end of the story. All right.
I know there's people who think, oh no,
you can't use Google because they're evil and even through evil,
like they're doing a better job than you are.
And, and
I've given up Google one Google. You can have my email, right?
Like evil or not, you win,
-- you
-- know. And so,
yeah, you know, I just fundamentally and some of the advice here, like,
don't use or don't trust open networks.
-- Great. So, like, how do I get internet access again? If I'm not at my house?
-- You don't,
again, um, curl up in the corner, rock back and forth. Maybe
that's fine. That's fine.
Right. And the thing I keep thinking of here is
if, if you and I went to mechanics
in our respective locales
and as
the
mechanics, like,
what are the top three things we can do for the maintenance of our car?
I bet we get back the same list
because it's probably stuff like,
change your
oil
filter.
Right.
Exactly.
I don't know if that counts as one thing or two,
-- whatever.
-- It doesn't matter.
You know what I
mean? Like,
and make sure your tires are
-- inflated.
-- There are certain things because in a part of this mind you is
this is a very mature industry
and we are not.
But I think also,
uh, if you change your oil
or rather, I should say if you don't change your oil, like,
and obviously bad thing happens. Right. Like
we know what happens
if I don't use a password manager. Does a bad thing happen to me?
Maybe.
No, no, we can't say yes because the answer isn't. Yes. The answer is maybe. Right.
And that's one of the challenges
there's a statistical likelihood that something may or may not happen,
which is basically useless.
You know, it's like trying to convince Children not to smoke.
Well, will this kill me?
Well,
there's a statistical increase in the chance that you will
develop something that may or may not kill you.
So I just lie to my kids and say smoking kills you.
And although I think history has shown us that,
that lying in such a way has backfired.
But, you know, for now, like with simple things, like,
you know, we look both ways before we cross the street so we can get smushed by a car.
That is good advice
or, or if you're in the Netherlands, you look both ways so you don't get hit by a bike,
right?
Same thing.
But yeah, just looking at this list of 100 and 52 things,
the only things I can see that are maybe actually somewhat helpful is
to just, um,
if it's too good to be true, it probably is.
And there was actually a really good article on CBC market watch.
It's uh our marketplace, it's our national news, their little thing where,
you know, people get ripped off and stuff
and people signing up for free trials online
of like skincare cream and stuff.
And there's like some fine print somewhere that says basically by signing
up for this free trial and paying the $5 shipping handling,
you agree to pay like $89.95
a month for continuing shipments unless you cancel in the next 74 seconds.
You know, and you can only cancel through registered mail to like Zimbabwe,
of course
or whatever.
And so, you know, all these people, of course,
sign up for a free trial and they're like, oh, it sucks.
I don't like it, whatever.
Throw in the garbage and then, you know,
a month later they get this huge credit card bill
and the beauty is apparently the credit card companies are like, well, yeah,
you signed up for that,
sorry.
You know.
And so they were looking through these sites trying
to find the fine print that actually covers this
and in some of them it just flat out
wasn't possible unless you went like 23 clicks deep,
you know, and, and what,
what offends me more about that is not that they're ripping off people.
I mean, that is offensive
but that the credit card companies are letting them get away with this.
That's interesting. I, I wonder if you actually,
like,
called your credit card company and put up a fight if they wouldn't cave quickly
and
the argument from the supplier would be, is that, yeah, you know,
they signed up for this and we ship them the product
right there was,
you can't do a chargeback dispute easily in that case.
I mean, if they don't send you something or,
or flat out like you know,
it's just straight up.
I've gotten chargebacks put in place for less.
-- So I wonder,
-- well, I'm guessing these guys have also figured out how to shen
the system,
by definition, they figured it out.
Otherwise people would be calling the credit
card companies and reversing the charges,
like,
pretty quick.
Um, part of it, as I know is that the company is like, oh, you know,
you can totally reverse the charge. That's totally legit.
We need you to send back the product,
right?
And of course, sending back the product costs like, you know,
some obscene amount of money
because it's going to Zimbabwe.
-- Yeah, or
-- whatever, you know, it's got to be registered and blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah.
You know, this is,
this is honestly the reason why I won't sell anything on ebay because
it's just such a hassle.
Like if the person I send it to decides to rip me off as a seller, like,
how do I prove that I sent this thing to them
-- registered
-- man.
I've read tons of horror stories about dealing with like,
like essentially malicious buyers on
ebay
and they generally side with the buyer in almost every instance.
And so, I mean, yeah, like selling things on ebay is a terrible idea, in my opinion.
I mean, that's another story,
although I also know people who are very successful doing this.
So my suspicion is
if you know what you're doing,
you can probably protect yourself but if you're like us,
yeah, you have no chance. Well, I guess it's kind of like security. Right?
Like, if you're an expert, you're fine.
If you're a seller of a lot of stuff and you have like a 1% failure rate. Cool.
You can probably eat that loss. Right.
But if you're like us and you sell one thing every couple of months,
if it fails, it becomes a huge pain in the butt.
You know, that's, that's kind of how identity theft is.
You know, because like, out of a million people, identity theft, me, whatever.
But for that one lady who's had her identity stolen, what, 15 times now, since,
since the Equifax breach,
you know, her life sucks.
That's true.
You know, and I mean,
I know it's going to be very hard for her to
prove some loss and get some money out of them,
but
I'm just thinking maybe we should come up with like, ok, you know, here for,
let's say,
maybe minimum wage, right?
For every, you know, you keep a log of the hours you spend dealing with this, uh,
with the, uh, the identity theft issue and we at least pay,
make the person breached your information, pay you minimum wage.
I don't know, super lucrative business and scamming those people.
Well, you know, something because, I mean, you know,
what incentive does Equifax have?
The last time this happened,
they changed their name to Equifax and kind of got rid of their bad history,
like, straight up.
I mean, it's farcical because you and I both know nothing will change.
Probably all of our listeners are like, Equifax, grumble, grumble grumble. But
I think in their hearts they know nothing will change.
No, nothing
out of
Equifax.
The best we can do is freeze our credit report
and then unfreeze it and freeze it and unfreeze it and freeze it
is,
that's probably the best thing without question.
It's,
well, I haven't looked at the
Equifax stock in a while,
but my suspicion is it's probably going to recover fairly soon if it hasn't already,
which is generally, you know, I'll never forget that. It was
right.
So
I remember
it was one of the Yahoo breaches,
um, some years back
and I was, I was talking to a friend
and he was, he was saying, oh, you know, it was one of the,
there was the big Yahoo breach story came out, the stock kind of went down and then a
couple of months later there was like, oh, yeah, we increased the number again,
right?
Because they increased it like 10 times
and they increase the number again.
I was talking to someone and they're saying, oh man, did, like, did you hear the news?
Like, like Yahoo? They're totally screwed. And I looked at him and I said,
what do you think their stock is doing right now? He's like, oh, it's tanking.
I said it's like it's up two points, you know.
Nobody care.
Sorry,
I lied. Uh, the
Equifax stock was hovering around
115, 120 back in January 2017.
Uh, then it was
going generally up and it hit, uh, about 100 and 45 100 and 40 over the summer.
And then, yeah,
the breach happened and it went as low as 93 and then now it's back up to about 110.
So essentially, if you look at it on a one year basis,
it had a bit of a bull run up over the year and then, you know, kind of tanked a bunch,
but it's essentially maybe 5 10% lower than it was at the beginning of the year.
Um,
you know, I should start with fund that buys companies when they get hacked
and then sells in six months.
I
recover it.
And then the other thing too is who cares about the stock price?
Like the CEO of Equifax took a, what was it?
$18 million golden parachute and left and left.
Yeah, we'll put that in quotes, but it wasn't his fault.
I was told it was one guy's fault. You didn't patch
his server.
Yeah.
Uh, no, apparently it wasn't that he, it's not that he didn't patch there.
It's like that he didn't
look at the issue and decide whether or not to patch or something
he had to tell someone else to patch it, that's what it was.
Right.
Right. Right.
Anyway,
so, yeah, I mean,
yeah, but fundamentally we can't opt out, we're not their product.
We, we can't sue them.
Uh, I am really curious to see where those class action lawsuits go.
I assume there's going to be something like $10 off your next identity
theft monitoring service from them
or
something.
Exactly.
And, and the lawyers are going to settle for a small fortune.
I mean, and that's how they all work.
It's,
yeah, whatever.
But, but again, I mean, I think this, like, personifies our problem
is
we can't even decide
what the problem is and,
and obviously security pros came up with a list of 100 and 52 things.
I mean, it, it is madness.
What is going on.
Right.
Yeah.
Yeah. No, it's,
yeah, I'm just looking at all of these and, like, honestly, um,
yeah, I, I don't know what to say or do,
like, you know, and I'm beginning to wonder because my kids are getting to the age,
like, well, how do I get them computing safely and not,
like giving out their name online or, or, you know,
going through my wallet to get a credit card because, hey,
this website says it'll give me a free
whats it if you put in your
credit card.
Ok, seriously, man.
The way you talk, it sounds like your Children are like deviant criminals.
The one guy is like, he's really good at shoulder surfing.
So, here's the deal, I guess.
And this is something I think about a lot because my kids are
in a similar situation.
And obviously you and I grew up in a time when, like, there just wasn't internet.
-- So we didn't have to
-- wait. I didn't have a computer until I was 16.
I was slightly younger than you. But it doesn't matter.
So, here's, here's the point though
is
everyone is going to have pictures on the internet,
everyone is going to have their names on the internet.
And so
I, I think what, what we consider normal
is going to change drastically
by the time, you know, let's say in 10 years or 20 years or whatever.
And the question that kind of becomes,
what does that mean?
Right. Are, are we going to have governments protecting the data?
And like Europe is trying to do this and,
well, no, no, no Europe is trying to pass laws to make companies protect the data.
Right. Yes.
Right. Right.
And it's going to be like the companies, we hope that they're honest.
Uh
Yes.
And, and II, I have no idea how this is going to turn out. My suspicion is
the devil's in the details and it's gonna fail miserably.
I mean, like a great example is a European cookie thing, right?
Like now when you're in Europe and you visit a web page, it kindly instructs you,
it's collecting your cookie, you're setting cookies for you and it's, like,
stop telling me this.
Everyone's doing this. I'm sick of clicking. Ok. Right.
Yeah. Its
me nuts because,
and, and has that made anything better? My assumption is the intent
was to make websites stop using cookies.
And
it almost certainly,
I thought the intent was more the third party cookies because let's face it.
The problem is not usually the cookies with the website you're actually visiting.
It's the Facebook, Google
17 other domains with cookies,
-- but they're tracking you around the entire
-- web. It still happens
and
they didn't fix it. And my guess is GDPR will be very similar. And so that kind of
this is where the great question lies, especially around privacy is
where do we end up? And, and I don't know the answer.
My guess though is, well,
if we kind of put this in some context is
I bet when things like credit monitoring became a thing,
there were people having very similar discussions about how it was going
to be the end of the world and now there's a company
collecting all the information on all the people and they can know
what's going on and the government's gonna take it and they're gonna,
you know,
they're going to sell us to space aliens or, or make something, right?
You know what I mean?
There is some, I mean, there, there is some generally creepy stuff going on
around
like the one of the biggest things that really frustrates me and it worries me
is for example,
your credit score is not just now a thing about whether or not you get a loan,
but it also determines the rate that you pay.
And so for people that have bad credit scores,
it's getting really hard to get out of that hole because once you're labeled,
yeah, you know
what, how do you get out of that hole?
Um and then taking it to its somewhat logical extreme is, you know, China with their,
their social score for people.
You know, and if you kind of do descent online,
you get a lower score and good luck renting an apartment or getting a job.
-- It's like
-- a black mirror episode.
-- Yeah.
-- Well, but the reality is we already do. This is North America, right?
How many jobs now request your social insurance number and your credit score?
And they don't want to hire anybody with terrible credit because, you know, the,
the fear is that, oh, this person's bad with money,
they're going to steal from us or do something stupid or whatever.
But again, it boils down to that once you get a bad credit score.
How do you get out of that?
Yeah. Actually I don't think I've ever had to do that.
You didn't have to give them your credit score per se.
That is true. They could have looked it up.
No, no, they couldn't have because
the last couple of jobs I've gotten.
No, you can only do a soft check with the social security number though. Right.
-- Which they would have for tax purposes only
-- after I was hired.
So, so, like, in, in, in this particular case, when I,
because obviously I just got hired at Elastic, you know, a couple of months ago
I did not give them any sort of information they
could have used in that way prior to being hired.
Now, granted, they could have pulled my credit after I filled out like my new hire,
you know, information and,
but
in all seriousness, I, I'm fairly certain they don't.
-- But, yeah, I guarantee there's places that, well, here's,
-- uh,
according to the surveys I'm seeing here it's, uh, well, in 2012 it was 47%
of employers.
Ouch.
Yeah.
Crazy man.
And, uh, oh, also good news. It's growing in Canada.
We're lagging a little bit behind you. But, you know, we're, we're doing our best.
-- You'll catch up one of these days,
-- right?
For sure.
-- Uh,
-- oh, and TD. So this happened with, um,
with TD.
So this man spoke to the Huffington Post candidate after
he was given a conditional offer from TD insurance,
Milo
Monex.
Uh, so that's like T DS.
They, anyways basically bought an insurance company,
um, blah, blah, blah, to start a job as an insurance advisor, blah, blah, blah.
And then basically they did a credit check on him and rescinded. The offer
and TD is
really unashamedly. Uh, what's the thing
essentially that, uh, you know, they want the best candidate possible? Too bad.
Right. And it's not illegal to do this.
It's not illegal to discriminate based on a credit score. It's not like a protected.
Right.
So, yeah,
you know,
and that's what kind of gets me about these things. Like,
you know, what happens when somebody actually gets that image
recognition thing going and like, you know,
people who did stupid things on skateboards are being, you know,
discriminated against
because you know what, it's going to cost us law
insurance claims later down the road because there are, you know,
arms and elbows or whatever, all messed up or, you know, whatever, right?
Like
-- we laugh now
-- but
I, I don't know, man, I mean, I, I guess we could.
So, so this, this is interesting because
I, I I'm putting my security hat on while I'm thinking about this. And
if we look at the problems in the security universe,
which I don't think are necessarily drastically different in many ways,
we have been completely unable to solve these problems.
But you look at something like the insurance
industry or the banking industry and they are,
they're quite willing to be just ruthless,
they don't necessarily solve the problem, but they price the market accordingly.
It's like
you can,
that's solving the problem though,
right?
It's, it's basically, but they're in the position of
um in the classic where we can,
when you have a risk, you can
minimize the risk. So you can do things to limit the risk, right?
Get a seatbelt and an airbag in your car, right?
These minimize the risk of you getting all smashed up.
You can choose to not accept the risk.
So for example, you could choose not to get in a car.
However, the majority of us don't have the ability to make those choices.
But when you're, for example, selling insurance,
you can very easily, not sell to somebody
that is
not service that market. And that's the problem, right? Is,
is I, you know,
it's like all those people that are like, oh, you know,
you can reduce your risk of like online fraud and theft
and stuff by like not using your credit card online.
I'm like, awesome. So like, how do I buy stuff again or ever take a trip?
Ok.
I think you're on to something here though. Is you talk about
kind of insurance pricing people out of the
market because they don't want to help them.
We don't do that in security or,
-- or in it in general like they
-- are because they're gonna
go do it anyways whether if we say yes or no,
a
business
case
to go do the dangerous
thing.
Ok. So that is yes.
And that's a topic I think for another day and, and we can talk about it. But
the point is even ignoring the fact that security and it don't
necessarily get along or see eye to eye in many instances.
I think there are,
it's weird to me that security and it are two different things.
Yeah. That is weird.
And actually I just gave a talk about that today and we'll, we'll cover that another,
another day
because
they shouldn't be different.
But that's another story. But anyway, the point being
that,
uh, let's ignore
security and our, it, let's just say it
right.
We all have vendors who are
terrible,
like unreasonably terrible.
-- At some point, I have to buy a wifi access point from somebody ignoring
-- that.
Even, right.
Many of us will stick with crappy vendors
and, and, and we won't walk and say no, this isn't worth it.
And, and there's a variety of reasons for that, but I think,
I think we struggle and, and this is again,
like security is part of the overall quality discussion.
But I think there's certain quality discussions where like
there are a lot of organizations running incredibly low quality software.
And in reality,
like if we were looking at it from kind of a capitalistic marketplace perspective,
we should be walking away from these and saying like your stuff is crap,
but we, we really don't very often
well.
But part of the problem is so a great example being Equifax, right,
they ran a whole bunch of software, they didn't update it, they got nailed.
I mean, they've got to attend some annoying congressional hearings
and the CEO had to step down and take $18 million with,
ok,
chances are he probably could have made a lot
more money if he'd stayed over the next 5,
1020 years, whatever.
But
like,
I'm sorry, but if you say like, Kurt,
the downside of your failure is $18 million I'm going to be like,
awesome.
Like, can I fail tomorrow and be out of here?
You know. And so that's part of the problem, right? Is
I, well, data breaches as an example. Has any company ever been
killed or
severely censured so much so that it
like probably mattered.
The only one I know of is what's it, Diginotar,
which was the, the
C A that was not a data breach. That was ac A that was so grossly incompetent that
they had to be put down because it was just like,
you know, if the browsers didn't do that then any like you and I would be CAS.
That's true.
I have always wanted to be ac A
Yeah. You know,
um,
like Target, certainly, I mean, I still shop at Home Depot,
you know, Target.
Well, Target failed in Canada but for a whole pile of different reasons,
actually, quite a brutal case study. If you read it, just Google it, it's,
it's basically everything they could have done wrong.
-- They gleefully did
-- and, and the weather helped too.
Right?
A
little bit, but mostly it was things like not, you know,
having enough shelf space or logistics or
people or transport
or a plan.
Yeah, exactly.
Oh, my favorite is the case,
the case studies of why Walmart failed in Germany. Now, there's a good one.
-- I can only imagine what that looks
-- like.
-- They also tried to make the Germans sing in the morning.
-- I
would love to see that
because
it did not go over well anyway.
But, uh, yeah, so, I mean, that's the biggest thing I'm seeing with security is like,
we can't,
like, I can't walk away from products, especially when I've inherit, you know,
companies that inherit this technical debt.
You can't like a great example, like every I airline it system ever,
right. Like Westjet just had a meltdown over the weekend and
had a whole pile of delays on Saturday because their, it system cratered out. Right.
You can't just go buy a new airline it system.
Uh, no,
no, you can't. And, and in many cases, yeah, you're, you're, you're trapped.
It is.
I don't know.
I don't,
maybe we just need 100 and 53 items on our list now. Right.
Yeah,
I, I honestly think part of it is
where possible outsourcing to trust your providers.
And, I mean, people give the cloud so much grief about this, like, oh,
you're outsourcing, you know,
core competencies to some third party who's basically going, like, screw you over.
Yeah. Yeah.
That might happen.
And on the flip side though, you know.
Yeah, Microsoft Amazon and Google will
screw up.
Not Mike, but they will screw up at some point, you know, like office 364 being the,
the good one, you know, where they,
the, they didn't take, uh, like, leap years into account for their certificate,
renewal practices.
Um, but
are they gonna screw up
more often and more terribly than me? Yeah. Probably not.
Right. Right.
Well, not only that, this is, I just had the discussion a little while ago. In fact is
if you look at like the cloud
and, and I'm going to pick on elastic in
this case because we have something called elastic cloud.
And the idea is right.
Very clever.
It's,
it's essentially a managed elastic search instance that kind of we take care of.
And if you run this stuff yourself, you have to take care of the system,
you have to keep the system updated, you have to keep elastic search updated.
You have to keep, like it can figure correctly. There's like a million, right?
Backups. There's a million things you have to worry about
or
you can just pay elastic some money and elastic does all of that stuff for you,
but not just not just that they do it.
We also have the people who built it.
So like we have a level of expertise that
you just cannot have ever under any circumstance,
ignoring economics. Kurt, like the fact is
nobody working for anyone who isn't elastic is building elastic, right?
Like that's just the reality of it.
And so you just by definition,
you will never have the core developers on your team,
meaning you will never have that level of talent,
right? And, and this is true of nearly every cloud provider
where if you're working with this cloud
provider and they're providing you a service,
they,
they almost certainly by definition have like the
best of the best for that particular service
right there, right? Like literally right there waiting to help.
Well, I mean, that's the beauty of the whole open
source model, right?
Is we have these open like Kubernetes is a great thing,
a great example of this because it just in the last like two weeks,
it's basically come out as the winner, right?
Even Docker movies with up
on the
street,
you know, like I saw Swarm and I'm like, oh, that's pretty sweet. Like, you know,
a year or two ago, it was pretty cool,
but
the only people working on Docker Swarm were Docker,
right?
And
that's not even the bad part.
The really bad part is when somebody comes up with a really cool feature.
And in a traditional open source project, it's very much a meritocracy,
right?
Even though you have large companies involved like Kubernetes is a great example,
You got Red Hat, you got Microsoft, you got
Google, you know, some
big players.
Yeah.
So even though there are these huge companies involved,
they kind of balance each other out.
Right. So, you know, for example, if Microsoft had some crazy agenda,
the others would be, you know, call them on their BS and conversely, you know,
Microsoft isn't,
or Red Hat isn't big enough to block any one person with a really clearly good idea.
And that's the biggest thing I find with these open source things, right?
Is that somebody with a clearly good idea, especially if they have working code,
right? OK. We're gonna go do that
right. We're going to merge or commit and boom, cut a release, you know,
and
yeah, outside the open source world, you can't do that or they won't do it. And
yeah, we have these clear cloud winners where it's just, yeah, like
Kubernetes.
Yeah, I'm sorry, it won,
you know, things like elastic search, right? Like uh
I
honestly, when most of these open source things,
I can't even be bothered to look for
commercial alternatives now because the open source thing is
like more than
OK enough or good enough.
It's literally not even worth the time,
but on the off chance there's some like
specialized company somewhere that made something awesome.
It did and it never happens.
No, I agree.
I agree, man.
So in, I guess in summary, uh
everything's broken still,
I think we're beginning to learn why it's broken.
I
maybe, you know, we're kind of, I would say we're at the 19 forties
stage of
uh automotive stuff right now, we're,
we're starting to industrialize and we're starting to,
to sort of do
mass production.
So instead of handcrafting everything,
we're actually building assembly lines that build the widgets,
I, I think that's fair. I think, I
-- think we can
-- say that and once we do that,
then you can actually apply safety to it because
the problem is right now with handcrafted stuff,
you apply safety to it.
And that one handcrafted thing is safe,
but all the other handcrafted things are a flaming pile of
garbage.
And
so
the armed security paper right arm came
up with a security paper basically pointing out
that they're going to do a bias and part of an Os or a Full Os
wasn't 100% clear
because basically if they don't,
all their vendors will
and you'll have like 300 flaming piles of garbage.
Now, we just have one flaming pile of
garbage
which will get fixed
now, whether or not those vendors allow updates.
But hey, we're still
ahead of where we were before. You know, at least there's a chance now.
Yes.
And I, I know,
you know,
it's like Android versus like all can you imagine if Verizon tried to write a phone SS
II,
I bet they did.
And it was so bad. It never made it out the door.
Yeah. Yeah.
Yep. Anyway.
-- All right, man, I I think we should call it. Any, any parting
-- advice, drink water.
It's good for you.
Right, man.
That'll do. Thank you. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everybody for listening.
If you want, you can go to open source security podcast.com for the show notes.
For all the crazy things we talked about,
you can hit us up on Twitter at the Poland Os S podcast.
Hashtag We have a Facebook group. You're welcome to join.
And if nothing else, Kurt, you have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Everybody have a good week.