Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
and my partner in reading massive amounts of email.
-- Josh Bresser, dude,
-- I, I haven't read email in like three days. It's fine.
Oh, no.
Yeah, it's piling
up.
I can't wait, I can't wait to go back to it. I'm in the middle of a bit of an emergency.
That should be,
hopefully by the time this show comes out exactly what's going on will be known,
but it's been been a treat anyway.
Anyway.
-- So,
-- um, it's funny because that emergency is kind of related to today's show topic
which is
github
getting
sacked.
Yeah. Yeah.
So there's, there's an article and this has been going around a little bit,
but I'll just
the,
the title of the article is github besieged
by millions of malicious repositories and ongoing attack.
And I really like this story
because a
bunch of people are calling this a supply chain attack
and it's like this is not a supply chain attack,
this is a github
attack,
Ashley. I'm gonna disagree with you
because Github is people's supply chain.
I mean, it is, but this is like saying
anything that happens to github
equals supply chain attack.
Yeah, that, that's how the world works. Now,
I don't
-- think
-- I agree with that.
OK. Find me an open
source project, not hosting on github.
OK?
I agree with that.
Github
is critical path
in that regard.
It's not just the critical path, it's,
and we're gonna, I'm gonna throw it out. Now,
github
is the discoverability aspect of open source by and large. Now
it is now, I agree with that,
but I don't think every single incident
at
github equals supply chain attack.
I'm
gonna
disagree.
I think it, I I'm not gonna say, OK,
single incident obviously, but the this incident very specifically has the intent
of polluting the open source supply
by getting Typo squatting names, getting close names.
But also for example, perfect example,
I needed a
HTML to mark down library.
OK. Right.
And so I went to P Pie
and there's a couple,
the top rated one was not updated since 2019. I'm like maybe it works, maybe doesn't.
Then I looked on github
and how do you determine what is the best on github?
I mean people love stars and,
-- and, and
-- they are usually a good indicator because it
can be, they were
a lot of stuff I look at
it works except well now it's not going to because
you're gonna find some garbage repo with 10,000 stars,
10,000 forks.
We need to explain this story before we
go on because we're already ahead of ourselves.
-- So,
-- so all that's happened is somebody automated the
production, if you will, I guess production is the right word.
Uh the mass production of forks of github
repos
where they make a few changes.
And they're also
to put it bluntly, this is uh this is Web Farm
seo blink farming
seo, but they're using it to distribute malware.
Well, and that's the catch, right?
So they get this repo that is more popular than the real repo.
But what,
what is the attack angle and the attack angle is malicious backdoor software stuff.
Well, it's not just that
they're also going,
it sounds like they're going to like to Discord
and forums and places like that and suggesting these links
as a solution to the problem and because they're
spamming these bad repos with stars and forks and things
when an un
suspecting user looks at it, they say, oh, it has 2000 stars. It must be legit.
And I think historically, that was a reasonable conclusion to make.
This is exactly how I go and look at restaurant reviews is first of all, I want no, no.
First of all, I want to see a 4.5 and higher,
ideally or four and higher.
But I also look at the number of reviews because no offense.
But if you have a restaurant with 10 reviews and a five
star rating like,
yeah,
they got 10 friends to review it.
Whereas perfect example, we went to Flat Burger the other day.
Flat Burger has a 4.9 rating on 450
ratings spanning the three years they've been open.
I mean, that's not bad. D A 4.9 is not bad.
-- No, that's
-- spectacular. No, I was more thinking the 450 ratings.
Oh, yeah.
So 450 ratings over three years. And it's like, so there's consistency there.
Right, going back three years.
So I'll look at the oldest ratings and the
newest ratings because I also have been to a,
a really high rated restaurant
that had just changed hands. And then when I actually,
after ordering I'm like, this is wonky,
what's going on and I looked at the newest ratings.
I'm like,
oops, I've made a horrible mistake
and this is exactly what's happening. Is it pollutes discoverability
and validation? And now you have to do more. It's not enough to just
like, type in, you know, html to,
uh, mark down Python and, you know, the top three results are probably ok.
Well, now there's a whole bunch of malware and stuff like that. Ok.
Well, I guess I'll look at like,
Forks and Stars to see who's the most popular and well established.
Well, that's not helpful anymore. Ok.
Now I have to look at which one's kind of been around for more than a few years
and all of a sudden you're asking people to
uh need to be experts
in reading the tea leaves of github
repos
-- to determine what's good and bad.
-- Sure. Sure.
And, and that's a related problem, I think,
but I would not call it necessarily a supply chain problem specifically.
-- I think it's maybe related.
-- Can I make a suggestion?
I think I know what the problem is but github
has effectively become something like pi pie or N PM Js.org.
-- But it does not behave like that.
-- It does not,
-- but people treat it like it
-- is.
These Attackers could almost certainly publish
these packages into pie pie or N PM, right?
Like it's been proven time and time again that
the verification process is not amazing there. Right.
Right.
But they also have done that in the past and the name space owners have cleaned it out.
I mean, that's fair and well, and I guess
the other aspect of that is if you look at pie pie,
it becomes harder to fake
-- the the like linkages and
-- well, there's no forks and stars,
not just that.
No, no, the the like pi pie and M PM will say like, oh, there are 4000
and other
projects using this dependency and that you can't fake, right? You can't,
-- well, you could, but it would be really hard,
-- you can fake it. But
but it's also easy to detect because it's an island, it's a new island. And
so that's why remember all these people who are always like,
hey, you got a great blog. Can I get a link in there
because they want, they want to connect their island to the mainland
for sure. And so,
but I think this is a key thing. I just, I never thought about this but
I know that github
is not
a name space managed,
it is name space managed,
but they don't behave like a name space managed place like PI
P or N PM js.org like perfect example is github.com/red Hat.
What is that?
-- As far as I can tell some random guy, I don't
-- think they own that. They were
to
get
it.
-- Yeah. And
-- it's some random guy with like two commits. Did
they get it?
No,
-- they still don't,
-- they still don't.
Red Hat has something like 100 orgs in there. It's a mess.
And so that's the problem is github
does do name space management
but they don't
do curation is maybe the word I want to find or
look for and but people treat it like they do.
-- I
-- I think
something you said is important, especially when it comes to
github. As you were mentioning, you're talking about an island, right?
I think by definition,
Github is basically a bunch of islands that are not necessarily connected.
What's the world?
It's the world
is
the world,
but it's we don't have the kind of connective
tissue in a lot of ways specifically on github
and I think
it, it, you are correct at the beginning when you mentioned there's
like a certain amount of like trust and authority
in github
things going on. Right. Rightly.
So, because generally speaking, it's where everything is going on today.
Well, implicitly, I have to trust github because I
have to trust github.
Like I, I have,
I have over 100 and 50 fork repos in my personal thing because it's all stuff I use
and need and I want to have a copy of it in case they ever delete the repo,
right? I'm
here with this. I
do
-- the same
-- thing and it makes me laugh when people are like, oh, you shouldn't do that.
And I'm like, what? And they're like, you should,
you should start it, not fork it, forking takes space and I'm like, well,
you can start and fork.
That's not how enterprise disk storage and git works.
It's I'm not taking up any space, I promise.
-- Oh, wait,
-- they're saying forking is using up this space.
Yeah, they don't understand how git works
anyways. It was funny because I was like, I'm gonna not even try and educate them, but
regardless
github
gives the sheen of authoritative trust just like a linkedin page for a company.
-- I mean,
-- to a degree.
Now, I, I think there's another piece to this though we need to bring into play
is so there are Attackers
doing the shenanigans on github,
but github
is also fighting them
and they
taking down a ton of this stuff on a pretty regular basis. So it's not like
Github's just sitting there throwing their hands in the air and saying, oh,
poor little Github.
There's nothing we can do.
Poor Microsoft. If only they had some security and technical expertise to battle,
maybe you could start a gofundme to, to hire security people or something. Right.
I mean, and that's the good news is at least it's github
that's getting whacked by this because they
have the backing of Microsoft and Microsoft.
It does have several decades of
like dealing with fancy Bear, let alone these people.
Yeah, they're pretty good. They know what's up for sure,
for sure. But the problem is, for example, there's some very
conceptually simple things they could do
to really murder this like we did with DNS tasting, which is like a 25 cent fee.
But then github
would become literally unusable for everybody without a credit card,
which globally is a lot of people.
So one of the problems is github because they want to
be accessible and available to the community and to the world.
Well, that makes life for Attackers a lot easier
and that I think is one of the interesting challenges here.
I I don't think I would say it makes life for Attackers easier. I think
Attackers are opportunistic
and defenders by definition have to chase the Attackers.
It's the perpetual cat and mouse game right?
And now you have Attackers focusing on this particular aspect
of github
and now it is fundamentally up to github
-- to decide how to react to that. And for now they're taking down repos.
-- And I like that
not even pretending
that the end users being affected like the people on Discord server saying, hey,
how do I do X?
And somebody's like, oh there's a library that does X here it is.
I like that we're not even pretending that we can educate those people.
Like, no, no, we can't. This is like this to me is the phishing thing.
Like I love that phishing is like who educate users to only click trustworthy links.
And I'm like, cool, it goes through bitly,
is it trustworthy or not?
And they're like, uh
it's
-- like
-- this, this can't be up to use. I mean, this is where
so as much as I've complained about it and I complained about it constantly.
Like the open SSF has their scorecard project,
which I still think is fundamentally flawed for a number of reasons because there's
the lack of scientific rigor behind the score.
But like this is an example of the kind of thing
that
I think we need to understand better is what are the signals
in like github
and open
source projects and dependencies and things like that.
Like what are the signals that actually matter in that data?
And the trick too is that there are the
counter examples like youtube downloader is a perfect example,
youtube Downloader, youtube dash DL is effectively broken and dead last I checked.
Maybe they fixed it but for over a year
they haven't done a release because some release,
part of their process is broken and youtube made a change in the I DS.
And so it doesn't work anymore and there's like a,
like a couple of line fix you can do to make it work,
but somebody forked it. YT dash D LP.
And not only did they fix that, but they've been keeping it up to date.
Yeah, that's the one you want.
But, and
well,
that could have also like,
and that's kind of what these malicious people are preying on is like, oh,
we forked it and we're making it better.
We're improving it, we fix this problem, whatever,
you know.
And the thing is there's also a lot of repos that are like stale that you can fork,
like things that haven't been updated in years.
And so it's forked and like there's some new commits like, oh, well,
this looks better and more up to date,
I guess it is like you're not going to audit that.
Like, come on,
we're gonna
grab
the most recent reasonable sounding, you know,
html to mark down Python Library that we can get our grubby little hands on.
Right. But, but now I will say that
I think historically
no one would have thought twice about just
looking solely at Stars and Forks and I think
for the
future
people are still going to do that. Right.
Yeah,
I mean, I will also look for example,
at the commits because there's typically the pattern is there's
one person with like 80 or 90% of the commits
and then there's like a long tail
and then I kind of look at that person and in some cases, you know, like
-- curl, it's like, oh yeah, I know that guy who was on the show, he's trustworthy.
-- Ok.
So I've just changed my mind.
I do think you can call it a supply chain attack,
but I'm going to create two buckets for supply chain attacks.
There's the, we'll say existing supply chain attack, which this is not.
And then there is, we'll say more of a Greenfield supply chain attack.
And I think they're, they're very, they're very different
-- when you kind of think about them. Can I
-- suggest the word is
the first one is targeted and the second one is
sort of like putting out a box saying free kittens,
but it's actually full of alligators.
Like it's opportunistic. It's, you know what I mean?
-- Like it's, it's kind
-- of what it is, it kind of
is I would for now,
I would be comfortable saying targeted and opportunistic.
I mean, that's kind of all attacks work like that though.
But in supply chain,
especially like this is back to the whole like fishing email thing is like
there's fishing where it's uh what is it? Spearfishing?
Yeah, spearfishing where,
like I find out your CEO S name and his name of his dog
and then I find out your CFO and I email your CFO saying like,
hey, my dog is sick and I need you to send me like gift cards to pay the vet.
I need itunes gift cards to pay the vet.
I love
it.
And then there is
the kind where you just blast out
a
million emails and hope one person clicks and you don't really care who.
And maybe it's high value, maybe it's low value, don't know.
You know, it's kind of, it's this,
it's like those people who walk around jiggling car doors to see
if your car's locked or not and if it's not locked,
they like go into your glove box and grab your, uh, your car wash changer or whatever,
you know, you keep in your glove box
and I think that's part of it is
the industry has never been good at these opportunistic attacks at scale because
I can basically solve them sort of for myself.
But that doesn't help anybody else. Like I could have the best anti spam on the planet
and spam is still going to be a problem for everybody else.
Same thing with the same thing with everything else
that's very normal. I think in, in this context is
like I have locks on my doors it doesn't really affect
me if you put locks on your doors or not.
In fact, it might be a benefit to me if you don't have locks on your doors because now,
now you're the easy target and maybe they won't get to me.
Yeah.
And so this is like, I see people
when I see people grabbing code and using software and all that, they're just,
what choice do they have?
They don't, if they have the expertise to audit this stuff, by definition,
they wouldn't be on stack overflow asking how to do it.
I want to say something right now that you often hear people talking about, oh,
you have to verify your dependencies and you have to inspect this.
No,
the reality is almost all developers unless they have
like some heavy handed security or risk department above and
funding.
Right. Yeah.
Well, that too, you need the funding for it,
but most developers are going to just like literally take whatever source code
they find laying on the ground and they're going to use it.
If it solves the problem they have, they don't care where it came from.
Stupid question at Redhead. Did we truly validate?
Like, as far as I know,
I don't know anybody that ever read like all
the source code for something we were shipping,
we didn't read the source code. But I would say for one thing, it was a different time,
right? Where I think it was the, the projects,
they had a much higher bar of entry, I think in a lot of instances.
And additionally, the thing Redhead did that was really quite clever
is they would often hire people from these ecosystems to work on things.
So for example,
you weren't just like dumping some random person into packaging up pearl things.
You had a actual pearl developer
and they understood what was going on and,
and most of those dependencies weren't there specifically.
It was I want to package this piece of software,
but this piece of software has these dependencies.
So I also need those. And again, in that instance,
you have no choice, you have to package those.
If you want the thing, you actually want to work, right?
No, I think going back to this,
I think the problem too is that these attacks are getting much cheaper,
especially with A I being available to kind of
like like doing the scripting to and you know,
to fire up a VPN connect to github,
create an account, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
Yeah, they're totally doable.
Um Even if you have all the the the the cloud flare
verification blocks and you know, captions and like move a little like which,
which green frog is standing the right way things.
Yeah, you have a person do that takes some 10 seconds. You pay them a dollar an hour,
they grind through these.
Like that's, that's a well established market capability. For Attackers.
And so the problem becomes like,
because I remember gaming this out in my head at Red Hat and kind of bringing it up.
I was like,
how are we protecting the email address that people report stuff to at Red Hat?
Because like what happens if we get a flood of crap?
Like, what are we going to do? Because we, we got
like, we got emails that were like, very,
I don't want to say suspect.
And once in a while they turn out to be a gem of like, oh my goodness,
we need to go deal with this crisis
and a lot of them were not like, like ftp.redhead.com has source code on it and like uh
yes it does. That's the point.
But the problem
is what do you do when you get 100 emails a day?
I remember hearing one time that Microsoft security
at or whatever that, that email address was gets like literally like,
I think it was 300,000 emails a year.
That's it.
That's it
1000 a day globally.
That's a lot of email.
Also. Security at microsoft.com is their old campus security email address.
They're actually
one is I forget what it is.
1000 emails a day is an absurd amount for humans to sit through.
-- I
-- get
a
get 1000 a day. There's no
not counting that crap. I mean, like, and this is you're not sending github
spam to like your security address. Right.
Well, but what I'm saying is like,
what happens when you start getting 1000 or 10,000 or 100,000 emails?
Part of what's interesting is it breaks
discoverability because how do you actually have
determined?
Like, oh, like, remember that time those random guys in New Zealand,
the right point of sale software
found a flaw and came to us and I'm like, oh my God,
we're gonna help you and it even affected IIS and I
had to go talk to Microsoft and stuff like it was,
I I can't even remember the vulnerability now,
but they were like,
like we were point of sale software. We don't want to deal with this.
Like we want to sell point of sale systems,
but we found this nasty proxy security clothing that affects Apache, you know,
and on further testing, it affected everything,
right?
You can't discount kind of these random sounding weirdos because
no, no. And I'm not saying you should,
I'm not saying you should at all.
-- But the
-- problem is what choice do you have when
you get say 1000 of these a day from random people
that are A I generated like curl is dealing with
this where people are using A I tools air quotes,
-- right
-- to generate these like
really not great
security reports.
I mean,
there's I I think you've conflated different
problems together and you've made this confusing.
So let's ignore all of the email and reports and all that and go back to
github
and the challenge to github
now becomes we historically use things like Stars and Forks
to try to discover the signal hiding in the noise.
And
github
is probably going to work really, really hard to keep that true
because it's in their best interest to have the ability for users to know
what they're looking at is like a real thing versus a bad thing,
right?
And
I'm sure they're doing a ton of things that they aren't going to tell
us about because one of the things that happens are these sort of detections,
you can't advertise what you're doing because then Attackers work around them.
Well, that's the problem like, yeah,
with all of these security measures for anti spam basically is,
yeah, if you tell people what you're doing, then they engineer around it.
-- And they also do, you know black box testing essentially where
-- they
seo, right?
This is why no one knows what Google's algorithm actually does because if we did,
like the seo problem would be a million times worse than it is now.
And so we now as developer have this problem of ascertaining
like what is good versus what is potentially not good in,
in this whole like open source ecosystem.
And this has been a problem that's building for a long time.
And like security people have been complaining about this for forever
claiming, you know, someday you'll be sorry, which will never happen. But
I do think this is
we are coming to a point
where there is so much open source and, and
let's pretend every github repo equals open source you're talking about, you know,
like probably tens to hundreds of millions
of things.
And we now have to start unwinding all of this.
The thing that gets me is finding a
library to scratch my itch is
often
the biggest challenge I have is not finding a library. The scratches my,
just that I find 10 or 20 or 30.
And then it's like, ok, the one that had, you know,
basically my rule of thumb is anything not updated in the last two years
because it'll have a bug at some point that I need fixed. So, ok, let's ignore that.
And then, you know, like,
and I kind of winnow it out and I'll end up
with two or three and then I'll try them and like,
whatever, whichever one kind of works first.
I just sort of go with that. Like, I'm not going to spend a ton of time,
you know,
uh I,
I just, I don't have a ton of time.
Like I could spend five hours evaluating these libraries or I could spend five
minutes valuing the libraries and four hours
and 55 minutes writing the software I need
and be done with it. Right.
And
with github, I've already seen
github
search is
not useful really anymore.
To put a belly.
And I'm gonna actually generalize that
traditional algorithmic search as we think of it like.
So this is going back to the days of like Alt Vista,
which for those of you that are under the age of 35 or 40
alt Vista was, you know, a web search engine that crawled a big chunk of the web.
And then you could look for keywords using and or not. And it was amazing because
that
Netscape
directory and Netscape directory was literally
a list of links somewhat categorized and
you had to click through them and like find the page on cats.
Well, there were only 10 cat pages at that time.
It was fine,
but I think algorithmic search is dead for two big reasons. One,
there's too much stuff and teasing out the teasing out the
signal from the noise using the traditional algorithmic approaches like,
oh
like pagerank was amazing because
instead of like, oh this page has all the keywords.
It's like, oh,
this page has all the keywords and 10 different sites linked to it clearly.
That's the better one
until you know seo link blog spam stuff,
-- which
-- I guess ironically is basically the way
looking at stars and forks work on github,
right? It's that idea.
It's exactly the same thing and I'm going to pause it.
The second problem is algorithmic search is too easy to game,
right? It's just too easy to generally abuse at
scale. Though, how do you have
a
trustworthy person sort of review a library and give a consensus of it.
Because for example,
I do this all the time where I go like alternative to
X and I find some blog post where they compare several alternatives
for, you know,
downloading web pages or whatever and they're often I
know incorrect or missing stuff because I'm like,
oh,
there's also this solution that's better or
this solution that's better or whatever.
And I hate to say it, but I like, apart from a, I,
I don't see any tools that are going to allow
us to categorize and analyze this data at scale.
I'm, I'm skeptical a,
I could do it either because there's too much
crap and A I struggles to cut through crap.
I mean, that's the current it might someday.
But I think the reality is and let's focus on open
source because I'm not going to turn this into some,
like, bizarre A I discussion.
But like from the open source angle, right?
We have all these open source projects,
we need to try to figure out what's good and what's bad and like,
lots of organizations are trying to do this.
You have all these open source program offices that huge companies,
you've got all these foundations doing some of this work
and the reality is like, we don't exactly know what to do.
And for the most part it's cargo, cult security
where you've got people saying we're going to do this
and it seems to work. So we're just going to keep doing this thing and assuming it was
they have, they don't have the resources
to do A B testing.
Like you want me to do twice as much work,
right?
The other thing that I was just thinking, for example,
in theory, if we had feedback loops like, oh you know, of these two libraries,
1000 people use this library and it works without too much
trouble and 1000 people use this library and are constantly complaining about
it.
So for example, looking at github
issues might be kind of helpful. But again, there's like
people don't report issues unless it's really bad.
Right. Right. So II, I generally, I don't know what the answer to this is.
And I think honestly one of the better answers is to have
a
really good end to end testing framework so that if
you start plugging and unplugging stuff in the middle,
you'll kind of know if it breaks or not
for sure.
But again, that's like saying, you know,
have you tried being less poor to the answer of like, how do we solve world hunger?
It
is. Yes.
I mean,
I think the thing I'm coming back to right now and maybe this is a foolish connection.
But it's like when we were talking to Tama a while back and he was,
you know,
going on about how there's like all this open source that
is like critical path and functionally abandoned at this point.
And this is where some of the groups like the Sovereign Tech Fund, for example,
like that might be a good example is
the sovereign, if the Sovereign Tech Fund is, is financing a project,
that's a pretty good signal, I'd say. Right.
Well, and actually it's funny because I just,
I finished the evaluations and one of the questions
I had for several of these people is what?
Ok.
Now you have to tell people what you're doing
-- with the Sovereign Tech Fund because they don't
-- know.
Ok, so I did some base. So for the Sovereign Tech Fund, they hired a bunch of
people like myself to essentially stack rank a
couple of projects for funding to determine,
you know, which one should we fund.
-- Let's ask these experts and why and
-- the projects have to request to be funded, right?
-- This isn't like random projects. No,
-- this isn't like cash cab.
That's
not
-- really also,
-- that's, that would be, you know, hi, I'm from the Sovereign Tech Fund.
We'd like to give you money.
That's I don't think I'm gonna make it
answer
10 questions.
But anyways,
so with respect to the Sovereign Tech Fund,
one thing I'm noticing is some projects wanted
money to essentially pay people to do stuff
on sort of a like sort of very specific stuff like um there was one, it's a web
related thing and it's like we need HTTP three support. We cease to be relevant.
And I'm like, yes, that is correct.
I mean, that's fair.
Totally fair.
And, but that's interesting because that's kind of like implement HTTP three.
And then, well, it's, it's,
I don't want to say done, but it's in maintenance mode and it's, you know, it's a,
there's a heavy shift at first and then sort of a maintenance cost.
But some of them, it was like, it was a, it was a project for the base,
a single person
which is most projects
and they basically want to be paid to work on the project full time for 12 to 18 months.
Fair. But then my question is what happens next,
like when the sovereign tech funding ends, what's the plan? And, and
we don't really get to ask them these questions, but I'm kind of in my head.
I'm like, well, is this
better or worse?
I mean, that's a perpetual problem of nearly every, like
we'll say, charitable type organization.
You know, like a lot of nonprofits, they don't have a,
a expected funding source forever.
They have to live a year by year that's partially taxes and just the way it works.
But, but I'm also wondering from like the perspective of the software,
so the software kind of gets this, like,
really great boost for 12 months and then goes back to being, being ignored
overall.
Well, it was already being ignored. So I think this is better. Right.
We went from being like, our choices were be ignored and stay ignored or be ignored,
be loved for 12 months and then be ignored again.
Well,
-- we're back to being ignored so they
-- assume they
-- will be funded for multiple years.
-- I
don't know
how it works.
We,
we don't know for sure.
So, the Sovereign tech Fund is doing something so brand
new. There's no, there's no precedent to even look back at, you know,
-- but
-- going back to, well, the end state,
if the end state for both is they're both still being ignored,
but one had a bunch of improvements made.
That sounds better to me. That sounds like a net gain.
Oh, you're saying, paying for specific improvements.
What I'm
saying is we pay the person to work on it for 12 months and
they vastly improve it and then they go back to not working on it.
So the end state for both is funded or unfunded, it's still ignored,
but one has a bunch of improvements,
I guess.
Like that's a benefit, right. That
like it's not,
we're not worse off is what I'm saying.
Right.
And I, I'm wondering,
I think part of this is just
at this scale and at this,
I don't know what to call it price point at this whole,
free as in not just free as in freedom, but free as in beer.
I think this is just sort of how it works and
most people will totally get away with grabbing
random stuff because they'll probably grab stuff that's not
fine.
But
there are the really
less educated people who, you know, like that, that crypto wallet
that grabbed some locking code and it
logged
everything including the private seeds and then that bucket of data logging,
data leaked
and they all got whacked and all their crypto got stolen.
So
there isn't a nonzero chance of something truly measurably
like a whole bunch of money gets stolen,
bad happening.
But the flip side is,
well, what choice do these developers have?
Well, I mean, today we don't and I think this is one of the discussions
that we have to have moving forward and and it's not even that
we have to have answers coming out of the the podcast episode.
It's just the fact that
this is a topic that I think is coming up more and more often, right?
It was like literally
the focus of our chat with
Tama a couple of weeks ago, you're seeing
signals from various governments. The Sovereign Tech Fund exists.
I heard France is trying to do something very similar to the sovereign tech fund.
You've got the US government
had that whole like
that call, a request for comment about open source usage. So
I think
we have a number of organizations starting to kind of wake up to this. And I think as,
as individuals, while we can't necessarily impact
the like giant machine
that will call open source. What we can do is make sure that
the various organizations we have sway over, be it your government
or maybe some foundation you work with or work for whatever.
Like those are the places we need to
keep giving them little pokes constantly and saying,
what are you doing about this? How are we moving this forward?
And that is how we see progress, right?
We don't see progress by throwing our hands in
the air and saying there's nothing we can do.
Let's just give up.
Well, and I'm going to make a prediction that this is going to get much worse.
And that the barrier to entry to open source was historically, always low.
Essentially. If you could program,
let me finish. If historically, if you could program, you could participate
and now it's changed,
it's even lower in that you don't actually have to be able to program.
People are churning code out with A I
and the quality is all over the place
depending on how well you prompt them.
Like I've noticed, for example, when I prompted for Python scripts,
about 50% of the time it'll handle command line arguments
sort of gracefully and half the time it's just like equal
Sisy zero,
I'm like, sure it only takes one argument, fine, whatever.
But then I have a script that takes three arguments and I'm like, oh, come on, like,
let's use some arc parts.
And I know to ask for that.
I know that that's possible so I can modify my prompt and get that result.
But like a true person who's literally just bashing rocks against the
A I and getting code that kind of works out of it.
They're not going to know that. And
so I'm going to pause it,
but
the barrier to entry to open source is going to
continue to get even lower and lower and lower.
And thus these types of problems where
it kind of relies on the person not knowing what to look for or not knowing
what the signals are, is going to become
easier to exploit.
-- Because you've,
-- I mean, this is a problem with A I everywhere, right?
Like you have A I generating
nonsensical text, you have it generating images,
there's misinformation up the wazoo.
-- Well,
-- what? But the difference is
in the past when you had a,
when you had a programmer try to write fizz buzz and
they didn't know how they wrote something that didn't work,
but now they get something that appears to work
and that's fair. And that's the difference. Like you have to
get your columns to line up in Python.
Now you don't, the, the A I will do it for you.
And so I think what's interesting is
we need to not just think about where we are now and where the Attackers are now,
but where we're going because
if we are, if we are improving the state of things
slower than the Attackers are slower than the industry is changing, then
-- maybe we need to speed up and go a bit faster and
-- that's
easy to do.
But it's hard to do.
I mean,
and,
and you could probably make the argument and I think
that that's how we have to end this because there's just
at this point
other than awareness, I don't think there's a lot else we can do.
I think there's some organization starting to
pay attention and that's a good start.
But for the moment,
it's just knowing this is a thing is probably the best we're gonna get.
Yep.
So, yeah, that's that.
I guess
I,
I feel like we end all these shows lately. I'm like awful. Like there's nothing
I was thinking about this with like the light bulbs and stuff in my mobile app.
How do I validate that? Like, my mobile app is not gonna spy on me at some point.
-- You don't.
-- I can. It
is spying on you. I'll save you the trouble.
-- Yeah, exactly.
-- I,
I agree. Anyway. All right. Let, let's call it. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. Go to
over social security podcast.com head at the show. Not two Z Pound Os podcast.
Hashtag and Mastodon
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.