Hello and welcome to episode 27 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime.
Josh Bresser.
Hello, Kurt. How are you doing
quite well? Finally over yet another virus my kids brought home.
Yeah, I'm still not. I, I have a terrible head cold still. Like, it won't go away.
I, I don't know. Maybe this is just how I have to live from now on.
I, yeah, I worry about that.
-- Kids are filthy.
-- They
are.
But, you know,
it kind of what it reminds me of is it's like being on the modern internet,
you know,
that's
not,
I'm talking 20 years ago,
man, except like the internet will.
No,
the internet is like your kids bringing home the
plague and then everyone dies three days later.
I mean, it's not even comparable.
Well, no, I mean, you know, the internet is bad but
the internet is what would happen if none of us had immune systems.
That is what the internet is
-- or washed our hands, I guess. Yeah,
-- I, no, no, because
I suspect there are people who don't wash
their hands and they still live relatively productive.
And meaningful lives. So we'll say immune system.
Yeah.
So, speaking of immune system, uh,
looks like some NTP massive attack occurred last
month and then they sort of figured out
-- it was a bit of an
-- oopsy
attack. We'll put those in, get your air quotes back out. Kurt.
It was not an attack. It apparently was
Snapchat.
That's true. It still was an attack. It just wasn't really on purpose.
It was, it was a Snapchat
app update,
did something that started pounding on the NTP pool,
which I know we discussed a couple episodes ago,
but there's essentially a public NTP pool that
basically anyone can join and anyone can query.
And it's basically just what is it pool.ntp.org.
But they also, I, so I was doing some reading here and they ask vendors not to do this
where they want a vendor to basically get their
own little kind of sub domain of ntp.org.
So you have like one dot vendor dot NTP
pool.org, I think it is and then two dot And three dot And, and, and so on and so on.
And obviously the advantage of that is if,
if you have an app that starts misbehaving,
you can just kind of black hole those domains while the app manufacturer,
the vendor, I guess in this case sorts out the details.
Yeah, I mean, and, and that's one thing I find interesting is, you know, I don't,
at this point, I don't really care anymore,
whether or not it is an intentional attack.
The reality is the end result is that, you know,
a
good portion of the internet was affected slightly.
Well, I think a lot of this too is we are approaching
just kind of the law of huge numbers
where it basically says when you have enough of something in this case,
it's crap on the internet, just like everything you can imagine
happens all the time.
And in this case, obviously with all the apps and all the people,
with all the devices and the just constant connectivity,
you're probably D OS someone all the time, right?
To some degree, I mean, you know, what gets me with these apps is,
you know, being able to like Pokemon uh that went from like,
basically what zero to like tens of millions of
users in the span of something like days,
you know, and that's what gets me um
is not just the scale of these apps, right?
Like we're talking millions or tens of millions of users of these apps, you know,
basically, and these apps are running on, we call them phones, but really,
-- you know, they're in some cases, quad core machines with like what
-- eight
-- gigs of
-- ra m
what kind of crap phone do you have an
iphone?
But uh I think it's only dual core on the iphone
at
this
point. I don't
care.
It,
it'll run Nintendo, run, it'll run my
web browser.
So actually, we talked about Mario run, not Nintendo run.
Uh So we talked about Mario run, what, a couple, couple episodes ago and about the,
we'll say uh scammers that were filling the gap
in the Android ecosystem because it's not released yet and
they put out, it's not an app, but it has like a button to say, register my interest.
And so now when Mario run comes out on Android,
it's going to, I, I don't know if it'll magically install it for me,
but it should at least tell me
and
well, it, it, it, it pains me to look at this and because why can't I have my,
my Mario game.
But more importantly is the fact that now when a normal
person searches for Mario run in the Android app store,
they at least get something right.
This is kind of like
I always come back to when I, when I deal with, you know, various people is,
there's really three answers to every question.
There's yes, no and no answer and no answer. It's the worst answer. Right?
Even if you don't like getting a no, it's better than no answer.
And that's kind of what I see here with this app.
True.
Yeah. It's funny.
I was like looking for, um, uh,
I wanted to play Hearts of Iron Four on my machine and I was
looking at the specs for Hearts of Iron Four and looking at my machine
and this one site very helpfully said, download uh this dot exe and run it and we'll,
like, scan your hardware and
it runs or not. I was like,
no
delete that tab or close that tab out.
But, um, you know, most people, yeah, they just, they want to play their Mario game.
I mean, I know my six year old certainly does love that game.
Like, between that and Mario World creator. He is a happy, happy guy,
which, which I must say uh Mario maker is like the greatest game ever. Yeah,
but going back to the NTP abuse, I mean,
this is a significant problem because uh the, I mean,
the funny thing is the reality is for the
majority of these sort of iot and home devices,
realistically speaking, if their clocks go out,
it's not really going to matter all that much
because, you know,
uh industrial control systems running a power plant.
Yeah, that, that it will matter there.
-- But you know, they should be running their own NT
-- P time.
Question is why is the Snapchat app talking to an NTP server?
Shouldn't it be getting the time off of the device?
Yes and no, because
can you trust the device time?
-- Can
-- you trust the NDP server time?
Probably more than the device?
Probably,
you
know, that
um the other thing is uh I'm assuming Snapchat is doing maybe some cryptography,
which means, you know,
the times need to line up within a few seconds or tens of seconds
maybe. You know,
because like I, I actually run into uh webex,
uh at least the Mao
uh
webex client
uh wants to go talk to Google's DNS server 8.8 0.8 0.8.
I've heard of this before, which I think is totally the right thing to do
except I block all outgoing,
uh DNS and I filter it through my server which logs everything
because I want to log all my outgoing queries.
So that, you know, it's one nice thing is it makes it easy to block a domains.
And also I have like a traffic log. So,
you know, later on, if somebody says, oh, you know,
if you were talking to this DNS site that's command and control server for a Botnet,
uh I would be able to have that forensic log to check, you know.
Um And just, it's also curious, right?
Like, because there's,
there's some web pages where you hit them and it generates 2 to 300 dns pages,
you know, it's, which is pretty kind of shocking.
Um
So, you know, on the one hand, I mean, what,
what frustrates me is I would say for the general case,
having your app do its own time and its own DNS.
I mean, that's gonna cut your support costs.
It's gonna cut your hassles where people are like calling you and saying,
why doesn't the app?
You know,
it can't locate the server?
Why is that and it's like, well, because you have a broken network, I'm sorry.
But on the flip side, for the few people that do care, we,
we end up with these apps that do
you know, bad things, right?
That, you know, we have to poke holes in our firewall or our, you know,
security posture so that these,
you know, these apps work.
Now, I think that's a bit less of a problem with mobile apps because quite frankly,
you know, mobile apps,
the expectation is they run on a device
that is constantly moving around different networks,
wi fi cell networks, you know, whatever, right?
So for mobile endpoints might, you know,
uh this actually goes back to a Twitter thing where,
you know, these people were talking about um traffic inspection.
And quite frankly,
if your security posture relies on behaving like a state level attacker that is,
you know, decrypting tlsns cell and inspecting the content.
Um You're kind of doing it wrong because that
capability is rapidly going away, you know,
with everybody deploying perfect forward secrecy
and then deploying things like certificate pinning within apps, right?
Like Google Chrome does this where it'll still
more trust uh an a uh certificate you import
than, you know, the regular root store.
But you know, as a user, I, I
don't want some company, even a company I work for installing, you know,
certificates on my device.
Would they allow them to inspect all my traffic, like,
unless it's a really high paying job in which case, then I would consider,
you know, what's funny is, it's actually gonna be the opposite of that is
I think any reasonably senior individual is not going to
want to let the company kind of control their devices.
Whereas very entry level doesn't have a choice
because let's face it.
If you're senior, you can be like, heck, no, you're not touching my computer.
-- But if you're the entry level guy, like they're just gonna fire
-- you senior
level people that need it the most because like, you know,
as the John put us to email that
shows like we.
So you know, here we, I think,
I don't know if we talked about this on the podcast
but remember I am now going to be moving to UTF
uh
authentication,
U two F, sorry, U two F authentication.
You know, my token should be arriving tomorrow
and I'm going to be deploying that because
here's the reality I have, you know,
accounts with administrative privileges for some uh organizations
and one day I will be tired and stupid and I will click on the wrong link in an email.
Absolutely.
You even,
even experts are going to fall for this and actually U two F is better than just the,
the number you type in
because
if I if I'm a bad guy,
right?
I can man in the middle, the token code,
but I can't man in the middle U two F because it's got some magic built into it that
basically it actually
does crypto on the device, right?
It does crypto on the device and it basically the browser uses the
host name as part of the the I guess challenge response that happens.
So if a bad guy has you going to, you know, like not google.com, then
your U two F token just isn't going to work, right?
Which is awesome.
Yeah. And that's combined with uh I'm using uh what is it last pass or whatever?
And it has a browser plug in that
stores, passwords and remembers for them for me, but also ties them to the URL,
the domain name, right? So that I can't accidentally, you know,
uh enter my Google password into. Yeah, totally legit google.com.
And I think
that's the reality, right? Like
authentication credentials
have to be tied to the site that they are
dealing with.
And I, I think that's a reasonable requirement because the reality is right?
People don't change their domain names very much because for one simple reason
-- you take a huge hit on your search engine
-- optimization.
People just don't, I mean, they don't change their passwords.
I mean, let's face it.
Right.
So, yeah, and I'm actually going to also be pushing for other
uh people within one of the organizations I deal with
to use UTF if they're like a senior person because,
you know, just the, the stuff they have access to, you,
get access to their account and
see, here's what really,
I,
I realize what really worries me about a password sniffing attack for my
email and somebody getting into my password or into my email is that
they can now start going, uh,
and resetting passwords across all these other sites I use.
Yeah.
I mean, that's definitely the risk in that and,
and they'll steal the recipes my aunt has sent me.
Well, it's just the problem being right,
is most of these sites for their account recovery, like,
they don't have strong account recovery procedures and, and the majority of them
seem to boil down to type in your email address. Hit lost password.
We'll email you a magic link, click the magic link, reset your password. That's it.
You don't need to know anything other than the person's
email address and obviously have access to their email.
I wonder,
I, I've,
I've never tested this but I wonder if
you change your password or not change your password
but lose your password on one of these U two F enabled sites if it demands the token
before it lets you change something
that I would not know
because the other reality is like, for example,
Google lets you print out account recovery codes,
right. Which I'm sure like a half of 1/10 of a millionth of a percent do.
Yeah, probably like, really? I mean, I know, I know, I know.
-- So,
-- yeah.
No, I'm, I'm, I'm basically, in the last week,
I've realized I need to now adopt a security posture that is
resilient enough to deal with me at three in the morning.
Right.
II, I can totally
remember.
It's,
you know, that's that because that's going to happen someday. You know, like,
um,
in
this, you sent me
a,
a little snippet
when we were chatting earlier today,
was that the RS A talking about comprehensive training programs?
And it comes back to that.
I mean, we just talked about this a couple of episodes ago,
like you cannot patch people.
Even if you train them to death,
-- they're gonna screw it up.
-- Even, you know, even myself, I have received
-- legitimate emails that I've misidentified as phishing emails like
-- from Google,
-- well, from Google, from my bank from
-- Amazon.
So
actually, you know what's really cool is my bank
does not send me email.
They,
they, they have a,
they call it the secure messaging center when I log in to the website.
And
that's it. Like if there's a message that's where it is.
And occasionally I will get a mail from them that just
says we have a message for you in the secure message center
and they don't even have a link to log in. They just say they have the message.
So obviously I type everything in and I don't
have to worry about fishing and it's very,
-- that's
-- a perfect example.
Of one of the few things you can train
people to do that will actually make a difference,
which is the call back.
Hey, this is Bob from your bank. I'm calling you blah, blah, blah.
Give us a call back. Click and then I call the number printed on the back of my card
or, or even better is I just go to the bank. I, I never call the bank. I don't trust it.
So I go talk to a human being there and,
and I think one of the,
the, I forget the guy's name. Uh He, I think he thinks I'm crazy
because I'm always in there asking him silly questions
and he's like, you know, you can just call us. I'm like, no, I won't call you.
I don't trust it.
And then he looks at me funny and I'm like, just,
just go along with it like I'm crazy and I know it and everything's fine.
Well, you know, uh yeah, let's,
we'll save SS signal uh signaling protocol seven for a different episode or
sorry, signal protocols nine. Now, I think anyway,
it's the phone signaling system and we'll talk about some other podcasts.
But coming back to this. So,
yeah, with this, with this whole training people thing, I mean, the reality is,
I think the Callback is one of the few things
that's effective.
But the problem is you, you have to do it consistently and then, and you know,
the remote end has to be available, right?
You never, no, it's never gonna work.
You can't even say that because let's face it, man. If I called
a grandmother today
and said I'm the bank,
do you think
they're not going to talk to you? They're lonely, right?
They want to talk to someone. I'm gonna talk to them.
That's why the Callback has to be trained because, you know,
the reality is like someday they're gonna get you.
Here's the deal. It can't be trained.
I'm I'm saying this,
-- it cannot be trained
-- because how do we deal
with people and phishing phone calls or phishing emails,
make sure that there is no way
using things like U two F tokens,
you make sure there is no way
that they can do what is being asked of them.
Technically speaking.
Now,
-- granted that is
-- not possible because there was a case
I was reading about and it's really kind of heartbreaking.
Um
So these guys basically get lists of immigrants in the
US for people who moved to the USA long time ago
and are like legal.
And so part of it is targeting the immigrant population because they're, you know,
they're immigrants or maybe their English isn't as good.
They're a bit more fearful of authority and you know, being deported and whatnot.
And this one lady got this call and, you know, they basically said you're gonna be
like your husband died, the paperwork got messed up. You need to send us like $2000 in
itunes gift cards
and the way they do it is you have to go,
um you have to like,
you know, you basically go and buy itunes gift cards,
scratch them off and read the numbers back over the phone.
And so she actually went to her bank to get money and told them what was going on.
And like the bank teller is pleading with her to not do this.
Like she's like, please don't do this.
Like, for the love of God, you know, this is, this cannot be,
you know, the IRS in the US and the uh what is it? The, um,
the depart, what's the Department of Immigration?
Is that under Department of Homeland Security or is it I,
I ce
immigration control whatever anyways,
the reality is they don't take payment and itunes gift cards,
right. I'm pretty sure it's like
-- cash or check or maybe
-- wire
transfer. The IRS doesn't email people either.
Yeah.
And that's one thing and, you know, as annoying as it is, I,
I actually agree with that.
I think a lot of government, like,
especially every tax department on the planet
should probably just never email people.
Oh, totally. I agree completely. I think email is too insecure and crappy.
Well, it just, and it trains people to, you know, reply to these emails. But um,
yeah,
but so the problem is you have this human behavior
where you have like a person going into a bank
telling the bank what's going on the bank is clearly like, yeah, that's a scam,
don't, you know, don't.
And, but what, what are they going to do?
Like refuse service or like, you know, she'll go to a different branch and do this.
So if the scammer can get somebody that worked up in that, you know,
into that mindset,
you know, there's literally no technological measure that
will fix that.
-- But
-- OK, so here's the deal though is there's a difference between
willful ignorance
which
people get tricked and it's just an unfortunate reality and
that's been going on through all of human history.
I mean, that's what
right, seriously,
but there's also what I would call failures in our technology.
And this is where like I can click a link
and it hacks my email or I click a link and it sends me
to a fake login page and I didn't type in my gmail credentials like
that is a solvable problem with technology like U two F OK?
Or, or just honestly,
we need to fix the freaking browsers in a lot of instances I think.
But that's another story.
Well, more to the point, shouldn't I be, you know, I have this piece of software.
Well, two email client and a web browser. Um but claim
they can accept remote data and open it and display it to me safely.
Well, clearly they cannot, right.
And,
you know, we know that to be true now.
So,
I mean, this is why I don't use an email client anymore.
I use a web based, you know, email
because it's one less big piece of software to go horribly wrong.
I agree with that. And I'm in the same boat.
Yeah.
-- And
-- so I, I only use Thunderbird with the GP G plug in so I can, you know,
do my encrypted email.
Did you know, I don't think I've ever used a fat email client in my life.
I think I jumped from terrible text based things into gmail.
And I don't, there was really never anything in between.
I just, I never could deal with the fat clients. They were just too crappy for me.
I, well, so I came from,
I started out honestly doing email with something called Elm,
which is about as old as it gets and then ironically,
oh, it gets better. And then I moved to N MH, which I became an upstream developer for.
Right. Which actually predates Elm, I believe as a male client.
-- But
-- it's
not like
it's no, it's not even painful. It's, it's like
you bought a pile of parts and you have to assemble them into something
and in this case, it's an email client.
It was. But the thing is after your like two years of getting it set up, it was awesome.
Right.
And, and in fact, I even, I,
I added unicode support because it didn't have it at one point.
And I'm like, I can't read this like, you know, spam from China and,
and so that was my solution.
But anyway,
that's fine when you're running your own, like pop, pop and IMAP server.
But then when I eventually moved all my services to gmail, it was just,
it sucked way too hard to use.
N mh with it and I'm like, screw it. I'm, I'm doing Gmail, you know, I'm all in now
and
I mean, there's days I miss it, but for the most part like it's ok.
I can deal with it.
Yeah.
So, and,
but going back, so back, way back to the whole NTP conversation.
Part of the challenge is now is, you know, we have what we think of as phones,
but they're actually full computers and they have a lot of bandwidth.
Like even though at my parents' cabin in the literally kind of the middle of nowhere,
it's a, you know, 57 cabin subdivision
and then the nearest town is like
25 30 minute drive away.
There's a cell phone tower across the lake and I can reliably
get 30 megabits down and about 2 to 2.5 megabits up,
you know, and in the city it's funny because in the city,
I typically get slower speeds
um because there's more people in
here. Right?
But the reality is, you know, my, my dirty little cell phone has, you know,
typically at a minimum one or two megabits of upload capability, which
you get a million cell phones doing that. And all of a sudden we're talking about,
you know, that's a terabyte per second.
Like that's a real, that's a big problem, you know.
And
one thing, uh, so a few weeks ago,
uh, cloud flare, uh, who's a big, uh,
they're basically a big content delivery network provider.
Um,
they started seeing these weird attacks that they called porcupine
attacks because essentially you have like your typical sort of cycle
cycle of traffic. You know, it ramps up during the day and drops during the night,
but they're getting these weird spikes of traffic. Um, of what is it? Here we go.
500,000 to 1 million http requests per second
every 80 minutes.
And they've, they've written this huge long blog post,
uh analyzing the payload and, you know, somebody wrote to them and actually said,
hey, I recognize the function that creates that payload.
It's this really little simple function,
but
they don't know what this is
like. They don't know. Is it like a misbehaving piece of software?
Is it somebody probing them, you know, attacking them to see what happens?
Is it like, who knows what it is? Right.
And that's, that's kind of what really worries me is that,
you know, if it's just a flat out simple D
OS attack against, say a gambling site, it's,
it's really clear what's going on there, right.
They want money otherwise, you know,
you can't take bets for Super Bowl Sunday or whatever.
But, you know, now we're seeing these massive attacks like the one that took down,
uh D DNS.
Do we know why?
You know, is it a simple proof of concept and,
or testing of the bonnet or was it maybe testing DN
DNS to see what it takes to knock them offline?
What's interesting to me?
So the way cloud flare deals with these attacks is they just scale massively, right?
They use what's called any cast. And so
the idea behind the internet is, is you have an IP address for your computer
and that IP address is, you know, basically broadcast by your ISP to other ISP.
So people know how to get to you.
And traditionally IP S had an IP address was attached to like one machine.
It was lived in one location.
Now with any cast, what you can do is you can have a single IP address.
A great example being 8.8 0.8 0.8 you know, Google's DNS server and you can have it,
you can have multiple servers in multiple locations
broadcasting that I am 8.8 0.8 0.8.
Now the advantage of this is, for example,
you have servers in North America and servers in Europe.
The people in Europe, go to the servers in Europe, the people in North America,
go to the servers in North America.
If the servers in North America tip over and die, then, well,
everybody goes to Europe.
Um
And if you create enough of these, like in cloud flare's case,
it's more than 100 sites now with their servers,
you know,
when, if you have say a
bunch of machines in say for the sake of argument, China
attacking cloud flare, you know, attacking their IP addresses,
they get routed to the Chinese service.
So they can only really impact the cloud flare.
You know, China Asia servers and the ones in North America are just like whatever.
We don't see any of the traffic. We don't care
the problem with that, of course, is not everybody can afford to deploy
servers in 100 different data centers
with any cast, right?
So what worries me is not only do you get this like law of large numbers
where like let's face it if somebody attacks me with more than a gigabit of traffic,
I I'm done unless I hide behind somebody bigger
like Amazon web services shield or cloud flare.
And what really worries me is we're now,
you know,
centralizing the internet quite a lot.
Cloud flare has something like 30% of the
world's internet traffic going through it now,
-- you know, between them and Amazon web services,
-- I guess,
-- I believe that it's
-- free and it protects you from the tax.
Well, it's,
I'm sure anyone running a reasonable size business
or website is not using the free stuff.
Uh, no, the, the pay stuff starts at like, 20 bucks a month. It's, which is
what you get is super awesome.
Yeah, for 200 bucks a month you get some really cool technology.
So it's totally affordable and like,
Amazon now is just rolling it into their default stuff.
Like,
if you use Amazon Cloud front and Amazon
wrote 53 you're automatically protected by their,
I think they call it shield,
you know, their D
OS protection stuff,
you know, same thing with Google, right. They have Google has their,
you know, behind Google compute engine.
You know, they were talking about this and they, they just released a paper.
The uh what is it Google Infrastructure security design overview
and the long and the short of it is,
is the way Google compute engine and all that stuff works for a tax.
Uh you know, denial of service tax is
they just have crazy, crazy, crazy large amounts of bandwidth and servers,
you know, so they can soak up a terabyte per second
because the reality is you can't deal with a
terabyte per second attack in any other way.
Right. There's nothing clever you can do to like,
-- block it unless it's coming from a single source, you know, which it's not going
-- to,
it never does anymore.
Yeah,
like I said, as a, you know,
as a normal individual or even as a large organization you,
you have to go hide behind an even bigger organization like Cloud
flare or Amazon web services or Google or Microsoft or whatever.
Right.
Which is
totally reasonable today.
I mean, you kind of think that, do you remember the, the slash dot effect?
Yeah. Yeah.
I mean, we, well, we intentionally built our service to withstand it so we
traffic.
But I mean, you think about that is that wasn't that long ago, maybe, what,
1015 years ago, if you had a popular website linked to you,
it took you down
and these days I,
it is rare to find a site that is down when
they get linked to obviously because of all this stuff,
which is, which is super cool.
Yeah, I guess this conversation could go one of two ways.
Do we want to talk about security claims or do we
want to talk about maybe blocking all these IOT devices and
-- how they get the IOT
-- we talk about iot too much.
Yeah.
Well, I think the problem is the IOT is just, I,
I think what I realize now is what I don't like
about the IOT is it's not the internet of things.
It's just
-- more stuff on the internet. It's the
-- internet. I know. I know exactly what you mean.
It, it, it's the way it is and
it's not even coming like it's here. This is the way things work now.
Welcome to the future, everybody.
Yeah. So,
but Yeah.
So what's, what's really also interesting to me is that first cloud flare didn't
detect this attack because
the requests were essentially malformed a bit
enough so that they didn't get through
and hit their, like, D
dos protection system, they essentially were being, like, dropped as, like,
just mangled traffic.
Um,
and so it wasn't until they started looking
into some other things that they detected this
and,
you know, that's what part of what gets me is. I remember when, um,
oh, what was the guy that was head of Yahoo security and left about a year ago, a
year ago.
Yeah, the guy that was in charge for about 23 years and then left because Yahoo was,
-- like, spying on everybody's email and they didn't tell him
-- no, that was stamos.
He was there for like, two
months.
I don't think
he wasn't there for years. He showed up.
Maybe it was the guy before anyways or
I,
I just remember a quote from some Yahoo high level
security person basically saying when they went to Yahoo,
like,
what they were typically thought of as bad attacks and
everything was just like every other normal day at Yahoo.
Yeah. Right.
Well,
this is true of any of these large organizations and
I think people don't realize that all the time is
when you're the size of Amazon or Google or Yahoo or even cloud flare, no doubt,
sees this to a degree
is
you're getting attacked by every person in every country, every which way.
It, it's completely insane. The scale they have to operate at. I,
I was listening to an interview with a guy from Microsoft one time
and he said,
you know, you're in a real data center
when you have to worry about physics being what's limiting you,
right?
You think about that just because you have such a huge amount of data and like,
actually moving the electricity across the data center is a huge problem.
I mean, that's crazy.
Yeah, I know.
And it's, I mean, on the one hand, it's lovely because for example,
you can build a website now that scales with use, you know, you pay by use and it can
be one hit or a billion hits,
you know,
and you can do this starting for like,
-- tens of dollars a month.
-- Yeah. Well, it's super cheap. Although, although
you do need to be careful because if
your website suddenly becomes denial of service,
your bill could get very high, very quickly.
Well, I mean, most of these providers have ways to prevent that.
Like, they can have alerts or they can just cut it off. You can set a limit. Like,
I only
-- spend this much
-- assuming
you set that up.
Right.
Yeah.
Well, and it's happened in the past and most of them seem to be willing to, you know,
cut some slack to these poor people because, you know,
it's kind of bad press when you
bankrupt somebody because their website got attacked,
you know,
or like that guy whose kid bought like a billion in game
items and ran up like a tens of thousands of dollars bill.
Right. Right.
Which is always the best. That's why
some of my kids don't have a tablet account with a credit card.
Yeah. So,
but no, it's getting back to this. So,
the other problem too is,
is that this sort of large scale attack is is actually relatively
easy to pull off now because when you think about it,
right, like a popular, a
popular website or a popular app can tell a web browser, you know, go here,
get this thing,
right? Um
And so let's say for the sake of argument,
you run a really popular website with say
tens of thousands of people accessing it daily.
You know, if you include uh like, let's say, for the sake of simplicity,
you'll link to an image on somebody else's website
and tell it to display as like a one by one, you know, image. So nobody will notice it.
You now have tens of thousands of people
requesting this image from this other website,
you know, constantly.
I believe that's actually the case with our podcast.
Oh, there there is,
there is somebody who grabs episode three of
our podcast every 15 minutes it is downloaded
and I assume it's just something is broken and it keeps pulling it in And so
it, it is comical when, when I look at these graphs and whatnot of, of data.
But I'm also pleased that I don't have
to pay for every single individual download either,
which would be unfortunate in
this instance.
But yeah,
so episode three is the most downloaded episode of our podcast by a wide margin.
Well, and here's a really good question.
Is there anything we could possibly do to deal with that?
There's
something
if I really cared, I'm sure I could work with because Soundcloud hosts the data
and
they don't seem to care. I, I don't really care either
and whatever, you know, if, if, if I'd control over the server hosting the data,
I could obviously find out right away and block them in some meaningful fashion.
But, I mean, as such, I can't
and whatever, it's, if they don't care, I don't care. It's kind of the way I look at
it
and this kind of
comes back to something I've been thinking for a long time is
I think a lot of these sort of security issues and problems,
especially around
service attacks,
we should just engineer around them and ignore them
because quite frankly actually spending the time and money to chase them down
is going to cost a horrendous. It's like spam, right.
It's just cheaper to block it than it is to
find these people and prosecute them by and large,
which sucks. And I hate to say that. But that's just, it's, that's the reality of it.
Yeah, it's totally the way it, it just, it is what it is. Right.
I mean,
it is the modern internet. This is how things work now and
I, I don't do other industries have this problem. I'm trying to think if there's,
yeah, I guess pollution.
Yeah.
Well, or a great example being, you know, the whole fossil fuel industry in cycle.
Right.
So, like,
almost everybody is guilty to some degree of either
directly burning fossil fuels because they drive a car,
they heat their house with gas
or indirectly, right?
Because you consume plastic, you consume devices that were delivered to you.
Right?
So the reality is everybody is making lifestyle choices that involve at some point,
almost certainly, you know, fossil fuels being burned.
You know, unless you, like go out and literally live naked in the middle of the woods
even then
you're probably going to have to start a fire someday.
I
mean, this is true.
That's carbon
dioxide.
You could argue you're carbon neutral if you're burning trees,
-- but
-- you have to plant a lot of trees.
Well, and I guess this is not,
your analogy might be apt because you also think about if you are in industry
and you, like,
like this happens all the time where a factory will
accidentally dump a bunch of something into the river,
we just pay a fine.
Yeah. No, it's, um, I think that's you know, part of the challenge is
there's so much of this going on accidentally or otherwise intentionally that,
you know, actually tracking all of it down and, you know,
prosecuting everybody or getting everybody to stop doing it would be,
it's just invisible.
Right. Exactly.
You know, it's, it's like law enforcement if, you know,
I mean, I, I,
the thought of a society where every single law is actually enforced 100%.
that's
just it.
You know what? That's a really interesting thing to say because
you can't enforce all the laws 100% because, like,
80% of the laws in the books are crazy nonsense.
Things. Like, you know, you can't carry an ice cream cone in your pocket or, or
-- in the
-- US.
Um, due to the, the way some of the federal Wildlife Protection laws are set up,
something can be legal in your state, but it's still illegal federally.
Well, that's, uh, the,
the whole marijuana legalization in these handful of states that have it.
It is technically a federal crime but
the states say it's legal,
which really just means the state law enforcement has
said we're not going to help the federal government
enforce this and the federal government doesn't really have
the resources to do a whole lot about it.
And so,
in fact, it's created a bit of a mess for these companies selling this stuff because
their funds can be commandeered by the, the federal government
and so basically they're afraid to put money in the bank because the, the DEA can,
like, show up and take their money away.
And so what do you do? Right.
You keep it in a billow case.
Like,
I mean, that, that's actually what they're doing. I mean, it's crazy.
Well, maybe Bitcoin will save us all,
-- or at least the marijuana industry.
-- Right. Bitcoin. Bitcoin will save us all.
Yeah.
All right. What else we got here? I got, uh, did you hear a drone
collided with an airplane?
I'm surprised that hasn't happened sooner because, uh, one thing, you know, it,
it's one of these simple facts that
I never really thought of, but apparently a, a jet engine,
you know, they suck in
a huge amount of air, like, not just the little 3 ft cross section of the engine,
but they're, they're like, literally, it's a jet turbine.
So it's, you know, it sucks air in burns, fuel, spins the thing.
So it spins the front even faster to suck air in.
And so these things suck in.
Like I was reading somewhere like the, the, you know, the modern turbo bypass fans.
Like, anyways, the point is like, if you get within 100 ft of one of those things,
like you're gonna have a bad day,
you know.
And so, because I was always kind of thinking, you know, it's,
it's a good thing like planes are, you know, for their size,
they're relatively small
and same with drones. Right.
And so, you know,
the chances of a mid air collision or even if you're trying are probably not,
you know, it's not as easy as it looks.
Right.
Um, but when you have a jet engine sucking in that much air and, you know,
like potential debris and stuff like a drone,
yeah, all of a sudden it become.
So, here's the thing though, this drone,
it wasn't sucked into the,
the plane,
the engine, it, it hit and if you look at the, the show notes will have a link to this.
There's a picture of the nose of the plane, like,
basically,
but at the same time this plane was on approach to land
in Mozambique.
And
I would bet you anything that when an airplane is landing
it has the engine significantly throttled down as opposed to when they're actually
-- flying or even taking off
-- as I've learned from my airline disaster binge
watch last month.
Yeah, that's, that's why,
that's why accidents on landing are so dangerous because you just,
you don't have the power to recover.
I've heard that, you know,
and it takes a jet engine several seconds or tens of seconds to spool up and get power.
I believe that.
So, if things go wrong and you're pointed at the ground.
Right. Right. Yeah, you've got problems. Definitely.
Yeah, I mean, the good news is, planes are like,
if you've ever watched some of those structural failure tests.
Boeing Posts, a few of these. It's
amazing.
Oh, they're like, they, they basically bend the wings and they're like,
here's where the wing is supposed to go, like the maximum amount
and we're just going to keep bending.
Right. Well, you, you have to test it that way though. Or I've even seen
footage of airplanes where there have been like,
explosive decompression for some reason or another
and like half the plane is missing and the things
I think it was
five, somewhere between like five and 10 rows of,
of like the length of the fuselage of the plane.
And it
was
crazy. I mean, but this is also why, like, keep your seatbelt on everybody because
you never know when you're gonna get sucked out of the airplane.
But it's, yeah, it's crazy stuff.
I mean, they, they're built to such an amazing specification.
Well, they're big and expensive.
That's true.
-- They cost like, what, 30 40 million bucks for a cheap one,
-- a lot more than that.
Really? Like,
oh,
like, uh, try 1 to 200 million for like a modern 787,
787 is special though, right. That's, that's a big,
-- or a 747 or an Airbus, a 380.
-- Those are the huge planes though.
I mean, well,
I shouldn't say those aren't the kind of
planes I find myself in generally because I'm,
I'm often not flying across the ocean or
I wonder what I'll take when I go to Rs A.
Well, I should look at that and see what kind of,
-- uh, here
-- we go.
The company lists the price of a 737 is between 51.5 million and 87 million.
That's like a deal, man. Right.
That's, and that's a 737 which is basically like the, the school bus.
Yeah, that's what I'm in most of the time.
In fact that's what was in this, this collision here
in Mozambique was a 737.
I spend a lot of time in 737. Yeah,
they, I mean, they are nice plane. I, I do, I, I wanna go somewhere in a 787 though.
I've heard they're amazing airplanes and I've never had the joy of being in one.
However I was at, it was it, I was in Chicago. I think it was.
I, I forget what airport it was now.
And I had my family with me actually because we're going on a trip
and
here comes the
Airbus a 380 which is like their Gigantor monolith. Right?
-- And
-- then
-- the double
decker one,
it's enormous.
And then behind it is a 787 like one after the other.
I'm like,
look at that kids like those are the two biggest airplanes in the whole
world and they're like playing their games on their phone and they don't care.
But I was very impressed.
Yeah, I actually remember flying on 740 sevens as a kid to Europe and it was just,
it was magic.
They're crazy man.
Well,
especially back in the day when they actually had some leg room and stuff and as a kid,
of course, everything was bigger.
-- You know
-- what's really funny too? II I didn't know this but
so the 747
the,
the front of the airplane can open up like kind
of a hatch where it opens to the other side.
And they did that because Boeing assumed that the Concorde was
going to be the dominant carrier of people across the ocean.
And the 747
wasn't going to be a practical airplane for moving humans for very long.
So they made it
so it had a dual purpose of cargo or people
and obviously like the jokes on them people.
It's, it's interesting because I mean,
that's a classic example of we went from like literally
one or two miles an hour with the Wright Brothers.
Well, not one or two miles an hour but like, you know, below 20 miles an hour
to
supersonic speeds, you know, the, the bell X whatever
-- in the span of like, what was it like 50 years? Less than
-- 50
years.
It was really,
it was just shortly after world war two.
And, but the problem is the economics,
right?
When you start pushing something at the speed of sound, you eat fuel like crazy.
-- And also Sonic booms really
-- annoying
to
people. No one cares about because you're flying over the ice.
I
mean,
they
-- do when you live near the airport or you forget how densely populated Britain
-- is
over the ocean,
Britain,
whatever nobody cares about Britain.
But um
yeah, so I mean, the, the reality is the economics of airplanes.
I mean, people have tried supersonic flight commercially
and it's just always been a failure and
now you're seeing more fuel efficient designs and things
that are like just at the speed of sound,
you know, so there's no sonic booms or different shapes.
-- But yeah, it's just economically it's like,
-- and, and let's face it also,
how many people going to Europe?
Is there a difference between three hours or seven hours?
Well, it's worse than that when you consider security and stuff now, right. Show up
at the
airport
and then on the back end you're like, at least, you know,
especially with immigration,
especially if immigration's computers are down as we found out a week or two ago,
like holy jeez.
I did you see that one video? Like people were posting?
So for those of you that don't know, don't know,
apparently like us immigrations like their whole computer system just died,
right?
And I haven't seen any details as to why or how,
but the whole thing just stopped working
and yeah, so regardless, you know, the the lines were
essentially the full airports full of people
and you know,
people are posting videos of fist fights and stuff because it just got so insane.
Well, I, I
don't, can they even process people without, they
-- said
-- they
-- were
-- manually processing people
so they can manually do it
well, but
they definitely can't look up your records without the computer.
Uh,
yeah,
I wonder
what
the reality is with a lot of this stuff. Right.
You, you know, you, you start talking to people like this is one thing I,
I binge watched last year was, um, a combination of Australian border services,
UK Border services, Canada Border Services
and the US border services and, like,
the, well, obviously the stuff they're posting on these TV shows, you know,
you kind of have that Survivor bias if they only post the good stuff.
But, like, some of these people were, like, clearly up to no good. Right.
They're like, dancing around and sweating
and it's like, yeah, we're a little suspicious because he, like,
you know, he's dancing and sweating or, you know,
the guy's talking a million miles an hour or
the guy is like, so obviously on drugs'.
My favorite is when they admit to carrying drugs.
But they're like, no, no, no,
it's ok because I'm on an international flight and I'm just transferring through
and the Canada
border services guy are like, no, that's illegal here.
And she, and, you know, this, this guy was like,
but it's not illegal where I'm going and they're like, yeah, that,
that is technically true.
But you're in Canada right now?
Oh, great.
There is actually, there was, there was an article
I, I'll have to look for this but it was talking to a,
one of the heads of security for one
of the Israeli airports and they were talking about
because let's face it in Israel, they have like,
real security concerns about their airports.
It's not just a bunch of theater like this is the real deal
and
the things they do are fascinating and, you know,
you mentioned a guy like dancing around and sweating and
what they're doing,
like real security is very much so watching people
more so than anything else because I mean,
there have been tests done like the TS A in the United States and
they miss like 80% of the weapons that go through the X ray machine.
I mean, just
what you might as well not have.
And it's a lot of it is, you know, you need to train people.
It's part of the problem is this requires real training of people.
This is not like an afternoon course, this is weeks or months of training
because a lot of it is
like small factual details.
Like, uh I remember reading one where they were talking about, you know,
if you see winter coats in summer suicide bomber, right?
Big bulky coats, bad thing to have in, you know, Israel.
Uh and a lot of it too, was very sophisticated, you know,
putting the pieces together.
Right.
Because you might notice three or four things but you have to put them together.
Exactly.
And, and again, this is,
so, I guess this is funny, this,
this comes back to the beginning of our conversation of, we were talking about
you can't train people
to do security,
which
is true of normal people. But this is kind of the other side of that coin
where you're training personnel
to look for certain things to determine risk.
And this obviously worked very well. But at the same time,
everyone can't be trained like this.
-- Right.
-- Well, exactly. And I suspect that's why, for example, what was it?
23 days ago, Amazon bought Harvest dot A I which
from reading their website basically is a,
it's a company that is building an A I engine
that monitors access and use of computing resources, you know, access to files,
editing them, blah, blah, blah.
-- And then based on those patterns says bad guy or normal person,
-- right?
Which I mean,
that totally makes sense though too because you look at the amount of data
that any organization is going to produce and you
don't even have to be a huge organization.
There's no way you can go through that data.
And I mean, I remember, I, I don't know anyway, currently,
but I remember people whose job was like
to go through the I DS logs and no human can do that because after 10 minutes
you're not reading anything anymore, you're just clicking next.
Well,
it's funny you mention that because if you look at the
actual specifications for training around direct X ray machines and whatnot,
officially,
they're not,
you're not supposed to work more than 15 minutes because like the human brain just
can't do that kind of activity for more than 15 minutes without zoning up.
This also applies to a bunch of other,
uh, security situations.
I remember they were also talking about for snipers, you know, like police snipers,
they have to trade off every 15 minutes because you can't,
you just can't stare at something for like, two hours
-- and be mindful and aware of what's going on really, you know,
-- computers,
they love doing that kind of stuff.
Right.
-- Well,
-- yeah.
And they're great, you know,
they're great at it.
And the other thing about the computers and this is what
always gets me when people talk about A I and automation,
you can always make the computer better and once you've made it better,
it stays better.
The problem is you make humans better
and they either quit or they get a different job or they retire, you know,
like they don't,
you, you get one human better, awesome, good job for you. But
unless that person becomes a trainer or something, you know,
that knowledge is effectively locked up in their head
and it's never shared and and apparently this is the reason now why, for example,
image recognition for A I has become such a,
a successful thing now is because there's all these training sets of data,
you know, there's all that existing pre-existing knowledge
-- that you can just like scoop up for free or next to nothing now to use to train your A
-- I.
Right. Right. Exactly. It's amazing what you can accomplish now.
Yeah.
And which, you know, I'm really curious about this arms race between.
So, on the one hand, we have proof that you're a human to me because, you know,
you're registering an account or whatever,
you know, those capas
and like, uh, now the ones are like, what is it, like, pick all the pictures with,
like, pizza without fish on
it
or pick all the storefronts?
And I'm looking, I'm like, is that a storefront or is that somebody's house?
I don't know, like, it looks kind of like I've seen
like, there's this. Right.
I feel like I'm taking like a college aptitude
test where they're purposely trying to trick you.
Exactly. And so, you know,
the problem is a, is, are going to get good at that.
Of course, they're going to be trained on this. So
I, I'm actually kind of looking forward to this arms race between, like,
prove to me that you are human.
And
-- the, of course, on the other side is like, I'm going to pretend to
-- be,
you know, what the answer is to this is, don't have
every freaking website have their own login system.
Just use something like Facebook or Google to deal with the
logins and then it becomes their problem to identify the human.
-- I'm totally serious.
-- I agree. No, no, I, I fully agree.
Um, at this point, I, yeah, I mean,
Google is a great example because they require you to
have a phone number that they send a code to
and that allows them to, for example, identify, you know,
cell phone providers that sell burner phones very easily or low cost, you know,
prepaid or whatever.
And then they know that those are higher risk accounts and, you know, shenanigans
and let's face it, every organization is gonna have fake accounts. It's just
if you're a small company or a small group,
you don't have the resources to actually deal with that problem and things like,
I mean, cap just basically don't work today, let's face it.
I hate them because I, I'm actually getting to the point now where,
especially with the mangled letters and
stuff and having to hit refresh two or three times.
I,
I can't even imagine what it must be like for
somebody who's 70 or 80 or who has bad eyesight.
I bet the A is, are better than people at the stupid things now.
Oh, probably
I would
hope,
you know, they're a human because they can't figure it out. Right.
Yeah.
Well, and that's kind of what I'm wondering is, you know, prove you're not a machine,
you know, say something uniquely human.
Right? Yeah.
Let me into the damn website. All right, you're a person.
Yeah.
It's kind of like those when you call up the, the uh Robo.
Uh what, what is that?
The Robo call center thing where your call is important to us, you know,
the menu may have changed but, and you, like,
you start swearing at it and it transfers you to a person immediately
like that basically works. Just, just so
anyway.
Yeah. So, no, it's, it's a brave new world and I mean, that's,
you know, what's interesting.
I wonder what else this law of large numbers is going to affect? Right.
Because there's, there's a lot of these things happening,
it affects everything.
Yeah, because that's,
that's the other reason I had to turn off antivirus on my desktop was
I have over a million files on my desktop. Apparently
-- I run Linux. So I don't think I have an antivirus. I can run. Yeah.
-- So I do
occasionally run like an antivirus scan of my backups,
but to run a full antivirus scan on my desktop now takes like an hour or two, you know,
and it's just, and it never detects anything.
Of course, that's the best part. Right. It never finds anything.
Yeah.
Right. Right. Well, in,
you know, man, so here's part of the deal too is I,
I have family members will say that
have antivirus software and they always have viruses
and every time I see them,
I have to fix their computer and we'll put fix in air quotes here because it's
really just run the antivirus software and then click delete.
And that's pretty much all I can do.
I don't understand why those things give you an option.
I don't know, whatever it doesn't matter.
But then, like,
I, I don't want to sound like some, like,
pretentious a hole here, but I have never
downloaded a virus
because I don't click on dodgy links.
I don't do stupid things for and I'm not saying I'm immune mind you. I'm just saying
that these people have this technology and it clearly doesn't work.
And, you know, even, even though I may have antivirus running on a system,
I'm still not, I, it's not a problem because I'm not doing crazy things.
Now, my kids on the other hand,
scare the crap out of me because they're always looking for like,
you know,
dodgy, Minecraft mods or things.
And it's like here download this exe and I'm like, no, don't do that stuff.
This is honestly why I haven't let my kids near a quote
unquote real computer.
It'll be
ipods and ipads for the foreseeable
-- future.
-- You're gonna crack some day
someday. Kurt,
-- it'll happen.
-- I'll give him a Linux box that'll show
him.
Uh,
that's, yeah. Well, well, for what it's worth though.
So this is actually part of it too, is like with Minecraft,
my son
found a book
and I think it was at the school library talking about Minecraft mods.
And he says, oh, look, here's a program I can download that will
install mods for me. And I look at it and I'm like, this is actually cool
because you have basically like a company now that's managing the mods
for him and he clicks on them and they install themselves.
So he's not going to these dodgy websites.
It's really, no.
Can you please
send me that?
Yes,
I will. I
put it in the show.
I,
there's a lot of parents no
serious. That's why
that is,
that is 95% of the use case for a laptop for my one. So
-- will be Minecraft with
-- mods on, on its own private Wi Fi network.
So nothing else will ever see it.
Yeah. Yeah, I'll look for it. I'll look for it.
All right, man. I think we've wasted enough time for our dear listeners.
So, yeah, if anybody else has any good Minecraft links to stuff that will make it
easier for a six year old.
We're moving on from
now. We'll talk about Minecraft and nothing else.
-- We
-- should do
a
show.
I love Minecraft. Oh, my goodness. You have no idea how many like you talk
about your
machine. My chicken, the chicken cooker is, is fantastic. I have several and
not only that will actually, my, my real claim to fame is,
have you ever heard of something called Sky Block?
So it's where you basically start out with this
like extremely minimalist world that basically has like no,
nothing in it.
It's you're on this little teeny tiny, like nine by nine patch of land with a tree.
And
I have an enormous world I have built and
I have a village which means to make villagers.
I had to create zombies
and then wait for a zombie Villager, heal the zombie Villager.
And I needed more than one. And then I had to have them kind of do their thing
and multiply
and I have an enormous village now.
Yeah, it's,
you have become a God. I, I have too much freaking free time.
Actually, I haven't played it in a long time there.
There's a period of time where I found myself home.
I would put my kids to bed and I had like an hour or two
at night waiting for my wife to come home. And
then I, I had time
to do that. Like that's what I did is I played Sky Block for like six months and it was,
I don't know, it's clearly
I have nothing to show for that six months of my life. The time I spent in the,
except this crazy sky black world. Anyway. Anyway. All right, folks,
you can go to
open source security podcast.com.
We love all the show notes to all the things we've talked about.
You can hit us up on Twitter, there's Pound
Os S podcast
and there's of course a link to that on the show notes
and you can find Kurt and I send us messages, whatever, we'll certainly respond.
I also,
I'm gonna try something new is I put together a
Facebook group for open source security podcasts and there's gonna be
a link to it in the show notes and we'll see
if that's maybe something people are interested in or not.
Either way we'll see, we'll give it a chance
and
I have nothing else exciting to say. We've got Rs A coming in a couple weeks.
We should probably talk about that at some point.
Kurt,
because we'll both be there and maybe we'll do something special for the podcast if,
if nothing else, you know, come find us and, and, and hang out or say hi or whatever.
But,
yeah, I guess, uh, you have a fantastic day, Kurt.
Thank you for listening, everybody. And until next time.