Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
and my partner in opening presents, Josh Bresser.
-- Are
-- we opening presents should have been opened by
now because it's totally Christmas Day or Boxing Day,
depending upon where you live or depending upon what day you
-- listen to this
-- or if you celebrate Christmas at all.
That's true.
So, today we're going to talk about Boxing Day,
which is not a holiday familiar to, we'll say most of the world. Well, maybe it is.
I don't know
-- if
-- you're a British colony. You are so.
Well, I mean, the United States is technically a British colony.
-- We just
-- not anymore.
Who's on your money again.
No, no. Well, we're not part of the Commonwealth, right?
Canada is part of the Commonwealth
and I know the UK and at least Canada,
probably some other places celebrate Boxing Day.
And now Kurt tell us what Boxing Day is
because you actually experience Boxing Day and then we
can talk about what Boxing Day used to be and how we're going to talk about that today.
So, modern Boxing Day. Well, it's essentially what we did instead of Black Friday.
Right. It's our sales day now, although now we celebrate Black Friday here in Canada
as well
after Christmas. Why are you buying stuff after Christmas?
After you just bought a bunch of crap and gave it to people?
Yeah. Well, the traditional, because it's a holiday to go shopping.
I mean, the traditional thing was that essentially it was when you, um,
-- you gave your servants and whatnot gifts and such,
-- the,
-- the less fortunate is the term we'll
-- use the old time.
You less fortunate.
Right. Right.
That's right.
That's right. Everyone but the wealthy.
Yeah. So,
but, yeah, I like many things now. It's just morphed into another shopping day.
Ok.
But here's what I want us to talk about today, which Kurt totally did his homework on,
on that.
I gave him earlier in the week. I found out just a few minutes ago. But that's fine.
I'm deadline driven. That's right. Exactly.
Gotten that one pretty close.
So there is a person at Wendy Nather who is, I,
I think she's in her title is like Advisory Ciso at Cisco or something like that.
But Wendy has this concept. She calls the Security Poverty Line where
she talks about how
we as security people love to go on and on about, oh, you need to do this and, and that,
-- and you need to go
-- buy $75 yi
keys and at least get at least two of them because the
and get a safe deposit box to keep it in and,
yeah, exactly. Patch your systems. Like there's so many things we spout
and the, the reality is the vast majority of organizations
don't have the resources. They don't have the time.
They just can't do anything about it.
And it's not that they don't want to.
And there's a good, is it, is it Neil Gaiman who wrote about the boots?
Have you ever heard the Boots thing where it's basically like,
if you pay $100 for a good pair of boots, it'll last for 10 years.
But
the poor people are paying like, what, $30 for a pair of boots that last,
like one year and they have to buy new boots every
year and their back hurts and all that stuff and I'll,
I'll find it and put a link in the show.
Oh, it was Terry Pratchett
-- in Men at Arms? Oh, Terry
-- Pratchett. Ok.
Right. Right. And so anyway,
you, you kind of get the idea.
And so something I was thinking about,
we are the open source security podcast if someone
said I don't have a lot of resources,
but I want to improve the security of using open source,
specifically open source because there are tons of
advice on just like general infosec and it,
and stuff like that.
But I was thinking we have a unique angle and so what would,
what would you tell someone if they came to you and said,
I don't have a lot of resources.
I'm using open source. What can I do to, I guess,
-- improve my life.
-- Honestly,
I would say the first thing is kind of go with the, how do I say it?
It's like the bigger branded open source if you're,
especially if it's something like you're relying on to get your job done,
you know, use something like ubuntu, not some crazy random obscure Linux distro.
You know what?
I didn't write down anything like that,
but I think that's a very reasonable thing that anyone can do.
-- It's just,
-- you're gonna have less hassle.
Like a perfect example of this is
there are versions of Linux
that
have things that would kind of benefit me for some of the things I do.
But I basically just force myself to use Ubuntu LTs long term support because
it might be a little more work upfront to get it to work,
but it's way more sustainable and Ubuntu LTs is going to be around in five or 10 years.
So I have a, a better example of that I think.
And this will tie into, I've got containers are one of my things.
We'll talk about that a little more in a minute.
But there are lots of container images and one of the favorite things. OK.
That's an understatement ba images,
whatever. Stop it, stop it. All right.
I know. I know. Anyway.
So there's all these bases images, right? And you've got like big fat images like
bu you've got these really slim images like alpine
and there's everything in between.
And one of the hip things going on right now is people are becoming obsessed and this,
this like comes and goes constantly because a couple of years ago,
I remember this was huge news at redhead,
but people become obsessed with like we're
going to build the smallest possible container image
that only has what we want.
And it's usually driven by vulnerability scans where they're like, oh look,
my vulnerability has zero CV ES
which is a fool's errand and we'll talk about that some other day. But
you often get this. But the problem you have is if you take like a fat image like a
Buntu, it usually has the things you need to make it work, right?
And it'll usually not break very often.
Whereas when you have these like crazy custom distro list type things,
I'm not saying they're worse,
but you've now shifted the burden onto to having to kind of feed and maintain it
at the creation time because now you're responsible for all
the tools you're responsible for everything going in it.
If you miss something,
it might break for who knows what reason because it,
it's expecting some weird file in Etsy only on the
first of the month when it runs billing or whatever.
And, and so I think
that is a very reasonable piece of advice.
In my opinion, I know a lot of people will probably disagree with this,
but I think it buys you a certain amount of just boring
and boring is good in security.
Well, and to be clear,
this is not about fat or skinny containers
because fat containers have their own problems.
Like stuff randomly goes away that you were depending on the
base image to have and that you didn't explicitly install.
Uh a great example is like I install Apache and
then I tried using mod rewrite and I'm like,
it doesn't work.
What the
and I'm like, oh yeah, the module is not turned on by default. OK? I got it. Do that. Ok.
Great.
What it is is it's about that sustainability of like,
I don't suddenly want a six months from now notice like I've gotten zero updates
or worse, something
like chrome or whatever app I'm using inside
the container makes a change and it breaks
and the container is just not kept up to date.
Like I, I want my stuff to be kept up to date ideally by somebody else,
right?
And if you're using a lot of the distro list type stuff,
it's often your responsibility to keep things updated
because you're the one who's adding it and
we love to pin our dependencies because then things don't break.
So
it's so this one actually ties in nicely with, with the last thing I wrote down
which let me check my list here. I, I put in about kind of, uh, updating the software.
Right. Like you're using open source, it's a fire hose of updates.
And anyone, like, I run Fedora on my laptop, the laptop we're recording on right now
has Fedora on it
and every day I run DNF upgrade
and it
just is, like, in hundreds and hundreds of things every single day. And
if you're running a desktop,
you should definitely turn on auto updates, right.
This is true of like any desktop Linux windows, like anything, turn that stuff on.
And actually there's,
there's actually a really subtle reason for this too is as the updates come out,
there's a delta between your out of date system and
upstream, let's call it
and that delta grows.
And so when you finally do an update,
because at some point you're gonna have to do an update
that if the delta is sufficiently large and you have any problems,
it's going to be a nightmare to track them down
right
now.
This is offset by the fact of or do you
accept the kind of constant pain of keeping your,
basically, this is the difference between,
do you clean your toilet every day and it only takes a minute to
clean because it's relatively clean because you cleaned it yesterday or do you,
you know, clean it monthly
and then it takes like an hour of scrubbing, kind of,
right.
But it's the same thing it's this kind of maintenance activity.
Well, no, it's this kind of maintenance activity versus, you know, do you do a lot of
maintenance?
Do you
do the
right? And,
and again, that's also, I would say
so in this case, that may or may not be appropriate because for example,
if you're supporting a manufacturing line,
you can't run the risk of breaking it every day.
You should probably do that on the weekends.
OK? So manufacturing lines are a different story and there's a part two
to what I wrote down
and the part two is not desktops. So if you're running like servers,
you don't want automatic updates.
And anyone in in any kind of enterprise knows you have like
patch weekend or things like that where you on Friday at five
PM, you start upgrading systems because if you did this in the middle of the week,
you're going to get fired the next day because you're going to take down production.
And this is where containers come in because containers are kind of
a get out of jail free card when it comes to updates.
Because I've got my old container that I know works.
I upgrade stuff in my container. I now have a new container,
I can test or deploy my new container.
And if it doesn't work, I just use my old container
because when you're dealing with actual servers,
if you upgrade a bunch of packages,
I know all of the distro claim they have rollback functionality.
-- That is a lie. Like I have never seen rollback actually work rollback
-- functioning.
Even when it does work, still doesn't fix the four hour email window outage
where nobody got me work done.
That's right. That's right. So,
so anyway, I, I feel like
that is one of the easiest things we can do
in terms of using open source is things like containers bring us
into a modern era that gives us a lot of power.
Most of us aren't running open
source like Linux or things on our desktops.
I mean, that's just the reality of it and that's fine,
but no matter what you're running on your desktop, like auto update that sucker,
you need it.
Well, actually, that really dovetails nicely with
my next, I don't want to call it prediction advice. And
the next thing you totally didn't just make up right now,
which is no is to use github.
Now,
having said that
is one of the challenges with github used to be that you didn't have,
you had to pay for private repos basically.
And they changed that like two maybe three years ago. It was, it's been a while.
So they have unlimited free public and private repos.
So for example, like I, I personally use them for tons of stuff.
We manage this podcast out of one
and I do actually use a handful of private repos,
which is why I didn't realize when you click on a anyways.
But the thing is using github
gets you two things that are really important.
Number one, it gets you an off site backup of whatever you're shoving into github.
And number two, it gets you version and control, which means, oh,
you delete something, you revert it,
right?
And
also collaboration and sharing.
So it gets you three things, right?
And collaboration and sharing is actually, you know,
that's the reason Google Drive took off, you know,
and Microsoft finally caught up and is there now, but
like for about four or five years, Microsoft didn't have office collaboration.
And you know, Google Drive really took over the world because of that,
you know, it's weird but it turns out people want to be able to work together.
Maybe that's why companies are a thing.
Do you remember when we used to just like email
word documents to each other over and over again?
I still deal with some groups that email the word dog with change
track enabled and then some poor person has to manually reconcile it.
I'd take change tracking in a second.
I remember it just being people saying, oh, the document I sent on Tuesday,
that's the one you want.
It's like you sent three documents on Tuesday. Like this is insane.
Well, and it's funny because like,
so my son is taking technology as one of his options and they're doing
some basic programming in this sort of
like extended javascript uh Js five something.
It's like basically think logo, he was emailing himself his code to keep it safe,
right?
And I'm like, well, number one, that's actually a really good valid strategy.
Number two,
you already have a github account.
Let's teach you how to, like, I'm going to start teaching him how to use it.
But do they allow github at his school?
They allow the web at his school and it's a single file so
-- you can just cut and paste it so
-- he can get to github
website?
Ok. Because
at, at the high school, my son goes to where I help with the robotics team,
they've blocked github
because it apparently has naughty content on it. Well,
yeah, because it's like Wikipedia,
-- it's
-- github.
No, Wikipedia is allowed. Ok?
Because Wikipedia definitely there's some articles in there that are like, whoa,
nothing about the way they block content at schools makes sense.
It's
obviously random nonsense and for whatever reason, someone decided this is bad.
-- And so now it's bad and there's no way to change it. Two
-- challenges.
One,
you're trying to solve a social problem with technology that almost never works.
-- It literally never works
-- well.
Some things like self driving cars will hopefully deal with drunk drivers
assuming the self driving cars ever work. But that remains to be seen.
And number two,
I forget what number two was.
-- Oh,
-- you have
-- to
-- be seen to be doing something. The goalkeeper's dilemma. Right.
So even if it's an ineffective thing, we, we tried.
So, yeah, so use github
with the caveat being, you know, don't abuse it.
Like don't shove 100 megabyte files in there or get repos that are over a gigabyte.
And if you do that, you'll have to pay like five bucks a month for the data packs
because we actually do like, I use github
for backing up some stuff for the CS A.
And so we just pay like it's like $10 a month for the extra data storage. It's
-- super worth
-- it
-- anyway.
-- All right.
Moving on, moving on.
I have
the next thing.
Actually, my next, I,
I've got two more things I wrote down that I'm going to just smoosh them together.
So it's,
it's around when you're developing software kind of knowing
what you have and understanding what's critical path because
if you are building anything today,
you have thousands of dependencies.
Right? There's just no way around that.
And there's always, now you run into how do I update things? What do I do? Do?
I just run current and go with it?
Do I pin everything and, and figure out what to upgrade?
And when, and if we're talking about organizations that aren't over
resourced,
I think you've got the,
the kind of the three problems of do I update everything quickly.
Do I pin everything and pray?
And then I also need to know what I have, which is just kind of part of all of this.
And I think it's, it
is hard to do and it's easy to say just oh go oh generate an S bomb and store it.
But like generating S bombs is hard and knowing what to do with them is hard
and pinning dependencies creates challenges.
-- Running current creates challenges, you know.
-- Uh I have to,
I was just thinking one thought is if you're under-resourced,
anytime you do want to do something,
you have to have a very strong and like easy to understand reason for doing it to get,
you know, approval.
Right?
And so that actually is almost one advantage of pinning dependencies.
So it's now it's like I have to fix the CV versus oh,
I just want to spend 10 minutes every day, updating stuff.
So it stays up to date. We don't have any big problems. Well, is it critical right now?
No. OK. Don't do that, do something else.
So I think maybe that's part of, I,
I don't want to say I'm in favor of penning dependencies,
but it's one of the arguments you can use to support it.
Yeah. Well, and I mean, so
if we un untangled this even more though you just said, oh, I have to fix the CBE.
If you're not well resourced,
you don't even know you have security vulnerabilities,
you probably don't have any insight into what you're doing.
And
I think that's getting better because, like, if you look at N PM and PP,
they now have the ability to at least, like, warn you about old crap.
It'll, there's what an audit command that'll tell you.
Like, these are the vulnerabilities.
They've, they've had built in packages that use their, like,
security databases for years now.
Um, and I think now it's actually becoming, yeah,
it's kind of becoming more of a default built in as opposed to something you can,
you have to like actually try to use.
I agree with that.
Well, and just like, I mean,
in line with that would be like enabling um
I'm spacing out what is it called in github?
The security
tracker.
Depend,
-- that's the one. Yeah. So,
-- OK,
so depend
AOT
is a cool tool but depend
is also it, it generates a lot of work
because it's gonna constantly try to upgrade your dependencies.
And if you don't have good tests, depend
aot
is
I
thought you could have depend,
just send you warnings but not actually do
-- anything because
-- that's what you can have it,
send you warnings, but it can be very noisy but it also try, you can, it'll
so the way to, you know, we should clarify this because not everyone might know this.
So you've got this tool github
wrote called Depend A bo
Depend A bot will try to look at your project, figure out what your dependencies are
and then tell you when things are out of date.
It's very cool,
but it'll what to upgrade and when to upgrade it is always a challenge.
Obviously, you can have depend
bot try to send like, pull requests to automatically update certain things.
But obviously you need tests to know like is this,
can I upgrade this thing without blowing everything up?
Because like, especially in the N PM ecosystem, you can upgrade a package
that will then upgrade like 300 things beneath it
and then
it might have a different API or it might
behave differently and you might not know it.
Right. I mean, this is just, this is,
you know, it's how it works.
Uh
I remember so many things updating things and
config files would or would not change or,
well, you wouldn't want to change the config file,
but there were new capabilities that you wanted to pull into.
It's,
it's difficult and tough and there's
again, if you're beneath that security poverty line, defend a bot
probably isn't particularly valuable to you because it's going to create a
huge pain in your butt.
Yeah. Right. And so you're just not going to do it
and now you have a situation of,
you don't know what you have and you don't know what to do with it.
And,
and this 10 man, like I think about this one a lot and just, I, I don't know
what to tell people. You know, it's easy to say,
know what you're running.
One aspect of this is,
is maybe unable to depend upon and have an
email filter rule that just archives it all.
So that like, uh for example,
when the cloud security lines was using Amazon web services,
I one day turned on cloud trade.
The next day I looked at what was in there and it was like, wow,
like literally a million events.
I'm like, I have no idea what to do with this.
And so I just left it running for three years
because it's,
it's, it's logging of events in your Aws, like everything, like every web request,
every S3 bucket request.
Like it's
a fire hose of, of X of
JSON or XML files in, in S3.
And I left it running and I ignored it for a couple of years
until we left Amazon and then I deleted it and
it was just there to have as a record.
Well, because it costs like five bucks a month or whatever. Right?
And so I just, I had this like archive of logs
that if I ever need them, I have them and stuff like this has saved me like,
thank goodness Google logs,
everything exhaustively because like we had somebody get a new Huawei phone
and it's like, oh,
your local calendar is blank in this remote calendar you want
to sync with has a whole bunch of stuff in it.
Let me reconcile that.
And so
in four minutes, it deleted one of our main calendars
and literally, you know, somebody's like, Kurt, do, we just get hacked.
And I'm like, what?
He's like, the calendars are all blank and I'm like, that's not right.
And so I look at the logs and I'm like, ok, this IP address in this country.
Do we have somebody there? Yes, we do.
Hey, can you, have you done anything new recently?
And he's like, yeah, I just got a new phone. I'm like, ah,
and luckily I was able to roll it back and fix it but, you know,
without those logs and everything,
yeah, my life would have been very
unpleasant because as it turns out there's no way to back up Google calendar stuff.
Really.
It's not like Google Drive where you can shove it into, like, some service.
Google calendar is just,
yeah, good luck with that.
So, wait, how did you get the Google Calendar back?
Ah, they had just implemented the trash bin functionality, like,
three months before.
So I went into the account, went to the trash bin. I went, yep. There's everything.
Thank goodness that the app doesn't know how to empty
the trash bin or I would have been like,
well, everybody,
you get to manually recreate your calendars.
Yeah.
Well, and I still love, like, I just had somebody email me.
Can you please remove me from a Google calendar?
And I'm like, no, because I can't search for you.
Like, you can't search Google calendar items for an email address,
even in your own,
let alone somebody else's
man. No, we're not talking about
calendaring. Calendaring is a rathole and
it
will always be terrible because,
-- but it
-- was worse 10 years ago.
It was a lot worse
anyway. Anyway.
Ok.
So security poverty line.
And I think you, you just hit on a really important point that
II I
think is valuable to all of us.
It's easy to say you need to monitor all your infrastructure.
It's easy to say you need to monitor all your open
source. It's easy to talk about all this stuff. And I think one of the tricks
maybe if you don't have a lot of resources isn't
about fretting over what you're monitoring or not monitoring,
but just make sure you have those kind of logs available for if you ever need them
and you might not even be the one who needs them.
Like for example, let's say you get epically hacked,
you can call an organization
that will help you
just kind of untangle, right?
And, and figure out what happened and if you have those logs, they can,
they have tooling,
they can use that on same thing with your open source dependencies.
If you're using something like
github and you're tracking your source code, you can look back in time
and say like this is where we picked this thing up
and I know something happened here at this other date.
And this is when we start seeing these weird
changes in our logs or whatever and you can,
you can start putting pieces together.
And I think that is very valuable and it's
not expensive from a resource or time perspective.
Like a perfect example of this is I, you know, I have
security cameras at my house and I hadn't mounted the one above the garage door yet.
And of course, that's when my, you know,
the neighbor smashes his pickup truck into my garage.
And,
you know, and the
like, and unfortunately the doorbell camera didn't catch it.
But yeah, I mean, that would have made like the cops were just like,
oh, he's like, literally said, I think something like, oh,
that would have been so nice to have.
And I'm like, yeah, I imagine,
you know, and now, yeah, so it's just,
yeah, you're probably never going to need it.
But it's a lot like toilet paper in that. If you need it, you need it.
Why do you keep using bathroom analogies today?
-- That's
-- so weird because everybody has a bathroom.
-- It's Christmas.
-- You know, my favorite thing is my favorite Christmas story.
I did a contract in Argentina writing tech documentation
and I happened to get there
the week they were doing the national census.
And so what's interesting is I get counted in the
census because I'm in the country and I'm like,
really OK, that makes sense
because, you know, at any point in
most countries you're gonna have thousands, tens of thousands,
he even millions of foreigners.
Right.
You know.
And so what was, and then so the next day when I went to the office there was another
there that was actually there, like, permanently
and his Spanish, uh, wasn't so good.
And so he's trying to, you know, figure out the census for him and he's like,
reading it and he's like, ok, like
something, something in your bathroom. I'm like, yeah, that makes sense.
He's like,
it says a bucket. I'm like,
yeah,
and in his mind he just didn't compute like, why,
why would you have a bucket in your bathroom?
And I'm like, well, hm, let's explain, you know, poverty to you.
Right.
Right. And so, but that's the thing, like, no matter what,
everybody has a bathroom or some sort
of bathroom situation figured out because we're humans
anyway.
Oh, my goodness.
This is, but this is like tech now, like,
I have to give that talk at Career Day on Thursday
and I'm pointing out that one of the aspects of it now.
No one knows the context of that. You told me that before we hit record. Explain this.
Yeah. So, but anyway, so I'm giving it a career day talk about it.
And one of the main points I'm making about it is that it is everything now.
-- It's not like
-- this is no.
-- Ok. And
-- that's just like the security power
-- everything.
-- So
stop it. I'm going to give context. Then you can explain this. Kurt has a son
at a school.
Ok. Right. You have two sons. They go to school. There is Career Day at the school
and you volunteered to talk about it at Career Day.
That is the context of that.
And one of the big points I make is that it is everything now.
-- It
-- absolutely
-- is like we shoved a computer and everything, you know,
and, and, and also I also make the point that you don't have to do.
I like, you don't have to be in it full time to do it. Like there's also,
you can also end up being the person who like
is good with computers who people go to first.
And that's the worst person
in
the world.
But that's also like, as I point out,
that's a very valuable thing to be and
people love people who can solve their problems.
And so if you can learn to like,
you know, grin and bear it,
I can't condone that advice at all.
I think this is literally the tail end
of Christmas that this episode is being published.
Many of us will have been subjected to
our relatives tech questions for multiple days.
At this point, we fixed,
who knows how many printers and we are fed up with anyone using computers.
I
I detest going to visit family because they
inevitably asked me to fix their computer every time
this is why we made our, like, we made my parents get Macs and iphones,
-- I made
-- my parents get a chromebook.
That's also an acceptable
answer. And it's funny, I actually point that out explicitly in my slides that
like this is one of the reasons why Edmonton public School
board is a chrome shop because I get all these,
it, like all these kind of basic, it functions that maybe you can end up doing.
They can also be like, just we use chromebooks.
Yep. No, I totally get it. In fact, that's always my advice.
How do I, when my, my computer is broken, how do I fix it?
I'm like, get a chromebook or buy a Mac.
Those are usually my two bits of advice because although honestly,
Windows I think has gotten better, I will say it's not the virus ridden cesspool.
-- It once was, it's not great, but it's better.
-- Windows
with Windows. Defender is pretty
like Defender built in and it doesn't,
the biggest thing is it doesn't break the system like most A V will.
Right. Right. Which is not a very high bar to set for a V.
It's like, does this make my system worse? No. Hey, that's the one I want.
Well, you know,
the funny thing about that is the Windows defender definitely kind of blows.
It catches the easy stuff. Right.
But the thing is like 99% of this crap, your family's gonna pick up is the easy stuff.
You know what the biggest thing I think for a lot of people
is just two simple things. One
use the web interface for your email, right? Like gmail, whatever.
And number two use
like use Chrome or whatever with an ad blocker.
The with an ad blocker,
I can't use the internet without ad blockers.
Although I would say use Firefox these days because the chrome
ad blocker is starting to suck because they've crippled it.
Um For some reason, no one understands why
it's not to protect advertising revenue at all,
-- which is 80 something percent of their money,
-- right?
But Firefox with an ad blocker is delight. This is a delightful experience.
An ad blocker.
Yeah. Well, well, but it is
less
so with chrome because I was using Chrome for
a while because the people at work were like,
oh,
you have to use chrome to access some stupid website we have and I gave up and I'm like,
whatever I can just run Chrome for this one thing
because the ad blocker like just doesn't block a
-- lot of stuff and it's getting less
-- effective.
That's why everyone run Firefox and it's open source
except the persona profile management is still terrible, which I don't understand
it.
It is not very good and I will agree with you,
but it is good enough that I can suffer through it.
And the advantages of having a functional ad
blocker vastly outweigh the negatives of the,
the profile management.
-- Yep,
-- that is true.
I can not live without a blocking because no,
like every time I use the internet on somebody else's device,
I'm just like the hell is wrong.
Oh, right.
I
know
-- this is what it looks like.
-- It's unbelievable. Anyway, anyway. All right.
Do you have one more thing on your list?
We can probably bank through one more of these.
Uh
I had those two things. I was actually
gonna
say this is a really open source. But
ok, so if you had a box of family photos that you really deeply treasured,
would you be willing to pay $2 a month to make sure it's backed up?
Probably. So here's the thing
when you go home for the Christmas or with friends and family,
make sure they're ok by default iphones and Apple
World and the Android phones of the Google World,
get 15 gigs of data storage,
right for free.
So pay the extra $2 a month to get the 100 gigabytes
or whatever so that all your photos and videos are backed up,
that's actually good advice and it's not open source related,
but I think the pictures are a big one.
Now.
It's not that simple always though because you can be a Google paying
customer and if you violate their terms of service in some way,
you can just lose your account and you can lose all your old
-- photos because like
-- you can also lose it by being a free customer.
-- And,
-- and absolutely,
this is,
this is why actually the right way to do this is to have multiple copies where you can,
for example, like on my Mac, I have all my photos downloaded,
-- but
-- this assumes that the person is rich enough to afford another computer.
And, and that's a good point. A lot of people just have a mobile
phone.
Like, I,
I have a friend who works at the government of Alberta and
she works with people who don't have a home computer anymore.
They just have their go,
a issued cell phone which they use for all their personal stuff,
which for the love of God don't do that.
Um, because one person was retiring and they pointed out like,
you can't keep the phone number,
I suppose
you've been using it for 10 years and it's not yours. Wow. That sucks.
Well, don't use your work phone for personal stuff.
I mean, that's fair, especially when you work for the government.
But so I, I don't like,
yes.
And this is a perfect example of, like,
I like the advice and theory of having multiple copies and off site and blah, blah,
blah.
Yeah,
-- you're right. You're absolutely right.
-- But for many people, the $2 a month it auto.
So
you don't have to do anything.
That's fair. That's a good point
-- I had. Yeah. Oh, man, because,
-- like, I'm, I'm in the same boat.
Like I've literally got,
I it's on my to do list of setting up a thing where basically I will have my
Windows or Mac download my ihos and copy it out and archive it and back it up.
But like,
it's actually really difficult to do to ensure that all the photos get actually
backed up versus some because I just did an export of the directory.
And I'm like,
like, it's only half full
for whatever reason, half my stuff is missing.
-- I'm like, so
-- I, I just did this with uh iphoto because
I needed to give someone a bunch of pictures
and
I used Windows.
You can install the icloud app, you can tell it to sync the data,
but it doesn't really sync at all.
It's weird
what I kept doing is I would go and open the directory.
Now, mind you, I have like 40 gigs of photos and videos and stuff. So
I would open the directory control a like select all drag it somewhere else.
It would run for like literally hours.
Then I did, I kept doing that over and over and over again until it ran.
It didn't find new stuff to copy and it took like
-- days
-- and I'm looking at basically writing a
Python or something script to walk the directory,
touch each file or whatever, you know, basically force Windows to,
to do something with it.
-- I wonder if that would work. I don't know. Anyway, I got it done so
-- well.
Basically you need to get windows to actually, like, see that
I need to copy the file locally versus, like,
I need to pretend that I have a copy of the file locally until you don't click on it
and it does that anyway. All right, whatever. We're in the weeds.
But, and this is a perfect example of like, that is not
like normal, people are gonna be like, what the hell are they talking about?
That's true. That's true.
I think this is, I mean, and, and you raise a good point,
like not everyone has computers to, to do like backups of this kind of stuff.
And that, that's a hard problem.
And your least worst answer here is spend the 2 to
$3 a month to get the 100 gigs of storage.
Except if Google decides they don't like you one day, like you're hosed.
-- This
-- doesn't create a new problem. That's always a problem.
That's fair.
That's fair. All right. Anyway, anyway, let's, let's call this one.
It's Christmas. It's Boxing Day.
Kurt.
Merry Christmas.
-- You too.
-- Merry Christmas. To everyone listening.
-- Oh, yeah.
-- Merry Christmas to everyone. To all a good night.
Yeah. And I hope your relatives didn't torture you too much with tech problems.
All right.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.
That.