Hello and welcome to the open source Security podcast episode 41 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime.
Josh Bresser.
What's New Kurt?
Well, still can't get a Nintendo switch.
And Best Buy has now changed their phone message to
say that we're not going to talk about it.
Go check our website.
You know, I wasn't gonna ask because I, I didn't want to make you feel bad.
It's ok.
But the good news is actually it's teaching Felix delayed gratification.
I mean, partly because he doesn't have a choice in the matter.
And also because he's like, he, he wants to go spend,
he wanted to go by like $60 worth of gems and Castle Crush or whatever.
And I'm like, ok, we can buy that but then we can't get the, uh, the switch
and he's like,
oh,
I want the switch. I'm like, thought
-- so
-- I
think that's a good
choice.
Yeah.
Yeah. And the good news is I have gotten open
emu with, you know, um, some old controllers and stuff working on the TV.
So he's getting a Super Mario fix
it.
There's not even Mario on the switch though.
The only game that's really any good is Zelda,
please.
Noon's
not out yet.
Uh,
one of the websites was gonna let me buy it.
Are you sure you're buying Splatoon and not like an empty box?
It's
Amazon.
So that, like the Super Mario run fake apps sort of thing? Like you're an
empty
-- box?
-- Well, I Right. Right.
-- I was gonna say, I remember this, this was like PS two days, I think when the PS
-- two
switch,
Nintendo,
is it out?
I don't think it's out yet.
Ah, this item is not yet released. Pre,
why would I preorder something that has no release date?
Because
like, if it had like a release date of like, like,
um, you know,
I pre-ordered a book and they had like a specific release date and being a book, it's,
you know, probably gonna hit that release date.
But I've never understood people who pre buy stuff, especially when it has like,
no release date.
-- Uh,
-- well, not only that, the, the true irony of it all is for something like platoon,
you can just download it from their app store on the day it comes out.
So why pre release by it at
-- all?
-- Right.
In case you don't have bandwidth or you're stupid. I
don't know, I don't know,
I kind of want to have the physical games though because
all chances are I'll end up with more than one switch
-- and I don't know how that sharing stuff works.
-- I
don't know if I had to guess it won't because Nintendo
has never done a good job of the kind of online multi
everything
-- universe.
-- Well, even if they're hooked up to the same account, can you do that?
I, well, there is no really hooking up to the same account at this point. So
we don't know. Well, well, that's like you can't even back up your safe.
There are reports of people who sent in their switch
for repairs and they lost their like 4000 hours of Zelda
that was on the safe.
So,
so Nintendo went full out DRM with this, which I, you know,
every console is full out DRM.
But
the other guys like Microsoft and Sony have the ability to
like upload your saves to the cloud and things like that.
And Nintendo has none of that today.
I'm sure they will.
-- But
-- Nintendo has never really been like an online gaming company, right?
They've always been sort of that more traditional console and, you know,
and they're, they're good at that, like the fact that I pulled my wii out of the,
you know, box in the garage and it just works
and the games are still fun,
you know,
I'll give him that.
But speaking of like learning and sharing Nintendo switches actually,
uh do you wanna talk about the insanity or shall I?
Oh man, this is, why don't you intro this? Because I know as a frequent traveler.
That's just uh the pain I feel from reading the story.
So the deal is we don't know why people have been, you know, making.
There's been tons of rumors and conspiracy theories,
but what it boils down to is a bunch of Middle Eastern airlines
have been uh given essentially a rule by the US government saying
like, uh yeah, you,
you can't have people bringing laptops or like ipads onto the plane anymore,
right?
Which I, I think we briefly discussed this an episode or two ago and Schneier
had a little write up where it sounded like
this was not politically motivated, but there was real intelligence behind it.
But it's still just, oh man, I can't imagine.
I don't want to go on a plane with my kids without their ipads
and,
you
know,
-- ignoring
-- the Children, even just
number one. I don't wanna let my laptop out of my possession for that long.
I don't trust the baggage handlers to not like, stop on my bag or like, you know,
like crush it with a fork,
that
laptop, the tablet, like a small tablet
that I thought was reasonably robust, got like folded in half, well,
not fold and a half but bent enough that the screen was just crashed
with the little TS a inspection, you know, ticket inside. Thanks.
Yeah.
Well, I mean, it,
it never ceases to amaze me when the few times I
do have to check a bag for one reason or another
and you go to that carousel and like some of these
bags look like they've literally been run over by a truck.
-- And I'm like, how does this even happen?
-- Because that does happen? I mean,
you've seen the videos, like, where, like, you know, what was it?
Like, Delta broke my guitar,
you know, the guy made a song about it and finally, Shane, Delta or whatever,
he was giving his
money
back or the guy, you know, where they're, they're doing the air side check.
So basically the, you're boarding a small plane and they're like, yeah,
we have no more room for bags.
So like drop your bags at the,
you know, in the hallway of the, uh, the gangway, the jetway thing here,
you know, and then we'll have somebody to carry your bags onto the plane,
like the belly of the plane, put them in
and then at the other end they'll be pulled out and put by, you know,
when you walk off the plane, you'll get your bags, which honestly when it works,
it works quite well.
The problem is, is jet ways, you know, there's a lot of stairs
and so I guess,
you know, instead of walking the bags down, they were just, you know,
just kind of kicking them off the edge.
I've never seen them do that. I've seen a lot of times they have a slide
to send them down and, yeah, I mean, they, they fall on the ground.
I mean, if you had anything,
uh, very breakable in your bag,
it would break without
it goes down to is, it's, you have to treat your baggage
like
something you're shipping through ups or fedex,
you
have to be able to, with
a 3 ft drop, you know, because it will,
you know, you know, what's actually really funny is I remember
when I was much, much younger,
I was working for a company and we had to ship a demo system to a trade show.
And this was like, back when computers were really big and heavy
and this was like a full tower system, right? So this thing was enormous.
It probably weighed more than 50 pounds.
And
I remember,
I
know I'll never forget we ship it out to the conference and it gets there,
which is great and, and it, it worked.
I, I was really concerned actually that it wasn't gonna work when it got there
anyway. It gets there. It works demos great.
And I remember I was at the loading dock when the ups happened to show up
and
like, the dude opens the door and I'm like, oh,
I bet this is a computer coming back and he literally
just like wings the box out of the back of the,
and it flies through the air in LA.
And I looked at him and I was like, did you really need to do that?
He's like, hey, this thing's heavy and I'm sick of carrying it and I was like,
ok, thank you. You know, I was like, sign here,
I like part of me thought I just shouldn't sign for this thing,
but whatever I got it and actually we, we packed it up really well.
So it, it had no damage even after its little uh flight.
But
yeah, man, it's, I,
I get it and that's kind of the way you have to think about baggage on airlines.
But anyway, that's not the point here.
The point is
what do you do with no laptop?
Yeah. Well, how do the airlines keep their business customers happy?
Cause like those guys are paying like 10 grand a seat.
I would, in fact, you know what's funny is thinking about this,
I would seriously consider like driving a long distance to an airport that didn't
-- have this rule if I was not an
-- option in the Middle East.
-- Unfortunately.
-- Yeah, probably not. Probably not. So
anyways the airline
have what? On the surface of it seems a reasonable
solution, right? We're just gonna have a bunch of loner laptops on the plane,
-- right?
-- Which you know, on the surface of it is not
terrible.
It's like those public
kiosks at hotels.
That's the first thing that came into my mind and the people using them.
It's terrifying to me.
So I
think
so every time I am at a hotel there is someone sitting at those
kiosks, like I'll see people on their bank website and, and I'm just like,
I wanna grab them and shake them and be like, what's wrong with you?
And, uh, oh, my goodness.
So, here's the question I have,
uh,
I mean, well, obviously it's, it's,
you can't use one of these safely if you're using the operating
system and software that's pre installed on it because it could be,
have God knows what.
And there's no way for you to reliably detect that, right?
Like even if you go to malware bytes or something, you could be, you know,
whatever point is
you can't trust the operating system and the
and the software installed on that machine.
So here's the second question.
So let's then we need to be able to boot off of like an external USB device, right?
You bring your own USB key with your operating system.
Normal people can do this, no problem.
Normal people won't. But you know,
their it department might have them do this if they know that this is happening,
right?
I mean,
-- because what other choice do they have?
-- Right? We'll
just pretend.
So
one
question I would have is, is, can we also even do that safely?
Can we safely boot off of a USB stick onto unknown hardware
and be
guaranteed of our safety and security?
And I think the answer is no, because for all, you know,
there's like some sort of co processor running or
they interrupt or inject something into the boot process.
Ok. Look. Right.
You can't be 100% certain, but unless
a three letter agency is after you,
you're probably ok if you do that.
Well, see, and then this loops back to my written or a second thought I have is
so for the sake of argument, we,
we definitely can't be safe using their software and operating system and
we can be reasonably safe against not a state
level actor but against like normal kind of Attackers
if we boot off a USB thing. But
the reality is,
yeah, people aren't really going to do that because it's too much hassle.
So here's my question,
for example, using,
if you're just accessing cloud services, can you do that reasonably safely?
And, and like what I'm thinking the scenario is, for example,
you set up like say a throwaway account,
um that you use, you know, for your trip,
you know,
and that might start being a thing because
also with all the border searches and stuff,
you know, where
it doesn't matter if you have a USB
stick in a heavily encrypted system because they're,
they're gonna make you decrypt it.
I've actually done.
You have to
for defcon
is I create essentially a bunch of burn burner burner
gear and burner accounts and I don't use anything real.
Yeah.
And so for example,
you set up basically a burner account with say just the sales
presentation you need and just access to that one client or,
you know, whatever it is you specifically need.
So if there is a breach, it's, it's as contained as possible,
right? But, but here's the deal too is you talk about this,
like, it's a practical thing to do and for someone who only travels say once a month
you could do this.
But some of these guys are literally,
they live on airplanes and so they need like 400 burner accounts,
which is not practical.
Well, but the thing is if their it department was setting this up,
I mean, because this could be totally automated, right?
Like, oh you're going to the the the Alpha sales call.
Boom, here's your alpha account, ok? You're done with that.
We're closing it down, here's your access to the beta sales account.
Now the gamma sales account, you know,
that sounds like a lot of work man
and see, but, and one potential advantage would be for example, now is, you know,
you just have the guy traveling with like a blank ipad.
You don't have to worry about backups.
You don't have to worry about data, security, data encryption.
It's because there's nothing with him,
right? It's all in the cloud.
Here's the question I would have though is what
is actually the return on investment to doing this?
And I suspect it is a negative return because I think it cost a lot of money
and I suspect the benefit is minimal. I mean, look, let's face it,
the vast majority of people
could probably use that,
that airplane loaner laptop and even if their accounts get stolen,
it's still not even gonna really impact anything drastically
for now.
But what I'm thinking of is more, you know, as, as for example, the world is changing,
right.
We're now talking about encrypting all web traffic whereas, you know,
10 years ago it was
just
a
lot
of crazy people did it.
No, no.
When you look at things like Cloudflare,
they're encrypting a significant portion of the world's web traffic.
-- Ok. That's true. Cloud flare is doing a nice job
-- and then there's less
encrypt and then there's all the, you know,
hosting providers that are tying into let's encrypt with a plug in.
So it's just automatic, you know, click a button.
Well, right.
So here's kind of the way I view that though is
it, it's a bit like the space program.
We went to the moon in the sixties
and then we never went back. Why do you think that is?
-- Well, there's, there's no real economic reason to do so,
-- that's part of it.
But also we were technically capable of doing that in the sixties,
but it was an enormous amount of work to actually accomplish it.
Not unlike
run using certificates, say five or 10 years ago
where you could technically do this. But it was a monumental amount of work
and now
there are certain economic incentives that have lowered the cost of adoption.
Not unlike our private space program that we see now where essentially
we've got a bunch of billionaires racing each other to Mars.
And
I, I see that and,
and this kind of falls into that category where if this
is something that is the future and it might be,
I'm not gonna say it is or isn't it
is?
It's technically possible today, but at great cost and pain,
-- where
-- is
the
cheap? And
that's just it, right?
If this is the future in five or 10 years, this is going to be cheap and easy to do.
-- And so
-- again, there are,
there are already services that sort of do this, right?
Those cloud access security brokers,
right? That essentially act as a centralized point of
uh control for like all your cloud services, right? For your accounts and stuff.
Yeah, it, it's kind of a start and
this might be
something to start thinking about.
In fact, this is something I've been really sensitive to lately is
I'm starting to make an effort to detach myself from a physical machine
because that makes moving around when I travel, for example, a lot easier.
It makes even just like switching computers in the house easier, things like that.
And
I'm finding
it's pretty easy to do, you know, even, even three years ago, I think
I would have suffered trying to actually exist like this and now, I mean,
I keep most things in, in a Google Drive for example.
And it, it just works. It's no big deal and all the data is there.
I can access it easily wherever I'm at. It's,
it's fantastic, man.
Yeah. Well, I mean, I, I've already done that.
That's, that's, I hate to say it,
but that's one of the reasons I picked Apple products is because
how do I set up a new computer?
Like I, I basically bought one of my son's a new ipad this week.
And so I got his old ipad because it's a newer one than my ipad.
And so basically, all I had to do was factory wipe it
and turn it on and log into my icloud
account and, and then just wait
and then like 2030 minutes later,
it was my ipad.
And the only thing I had remained to do was, you know,
re enter all my passwords into my email accounts
and, and that's it. It's done. It's, this is now my ipad.
Um
And like at home, I'm down to, you know, two firewalls, one for each network link.
And then,
and those are like small hardware devices, you know, and then
I still have a file server just for hosting a ton of media because
I don't have a fast enough upload to like,
basically dump all the stuff into the cloud in a reasonable amount of time.
Otherwise, I, I honestly would
-- and I would get rid of my file server.
-- Did I tell you about my backup to S3?
It took literally two months to upload all the data.
Yeah, exactly.
So, you know, I just, I, I, but the thing is all the data I care about like is,
is backed up to the cloud automatically because it's, you know,
it's in my my documents directory or whatever that just automatically is
also replicated to all my machines. You know, so when I make a change,
even locally, it gets replicated to, you know, my other two
uh desktop,
I'm gonna last saw
us back in here.
So, but yeah, so back to the laptops, I think, I think what will happen is like,
for example, if you had a cloud based desktop, like a Citrix type environment,
you know, a lot of companies already do that because not only, I mean,
it's not a security thing,
it's just simply like we're not going to set up every single
desktop to run these apps because we'll just centrally manage it.
And so
the reality is, you know, you and I have both been on planes now where and,
and these are not like even first class nice, you know,
Dubai or what is it? Emirates Air. What's the nice one in the Middle East now?
Uh
Emirates
Airways, is it or whatever? You know, we're talking like, like Delta and Jet
like, you know, United
and the internet on those things is good enough that, you know,
you and I were talking, I was, I was actually, you know, working with github
and,
you know, uh
downloading and uploading data and, like, checking my email and, you know,
talking in real time to people, you know,
it works pretty well. I agree.
Yeah.
You know, so,
I mean, I don't know that a cloud based desktop maybe would have enough bandwidth.
I don't know. I mean, I'm guessing those things are pretty good with,
uh, compression and what not. But,
you know, that's the, be a
LA.
Yeah, that latency is the problem.
And so,
but what it boils down to though is an it department if all I had to deal with was like,
here's your tablet log into it.
Ok. We're done.
Right. As an it guy that, you know, I've had to support desktops in the past.
I, you know, my first, one of my first jobs was supporting Windows NT 3.51
and Windows 95 in a government office.
I got really good at reinstalling Windows 95 because there was,
that's how you fixed it.
You know, what's really funny is I remember when I was in college,
I think it was 95 or 98 was on the systems.
I forget which one it was.
But we had this system set up and I forget it was some product that, that they bought.
But basically every time you booted the machine,
it just re imaged the machine off the file server.
And so I, I forget what it was called.
Well, there was like a central file server with the machine images.
-- It actually was like ghosting it and redoing
-- it.
It wasn't ghost. It was
some like off brand but same basic idea
and, and yeah, essentially,
like every night we'd shut down all the computers because we knew in
the morning when we turn them back on they would just reimage themselves.
Like we didn't even care and let's face it back then too.
Like, there was no such thing really as security.
Like, if you wanted to become an admin it wasn't very hard to do.
Well, I remember, you know. Yeah, just all that stuff and, yeah.
And I mean,
back then it's funny because actually people started getting into the habit
of treating their fleets of machines as cattle and not pets.
That's
true.
Security was so bad and then security got a little better and we went back to pets.
Yeah. Exactly.
Um, yeah.
No, I very much try not to teach or to teach to treat my machines like pets because,
you know, at some point I am going to fold my laptop in half or sit on it or,
or my kids are gonna, you know, get juice into it or whatever.
Right.
And I don't wanna have to spend, like, 10 hours recreating my laptop.
-- It's true,
-- actually, you know, what I'm,
I'm doing that now is so you'll love this story.
My neighbor,
well, not my neighbor. It's my, the neighbor of my parents. Ok, calls me up yesterday
and first he calls and I was on the phone and I see this guy called and he's an,
an older gentleman will say.
And I look, and I'm like, all right, either something terrible has happened
or his computer is broken. Right. Right.
Right. And I'm like, I bet his computer is broken
and I call him back
and computer is broken
and then I'm, I'm talking to him. I'm like, so what's going on?
He said, I'm trying to get this stupid printer working
and, and he's like, I go, I went to their website
and now they're, uh, they're connected to my computer fixing it. And I said, what,
what, what I'm like, what, what did you do?
And then you see
the story, it gets better, it gets better. So, anyway, was it legit
or we'll get to that?
So, anyway, I'm like, what did you do?
He's like, I just, II, I typed in Canon printer in, in the, in the web browser.
And I'm like,
and where did you go? He's like, I went to Cannon printers.com.
And so I opened this website and it's like some,
basically, it, it's just a front for some spam operation thing where they, they,
they get you to pay him a couple of 100 bucks.
They could they, like, connect into your computer with one of those remote
access points
and then
they, like, mess it up and anyway, I'm talking to him and I'm like, what, what,
what's going on?
He's like, yeah, they're in it right now and I said, what are they doing?
And he's like, oh, I don't know, they're gonna,
they're gonna install some antivirus for me.
And they, and he, he's like, going through, I'm, like, just
unplug your internet.
All right, unplug your internet right now and just bring all of your stuff to my house
and in a couple of days I'll bring it back to you. Ok.
Because I'm like, I'm not even gonna try to talk to on the phone to pick,
I don't wanna go to his house because his computer is kind of
old and it's gonna take like two weeks to clean the freaking thing.
So, anyway, I have it now in the other room. Uh,
running Windows update still, which has been happening for like,
almost a day because there's so much crap.
And it's like,
oh, my goodness, it's,
it's mad
man.
II, I like two weeks ago, got my mom, uh,
she wanted to get a new printer because her existing printer is like dying.
So, yeah. Ok.
II, I found a, a reasonably priced color laser jet, you know, a little Samsung Joby.
And I, I also like Samsung because
they generally have not completely terrible drivers in software for their stuff,
like, say HP where you get a 600 megabyte blob
when all you want to do is like, print a picture. So anyways,
I'm like, whatever, I'm not gonna use the CD, I'm just gonna go to the website, right?
Because, well,
uh, you know, it'll be a bit faster and I'll get it up to date.
So I go to the website, you know, plug in the printer number, blah, blah, blah.
Ok, great. Download the thing,
start the install
and, uh, it's like, do you want to install the drivers? Yes, obviously.
Do you want to install the, uh, like add on admin package? I'm like, sure.
And it like,
installs the admin package and then it's like installing drivers and it just
times out. Basically it sits there for like 5, 10 minutes and I kill it.
I do that like 23 times.
Yeah, the drivers from the Samsung website won't install, just flat out,
won't install.
So I use the CD,
the printer came with and the drivers install and just work perfectly.
But it's like,
you know, how is a normal person supposed to deal with this crap?
There's like no hope, man. I, I know what you mean.
Well, in fact, funny enough, I have a Samsung color laser jet printer and it's,
it's amazing.
But,
yeah, getting like getting their drivers to work was a pain.
So, you know what I did is I,
I hooked it up to my file server in the
basement and it just has like a postscript interface now
and I just installed generic postscript drivers and
all the machines and they print just fine.
Yeah. II, I would not want to walk somebody through that
-- and
-- that's just it. Right.
I wouldn't dream of expecting anyone but me to set something up like this. It's,
uh,
everything sucks. Anyway, speaking of everything sucks.
-- Uh, let's move on to our next story we want to talk about which
-- is 18
-- holes in them.
-- How exciting is that?
-- Well, it's, I'm not at all surprised because,
-- you know,
the story.
So basically a little
bit of back story ATM S fundamentally are a small
computer running in the past OS two and now usually windows
hooked up to a bunch of, you know, like a money counter, a money dispenser,
you know, the, the thing that, you know,
takes a picture of your checks when you show a check into it or whatever, you know,
just basically a
bunch of USB peripherals really
or, you know, serial line peripherals even.
Um, so nothing, you know, it's basically just,
it's like a cash register point of sale system basically
really. It's nothing, it's not like some
super hardened, you know, system even software wise or whatever.
And so the deal is, um,
uh, like most computers, you know, if you can, like, talk to the computer directly,
you can ask it to do things like give me all your twenties.
-- But hey, these things are like in a physically secured case,
-- right?
You think so?
Because they're like
a
lot of them are
like when I go to the bank, the ATM there is,
it's pretty hardcore man.
However, if you go to the gas station
that ATM is slightly less hardcore and you can
see like the phone line draped over the lights,
you know, over to the other side.
The other problem is
like USB, for example, has no concept of security.
-- Right. Right.
-- The USB protocol has no concept of security.
So
it wasn't even USB, was it? It was,
-- I think,
-- yeah, exactly.
It was, it was because, you know, all that old money, like dispensers and stuff.
Yeah, they're cereal because why not?
And so basically the deal is you drill a hole in the ATM, stick a wire in
and, you know,
we connect
it up to the s
and
sending commands.
There's a port where they're,
they're drilling the hole and they're plugging in a serial cable essentially
is what's happened
because I was reading one where they actually were just, like,
basically shoving their own wires into the serial thing.
That could be, that could be,
we'll assume there's some sort of port because plugging wire would
have
a
right.
-- Sure.
-- There's, you know,
they're hooking up one computer up to another computer or serial
and then telling it to give them all the money.
Right. I mean, that's basically what's happening.
Yeah.
Yeah. And so, I mean, like, I think you pointed out that,
you know, uh, these things were really not designed with security in mind so much as,
like, well, it's sitting in a safe, you know, it's sitting in a physically safe,
secure process with people who can sort of keep an eye on it.
So, you know, hopefully if somebody goes up to it with like a power drill and some,
you know, box of tools, they're gonna be like,
-- you don't look like Bob the repairman.
-- Well, I can see a couple of angles here.
So first of all,
someone designing this gear is probably not taking into account
somebody attacking it in that manner, right?
They're probably thinking direct theft of the machine.
So they make it heavy and they lock it down, you know, they, they chain it to things,
whatever
and you've got instances of people kind of hacking in remotely.
But I think
the idea is there's a lock on the door
and people don't have access to the actual hardware.
And it's also quite likely that when it was designed a million years ago,
these devices were made of metal,
whereas now they're all plastic. In fact, you know what this reminds me of is,
do you remember what people used to call the old pay phones back in the day?
The fortress phones. I
may have seen a few of them disassembled in various hacker cons and yeah,
those things were
the amount of metal in those things were,
it was huge. Seriously.
Like you weren't getting in unless you physically remove the phone
and you had a long time to work on it.
Right. And, and that's the intent.
The intent wasn't to make it Impenetrable. It's to make it.
So it's not worth the, like, 20 bucks and quarters inside the thing.
See, and here's so I just pulled up the Wikipedia page for ATM security.
Here's the thing.
So they talk about security measures of ATM S.
They talk about online pin validation, offline pin validation, you know,
pin validation for blah, blah, blah,
um
the hardware security module and the encryption.
But the thing is that all ignores the fact that for example,
if the cash dispenser talks, you know, is talked to over a serial line
and you can inject serial commands
unless that, you know, uh cash module is smart enough to like,
use an encrypted protocol which let's face
-- it.
-- It's
not,
it's absolutely not.
You know, you can just basically tell the cash dispenser politely to like,
give me all your money,
all your, all your money. I belong to.
I know what happened in one case where, um and there's been many articles, you know,
where like some kids or somebody basically goes up to an ATM and uses the default,
you know, service code of like, you know, 22894 or whatever the heck it is.
And, you know, and it puts the machine into, like, maintenance mode and they can,
like, monkey around with it.
And what one enterprising person figured out was they,
they would have it swap the two money, uh, bins
and it was like fives and twenties and they
would swap it and then withdraw money and get,
like, four times as much.
You
sure. Right.
Um, because I know there's ATM S locally they'll dispense, you know, tens,
twenties and fifties and yeah, you swap the tens and fifties in the machine,
like mentally and like
that's a, that's a pretty decent payout.
Nice. Well, except, of course they know
you took it out.
So
even, even if they can't prove you did it, you're
gonna
ask for their money
when you're doing that,
somebody
smart enough to do that is typically smart enough to also just
somebody and like,
you know, they,
they recently raided a house, uh, in Edmonton here,
um, and arrested a bunch of people and they found
thousands of identities in the house and paperwork, stolen mail
the whole nine yards. Like these people were just,
you know,
you know, I mean, for what it's worth though, in my brain,
this seems incredibly excessive is first hacking the ATM
and then using stolen identities. It's just,
if you have access to the identities, you're just gonna, you know, yank
tons of money using the 45 stolen identities. You have, you're not gonna hack an ATM.
Well, alternatively, there are ATM S with maintenance modes that do involve like
there are
a maintenance mode that lets you withdraw all the cash is a,
that's a broken ATM.
Well, you need to like, have it, be able to, you know,
make sure the cash dispensing mechanism works
without hooking it up to an account because, you know,
obviously they're not gonna want to have to like, have the
guy have a bank account with $1000 in it so he can dispense cash at an ATM.
And then at the end of the day, reconcile it. Right.
They're just gonna be like the manufacturers just gonna,
you know, here's the magic
code to make it work.
I
-- know how software gets built.
-- You're right, you're right. I know. I know. All right.
So anyway, ATM S being stolen.
Uh,
yeah.
Well, and what's happened locally, I mean, is people,
especially in earlier area is just use a front,
-- a stolen front end loader typically or a stolen pickup truck,
-- right?
Put a chain around it and just take off with the ATM. And then,
you know,
well, I mean,
that's probably more work than what these guys are doing with their computer,
but it also you, these are smart cookies obviously if they're doing it.
So,
yeah,
driving a front end loader into an empty gas station
and taking off with the ATM is not rocket science,
-- but you do need a front loader, which is not the easiest thing to come by.
-- Uh,
-- I'm sure
-- even,
even stealing a front loader cart isn't going to be a trivial task.
No. Well, you break into where the keys are stored on the construction site
-- and,
ok, so here's one of the problems with a plausible attack is
how many ans do you need to describe it?
And we're at about three at this point for your attack.
Whereas these guys, you just need a drill in a computer and you're good to go.
But
you also need a level of expertise,
which is
going to,
that is true. That is true. But even then, I mean, how
much, how much money are in these?
ATM si mean, I think a couple of $1000 at the most, right.
You're, these are people that I would think
they could apply their skills in a non
nefarious way and probably make way more money.
I doubt that because how are they going to apply these skills to make money,
you pen
test
or become a great security researcher?
Yeah.
But the problem is these people are typically not living a lifestyle that involves,
you know, regular hours and actually,
you know, being reliable.
Right.
That's one of the things I've discovered with
because that's something that keeps coming up is,
oh, you know, this guy is a great hacker.
He should be hired by the security companies.
And I'm like, well, maybe because you know,
I've met a lot of really great security researchers who are, like,
awesome at security research,
but they really can't hold down a day job.
Yeah, that could be
-- part of it is just they get bored
-- or
they want to do what they want to do,
you know?
All right. Anyway, anyway. All right. So,
stealing from ATMs,
there are atms that can hold up to 200 grand.
That's solid man.
That's,
uh, I'm not advocating robbing ATM S but like 200 grand.
Oh, no, no, no, sorry. That was a series of robberies that made off with 200 grand.
Most machines contain less than 10 grand.
That seems reasonable to me because it seems
really dangerous to really load these suckers up
like a
major, like an ATM in a bank at a major, you know,
that's totally different. And
-- that's not what this is. I suspect this is going to be like
-- gas gas stations.
Yep. Yep. Exactly.
-- Well, and
-- there was that ATM fraud ring in, what was it?
I want to say, Malaysia or whatever that, you know,
withdrew like 20 some million dollars in a half hour period.
A few weeks ago,
man. We got trace that down. But, yeah, I mean, like, like, so these are,
I mean, that, that is a sophisticated attack.
I mean, just getting that many people on the, you know,
to get their watches synchronized alone is a,
well, you've tried scheduling meetings with 20 people.
Yeah.
Well, yeah, it's,
it's impossible.
-- I wonder does the underworld use like Google calendar? I wonder, like, I
-- bet they do.
I, I think these guys use typical business tools way more than people think
it's,
well, let's face it too. They're running a business.
It might not be a legitimate business, but they're running a business.
This is true.
-- All right, let's, let's keep going, man. We all
-- right. You wanna talk?
Uh Well, this is something I really liked. Uh
the Japanese rail safety thing.
-- That is awesome, man. I really like that story.
-- So OK, I can't remember the name of it.
Hang on a second. Let me pull up the uh
-- uh does it have a name? I'm sure it does.
-- Yeah, there's like a Japanese name for it.
So basically the idea is, is that,
you know, when you have people doing somewhat routine tasks, they tend to, you know,
get bored or skip them or do them improperly, right?
Cause you know, humans are human
really.
And the problem is though is when it's like part of a safety system like like trains,
you know, you, you skip a step or two, somebody else skips a step or two.
And then the third guy who was supposed to just absolutely make sure
nobody's like on the tracks when the train pulls into the station,
you know, decides to go to the bathroom instead of doing his job.
And you know, some poor guy gets smooshed by a train or whatever
or
derailing whatever. I found the name. It's called uh
Shish
Shisha
Kenko S A
Isa Kanko. So for any Japanese people listening, I
for
horribly mispronouncing
it,
it's pointing and calling.
So for example, when the guy has to check the speed of the train rather than, you know,
like he has a check to say like check the speed of the train,
make sure it's like whatever the speed should be.
He actually not only calls out what the speed should be like,
say 80 kilometers an hour, but he points at the gauge,
right? And they showed a guy, uh
I think a station master anyways, a guy who on the side of the, of the um the platform,
you know, checking
the tracks to make sure they're clear before the train comes into the station.
And he like,
looks up and down the tracks and like swings his hand and follows his finger,
right.
Which, and I've, you know, it's so it
-- apparently reduced their human error rate by 85%.
-- I totally believe that, you know,
and what really gets me though is so
uh somebody from the uh from the New York mt A went and saw this and was like,
this is awesome.
Brought it, tried to bring it back to New York and it's like
the American workers didn't really want to do it because they felt it was like,
silly or something.
And, and it's funny because the Japanese response is, this is not silly.
This is like safety. So, of course you would, would, you would do it.
And as an infosec guy, I'm like, if it reduces error rates by 85% and is like simple,
like,
oh yeah, we're doing it.
I, well, yeah, you say that except
infosec is like a total disaster.
-- We
-- don't have.
And part of the problem though is we don't have reproducibility and we don't have,
I mean, let's face it.
What this really is is pointing and saying
you now have essentially triple redundancy error checking.
That's what it is,
right?
And like in our case for security, we have uh like zero error checking in most cases.
So, so II I get this right.
I can see a couple of huge advantages to this is first of all,
you have the muscle memory aspect of doing something where
if you, if you do a certain thing like as a human
over and over again, you get kind of the muscle memory.
So you if you do one thing, you expect to do another thing after that.
And so obviously, if it's time to check the, the speed
and you point
you get that
it,
it's just something that you keep doing
automatically without even thinking about after a
while and then obviously speaking it as
well just helps to reinforce what you're doing
because like you said, humans suck at doing things that are boring and routine.
-- It,
-- it's kind of
like when I go to lock the, when I go to make sure the doors are locked at night,
I actually go up to the door and
even if it is locked,
I do exactly the same thing because,
yeah.
Yeah, I've,
I've had many instances where I thought it was locked or I forgot whatever.
Right. And, yeah, absolutely. I totally get this man.
It's,
I, you know what else?
I'm, I'm really sensitive to about this is I think about people,
I used to know whose job was reading I DS logs,
right? And that's something like literally after five minutes you're worthless.
-- It's
-- more like a punishment than
a
-- job.
-- It was a job, it was a real job. It was,
it was
people
and, and right, like this is totally one of those things like
not that I'm advocating.
You should let people look at your logs point at them and then read them or something.
But you know, it's by,
by not just doing the same repetitive task over and
over again and adding in a little bit of change.
You, you don't fall into that trap of just blur, right? This, this is awesome, man.
I love this and,
and part of me has been thinking now, like, how can infosec do something like this
in theory? We are sort of, you know, code reviews, right?
You can't check your code in until it undergoes a code review by a second person.
But like how many of those are really actually
reading the code versus like skimming it and clicking?
Ok, because they just
are hungry and want to go eat lunch.
-- I'm sure you get plenty of that. It's maybe, maybe I should point at the
-- code by
definition, all these companies that do code reviews and still have CV ES like,
obviously it's not 100%.
And
my,
my
question would be well and do does, here's my one thought,
does anybody actually keep actual proper statistics?
Like, for example, do they have a code review process that also involves, you know,
I found an actual flaw in the code review.
So I'm gonna file a bug and then we'll close it
as fixed and we'll actually track it as a security issue
and the answer
is
no,
-- nobody
-- does
-- too
much.
You know, we might be able to do this because with
you can download
various information
and we could do some analysis of that,
but you'd have to have somebody basically audit, not just the code,
but audit all the commits
the level of expertise and effort involved in that.
-- You know, I'm going to think about this. I bet we could do this stupid
-- question.
Could something like co
-- scanner do this?
-- I know I'm more thinking we could we to download the data,
we would need a way to identify a CV E to a specific patch
which kids a little, it's not impossible.
But I'm talking about the things where the
code commit actually caught a security flaw.
I
see what you're saying.
And then they were like, oh your, your, your code commit is bad, go fix it
-- and they come back with a fixed one. How often does that happen?
-- I bet. Not very often.
Well, well, let's face it too. How many, how many security reviewers are security?
I'm sorry, how many code reviewers are security people?
I bet the number is very low.
Well, in theory, I mean, it should be about code correctness because in theory,
if the code is correct and of course,
this also assumes that like the logic and the intent of the code is correct, right?
Because I've seen code that's correct, but it implemented like the wrong thing
and
you know, all the time
or like, you know, like the downgrade specification in in you know, very soon
description protocols where it's like we've now discovered like, yeah, we're,
we're removing that in TLS 1.3 because like downloading is a bad idea.
It's a terrible idea.
-- I know
-- but you know,
from a backwards compatibility and like making all this junk work together.
Yeah. No, it made sense
-- back in the day.
-- Backwards compatibility is terrible.
Yeah,
so,
well, I mean, speaking of TL so I just ran into something today that's kind of cute,
but
I think basically useless.
Um So the idea is you have certificate,
authorities who issue certificates and some of them
have a bad habit of issuing certificates to
some people who are, maybe not who they say they are.
-- All of
-- them not saying any names like
Symantec, like
all of them.
It's not just them, they just
repeatedly. This is like, I love it when someone gets caught cheating in sports.
It's like, no, they all do it. It's like this guy just got caught, you know.
Um, so anyways, there's this, uh, uh,
this thing called DNS certificate Authority Authorization.
And the idea is you have a record called CAA
the certificate, authority authorization.
And it essentially contains information on a list of,
and
-- this
-- is
your
DN,
your DNS.
Yeah, for like,
do or whatever.
And so the idea being that you list,
which CAS are allowed to assign certificates for you.
So, like, lets and crypt.org or
I guess,
verisign.com or whatever,
um, what they're sort of, uh, allowed to, like, can they, uh, issue for, like,
just the specific name or can they, like, issue wild card certificates?
Right. Because, you know, one challenge is if, you know,
you get a wild card certificate, then you can do whatever you want.
And some people don't want any wild card
certificates being associated with their domain at all,
even legitimately
because it
just,
it, problems.
Here's what makes this hilarious.
I bet if you went to any medium to large sized organization
and said,
how many certificates
do you have?
They would be off by a magnitude
because they have no idea.
Yeah. Well, I mean, with the waste cert,
well, so for even
so for domain validated certificates, yeah.
Anybody who controls that domain can get a certificate.
Right.
Because you, you just do an email check or you do a, a
DNS based check or whatever and boom, you know, you, you got a certificate,
um even something like extended validation.
I mean, you're just submitting business records and stuff and I mean,
I, yeah, a large company isn't gonna have like a single point who can only do that?
Like anybody can get a hold of those, you know,
what is it done in Bradstreet or whatever,
you know, agency they're getting the records from.
But what makes it even more hilarious and terrible
is that for this to actually work every single certificate
authority would have to check for this record every
single time they issue a certificate to a domain?
That's true, I suppose
because
we have it
well, and then, then,
then there's the question of does the record not
exist or are we being man in the middle?
Right. So,
so for now,
so that means you need DNS Sec to get a signed nex domain saying, oh no,
there is legitimately no record of this.
Cool. Right. Let's go.
Um
And then the best part too is uh, so currently of the, apparently Alexa
top 1 million websites. 300 of them have this record.
A CAA record.
Yeah.
Really?
Well, but, I mean, you know, because there's a couple of crazy people in there, like,
I mean, look at the, look at the HSTS white list.
Right. And there's people like me in there from, like, years ago. Right.
There's always a bunch of crazies.
Um,
and so, um,
you know, the problem is though, is that,
uh,
some C A support this and there's a list here. But it's like, uh, it's like a dozen
and here's the best part.
It's like, we don't even know globally how many certificate authorities there are.
Well, no, because for example,
I use cheap SSL s.com when I have to buy wild card certificates
because they're well cheap and they sell SSL certificates cheap SSL S,
you know,
and they're terrible and they use like Godaddy
and Komodo and a bunch of other certificates.
So they, they don't have their own certificate to the best of my knowledge.
They piggyback on all these other providers
and, you know, so is cheap. SSL S AC A Well,
yes. Yes. And are they using CAS that check C A records?
Well, I think some of them do and
do all of them. I don't know.
So, like if you look at all the root cas,
all the root CAS would have to be doing this and there's like, what, 200 of them
in your browser.
Uh
-- Yeah, there's a lot
-- more than 100 and,
and, oh,
man, the ca, I guess here's the thing. I always come back to
the C A model is a disaster
but the world is functioning
so
well. I think it's terrible because I kind of understand how it works.
Like, fundamentally at the end of the day
it's basically doing what it's supposed to do.
Right.
And
it,
you
-- know what it's supposed to
-- do
whatever the world works. Kurt, you can go to Amazon and buy stuff.
I'm
not
NTCA. I think the whole thing is a train wreck of,
you know, amazing proportions. But fundamentally, it's,
it's,
I, I'm just not really clear on what I mean,
I think we need to have this stuff encrypted and we need to have this to some level of,
you know, validation.
You know what this is?
Did you ever see the episode of The Simpsons where Mr Burns had like every disease,
which is why he wasn't dead.
Right. That's what this is.
Everything that could be wrong is wrong,
but it works because everything is so broken all at the same time.
And like, that's all I keep thinking of is CAS is.
But
if any security person, like sat down and wrote down how the C A system works today,
we'd be like, there's no way this could work.
There's no
way
I wrote,
I wrote an article about this back in like 2001, you know,
the death of SSL and SSH and I got death threats
uh for it. Um It was when D sniff came out right back in the day. Remember D Sniff.
Uh Anyways,
one of the Netscape engineers emailed me.
He was like, yeah, no, like if we had half a clue that this thing would have, you know,
been used the way it was, we would not have designed it this way because we literally,
our mandate was to make it safe to use credit cards online.
That was it,
right.
And then now TLS and SSL is like, well, if you have to encrypt on the wire,
that's how you do it,
you know.
And so there's like fundamental design choices that were made that are just not
so good anymore.
2530 years later, like who knew 30 year old design choices, you know,
sometimes bite you in the butt.
Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah,
-- it's,
-- you know, and
so, I mean, it's,
it's definitely better than just having everything clear text and like,
especially now with Wi Fi networks
like good Lord, you know,
well, that kind of brings up to an issue.
We didn't put on the show notes,
but the whole apparently so um as well for those
of you who live in caves with slow internet,
um your ISP if you're in the US is now able to sell your information,
you like browsing history and stuff.
And so this has led
to a plethora of fake VPN stuff.
The bad guys
on
-- there.
-- It's not,
I think because in fact, there was a report came out,
man, when was this?
This was a couple of months ago talking about all the
Android VPN apps and a significant number of them were fake.
-- You know, it's,
-- I
mean, I was talking about VPN providers but
no, no, I know same deal though. I mean, it's basically the same idea. Right.
Where these, well, it's meant to be like,
download this VPN app and we'll secure all your traffic using our secure VPN server.
Right?
And of course,
it doesn't do anything and they charge you like five bucks or whatever and,
and it's not like most people have no way to verify this stuff.
-- So, how would they,
-- well, yeah, you'd have to be using like Wi Fi and sniffing it,
which
it's,
you know,
well, but here's ok. So here's the thing, right? We tie this back to the ATM story is,
criminals are very opportunistic.
And if we look at it from a very business point of view,
there is a problem
that needs a solution
be it.
People are scared their ISP is going to sell their data,
which I'm sure they were doing anyway, just calling it something else, whatever
-- they were doing,
-- it aggregated
in.
-- Yeah, I know. I mean,
-- how do you think we get traffic data
from
cell
phone?
I know. I know. But anyway. Anyway,
so
people are, are worried, they, they hear about VPN S,
they read about it in the newspaper or whatever the neighbor kid told them.
Now, they, they, they probably just type in, like VPN service into Google
and they're gonna click the first link. It's like the,
my,
my parents' neighbor who typed in, you know,
cannon printers.com that I'll go there.
That looks neat.
And like,
what's the
poor guy supposed to search for? And cannon
printers.com
looks legit. I mean, how are you supposed to do?
But to him it looks legit.
All right, maybe whatever, whatever the point being,
-- these people, I've
-- actually got worse news for you.
So I have a block running but I typed in VPN link in Google.
First result is the Wikipedia entry followed by a link to open VPN,
followed by how to connect to a VPN Windows, followed by a
VPN at us. Cd.edu.
Like how to
follow by private internet access, anonymous VPN service from the leaders.
So it's just like somebody normal types this in and
they're gonna have to go to the ads because
the actual links that Google is finding me are,
you know, they click on open vpn.net and they're gonna get
um, something that makes no sense to them. Really?
I know, I mean, oh, open VPN, like, I love it to death, but it's
a normal person. Probably can't even
understand what it's supposed to be.
The,
a lot of the providers now have an installer wrapped
around it and they use like certificate based authentication.
So they wrap the installer. You get your cert boom, it just works.
Yep.
Yep. You know,
so there is some hope but the problem is how do you know you're using a legit?
Like, and, and for you and I, why,
why do we say open vpn.net is legitimate
and like super open vpn.ru is not legitimate?
You know what I mean? Like, seriously, right? Like
the only reason I'm saying open VPN is legit is because it's got that like open
open VPN logo, which is pretty and I've seen it before.
We know the people who work on this stuff. I mean,
that's how
we know it's
open VPN. This is open VPN, the service,
there's
open,
what is this
open VPN technologies? Inc
VPN
dot
So there's the, there's the open source software like which is open vpn.org.
There's open vpn.net, which is
one of the few times I've seen a person using the.net legit.
See
what this is
interesting.
I, I have never noticed this before. I would assume this is dodgy for what it's worth.
-- I would not trust this in a million years.
-- Well, I don't know who these people are.
They, they seem to be affiliated with Open VPN.
They stole the logo.
I,
I
have no
idea. I would assume they stole the logo. I would not trust this.
-- I think
-- they're legit, but I seem to remember looking into them a while back.
But anyways, that's the point.
We're security researchers who, like,
actually have talked to the people who work on open VPN.
I don't even know.
I
would not trust this.
Well, who would you trust then? Right.
I trust I predator who are the Pirate Bay guys that
run the VPN because I'm confident if anyone's gonna give the f
to the authorities, like it's those guys
that's fair
and, and in all seriousness, I would
be very, I,
I'm very hesitant to trust VPN providers because I know the vast majority of them.
Let's face it. If the n
he shows up at their door, they're gonna be like, do whatever you want,
just don't arrest me.
Right? Like that's the reality of it. And,
and granted,
in my case that that isn't really a threat I'm concerned about,
but you get the idea is,
well, I've always wondered, you know, are these VPN providers, for example,
just opportunistically sniffing on encrypted web traffic looking for
-- sensitive stuff.
-- I'm sure some are, I'm sure.
Well, I'm sure some of them mine your data and they sell it
right.
Like I have no doubt that is happening in,
in some of those instances and there is no way
you will know.
Yeah, I think fundamentally what has to happen is we have to,
as much as I had to say is we have to get, you know,
everybody has to get certificates and we have to
encrypt all the traffic as much as possible because
let's face it like the, the pretty much all the network traffic now is over is the web,
there's a
-- bunch of other
-- protocols, but basically it's the web.
That's how people interact with
-- stuff.
-- It's beyond court, man.
I mean,
I think Google has the right view here of that
zero trust networking where you cannot trust the network.
Even if you own the piece of wire running between the gears,
you can't trust it, just don't do it, encrypt it all. It's the only way to go, man.
I, I agree
100%. And
granted that's easy to say because it's not
something that's going to just magically happen.
-- At
-- least it's possible now, like, you know, all the CP US have AES, you know, crypto
capabilities where, you know, back in the day, remember like Aes,
you were lucky to get a couple of megabits.
Do you remember all the crypto
accelerators that used to be able to get?
They were terrible.
They were super expensive and they all suck too like they,
they were hard to use and they were, they were super fragile and, and they,
they never worked, right.
But
yeah,
to your
stuff, I mean,
you know, f five used to be able to charge whatever the heck they wanted,
right? Because what else were you going to do?
Like, literally you have no choice unless you were some crazy guy who like,
set up a bunch of
PC,
you know, like
that
like that around here.
Yeah, I
know,
man. I know.
Although I must admit that these, this stuff is super cool.
I remember playing with some of this gear once and,
and doing like various tests where you do, you know,
like as many connections as fast as you could
to,
to, you know, an SS A, it was SSL back then and,
and SSL enabled web server and like you turn it off and you'd get, you know, maybe,
maybe a couple of 1000 if you were lucky and you turn that sucker on and it was like the,
the machine sending the request, couldn't send them fast enough.
It was amazing.
Yeah. No, it's, uh, the times are changing. I mean, it's, that's
what really gets me now is, you know,
we're at the point where like a standard one U
rack mount can easily saturate 10 or 40 gigabytes.
No problem.
Yeah. Yeah.
Well, you know, I guess part of it too, this comes back to the whole space race concept
from way back when is just because you're technically
able to do something doesn't mean it's economically viable.
And I think
encrypting
encrypting all of your traffic
was not a, a, you could do it say 10 or 15, even 20 years ago,
but it wasn't really economically viable.
Whereas today, like,
we're pretty close, man, we're really close.
Honestly,
we're at the point where it's just the
whole certificate management thing is such a hairball.
Yeah. But
there's,
I'm
confident it's going to get fixed because I
-- think there's huge market opportunity for that
-- now.
Well, no, the point is we're past the hardware issue.
That's right. And you can't like the hardware issue is the hardware issue.
Like, if your, if your system can only encrypt data at like 10 megabits per second,
that's it. You're stuck with that.
But, you know, as long, like now that we have AES and all the CP US,
we can encrypt as much data and decrypt it as much as we want.
You just have to handle all the keys and that, you know,
there's management and pain in that and yeah, but we're getting better, you know,
-- it's,
-- it's getting there, it's getting there.
All right, man, I think we should call this one and we should assign some homework.
Yes.
So as any of you paying attention, no,
this is episode 41 of the open source security podcast.
-- The next episode is going to be number 42. And why is the number 42 special
-- Kurt?
Because it's the answer to life, the universe and everything.
-- That's right.
-- And,
and also all of our info.
That's right.
So initially we thought, oh, let,
let's review the security of the Hitchhiker's guide to the Galaxy
book and then books are hard to read and they're big.
So we thought that. That's a lot of work.
So, yes, that's right. Reading's hard. Everybody, kids stay in school.
So anyway, what we thought would be really fun to do is we're going to go through
the hitchhiker's guide to the Galaxy movie from 2005
and kind of review the security themes and concepts from
that and just have some fun in episode 42.
And so
you won't have to watch it if you've never seen it before.
We will totally spoil it for you though. I'm not gonna lie,
-- but it was
-- surprisingly not terrible.
I will say like, because, and I've seen, you know,
the BBC series and I've seen the other stuff.
I thought it was, it maintained the spirit and culture of it reasonably well.
I don't know, I didn't think I thought it was ok, but
I'll argue about that next week.
Uh So anyway, if you'd like, uh give it a watch, so you're, it's fresh in your mind.
So as we go through all the silliness of it,
you know, exactly what we're talking about. So,
yeah, I'm, I'm super excited. I can't wait. So.
All right, let's, let's take it home folks. Thank you for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com for the show notes.
We've got the Pound Os S Podcast, Twitter. Hashtag you can use to hit us up.
We've got links on the uh, website to a Facebook group.
You're welcome to join and chat with us
and, yeah, nothing else. Thank you very much for listening. Kurt.
You have a fabulous rest of your day.
-- You too. Enjoy the spring.
-- Yes, spring, thank goodness, it finally came.
I know.