Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 101 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime Josh Pressers.
So it's new man.
My little part of the world is no longer on danger of catching fire.
So we can now have campfires
and I'm so happy.
Yeah, we had a beau
we had like literally the best May long weekend we've had in years and
fire band because it's been so dry and hot for like a month.
Oh, I got you. I got you.
It happens,
-- but we had rain so now we can set things on fire safely.
-- Sweet
and exciting.
Life is good.
So this week
the world isn't on fire that much.
There's not anything super crazy going on, which is
nice.
I don't know what to say.
Well, I mean, there are super crazy things going on as usual in the world.
Uh for example, the whole tariff war thing, but I don't want to get into that because
you know, you bring up softwood lumber with Canadian and we just get ornery
and uh
OK, it's a thing. Hey,
dude,
some of my earliest childhood memories are hearing
about softwood lumber disputes on the news,
watching the news with my dad in the evening.
I feel bad for you in your childhood.
But uh yeah, no one thing that was interesting though is,
is this whole electric scooter thing?
Those are wild man. So I remember when I was out in San Francisco at RS A,
they were everywhere and at first I was like,
who are these people who are leaving these scooters all over the place?
And then after about a day, I realized this is like a rental type thing
and, and,
but, right, I mean, look, if you're in a new place and you see, like, scooters,
you're gonna think who left their scooter here?
Why is no one stealing it?
Well, yeah, it's like, I mean, city bikes, I get, you know, they, but they get, like,
locked up and stuff and they have, like, the little,
a lot of them have like that wheel lock thing that doesn't disengage until you, like,
hire the bike.
Does it work? Do the scooters do that?
No, they're just like sitting there.
I, I don't, I assume they, they don't work in some manner until you use your app to
get
-- the electric
-- assist.
Well,
I'm certain you don't get the app but I also have
a suspicion that they may have a break or something.
I didn't actually touch one.
I should have, I should have, I wish I would have known more about it.
I would have given it a go
although, although they were very annoying, but that's kind of another story.
Well, and, and that's,
it's funny you mentioned that because actually I just had this talk with my parents.
My parents no longer like walking in the, in Edmonton here.
We have a beautiful river valley with these like really nice paved trails
that are for cyclists and, you know, roller bladers and, and people walking
and, um,
my parents no longer like walking on them because
the problem is you have so many different um,
speeds of traffic, right?
You have people on bicycles that are just
like going leisurely with their little kids,
you know,
and then you have like some pretty hardcore cyclists that are doing like,
you know, 20 kilometers an hour
I
hate
and
yeah, you know, my parents don't want to get clobbered,
right. So, you know,
um, they no longer walk in those places and,
and, you know, that's something I've really noticed like
at the mall. Oh,
the tourists, because the tourists walk slow and want to look at everything, right?
I, the only reason I go to the mall is I have like, things to do a mission to accomplish,
you know,
get some fro
yo and a, and a new device at the Apple store.
Oh my God. I just want to run over them.
-- You know,
-- you have, you have like a problem with tourists at your mall
and
it used to be the world's largest mall and it's still a major tourist attraction.
Oh, I see. I see.
You know, it's,
I didn't realize that all I've ever heard about is the Mall of America.
The mall of America is bigger. But my understanding is West
Mall has better attractions. Like, it has a water park with a wave pool.
It's got, you know, like a whole bunch of theaters. It's got the hotel, it's got,
um, the amusement park with the indoor roller coaster and all that stuff.
Um, you know, too many golf courses, indoor cart racing.
Now, I want to come and see this mall.
Yeah, it's actually, I mean, as malls go it's, you know,
I just, I personally hate it because, you know, it's always full of people.
Right. And people are the problem as we know.
So, anyway, you talk of the
bicycle
and that's a real problem, right. Traditionally on,
on, uh, large,
you know, in large urban environments on the sidewalks, you have people walking
and that's it.
And, and especially in denser places like San Francisco and New York City.
You, that's it because, like, you,
you physically could not ride a bicycle there if you wanted to
right there just is not enough room and more
to the point you'd have to go at walking speed
because you can't even get out of people. Right.
Whereas, like,
say here in Edmonton we have vastly fewer pedestrians and a
lot of people ride their bikes on the sidewalks which,
as a pedestrian, I absolutely abhor and hate, but as a cyclist. Yeah.
No, I have like, a dividend, my chin from a Volvo.
So I totally get, wanted to ride on the sidewalk.
You know, I got clipped by a car when I was a kid
riding, uh, to home from school one day.
Yeah.
And so, yeah.
No, I get it, you know, because that's, well,
like anybody who drives on the highway and comes up on somebody doing like 20 miles
an hour under the speed limit or 20 miles an hour over the speed limit,
like that is insanely dangerous.
Like people who merge at
not highway speeds,
I, I
think that should be pretty much an automatic suspension of their license
-- because no, it's really
-- dangerous.
It is, it really is,
you know.
Um, and so, you know, now you're creating that problem, like sidewalks,
traditionally you had people walking and granted some people walk slow or worse.
You had like three or four people walking abreast of each other
again.
Uh The, you know,
it's funny because if you Google on Reddit for those comments around that,
there's quite a lot of rage around those people,
you know, that like form like a rolling roadblock down the side.
I mean, it's not rage inducing but I do find it annoying. Yes.
But, um,
but now the problem is, yeah, you add these electric scooters,
which are going quite a bit faster and more to the point.
I feel like these people didn't take a training course.
You know,
and, and see that's the thing I was thinking about, like, the thing with, um,
oh, what the heck,
what's the two wheeled one that was supposed to change the world in the
se the se,
yeah,
I remember that thing was supposed to be like a game changer and world transport
and even the segue takes some skill to ride.
Like there are some pretty funny youtube videos of people on those things.
-- Just, you
-- know, I've never been on one
part of
he wants to and part of me is like, I just don't care.
Honestly, the,
the thing I can most liken it to is like riding a well trained horse because
it's not like I'm, you know, you've ridden a bicycle, you've done roller skating,
right?
They're just a machine that doesn't care.
Like if you want to lean to the left and fall over, cool. You do that
right? Like the bicycle doesn't care.
But on the segway, like you start to lean forward and it kind of comes up under you,
you know, so you don't fall on your face, right?
It starts moving forward. Like when you lean forwards, you start to fall forwards,
the segway moves forward.
So you don't fall, you know, you lean backwards to break it,
it breaks and comes back under you So it's,
it's like I said, the closest thing I,
I would compare it to is like being on a horse where, you know, the horse,
like a well trained horse.
Mind, you
will like, move under you to like, keep you on its back
if you start to fall off or start to with it a bit. You know what I mean?
And, and for a machine to do that is I, I found it quite unsettling, like,
because it's just something
-- I've literally never experienced before.
-- Right.
Well, in, in the advantage to a horse is a horse will avoid obstacles.
I
assume a
segue.
Will you say that? But not always some horses are dumb.
Well, ok, in, in there's dumb people, all the segues are dumb.
Yeah, exactly.
Yeah, they don't have like the little obstacle avoidance,
beeper thing or whatever.
Um
But yeah, so that's, that's, that's the problem, right?
Is these electric scooters, I think kind of hit that
mediums of, they're easy enough for pretty much anybody to ride because you,
you really only have to be able to balance left and right.
Like you don't really have to balance forwards and backwards as well.
So
most people can walk without falling over.
So most people have that left to right balance thing. Pretty, pretty damn.
Uh That's again, one of my favorite videos on youtube are,
are the people with the field sobriety
test trying to walk a straight line
because normally people can walk a straight line to toe
and drunk people. Not so much,
you know.
You know, my favorite is the one that, where it's, like,
lean over and she just leans over and like, falls on her head.
Right. It's like, yeah, you're drunk. Seriously.
I love watching these videos because as, as poor as some of my life choices are,
they've never been that bad.
That's the spirit.
You know.
So, you know, you get, basically, you get untrained people on an electric scooter.
And I don't mean just untrained in a technical sense of like,
how do I ride this thing safely but untrained in the sense of like
kind of what's the culture on this? Do scooters yield to people,
-- do people yield to scooters?
-- No
-- scooters
-- yield. It's
well, ok, so
I spend a lot of time riding my bicycle on trails
and I try very hard to not be the bicycle. That is the terrible human being.
And I give people, you know, I know I'm coming, I slow down when there's
because there's nothing that ticks me off more when there's kind of, you know,
two walkers meeting on a trail and there's like the bicycle that
just blows through the middle and almost runs them over and no,
don't, it doesn't work that way.
You're the bike. You wait
and, and
the scooters should be the same way, obviously.
But I think that's easier said than done because I mean,
look you go on these trails and there's signs everywhere,
telling bicycles that walkers have the right of way.
And I bet less than 10% of bicycles actually pay attention to those
signs and it infuriates me to no end.
And so I can see where
the scooter shouldn't have the right of way, but I'm sure a lot of the people on them
believe they own the sidewalk
or they just don't care and they're not paying attention like
in that text while making left hand turns in traffic,
-- right,
-- like straight up, you know.
Yeah.
So, so you get that, that,
that problem of not just the technical lack of skill but like that lack of,
here's the biggest problem, right?
The reason traffic works is because we have some
very well defined rules that most people follow,
you know, red means stop,
green means it's
well, green means it's safe to proceed.
Uh rather no green means
you have the right of way and you can do so if it is safe to proceed,
but it's on you to make sure it's safe to proceed, right?
Because there might be a fire truck
and, you know, in most of the world we drive on the right side of the road,
not the wrong side of the road.
That's
right.
And so,
you know, traffic generally works if people do that and when people don't do that,
uh it,
well, it doesn't work,
you know,
but I feel like,
we don't have these rules or even this culture in North America of who yields to?
What? On a sidewalk? Is it faster moving? Is it bigger? Is it,
you know what if you're bigger but slower moving?
Like, what if you're on, like, a tricycle bike and you're going really slow?
Do you have to yield pedestrians still?
And same thing with this electric scooter? Right.
What if you have a really small personal electric
scooter coming up on a really big person,
you know? Do you do wheels always yield to feet?
Yes.
You know, I, yeah, I would agree. I think that would generally make sense.
But the problem is,
like, do these electric scooters have brakes?
I assume. So,
uh,
I'd be shocked if they don't.
Well, and now, like,
I know the little razor scooters their break is you smash your heel into the,
the rear fender?
Oh. And it, like,
like, uh, yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
And those work really well
if you know how to use it.
Ah, ok. It does have, it does have
a, a break built into the handles
with the right hand to accelerate and break with the left
anyway. We, we're in the weeds,
but basically this is a classic security problem of,
we have all these new behaviors with no defined,
uh, you know, no defined way to sync them
and
we end up with this huge problem, you know, it reminds me of like, the early web,
right, with web browsers and web clients, they just did all
sorts
of,
let's, let's back it away from the web though for a second.
So you say we have a new technology
and we don't have clear rules.
-- The problem is it's not a new technology, it's an old technology, but we're
-- actually
using
it now.
Let's pretend it's new
now
in history
when something new like this has shown up,
how does it get dealt with? Do people just decide on some rules and say that's neat.
I'm going to do it this way
-- occasionally but never,
-- they never,
it's regulation
every time expecting people to do the right thing.
In fact,
the only instance I can think of where an industry purposely self regulated was
the ESRB rating video games simply because they didn't want the government to do it
well.
Well,
and that's interesting that you mention that because
that actually is kind of a core component.
Now of a lot of these start ups,
like Uber has literally part of their
business strategy is to bypass legislation and laws
-- and,
-- and sometimes they do
well, like locally they did.
And then it was funny because the, the police actually started investigating them
and Uber would block their credit cards
and, you know, somebody mentioned, like,
does that count as obstruction of justice?
-- No, like
-- straight up. Right. Not when you have a lot of money.
Exactly.
So, yeah, they came to a deal with the city. But
actually do you know what I read the other day about Uber?
So I mean, you've been, you've been to SFO and when you take an Uber,
they pick you up on the top level,
which is arrivals and the bottom level is departures.
And I read they're now giving advice to people that when you arrive,
drop people off in the departures level because the
arrivals level is too busy with Uber drivers.
And it's like that is the dumbest freaking thing.
How would you too busy with Uber drivers?
-- It would be the same amount of cars dropping people off. No,
-- no, no.
They, they,
they told Uber drivers you're not allowed to pick people up in departures.
So they started picking them up in arrivals
and now there's so many cars that arrivals
because in Uber you can't drop people off and it's like this is so freaking stupid.
It's not
the first thing here. The uh the airport cab
company authority, whatever it was
decided to not let city cabs pick people up at the airport. So the city cab
commission, whatever retaliated by not letting the airport cabs pick up fares in.
And
so you had the situation of
the airport cabs could take people from the airport into
the city and then they had to dead head back and
and the city cabs could take people to the airport and then had to deadhead back,
which
obviously that's, I mean, our airport is like a good,
you know, it's a ways out of the city. Right.
And
exactly, and it was like that for a year or two and then they finally, you know,
stop playing chicken with each other and came to an agreement.
But
yeah, I mean, fundamentally we will need
legislation to handle this but more to the point will it,
well, people know or care because, I mean, part of it, you know,
like Uber is a great example.
One of the reasons I love Uber
is because we have Uber everywhere now.
So I just pull up my phone wherever I am in North America basically.
And I like, get a car there in five minutes and then I get my receipt emailed to me and
I don't have to like, know which of the local cab companies are dodgy or not dodgy,
you know, I don't have to like,
you know, like,
yeah, I just, whatever I take my Uber, right?
And the same thing with these scooters, right?
If, if this, uh, what is it bird or whatever thing takes off and is
all over North America,
then,
you know. Yeah, different cities will probably end up with different rules.
But as a bird rider, like, what the heck do I know about?
Like, these rules even in my own city, let alone in some city I'm visiting.
No, no, you're gonna have to care though because,
and, and this is something that will be interesting because generally speaking,
like in the context of Uber, it's up to the drivers and Uber to follow the rules.
But in the context of Bird,
it's gonna be also heavily dependent on the writer
and, and look, if you don't follow the rules, man, you're gonna get a ticket.
That's just how this works.
And, and being ignorant of the law isn't an excuse in any jurisdiction.
And so
this
in all seriousness,
this, this might be the money factory these cities need
now that, like, their, their drunk driving fines are way down because of Uber.
That's actually a really good point is that, you know, in theory,
when we get to self driving cars in 10 or 20 years,
pretty much 100% of revenue from speeding tickets,
red light cameras and so on should,
yeah,
it'll be.
Exactly,
it should be.
And so, yeah, do we, we do we shift to for lack of a better term,
pedestrian traffic enforcement.
Well, look, they're gonna do something because they want the money. Right.
-- Yeah.
-- No, this is interesting.
I mean, because I, especially in places like San Francisco, right.
There's a lot of things where, you know,
you want to travel one or two kilometers which is, you know, it's a bit of a walk,
especially up and down those hills.
But, you know, if you, if you do an Uber,
the Uber actually takes longer than walking because traffic is so horrendous.
-- Most of the time
-- it does.
In fact, I remember at RSA, I took an Uber and the guy was like,
you can walk faster than this.
And I said, look, man,
I'm so tired. I don't care. Just let me, let me sit here for a
little
seriously. I need air conditioning
and I said, if it takes a little longer, whatever that
I had that happen in Ireland, the guy is like,
this is literally a three block away dress and I'm like, yeah, but I can't find it.
So like down
there before,
yeah, it's like I'm, my phone isn't behaving and Google Maps isn't helping me and
take me to my hotel, please.
I don't care.
Although I,
I saw there was something on Reddit once where somebody was lost in the city
and they,
they got it in an Uber and literally like they were
on the wrong corner of a city block from their hotel.
Uber
driver, like, literally drove them down one street,
turned a corner down the street and dropped them off.
It's like that story, you know,
the car mechanic that like spends five minutes
fixing the engine and charges them 1000 bucks
when it's like 999 bucks for knowing which part
to replace and a buck for the spark plug.
That's right.
That's right. You know,
there, there's actually, I read a story of a better story than that.
Uh, just recently was,
I guess Picasso Pablo Picasso was in a cafe one time uh doodling on a napkin
and a woman saw him and he was, he was like going to throw it out. And she said,
can I have that? And he said, no, I'll sell it to you for $20,000.
And she was, of course appalled and said, but you drew it in like two minutes.
Well, I don't,
whatever. It's a story.
Uh and, and she says, you drew it in like two minutes and he says, no, ma'am, I,
I drew this, it took me 65 years to draw this, right?
And like, that's very true.
Oh, totally.
So back to this,
the other thing I found really fascinating with this bird story
was the whole because I was kind of wondering that too.
I'm like,
how do these things get recharged because they don't have like docking base.
It's like again, going back to like places that have city bikes,
they have those big ranks,
right? You're like take the bike, jam it in
and
I get it. But it's also very uh me as a rider. That's very inconvenient, right?
I ideally I want to go from point
-- to point B and not have to do any care and feeding of this device.
-- Yeah.
And the, the, the bird scooters you like find one on the street,
you scan it, it starts working and then you like literally park it and that's it.
And it just sits in the middle of the frigging. It's crazy.
And so apparently the way it works is they have these people,
they pay kind of piece meal again, like the sharecropping, you know,
piece work economy
and they get paid to, you know, pick up these bird scooters,
take them home and charge them up and then
it sounds like Pokemon go.
Yeah.
And, you know, they're talking about this and there's some really, like, you know,
they get into some very aggressive, angry situations because,
you know, it's a first come first serve, right?
Like there's a pile of scooters on the map. Go find them.
Good luck, you know,
and some of them people throw them in garbage cans or people
hide them or throw them in the lake or whatever because,
you know, they're angry at these scooters.
Um, you know, it's like when in, what was it, Amsterdam,
when they tried their first city bike program,
like within a week they all ended up in the canals.
I know.
Not
surprised.
Um
Yeah. So
I, again, it kind of comes like I get it, you know, people, businesses,
especially literally if you tried to
create a legislative framework for your product
prior to releasing it by definition,
that would take so long you'd go out of business.
And I do agree with that.
And I also think,
and this is true of nearly any industry that I think
trying to regulate before release is a nonstarter you know,
it reminds me of TCP.
Flow control.
Remember when TCP was invented,
they came up with all these flow control ideas and implemented
them in software and guess what did any of them work?
-- Really? No, no. In fact, most of them made it much, much worse.
-- You know.
That's funny you say that because I mean, it's the old saying,
premature optimization is the root of all evil
and that's true of regulation as well.
If you prematurely regulate,
you end up stifling innovation and potentially ruining
-- the industry even
-- more to the point.
Do we need regulation? Right?
I, I see all these things were like, oh, we should regulate Xy and Z and I'm like, well,
what is the actual cost to society of Xy and Z?
Like, I, I hate to say it but, you know, if, for the sake of argument, some
food product or whatever technology kills, let's say one person per year.
Is it worth spending $10 to regulate it? Well, yeah,
yeah, that, that definitely 10 bucks for, to saving a life. Sure.
What if it cost $10 billion?
Well,
we very easily could spend that $10 billion somewhere else and
save a lot more than one life part of it too.
Is even if we want, like, even if there are good reasons to regulate this, does,
does it make economic sense to do so?
You know, is that the best way to spend our money? And time
and
will these regulations even work, right?
Like, dude, we've had seatbelt laws in,
in, in Canada and Alberta for
decades.
Like I remember as a little kid it went from like, you, whatever,
you probably should wear your seatbelt to like you have to wear your seatbelt.
The argument being
especially with socialized health care,
like we're paying for you to go through
the windshield so you better wear your seatbelt.
Yeah, that seems fair.
And there are still people getting seatbelt tickets 30 some years later,
it'll never go away, man.
-- You
-- know, I had,
I had to move my car from the driveway to across
the street so I could move another car into it.
And I'm like, I, I started backing up without my seatbelt on.
I'm like, oh, that feels just weird.
Put my seatbelt on, move the car, like through defeat
on the flip side though.
I see like what Uber has done in some of these cities and it's just like, man,
that's like borderline evil, like some of the stuff they've done is
literally like, quite,
you know, morally, ethically and legally questionable.
So, yeah, I don't know where that happy medium is. And then
the other thing is too, like,
stuff like this scooter regulation that's going to be on a city level and
there's going to be like all sorts of different rules and different things.
Yeah.
Well, a great example would be, I know in European cities, there's, um,
a lot of city centers.
We have, uh, pedestrian zones, uh, that are open to pedestrians, bicycles,
some of them, you have to walk your bike, some of them you can ride your bike.
Most of them obviously allow emergency vehicles.
Many of them allow commercial delivery vehicles. Right.
Because you know the stores and stuff and they're gonna, like,
do stuff and like have food to serve you and then there's, you know,
the different strategies, like, uh, one of my favorite strategies, Cobblestones
straight up. Right.
You try roller blading or skateboarding on cobblestones. And the answer is no,
no.
Right.
And,
and that's one of my favorite ways of making
an area pedestrian friendly is just use cobblestones.
That is true. And Europe has tons of
Coles
even riding in cars on those things is terrible.
It's when they're wet on a bicycle, you wipe out a lot.
I don't think I've ever ridden a bicycle in Europe because all the
bicyclists in Europe are crazy people and I'm afraid to interact with.
They, like, they take it very seriously. It's not quite as leisurely as
the
thing is, I don't want to get run over by a car and conversely,
I don't want to run over a pedestrian because that would be a
very rude thing to do.
-- So.
-- Have you ever been to Amsterdam before?
Yeah. In Amsterdam. I'm not afraid of the cars. I'm afraid of the bikes.
Well, but see, the thing is conversely, like, I feel, you know,
like in Germany just don't walk on the red pavement,
the red pavement is for cyclists. Right.
Right.
Yeah, that too. They, they're pretty brutal there as well.
Less so than Amsterdam, but it's, it's definitely serious.
But, uh, no, so I'm just, it is curious to see, like,
it's, it's pretty clear to me at this point.
Uber has won over cab companies because, like, even locally,
all the cab companies now there's two or three main ones and they have, like,
we have an app and you can order us online and it's like, yeah, great.
Except every time I try and, like, use you guys,
it's just a freaking nightmare and it takes like 20 minutes for your cab to get here
and it smells weird, you know, and, and more to the point.
Uber emails me that nice receipt and also Uber works in all the places I travel to.
Right. My local cab company. Not so much
and I feel like this scooter thing, I feel like Segway
didn't work because it just requires a level of skill that
a lot of people don't have
expensive.
Yeah.
Yeah, exactly. Yeah.
Well, less so now because the electronics have really come down in price.
But still compared to like, these scooters. Yeah, they're, they're pretty pricey.
So,
I feel like these scooters have a good chance
of winning that 1 to 2 kilometer travel thing,
you know.
So, like, ideally you get off public transit and then you,
you grab a bird and do your one or two K to your office or whatever.
I feel like these could really be actually useful and successful
except, you know, places where I live here,
like where we get snow and stuff and it's not going to work so good.
Right. And I'm, I'm familiar with that problem also.
It is, I don't know. I mean, I, I look at this and
I think
it is, it is one of those unique problems
where
it's, it's a new idea
and it's kind of a nuisance and something probably needs to be done.
But I, I think you have a fair point about regulation. Is it a big enough nuisance?
Something will be done? I have a suspicion.
Yes.
Well, and the other thing is, is you go back to, is it a big enough problem?
And that's the thing. Right.
There's al,
there's always been one or two people that will ride their
razor in pedestrian traffic and if it's one or two people,
like, who cares?
It's like
if there's one person riding a horse in downtown New York, that's fine.
There's 10 of them.
If there's 10 of them,
it's kind of like this is getting a little weird and annoying and if there's like,
1000 of them then, like, I, I'm pretty sure traffic would come to a standstill,
-- you
-- know.
And no, no, like that, that argument though, I think is invalid just because
there aren't
horses everywhere in New York City.
Well, no, but what I mean is with the scooter,
scooter
as long as there's like one or two scooters, who cares?
But when there's like,
say 10,000 of these floating around New York being actively used
and, and at that point,
I guess we're going to see regulation that's going to clearly define
what has to happen.
And I keep thinking about this in the context of, of security on the internet
and,
and I'm coming back to your point about how much is it going
to cost to regulate and how much value do you get back?
And, and I, I'm wondering,
it is quite possible that regulating computers on the internet
will have a negative return on investment essentially from the context of,
of what you get versus what you have.
And if that's true,
it just might not ever make sense
to have that
-- stuff.
-- And,
you know, I look at like
right now I've, you know, I'm buying, uh, the led light bulbs and they're,
they've really come down in price, you know, they're, there are a few bucks now,
but quite frankly, like, you know, trying to convince me to spend like,
50 bucks or 100 bucks on one of those, like,
really nice iot light bulbs with the changing lights or the music or whatever.
Good luck.
But when they're $10 sure
Well, even in that context, like, look, let's say like meds.
Right.
There's clear value
of
-- you.
-- Right. Right.
There's clear value there because people literally die.
If I have a light bulb, that's part of a botnet,
is it, is it really negatively affecting me? Nope, it sure isn't.
Is it negatively affecting the world
so far? We've yet to see any sort of DD OS
-- that has been more than like a day's worth of annoyance.
-- So
talking about
doctor sloppy handwriting kills more than 7000 people
annually in the United States of America.
And this is from 2007.
So you know that 7000 is too small of a number for killing people before anyone cares
well, and it's also distributed, right?
You know, it's not like you have 7000 people die in one event and ok,
-- now we care a bit
-- or, or even from one specific product,
like let's say you have one pacemaker and 7000 people die, people would flip out.
But, but I think if it's,
if it's random distributed sampling 7000 is obviously too low of a number,
it would be interesting
to look at what is the threshold when people start to care because you look at
like automobile safety man and it was horrifying
how many people were dying before they really,
really started to care
well,
and the industry actively campaigned against it
because of the perceived costs and whatnot.
You know, like they fought tooth and nail for a long time.
And, yeah, it took Ralph Nader to, to really,
you know,
to put it bluntly, to publicly shame them into,
you know, it's funny and people don't always like it when I say this,
but I consider what Nader did to be stunt hacking.
Oh, it totally was. And it works.
And I think that's part of it is, people have to understand and, you know, the,
the optics on a thing, right?
Like, no offense.
But if I show you a real server hack,
what you will see is a rack of computers with blinking lights
and that's it, nothing will change, right?
Literally, the lights won't blink more or less.
-- It won't catch fire,
-- it
-- won't
-- bloke more.
Like, look the yellow lights blinking twice as fast as it was
before.
You know, that little network light is solid now
and like, literally, who cares? Right.
Whereas, you know, you do like a skater demo hack and it's like, ok,
you know, this thing does this thing again, who cares?
Like, when you can make something blow up? Oh, ok.
-- Now I'm going to blow up this house with, with my computer,
-- you know,
or turn every traffic light in the city green
or it'd be even funnier to turn them all red
and never turn them green. Measure
the patients.
I,
I wonder, I mean,
-- everyone has a limit but I bet there's a lot of people that would be
-- actually,
you know, it's funny.
No, because when it's, uh, red all the way around then you treat it as a four way stop.
So this is the thing is there's an actual rule to deal with that,
whereas there is no rule to deal with all green.
That's
true.
That's a good point.
Although when this happens though, most people do tend to ignore it.
So
interesting, man. I don't know. We'll, we'll see. It's,
I, I have a feeling
we will be revisiting this topic more than once
in the coming days.
You know what I'm really curious about what other
transport alternatives are gonna be coming out because
I would have never guessed electric scooters.
Well, it's even more than just transport. I mean, I think so
the story, I think the
-- drone thing is going to be
-- the biggest, well, drones are coming. There's so, so
we are approaching a point where we have an
amazing amount of technology kind of coming together in
this interesting way and it's because of things like
cell phones and cloud computing and GSM networks and,
and everything we have
and so people are able to do crazy things nobody could have dreamed of.
-- It's just like
-- the internet 20 years ago.
Right.
-- Yeah, exactly.
-- We, we suddenly hit this inflection point
of
not every, a lot of people are on the internet,
they have enough internet speed to actually do something interesting with it.
We have enough servers, we have enough bandwidth.
We have programming languages, like, well back in the day,
Pearl and stuff that are finally getting smart enough to do useful things with.
And, yeah, and, and the,
the two thousands was the amount of creative destruction
that went on in the.com world was stunning.
And we're doing that again with drones and with, you know, well,
like 3D printing and,
you know, computer vision. I mean, yeah, all these things coming together is
like, when I think about, if I had a hobby nowadays and I could spend like,
20 hours a week on it and say 50 grand, I, you know, I could build like a drone that,
like, catches squirrels
-- and delivers them to people. I don't
-- like,
oh, my goodness.
We need a Kickstarter for this.
Like a squirrel catching drone. I would pay huge money for that.
And if it can catch or kill rabbits also, oh, man, that'd be golden.
-- Like, they're the bane of my existence.
-- I thought you had a dog.
I
do have a dog.
They're still,
he's not outside all the time.
Well, isn't that the traditional solution?
He's helping actually, for what it's worth.
I do have less rabbits in my backyard but, but only where the dog is, right. I have a f,
in area
and, and the squirrels are squirrels, climb up things. Right. Like when
I, I'm,
I'm very militant about keeping branches away
from my house because I hate squirrels.
I hate them so much. You have no idea.
And, well,
they used to live in my house and it took a long time
to get rid of them because they kept chewing holes and stuff.
And so anyway, now I just keep all the branches very far away from the house
and I still see them on there every now and then. I'm like, oh,
if I could go up there and get you, I would. But it's too far
anyway. Sorry, I'm done ranting with squirrels
anyway.
Right.
No, it's, it's,
it's interesting and I think we're going to
see even crazier stuff in the near future.
-- But
-- yeah, so going back, like my favorite thing with drones is like,
you think it's bad to get pooped on by a bird?
Imagine when a drone carrying a milkshake hits you?
-- That's going
-- to be epic.
I hope I am the first person to have a drone carried milkshake dumped on his head.
II, I hope I can only pray,
you know, are people going to be just be randomly covered in Chinese? Take out?
I don't know. And I think that's how we ended.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
If you want any of the show notes from the discussion today,
you can go to open source security podcast.com.
We have links there to Facebook group
and you can use the Pound Os S podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media.
So Yeah, I guess until next time, Kurt just keep looking up, man.
Watch out for that Chinese
take care.
Thanks folks.