Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Heat Wave crime.
Josh Bresser.
Yeah, you guys are like on fire up there in Canada right now, aren't you?
We set a record yesterday.
-- Hottest day in Canada
-- ever. You're going to set a lot of records. I think
we did set new records in Alberta for electricity consumption.
We beat the previous record by a gigawatt.
That's neat.
Yeah, the previous record was December 2019 when it was stupid. Cold.
And, uh, now it's
air conditioning obviously is kind of the big thing and
I didn't realize 60% of Canada has air conditioners, which I,
I would have guessed way lower.
So you told me that.
Well, I grew up without it
and, and I also did, which was terrible,
but
you told me this and it didn't totally
shock me just because a significant portion of Canada
lies south of where I live,
like the population because you figure that like Toronto Montreal area,
there's a lot of people there.
Well, it's also to put air conditioning at your house is like $20,000.
And so like my parents don't have it.
Right. They have an older house and it would be
20 grand to install an AC unit
and chiller and pipes and all that other stuff.
And so a lot of people, you know,
just haven't bothered because quite honestly most summers we have, like,
five hot days
and, well, and where I live humidity is a non issue. Like I,
yeah, I, I think it was humid once.
Yeah. And again, the Toronto area is literally surrounded by water.
-- It's disgusting. It's incredibly humid all the time.
-- Yeah.
Whereas I'm 1000 kilometers from the nearest
body of real water with a mountain range in between.
This kind of reminds me of the whole solar winds thing, you know, and that it's,
it's one of those classic things.
It's like we've kind of known for a while
that this something bad is probably going to happen.
-- But like if we just sort of don't pay attention to it long enough.
-- All right.
That's the worst transition
I've ever heard.
Now,
here's what we're actually going to discuss is we
had a listener send us a mail last week,
I think maybe, I don't know.
It's sometime before now
that basically said, hey,
do you think Se Linux could have stopped solar winds?
And I thought this is a marvelous topic because
it, it is a thought experiment
in the context of the answer is technically yes.
But
because
it,
it probably could have in the same way I could build an
uncrushable car if I had $12 billion to buy a car with.
You know what I mean?
I think part of the problem is, uh
and what we're, where we're eventually gonna end up at one point.
So I'm just gonna kill it now is
no amount of technology can fix problems.
Like a vendor saying, oh, hey, our package isn't signed properly,
just smash that button and just jam it in.
So,
right? Like no amount of
technical
problem.
But that's what I'm saying. It's like no amount of technical controls will fix
the problem of, oh, the technical controls are misbehaving,
just ignore them and force it
-- right?
-- So let's just get that out
-- of
-- the weapons,
right? And that's,
you know what I always think of is
and, and I I'll use Se Linux is a perfect example is so
my laptop finally came,
remember we talked about that like way back in the many episodes ago.
And so for those of you who don't know,
I ordered a new work laptop and the original date they told me it would
come was in 2024 and I ordered it in early April of the year 2021.
So obviously that was a place,
right? And the date June of 2021
uh the end of June, right? It it came on like June 25th or 26th I think
is when it like arrived at my house and so April and beginning
of April to end of June is what we ended up with,
which was better than I expected.
I'm not going to lie. But anyway, I have it
well, with the current GP U shortage. Yeah.
Right. Right.
I have my computer.
I do all the set up and everything
and of course, se Linux gets in the way here and there
and I just turn it off, do what I need to do and turn it back on because you know what?
That's way easier than figuring out what's going on
and then adding one rule for the one thing I need to do.
And so yeah, like, and, but this is a great example.
Well, and making sure that that rule persists.
Well, I don't need it to persist because this is like edit a file.
Oh, you can't edit the file because you're not special. It's like F us E Linux,
I am special.
Well, but that's the problem, right is in production.
If you're going to make, if you're going to have to modify Se Linux
policies, you,
you're gonna have to edit them and make it that change persist across Se Linux
updates.
Right. Right. You know,
plus
then for example, the, the server that wants to write the log file to
vlog slash whatever
changes that location or you want to log to a database or you want,
you know what I mean?
You, you change it and then
-- it breaks. I,
-- I've got, I think a nice way to think of this. So
in the case of solar winds,
it was the build system
that was compromised.
And let's say you have a build system and you have Se Linux running on it, right.
There's kind of two ways you can treat this, you can treat it as OK.
We're going to have a very loose se Linux
policy designed to, let's say,
look for a couple of of obviously bad things and then we're gonna,
let's say it'll be a little squishy in the middle, you know, hard,
crunchy outside squishy interior.
I don't see how that would really help here when the Attackers like I don't,
-- it wouldn't,
-- I don't really care about attacking the build system per se.
I just want the bill to have some funky backdoors.
We'll get to that, we'll get to that. So you're right,
it would basically not have stopped an attack like solar wind.
So now you say, ok, we're going to
lock everything down and we know
that the build and test are going to do these activities in this way
and then we're going to block like everything else, right?
So you're talking a super strict policy,
but the problem is as a product is developed and tested,
it's, it's constant change.
So you would have to have a policy that's also
being updated as often as new builds are happening,
which is you're talking about,
probably a team of people would have to maintain that.
I'm skeptical
they could keep it updated quick enough.
There's an even worse problem.
You're making the fundamental assumption of using a persistent build system,
which in my opinion is wrong.
Don't use a persistent build system.
Use a non
persistent build system that fires it up in a container
and you get like a fresh build every time.
That's the vision I have in my mind,
your build system should never be reused because even ignoring malicious stuff,
like
what happens if a build leaves some crap behind or
what happens if you some Brando installs a weird package.
You know, there, there's a million things, build systems should never be reused.
-- Well,
-- if somebody tweaks something to fix it, you know,
they tweak an environmental variable or they
whatever and
like, do you even know that that happened? Really? You know,
and that's why I like containers.
Is that whole, here's our version of reality and if we want to fix reality,
we actually have to like, fix it in a document weight,
like in the container file or whatever.
Right?
You know what I always think of is,
I've worked at more than one place now where it's the only
way to build a certain product was to ssh into someone's machine.
You had to build it there because
no one else could figure out how to set it all up. And it's like this is madness.
Well, I mean, like what is it? You know, what's the Python stuff called again?
I'm spacing out which Python stuff like pip.
You know, the stuff that sets up your magic kind of
magic Python environment with like conflicting library version.
Yeah. Virtual,
you know, stuff like that where it's like
I, I get why Python developers built that.
But at the same time again, it's like you're solving the problem by letting people,
you know,
punch giant holes in the side of their house and put Saran wrap on it instead of
having a proper box, like a container or something.
-- And
-- I don't know if I'd agree with that. I mean, so I use a lot of virtual environments.
I do a lot of Python work
and I think the biggest advantage I see is I can make sure I only have the things I need
in each of my little development universes. That way.
I know, for example,
I'm not just like throwing garbage into this project when
the other project doesn't need any of those dependency.
-- So I mean, I really like it but containers functionally can do the same thing.
-- Yes.
Well, the nice thing about containers is you have a real clean boundary.
Like it's a, it's a really sharp clean edge.
And
I mean,
that's what I'm seeing more and more of an it is I want real
sharp clean edges between my stuff because I remember back in the day where,
you know, this whole idea of one server per service.
No, we, we, we can only afford one computer.
So we had to put everything, you know, we had to put the DH P server, the
FTP server, the web server, the email server, the DNS server,
you had to put everything on one computer
because that's all you could bloody well afford.
Not just that we used to brag about that in the Linux world is, oh,
Windows can only do one thing for a computer.
We can do 100 things for a computer, aren't we? Awesome? And it's like
in back then that was awesome. But now it's like, no, that's the opposite of awesome.
And so now it's, I mean, between either virtual machines and,
or higher level stuff like containers,
you absolutely should break stuff down, you know,
use network sockets as sort of your, your boundary condition because again,
it's really clean and clear what's going on.
There's no magic
like, oh,
it dumps something onto the file system somewhere that something else needs.
All right, I wanna, I wanna reel this back just a little bit and, and
focus on something you said, as you said, you know, people want clear boundaries
and
I think
that is why containers have won this battle.
Whereas you look at some of these other sandbox type technologies like for example,
Se Linux
-- has not or, or app Armor or pick one of them.
-- Well, And do you know why?
There's one simple reason,
trust boundaries with containers inside of your container,
you can have a single trust level and just essentially, right?
Like who cares? YOLO?
Because quite frankly, if a container, if an attacker breaks into the container,
they don't
have to care about rooting it.
Like they've just rooted that container,
they've taken over that container at the application level of say
the database or the mail server or the web server.
So it doesn't really matter if they get more
access within the container. Whereas if you have a multi
user sort of multi-tenant system
being protected by Ac Linux,
you know,
and you have the mail server and the web server on it
and you have to keep those two from touching each other.
And that's really hard because they share
the system in so many ways like DNS lookups libraries, you know, all, all that stuff.
And
so when I build a container,
I can say I'm gonna maybe decompose my application into a web server,
an application server and a database server, right?
A classic three layer cake
and
each of those cake layers effectively has a single trust layer
with
like a port exposed, you know, on the web server,
it's going to be port 80 or 443 or whatever on the application server,
it's going to be port like
and on the database server, it's going to be port uh
whatever post Chris SQL uses, I think 4321 or something.
I don't know anymore. And, you know,
that's
super easy,
you know, and, and to put a blank, if you can break into post Grass SQL via the network,
well,
you can do that anyways like you can, it's, it's on a system.
Se Linux wouldn't be able to protect that because the,
the application server has to talk to the database,
you know, and if the attacker, so
I, I really think this whole multi
system
and by system,
I don't mean just a hardware machine or a container or a virtual machine,
but I mean,
like a running sort of quasi whatever
you want to call it operating system environment
that has multiple levels of trust
is
-- it's just too much work to do it correctly. I
-- mean, I agree with that.
And again, this is, it's not just,
it's not just that,
I mean,
well, sure, but this is,
I think this is fundamentally why containers one
because containers solve like 10 annoying problems.
-- And this is just one of them that it solves a perfect
-- example is, is like Jenkins,
Jenkins, like in classic terms was, you know,
you install Jenkins on a server and you use it, it's persistent,
it's highly persistent
and then that changed. And Jenkins is now, you know,
when we worked at Red Hat, remember openshift used Jenkins and it,
every build was a new instance of Jenkins effectively running in a container,
did the build and the proof it's gone
and the BUILD artifacts were extracted.
And so there's a whole pile of Jenkins security vulnerabilities that
just no longer matter.
That's right because it's like, oh, you know,
the attacker can do this and then get persistent.
Well,
yeah, they get persistence for like, three minutes and then the container is gone.
I mean, now, mind you that doesn't always matter.
-- There's a talk I will try to
-- find gone in 60 seconds.
Yeah.
Is that it where they basically,
-- it's an attacker
-- shows escaping function as a service.
-- Right.
But at the same time
that raises the bar for the Attackers and something we always forget
in the world of security is we love to think of
this all as binary of attacker wins or we win.
But the reality is,
it's all about, I just want to make life miserable for the attacker.
It's not about I win or they win. It's about I'm going to make their life suck.
So they give up eventually.
Well,
but also you can gain the ability to
notice something bad happened because for example,
your Jenkins ephemeral build service should never try
and poke the rest of your network infrastructure.
You know, the Jenkins build server should not, you know what I mean?
If it's in a container, there's a whole bunch of stuff it just will, should never do.
And it makes detection so much easier because again,
when you have a server running an email server, a web server and a database server.
Like I remember back in the day
having firewall rules on my servers that they couldn't connect out
to create network connections. So if somebody broke into me
and then tried to connect out to attack other people,
I would notice it
right away.
Now, of course, that breaks updates and a whole bunch of other stuff I need.
So there's then, you know, you need a proxy server for DNS.
You need a proxy server for updates and a whole pile of other junk.
But the point is the whole point of it was so I could,
if somebody broke to my server and then like tried to port scan my network,
I would, I would know right away
and I could take corrective action.
And that's the other thing, right? Is this
this thing of detection? Like what gets me about the solar winds timeline?
December 8th Fireeye,
our prominent cybersecurity firm announces that they were blah, blah, blah,
hacked
December 13th Fireeye discovered a supply chain
attack while investigating blah blah blah,
Trojan Eye solar winds
like December 13th 2020. And then this whole thing chugs along for a while
and then kind of blows up later.
You know what I mean?
And that's the thing
or like the home I remember Home Depot.
Remember they got hacked for a whole bunch of credit card data
and their security firm had told them, like, months before that there were like,
bad guys in their network
and, well, they ignored it
-- or something. I don't know. Right. And that's human nature.
-- It is. And
you talk all the time about,
actually you haven't talked in a while about aircraft horrifying accidents.
But
one of the things you always talk about is the
fact that it's rarely one thing that went wrong.
It's like 10 things had to go wrong in just
the right order for this to turn into a catastrophe.
-- What
-- the Swiss cheese holes had to line up. Right.
And, I mean, it's the same thing in all e every security incident when you read
what happened. It's like, oh, holy crap.
Look at how they screwed up now, mind you,
I'm not going to pretend that that couldn't happen to any of them.
Us because goodness knows we're humans and we make loads of mistakes.
-- Well, I mean, I had my servers hacked once upon a time
-- even now.
You could be hacked now and you might not know it, you know.
Well, and that's part of why I outsourced all my junk to the cloud because to hack me,
you'd have to hack into Google.
I mean,
kind of, it depends how you're running it, but
it's irrelevant. Right. The point is the point of all this
is just the fact that
when you look at a problem
and then some of these proposed solutions there is like, technically correct.
And then there's actually working
and you know what I mean? And I think this is part of the disconnect.
We run into a lot in the world of security is there's these like,
technically correct things where you say, oh, you should do this, you should run
this policy, you should run this thing to lock it down.
There's a million things, but the reality is
people are people and you have to pick something
that actually works and can be worked with.
And I think that's where a lot of these security technologies fail.
Well, I look at the,
I've had a lot of people sort of try and sell me security solutions like AC M
and I'm like, no,
I'm not going to do AC M because we don't actually we have one VPs
server and everything else is essentially platform as
a service or higher in the cloud.
I literally, there's no value for me in AC M plus
the expertise and time and effort needed to run it properly
-- is more than zero, much more than zero.
-- There are a lot of work to do it, right.
That's the thing is, is just that
like I look at Se Lenox
and to make policies you have audit to allow.
And as far as I know, that's the only tool and audit to allow is not fine grained.
It basically looks at the errors in the log and says,
you know, this thing tried to touch this thing in this way.
Boom, here's a rule that allows that like, but typically a very broad rule, you know,
there's because I remember writing back in the day about se like
there was this one cool tool, for example, that would,
it would watch why you did like, you know,
back in the days of uh what was it dot slash configure make test, make, make install.
Um And it would watch the make portion of the tarball creation
and create like a list of files and try and make some rules to kind
of cover what the server would probably have to do with those locations and stuff.
And it would kind of try and make a policy, you know,
you know, based on that
as far as I know,
there's one person on the planet that actually
knows how to make proper se Lennox policies.
-- There's, I can think of about 50,
-- ok.
Well, I was thinking of Dan Walsh and maybe he taught a few people.
Dan Walsh is the best by far.
But yes, it is definitely one of the challenges
and then the problem is too, it's going to randomly break stuff.
I guarantee it's gonna have to at some
because if you actually have a properly restrictive policy
at some point, your server is going to do like the,
the yearly backup or the yearly report
that wasn't accounted for in the rules.
Oh, I don't even think of that anymore.
I mean, you think when, when Se Linux was created,
it was created in like the early two thousands
by the NSA literally by the National Security Agency.
And back in those days, it was very much a universe where you would set up a machine
and that was it, it was like cast in, in
epoxy forever and you never changed it because if you touch it, it might break.
And I mean, that's, that's the world. Se Lennox comes from and today
and this whole like madness of Dev ops and whatever you want to call it,
your application is changing.
Probably, I'd like to say multiple times a day, but let's face it.
Most people aren't, don't move at that speed,
but it's still going to be a couple of times a month for sure.
And so if you have some sort of security engine policy,
as soon as you push a new update to prod
it, it breaks. Right.
-- And that's
-- unacceptable
and it doesn't break in a simple, nice, easy, clean way either.
Right. It breaks in a way you're just going to turn off Se Linux
because that was the quickest solution.
Well, but also you, it's kind of the quickest way to troubleshoot.
Did Se Linux break this or did the application just break?
That's true too. I
it's only,
I've done that so many times when I turn up Se Lennox and it's still broken.
I'm like, well, crap.
Now, I know.
Right
now I really have to figure it out.
Yeah. Or you put Se Linux
back into, um, from enforcing to what is it,
-- the logging? Permissive
-- mode? Permissive. Yeah.
Permissive is when it doesn't fail.
-- Yeah. And you watch your log files.
-- Yeah.
Yeah. Well, and that's how you use the audit to allow is you,
you put Se Linux in permissive mode,
you do what you need to do,
then you analyze the log file and it will add the
rules you need and you can put it back into,
you know, the the restrictive mode and it will
in theory
work and see and this is a perfect example of you.
But to do that properly,
you have to account for those multiple trust barriers and get a tight policy.
Whereas if you go with the idea of we're gonna have a single trust level,
then you just YOLO in a container,
that's it
done,
right?
And like I know which one I'm going to pick nowadays.
So there's also another side to this that I don't think we talk about a lot.
So let's say I have an application I built I now
am solely responsible for my security policy on that application, right?
I have no help.
I can't get help because literally no one but me is
running this assuming you're running a Sass or something like that.
Now,
if we look at the world of containers,
the whole world is using containers in fundamentally the same way.
So everyone working on container security is doing so
in a manner that can basically benefit everyone else.
That's amazing.
Well, and even better than that, not only is it shared,
but it's quite often it's the vendor publishing a container.
It's, it's like good and legitimate and works
properly.
You know, it's no,
it's not some like random container from some guy in Switzerland that, you know,
needed this to work in a container.
-- So he built it
-- right.
90 percent of the internet runs off of some random container.
-- But
-- more to the point
that
the vendor has a very, here's the beautiful thing.
The vendor has an incentive that the container
works and people don't phone their support line.
I mean,
like from the perspective I deal with, yeah,
that's totally true is we need to make sure our containers don't
-- suck
-- because here's the thing with Se Linux as a vendor.
The only thing that Se Linux will do for me is create support volume
compared to the number of calls that will prevent from security issues.
Whereas having a fully working container.
Oh, all those calls. What, how do I install the product and get it working?
They stopped
because they, it's just like download the container. Ok. And then you turn it on.
There's no step to, right. That's the beauty of containers. That's why I love them
stuff just works.
Absolutely.
I,
you know, there's a, so the beauty is,
there's a huge incentive for vendors to do this correctly and most of them do now,
you know, because it, things just work,
you know? I,
yeah.
Yeah.
I,
I remember the bad old days of downloading a vendor product and trying
to make it work on like a system they said it would work on
and they'd be like, oh, yeah, there's this magic step. You forgot.
Yep. Yep. I've done that. I remember that.
Or my, my other favorite is when they would just like, literally throw
a huge pile of crap into like slash opt
and it like, came with its own operating system, essentially all the,
like its own lib sea, its own everything
because
it worked.
I mean, ironically
that was basically a container.
We
-- just didn't have a name for it.
-- Well, or a nice clear boundary.
Yeah.
Yeah, exactly. Exactly. I mean,
-- so,
-- yeah,
-- it's,
-- oh my
-- goodness.
-- I, I honestly think things like Se Linux
are,
they're not dead but like pearl, they're a dead end.
-- I mean,
-- I don't know if I'd go that far.
I, I, the thing I think about a lot is so let's, let's talk about Chrome for a minute.
Let's kind of change directions a little bit. So the chrome web browser
has a sandbox
and when you run Chrome,
it basically uses all of the same technologies that things like Se Linux
used to lock itself down
and it uses this stuff to basically neuter the Chrome processes,
-- the Children it spawns
-- there.
You actually have a vendor whose incentives align with.
We need these web browsers to just accept any and all data off the
internet and not get users hacked so that they keep seeing our ads.
There's that side of it. But I mean, like all all the browsers do this now, right?
Sandbox is not new.
It was when chrome started, there's the angle of we have a vendor with an interest,
but there's also the aspect of when
you have a very
understood and specified, use
these things have immense value, right?
But when you're doing, who knows what,
then it becomes extremely difficult. So for example,
if you know
that you have something doing one thing like a web browser, for example,
or if I had like an upload service where I was accepting files,
like that would be a great
use where you can say Se Linux
only allow rights to this directory and only
this directory and never ever ever execute anything
outside of slash bin
like that makes sense, right?
But saying here's my Sass app that's made of 72,000
random piles of stuff I've downloaded off the internet.
-- Good luck. Like that's out of the question. Well,
-- here's the thing.
I keep coming back to
vendor supplied. Se Linux,
100 and 26,000 results in Google
vendor supply container
about 9.5 million
again, like looking for Se Linux
tools.
Se Linux
tools, you know, 1 million results,
but it's all how tos it's the same set of
like here's kind of the basic Se Linux walk through.
There's no like there used to be a graphical user interface tool to creating Se Linux
policy, which was really nice because just something as
quote unquote,
simple as figuring out like what is the name of the thing I need to call to like
add to this policy,
right? And it's like something with like five underscores and it's really long.
Se Linux is
too complicated for most people to get, right? So they don't and
there's no vendor support really. Like I, I don't remember ever.
I've never seen a vendor ship an Se Linux
policy that works properly.
Red hat does, I mean Red hat stuff is great
-- but like
-- Red Hat, but then you need to install other people's stuff on it and se
breaks
it
gets dicey after that for sure.
That's like saying open BS D is secure because you
just run what open BS D ships by default.
And it's like cool, but I need more than like a dns and email server.
I actually needed to run stuff
well, and, and right, and that changes then obviously,
but
it's,
I, like I said, I think fundamentally
se Linux is a dead end because
it's had 20 years
and we still don't have an ecosystem for it.
People just don't care enough to write tools.
All right. So here's, here's a question though.
Is there no se Linux ecosystem
because nobody wants it
or is it because it's too hard or is it because
the authors of Se Linux
-- didn't nurture a community in the way they should have.
-- I think it's honestly,
it's a solution the NSA needed. It's not a solution. Most people need.
Most people need to inventory their systems and patch them.
And then they can start thinking about Sc
Linux, the NSA.
On the other hand,
has a bunch of ridiculously constrained systems that
need to absolutely just do like geospatial data analysis
or take in data from whatever
and,
and but they need,
they have like they have a check box that says
this thing needs to provably be secure in this way
and we care because it's handling like the most ridiculous level of top secret,
you know,
satellite imagery out of North Korea or whatever
the majority of us don't have that constraint.
So the thought experiment for everyone as we leave this,
what it can only be described as an Se Linux bashing session
is
could se Linux
have become the general purpose tool we need or was it always doomed
for this kind of specific use case?
I'm just looking actually the Se Linux project has a github
organization and there's an se tools repo
it's kind of up to date, but most of the stuff is not super up to date. And
I, I think realistically that the ship has sailed,
we have
things that will get you a much better return on investment,
not in the sense of just security, but in the sense of
here's the thing,
we can spend time and effort on Se Linux
and that might buy us some security or we can spend time and effort on containers.
And that absolutely will
make this thing install super easy
and it will buy us a bunch of security stuff real easy. And you know what I mean?
It, it forces us to do some automation that then benefits us down the road because,
oh, you know, we released an update, boof, here's updated containers.
All right. Now, here is the question I will ask you as we come to the close
-- wood containers have stopped the solar winds
-- attack.
Nothing would have stopped solar winds attack
because they have like an intern set password.
-- 123, you know,
-- no,
that wasn't the attack even though that
was just an unrelated incident that everyone
keeps pointing at which drives me up a wall because it doesn't make,
it's not important.
Well,
it matters in the sense of solar winds would have got and hacked at some point somehow
because they just had so many massive problems.
And that's kind of a separate
and that's my point, right? Like
when a vendor says, hey, this sign package, yeah, the signature is wrong. Ok. Just
smash that install button and ignore it.
Ignore it's fine at
some point,
you know, it's, it's when you have maintenance,
people who don't do maintenance correctly, eventually it's going to fail.
It's not a win or it's not an, if it's a when and how bad
that's true. And so
there's nothing that
could have prevented a solar winds hack at some point
in the future with the way their culture was,
it was inevitable and they were also a huge target. Like,
you know, now that certain countries have figured out who, you know,
we attack this one company and we gain access to the, well,
to all the,
yeah, to every organization with over 100,000 computers.
That's a no
brainer.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
All right. I,
I want to apologize
to any Se Linux
fans out there because
we poured on some hate, but I
don't hate it.
I think Se Linux is cool. It just needs, I wish it was easier.
Yeah, I, I wish it was, I wish it actually worked
the way. I think that a lot of
it, it, it has usability issues which basically make it unusable,
which makes me sad because,
because there's a lot of things
where
Se Linux won't necessarily
block or prevent or stop the attack, but it would sure as heck
give me an indication that there's an attacker doing something bad
fast and right away and then I could go deal with it.
But I have to disable it to get the system to work.
Yep. Yeah, and that, that's a challenge.
All right, I'm gonna call it. Thank you, everyone
for listening. Thank you, Kurt. Go to open
source security podcast.com. Head up our show,
Not Susie Pound
O
Podcast. Hashtag hit us up on social media. Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You
-- too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.