It's December 14th, backdoors, backdoors. No, I like this.
This is, this is a good topic and this is just kind of,
one of the more general things is backdoors in open source.
Keep coming up over and over and over again. Well, backdoors in all soccer.
But I think in our context we can focus on open source. But yeah.
Well, and what gets me is like,
I'm trying to think of actual good examples of like proper backdoors and
open source and they're so rare that I know there's been a few,
but
they're so rare. I can't recall them.
So,
the ones we keep seeing right now are things
like Python modules and Ruby modules and node modules.
Well, that's not so much a back, well, ok, technically that's a back door.
They're adding back doors.
So people down,
they either sometimes it's a legitimate module having bad code inserted into it.
-- Sometimes it's like a misspelled module that's purposely malicious
-- or
sometimes they compromise an account and hijack the module.
Yeah. Right. Right.
But here's the thing I think that's really important with open source is
I think generally speaking, we catch a lot of these problems.
Now, granted, you could maybe argue that there's some we're not finding in the code,
but my suspicion is there aren't very many at all.
I would say to those people, then if you're going to use that argument,
then you basically have to throw the commercial software world under the bus.
And that's my whole point is
you find these, these large vendors
are caught on a regular basis and all of them where they were
inserting backdoors for what can only
be described as extremely questionable reasons.
Well,
and what I love here is the title because I just googled Cisco backdoor because
I know they've had a bunch backdoors keep appearing at Cisco's in Cisco's RRS,
-- right? Not just the one, but they keep happening.
-- Right?
-- So,
-- well, here's what I would say to that. I know a lot of people from the
product security team, they're really good people and they're really bright.
Those back doors aren't there for nefarious purposes.
I promise you that like they were put there by someone for a reason.
Well,
what always gets me is how stupid some of these back
doors are like a 1234 admin account that should not have escaped
dev some of those, some of those I think were mistakes,
but there are also instances where it's proper
wasn't a mistake that a back door ended up in there.
And it's always funny because when
you've got these large commercial organizations,
they just be like,
oh, never mind, ignore it, you know,
pay no attention to the man behind the curtain sort of stuff.
And so the discussions often die because
there's just they don't offer any information.
Whereas I think in the world of open source, you can totally figure out what,
how did this get here?
-- Who did this, what happened?
-- Well, we have get
right, like pretty much everybody uses source control often signed
so we can with a high degree of certainty. Say, yeah, this line of code was due to Bob.
-- I
-- don't think I'd say often signed.
Well, not,
not often signed, but I mean, and signing is not even that important because even,
you know, you track it back to Bob and you ask Bob, did you put that code?
And if he goes what? No, I, what I don't recognize this.
Well, yeah, you know, Bob's account got hacked and it's, it's, it happens.
It's rare but it does happen.
And I think that's a big part of it is, is we have the ability
to have a conversation about it because we,
we have information and not just some binary blob, but
we don't even,
you know, going to IOT because we talk about IOT a lot.
I,
I am 99% certain of the IOT people are buying
that company did not write any of that software.
In most cases it is just farmed out to.
Oh, absolutely consulting firm.
And So even that company can't
necessarily have conversation about their software.
Right. They may not have the source to it, even though they shipped it.
-- Right.
-- Well, and you read all these stories,
but all these iot companies researchers contact and it's clear
no one's in charge of security at half of them.
-- Well, why would
-- there be like, there's no, it's,
-- there's no market need
-- security costs money.
And what makes it even funnier is so, like I run Plex
in my, in my house
and I can connect to my plex server from
anywhere on the planet because that's how Flex works.
-- They have a connection broker. It's pretty,
-- basically.
Plex is just a giant freaking backdoor into my,
I'm not working.
Oh, yeah. No, I,
I, that's, I, when I real, like,
I love Plex and being able to view stuff remotely is awesome.
You know, I can watch it at a friend's house.
Like I can watch my content at a friend's house
and, yeah, like I just, whatever,
there's a windows 10 machine with running a giant binary blob of code on my network.
-- Right.
-- Yeah. And I have no idea what's in it. And, right.
That's Flex is the reason I don't pretend my network is secure in any way.
What I always love is these people go through these network security shenanigans.
But then it's like, wait, do you ever take your laptop to a coffee shop?
And they're like, yeah, of course. I do. And I'm like, well, ok, then
didn't we just talk about unsecured networks a couple of days ago?
-- It definitely wasn't
-- yesterday pretty much
anyway.
So, I guess the point is so backdoors,
they exist, they will always exist. We're never going to make them go away.
But I think this is, while I detest Linus's law,
I think backdoors and open source have the unique advantage of.
They do seem to get found very often
-- and very quickly, more
-- to the point.
If you're putting code into something,
you should be able to explain why you're adding that code.
-- Like what feature does it add? What does it do? Right.
-- And if it's, if it's github,
you can't.
So,
all right, we will see you on December 15th.