Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
-- Josh
-- Pressers.
Oh, it's Thought Crime again. That's very exciting. We have
a
ghost.
Yeah,
I know we do. I'm super excited. We are here.
We have the man, the myth, the legend,
Larry Cash Dollar who is a senior security researcher at Akamai Technologies.
We have talked about Larry literally for years
and he's finally honored us with his presence.
Larry, welcome to the show.
Hey, it's great being here. We are ecstatic. So I guess we
start out, tell us who you are,
tell us what you do and then we'll get into some of the why you're here.
So I'm Larry Kasher.
I work at
a my technologies in the, the security intelligence response team.
And generally they sort of pay me to look for
either vulnerabilities on the internet threats on the internet.
-- So it's sort of like being paid to break things and write about them. So
-- awesome.
-- Awesome. And Kurt I'll let you do the honors. Why is Larry
-- here?
Well, because that one year he broke CV.
-- Oh, he didn't break CV, but he screwed up. All the stats. All right.
-- Let's go.
Why don't you?
Well, I guess Larry's here, Kurt doesn't have to explain what happened.
Larry, tell us what you've done.
-- I'm
-- assuming the year you're talking about is when I started
attacking Ruby Jams. Right.
Yeah. So the back story to this goes, I was bored
and looking for something to poke at on the internet.
That might be interesting to find vulnerabilities in.
And I noticed that there wasn't a lot of stuff for Ruby Jam.
So I decided to download a bunch of them and
just start looking through them at places where easy stuff,
you know, low hanging fruit where folks were
pulling in user supply data into, you know,
functions that were shelling out so you can get
command injection and found a bunch of stuff.
So I guess there were no
that impacted Ruby gems until I started poking at them and found a bunch.
-- So I don't remember how many, but it was a bunch. Wait,
-- there were none
-- before that.
-- I think there might have been one. Wow,
that's madness.
This is common for most of these large ecosystems.
Like if you look at Ruby gems or node or whatever,
they generally are quietly ignored,
-- chug along and
-- I don't know if I'd say that's necessarily true anymore.
I mean, it might have been back in the day for sure,
still ecosystems that are vastly ignored like every web
-- browser that's not Firefox chrome or edge or
-- Safari?
That's fair. That's fair. OK? So
we're not going to argue about this. Larry's here talking to Larry.
And I'm curious because one thing I noticed is
with the research you did on the Ruby gems is
you sort of set a cut off for like these
actually sort of have to matter like command injection,
for example.
Yeah, I was looking for code execution really was my thing for that.
I have this joy which I'm sure everybody else
has of getting code injection or command injection on,
on stuff. So that, that's what I was looking for.
And they were relatively easy to find just
looking for functions that would shell out,
you know, if somebody was executing a curl command and then sticking in
a
user supply data into the command line to for a query parameter
on the URL that I was looking for stuff like that.
And I found a bunch. So it was, it was a lucrative enterprise for me.
OK? But I mean, so you have a story to tell here.
I, I remember this has been like 100 years ago. I think you,
you I gave you my,
my, my B sides badge in Vegas one year and we had dinner together and
you're I I still I I must say, OK, so most people don't know this. So
uh this is like man, this 100 years ago, Larry basically puts on Twitter.
Hey does anyone have a Bides badge and I had an
one and I was like, I will give it to you but you have to come get it.
And I feel like a huge dirt bag because like,
you brought your whole family and you guys, like,
walked clear across Vegas and it's like, well, for, you know, FFS Larry,
I would have freaking brought it to you don't drag your whole family out.
But, but anyway,
we had a lovely evening because we went and had dinner and everything.
But you told me the story of kind of what you
did and how you found this and what all happened.
So recount that story for us because I think it's super interesting.
Is this the SG story or is this,
I have a lot of stories.
-- So you have to,
-- well specifically how you,
how you found all these Ruby Gems because it's not like
it's not like you went in and did it all by hand.
You actually had some automation that helped you do all this.
Yeah, I was,
I was a dork and I downloaded all the Ruby Gems
which was probably what like 10 megabytes back then at least,
right?
I can't remember how much disk
space it took it, it, it didn't take as much as you think.
But, but I ended up downloading all of them.
I think I scraped the page,
the Ruby Gem page and then parsed the html data to spit out the download URL
S and then pump it into a shell script and then downloaded all the URL S
or all of the uh the Ruby Gems and
then another script went through and un decompressed them.
I think they were Targ
zips that converted over and, and then
I ran a bunch of
other shell scripts to go through the code and look for key phrases, you know, like,
like uh execution commands or shell out commands
and, and you know, and then that created files that I could look at, you know,
to target is this piece of user input
being sent to something that is being passed to the shell and can I
stick a semicolon in there and get, you know, to execute ID?
So it was, it was a lot of fun.
I had to stop after months of doing that
because I started to have dreams about Ruby Gems,
which is, it's going to lead you to a psychotic episode eventually. If you're,
if you're dreaming about command injection and Ruby Gems, and you're
dreaming about code and
assigning IP addresses to people
in your dreams and it's time to take a break and walk away from that.
So it, it was getting pretty and
then I moved on, I think to wordpress plugins. So
-- that's
-- a healthy choice.
Those are equally more,
they were more fun. So
that's awesome. OK. So I guess this is
super interesting to me is
so you had all these, I guess, maybe bugs.
And how did you make, like,
how did you verify you were actually dealing with something real?
Because I think one of the,
the enormous challenges when you're bug hunting is figuring out, you know,
kind of the ham from the spam of the things
that cannot be exploited versus the things that can.
Yeah, I like to do proof of concepts for everything. So I would,
it was a real pain to try and
verify these bugs because some of these gems were
sort of,
you know, there was like this very small gem that would,
it was a little library that somebody wrote
to download,
like using curl to download binary packages or websites that you pointed at.
So I had to
try and put that
in a,
in a ruby environment that I could actually get it to run and execute and it
was tedious and in some cases near impossible
and annoying to just do something quickly.
So I started to target stuff like someone had implemented an FTP Damon ruby gem,
which it was a, it was a project that you could launch
and it would, it would have an FTP server that would listen on port 21
and you could FTP to it and, and use it like a regular FTP server,
except all of the commands that you were sticking in
the FTP server side were being shelled out to EXEC.
So if you did an LS
semicolon, ID, semicolon.
You'd get a listing of files and you were running his route.
So.
Oh, my goodness. So that was one of one of the fun Ruby J
ones that I had found.
Well, I mean, I, I remember when I had to go through one code base and I,
to introduce myself, I just looked for their temp vulnerabilities
and they had about, they had 13
and one of them was, they'd actually written
a
function to exec
bash.
It was about seven or eight lines long and they almost got it right.
They were so close if they'd included, oh, exec,
they would have been OK.
But like, yeah, sometimes people have to accomplish something and I, they,
they choose these, like Rube Goldberg machines
because that's kind of what they know or I, I don't know,
like, what, what are your thoughts on this Larry?
Because I, I feel like a lot of software flaws,
especially in these gem sort of plug in ecosystems.
You get these developers who like, I know how to do this. So like
everything I accomplish is done via this method.
Oh II,
I know what it's like to be on the development end
of that as a researcher a couple of years ago,
I, I, well, maybe two or three years ago I, I wrote my own web server and see,
uh years ago.
Yeah, it runs my website right now. This is not RFC compliant.
It's it's, it's pretty crappy code. It works.
You heard it here if you want to P
Larry?
Oh, it is.
So, so I wrote this web server.
I had fixed a bunch of bugs in it and I sent it to a friend of mine, his name is Vlad.
He's in France. He's my, one of my hacker friends.
He's really good with C and, and kernel development and things like that
and he's, you know, CTF
er
type guy. And I'm like, hey, why don't you look for V
abilities in this?
He's like, sure. And he compiles it on the system and he's running it and
he's like, hey, I have, I found a path transferal
bug and I'm like, what? He's like, oh yeah. And I got code execution.
I'm like, what the hell?
And I'm like, what the hell's going on? I'm like, all right. Hang on a second, man.
You're having a free for all on this. What, what did I do?
And I went through and I looked at my code and I realized that I had disabled
a function that I wrote to strip out any
malicious characters because I was doing some testing with
Aami network. What I, what I had done was I had put
my web server which, which was running off of a Raspberry Pi. I put it on
a network. So imagine a content delivery network that's got 150,000 servers
and they're using this little Raspberry Pi
uh as an origin server for my website,
vapid dot DH s.org.
So
which isn't on the CD N anymore? It's, it's Vapid
labs.com. It's on CD N now. So it was uh it was pointing at my web server and I had,
you know, all of
my like enterprise level solutions, like on my website, I have
w
you know, I had their DNS solution.
So my, my name servers like distributed or my DNS is distributed across
a
DNS clusters globally.
And
I had disabled the security features of my
web server because I was doing testing with
a WF because one of the things I did a lot of back then was attacking my own website
and um testing
my
uh
W
signatures and things.
So I had disabled this function
and then
stupidly sent it to my friend who,
you know, was
honing my, my software left and right because this, this was letting in every,
every character and field and thing that he uh
that he could throw at it.
And it was, I just felt like an idiot, you know, it's like, what were you?
I wasn't even thinking about
the security of it. I was just thinking about, you know, will a core dump on a system.
So I ended up, you know, it was, it was,
I knew what it was like to be a developer at that point.
And it's, it's, I've seen, you know, both sides of the coin where,
you know, you're,
you're looking for vulnerabilities and then you're writing software,
but not necessarily
thinking about security first.
And I, I being a researcher, I tripped over my own shoelaces there, you know,
so I kind of understand how developers can
make mistakes when they're doing the gold
borg
type implementations on their software.
Well, and this goes back to
something Kurt and I have talked about
multiple times
is you literally know what you're looking for and you
know what you're doing and you still made mistakes.
So expecting anyone to write bug free code
is a ridiculous expectation.
And I think it's worse with security
bugs because they're not immediately apparent,
right?
Like they need to be triggered.
You know, it's not like, oh, the background is the wrong shade of blue.
Let's fix that or, oh, it doesn't work at all. It just core dumps.
You know, the security bug is,
well, you know,
we've had those bugs in bash and open cell that were there for decades before
somebody found them.
It could be something really nuanced.
I remember I was looking at a, uh, a wordpress plug in with, I had an intern
that we had taken in on the
A my cert team and uh she was an intern from MIT
and she was studying computer science and she was really interested in,
in security vulnerabilities.
And I'm like, you know what
I'm like, let's find security holes together.
I said I'll download a random wordpress plug in.
So it's how cocky I was
back then and we'll look for holes in it.
And so we downloaded it. I set up a wordpress instance on our local machine
and sold the plug in. And so we started poking at it.
I realized,
or we soon realized that it had cross site scripting vulnerability which,
which was pretty easy to find and it was, you know, fun to exploit.
But I also found out in that same field, it had SQL injection.
So
we came up with two payloads, one to execute
the cross site scripting vulnerability and one to execute or,
or verify that there was SQL injection.
So it was kind of like a funny,
you know, the same
user input field on this was vulnerable to cross site scripting and SQL injection.
And we had to come up with two different payloads.
And um you know,
when she was all excited because she got to find a vulnerability with me and,
and, you know, actually see the process of looking for security holes. It was fun.
And now did that get one or two CV?
-- I,
-- I
think we ended up with four. I can't remember.
Nice because I think there was multiple
fields that also had other other vulnerabilities.
I don't remember what year that was was that 2017?
I don't know,
it was all hundreds of years ago.
-- This is
-- one thing I love when
people think that finding security vulnerabilities is hard
and it's,
I mean, it, it is,
there's a certain type of skill
and tooling to it.
But from what I've seen, you know,
just downloading literally like you downloading random code and looking at
it, it, it all has bugs and security flaws.
So, so back in the day before I was doing this in the
a of my
cert, I'd say like 2005, 2006,
I used to look at Trade Max
and look for software that they're advertising
like Linux
based software.
And then if they had a free demo, I would download it
and then I would just start poking at that
and I would find security bugs that way, you know,
bounce a couple of temp vulnerabilities that way. I think I found path
Veral in some software too.
So it was like, you know,
I was sort of shopping for something to attack by looking at a trade magazine.
Ok.
But now let me, let me ask you a follow up to that is so back in those days,
how often did you report an issue to a company?
And they basically said, go away nerd, we don't care.
You know, I actually lucked out pretty well. I,
all the companies that I had talked to were pretty receptive. So
I managed to, I mean, I've had, I have research friends who were sued
by, you know,
application developers because they
found a security hole in their I OS app, their, their mobile app and, you know,
they ended up having to deal with lawyers and court issues and I,
I lucked out maybe they just thought that
my name was fake and I'd be too hard to track down.
I, I love how that is a recurring theme with everybody.
You know, when I, when I talk about you, you know,
and when I know I've actually met him and that is his name.
Yes,
it's such a good name. You got to admit,
I do see people on some of the forums that defend my name, defend your name.
Yeah, saying it's real. I saw when I disclosed the Blue imp vulnerability that
Jquery file upload vulnerability. And I think that was 2018,
I was looking on a forum and I saw
one of my former Akamai
employees or employee or wasn't my employee, but he was an a
my employee uh
from the
Infosec group
and he was talking to people on Reddit saying no, Larry is his real name.
He's a nice guy and, and it's not made up and,
and that's because they were, they were having a debate on this Reddit,
you know that whether I was a real name or not. So it was a, it's pretty funny.
That's awesome.
Ok. OK.
So I guess 11 last question and then we'll move away from, from talking about the,
your, your ruby gem research.
So you found all these problems and then you got C VS for them,
which I think is amazing because I don't think
many researchers who find lots of problems do this.
So
how, I mean, how did that work? How was that painful? What did you have to do?
Because I know back then Miter was a lot harder to deal with than they are today for CV.
-- Si
-- remember folks were giving me ideas like
you should have a month of Ruby Jam vulnerabilities
and release a vulnerability once a day or you should release them all at once. And
I, I think I just pretty much would let me
know that I had, you know, a vulnerability and that I'd need a CV E
and they were,
I mean, they were pretty good, you know, they were pretty good to me.
Then they just would,
I think they had the cycles to process everything.
And then I think after that things just started to get overloaded and then
Kurt had to step in and start
create fork of his own
distributed weakness filing. So,
but I think that I think my,
I don't know if my thing broke it or not.
I know for sure. I skewed the stats for Ruby gem
vulnerabilities. I remember Steve Christie and Brian Martin
reaching out to me and saying,
hey, uh we're gonna make you famous and I'm like, what?
And they're like, yeah, we're,
we're doing a talk at black hat and we have a slide with you in it.
And I'm like, oh,
and I, you know, I don't really trust Steve or Brian too much. So, it's like, are they,
are they being
friendly, funny or they being malicious?
Like, I don't really know how to interpret these guys too much yet, you know.
So,
so I, I was talking about in my group, like, I just got a threat from,
from Steve
Steve
and uh
and Brian Martin and I, I'm not sure to be scared or happy.
So I reached out to like, I think it was Dave Lewis and I'm like, do you know
Brian Martin? Really?
Well, and he's like, yeah, he's a good guy and I'm like, why I'm like, well,
I'm scared.
He's like, no, don't be scared. He's like I talk to him.
He's like, it's gonna, it's gonna be good. And I'm like, ok,
so
my, I think the, the CSO
A Andy Ellis found out
and he's like, you have a slide deck,
they're doing the talk of black hat. There's a slide deck on you.
He's like, you need to be there.
He's like, you're going and I'm like, ok, he's like, we're gonna get you
tickets to Black Hat. And I'm like, oh, nice.
And you know, this was, I had just joined
Akamai
from, or I had just joined the Infosec group from the UNIX group
and the Infosec group was all about, you know, you could go to
all sorts of um conference and things. So it was, it was like,
it was sort of like being on the price is right?
And being showered with gifts, you know,
because you're not used to going to conferences when you're in UNIX administrator.
Are there any use?
N,
I don't know, I'm sure there is,
I'm sure there is VM Ware World or VM World or whatever they have. They,
they didn't send me to but um
but uh you know, but
infosec they just have the CSO like, yeah, you're gonna go,
we want you to go see what's on the slide and tell us about it and
it was really nice. So
it was good. It was just my, my skew on the ruby. They had a graph.
Well, I mean,
this isn't actually totally uncommon because if you look in CV database,
for example, there's
a company that did
a uh basically the mint token function of
a smart contract implementation for blank in Ethereum token
and there's like 380 of those.
Um And so a perfect example,
right is like CV has coverage of smart contracts to the tune of 500 CV S
all from 2018.
So the good news is that means that since 2018,
smart contracts have had no security flaws.
Right. Exactly.
Right.
Um So that's, that's what always frustrates me. I mean,
the whole CV database as a source of
data for making decisions about vulnerabilities globally is,
you know.
Yeah,
if once you learn how the sausage is made, you,
you understand that you can't use this as a reliable data source.
Right. Right.
OK. OK. Let's, let's, let's move on. We're, we're running ourselves out of time. And
I want to, I know and I feel like I could talk to you for days,
which we won't subject the audience to.
But
all right. So
before we hit record, you mentioned, I should ask you about your favorite CV E. So
what is your favorite CV E, Larry?
Oh, there's a, there's a few,
there's my first CV E and then one that I found shortly after that I,
I'll tell you about the first one because that one is probably the,
the most interesting.
And that's what people have been asking me about.
Back in 1998 1999.
I, uh I train, I moved from a small security company in Southern Maine
to Computer Sciences Corporation in Bath
Me, Computer Science Corporation, which, you know,
if you're not familiar with it is a pretty large, uh, like
company that was subcontracted by other companies
to sort of handle their it infrastructure
and Bath Ironworks had a contract to
have CS C manager their IT devices.
And I had gotten a job there and I went from
having access to, you know, maybe a couple dozen of machines to 3000. I mean, they had
3000 UNIX
A
UNIX systems ranging from uh Sgiirx machines to hphpu
machines to
so machines. Solaris
A IX
and
secure
wasn't
in the forefront of systems administration back then. It was
make sure this machine is running,
make sure the C AD D developers or C ad designers can use it.
Make sure that you know
when the desktop is imaged
or that the solar systems image that it, it's working,
you can run C AD on it and whatnot.
And um
it didn't matter if it was listening for every
service that son offered as long as it worked.
So
my first day
on the job I had, you know, my manager was showing me around
Biws campus because there's pretty big campus, there's multiple buildings
and we walk into this,
this new SG I lab that they just built and it's full of these SG I indie boxes,
indigo boxes.
And he says he sits down at one
and he says, you know, someday when you're, when you prove your worth,
I'll give you a log in on one of these systems.
And you know, me being from, coming from a security background, I knew that the LP
user on, on the IRA system had no
password. It had a valid shell and no password was blank.
So you could just walk up to an IR machine,
hit LP and hit enter.
So I walk up to an Ira machine.
I type in LP, I hit enter. I say thanks. I don't need one.
And my manager spins on his chair and he looks at me and he says,
how did you do that? And I'm like, I know
that these systems when they default don't have passwords assigned on LP.
And you could just log in.
And he looks at me and he says, will you do security for us?
And I said, I was hoping you'd say that
he pretty much let me
penetration test. Well, actually, I sort of
ran around the network breaking in the systems all over the place.
And
we had this one
machine room that had an SG I Onyx two in it.
Um If folks aren't familiar with an SG
Onyx two,
because it's, you know, a 25 year old computer,
it's about the size of a refrigerator. It was pretty much uh used for 3D modeling.
It had the reality creator or the reality 3d cards in them.
And,
you know, this system was anywhere from 250,000 to $500,000.
And now this thing is sitting in its own locked data center.
There's only a handful of assisted men who were allowed to go near it.
I was not one of them. I think there was only one or two guys that had access to that room
and these guys would taunt my friends and I my, my fellow coworkers. Hey,
you know,
we have access to the Onyx two and maybe someday you'll get access to the Onyx two.
And because, you know, I was assisted in level one,
they were like system in level three
and that, you know, kind of irked me. So I'm like, you know,
I want to get access to the Onyx and I want to get rude on it.
So
I'm like, how could I do that? So I started looking at um I had an SGI,
I think it was an indie that I had access to probably through the LP account
if I remember correctly. And
I'm like, how can I get rude on this box?
And I thought to myself, I'll,
I'll just start looking at set U ID route binaries because
because there's a bunch of them on here
and those are usually what you try and target and leverage back then to,
to elevate your privileges from an ordinary user to route.
And I, I started looking at user Espin and I saw
uh midi keys and I'm like, what's this midi keys
that set U ID root?
Let's let's fire it up and see what it is.
So I, I launch Midi keys in my, in my X window and
up pops this little keyboard
and it's this little piano keyboard that you can type on
or click with your mouse and it'll make little sounds.
So I'm like, why would this thing need
root access? You know, I thought maybe perhaps to access the sound card.
I'm like, I don't know. That's kind of odd,
but I can say files with it, edit files with it. Open files with it. What can I open
password? So, yeah, II, I ended up opening up Etsy password,
changed my Larry user id from whatever it was to zero, saved it
and s sued and got to,
you know, root as Larry. And I'm like, oh, neat.
I'm like, I'm gonna go try this on the Onyx too.
So,
so
I log into the Onyx two with LP,
I fire back an X window command or an X windows to my back to my desktop.
Launch midi keys,
edit Etsy password, modify the Larry account
to have a U
of zero log into the Onyx two as Larry
getting a root prompt and saying, oh, wow, I have root on the Onyx.
So I thought to myself, you know,
I should probably assign a password to the Larry account
because I don't want to leave this open. It's an open root account with no password
and I'll just change the password.
So I changed the password or I go to change the password and I realize
my user id is zero.
I'm changing the root password.
So I hit control D, control D
Iris took the password as control D.
So
I,
yeah, I changed the password on the Onyx two to control D
and at this time, I'm like, oh crap, I'm like,
I'm in trouble now. I'm like, I'm gonna have to go tell
the
Sidman guy that I just changed the password to control D
and he's gonna choke me because these guys didn't like me.
I was some 23 year old whippersnapper
who was running around blabbering about security.
So we already didn't have a good relationship.
So I asked my friend Donovan
who is much bigger than I am. He's like 6 ft three.
And I'm like, Donovan, can you go tell Dave that I,
I accidentally changed the Ro pastor on the Onyx two
to control D and he's like, sure
Donovan comes back about 15 minutes later or so, 20 minutes later.
And he's like, dude, he's like, they're so angry with you.
And I'm like, why, what happened? He's like
you changed the route password, right?
When they were about to give a demo to the US Navy.
And I'm like, oh my God, he's like,
there's an admiral in there with a bunch of senior management from our companies
and they're all standing around trying to log into the Onyx's route and,
and the password is not working.
And he's like, they had to scrub the demo and I'm like, oh my God, I'm like,
I'm getting fired.
That's it. I'm done. They're gonna kick me out.
So
Donovan is like, he's like, Dave came back,
he was able to change the room after because he had a show open on his desktop.
And I'm like, ok, and
So I'm like, all right, I got about a half an hour,
hour before my manager comes down here and throws me out.
And about an hour later my manager comes down, he goes, Larry.
He's like, I need you to come with me and we got to go talk to my manager in
a way.
Crap.
I'm like, here it is. I'm like, all right. So I don't have much stuff here.
You know, I'll be able to clear out my desk pretty quick and I just go home and,
you know, tell my wife, I just lost my job
and uh, I go into the,
into his manager's office
and I look on the wall and I see he's got a SANS security poster
and I'm like, wow, I'm like, this guy is actually,
you know, aware of
security, computer security, network security. So I'm like, cool
and I sit down and he goes all right, Larry, he's like I heard about the Onyx Two
and uh,
he's like, we're gonna need to change things and he's like,
before you do a penetration test,
he's like,
you have to tell the administrator that you're doing a penetration test and when,
and if it's ok because
things like the Onyx two incident today cannot happen.
He's like, you can't,
you can't make our systems unstable by testing their security and unavailable. So
he's like, you're gonna have to have, he's like, I want you to write up
an email to me and your boss to,
to tell us what machines you're planning on testing and when,
and then cc the administrators of those systems
and then get our, get everyone's approval before you go ahead.
And he's like, ok, he's like, you know, have a nice day and I'm like, great.
And I, I'm like, walked out, I'm like, elated, I'm like, I didn't get fired.
I got some legitimacy now that I can say, hey, my manager
and his manager are authorized me to ask to test your system.
Can you send me an email proving or, or give me a date when I can?
So
I, I lucked out again. I won. I kind of like,
you know, they,
they gave me some sort of some sort of framework
that I could work on in getting legitimized testing going.
It was, it was a good thing.
It actually helped me and I was all excited to,
to be able to post on bug track that I found this vulnerability in Iris
and then got my first CV ID.
That's awesome, man.
Curious,
how long did it take you to get all the systems like password on the LP account?
Uh I don't remember. Um I don't think we had ssh, then
I think they were still using Telnet.
So it wasn't something you could easily automate
they did have, I think they had open our remote R shell
where you could,
our shell into most machines just from, as root from almost any system
in the UNIX administrators network. So I think I might have,
I think I might have automated that. But you know what?
I think I automated it to where I had to keep typing in a new root password for, for,
or new LP password for all of the Ira systems.
I think I went back later and then just disabled the password
by putting an X where the, where the cipher text should be in the, in the
password violator. But
it was, I mean, I, I
had all sorts of fun with
a IX and stuff. I remember logging into an A IX machine
that was running the one team's um, local or infrastructure website.
One of the guys there was,
was savvy enough to have his own internal or internet website for their group.
And I logged into the machine by guessing
a password and then saw that they were writing
a file to temp
that they were executing that I had right access to.
So I ended up putting a Cron job in there to, to
set one of the shelves is set U ID root so I could get root on the thing. And then I
defaced their website with some hacker speak
and then sent it to my,
to my friend
and my manager
and
they were like, Larry, you can't do this, you can't do this hacker stuff.
He's like, you're going to scare the hell out of these guys,
you've got to just say, hey, you know,
I was able to get into your system. You can't deface their web page
in their infrastructure.
And I'm like, oh, yeah, that's probably, they don't know how to
speak either. So,
what are all these numbers?
So,
you know, I was in my twenties, I had a lot of learning to do.
-- Awesome.
-- All right, we are
100% out of time. I will give you the floor, take us home, Larry.
Yeah. So um it was great talking to everybody.
I just, you know, I enjoy doing these podcasts and, and talking to folks
and talking to you guys. I, I,
I've been talking to a lot of journalists and it's nice to talk to journalists and,
and then friends from the past, I haven't seen you guys in a while and
now being in isolation, it's, it's
nice to actually talk to other folks that are, you know, your friends.
Seriously, man.
Indeed, indeed.
Hopefully, hopefully in the not too distant future, we will see each other again,
summer camp.
I know I keep saying that. All right. Awesome.
Thank you so much, Larry. This has been a marvelous conversation. So
you can,
you can go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up our show notes, you a pound
to says podcast.
Hashtag You hit us up on social media, we'll put some links into Larry and his,
his awesome findings
and yeah, I guess Curt and Larry have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too.
You too. Thanks everybody.
Awesome. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.