Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 136 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Pressers.
So I uninstalled almost every app for my phone over the weekend.
Yeah, I
actually, yes, that was not the reason,
but it's,
my battery is rocking it right now. No, I realized that
I,
I, I'll be doing nothing and I'll just, like, whip up the phone and start, you know,
doing, looking at Twitter or looking at Reddit or, or whatever.
And I'm like, I'm just like killing time or, or I'll,
I'll have 10 seconds where I don't have anything to
do and I pull my phone out instead of,
you know, being like a functional human.
And I thought I'm, I'm tired of this and
this will tie nicely into our, our conversation later.
But it was basically one of those things of, I, I think
I can still get to everything that I took off.
I, I put a bunch of websites back in the browser and whatnot,
but I've made it slightly difficult for myself.
And so I've given myself a perception of
difficulty and now I've drastically altered my behavior,
which pleases me immensely.
Yep.
No, I'm the same way. I don't keep really much alcohol in the house because
I honestly can't be bothered to drive two minutes to a liquor store to get a beer.
Right. So, like, I'm pretty sure I'm not an alcoholic.
-- Right.
-- But you know, if it's in the house, why not?
No, I hear you, man. Like junk food. I'm terrible with that too.
It's like, oh, look, there's Doritos, I better eat those.
But if there's no Doritos, I'm not like, man,
I really could use some Doritos right now.
No, I hear you.
It's, it's funny how humans are so easily swayed in one direction or the other.
Well, I mean, I think that's the beauty of all this,
these attempts at online delivery services.
You know, where,
uh, what is it
dial for dine or whatever will now deliver mcdonald's and
like Tim Hortons to your house and I'm like,
who gets mcdonald's delivered to their house?
I have never done that. I, I know we have multiple de delivery services here.
There's like Uber Eats and Grubhub.
I
know that
all the more
and it's, it's one of those things where, yeah,
it's mcdonald's and stuff and I keep thinking, I,
man, if I need food delivered, it's not going to be mcdonald's.
But on the other side of that,
there are some very nice local restaurants on the list.
And so in those instances I think it's awesome.
Yeah, I know because github
has been in the news again.
Well, it just, it cracks me up because they, they have this appeasement strategy.
-- That's ridiculous and totally works. All right.
-- Well, first explain the story
-- that we're discussing. So this
-- time it's a thing called deep fakes.
And the idea is very simple. You take a neural network,
you feed it a bunch of pictures of somebody like say Steve
Buscemi or whatever.
And it basically creates a model of his face and then
you can insert that over top of somebody else's face in,
say a video or a photograph.
So you can basically, I, I could take your face and put it on top of,
you know, some politician giving a speech
or you could introduce, you know,
famous historical figures into modern events or vice versa,
right?
And it's also been used for pornography,
which is where it gets most of its attention.
Yeah.
So yeah,
people have created celebrity pornography by taking just
regular pornography and swapping in a celebrity's head.
-- So,
-- so we also say this is, this is open source so anybody can grab this code
-- and do it. Yeah, it's,
-- it's been around for, oh jeez.
I don't even know how many years now I have to check the first commit. But
um so github
has,
I guess the word hidden is technically correct.
No, they didn't hide it. They just added a silly restriction onto
-- going to
-- the, well, the web
interface, web
only the web interface. Yes.
So, so basically you have to be
a lo like a github
user. You have to log in with the github account and then you can go to the deep fakes
github
page. And if you're not logged in it basically pops up a hey, you have to log in page
and here's the best part though, is cloning the URL.
Yeah, you don't need to log in to do that
you can on. So it's like this is madness.
Well, and I've, I've been through this myself where
I had a repo that contained email addresses where people, you know,
agreed to an agreement, put their email address and it was very clear like
it said, your email address will end up in this repo for this reason,
it will be public.
Somebody made a GDPR takedown request.
And I'm like, well, I can't really comply with that because of how git works, right?
Unless I
delete the repo rewind.
Two years of transactions, take that one transaction out and replay them.
Your email address is in there.
Um But all that was needed was to actually just remove their email address,
like to, to delete it out of the file basically.
So even though it's in the get
log and the get, you know, commits back in the day,
they're ok with that because
what it seems to really boil down to in all cases is does this show up in Google or not?
That seems to be the problem, not that it's there, but,
but does it show up in Google results?
And I sort of understand that because quite frankly,
ok, Josh, I have this really cool article on something and I could describe it to you
and you're not going to find it in Google.
Does it exist? Is it like, it's like a tree that falls in a forest?
But Google doesn't know about it. Does it exist?
I think you could easily make the argument of it doesn't
because, I mean, well, look, I run
a multitude of blogs and obviously the podcast
and various other,
I guess social interaction style sites.
And I can tell you now that the amount
of traffic that comes from Google is it's significant.
I mean, if, if my stuff
traffic,
like the amount of new traffic, like people discovering your site,
if you're not in Google, you're dead.
Uh Yeah.
And, and funny enough,
so one of the other things I've come to realize over time is everyone thinks, oh,
you gotta be on Twitter and you gotta be on Facebook and
you gotta be on linkedin and this and that and that,
and, and the reality is those sites have abysmal click through rates.
I get almost no traffic from those places.
Now, if you hit Reddit or hacker news,
those places are outrageous which the traffic you get from.
Those,
I think part of it is people who go to, like Reddit and hacker news,
they're looking for new things to, to interest them and to interact with.
Whereas Twitter is kind of more of a news feed.
It's something I consume, but I don't go beyond it.
Yeah.
And that, that's exactly what I see when I look at my statistics and so, like,
I love Twitter, don't get me wrong.
But even when I think about it, I don't click a lot of links.
That's not even my primary concern.
I feel like I don't want to stop and look, I'm just scrolling through
the, like, you know, mental diarrhea of Twitter
and that's, that's why I'm there. Right.
It's like, it's like,
totally going and sitting at a bar and
just listening to people argue about insane things.
Well, it's like watching the, uh,
not the regular news but the news that they show at the airports.
Right. No, no, no. That's exactly what it is.
It's, it's so painful.
Like every time I fly I watch it for about three
or four minutes and then my brain is just like,
nope.
No, you, no,
just, no.
Yeah, that's fair. So,
so anyway, so Github,
let's, let's
-- back from the, the reality
-- is for Github.
Just simply making it. So it doesn't easily show up in a Google result.
That's enough to appease these complainers and
they go away
and, and honestly,
if I was a business and I could get
rid of somebody complaining by doing something that simple.
-- I absolutely would.
-- I agree with you.
And I think that the, the way I want to tie this into security as well is
there's,
there's an attitude in our industry of kind of perfect or nothing where, what Github
is doing isn't perfect.
And so why even bother?
And
it's one of those things that to you or I, we look at this, we're like,
this is ridiculous and stupid,
but most people look at it and it feels good to them and they think good job github.
You did something.
Now there's something that's completely worthless, but it doesn't matter
if
it takes the results out of Google honestly, for most people that's good enough,
it might be, it might be I
-- and like,
-- well to tie this in that,
that mug shot site that posted people's mug shots and
you had to pay a fee to get them taken offline
so that, you know, when somebody Googles your name,
they don't have to put your mug shot
and that's actually what's needed because that data, well, I mean,
that's my understanding is the classic case of Florida man.
The reason Florida man is so popular
because all of the Florida records are public like from the minute they're entered.
So that's why they get
such a bad rap is because just all their stuff is transparent and exposed.
Whereas, you know, other
states
to Florida
-- uh
-- No. II, I do know that it's somewhat bonkers.
It's pretty bonkers and I'm,
I'm going to agree with you that I think the fact that
the records are public makes it seem worse than it is,
but it's, it's pretty bad.
-- Like Florida is a crazy place.
-- Well, you can see how bad it is.
Right.
You know, whereas most states kind of keep it on the down low
and, and let's face it, Any populated state is full of crazy people.
I mean, California is, is in many ways worse than Florida,
which I can't wait for the responses to that, bring it on everybody
-- but it, right. It's just one of the miracle.
-- It's just the law of averages. Right.
-- You get 30 some odd million people and right. Right.
-- Statistically speaking.
Exactly.
So, anyway, anyway, here's, here's what I want to kind of tie this to.
So there was a discussion I had some time ago
where someone was basically saying we want to do
this security thing and actually I'll explain it.
I don't have to give away all the details,
but basically what it came down to was somebody wanted to know when,
when users were changing their password and
they wanted to basically take every line and
at sea shadow and
hash it and then store part of the hash
in a database and then you could say, oh, this hash changed.
So we know this user changed their password or, or something.
Right.
-- Something
-- doesn't
seem
unreasonable, but I would have just done it through Pam, but whatever
this is. Right. I, I, yes,
I agree with that. And that's, that's part of where the conversation ended up.
And here's what I basically said was
there's nothing technically wrong with this and it's not unsafe in any way,
but it doesn't, it's not going to feel right to users because now you have a process
reading Etsy shadow
over and over again constantly.
Right.
And so,
well, it has to read it to hash all the entries. Right.
But why can't it just, like, read it when the file changes or a user changes? Right.
Yes. Exactly. Right. Read it when it changes.
But you know what I mean?
Assuming, but every time you log in it updates a file because it also,
you know what I mean?
There's like,
there's a lot of crazy that goes on with this stuff. Ok.
And so
it was one of those things where it, it's technically correct, but it feels wrong.
Right. And I think this github
thing is the opposite where it's technically incorrect, but it feels right.
And this is where security.
I think a lot of times we fail to take that, like, ridiculous human element into,
into play.
And, I mean, this is totally like me taking all that crap off my phone.
It's, it's basically all still there,
but I've made it slightly more difficult for myself.
So, I'm, like, ah, screw it. I don't care.
Right. Like, this is like, humans are ridiculous bags of meat.
And I think we forget that a lot.
Oh, absolutely. And I, I love actually that the, um, the iphones by default.
Now, if you don't use an app for long enough,
it basically removes the app from your phone,
but it leaves the icon and it leaves like the little cloud with an arrow icon.
So, yeah, perfect example, here I've got an app called TV.
I don't even know what this is.
And if I click on it,
it's going to say loading and it's going to download
it from the app store and then run it.
Uh, whereas if I actually delete it, I'll probably forget
what TV is. I literally, this icon just says TV.
Right?
Um, delete TV. Yeah, whatever. I don't know what this does. Ok?
I probably don't need it and now it's gone and I'll,
unless I go to the App store and actually go hunting for it,
but it's gone.
Interesting.
Well, because I mean, you know, if that's the thing, I,
that's one thing I don't like about the App Store is,
is finding stuff that you've previously
installed but forgotten about can be tricky
because their search isn't great.
Um, because, you know,
over the years I've gone through hundreds of apps and deleted a bunch of them, right.
Especially kids games
because you know, the
very family account thing
so,
yeah. No, it's the, I
think what it boils down to is the appearance of security or the appearance of
we solve the problem versus actually solving it.
Right. Right.
And most people, the appearance that's, that's good enough
because they're not gonna, who digs into these solutions in autism.
You know, I, like I said, I had the alternator in my car changed out a few weeks ago.
Uh, my battery was dead and, or was dying and,
you know, it probably wasn't the battery because it was only two years old.
And so went in, took it in. They're like, yeah, your alternator is failing.
Do you want us to replace it? And I'm like, yeah, probably should be done and
they say they replaced it,
right?
I mean,
am I going to dig through my engine and try and figure out
if that alternator is newer than the one I used to have?
Uh, so my father
in law works on cars and he said, always ask for the parts because that way
they, they have to give you the old parts.
They, they don't do that often times here because I did actually, for example,
swap out the rear windshield wiper motor
and they basically, when you buy the rear windshield wiper motor, you pay an extra,
like 80 bucks and you get that 80 bucks back
when you bring the old one back because they want the
casing so that they can put a new motor in it and recondition it because
that casting is,
well, they're not making them anymore.
And you literally put in a new, you know,
$2 motor from some Chinese company that makes whatever exactly you need.
I'm sure they just go to Aliexpress and buy the one they need.
Pop it in and bam, you've just reconditioned a part.
Nice,
you know, for a few bucks
which I totally support because from an environmental point of view, that's great.
-- That's what we want.
-- Yeah. And, and that's fair.
But, I mean, in the instance of if your rear wiper didn't work,
you know, if you got a new one
-- and
-- I would know if my alternator doesn't
work because my car would have stopped starting.
Right. I, I had so funny enough, my alternator also went out a couple of weeks ago
and, but my, mine seized up
and it broke my belt.
So,
yeah, I got to pay for another belt
because,
and a new alternator
and then I, I, yeah, it was pretty obvious that they replaced it just because, like,
the car started so good job guys.
-- Well,
-- but did they replace it with a new one? It looks
very nice.
And I actually know the guy who owns the shop
so I'm pretty confident if they're screwing people over.
I'm not on the list.
But, you know, that's exactly right.
I don't have enough domain knowledge to look at a car part and say
if it's new or used or old or even if that's a problem.
Right. Because
there's a lot of car parts out there that
sure it's 10 years old. That's fine. It's been reconditioned, it's been certified
and that's fine.
But again, perception, right, it all comes back to perception and humans,
our perception is our reality.
You know what? That's very true.
Our perception is reality because unless we go digging deeper to actually
what's going on,
how would we know?
Right.
And this is what makes security so annoying, I guess is we, we always dig deeper,
right?
We totally know what's going on now.
Now,
I'm going to put a big asterisk here and
I hope someone's like throwing their shoe at their,
their phone right now
is things like crypto
yet, perception isn't reality in crypto reality is reality in crypto.
Well,
I think it goes deeper than that is
most computing systems now are horrendously complex.
Like witness all the specter meltdown vulnerabilities,
you know, that wasn't even, well, it could sort of be corrected in software,
but I wouldn't blame software on this.
That was, you know,
hardware manufacturers doing tricks to make the hardware go a lot faster.
Which
honestly, I mean,
when you think about the amount of electrical energy they
probably saved over the last decade alone makes it worthwhile.
But these systems are so complicated. Now, I was reading
the Cloud Flare blog and they were talking about this TCP, socket
reassembly thing.
And the thing is they're benchmarking this stuff and
they're getting results that they can't fully explain.
And they're, they even had a,
a chart where they were talking about some
of the behave like the foundational behavior of,
you know, socket versus these other things.
And they had, yes. No. And then question marks.
So, so the software has gotten so complex in the Linux kernel.
But you can't even say with a high degree of certainty
how something behaves or what it does in some cases.
So I I've not read this blog.
So they're saying that it's, it's faster or slower or what's what's happening.
Well, so here it is. So basically they're talking about this thing called uh sock
map TP splicing
for so for level seven proxies.
So they talk about send file versus splice versus VM splice.
Now, they know for sure kind of how they work. Send file. Does this file to a socket?
Right? Reads it in boom fast. OK.
Uh It's definitely avoiding a user space memory copy
and it's zero copy. It, it is not zero copy. Now, splice is a pipe to a socket.
Cool pipes are great. Get it to a socket fast. It avoids the user space memory great.
But is it zero copy? Well, it's yes with a question mark.
And then there's VM splice which is memory region to a pipe avoids user space memory.
No and zero copy. Yes. And then
there's literally some more results later on where it's just uh
here we go, splice cis call cost two cis calls waking up user space.
Yes, copying cost zero, copy question mark and brackets
interesting,
right?
So, and,
and that's the real you and I have both dealt with Linux kernel issues
where trying to define the behavior of a specific version of the Linux kernel,
let alone multiple versions spanning even like version
three and four where you have major modifications
is very nontrivial,
you know, especially in the networking space. And you know,
some of these things where there's just so many moving parts
and there's been so many changes over the last two decades.
Yeah.
Yeah, I mean, that's,
that's fair.
But at the same time,
there are a small number of people who really
care and for the vast majority of others,
whatever, right? I I feel good because my computer says it's faster than whatever.
And I mean, I I'll pick on specter and meltdown here, man.
How many instances of specter and meltdown being actually exploited in the wild?
Have you heard of
-- the
-- answer is zero, right? It's zero.
And, and I'm not saying it's not being exploited,
but it's one of those things that we everyone lost their minds
for really no reason. I think the reaction to the actual issue was highly overblown
and this like deep fix stuff, right? People are freaking out
and the reality is, it's like
it's probably not as bad as you think, but it's easier for github
-- to just be like, yep, we are taking it seriously. Everybody look at us
-- in some ways.
It's worse because you can't
solve this with technology solution.
This is a very fundamental human thing of when humans have
been conditioned that when a picture is worth 1000 words,
a picture doesn't lie.
Video, never lies. Right. You, you watch surveillance video of a crime?
Yeah, that must be correct. That's what happened.
You know, that's, that's what we've been trained, you know,
same thing with DNA evidence in court cases.
You know,
and if you read some of the studies now it turns out
some states in some areas have really messed up their DNA evidence
calling into question a lot of criminal convictions.
But, you know, juries have been trained, hey,
-- this DNA matches this boom case closed
-- and, and here's what I'm going to go back to
on this topic is the ability to fake video isn't new.
It's just, it's becoming
attainable for nearly everybody. Do you remember the hacking tool, Satan
or even, I mean, metas
will, will pick on to a degree.
Let's go with Satan because that was such a big kerfuffle.
And now it's a professional and nothing happened. Well, not even that.
And now it's a professional product
but you're
required by PC I to run
or some version of that tool you're required to run on your knees.
And here's the thing though is, again,
we learn of a new thing
and we all lose our minds
and the world is gonna end because now something that was hard is easy.
And in,
I would bet you in 99% of those cases
it doesn't matter. And this is even true of security.
We do this all the freaking time, man, where everybody loses their minds because,
I mean,
uh, we could pick on the container runs sea thing, right?
Which we just talked about a little while ago. Is, is
it, is it bad? Yeah, it's bad. Is it as bad as people say? It is?
Probably not.
Well,
it kind of reminds me of like how many
magicians hate Penn and Teller for revealing their secrets.
-- Whatever
-- man, those guys are the best.
I know. Exactly.
So it's kind of like that there, you know,
magicians used to have that code of never revealing how a
trick is done so that they could protect their industry effectively.
Right.
-- Right.
-- In, in, in all.
But here's part of that too is I would
say Penn and Teller have saved the magic industry.
Oh, yeah, they've made it interesting again.
Right. And before them, I remember
so a real long time ago there were a lot of magicians that,
that they claimed they had real magic.
And this is actually something Houdini loves to do is he loved to,
to basically trick the Charlatans and catch them in the act.
And of course, the funny enough,
one of my favorite quotes from Houdini is I think he was testifying before Congress.
And someone basically said, what's the difference between you and them?
And he said the only difference between me and them
is you will never know how my tricks work.
That's freaking awesome.
Yeah. But anyway,
the point is right is
as humans,
we are very bad at assessing situations and
you look at something like Penn and Teller.
And I think if you would have looked at it 2030 years ago,
you would have said these guys are going to ruin the magic world
and the reality is they probably saved the magic world
now that we can look at it in hindsight.
And I think this is very true of, of nearly every situation.
Security people look at and say, oh my goodness, the world's gonna end
in less than 10% of situations is our reaction
actually correct for the severity of the problem.
Well, it's also really hard to
have a reaction to something that is air quotes. Correct because
there's so many 2nd and 3rd order effects.
You know, one of my favorite examples of this is,
is a lot of police forces now
are putting their graphical information systems online
to show crimes like in the last 30 days, last 60 days, you know,
the Edmonton police do it, the London Metropolitan Police do it.
And what the London, what they found in London was, is in richer areas.
People stopped reporting property crimes because they didn't
want to drive their property value down.
Yeah. Right. Exactly. You know. Exactly.
And you can't always think of what's going to happen next.
Yeah.
Well, and part of it too is human behavior is quite often for lack of a better term,
broken or wrong.
And that's just how humans are.
And for example, can we teach people to really critically like watch video
and not, you know, from a technical point of view, figure out if it's true or not,
but from sort of a critical thinking point of view, say,
OK, who produced this video? Why did they release it? What was their agenda?
You know, could this, you know what if this video was faked? What
you know, why, why would they have done that?
You know, for example, if you see a video of a famous politician eating a baby,
right,
I'm gonna say it's probably fake. I'm really hoping it's fake. But
um
you know,
but I feel like a lot of people would act with just
instant outrage and just go from zero to pitchforks and torches,
you know, in 30 seconds.
So here's my thought on this is I don't think you're wrong
that people will overreact because I think it's human nature to overreact and
at the same time
that is fraud,
right?
You can't do things like that to people because it's,
we have laws that govern that and that's where
you need proper police investigations
to figure out who did this.
And then you go get them
because
you can, everyone will say, oh,
but you could do it anonymously and use the black web and blah, dark web, black web,
the dark web
and you know, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
But the reality is it's very, very difficult to do things truly anonymously.
And if you do that,
I hope you get caught
and you deserve to get caught.
Well, I just, I can't help but wonder, you know,
with all the election shenanigans going on in
the UK, the US Canada.
And I don't mean like actual shenanigans with the election but just the,
the advertising and the, the Facebook postings and all of that influencing stuff
that apparently works because again, humans,
you know,
they see something and they believe it to be
true because by and large up until recently,
we haven't
kind of had,
we've only ever really had sort of propaganda at the state
level where it was kind of obvious it was propaganda.
But now, you know, you can have individualized propaganda based on well,
advertising, right?
You just use the same techniques we use for online
advertising to instead of sell a product to sell an idea
and that this political party is evil or that, you know,
Brexit is a good idea and sorry, I'm going to go right out here and say,
I think Brexit is a bad idea.
I think everybody in Britain pretty much knows it.
And I don't understand how they're not just getting off
the crazy train and saying let's not invoke article 50
-- maybe just take a breath.
-- So John Oliver has some videos about this you should watch.
It's,
it's insane to say the least.
-- Oh yeah,
-- I was reading about Corbyn and May and it's just bonkers.
It is.
But again, this is, this is how humans work. We are bad at this stuff.
Now, here is the ray of sunshine. I will shine down on us all
before we end this because I feel like we most of our podcasts like
you're going to be huddled under a blanket by the end of it.
And I'm going to say in
this instance,
I think it's going to be ok, but not yet. We got, we got a ways to go. If you look at
the way the newspaper industry worked
at the turn of the century,
it was super messed up man because
you had these newspaper industrialists that were controlling
all of the discussions about everything the people they wanted to win
in politics were winning.
They would make up news that, that made them look better.
They would cover up stories that could make them look bad.
It was crazy town, right? It was very, very messed up.
Well, and there was no other way to find out about this stuff. Right.
If,
if it didn't happen in the newspaper or I guess maybe
on the radio and back then TV wasn't really a thing.
It just didn't exist much like the Google search results.
And, and so here's the thing though is
I think the reason that happened is because
humans as a species
were unprepared to deal with what was going on around them
and we gained the ability to deal with it.
And now part of it was obviously old people went away
and new people figured out how to deal with it.
I see this with the young people,
young people are extremely skeptical of things they see online
and my parents believe every freaking thing they read and it's like holy cow.
Oh, it's, it's even worse than that.
There's a lawsuit that was announced a few days ago.
Uh course entertainment is this giant
Canadian media conglomerate that owns a bunch of radio stations.
And in Ontario, uh
obviously they take advertising on these radio stations.
These two scammers ran these ads that were not, well,
they were apparently labeled as ads but not so much that you would really notice.
But it was like a half hour or something call in show with these financial experts,
giving advice to invest in this company.
So people did, they literally based on listening to the radio,
these radio shows for a few months or weeks or whatever,
invested their life savings into this company that turned out to be a complete scam.
Yeah. I'm not at all surprised.
Well, but the best part is now there's a lawsuit against these two guys,
which I totally get
and also against chorus entertainment
and I really don't want to blame the victim.
But if you listen to a radio program a few times and then
decide based on that to invest your life savings into a company,
how do we protect you from yourself?
People do it, man. People do it all the time. Yeah,
but that's what I mean is how do we, you know,
how do we protect people from themselves when
legally speaking, they're adults who have autonomy and agency and are allowed to do
what they want with their money by and large,
you know,
how do we stop them from investing in a scam or a multilevel marketing scheme or,
or heck buying beanie babies. You don't or?
Oh, better the fidget spinners,
you know those things that were popular and are now landfill.
Uh Yes, I had a lot of them. I ever went to one of the, some conference.
I think it was a black hat conference and I came home with something
like 45 fidget spinners for my kids and they thought it was great and
I guarantee they're all in the trash now or under the beds. I don't know which.
But,
and here's the deal, man is,
I'm not saying we should stop. Absolutely. Everything.
I think in some instances I'm not going to blame the victims.
I just think this is how humanity works. I'm not saying people are bad necessarily
and there's always going to be some people who, you know,
some apples fall off the cart.
It's just, unfortunately the way it works
and
it sucks when it's you. It totally does.
But this is also why you need some social structures in place.
Like I hope this is illegal and if it's not, it freaking should be
and those people should definitely,
granted they're going to get probably sued to death.
I'm sure their money is long gone at this point
and no one's ever going to get anything back.
But, I mean,
this is one of those just social constructs where we need things in place.
This is the same thing with, like, the news,
the newspapers can't just make up news anymore because it's illegal.
-- Why? Because they did it
-- well, but they, they can still do opinion pieces
-- which if labeled as such are allowed to be whatever they want.
-- Yes.
And I think that is the next great challenge is going to be
what do we do about this?
Because a lot of,
a lot of opinion is being brushed off as news these days and that's obviously not.
Ok.
Well, as fact, I think it's a lot of opinion is being brushed off as fact.
Yes, that's fair. It's still news.
Well, yeah, but I mean, it's just, there's news but then there's news that's,
we know to be factual as
to.
Yeah, I mean, look at us, man, this is totally opinion. Right.
Anyone who thinks this is news.
So I don't, I don't know,
I feel like this is the next great leap we need to make as a civilization and a culture.
And
I think, I think we'll do it.
I really do because the option is basically, you know, the movie Idiocracy.
And
I'm,
I hope we don't end there. And I don't think we will though.
I think if you look at the history of humanity,
the youth have always persevered against whatever craziness is going on.
Whereas the elderly
have a very bad track record here and I don't
look forward to being elderly because everything is changing very fast
and to be clear, we don't mean just to
elderly. But, you know, you look at what was it?
I think it was Plato or Socrates throughout history.
Diatribes written about the, you know how the youth of today is so blah, blah, blah.
Right. Exactly. And it's always been the case and it always will be.
And in fact, it's funny, I talk to my kids about this where they're like, oh, so,
and so's mom won't let them play video games.
I'm like, eh,
that's up to them. But I mean, let's face it, man.
Like this is just life now, you know, play some games. It's it's the way it is.
So, anyway, I,
I think we should call this one before we delve back into some sort of dark,
terrible secret
about humanity.
But no, I do, I think, I think we're going to be ok,
but I think we've got some crazy things to learn along the way.
And I think like we github
is done
is
basically the stop gap
that we're going to see more and more people do where
they're going to do things that while not technically correct,
and it's good enough and it makes people happy and that's
sometimes that's the best you can do so. All right, sweet. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. Go to open source security podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes. You can use the Pound O
podcast hashtag to get our attention on social media.
-- Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too, everybody. Thank you.
-- Thanks,
-- everyone. Bye bye.