Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 123 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
Hey, Kurt. And today we are joined, we have a guest.
We have Liz Rice who is a technology evangelist with Aqua Security. Say hello, Liz.
Hello,
I resisted saying hello, Liz.
That's ok. Bad jokes are more than welcome here.
So awesome. So thank you so much for joining us and, and I guess
you just wrote a book. I, I found out it's called Kuber
Neti Security. Tell us a little bit about that.
-- Yeah.
-- So my pleasure to be here. Um
Yeah, myself and my co author,
Michael Hasen
from Red Hat. We wrote a book on Kubernetes Security for o'reilly.
And yeah, it was,
we felt that it was important to try to
give people some kind of pointers to best practices.
There, there are lots of things about Kubernetes
that you can
make really insecure through bad configuration or bad practices.
So we wanted to try to enumerate some of those and help people avoid
-- walking into those traps.
-- That's, that's all.
So, I guess, ok, I'm gonna I'm gonna put you on the spot. Now. What, what are the traps?
Right. If, if I, I'm going to run Kubernetes, what do I need to watch out for?
As, as I will admit, I, I run like, what is Mini
Co
right for, for my various personal projects.
But I,
I am totally inept about running Kubernetes at scale other
than things I've read or things I guess about.
Sure. So, um, some of the
kind of obvious things that you shouldn't be doing are leaving your
C TIS dashboard open to the public internet, which uh has been done,
you know, by I,
I believe uh Tesla was the, the company that did that.
Um
You can also very easily, particularly with older versions of
C tis, the defaults tended to be insecure
so you could very easily be running with your
API like the whole
server,
the API server port um open to
any,
you know. So,
uh making sure that you've got authentication set up is
one of those really basic things that you
definitely want to do.
And it's funny you mentioned that because I specifically remember having,
like I,
I used to do CV S at Red Hat and specifically
doing CV S for Kubernetes with Jordan Liggett and others.
And I remember those things came up and, but in Kubernetes defense, I remember that
Kubernetes sort of explicitly had documented that, you know,
you probably shouldn't do those things
and they were I think in general, uh,
at least a year or two ago in the process of switching to much better defaults.
That's absolutely right. And they have got much better defaults.
It kind of depends what installation tool you're using.
Yeah, that was the big thing is
what it boiled down to, is there were secure ways to install it and, yeah,
unfortunately some of the installation tools made some
-- well, you know, it worked when you install.
-- Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. But you needed to,
it, it's a good idea to check some of these things and, and things like um you know,
there's role based access control now, which wasn't there.
Well, a few versions ago, it's a really great thing.
If people are still running on an older version that doesn't support it,
then we're basically advising you might want to think about upgrading
and, and then there's all sorts of things that you can uh do to improve security
in the application code. So in the container images that you're gonna run,
um making sure that you're scanning those for
vulnerabilities or all that kind of good stuff.
So there's various different layers at which
you want to look at security when you're operating.
Ce
That's interesting. Actually, I, I don't think that's something
that we necessarily think about
in
kind of in, in most development environments, right?
Where we focus on our own code and our own,
I guess applications and deployments.
But you're right,
there's there's Kubernetes itself which needs security and there's as well as
obviously the containers you're running need some level of security as well.
Which is like, I mean, I, I feel like
this is a point
that people have been beating the drum on forever now.
And do, do you think it's ever gonna end, like,
secure your freaking containers people?
Right.
Well, I,
I continually sort of
surprised and surprised and not surprised that if I do a talk and I might
suggest to people that they should
be scanning their container images for vulnerabilities
and an awful lot of hands in the room
don't go up if I ask if they're actually doing that.
So
one way or another people aren't necessarily
checking whether or not the containers they run,
have got serious vulnerabilities in them
and, and obviously, that's a big problem.
So uh I feel like one of my,
my big missions at the moment is to make sure that everybody that I talk to knows,
you know, you can scan your images, you don't have to be paying for at all.
Like Aqua,
there are free solutions available that are pretty good and
we've got a free solution that we give away.
And there are open source tools, there's Claire and, and Anor.
So
there's no real excuse to not be incorporating an image scanner in your
deployment pipeline.
OK?
So, so let's let's touch on that then because you,
you work for Aqua Security which obviously has a container scanner
and I didn't know you guys had a free one.
That's really cool. Actually, I'm, I guess
so. Let's for, for people who might not know, let, can you explain to us kind of
what is the problem with
when we talk about container scanning? What, what is the problem that's solving?
And then let's talk about what does it mean when
we scan a container as well as how do we,
how do we fix that?
Well, let's say that the scanner does find something. What does that mean then?
Sure. OK.
So
what we're doing when we scan for vulnerabilities,
we're looking for these known vulnerabilities, what's called CV ES
the things like shell shock and heart bleed and, and you know,
thousands of other known problems that exist in third party codes that
you the dependencies that your application is very likely relying on.
And the problem is that when we move
from a sort of traditional software monolithic environment,
when we move from that to containers,
every container is bundling up application code with its dependencies.
And if you have a lot of containers, that means a lot of copies of those dependencies.
So each different
container could have a different set of packages and
a different set of these vulnerabilities included in that.
So
the key to dealing with this is automation,
uh like everything in the sort of modern DEV
ops world, everything
has to be automated
and you can build an image scanner into your build process
to make sure that every container image you build is scanned
by which we're looking at the contents of that container image
matching it against or or matching all the the packages against
a database of packages and their known vulnerabilities
and reporting back to you whether there's
you know, significant issues or not.
So for example, you might choose to fail the build
if there's high severity vulnerabilities in an image because
you really don't want to be deploying that.
And uh the, the sort of level of sophistication on, on what policies you
uh
you might choose to deploy or not.
Uh that will be the difference between a free scanner and a, and a commercial one.
But with a free one, you can find out whether you've got
high, medium, low severity issues in your code and
ideally not deploy the ones that have got significant problems.
Indeed.
All right. So
II, I love this topic.
I've been the, the problem with dependencies is something dear dear to my heart.
And I've been talking about this and, and dealing with, I deal with it right now.
In fact, I've got some things happening
at work that are, are dependency related and, and it's always a treat.
And I guess
here's the thing
I don't think people understand and I,
I'd love to hear some of your thoughts on this is, is it's kind of,
it's dependencies all the way down, right?
Because open source product, you know,
you might have an application that depends on open source,
but that open source depends on other open source
and that open source depends on other open source.
And you can imagine this kind of starts forking out of control very, very quickly.
And I think that's something people often don't understand is
that you're not including one library in your application,
you're probably including 10 or more once you walk your way down that chain.
Yeah, it's really true. And, and do you remember that thing that happened with um
uh the N PM,
the node package management that exactly the
left left padding or something like that,
wasn't it?
Yeah,
the shift left.
Yes.
And uh yeah,
basically the internet got broken because of
one dependency that was included by everything.
Uh Yeah.
So I guess that can be a lesson to us all.
Well, I know for uh what was it openshift, you know,
which is Red Hat's sort of version of Kubernetes with some special sauce on top.
And
the last time I checked the open source version was pulling in
something like 1200 dependencies.
Um, you know, not even that bad and, and well, and quite frankly, you know, I've,
I've, I've seen developers where
they need,
I forget what they needed but they're like
whatever and they just pulled in all of ruby
and I mean, all of it.
Right. And, and in fairness, their code worked,
you know.
And I'm wondering so.
So that's one thing I've been seeing is, you know, we,
we seem to now have a maturing market for security scanners where it's like, OK,
you know, this version is bad to have CV.
Food, don't, don't deploy that, you know, or if you do deploy it,
you need to fix that real soon now.
But one thing I'm not really seeing is sort of this dependency management thing,
that sort of a meta level of,
you know, do you actually need all these dependencies or, you know,
are you pulling in this one thing that pulls in
16 million other things? Um
that maybe you don't actually need, you know,
there's a lot of libraries that pull in stuff
that
you don't necessarily need them to do.
Like maybe they pull in the G zip and you, you know,
you're not actually using the compression part or
um well, the LIB XML gets pulled in by damn near everything it's usually used. But
is there any hope or any solution for this where it's sort of,
you can minimize your dependency chain in an automated way?
I think that's a great question. And yeah, a difficult problem to solve.
I haven't come across anybody solving it by
sort of removing unused dependencies like that.
And
uh but we do see this problem quite a lot with base images for containers that include
a whole Linux distribution,
which is fair enough except that most of the time
you're not gonna use very much of that Linux distribution.
So you're kind of leading me on to another one of my favorite topics,
which is about runtime protection
where one of the cool things that we do in the
aqua products and this isn't open source unfortunately.
But, um, we, we were basically saying given a profile of a container or its image,
we know what normal behavior looks like.
So my favorite example is
X, when you're running engine
X,
there is only one executable that should be running and it's called engine
X. So if you can stop all the other executables from running,
you know, even if there is,
I don't know some kind of network facility built into the container image,
if you can prevent those executables from running,
even if your container gets compromised, there's,
there's very little that an attacker can do because
they're just gonna get permission denied for every executable
that isn't gen
X. So that's like a super powerful
that,
that we can do at run time.
And you couldn't really do that in the sort of monolithic era because
there was just so much going on, on,
on a given server, it could be running all sorts of different things.
Uh But now with containers, it's much easier.
This is fascinating to me.
This is something I know I've talked about at length with many people, you know,
some time ago But
so how, how does that work? Do you, is it a configuration option in your tool?
Do you do something when you build your container?
I guess because, because the obvious thing I'm thinking of is
if, if you've, you know, gone all in on micros surfaces,
you could potentially have hundreds, maybe thousands of containers running.
At which point. How do you manage that at scale?
Saying this container runs this executable, this container runs this executable.
This container runs this executable.
And then of course, they're changing on probably a regular basis. Right.
Right. Right. And that's exactly where the, the tooling comes into it.
So we'll hook in at build time to
fingerprint the container images.
So essentially keep a record of what executables are in it.
And then you go through a, a learning phase where it, you know,
you're running the code and it's learning what
you know is supposed to be running and what user I DS
are supposed to be running and what network traffic it it does
again makes a lot of sense if you've got a microservice
because it's probably only doing a very small number of things.
And then once you've learned that profile,
you can apply that to any container running from that image.
So any running container instantiated from the same
image picks up the same profile and you can
kind of keep the same sort of profile
updated as you release new versions of that image
and just kind of automatically limit what each of those containers can do.
Not to sound like an old crazy person.
But I mean, this is the exact same problem we had with Se Linux.
Right. Remember Josh, I mean,
trying to contain a large app was
like wordpress was impossible. And,
you know, I, I actually looked at sort of a,
a local microservices architecture with Se Linux,
but it was just too painful And, and that's one thing I'm seeing with containers is
it's a lot
less painful to implement and to get working, you know, it's,
and it's easier to sort of dial in
Se Linux with App Armor.
You know, it's really powerful, but it's just so painful to configure
that people tend to not really use it as effectively, but moving to containers.
You've got that ability to profile each individual service separately.
Right. And, and I think the profiling is key.
And I remember actually
way back we'll, we'll,
we'll get in the time machine here and way back
in the day when Se Linux was relatively new,
there were discussions around some automatic profiling and the
back then
it was still very much that all or nothing mindset and, and it was decided that
it is conceivable, you could profile something doing something bad
and we don't want that.
So we don't want to profile things automatically. We want to write it by a human
and I have a suspicion. Right. Well, of course. But, but this was a different time.
Right. This was,
oh, no, I lived through those times. This is why I'm, I'm thinking about going to my
-- drinks cabinet.
-- The world was a different place.
Yes,
that's right.
But, but I mean, in, in all seriousness, I feel like
automatic profiling of a container image,
there is a possibility
of having something mis profiled. Right. Without question.
But I bet it's correct more than 80% of the time.
And if you're willing to throw away 80% accuracy for a system that's so broken,
no one will ever turn it on.
That's crazy. Right.
Well, yeah, and, and I think it's probably more than 80% correct, you know,
-- and also
-- I love the contempt in that answer.
You, you, you can do things like um
you know, you don't have to
prevent you, you can alert when something goes wrong. So
we, we have a lot of customers who do that who say, well, actually,
just to be on the safe side, I will do this in a alerting mode.
But hopefully, you know, it's right.
So much of the time that those alerts really only happen,
you know, on the rare occasion so that you can spot the signal from the noise
so it can be super powerful.
Yeah, that was another thing I found with Se Lennox was alarm fatigue,
right?
Because Sel even a properly written Se Linux profile still had a ton of alarms.
Yeah, and that's still an issue with um image scanning as well.
People finding false positives. It's a really hard problem to basically avoid.
So I I actually in Ulster,
you guys, you guys have a container scanner.
I'd love to hear any advice you have on this because this is, this is one,
one of the things I struggle with
on probably a weekly basis where someone shows
up with an automated scanner and says,
can you comment on this?
And I say I can't give you 13,000 comments, right?
Like pick, pick 10 and I'll tell you about 10 of them, you know, not 13,000,
what the individual
-- vulnerabilities that it's found or?
-- Right. Right.
Where someone, someone will want,
they'll want me to comment on all of them because let's face it.
I have a suspicion.
They didn't really look at the report,
they probably just ran it and then they're throwing it over to me.
But no, I'm I'm curious given you guys, I mean, you have a product that does this.
I'm I'm curious what sort of advice you have
around it,
just kind of false positives in some of these reports because it can be very,
very intimidating when you look at them.
Absolutely.
And it's a big part of what we do, you know, as a as a company,
we build up information about the vulnerabilities from lots of different sources.
So the
the problem with false positives usually comes from
uh your,
you're using version 1.3 of this library
and
the unpatched version of 1.3 has this terrible vulnerability.
But actually the version you're running with isn't
vanilla 1.3 it's 1.3 with this other little patch
and you need to know what the like distribution
knows about that patch or what the vendor knows about that patch
as well as what the kind of base vulnerable
or the information about vulnerabilities is in the base package.
Um
Yeah, that's,
that's kind of the information you need to
kind of pull together to avoid false positives.
Um And sometimes it gets really, um
you know, it, it's not even clear whether or not a version is patched or not.
You know, sometimes
different vendors or different distributions will have conflicting
reports about whether or not something really is
present or not.
Um And sometimes so we have a research team, you know, that,
that look at some of this and just try to
figure out what the correct answer is.
So it's a big problem and that's why people kind of,
you know, come to our
service because we're trying our best to pull together the,
the different sources of information and, and,
and to the best that we can uh remove the false positives where we can.
But yeah, it's a hard problem.
-- No, it is. It's, it's a terrible problem. Unquestionably.
-- Yeah. Sorry.
I'm just having a flashback.
My last seven years of my life was basically doing this, you know,
exact kind of work at Red Hat,
I mean, and yeah, it's, it's a, it's a tough problem. I'm, you know, trying to get CV.
One big problem I find is, you know,
we only have one good public source of
security data really that's consumable in that CV.
But the data is very coarse,
right? It's not,
you know, the CV data itself doesn't, for example,
have an exact listing of Red Hat packages
that are, you know, vulnerable or not vulnerable.
And to be blunt, even if it did have that
due to the way Red Hat distribute software and the channels and other things work,
that would not even be 100% you know, so things get
messy.
Uh And that's just one vendor and there's, you know,
probably what about a half a dozen major Linux vendors plus Windows and Mac and
yeah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah
and some of the individual tools will have different um you know, information.
So a great example will be,
well, anything with a client and a server that gets distributed separately.
Um
you know, so uh like on the NVD, there will be a list of vulnerabilities in Mongo DB.
But if you go to Mongo DB,
they've got information about whether it's in
the server component or the client component and
that may reduce some of the,
the issues that get reported. If you're only using one or the other, which you
probably are in many
-- cases.
-- Right.
Indeed. No, it's, this, this stuff is, is painful and, and I guess
why don't
let, let, let's do this.
II, I guess given, given the position you're in and the topics you talk about and,
and kind of the knowledge you have.
What, what do you think the world is gonna look like in, let's say,
five or 10 years and, and obviously,
we all know predictions are always wildly inaccurate.
But I'm curious, given just kind of, given the nature of things, I, I feel like
deep down inside, there's like the smallest spark of hope when I see things like,
like what you guys are up to and, and just some of the new technologies coming out,
you know, it,
it's not enough to squash my grumpy old man, but it's,
it's at least enough that I think there, there might be a future
that isn't completely terrible, which I'm, I'm curious if you agree.
Oh, I think as humans, we'll find other ways to make it happen.
Well, and one thing to keep in mind is, is as terrible as things are, you know,
we're now at a point where I remember when I
started and if an admin could handle a dozen servers,
that was good and if you could handle, she could handle 50 servers,
they were amazing.
And, you know, now we have small admin teams handling
thousands of virtual servers,
you know, or microservices or whatever.
And so, you know, people keep worrying about the world burning down and as do I,
but at the same time, you know,
the lights keep turning on and everything mostly keeps working.
So, II,
I do wonder if things may not necessarily get better but they may not get worse.
And I, you know, I think I can live with that. Not that I have a choice.
-- Yeah,
-- I think that's true.
I think human innovation has consistently found ways to solve problems and
also to create new ones. You know, we,
we give ourselves the challenge of
shipping software five times a day now that we didn't
used to do even three or four years ago.
Um, and with that,
we've created a whole load of
challenges about managing those software deployments.
But the positive side is, you know, it's great for businesses.
They can and be really responsive and they can
ch
functionality several times a day.
And, uh, that's presumably good for businesses and economies
and, uh, and everybody
presumably.
Yes.
No, I mean, I, I think that's fair. That's fair.
And, and so I guess
we're, we're kind of, we're nearing the end.
So I'm curious to hear what are, are there,
are any anything coming in Kubernetes or just containers in general
or even some of the things Aqua is working on that,
that you excited to see in the next, I guess,
couple of weeks or months or maybe even years.
Well, over the next couple of weeks, we've got keep
Con and cloud native con in Shanghai, which will be the first one in China and
I've never been to China before. So that will be exciting.
And, and now you're one of the co
founders or co
coa
OKA.
Yeah,
that sounds like a lot of work.
Yeah.
Yeah, for um
uh
Copenhagen back in May and then for Shanghai
and then a couple of weeks later in Seattle
and
-- then that's the end of my, my tenure as, as co-chair after that.
-- So, and then you get to
escape how exciting
I, I have this funny idea that I have loads of free time next year,
right?
You hear that folks, if you need Liz's help, like get in now.
No, no, that's, that's really cool.
Yeah. So, so that will tell that will give us over the next,
you know, couple of months.
We'll have a lot of, you know,
I'm sure there will be a lot of new things announced at those events.
We will get a, a
good idea of what's happening,
you know, in the world of cloud native right now.
Uh you know, bring ourselves up to speed.
But I think the thing that we'll see over the next year or so is
improvements to developer experience and operator experience.
Basically things just getting easier to use in the cloud native.
Sure that that's fair and, and I guess. No, no help frame this as well.
How long has Kubernetes been around?
It was announced at an Os
Con and I can't remember whether it was 2015 or 2016.
It
doesn't matter because think about the, the change it's created in,
in like three years.
Right. That's crazy.
How much it's transformed the world
and, and it's barely been around for any amount of time.
Yeah. And the speed of adoption has been astonishing. Like even a year ago,
we would have conversations about which container orchestrator are people using.
And now
pretty much all of the, you know,
unless you've got a really good reason to use something different,
most people are picking ti
well, I think it's the Apache of, you know, container management. It really has one
which I I'm actually quite glad because I,
I had experiences with a bunch of alternatives and
Yeah.
Oh, indeed, indeed.
OK, cool. That's,
that is, that is fantastic.
And, and I guess as, as we wrap up, Liz,
are there any any parting thoughts you might have for the audience?
-- Anything you want us to know?
-- You,
we mentioned the book already, didn't
we?
You can plug it again and I guess for the audience, the book will be in the show notes.
So by all means, you know, you can, you can hit up the show notes, get a link to the book.
Uh
Yeah, yeah. Uh anything else
and, and obviously you, you've hit on, uh, your, your, your conference in Shanghai,
which is also very exciting.
-- Anyone in the region by all means anything else?
-- Absolutely. And then, and a
couple of weeks later we'll be in Seattle as well. So, um,
if anybody wants a signed copy of the book, I'm sure we can arrange that in
Shanghai or Seattle or some other event. Yeah,
indeed. Yeah. And I guess that too.
I'll put a link to Liz's personal website in the show notes as well.
And you have a list of kind of all your,
all your articles you write and your speaking
engagements and things like that and you are,
you're clearly a very busy person.
And so I'd encourage everyone to take a look at that also. And so
awesome,
I guess.
Yeah, that's, we'll end it there. Thank you so much, Liz.
This has been an awesome conversation. I really had a lot of fun.
Uh I guess good luck in Shanghai.
It's always exciting and terrifying going to a new
place for the first time to run your conference.
So
that,
no, no. Exactly. Exactly. It's, it's awesome. Right.
And, and I, I can't believe how big these have gone as well.
So, like, congratulations to you guys there.
And I guess, yeah, if anyone wants the show notes,
you can go to open source security podcast.com,
you can hit us up on social media with the Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag
I'll make sure I put a link to Liz's Twitter account in, in the show notes also,
so you can, you know, hit her up on Twitter and, and see what's going on and yeah,
nothing else.
Uh Curtain Liz, thank you so much. It has been an awesome conversation.
-- Thank
-- you so much for having me. It's been a pleasure.
Thanks for being our guest.