-- All right. It's December 6th. Hashtag
-- always those podcast.
So, uh, this is the half dozen risks of using dirty public Wi Fi networks.
And what I love is that this somehow implies
that there's like clean public wi fi networks.
Well, I guess it's a library.
-- The library is pretty clean,
-- whatever you can't trust those librarians.
-- Yeah, but they're, they're tidy and clean. They keep their books in order, I
-- guess.
I love life libraries. I don't, I don't mean to pick on libraries. I love librarians.
Librarians are my favorite people in the world.
We have a new library. Well, not a new library.
It's, it's the old library location, but they gutted.
It got rid of all the asbestos and weasels rebuilt the whole thing.
The Stanley Miller library in Edmonton.
It's quite beautiful, not as beautiful as Helsinki.
Um, but
they have amazing Wi Fi coverage and they
have this giant wall showing a reef aquarium.
It's, it's really cool. But anyways,
what are the half dozen dirty risks?
Uh Sorry,
what are the half dozen risks of using dirty public Wi Fi networks like this is.
And, you know, obviously at Starbucks, you wipe your feet, it's clean,
whatever, whatever. But
I love that.
It's like scanning and ordering, fingerprinting, eavesdropping,
remote access exploits evil twin wi fi
lateral network infections and DNS hijacking.
-- So, ok, let's start with this.
-- No, I don't even think we should cover them.
I think it's just ridiculous. It's completely ridiculous.
All of us use public wi fi all the time. If there's public Wi Fi we're going to use it.
And my absolute favorite thing in the world is security.
People who talk about, oh, you can't use
Wi Fi without a VPN because blah, blah, blah
and I guarantee you every one of them does it because they're just a bunch
of annoying hypocrites and everyone is going to do this and the world never ends
and more to the point,
none of this all matters because everything to put it
bluntly nowadays needs to be done at the application level,
which means TLS 1.2 or higher.
Ideally, all except 1.1 for the most part and certificates
because like
I connect to gmail,
I need to know it's gmail. It doesn't matter if I'm on VPN or not.
Well, and now that the web browsers show non https
websites is untrusted.
It's going to be insanely difficult to properly
fish someone with any of this technology.
And now here's my favorite example and this is how I sum up security on a regular
basis of all the technology that has happened to make public wi Fi safer to use.
Has any of it been driven by the people who have
been complaining about public wi Fi for the last 10 years,
0% of it was driven by them.
It's all been other people who had good ideas who drove this industry for.
I wouldn't even say they drove it forward. They drug it forward with a rope.
Like, seriously, this is where
people complaining and talking about how bad and stupid something is
generally just makes it worse because now you have people saying,
-- oh, I can't use the public wi fi
-- and here's the thing,
I love people complain about this constantly.
And,
and so I actually have a spreadsheet for our internal CS a like for
all the vendors we use and one column of it is number one,
do they support http S because the spreadsheet is 10 years old.
And so the answer wasn't always yes back in the day.
Of course. Now it is yes.
And then the column right after that is do they use hsts?
Which is HTP strict transport security mode,
which means essentially do they either serve a
header or are they whitelisted in the browser
to force you to use htps? So for example,
cre.org cloud
airlines.org, paypal.com,
all of them are whitelisted in your browser. Like if you type in http
and slash L
see you.org, your browser is going to go. No, no. Like you have to talk http s to that
and it flips it over
and the point is that stuff is what fixes this,
it doesn't matter if it's Wi Fi Ethernet or, you know, you're dialing in,
from Australia
and for dialing in, we mean,
connecting over a phone line for those of you that don't know what that means.
-- What's
-- a phone
line?
Here's the thing. A VPN
is no part of this.
Exactly.
All the things, people,
all the things the security people have been talking about in the past
about why public wi Fi is dangerous and what you need to do.
Absolutely. None of those things.
I think nobody really ever did them,
but they're not part of the solution because they're obnoxious and they get
in the way and none of them really work that well anyway.
-- Well,
-- the problem is I like
buying a VPN Enterprise product for the CS A
but the challenge is none of them could be enforced.
Whereas very simply put, we can pick vendors like gmail,
like office 365 like sales force
that enforce HTTP S
so ok. Problem solved.
That's it. Seriously, like for real
and it doesn't just solve the Wi Fi problem. It solves like
-- all the problems basically. Right.
-- Absolutely.
It, it's, it's another one of those examples where
be mindful when you are a security person or you listen
to security people who are talking about the dangers of something
because I think quite often it's not as bad as they say.
I think it is easy to complain. Something is broken
and then not make anything better. All you've done has made the world worse.
It used to be as bad as they said.
But then the world got better for the people that chose to get better.
And funny enough when it was that bad, no one was really talking about it yet.
Exactly.
Like when people started complaining about it,
it is when things started to get better, which is hilarious.
But all right. Anyway, anyway, it's time to be done. I've lost my tab.
We will see you on December 7th.