Hello and welcome to the open source Security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner and being tired of winter.
Josh Bresser.
-- I
-- mean, look, I'm tired of winter, but that's not why I'm actually tired right now.
The ravages of old age are why I'm tired right now.
So I, I woke up the other day and I couldn't turn my neck because
did you try a new pillow?
No.
No, that's the thing. Like, I just went to sleep, woke up, couldn't turn my neck neck.
Really
took a bunch of medicine. I just did. I'm just old.
Of course, my Children laugh at me all that.
But then I didn't sleep very well last night because my neck hurts and,
like I can turn my head now, but I'm still tired and
it's like, well, that's my life now.
Yeah, that's my favorite thing is just those random days where it's like, ok, I,
I can't really shoulder check very easily.
Right.
Yeah, there's no good reason for this. It's just,
I'm old and who knows, whatever.
Yeah,
pretty much.
That's just,
you know, what gets me is so we spend,
or we're supposed to spend about a third of our life sleeping
and there's no like legitimate service or
kind of consultant I can hire to actually take a bunch of measurements for me.
-- And, you know, this is the kind of pillow you need to sleep. Well, I
-- mean,
-- I guess
-- like,
would you trust a pillow salesman to have your best interests in
mind or to try and sell you the most expensive pillow?
That sounds scary to me. What is, what is it?
Is a pillow salesman gonna watch me sleep?
-- Well, I
-- don't
know, like
comb
your hair while you're asleep. Like what happens here?
-- This
-- is like most companies and large orgs, you know,
you have like an ergonomic office assessment where they,
they make sure your chair is not, you know,
all wonky in your desk because it at the right height and stuff.
Right.
So, why don't we do that for sleep?
Because no one wants to pay for it.
But the funny thing is like
to go off on a tangent, but the whole mattress market now is like,
it used to be $1000 mattress was.
Wow, that's high end. And now it's like, that's entry level.
But, um, people will pay a lot of money for a good night's sleep.
But it's weird to me that I can't hire, like, like, if I wanna,
I can, I can hire somebody to survey my property and to do like a ground, you know, uh,
of the water runoff analysis and be like, ok, Kurt, you know,
you need to slope this more and like, put a drainage ditch over there,
right?
Or I can hire a mechanic to look at my car and be like, oh,
your car is in good shape but it could use new brakes or, you know,
I can hire all sorts of people to look at how I cook
or all these other things and improve and help me improve it.
But not my sleep.
I'm certain
there's somebody you can find on the internet
that will do exactly what you're looking to do.
But I, I,
I'm going to tie this back to security
because it's actually related to some conversations I've
been having lately and I think it's something for all of us to think about is
so we talk about something like wanting to sleep better and we're,
we would all say yes, I want to sleep better. Who doesn't? Right?
But
it's one of those things that
when you tell people, ok,
you will sleep better if you pay this person to do something.
And then it's like, wait a minute, I don't want to pay that.
So I'll be, uh, whatever I'll, I'll be fine.
And this reminds me of certain security,
we'll say requirements where people are always saying, oh,
I want to sign all my emails.
I want to sign all the S bombs, you know what I mean?
And, and like, I think signatures are a really easy one or people will say, oh,
I want to keep all my dependencies updated or
I wanna run all my code through the, the static analyzer tool.
And it sounds like a good idea
until you get the bill.
And then it's like, uh I'm probably OK the way it is now,
the other problem is, does it actually work and do what you want?
-- And
-- some of it does, some of it doesn't and I agree
with that,
but you don't find out until after you pay the bill
and, and I think sleep, like, having some sort of sleep,
a consultant. I don't have to call them
would be a similar thing of,
I could pay this person and maybe it would be better and maybe it wouldn't,
I don't really know, you know what I mean?
Like, there are sleep clinics locally but they're for people, you know,
with sleep apnea and, like severe problems.
Like, I'm, I'm sleeping ok.
-- I just want to sleep better.
-- I just don't want my neck to hurt.
-- Yeah,
-- I wanna wake up without, you know,
without movement, hurting everywhere.
-- But,
-- uh, anyway, anyway, whatever, whatever. Let's, let's
what are we talking about
today?
Well, I think the big thing is, uh,
I really like this N PM forcing two factor authentication on the top 100 projects.
And I love it for two reasons. One because it's absolutely the right thing to do.
Not just in the sense of forcing two fa on the top 100 projects. But
doing it only the top 100 projects to start.
Yeah, because
you got to start somewhere. So, yeah, exactly.
And so because all these people on Twitter are like,
why aren't you doing it for the top 500 or the 101st, or the top 1000 or everybody?
And it's kind of like,
do you bite and chew your food?
I, because I hope you do.
If, if you like, if you eat hot dogs like the Japanese hot dog champion, then, ok,
maybe you want to just turn on to a a for everybody all at once and see what happens.
But trust me when and Josh, when we say
-- that's not gonna work
-- well. So what, what happens
is when you do something like enabling two factor authentication,
80% of the people are going to have no trouble.
10% of the people are going to not be able to
get it to work for some bizarre edge case reason.
1% of the people are going to forget their
password or lose their phone or something immediately.
I'll never forget that when,
when we were at, at Red Hat, Red Hat acquired two factor
A for L
and this is back in the Rs A key days
and someone lost their token two hours after they got it. And it's like,
-- that's impressive.
-- I remember being at an event
and there was an ebay engineer.
And the ebay engineer saw that I had,
I actually at this point had multiple two of a tokens on my
keychain because I had one for ebay and I had one for Blizzard.
And they were super impressed that not only do I have an RS a token on my key chain,
but I had two of them and they're like, what are they for?
And I'm like, oh, it's like this one was actually for ebay.
Like I use it with you guys and this engineer replied,
oh, yeah, I tried it, but it was too much hassle.
I couldn't get off the couch so I just disabled it
and you know what that,
-- but that's how it works. It
-- is, if you don't force people to do certain things,
they will find a million excuses.
My other favorite was when everyone was starting to get the RS a tokens,
they set up a webcam pointed at their Rs a token.
-- So no matter where they were, they could get a hold of the token and then type
-- it in.
-- They solved the problem. It's
-- like, well, I guess
so.
So the other thing is too is you gotta like,
it's, it's not just going to be, you know,
it's funny that you say 10% will have edge cases.
Well, no offense.
If 10% of people have edge cases, they're not really edge cases anymore. They're
-- much more common than
-- we would be maybe so whatever. But the point is 10% of 100 people
is a lot different than 10% of a million people.
So I clicked on the two fa set up in uh N PM.
So what's interesting is it doesn't force you to
set up two fa when you create an account because
-- you're
-- not one of the top
project.
Um It encourages you to, it displays a warning label. So I clicked on it.
So
what I like is they actually give you
like here's what you have to do. So it doesn't break stuff.
So prerequisites update your M PM client to version 5.5 0.1 or higher.
OK. That's good to know,
right? Because II, I don't know what version of N PM supports this or not. OK.
And then number two,
install an authentic application that can generate one time passwords.
So they're using OTP one time passwords and they're
using the standard because they then say use off
the Google authenticator or Microsoft authenticator.
I would also assume open
o also works, which is weird that they don't link to that but whatever
on a mobile device or second computer that will always
be available when you work on your N PM account.
So yeah, like it, it has to be available
and then
uh through the web, they give a bunch of screenshots on how to turn it on.
Also, you can selectively you can have it only for authorization.
So it says for example, logging into N PM js.com or through the command line
and, or authorization and publishing.
So you can have it set.
So you just log in like basically you can secure your account with it
or you can secure your account and publishing of software with it,
which I think is really nice distinction to make.
Yeah, because for example,
on github,
I have two F eight but I don't do sign commits because it's too much hassle.
Sure. Sure.
Now I will say if you're protecting your publishing rights with an A a token,
you can't do kind of automated pushes
is going to be the downfall to that.
Well, not without your webcam hooked up to the thing
that
OCR
Right. Right. Which
I, I think this is one of those places as more and more people are using this service.
I think they can
refine what the permissions need to look like because there
are N PM developers that kind of one off put,
it's all very manual and that's just fine.
And then there's also developers that it's click a button
and the machine starts
and your, your published package comes out the other side.
And obviously, in that case, you don't want a human,
you know, typing in six digits because now they're the bottleneck.
Well, or, and that's, this is one of the biggest problems I find is so I like sites
that allow software tokens and hardware tokens. But I'm always afraid of sites
that only allow you to register one
software or hardware token because what if your phone gets lost or you,
you physically lose your token?
Yeah,
totally. And so I'm noticing more and more are allowing multiple tokens, right?
And sometimes they, you know,
explicitly allow it and sometimes you kind of have to discover it.
But for example, github,
Google, you know, they all support multiple tokens really well. And so I have
the one in my safe deposit box register, which is a pain because I have to go get it,
register it, take it back to the bank.
But you know, if my house burns down man, this is going to be awkward.
No, absolutely. I'm, I'm in the exact same boat. II,
I have two
hardware tokens
that I use. I have a UB key and a Google Titan key. I generally register them both.
One stays at my desk and the other I carry with me. And then I also often if I can,
I'll set up the Google Authenticator app because you're right.
If you lose a device, if my phone falls in the river or whatever,
I don't want to be, you know, sol
and,
and that's one of the things that scares me to death because a
lot of these services are quite explicit that if you lose your key,
there's nothing we can do because we don't care about you.
Well, and see this, this is one of those classic things where
like if it fails for you, 1% of the time,
it's annoying but whatever. But if it's like dead for you, then
that's a problem.
And so the other thing, here's the biggest problem I have with TU of A
is a lot of sites do good.
Two fa you know, no longer S MS because S MS is garbage, got to stop doing that.
But like they do tokens, they support the software blah, blah blah.
But then account recovery is just
email access
and I get it because it's tough because
well, what else? What
you can't really add anything else to it and still have it be account recovery
because people aren't going to remember that stuff.
Um
Like a great example is my bank.
I accidentally, I logged into my bank and it asked me, you know,
my one of my security questions that I
accidentally put in the wrong answer three times.
So it like locked me out
and then it was like trying to ask me essentially security
questions of like which of these transactions did you make?
And one of them was like an example transaction for 83
cents at Costco and for anybody that shops at Costco,
you know that there's no such thing as,
oh
wait, there is I bought a pop. Oh damn it. That's why I got it wrong.
Oh I just see. This is a perfect example. So,
so I got locked out of my bank account and I had to phone them
and the lady is like, you know, your, your, the last digits of your sin or whatever,
whatever, whatever.
And, but it's like I was like, if she asked me any of my transaction questions.
Well, I don't know because I don't have access to my online banking.
Right.
Right. Like, and,
and like just now I literally was like when
I saw that 80 some cent transaction at Costco,
I was like, no, I didn't make that.
That's, that's not even can you even buy something at Costco? 43 cents?
It's like
a pop. I forgot about like I bought a pop there.
I love it.
Ah Anyway, so, so this kind of proves my point
is that when it comes to account recovery, you basically have to support what I call
the naked homeless person scenario, which is literally a naked homeless person.
It's like I need access to my account
and I don't remember who I am basically.
So like help me out.
Well, because apparently I qualify for that scenario as of yesterday
and that's the thing.
So it can't really be much past email and it, so my email is very secure.
I actually have Google advanced account protection enabled, right?
Which is if anybody uses it, you know how much of a chore it is to log in and stuff.
But for the majority of people,
it's probably a weak link but from the providers point of view, what else can they do
reasonably?
Exactly.
There's nothing they can do.
One thing I would love to see is more account recovery, not just via email,
but for example, via a Facebook or linkedin or Twitter account.
So again, you know, people have a bit more choice,
I mean, but you still run into the issue of if someone takes over my Facebook account,
now they can
conduct an account recovery on my behalf.
But what's interesting is things like Facebook have other ways to secure
accounts that email doesn't have like they have the social graph,
they have pictures of you.
You know, I'm always reminded of that Instagram account recovery process where
Instagram generally has pictures of their users.
And so they have you write like a six digit code on a piece of paper,
take a picture and send it to them
to do account recovery because they have pictures of you.
Yeah, I mean, look, I'm not gonna start this conversation.
-- I
-- just, what I
-- think is I would like some choice. I would like some flexibility.
-- Ok.
Ok.
It, it
now at the same time,
I do think
things are better than they used to be
so we can at least agree on that. But
anyway,
I want to keep us moving because I don't want to just talk about this.
Well, and just one quick thing N PM does allow
email based account recovery.
So it doesn't matter how much to a a you do if your email account is insecure. So,
-- so
-- there you go.
-- Obviously secure your email account, please.
-- Folks,
I want to move on and talk about the Linux Foundation announced Alpha and Omega.
I don't know what that is
good.
This one's interesting and I'm, I, I
have many thoughts on this. So
there's these two projects, the Linux Foundation's open SSF,
which is the open source
Security Foundation. David Wheeler was on
at a couple of episodes ago talking about it. I'll put a link in the show notes. It
was
a
year ago.
What's that?
-- I think
-- it was actually quite some time ago.
No, it wasn't. I don't think it was, well, it was in 2021 but
I feel like it was in November maybe
October.
I don't know.
Anyway, doesn't matter.
So
there's these two projects they started and this is all on the
heels of log for Jay as these things tend to happen.
The idea behind alpha
is the Linux Foundation open SSF is going
to identify some of the critical open source projects
and then dedicate
specifically like security funding and people to it.
So like having people go through the code and do security reviews and
help with vulnerabilities and all this stuff.
And so it's meant to be kind of a very white glove service.
They're pro I'm assuming they're actually probably going to
start with making sure there are some code maintainers.
I mean,
-- it's all part of it, it's all part of that.
-- Well, that's what I love is.
A lot of people make the assumption that these critical projects have
like people buying them
and in some cases like they don't.
Well, and so this is kind of where the Omega part of this also comes into play
is Omega is meant to be kind of a more broad and automated system.
Think of like the Linux,
the open SSF scorecard project applying that
broadly across a great swath of open source
and then being very public about the findings,
I read this
and you know what the first thing I did was
I looked up all of the things just like this that happened after heartbleed
and I thought
I truly hope this works,
but
I'm going to hold my breath because
like
we have, this story has been told before.
This is the story of humanity.
I know. Oh, it's super important. Everybody.
My favorite is, you know, pick something really simple
to quote my former boss of full forecast and control.
We call them floodplains for a reason. Please stop building there.
-- Oh, wait, it's all the good soil. So people want to build there.
-- Well,
I
view
of the river, it's like,
and then I love people are like, but how could we have known?
It's kind of like, well, I know Alberta publishes all the flood maps online.
There's like a website for it,
like, really detailed.
Yeah.
So,
like when the Calgary flood happened is my sister's
house wasn't affected because my parents forced her to
buy a house. Not on the bow river flood plain.
I live on a hill. It's fine. Everything's
fine,
you know.
Well, anyways, but, um,
I,
I do hope it works out and I think there is a chance now
because automation is possible in a way that it wasn't 10 years ago.
Yeah, I, I do agree with that. I think we are in a
better place than we were after heartbleed.
But I think there's still always the,
the danger of this is the most important thing right now
and in six months it's going to be something else.
And as soon as the eye of Saron
is looking elsewhere,
all of this other work kind of collapses because no one cares anymore.
Yeah.
Well, I remember back in 2014,
like even just having an automated build pipeline was basically magic,
let alone any security tool.
-- I
-- mean, back then even it was
the big talk was open.
L was literally one person
and then everyone's like, wait a minute, we should maybe fix this.
And,
and then you remember Open SSL was forked about 100 times and now there's
like seven copies and Google has one and Open BS D has one and
I think Amazon has one and
it's like, well, that's,
that's one way to do this.
I don't think anyone's forked logged for Jay yet.
I really like the idea for something. As, see the problem with open SSL. Is that,
oh, we built a toolkit that does everything for everybody.
And that's good because that's ultimately what the world like,
certain parts of it need,
but the majority of the world needs something like the,
the strip down SSL where it's like
we support the three common use cases. If that doesn't work for you go get open SSL.
-- Well,
-- and I mean, this is, I think what, what TLS
1.1 0.3 I think it's 1.3 they basically just took a machete
to the TLS standard where like throw all this old crap away,
it's dangerous and no one should be using it.
It's one of those classic things where people engineered stuff that
is
nice to have, but it turns out to absolutely not be needed in the real world.
Like the, like renegotiating a protocol midstream.
Why,
why do that?
Well, I mean,
but think about the attitude in the nineties was always be strict on what you send
and generous with what you receive. And it turns out no
strict on what you said. It's stricter than what you receive everything else.
You just get rid of it.
But it, it, it sort of made sense from an interoperability standpoint.
-- Well,
-- if you want to actually work at any point,
then that's how you get it to work is by having, you know,
fax machines that can essentially send faxes over garbage wires.
Right. Right. Well, and you have to remember, I mean, you had Linux,
you had, so,
Os, you had Windows, you had OS two,
there were all these operating systems and they barely work with each other,
much less
each other, you know, across the wires. And so
you had to be like that because, I mean,
I remember Microsoft was notorious for just
like sending garbage in their protocols.
And so you'd be like, eh, it's probably ok.
My favorite fact is the old Windows talent client,
one character per packet.
And so it would, it would just destroy a
lot of
TCP/IP stacks with the number of packets it's in
or like the buffers because who sends one packet per character?
Well, like apparently Microsoft, if you want it to be low latency,
right?
And, and nowadays, like we're laughing because, you know,
the slowest networks we probably have is like wi
fi at a couple of 100 megabits per second.
But
I remember when I had, you know, 10 megabit,
like
coaxial
cable, attaching all my computers to each other.
Dial up internet. And
I was about to say,
but my internet connection was dial up.
So like one packet per character would have flooded
my network link if I was typing fast.
It's funny to think about
if nothing else just identifying what is critical is a good
first step because then we get a sense of scope.
Like, are these all like, do they actually have development efforts behind them?
We, we don't, we don't always know.
And, and here's,
I guess the one thing I will remind all of the listeners is
the open SSF is 100% going to do something you don't agree with
and
all of us will suffer from this and we're all
going to be tempted to be like those idiots.
They're getting it all wrong.
No,
that is the wrong attitude.
I think this is one of those instances of,
we need to put some effort into understanding these problems
and we're going to make mistakes along the way. And so
it's gonna be ok to Ridic ridicule them a little bit.
But fundamentally,
we need to be patient and we need to be involved in these projects.
I don't think
is the right word because part of this work that people
forget is that this work is exploratory and research in nature.
We are trying, basically what we're saying is we're trying to solve a problem. Ok.
What is the exact problem? Well, it's kind of
software security. Ok.
If somebody says software security is the problem,
they don't know what the problem is
that, that's like saying people die, we need to fix that.
No, you need to be a bit more. Are we talking car accidents or medicine?
All of it? All of it? No, I, I agree. I agree completely. I think you're, you're spot on
and,
and I guess this is one of the challenges is today, everyone remembers the pain,
a blog for Jay.
So lots of organizations are willing to just like shovel money into this.
But
if in a year they're like, all right, what, what, what progress have you made?
And they're like, we think we've identified critical open
source projects.
They're like, what that, what I gave you $3 million like that's all you did.
And so I think that's gonna be part of the challenge.
Well, I mean, and part of the good news though is, is for a lot of these,
you're not going to actually have to do a
lot to actually improve things because things are the, the bar is pretty low,
it's laying on the ground like don't trip over it. Yeah.
No,
but I like this because like a great example of this
when I was looking at their sort of what defines criticality,
is it that it does something important like the root level name servers,
is it that it's widely used?
Like uh what was it, the N PM left pad or left shift or whatever,
you know, uh
or is it something that takes user data from the network and processes it,
or is it a crypto component or you know what I mean? Like how do you define critical?
That's like,
-- I, I don't, I will admit, I don't have a good definition for what is
-- critical. No one
does and it's going to vary by users because what you consider critical, I might not.
And regulation explain that
right?
For the people that live in regulated industries, it's like, well,
whether or not you want to care about this, the law says you have to.
Right.
Yeah.
Oh, yeah. Yeah. Now, I, I think one of the,
one of the interesting aspects of this is going to be.
So if you have a critical package, let's say we,
we create some standard that defines criticality.
So now are the dependencies of the critical package also critical packages.
And I, I would, I would tend to say yes,
but I don't know if that's the way this is going to work.
But I think there's a lot of really weird and
strange nuance that's going to fall out of this as we go along
well. And part of the beauty is it doesn't matter if they're critical or not.
The very fact that we're attempting to start to measure this
is a huge step forward.
It's, it's absolutely. And
I think the really important part is there's currently a project
with the Linux Foundation has they call it L XL FX.
I, I forget the name of it off the top of my head,
but they're kind of trying to do this where they're scoring open source,
but it's not public data.
You have to be a member of the project and you have to
log into their special dashboard and then you can see the information,
but I feel like
this is an open source. You can't be, you can't work this way.
It has to be very public, it has to be very open.
And then I think you have opportunities for people to start saying, OK,
now I understand what this project is doing and you can decide,
I either need to invest in it.
I need to drop it.
You know what I mean? So, like, what are we gonna do now?
-- I'm
-- gonna
-- disagree slightly in that.
I think part of the problem is
so perfect example, back when we worked at Red Hat, remember I would,
we would assign CV S for issues right away.
Yep. Yep. And then we might not fix them for a long time.
And that actually was a problem sometimes where other companies would be like,
look, ha ha Red Hat has these outstanding CV.
S for days and weeks and months on end.
And it's like, yes, because as soon as we know it's a vulnerability,
we gave it a CV versus your company.
-- That only does the CV. The moment you release the pain.
-- That was, that was Microsoft.
We don't have to pretend like that. They, they don't work like that anymore.
But that, that's what they used to do. But
I think there is an element of
that in keeping this data private.
And right, especially because the data is not great yet.
Like, it's not, we don't know that it's necessarily correct.
And so I think part of it is I would be OK with the system, for example,
that the project can make it public.
But I, I don't want projects having to deal with the press, writing articles like,
oh, you know, this project that's supposed to be very important is like, got a,
got an F,
you know, why did they get an F like the blah, blah, blah?
No, I, I think you're wrong.
I think if there is a project that's supposed to be critical and it's getting an F,
let's make it not an F,
what I'm saying is for now while it's still in the infancy,
kind of keep it private on the download.
So they don't have to deal with this, you know, this insanity.
-- But at some point it does have to be opened up.
-- Absolutely.
I, I don't know. II,
I might be able to be convinced but I often err
on the side of openness for things like this because I think
if you don't open it,
it creates,
it's easy to drag your feet. You know what I mean?
I see this all the time, especially when,
when I'm working with
a project or, or some other people and like a get repo might be private and it's like,
oh, I'll fix that code later.
It's like, no you won't,
let's fix it now.
And if it's open, it's like, oh, wait, I'm going to, I'm going to push this, commit.
My name is going to be on it. I don't like this code. I'm going to fix it.
You know what I mean?
No, I think openness needs to ultimately be the end state for this to be
valuable. But during that sort of initial exploratory research phase,
you just said that I still, I'm not going to agree.
I don't know
it.
But here's the thing, you can always go from close to open.
You can't go from open to closed
because the moment anything tries to go from open to closed, it's like, well,
a great example.
O is V DB, they went from open to closed and it's dead.
Uh, they just got bought,
who cares?
-- I mean, I agree
-- but like, I, I don't know what their data said.
If it's any good or not, I don't care, like, unless I pay them a pile of money,
I just don't care about them anymore.
They, they took themselves out of the ecosystem.
-- It's complicated, I think. But
-- you know what I'm saying? Right. Like it's,
I used to care about OS V DB.
They used to matter, they used to be important, they used to be useful.
Now it's just another private database. Who cares?
Yeah, I know. That's another story.
I mean, and, and so, like,
I guess let's finish up,
let's let's talk about this Samba thing that just came out as well.
So there's a Samba R ce which is a huge deal, of course.
And
-- I imagine all the ransomware guys are like
-- w
yeah, you know it, but here's what's eating me.
And this was true of the pone kit CV E as well.
Like if you look at the CV E at the time, Kurt and I are recording,
it's been more than 24 hours since the Samba
advisory went out.
Now that the advisory was funny too because they had, they got the,
they got the CV E wrong.
It's a 2021 CV E but they accidentally called
it 2022 in the first draft of the advisory.
So that's kind of
silly.
But like the,
the entry in the CV E database is still blank and it's
like this is one of the biggest deals happening right now.
-- How is this still
-- blank? It's in the reserved state.
-- So it's technically not like, oh,
-- whatever. That's,
but a lot of people think reserve CV S exist
-- in a useful sense and they don't as
-- many reserved as there are filled out CV.
There's more now,
probably
-- don't count.
-- No, not, probably there's more now like
they've got huge blocks of reserve CV S and so people
think like people look at the CV database and go wow,
it goes up to like 40 or 50,000 and it's like,
no, those are like mostly reserved.
Like you look at the NVD data where they just,
they don't even bother carrying the reserve CV S because there's nothing there.
It says literally
value
reserved.
This candidate has been reserved by an organization or individual
that will use it when announcing a new security problem.
It doesn't matter,
it
doesn't matter.
-- The point is no,
-- no, but the sentence was
when the candidate has been publicized,
the details for this candidate will be provided.
Ok, cool. Can you do that?
Yeah, get on that.
I mean, but it, it's
Samba having an R ce is a huge deal, right?
Like, but then
the challenge becomes now
it has a CV E, the data is not published and it
-- is
-- that CV, the correct number.
I
got it. Right. But
-- maybe they
-- did.
But you know what I mean?
I feel like this is again one of those
instances where we have some security infrastructure but it's like
-- sort of there. But it's definitely failing us.
-- It's operationally broken.
Yeah, I agree.
It's like a wheelchair lift. That doesn't work. Cool. You have a wheelchair lift?
Does it work? No, it doesn't. It doesn't
like it'll work tomorrow.
Well, that's not very good for me today.
And I'm sorry, but
you can have the world's best
wheelchair lift. But if it doesn't work then it's,
it's not a wheelchair lift. If it doesn't
like this. The fact is even log for Jay had the same thing
where it was out for, over, well over, like, it was known to be an issue for well,
over 24 hours before it got into the CV database.
You know, and this, like, Samba thing is now what?
It's at least 24 hours, maybe more, maybe less.
I don't know if there's a weekend coming up,
maybe after the weekend they'll get to it.
And that's the beauty is we don't know.
No, I know. It's all, it's all hidden behind a veil of mystery and
-- it's definitely frustrating and annoying
-- to me.
This is a big deal.
I wrote up the GST entry in about five minutes.
I
know and like handcrafted the
JSON
because I don't have a tool to do it yet. And it's on my to do list.
There's literally
like, that's so wrong.
Like if I had a tool, it would have taken me two minutes,
you know.
So we're going to write a tool to do this so that
-- anybody can fill up these C DS because that the
-- Royal,
we,
yeah,
this is, this is beyond ridiculous that
it, it's,
but, but I mean,
this is one of the challenges and I
think this ties into the Alpha and Omega discussion
that we kind of started with and, and even the N PM discussion to a degree is there's,
there's all of this security knowledge, there's all of this security technology
and it is still
incredibly difficult to put the pieces together and make it work.
We accomplish things
in spite of our tooling today in the world,
we don't accomplish things because of our tooling.
And that is the problem.
I, I think there's a lot of unnecessary gatekeeping.
I mean, yeah, I agree because humans are
in all of these processes and humans are terrible at everything. They do
-- also. They're inconsistently terrible.
-- Yes. That's what I mean. Right.
-- It's just like
-- if we were consistently terrible, then we could just throw it away.
But the problem is sometimes they're good. So we're like, oh, it's ok.
Anyway, anyway, I guess
if you're listening to us and you haven't patched your Samba servers yet,
you might want to go do that.
That's all. All right. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening. Go to open
source security, podcast.com. Head up the show. Not, it's easy.
Pound Os S podcast.
Pound Os Si Can't talk today. Use the Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag to hit us up on social media. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks
-- everybody. Thanks everyone. Good luck patching those servers.
Bye bye.