Hello and welcome to episode 72 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
I saw the greatest thing today while I was walking my dog and it, it both
made me smile and it made me realize
how much the world has changed.
So it's obviously fall in the northern hemisphere,
which means it's cold. But also the, the leaves are falling off the trees, right?
Where do you live? Maybe that's true. It's technically winter.
There's still a lot of leaves on the trees here though, for,
for a strange reason that I won't get into right now.
But
so anyway, I'm walking
and I'm under this big old tree
and I happened to look up for some reason.
I, I heard a noise assuming it was a squirrel or something and, and lo and behold
in the tree
is a drone stuck in the tree.
And I'm thinking, I'm thinking
this is the new kite in the tree, right?
Or whatever, man, you can buy it for like 20 bucks.
Now, this was not a very expensive drone,
but that's all I could think of was
when I was a kid, we got kite stuck in trees.
Now, kids are going to be like, man, I got my drone stuck in a tree.
-- So
-- now I'm thinking, how do you get it out without damaging it?
Do you get a bigger drone with all
the,
I
-- get stuck in a tree. What do you do?
-- So, actually this one wasn't that high.
I think if you had one of those pole saws, you probably could have clipped the branch.
But regardless, I just, it,
it made my day thinking I haven't seen a kite stuck in a tree in a long time,
but I bet I'm going to see a lot of drones stuck in trees now.
Yeah. No, that's,
and, and that's actually a really good
use case for automated visual, like, recognition of like, oh tree. Don't go into it.
No, like, seriously. Right. Like
that would be like automatic tree avoidance. Like,
actually I'm just
ok.
Well,
it also depends on the drone though because my assumption is this drone
was probably not very smart and probably flown by a very inexperienced pilot.
Right.
I
think
pilots.
Are you an operator?
I don't know what to do.
-- Yeah. Well, because the guys flying, the military drones are
-- pilots. Are they?
Ok?
I don't know
if you drop
on people. You probably want some degree of competence.
Let's just, let's let the A is take care of that.
Well, they tried that too and that got a little ugly.
Um, so the good news is we've had, like,
autonomous drone
obstacle avoidance
for years now.
Right. Like in the lab and
apparently like the DG I Phantoms have this as a feature.
Well, right. I would expect an expensive drone to have it, but, I mean,
they're selling them at the gas station for 20 bucks right now. Right.
-- Like that,
-- that's what I love about. Technology is like,
yeah, when you see that the gas station,
like USB cords and chargers at the gas station, it's like, yeah.
No, clearly this is everybody has this.
Yes.
Well, part of me also wonders
who buys some of these cords at the, I mean, some of these cords are super,
you
charge
your
phone and you forgot it in you.
I,
so all the gas stations have the USB cords like the charge cables,
not the ones you know, that are good and actually can transfer data,
but just one little charge.
Most of them have like the little,
uh, what do you call it?
Well, I'm going to call it the cigarette lighter plug in,
but of course my Children and anybody under the age of like
20 is not going to have a clue what we're talking about,
right?
Ok. So folks just so you're aware
the power plugs in your car, it used to be for cigarette lighters.
Ok, because we all, everybody smoked,
-- including in their cars,
-- Mike my truck still has one.
My, my truck is from 2001 though. Yes. One of the things you push in.
I remember as a little kid we'd play with them and we'd, of course,
burn ourselves terribly with
who can hold their finger. The closest to it
of a
movie
where the, uh, they, they, uh, the ex presidents' wife got kidnapped. Remember?
And she burned the kidnapper with the thing leaving like little scars on his neck
as a clue.
I've seen that.
But you know what? I did notice that no gas station or
almost nobody carries anymore is USB thumb drives. Those are like at Staples.
And that's it. Like the grocery store used to have them.
They don't have them anymore.
I can't, I was looking locally for one and I actually ended up having to go to Staples.
I don't think I've bought one in forever.
I, I literally keep, I,
I have a Ziploc baggie that is completely full of
them because when I go to conferences or something,
I get a bunch of them for free
and
I don't take them from security conferences.
But generally, look, look, here's the thing,
let's face it.
If I'm at a normal person conference and they're handing out USB drives,
the odds of it being bad are effectively zero.
Chances are, it might have a virus. But,
and that's fine.
It's very unlikely though. That'll have like that hardware level tax stuff.
Right. I, I plug it into a Linux machine. I format it
and I don't even look at what's on it because I don't want to.
And I know it's probably marketing materials
but, and, and then I keep them and what I do with them
is when family members or friends say, hey,
I need this or can you give me that or whatever?
It's much easier to just copy a thing to one of them, give it to them and say,
I never want this back.
And then
80% of the time I get it back
to
that. In fact, I just did this for a neighbor,
an old neighbor some time ago where their, their computer,
they bought a new computer and they basically said, how do I get my data off it?
And
I just said, bring your old computer to me. I'm gonna take your hard drive out.
I'm gonna copy it onto this flash drive and then I'm gonna throw it,
I'm gonna wipe it and recycle it.
Ok? They're like, I don't know what you just said, but ok,
and it was just easier than trying to boot windows and figure out what's going on,
you know, I'm just, no,
I'm just going to copy a bunch of files and give
it to you and you can figure it out from there
anyway. Anyway,
we should
get to the topic of the death.
Oh, and what
it
is, say it, Kurt
say it
Bitcoin.
It's literally over 9000,
a month ago as a joke. And now it's not a joke but it's still a joke. But
-- it's just, it's a mess.
-- It's crazy. I,
I
don't even know what to say.
Well, I mean, the good news is,
here's the beautiful thing. If Bitcoin becomes,
reaches a million dollars or if it completely craters out,
it's not gonna have a real substantiative effect on the world.
Like, say, you know,
uh losing all the poodles would
losing
Poodles.
Yeah. Well, as an example of something we could
live without
these.
But
so the beauty is like Bitcoin everybody. Well, all the Bitcoin people, of course,
you know, Bitcoin is essentially the future blah, blah, blah.
Um And
OK, well, to be
blunt, and I think you also stand with me on this. We're going to tear Bitcoin down.
I in
the sense
of like we're not gonna,
you and I are not Bitcoin fan boys.
I, I'm not and I have, I, I remember when I looked at Bitcoin a long time ago,
I mined a little bit of it.
Well, back then, a little bit was a lot today,
but I remember I mined some and I thought
this, this stuff has no future. This is the most ridiculous thing I've ever seen.
And,
and Bitcoin was at, at, at
like a dollar, I think it was a dollar or less back then.
Uh Amazon is a company with real assets,
but like back then it was just a bookstore online. Like,
right
now I get like a dozen Amazon
here,
here is the deal though. Is I look at Bitcoin
and
it is completely unsustainable in every way
and it is
anyone who understands anything about it knows that
it is. We, we are nearing the edge of a precipice
-- where it is. I don't
-- know better than that
is that
it's completely unsustainable and unworkable
technologically politically and even economically.
Right.
-- Yes.
-- For
the technology I think is what, what is the current saying that,
that it takes more electricity to conduct one Bitcoin
transaction than your house uses in a month.
And that apparently Bitcoin is now
one of the leading energy consumers in the world.
Um, it's ahead of like something like 100 and 59 countries or something stupid.
Um,
but I mean, ok, well, let's start with the technology, right? Because,
or even some like,
yeah, where to begin with Bitcoin because it's just so
it's such a fundamentally cool idea
that it is just so completely flawed.
You know what Bitcoin really reminds me of is the whole, oh,
let's build a decentralized peer to peer,
internet and bypass everybody and it's like
super awesome, never work also back calls, also technology, also normal people.
But apart from that cool idea,
you know.
Yes. So I think it's a great
-- idea. I agree.
-- Technology wise, I, I love Bitcoin. It is actually pretty sweet
but for example, there's like one tiny little problem of like
it can't handle transaction volumes.
It just can't it. And it never will be able to
uh
because
of the proof of workout.
Yes.
Yes. And, and that is
you just hit on like three important points about Bitcoin.
And let's start with the transaction
problem of
the fact that it
forever takes up.
The problem is
one
which one should we?
No, I,
I think the biggest problem initially is that the block size is still one megabyte.
Right? Well, and here's the beauty though, increasing that won't really help it.
It, well, not just that is if you understand
how growth works
when you have kind of your exponential growth curve.
If you double something, let's say we go from one megabyte to two megabytes
that's going to buy you like days to weeks, not any sort of long term
growth, right? You need to go up by powers of 10 generally.
So we would have to go from one megabyte
to 10.
And the these guys can't, they can't even get on board to go to two megabytes.
They're never going to agree to go to
Well, and there there are sort of ways around this.
For example, you could,
you could effectively have side chains where you have like a private.
So a great example of this is paypal, right? Paypal started out as an online payment
thing
and then ebay bought them and then the beauty was
because ebay is such a big commerce site,
it's big enough to essentially use paypal and kind of
keep money in house in the sense of like,
I put money into paypal to buy something from ebay.
And then that ebay seller, you know, buy something from another ebay seller.
And so the money just sort of sloshes around paypal
and the money doesn't actually like
leave paypal, right? So,
and that's ideally what you want,
if you run one of these systems is you want a big pile of money to come sloshing in
and then you wanted to stay there
and just keep sloshing around,
you know, in circles basically.
And
that's actually kind of happening with Bitcoin because one,
my favorite aspect of Bitcoin is everybody's like, oh, Bitcoin's over 9000.
I'm like super awesome.
Hypothetically speaking, you have 100 Bitcoins. How do you turn that into cash?
Exactly,
man. I, I've been trying to figure that out because I have a couple of Bitcoins
and
-- it's
-- like a car right there now.
Yeah. And, and I've been thinking about that.
So here's the fundamental problem and, and well, I'm sure touch on these topics in,
in a bit is
so there are some places you can spend Bitcoin today.
Like new egg is a great example, right? Where new egg is a
when
you're talking about like actually legitimate places where you like
your new egg knew you were spending money there
and the cops knew you were spending money there.
That would be ok.
-- Right.
-- Yes. Exactly.
Exactly. Not,
not, you know. Right. Crap on
whatever. Right. Right.
Like, like new egg. Right. New egg is a totally legitimate real business.
And in fact I buy tons of stuff from them
all the time. Right.
They can, they will accept Bitcoin legitimately.
But the issue is if I spend Bitcoin,
the IRS is going to come and get me.
Right, because
it's money
and the IRS is starting to
pay attention to this.
And in fact, they, they,
there was an announcement a couple of months ago
talking about some company working with them to identify,
uh, basically Bitcoin users. Right?
-- Because
-- there's already been a bunch of those and some of them are really cool.
This one guy did
a,
essentially they were able to identify people buying,
um,
sex online, like, and other illegal things.
Ah, yes, that was with the machine learning or something, wasn't
it?
Um,
yes.
And
so here's the point, right is
if I buy real things with my pretend money,
then I have to pay taxes on it. And I'm actually just holding it.
I, I actually, I did research in this. I'm ok. As long as I hold it, it's when I try to
like stock that in the sense of you don't pay tax until you realize
I would compare it to collectibles
in terms of, because it's going to be taxed at your tax rate.
Not at, like, when you have stock, there's capital gains and
things
like that
because it's not a financial instrument per se. It's not regulated.
It's basically baseball cards with
magic crypto.
Right. And I've done,
I did a bunch of research in this because I, I, like, I want to understand
what the heck can I do with this? All right.
So, if I spend my pretend money and I have to pay real money taxes on it,
I'm thinking that's dumb.
Right. I don't want to do that.
So can I turn you
into
Bitcoin?
Uh, no, they do. Actually,
they had a fact about that. No, no, they do not.
And,
and not only that
they, they only
people,
no, I'm hoping they cut that one off at the pass,
but the other thing they do is they only deal in us dollar denominations.
So
they don't care
how many Bitcoin you had. You have to basically
turn that into us dollars. Right. And so,
and that totally makes sense. I get that right. It, it,
whatever.
So anyway, the, the issue now is
how can you turn a Bitcoin into real money,
which you could then obviously just withhold part of
the real money to pay your taxes later.
-- The first
-- step is not even, well, the first step is turning it into real money.
The second step is actually getting that real money.
-- I, I would say those are the same problem.
-- Right. Because it's, it's, I look into
this and there's a lot of places
that will happily convert Bitcoin into cash in an
account somewhere or on a credit card or whatever.
But I'm talking about, like, actually getting them dollar bills in your hand
because let's be blunt
if you redeem for the sake of argument, 100 Bitcoins online.
So, it's about a million bucks now.
Yeah.
I, I actually want to see somebody holding a suitcase with that money in it before.
I'm like, actually going to say that yes, they actually got their money
in,
you know, honestly, it's never going to happen.
And, and the reason why is related to how we got down this rabbit hole is the fact that
the Bitcoin network just can't handle a high volume of transactions.
In fact, I've got a chart I'll put in the show notes
where
you can graph the number of Bitcoin transactions per day
and it's beneath 1 million transactions per day on the Bitcoin network.
And it basically hasn't changed in two years because
the Bitcoin network at this point is saturated.
Well, the best part about the Bitcoin network being saturated is
my understanding is there's like these huge blocks of miners
and I mean, China is talking about basically making Bitcoin illegal.
They kind of did.
But, but my my understanding is a substantial number of miners are in China.
Yeah.
Um but, and it's, and it's become such a problem the miners, for example, is now that
somebody on Reddit posted a picture, they bought a new video card,
like one of the new Titans or whatever the heck
it is that are commonly used for crypto miners.
And it actually had a sticker on the thing
specifically saying that this product is not intended for
Cryptocurrency mining,
right?
Because the problem is apparently these people, well,
they run these cards flat out 24 7,
you know, max rate
which, well, honestly, in my opinion, if you sell me a product and I do that,
I expect it to work for at least a while.
But the problem is apparently they like intentionally
damage and kill these cards.
Um You know,
so that they can then get new ones like say a month
or two from now or whatever or a year from now.
I
understand,
you know,
these video card companies are seeing like they're taking
a real hit on these returns and stuff because,
you know, these people like, let's face it, right?
Most video cards are meant
well for people to play games on.
Well, and when you mine Cryptocurrency,
most of these guys are overclocking this stuff to death.
I mean, they're not just running the video
cards and
that's 10% more money,
literally.
Yeah, but they run super freaking hot. I mean, I remember,
I remember I,
I did some mining on a video card for Bitcoin
back when that was like a thing you could do.
This was
a million years ago.
And man, uh, yeah, I remember that like tweaking over clocking it just, you know,
as much as you could before you started
hitting too many errors to make it worthwhile.
Well, the other thing, these guys spend $0 on cases and cooling because that's
why would you spend money on that?
Uh Some of them do. I've seen some pretty nice rigs
and in fact, cooling was always a big deal for me is I made sure I had lots of fans.
I think there was a vice documentary and they showed this crypto mining like
thing in China and it was just, it was a warehouse
with like four or $5 fans
wasn't there at one point there was a fire at one of the warehouses and you could see
on the Bitcoin
kind of whatever the computing power measure is. I forget it has a name
but you could see where it took a huge dip because this warehouse
caught on fire in a significant amount of Bitcoin mining hardware went offline.
Yeah. So
technologically speaking, there's just so many problems and then, I mean, well,
-- no,
-- hold on, hold on before before we go on.
I, I just want to say
so
Bitcoin, the Bitcoin Network today is trans
is dealing with less than 1 million transactions per day
to give me an idea. Visa.
They do
100 and 50 million transactions per day.
So you're talking
more than 100 times the volume.
Well, and that's just Visa. There's also a, a
Mastercard Discover,
right?
And now we,
we also come back to the idea of these guys are talking
about increasing the block size from one megabyte to two megabytes.
When the reality is they need to increase it to 100 megabytes
to start thinking about things in the context of Visa.
Yeah.
Right.
So, and I mean, here's the thing politically,
I mean, there's already been, uh, well, not already,
there's been a huge crackdown for decades now on, you know,
transfers of cash and other legal,
you know, financial instruments
internationally because, you know, money laundering.
Right. Like,
I mean, just Google Panama papers, money laundering or whatever. I mean,
you know, what, uh, what is it,
every transaction over $10,000 if you're bringing or leaving with more than,
and that's one thing people don't realize often
is it's not just bringing $10,000 into a country
that will get you in trouble, but it's leaving a country with more than 10 $1000.
Here, here's a question.
If I have a Bitcoin wallet on my computer and I, I cross a border.
Am I carrying more than $10,000 with me?
I, I don't know
that
it gets to be a fine line because can that, is that a financial instrument per se?
The IRS has said no,
the IRS has said no, but it, it's still, I mean,
and it would fall into holding, like, say a big pile of expensive baseball cards,
I guess.
So. You wouldn't have to say yes or no.
But I will bet you money.
If they discovered it, they would confiscate the bejesus out of your lap.
I do not travel with a Bitcoin wallet, but
that would not surprise me if they did.
Uh,
however, however, the custom forms now that you say it, they do, they specify cash
or cash
-- equivalents.
-- Uh,
I don't recall anyone talking about cash equivalents, but it's,
it's certainly possible.
Anyway,
so the, the topic of the, the block chain
is
and I don't think there's much hope in sight
to
increase
it's cash or its
equivalent. So it's essentially
cash, cash.
Right.
Right. Right. But anyway,
I,
I do not think we're going to see the Blockchain fix itself in the respective volume.
Well, here's more of the point.
You and I are hugely technical people
and I guarantee you you and I cannot
safely store Bitcoins,
which leads to a really great
article. It's actually not hard to do. I mean, it's just,
I'm talking about storing bitcoins securely in a
way where you can also reasonably sanely,
access them and use them.
-- Uh, no, no, you cannot.
-- Right.
You can definitely securely store Bitcoins, like print them out,
put them in a safety deposit box
or you can store them online. So you can actually use them.
But then of course, there's a good chance you're going to get ripped off.
There's
a beauty.
Bitcoin is 15 times more expensive to keep safe than gold.
What, why did you come up with 15 times?
Did you?
That's the motley fool's number.
Uh
The Bitcoin Investment Trust,
a popular fund for retail investors carries
a management fee of two percent off assets
on an annual basis, which, you know, that's a lot of money anyways,
blah, blah, blah, blah,
blah,
a new solution from Coinbase costs 1.2 percent of the Bitcoin's value each year.
In addition to an upfront fee of $100,000
the service is designed for institutional investors,
more than $10 million of the digital currency. Wow.
Yeah.
So see,
that's what gets me is I like you and
I know what it would take to securely store Bitcoin
and it's, it's actually pretty easy to securely store Bitcoin.
The problem is you end up doing it offline, which means you can't use it.
Right. Well, and, and not only that,
if, if I stole all your Bitcoin, they're gone,
they're gone and there's nothing you can really do.
Whereas if I stole a bunch of gold from you,
you could send the police to my house or even
if you have millions of dollars worth of gold, you can't just sell, you know,
you're not going to the pawn shop with a million dollars worth of gold.
Well, remember we covered that in the previous one with that,
-- the guy that was stealing gold from the Canada mint,
-- that was
one.
And I will never forget because an old friend sent
me an email and said I just found your podcast.
You, I'm you,
you made me proud by talking about a guy shoving gold up his ass in the first episode.
And I love that.
The only way he got caught the jeweler was like, wait,
this guy is selling a lot of gold and he works for the mint.
-- Maybe I should tell somebody
-- right?
Or not the jewelry. Sorry, the bank,
the
bank was like
uh
any right? And and this is one of the many problems
that come with Bitcoin, right? There's there are tons of them
and I
I in all seriousness.
So I think the thing that's going to do
it in more than any of these other technical issues
is the electricity use because the amount of
electricity is just going to continue to increase as
it becomes more popular because the number of people
mining is going to continue to go up.
There's there's a pretty much built in technical death spiral at this point.
Yeah, to like you said to electricity usage.
There's also the built in death spiral due
to simple economics of there's a deflationary spiral because
number one,
there's a finite number of Bitcoins
21 million.
So here's the thing
we're gonna have to at some point really start, like
if we're gonna use Bitcoin for say
100 years, we're gonna have to vastly increase mining costs
so we can keep using it.
Right. And so the intent though of the creators
was that they would generate 21 million coins.
And it's, we're what, like halfway there now, I think,
and
the idea is
you,
you have transaction fees where people kind of tack on, like, for example,
it's like shipping and handling, right?
And you add that to a transaction and that is what the miners
are going to get.
And there's still going to be essentially minting blocks, so to speak.
But the minting a block won't get you any Bitcoin for free.
You're only going to get the transactions contained within the block,
right? And so the problem is if you have a finite number of Bitcoins,
then it's, it's not finite. It's, it's
negative because people are going to lose wallets.
I was just about to say that is that we have a finite number of Bitcoins 21 million
and it's going to be smaller than that
because we've already had people lose wallets.
There's been thefts, there's been uh where, you know, they just,
they can't be spent or maybe not for 50 years,
but more to the point.
Yeah, like you said,
people will lose wallets or destroy them or otherwise somehow just
delete them
and they're gone.
They're,
well, for the purposes of computation in this universe,
-- crypto cracks them. All right.
-- Yeah, exactly.
And then the whole Bitcoin system is broken anyways. But anyway, so
there's a deflationary spiral because by definition, if these things work at all,
they will become more and more valuable as time goes on.
Which means people will hold on to them and not
use them.
And the whole,
not the whole point. One of the major
points of currency
is to
not only store value.
See people always are like store value, gold blah, blah,
blah and cool storing value is not a bad thing,
but the transfer value.
Uh Yes.
Right.
-- What the hell is it good for
-- exactly? If you can't spend it, it, it has no value.
I mean, that's the reality,
-- you can spend
-- it if nobody's willing to spend it because they're
going to hang on to it because it'll be worth more tomorrow.
And this I think goes back to like look at the transactions,
there's about a million transactions a day.
What happens when you want to buy a loaf of bread?
-- You cannot, it will take only
-- a million people a day.
Get to buy a loaf of bread globally.
That is
correct.
Well,
and so this is I have also heard Fan Boys talk about the fact that
imagine Bitcoin as like the gold standard and then you have other alt coins,
-- alt coins being the like gazillion, other cryptocurrencies that
-- aren't Bitcoin
and
theoretically in principle,
Yes, but
-- deflationary spiral, the whole thing implodes regardless.
-- I,
I know, I, I agree with you 100%. You can't,
you can't have something like Bitcoin being your supposed backing currency. No,
it, it just, it,
-- it isn't how it works and
-- that doesn't get
rid of all the technical problems or anything.
Even if, even if the politician said cool Bitcoins allowed, I mean,
there's still the technical issues and the economic issues.
Right.
And then, and,
and we still have all these legal issues which I guarantee you are not gonna go away.
Like, I guarantee,
I will bet a Bitcoin
-- the, the global.
-- Do you want
to bet?
-- What?
-- Sorry,
do, do you have a Bitcoin to bet?
Oh, yeah.
Not yet.
You're going to win it for me right.
Here's the,
anyways. Yeah, pretty much.
Um, but, you know, it's not like the globe is going to be suddenly like, yeah,
Bitcoin.
Cool. It's just like, let's treat it like gold.
No
problem
to
just not
-- gonna happen.
-- No,
it certainly is not.
You know, it's like a suitcase with a million dollars in it.
I guarantee you any law enforcement agency on the
planet is going to do one or two things.
One, they're gonna take it
or two, they're going to take it and charge you.
Uh, they're gonna take it and they're probably gonna misplace it.
-- Right.
-- Yeah, like, let's face it. That,
-- that was option.
-- Right.
Um, you know, so Yeah, it's just, it's, it.
Yeah.
And,
yeah, I just, I,
I love the idea of these Bitcoin and these cryptocurrencies and stuff, but just
they're not going to work.
And the other thing is like Bitcoin is essentially thinly traded. Like,
uh, you,
you can't say they're not going to work.
I think some of the other cryptocurrencies could have potential. I mean, Ethereum
is like a great idea in
the,
but again,
when you build a turning complete
-- language into your Blockchain,
-- you mean,
like,
except for that
time where they said they would never roll back transactions
or not a bunch of money, a bunch
of
Ether
and they kind of did agree to roll it back and blah, blah, blah.
And it's been what, three times they've done that now.
Well, and then there was that programming error where they meant to get around to it,
but they didn't.
-- So $300 million worth of Ethereum kind of
-- went,
didn't they roll it back again when that happened?
Honestly, I don't know or care at this point.
The whole thing, here's the real point, right?
This whole thing is a lot like the world wide web between 95 and
99 and that it was the wild west and completely insane and crazy.
Now we're talking about
hundreds of millions of dollars,
-- but
-- we're
not because let's face it. I bet 80 plus percent of these people just
what they have.
The IC
Os
So let's get,
this
is not Bitcoins,
IC O are
essentially a giant
combination, MLM Ponzi slash, just straight up rip
offs.
I it's
uh this whole conversation,
the craziest coin,
send us your money
and we will send you
some sort of digital currency. Swears these,
yeah, this is not an offer that's
-- anywhere.
-- Yeah.
Well,
we know we need a reason to have the initial
IC O we're going to use synergy to increase your,
your investment by a factor of 9000.
We're
gonna take
your
initial
investment
and
use
it to
leave
the country.
Actually.
What's really funny is I was,
I was talking to my wife about this the
other day where I was explaining this IC O concept
and she basically said like,
well, what, I don't understand this, what, what, why doesn't everyone do this?
This sounds like a great idea. If you could just trick people out of their money.
I said because like this is how you wake up dead. You know, you can't,
you can't keep doing this
without somebody.
If you live in some country with a terrible economy where you only make
a couple of 1000 bucks a month if you're like really high skilled.
Guess what,
man, the IC OS I've seen have been like legitimate people in like the US, right?
Not all
but I saw more than one.
It's, and it's crazy.
Uh What's this one? Um, a
company called Confit
raised a small IC O by selling special CFD designed to allow quote,
safe and trust Cryptocurrency payments.
According to IC O drops,
they raised their goal of about 400 grand 400,000 us and quickly disappeared,
taking the cash with it.
The site is currently a park web server that points to nothing.
The apparent founder and former ebay employee,
Evan Thorn
Po
posted a message to a confit
reddit board claiming that
quote, we are in a tight spot as we are having legal trouble caused by a contract.
We signed,
we signed the contract with insurance from
our legal advisor that there was minimal risk
and it would not be an issue. I can't, won't go into details but he was wrong.
It is a problem
unquote.
-- Right? And, and look, man, even if
-- that's true, it doesn't like
that's 400 grand gone from. I hate to say it but suckers.
Yes. And now
they're pretty clearly in a developed nation given who these people are and
assuming
that this guy is actually this guy and it's not some other
person
that's actually true. That could be the case. Let's assume though. It, it is because
I,
you know what, this reminds me of all the Kickstarter where they're like, oh,
we're going to build uh what was that one?
Oh yeah, it's a little box, three inch cube
and it'll laser edge stuff and
no physics. You just can't do that
or like that underwater scuba breathing thing that
like fits in your mouth like Bat Manhattan,
it's like
pulls oxygen out of the water
except you'd have to like,
have like several 1000 gallons a second going through to get enough oxygen.
But
the point being
is these Kickstarter are like,
oh, we spent a whole bunch of money on R and D and stuff and that didn't pan out sorry.
And realistically like,
what are you gonna do? Audit them
and then what you audit them? And you're like, um so like
$50,000 on like beer and Vegas, like, please explain,
you're gonna sue them,
-- you can sue them but like
-- there's nothing to sue.
I, I know, man, it's,
and that's assuming they're even remotely in a jurisdiction that is well behaved,
you know, some dude in Kazakhstan is kind of like, yeah, good luck with that.
Right? Not to pick on
Kazakhstan. I'm sure it's a fine upstanding judiciary, but
realistically contract enforcement in a lot of the world is not super fun.
Right? Well, even in the US, it's terrible.
I mean, you have to go through the court system
and, and you have to think
if, and, and really this is the way to do it if you're raising say
400 grand
and I assume that split up over a large number of people
fighting the sodium.
Uh I'm, I'm just going to assume right?
And if you're smart, you're going to use more than one
because if if you keep the investment small enough,
it becomes cost prohibitive to actually come after you.
Right.
And so there's, and no, like you're not going to see a class action lawsuit for 400 K,
right?
Is not enough.
Whereas if you had like an IC O that would say, you know,
$100 million and you got it and then you took off.
Yeah. Yeah,
you're gonna have lawyers lined up to come after you for that one. Right
to the point.
You don't even have to take off.
You just have to, like, provide something that sort of meets the minimum, legal,
viable product and
whatever. Right. I mean, because here's a question. So these I CS
I gave you the digital currency. What more do you want?
Uh, did they though? I don't know if they did. It sounds like that's what
drives me
nuts is like,
you don't even have to scam people per se.
You can just actually give them the digital crypto
token, do hickeys and be like, yeah, good luck spending these anywhere.
Right. Because
part of what makes money work is people believe money works.
-- And
-- that's the only reason money works
well.
And also because you have things like you have certain types of money,
like us dollars where you have the backing of a major government that
so far hasn't, like, done anything stupid.
Like, uh, you know, all those dollars you need
there.
Yeah.
Well, no, no, I mean, stupid in the sense of like saying like, oh, you know,
all that foreign debt we have.
Yeah, we're defaulting on it. Good luck.
That, that is very true.
I've done that. Thank goodness. Um, some other countries have several times
and like, that blows me away that you have like,
developed countries with junk bond status for their foreign debt.
But whatever,
-- that's not an argument I want to get into
-- because anyway, anyway, I think
-- Bitcoin
-- is just
not even Bitcoin, but all of these cryptocurrencies,
the, I think the fundamental flaw with them is
is that to be a savvy investor in these things.
The degree of technological knowledge and economic knowledge that you need
is
literally over 9000. Like one thing that got me is some Cryptocurrency.
People were talking about how they had all the technology, right?
And it turns out like the financiers just
took them for a ride and they're like, who knew that was possible? And it's like,
uh the,
the, you know what they're doing,
-- that's literally their job.
-- Right. Right.
And,
-- and yes, that is, that is one of the
-- tricky things
this shakes out and like, literally we like have a government and by government,
I mean, like a proper government like the US, Canada, Germany or something or the eu
backing one of these currencies and like
properly running it.
This, this is just gonna be a,
a wild west free for all which for some people is exactly what they want.
And that's cool.
-- You know,
-- maybe I, I don't think you're wrong
and it is, it is likely, I think that one of the other cryptocurrencies could,
could accomplish this and, and let's face, it
is
-- already
-- getting there.
I, I,
the
-- fact that, you know, the whole
-- Ethereum
Z cash are the two I'm going to watch, but I think Ethereum is
going to be difficult long term just because their Blockchain is turn complete,
you can write, turn
complete contracts. And
because of that fact, you will never be able to secure it properly,
which means people are always going to be stealing tons of Ethereum.
-- What
-- this is also true of the world wide Web.
The world wide Web is a security disaster as we've often discovered,
but it creates much more value and
it's worth it. It is possible. I, I don't know if, if you're right or wrong.
Let me put it this way, Ethereum handles the transaction volume of visa
and there's say for the sake of argument, $100 million a day in fraud.
Now,
my first thought would be is
how much credit card fraud is there
per day? And I'm guessing it's
more than 100 million.
I,
you know,
I have no idea but I, I'm certain it is
substantial.
Yeah,
because the thing that gets me is is,
you know,
we talk about this with self driving cars though is as
Ethereum gets attacked and gets hacked and gets whatever whacked.
Hopefully they're gonna fix it and those problems go away.
Whereas when I look at, like, credit card security,
it's like all the same stupid stuff that's been a problem for 2030 years.
Some of it's gotten a bit better, but a lot of it is still a problem. Like,
well, like the US, you have Chip and signature.
It's so,
it's so bad.
Well, it's just funny because I realized I have a because I have a US uh
credit card with chip for some reason and
corporate thing.
And I was like, oh,
I don't know what the pin number is and I was like looking and I was searching my
and then I realized it doesn't have a pin
nope.
And I was like,
I, I had someone ask me the other day
if, if chip and signature is better than swiping signature. I said
yes, but not much.
It's, I'm not going to explain it to you, but just, just know it, it
-- is better but it's
-- more than a penny to clone the cards.
Right. It's still terrible.
We need pins.
But anyway,
anyway, uh Right. And I don't feel like we've properly addressed
electricity in
this conversation, we mentioned it a handful of
times.
-- Yeah.
-- So, so
the beauty of the banking system is they have a strong incentive to
be cost efficient because essentially they're
all cheap skate bastards because they're bankers
-- Right. That's cool.
-- You heard it here, folks?
Yeah.
And, but something like Bitcoin, on the other hand, it's a bunch of miners who
essentially get rewarded for being able to
do more computation than the other miners.
And one of the
basic facts of the current way the world
does, computing
is more computing requires more electricity unless you get better chips and,
and we do get better chips as time goes on.
But generally speaking, it's a level playing field for access to chips, right?
Everybody goes and buys them from Intel or a MD or whoever, right?
-- It's not
-- like uh well, no, not for Bitcoin. Bitcoin is now using as
six
regardless. We're hitting the constraints of P.
And what I was going to say is even if you go to special chips, essentially,
there's not some magic chip fab out there that's only selling to one guy.
If you have a chip fab,
it's even funnier than that actually.
So I did some research into this at one point because I actually, I still have an,
I have an Asic in my basement that I bought a long time ago
and it would make me like negative $48 a month or something if I plugged it in today
because the just
the power use is too high.
And, but anyway, well, I guess what a lot of these,
these chip fabs are doing for Bitcoin
is they build the gear and then they use it for like three months
and then they sell it
because basically the way,
the way this works and the way Bitcoin works with the ever increasing difficulty is
your mining gear is good for 3 to 6 months
and then it basically becomes too expensive to run anymore.
And so these,
these manufacturers are basically milking the golden period out of it.
And then they're dumping it into the market for like,
it's not like, like there was back in the day,
apparently the NSA had their own chip fab and, you know, 2030 years ago,
that probably meant something
quite amazing.
But nowadays, like,
yeah, I mean, if somebody can make a chip that they can sell for that kind of money,
they will.
And so it's in that respect, it's kind of more of a level playing field.
Let me put it this way.
Ok. If I had a billion dollars, I could definitely get some, like,
pretty good
Bitcoin mining chips.
But would they be 1000 times better than what's currently out
there or even 10 times better than what's currently out there?
No,
at
best, they'd be the same.
-- Well, or maybe like, 20% better if
-- you're lucky. But I think they'd be
the same and
that wouldn't matter in a month
because the, the difficulty workload is increased.
Right.
Yeah. And that's my point. Right.
So it's very much a level playing field that way.
And so
this electricity usage will continue because
you got mine more. Which means,
I mean, until we invent some sort of computation that doesn't require electricity,
um
like maybe photonic based stuff or quantum
based stuff that just magically is better
um
whatever
it's all
gonna do electricity.
But the trick is you need a Cryptocurrency that doesn't need
the amount of electricity your house uses in a month to conduct one transaction.
-- Right.
-- And see this is the ugly part though,
there's an economic incentive in the traditional
payment systems to be more efficient,
more energy efficient, more
just more efficient, more better with Bitcoin.
There is that opposite incentive to be more
wasteful because you increase the work factor,
you more people start mining, more competition.
So there's that built in thing to be more wasteful and more inefficient
and that is not sustainable, especially on a global level for like, well, like
a global currency is going to have to handle a lot of transactions.
Right.
And, and so here's the thing I keep wondering
is Bitcoin going to die because financial regulators
decide they should kill it,
which I don't think it will because a lot of these banks and,
and financial investment firms are actually kind of getting on board now.
Well, more to the point, people will use it for illegal stuff like they always have
and
ignoring.
Right. Right. Right.
But
I have a suspicion the electricity is what's going to do it in
it will make it uneconomical.
And then the question is what happens because somebody
has to do mining because the whole system is predicated
off of people doing the mining and the chains to maintain the chain
with, with.
And right now you need huge volumes of electricity
and I don't think that's ever going to change.
And so the question becomes,
will,
will the electricity be a problem from a regulation standpoint of you have
governments and organizations saying like this is
the worst thing for the environment ever
or this is just a stupid use of electricity,
you don't need to regulate something that bad because it'll just,
it'll
put itself out of business.
And that's kind of my suspicion actually is that
Bitcoin will end up killing itself because of electricity use, like you said,
it will become too expensive
and
-- you know, I
-- guess it'll become uneconomical for most people now.
There will always, but, and, but here's,
and then here's where we get to the really ugly side of that.
The, the alternate side of that is, is
as
if you gain more than what is it, 50% of the Bitcoin mining capability,
you kind of can steer the consensus, which means you kind of control the currency,
that is the intent. However,
I actually
-- uh uh someone
-- else what happens when this requires 1.62 gigawatts or whatever.
So, so actually the that is less of a concern actually, JJ Rusnak,
he's one of the Fedora Red Hat guys, you know,
and,
uh, he did a, uh,
like a thesis on that actually.
And the thing he pointed out and made a big deal about it
and he and I argued about this at length at one point was
there's no incentive for a miner to exert that kind of control because if a miner
tries to say
that,
uh, or rather if a miner tries to do something shady,
-- you're going to ruin the Bitcoin network essentially.
-- No, I agree.
And, but the problem is there's a lot of people, if you have 1000 Bitcoins,
what are you going to do?
Opt out?
It's, it's tricky man there, there's not a good answer
and
the
normal people aren't going to know about this.
No, no, it's,
and that's part of the tricky aspect of this is I think a
lot of normal people probably see the hype and they see Bitcoins,
you know, on fire invest now
and there's even funds you can invest in that are buying cryptocurrencies.
And,
and I think that is kind of the real danger now
is that you're going to have people tricked out of real money
because they don't understand what this stuff is,
right? Because they see, holy cow, look at what's going on.
I need to get in on this now.
And in reality, this is how nearly every bubble works.
I mean, we,
we've seen it countless times where people
invest money into something they don't understand
and they end up getting screwed
and that's just, that is the world we live in, I think.
-- Yeah,
-- we're gonna, we'll put a link to Bre
X in the show notes
if you're Canadian, you know what I'm talking about.
I have no idea what you're talking about because
-- I'm not Canadian
-- biggest stock scandal in Canadian history.
-- Bigger
-- than
the
biggest mining scandal of all time.
A
mining scandal.
Yeah. They salted the samples with gold.
The shares went up like way, way, way, way up, turns out there was no gold.
Oops,
-- this sounds like a Bitcoin lesson buried in there somewhere.
-- Kurt.
If it's too good to be true,
it's
either
something, a new paradigm shift and amazing and wonderful.
Thank you for that or it is too good to be true.
It's always too good to be true. It is always too good to be true.
And I think
that is probably where we should leave it. I, I think
so if, if we were going to pretend we're movie critics
and we're going to rate Bitcoin, we're going to give it two thumbs down.
But the trick is even though we're giving it two thumbs down and
we would have given it two thumbs down years ago as well.
It's still going up.
And so
what, what happens now?
And, and this is, this is part of the beauty of predicting the future
is it is quite possible. We are completely wrong
and Bitcoin is going to reach like a million dollars a coin which I, I hope it does
the transaction
volume and value.
Uh
that would be,
but here's, here's part of it as well.
This is one of the other things I think about is by keeping volume low
on purpose.
Are they artificially inflating the value?
And
if there's an X number of liquid Bitcoins
to, to sell and use
out of
whatever, how many million, then, you know, by definition,
if like 10 people want to buy Bitcoin and
there's only 10,000 Bitcoins available versus the full 10 million
-- or whatever the number is now, I forgot.
-- It's like 6 million, I think.
Yeah, then, then
that's gonna shoot the price way up.
Yeah,
I, I know,
I know, man. I don't know. I guess that is
we, we don't know, we, we, neither of us believe in this,
neither of us are going to be investing our life savings.
I believe in
Bitcoin. I just don't believe it's going to be like the panacea that
I think it's going to crash
and when it crashes it'll be done.
I, that is my suspicion.
-- I think it's going to fail.
-- I don't think it's going to fail.
I think it's going to crash.
I think it's a bubble and it's going to crash.
Yeah.
And I'm, I'm comfortable saying that.
Now the question though is how high will the bubble go?
And I thought, I thought the bubble was going to burst at 300
right?
I was clearly wrong.
Traded. It is. And with the behavior, I would guess 20 or 50,000 easy
before it crates.
Because the thing to remember is
like stock prices, right? You, you, you have bids and asks
and just because somebody let me, but it's like,
remember when oil went over $100 a barrel is because this one trader was like, oh,
it's like 99 point whatever.
I'm going to be the first trader ever to bid at oil for over
100 bucks and bid on like 20 barrels or something stupid like that.
Just so you could say he was the first person to do that, right? And
what's gonna happen is some financial firms going like, oh God,
we need these like right now, like, I don't care, I don't care,
just buy five Bitcoins.
I don't care what they cost.
And that kind of behavior is going to bid this thing up because
the reality is every normal person holding Bitcoin
at this point. Like at least half of them would have sold at nine grand
when you're in like somewhere between a dollar and 100.
Yes.
Iii I would sell if I could.
And then the thing is, you know, who's going to give you cash for Bitcoin?
-- I, I
-- maybe there's a crazy person out there.
We should start a Bitcoin hedge fund, Kurt then then maybe we could get away with it.
But anyway,
I think it's collusion now if we do it so we can't.
Uh,
-- right.
-- Pretty
-- sure it's also a wire fraud because I'm not in your country.
-- I,
I bet we could break a lot of laws
-- or
-- something.
Right.
Anyway,
-- anyway,
-- I guess the moral of the story folks is, if it sounds too good to be true
and there's a whole pile of economic
economists arguing against
it.
Maybe don't put your life savings in.
But, you know, if you want to put like 100 bucks in the Bitcoin or whatever. Yeah.
Go for it.
-- Although now it's
-- been 100 bucks. Even. How much Bitcoin is that? Like 0.0001
or a percent of a Bitcoin? Yeah, because math is hard,
right?
Um,
yeah, I mean, it's like I do kind of like go fund me your Kickstarter, right? Like
disposable income. Go for it.
But like, please, for the love of God, don't put your retirement into this.
Yes, I will agree with that. I think that's fair advice.
It's, uh, you know, caveat emptor buyer. Beware, right.
It's
anyway. Very good. All right, I'm calling it, man. It was fun.
Uh Bit
point. I'm sure I can't, I can't wait for the hate mail.
I, I, I'm looking forward to it.
So, thank you everybody.
You can find a link to the show notes on the website, open source security,
podcast.com.
As well as contact info to let us know all the things we got wrong,
which I'm sure there were plenty
you can hit us up on Twitter and join a Facebook group
and yeah, let us know what you think. I'm certain we got many things wrong.
Maybe the next episode could be the, uh,
retraction episode where we just discuss everything we screwed up with.
Bitcoin
will crater up before
this
episode.
It would be hilarious if that happened and I would still publish it. But
also
pretty
tragic for a lot of people's life savings.
I have a suspicion that Bitcoin is going to go up for a lot longer.
So we will see
they did. Well,
-- Kurt, have a good day. You too.
-- Thanks.