Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Pressers. How's it going? Good.
-- Today, we're going to have two of your favorite topics.
-- I,
I, ok, I know one of them is beer, which is a favorite of mine.
-- I would agree, but I have no idea what the second one is.
-- Reproducible
builds.
-- Hey, I love that topic, man. That's a great topic actually. But
-- here's a question.
What do beer and reproducible builds have in common?
-- I mean,
-- I could think of a number of things.
So I'd be more curious to know what you think they
have in common versus what I think they have in common.
-- So
-- for beer, obviously, there's different kinds of beer,
but I'm going to go with sort of generally mass produced beer.
I'm like, I'm not talking like one off cask. You know, we made this special thing.
I'm talking about like beer that generally, you know, they make a lot of it
repeatedly
and that's reproducible builds.
-- I
-- mean, functionally, yes, because this is true of nearly any, any product,
obviously, because a great example is
right.
I mean, this is,
this is kind of the power of mcdonald's will say where I know
I can walk into a mcdonald's in any country on the planet.
I go in and I, I know exactly what I'm going to get. If I order a Big Mac and fries,
you know what's really funny, I must say first though,
every time I visit a new country,
I literally go to mcdonald's and order a Big Mac and fries
with the secret hope it will not be exactly the same.
And they always are.
-- I've
-- also, yeah,
the one thing I will say that I love about mcdonald's
is they have these weird regional things in the Czech Republic.
They had that pork, what was it called? The pork something burger?
And I mean, it was beyond delicious. It was amazing.
And in like India, they have like, what is it lamb burgers, which I would love to try,
but I'm not going to go to India to eat a hamburger.
I've heard their chicken is phenomenal also.
-- But I have never, I've never set foot in India. So I cannot
-- say back to beer.
So, and one of the things I love about beer too is that to put it bluntly in 1516.
So 504 years ago in Bavaria, they
passed the reinheitsgebot
which is the, the essentially the German beer purity regulation,
-- which
-- why don't you explain what that is?
Because there might be some people who don't know. And it's very cool actually.
-- So
-- basically,
it's a regulation that specifies what you're allowed to put in beer and also
how big it is and how much you're allowed to charge for it.
So the ingredients thing comes later.
But basically,
it says the only ingredients used for brewing of beer must be barley hops and water.
So, I mean, this is 500 plus years ago where they didn't know about yeast.
It was magic. Exactly.
It has been updated since then to include yeast and other things.
But what's interesting is they said from micro
mass to Georgy, the price of one mass.
So it's just over a liter or one cult fits a ball shaped container for fluids.
Not quite one mass. I think it's like 900 or something.
Milliliters is not to exceed one Fennig Munich value.
Which, and I mean, that's another throwback, right?
You've got to remember back 500 years ago, Germany wasn't a country, right?
It was a series of kingdoms that loosely hated and liked each other.
So, you know, when you talk about money, it's like which one?
And then they talk about pricing for the rest of the year and
part of that was to prevent competition with bakers for the grains.
Oh, I didn't know why. That was, that's cool.
Again, 500 years ago, it's not like we had giant combines and tractors and, you know,
a surplus of grain.
A lot of people invest heavily living an engrained life, trying not to starve,
trying to make just enough extra food that they could sell it to have a bit of a life,
you know, and then all those people in the cities living off of that.
Not like today where we've,
is it 2% of the population grows all the food for the rest of us.
It's a mind boggling number for sure. Yeah.
Part of what I love about this is just, especially in Germany.
There's this huge emphasis on quality of beer and I don't
mean just quality in the sense of like making good beer,
but quality in the sense of it's the same.
I've literally had beer from Germany that I've, you can like hack
a
s
that you can have in Germany and also exports and like,
I'll be damned if I can tell the difference.
-- And that's spanning like a period of 10 or 20 years.
-- I would argue that's true
of nearly every beer you buy in the store today.
I can't think of very many beers that I've purchased at two different
-- times and I've gotten what I would call two different beers
-- I have,
but usually with the smaller micro brews where that's
also part of their shtick where it's like,
literally,
we don't do that. Like, it's,
it's very, it's variable.
But yeah, like when I buy a beer, like coconut or something, like,
I'm pretty sure if I could somehow, I don't know,
maybe freeze a can of it or something.
Keep it for 20 years and then try it against another can of Coke.
20 years. Yeah. They'd probably be, like, chemically identical.
I mean, Bud Light does this too.
-- That's not,
-- that's
-- what
-- frustrates me. Right. Is,
oh, my God.
I've had so many good rice beers and then I've had Bud Light and it's just like, what
is this?
It's Bud Light man. It's actually so, you know, it's really funny.
The story I will tell is long ago in America,
there was a marvelous beer industry and then prohibition came
and alcohol was outlawed and obviously the beer industry collapsed.
And then
after prohibition,
we ended up with just a handful of very large breweries that basically made
everything and generally things like Bud Light and Miller come to mind whatever.
There's people who like him, there's people who don't. And then I would say
that reigned supreme until probably the mid to late nineties in the United States.
And now like we have another booming industry of these micro breweries.
But what's really funny is there's still places you can
go and they're generally very rural where they will say,
haven't experienced this boom in micro breweries.
So I went to, I was at this bar out in the middle of nowhere.
This is about a couple of years ago. I walk in and like, oh, what are you drinking?
I said what you got, they said we got both kinds and I thought, oh, my,
-- one of these,
-- I had the experience once of being in a delicatessen in New Jersey and I,
I, you know,
where they would make you a sandwich and
they had like all the normal processed meats.
And then he's like, do you want cheese on that?
I'm like, yeah, and he's like which one? I'm like,
what you got and he's like, we have white and yellow and I'm like,
my brain is like this isn't, is this a brand? Is this like what?
And he's like, I'm like, what, what do you mean like white and yellow, right?
Like these are colors, not cheeses
and he's like, we have American white and American yellow and I'm like, OK, that's
not out there, man. I'm like, what
are those? And you know, it's just heavily processed,
I guess cheddar
ish
would be the
closest
thing sort of cheddar
and the white's gonna be very provolone
ish is what you're going to. I,
I guess they
whatever,
it wasn't like bad, bad cheese. It was just, but it was like, not
-- exciting look,
-- man,
you're not going to a deli in New Jersey for the quality of their cheese.
Like that's just the reality of it.
I just, I, well,
I was led to believe through movies that like all
the delis in like that part of the world were,
-- you
-- know, in Manhattan, the delis in Manhattan are Froy,
the Delis outside of Manhattan are just Delis.
Ok.
Right. Exactly. Yeah. So back to this, I mean, to me that's one of the beauties.
Like I,
there's one or two brands of beer I drink consistently because to put it bluntly
enough other people drink them that those beers are never stale at the store.
Like I prefer to get some of the fancier beers,
but I've literally picked up like Sam Adams is a great example because
they put their expiry dates on all their beers and they actually do
send out like random guest inspectors to like, clear them out.
But I've more often than not in liquor stores here,
encountered expired Sam Adams beer, which I mean, it's not bad but it's not great,
you know.
So honestly I drink a couple of major brands
that everybody else drinks because they're always fresh.
-- It just moves. I mean,
-- that's pretty fair. I can't think of it actually.
You know what? I did have skunky beer a while back I went to.
So we have in town, they call themselves a Chicago Deli. It's like,
it's basically a restaurant that just serves a bunch of terrible Chicago food.
And it's marvelous.
And I actually ordered,
there's a beer called Goose Island which started in Chicago.
It's actually brewed in New York now,
but I ordered a Goose Island while I was there. I'm like, I like Goose Island.
You've got Goose Island. Yeah, it expired like a year before I got it.
And I thought I'm not going to make a big deal about this because, like,
the guy was pretty grumpy.
I was already dealing with and I felt like this is how you get, you know,
spit in your food.
Yeah.
-- But
-- I
-- mean,
-- that's like,
this is what Gordon Ramsay starts screaming at
people and he's right to scream at them.
Yeah. But I don't want him spitting in my hot dogs. So it's fine
and, and they have Marvelous Chicago style hot dogs there, which is why I go.
But yeah. Yeah.
So it was, it was bad. It was so bad.
The thing I love about reproducible bills is
why do they actually matter for security?
And I would say they matter for security for the same reason, it matters for beer
and it shows me
that you can actually produce the product correctly
and in the case of software, you can actually correct it and get it out the door.
Sort of,
this is a complicated topic and I've probably written about this in the past.
I'll see if I can dig out some old blog posts maybe.
But reproducible builds are incredibly misunderstood
in the industry because people think
they mean something they don't all reproducible builds mean is that given
what the source code I claim I built, given the build system
claim I used, you should get the same thing on the other end that I got as well.
It doesn't mean that it's secure, it doesn't mean it doesn't have bugs.
And my favorite example of this is Ken
Thompson has a piece called Trusting Trust where he
basically took ac compiler on a unit system a million years ago and he hacked it.
So every time it built the login program, it would insert a backdoor.
But then he even turned it up to an 11
because the compiler also would look for when it was building
a new compiler and make sure it backdoor that compiler too.
Just so people couldn't build a new compiler and then build a new login system.
The whole point of this basically is saying that
there you can only trust what's happening to a certain degree.
And then you have to just say there's nothing I can do after this point.
And I mean, reproducible builds are sort of like that of,
can you trust all of the components in your build system?
Absolutely not.
I would agree, but also partly disagree.
If you're willing to go to ridiculous lengths,
you can essentially get a relatively clean build system.
And I don't mean just like bootstrapping it
from like hand coated assembler and like,
you know, wiring up your own eight bit chip on a bread board.
Although people have done those things. I mean, no, that's, that's absurd.
What you can do.
For example is, you know, if you're buying equipment,
you just go to the store and buy it randomly.
You don't, you know, order it and like have, you know, hey, going back to like our,
you know, the
about the NSA intercepting hardware and adding chips and whatnot.
For example,
if you just go to a random apple store and buy a Mac or
you go to a random best buy and buy like a Lenovo laptop,
you know,
chances are if somebody didn't monkey with it in the supply chain
on the way to you unless they monkeyed with all of them,
right?
In which case, all bets are off. Like that's, that's an like no offense.
If an attacker can monkey with a supply chain to that degree to then target you.
They're just going to like kidnap you and beat you with a lead pipe.
I, I wouldn't even argue that's
a
threat model.
I mean, what I would say is more likely is, let's say, for example,
I'm building Fedora and I'm going to pick on Fedora just because I've,
I've worked with them for a long time when we were at Red Hat.
So Fedora has a build system, right?
And logically,
the build system used in Fedora today can
trace its roots back to basically Red Hat Linux
from, you know, 1927 when it was first created
and there's kind of AAA lineage there.
And so far
as an attacker,
I know if I can insert the right kind of backdoor
or the right kind of malware in the right place.
The next and future build systems are potentially
going to contain this malware that attack model.
You can't defend against that with reproducible builds
because you're using the same backdoor build system.
I am. So we're going to get the same backdoor builds.
What reproducible builds can do though is you can say, all right,
so here's a build system, here's what comes out the other end
now. And I think is it the Firefox browser, the Tor Browser does this where basically
software comes in software comes out.
And so it's a way to say, I'm going to rebuild this software.
I'm going to check all the files and I'm gonna make sure that the files I get are
the files they built because between the time it
was built and the time it was published,
what if somebody mucked with that?
And obviously, in the case of something like the Tor Browser, there are real,
we'll say there are
well funded organizations that would have a real interest in back door, that thing.
Well, and part of it too speaks to the maturity of the organization.
Like I've encountered a lot of places where to do a
build of a software you need Bob because Bob knows how to
do the magic to make it work. Like literally right?
Versus you just shove some code and hit a button and
out pops, you know, something at the end with no human interaction.
There was a company I worked for once. This is before Redhead. It wasn't red hat.
The only way to build
software we had was you had to create a user with the name of the guy who developed
the build system on your system because it would
look for certain things in that home directory.
And
-- so I have hard coded paths.
-- If it wasn't there, it wouldn't work at the same time.
There's another angle to reproducible builds.
Let's say I have a product I built a year ago.
If I had to, could I basically like,
change it to that branch or check that code out at that point in time and rebuild
software and basically get back what I built a year
ago or am I going to get something drastically different?
And the reason I say this is so let's think of the node ecosystem, right?
Let's say I'm pulling in a package.
Let's say, I don't know, like make up a package name, right?
Let's say, let's say low dash.
We picked on that a couple of episodes ago,
low dash a year ago looks nothing like low dash today.
Well, it kind of does because their development is going very fast.
But you know what I mean?
Like,
well, and that speaks to the whole, you know, vendors, your
dependencies or pinning them and things like that because
yeah, like most, well, a year is a huge amount of time for software delta,
especially in something like the node ecosystem.
I mean, well, even in something like GCC 10 is just,
is it out or is it just about to come out?
-- I,
-- I
-- don't
-- know, I haven't paid attention to GCC in a long time.
Right.
But I'm going to assume you do a reproducible build system with like
GCC nine and a reproducible build system with GCC 10 and you're going to
-- get the same thing,
-- they're guaranteed to be different.
-- No way that's going to happen.
-- Right. Right. Yep. Absolutely funny.
You mentioned pinning
and I'm going to pick on that as well.
So even that's not something you can trust because for example,
remember when it was the left shift guy and node got mad and deleted all his stuff.
Yeah.
So now anything that needed that library that hasn't been updated and was built,
say back before that was gone now it just won't build at all because that NP MP,
it is. Well, I think it exists again because someone made it, you know what I mean?
Like, well, and that speaks to vendors,
your dependencies where you use something like I think, what is it like,
yarn or whatever to actually pull the files in and keep them locally.
-- So you have like a stashed copy. Yeah.
-- Yarn does that.
There's J Frog has a product called Artifact that does that I think
WASP
has something too they're pushing now. That's similar. But, yeah. Yeah.
That's hugely important.
-- And
-- again,
that speaks to not security but just having the darn thing
work at like Saturday at four in the morning when,
well,
I remember once when like python.org disappeared from the
internet for me because my ISP had routing issues.
And so like a whole bunch of Python related stuff broke because I couldn't, you know,
pi pie, right?
Like everything is broke. And I was like calling my IP.
and they're like, you know,
because it was hosted off of access for all back in the day,
which was also where the Pirate Bay was and,
and the guy was like, oh, you can't get to the Pirate Bay.
I'm like, well, I can't, but honestly, I don't care.
I need python.org like I need, I need freaking Python to work here.
And he's like, what?
And I'm like, Python, you know, they posted with the same people.
He's like, oh yeah, it seems to be down.
I'm like, yeah, so it finally after two weeks got fixed.
Ouch.
Yeah, I, I'd literally just VPN through a machine in the US. Yeah. Lesson learned.
What gets me though is looking at software when people make beer, you know,
they're constantly sampling and testing things to make sure, you know,
like the hops aren't all weird or full of squirrels or whatever, right?
And they're going to measure it right.
You're not going to just be like, I just throw some hops in. I don't know, whatever.
Like no, you're gonna, you're gonna measure it.
We're putting in exactly one bucket of hops. Right.
Oh,
my God. You Americans. You volumetric, man. A
bucket. A bucket is a measurement. It's fine. Everything's fine.
-- It's a volumetric
-- measurement,
-- which is,
-- oh, as
opposed to weight.
Actually, that's fair. That's true.
-- I, you know, I've been trying to do more
-- because every time I do baking,
is that packed?
-- Is it loose? Is it?
-- I agree.
And I'm actually, I've been, I've been making a lot of effort lately to use weight,
but I still fall back to volumetric all the time.
In fact, I just, I made waffles this morning for breakfast and
it was volumetric where I needed cups of water. Well, water, I guess is ok.
-- But cups of
-- temperature and whatnot. But, yeah, cups
of water and cups of flour. And
I kept thinking that while I'm measuring, I wish I had weight for this one.
Well, because every time something talks about, for example, using like nuts,
well, like a couple of walnuts.
Like, do you want me to get them in there with a hammer or do I just, like,
throw a handful in?
You put as many walnuts in as you can fit?
-- That's how many walnuts are the right number of walnuts.
-- Yeah, exactly. So,
ah, anyway,
-- by
-- weight, it should just say, wait all of the walnuts. That's how much it's,
well, and that's where you end up with the raisin scone. That's like all raisins.
I hate raisins. But yes, that's exactly right.
Well, just this weekend, not this weekend. Sorry.
Last weekend there was, what was it? Oh, here we go. Here we go. Found it.
Finally a one line package.
Broke N PM Create App and it's the is under or is
hyphen promise in node made a change that you needed to,
I think you need to change how you call it.
Like you actually had to change the arguments you used to call,
which of course broke everything.
Yeah, here we go.
However, the export syntax requires a relative URL eg dot slash index dot MGS,
not index dot MGS uh sorry.
So it wasn't the arguments or a number of arguments.
It was the the argument now has to be an actual
relative path name like dot slash instead of just file name.
I'm good with that though.
I mean that's and, and sometimes you need to make changes that hurt. I I get that
mean clearly,
-- nobody was expecting this
-- maybe one of the challenges in any ecosystem.
Well,
like Python two just released their final version like for real final version.
Thank goodness.
And if I look at my, you know, my terminal here on my Mac and I type in Python hyphen V,
you know, I get 2.7 0.6.
-- What is the, what is the current version?
-- The latest Python two?
They just released like a week ago was a 2.7 0.17.
And is that the version of Python that Apple is distributing?
-- No,
-- they're doing a classic red Hat, you know, sort of quasi.
Or at least, I hope they're doing a classical red hat of back boarding for all.
-- I know they're just shipping an old version
-- and they might be because let's face it,
the number of security issues is generally low
in things like core languages.
And I mean, to be clear,
-- they also have Python three and
-- everyone should just be using
that because it's vastly superior to Python two in every way.
Yes.
And it's supported.
That's a minor detail
back to this.
So I see stuff like this where somebody makes a change that, you know, is uh well,
technically a breaking change, it's not that bad because like, yeah,
a bunch of build systems broke and people fixed them.
-- Let's
-- put this in the context of beer. OK?
Because I think it might be easier to understand.
You have a supply chain in beer, you have certain ingredients,
you have to have to make it if one of
your suppliers suddenly has different quality or even just vanishes,
which does happen,
-- times you have to adapt
-- well.
-- The haw shortage in 2013 to 15,
-- that's a perfect example.
And this is the same thing with software where
sometimes your suppliers are going to flake out,
sometimes they're going to have bugs, sometimes they're going to disappear.
Part of being on the end of the production line
is you just have to deal with it sometimes.
And that's, there's,
there's no good way to ever be prepared except to be able to move quickly.
There are preparation steps you can take
like using something that actually downloads and keeps
a copy of your dependencies so that you have them in case like Python dot
routing gets broken or whatever.
Well, and so I would argue that's still comparable to our beer situation
because for example,
am I going to start making beer before I have all the ingredients in the warehouse?
No way. Right.
I'm going to say, all right, I have all the hops I need, I have all the grains I need,
you know, water's free coming from the city, whatever.
I'm good there. Then we start making the beer.
We don't say like, oh the hops are on the way. They'll be here tomorrow.
Let's start boiling the grains like no,
don't do that because if the hops don't come
tomorrow now you've just wasted and ruined everything,
right?
Well, I guess the difference between soft terms,
you don't have that kind of wastage or spoilage problem, right?
I mean, we don't, it's different.
Conversely, storage of software is actually pretty tricky.
It's very difficult, you know,
because I'm just thinking like if I gave you a tar ball of some dependency, great,
cool.
-- How do you feed that into the build system
-- these days, you basically can't,
unless you're willing to stand up like your own custom N PM system,
which is a nightmare in itself.
Yeah. Don't do that.
Folks use something like a tooling system like yarn or whatever.
No, seriously.
Like, I know, like all these people that, you know,
the whole idea of custom container registries, honestly, unless you're Netflix,
you're too small to bother doing it.
It's a pain.
Well, just because I've stood up, you know, I've,
I've stood these things up and to properly care and feed
for them and back them up and make sure that they're available
is just no.
Well, that's like anything. Right. It always seems easy
to get something running. But then it's hard to keep it running.
I see that every day where someone says, oh, we should do this and you say, all right.
But who's going to own it? And they say, what do you mean?
Like, well, we're going to stand this up and then someone has to care and feed it,
you know, for the end of time.
-- Well, yeah,
-- until we stop using it. Yeah.
And then they're like, oh, well, I don't want to do that. Like, yeah. No,
nobody does. So, but at the same time, if you're not willing to own it,
no one's going to do this because I don't want to either.
Well, I'm now making the transition, you know, we're transitioning out of
structure as a service and moving to platform as a service because quite frankly,
I don't want to manage the servers and, well,
neither does the DEV team and we actually
just had uh one server like randomly reboot.
And I go in, OK. The up time is weird. It's like it got rebooted. I'm like checking in
a did Amazon reboot. It did I make an image of this thing or something automatically?
No. And it literally was an out of memory error. And so Linux went all Ky
and killed something that ended up with the machine rebooting.
And I'm like, well, fantastic. Do I just double the ra M in this
or? That's the easiest.
Well, no, the actual answer is like, OK, this is slated for movement from IAS to PA
in like a few weeks.
-- So we'll just make that like, let's do that actually,
-- you know,
it's funny you bring this up.
I have a great I learned a lesson about.
So there's a game called Donkey Kong 64 that came out on the Nintendo 64 long ago.
This is probably, I bet what the year probably 9998 maybe give or take.
-- It came
-- out in 99.
I
was pretty
flies. So,
so anyway, this game was the,
I think the first game on the Nintendo 64 that required the memory
uh expansion pack, which is basically like it doubled the ra M in the Nintendo 64.
And the thing was, I don't know, it was 20 or 30 bucks.
I forget how much it was back then.
And anyway,
the only reason it needed this is because the
game had a memory leak and it would crash in
about four hours to play without it and it would crash in like 40 hours of play with it.
So,
their solution to the memory leak was just, you have to buy more memory.
And honestly,
I've seen that happen with large scale pieces of
software that just sort of don't clean garbage.
Well, it's probably cheap than fixing the bug.
-- Now, Nintendo's selling more stuff
-- that's not a memory leak.
A memory leak is where you expose memory according to CW.
You know, the common weakness, enumeration database,
-- whatever
-- that's from the security perspective.
Yeah, but so this is a memory allocation error,
-- whatever everyone calls it a memory leak or
-- what is it?
-- Sorry, memory use and lack of freeing or whatever it's called memory
-- leak.
We all call it a memory leak.
And,
and my experience like dealing with memory leaks is
the cost of having somebody competent to go do that
versus, yeah, telling your customers just add another stick of ra m
Well, like those, what is it? The Patriot missile system?
Remember because I had that integer overflow where it
drifted over time from time and same thing.
What is it like seven some model of the 777 I want
to say or 787 has to be rebooted every like 43 days,
-- like every 32 bit one
-- of
-- the Boeing
-- planes.
And
now I will also say though in the nineties, when Donkey Kong 64 was,
was being created, the memory, I guess inspection tools were really bad.
It was actually really common to have a memory leak in your application.
If you wrote c that you couldn't figure out because it was,
it was leaking in some ridiculous and weird way
because once you start doing crazy pointer arithmetic,
things are out of hand these days, there's tools like valgrind, for example,
that you basically run your, you know, you compile your tool with the debug info.
My devs like I forget which ruby thing they did,
but they basically bolted on a ruby thing and were like, OK, you know,
here's a bunch of problems and they fixed it in like a day.
Oh, that's like the A PM stuff,
not A PM was something else that like tells you about your memory usage and CPU usage.
And they just found like a bunch of code that was like, not at all optimized.
But and that's the thing like, and honestly, in modern computing terms,
you don't have to optimize code because like literally the
slowest machine I have in this house is probably my,
well, that's a computer, like not
my light bulbs that have computers in them, but
-- it's like a Raspberry Pi four with four gigs of ra M.
-- Right.
That's like the slowest system I have in this house.
Now, I will say you have to remember. It's easy to say that that it doesn't matter.
But like if you have to scale up because now
once you have a fleet of a million machines,
if you can decrease that by even 10% that's cash money right there.
OK. Then explain Google Chrome to me, please.
Because man, that memory is not their problem.
Like actually in all seriousness,
I've quit running Google Chrome almost exclusively,
I'll still like I use it for the podcast because it does work better.
Like they obviously test that the more, more so with the service we use.
Well, Chrome is the first class web browser nowadays.
-- I mean,
-- it kind of is,
but I've been running Firefox almost exclusively and the memory use is lovely.
It makes a huge difference.
I'm very and, and of course,
I'm happy to support Firefox because Google is
a terrifying organization for a number of reasons.
Well, you know, even if they mean, well,
if they accidentally like kind of lean up against you,
it's like an elephant leaning up against you like you're, you're a bug split,
right? So,
but anyway, anyway,
all right, all right. Purity.
-- I
-- guess maybe the moral of the story is,
is you don't need to do a lot of crazy things to make.
Let me put it this way. You don't need to get a full 100% reproducible build system.
I mean,
in my personal opinion, you should and, and that's not from a security point of view,
but purely from an efficiency, pushing a button,
making it build point of view and getting it to work.
I mean, on the flip side,
I've got like a bunch of Python scripts that literally say like mem
cash
D to walk through it and get all the items out of mem
Cash D from within Python is basically a complete pain in the butt.
Whereas there's a command line utility called like Mem
cash
D dump or something.
And so my script literally says before you run this script, you have to go run mem
cash
D dump.
Hyphen O space
file name, do that first and then run the script. Why?
Because it backs up everything in mem
Cash
D
I
understand. So basically I write stuff to mem
Cash
D and then I want to export it. Interesting.
So, you know, and that's per example, like with this reproducible build system,
don't maybe shoot for 100
percent reproducible builds.
But like for the love of God, maybe download all your artifacts just so that,
you know, when, when the network or something has a glitch or
no Js has a DNS related issue or who knows that you can still rebuild your software.
Reproducible builds are surprisingly difficult.
Well, I'm saying it's a continuum and you can,
you don't have to shoot for 100% reproducible.
But there are steps you can take that actually also have a benefit.
-- I would
-- argue you should shoot for 100% reproducibility.
But you have to understand it's a journey.
You're not going to go from 0 to 100 overnight because that comes
back to the typical security problem of perfect or nothing means nothing.
And it's like when with anything you do, you can't go from 0 to 100.
It's, it's a journey and it was the same thing with the quality and purity of beers
where
the ability to consistently make a type of beer that tastes
the same and is functionally the same that didn't happen.
It took us 400 years like
it's OK.
Well, I would make one caveat is that for some people,
you don't really actually need reproducible oil.
So for example, if it's like an internal tool,
having Bob come in and do the magic to make it work, hopefully,
as long as Bob documents it somewhere so that if he gets hit by a bus,
you're not completely up the creek by and large.
I mean, I'll be blunt, like
obviously there's variability in the beers I drink.
I don't have the palate to notice and more
to the point like every time they talk about,
you know, beer,
palates and wine palates and then they do the test where
they take like a red wine or rather they take two,
they take two bottles of identical white wine.
They put red food die in one and like, put it in a different bottle.
And of course, you know, these,
these master sommeliers describe them completely differently.
And it's like, well, those people are useless. No offense.
I have an opinion on this and I don't want to
get into it too deeply because we're nearly out of time.
But I think fundamentally
and I'll, I'm going to pick on wine here because I,
I do love wine and I drink it whenever I can
is part of the fun in drinking wine
is the experience
and
the color of the wine
and the smell of the room you're in and the temperature outside and all of that
is part of that experience.
And so while I understand that a lot of this, the descriptions people give is like,
-- technically BS,
-- well, I would say this is also true of beer and food.
Right. Like I don't ever want to eat hot wings in summer unless it's on a patio.
-- Yeah, that's true. If it's, if I'm outside drinking beer, I'm good.
-- Yeah, exactly.
And that's the point. Right. Same thing with Christmas pudding.
I eat Christmas pudding once a year at Christmas.
That's it. Like, I, same thing with pickled herring.
I eat pickled herring once or twice a year in the week between Christmas
-- and New
-- Year's and I can eat pickled herring anytime I love pickled herring.
I do too. But like the, you know, my breath and everything, everybody hates me.
Well, actually my problem is no one else in my family eats it except my dad. I buy a jar.
I split it in half.
And then, yeah,
by the time I'm done with it it's like I am sick
of pickled herring because this was a lot of pickled herring.
But anyway,
the point is it's part of the experience, right?
And so, and, and honestly, I think even software is this to a degree where it's
the journey is the reward, as we say, right?
Where do what works for you and screw everyone else. All right, I'm calling it.
This was, this was fun. It is
two of the topics. I do indeed enjoy beer and reproducible build.
So, thank you for that, Kurt. I appreciate it.
So. All right. Thank you everyone for listening. You can go to open
source security podcast.com. Hit up the show note to the
Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag If you hit us up on social media, Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks
-- everyone. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.