Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 182 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
How you doing, man?
Better. The cold snaps over and it's actually kind of nice winter now
and again,
we talk of the weather for people who live in strange places and potentially are
listening through the sands of time and it's the middle of summer for them.
So,
and maybe it's snowy where they live in the middle of summer. It is possible.
That's true. There is there anywhere that snows in the summer?
Probably some places in South America. Right.
Well, if you live high up enough in the mountains. Yeah, that's probably true.
Like we once almost got snowed on at summer camp.
Yeah.
Like I remember us having a snowball fight that
I'm not even gonna
comment on that. There's,
there's so much there, Kurt, I feel like
I went to summer camp like a normal person. I am completely normal. I do
normal things. Right.
Right.
Anyway.
Oh, my God. I didn't even know how to transition out of this.
That I'm normal, normal.
But,
well,
ok, normal. Human behavior
anyway.
OK.
So we have a special episode planned today and this one normalizing Eval code
it.
No.
So
I have a couple of stories that have come to my attention recently and,
and one of them I'm involved with more than I wish I was.
But
it is
something that's been on the back of my mind now for a while.
And this is kind of the question I will pose to you is a very general idea is,
does the maintainer
of an open source project
owe you anything?
I would say that's a complicated question.
And it depends, and I would say one of the biggest it depends on is
what have they publicly said.
Because for example, if I download a piece of source code
and obviously it has the standard licensing terms of, you know,
this software isn't good for anything.
And if it eats your cat,
that's too bad,
right? That's generally accepted software clause.
You know, if it causes any damage or problems, it's, that's on you
on the flip side. If
the developer or developer plural, if it's big enough to be a project,
have made some sort of commitment to the software,
what do I want to say?
Sort of actually, you know, in writing where they've said, like we,
we will support this version and the last version or,
you know, we are committed to improving the software.
Well, then I would say
ideally they keep their word ok.
So let's take the large organizations, like obviously there,
there's places like Apache or the open SSL group or Mozilla,
take them away
because they're, that's a different conversation.
Yeah. So, ok. Well, actually let's even take one
people who actually
make
money directly off of their software.
Not necessarily, I don't, I wouldn't even say that because I would say if I'm,
for example, I have a bunch of github
repos
and I don't make money off them.
They're in my case, they're not widely used by any means, but
they exist.
And the question I have is do I owe the people using my software anything?
So my thinking here is,
for example, if your software does have
some dangerous or pointy or sharp edges,
you should probably document or make those known.
Like one of my favorite examples is Python Pickle, right?
If you go to the Python Pickle web page and giant red text
use that it has, you know,
it says like, do not use this to take data from unknown sources because basically,
like we're going to,
we're going to unpick this thing and it's going to like
it can modify your, your code, like you in memory,
it will eat your dog.
Yeah.
But you know,
Python Pickle does have a place in the in Python in the use for various reasons.
I would say essentially
ideally, I'd like to see the developers
make
a reasonable best effort and I'm not going to
qualify that with the usual term that we use,
which is, you know, I will make every commercially reasonable effort to blah, blah,
blah, blah, blah.
Right. Because these people aren't commercial.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, that's fine. We're not lawyers. There's no
commercial relationship. It's,
and even broader.
For example, if I do a youtube video tutorial on how to say, take something apart
and I do it in a way that
you're going to damage it and there's a better way to do it without damaging it.
Do I have a duty to take down that video when somebody points out, hey, you know,
here's a better video that shows you how
to take this thing apart without damaging it.
I think that is a reasonable comparison and I would argue yes,
you should take that video down or at least note it and say, look,
there's an updated video that bla
yeah, and that's probably better even, actually
I've several times looked for videos on like
how to sort of do some little plumbing thing or take something apart.
And it's like, well, it's like the classic thing, you know, the first tear down.
Well, actually I fix it does this, you know,
where they tear something apart and then they're like, oh,
and once we tore the first one apart,
that's when we figured out how you actually take it apart without, you know,
snapping this piece off or whatever.
Right.
And, and that's fair, you know, because,
and then quite often they will actually have like
a corrected video or at least a warning saying,
you know,
uh, this step where we said this, don't actually do this, do this other thing.
And, like, what was it?
I bought a, yeah, a replacement battery from my iphone se and of course, you know,
I'm,
I'm pretty sure the first person to crack open an iphone
se there's a couple of spots where you can easily,
like, mess things up pretty bad.
Right. Right.
Anyways, but back to the software thing,
I would say people should ideally make a best effort.
The other thing,
well,
the other challenge too is we don't
necessarily know the circumstances of these people.
And I would say that also affects it because for example, sort of, uh in some cases,
these people are paid to work on this software, right?
They, they, they work for a company that's like we need a piece of software that does X
and so somebody writes an open source version implementation of it and releases it.
So
while they're not being like directly paid to work on it,
their company uses it and they get maybe some time to work on it.
Right?
Versus there are people that wrote something for themselves and they're like, hey,
I found this useful.
I'm just going to stick this up on my github because,
and then,
and sometimes these things become wildly popular,
you're conflating things that I think are irrelevant points to this conversation.
And so let me just explain
the stories driving this and then we can kind of
explore from there because I don't think that point matters.
So
the, the first story is
a Rust tool that's called Acti
web. And I'll put a link in the show notes to a blog post, that kind of
details the, the story behind this and what it kind of comes down to is obviously,
Rust is meant to be a safe programming language, not like
c for example, where C lets you basically shoot yourself in the foot, you know,
multiple times without even knowing you're doing it and it can be
extremely dangerous, right?
Russ is meant to fix a lot of those things,
but it also has the ability to run unsafe code
where and that makes sense because sometimes you might want to say like, right,
like II I understand, take the training wheels off.
I'm on my own here. I get it right
now. This, this
Aix Web apparently basically took just a bunch of unsafe code
and wrapped it all in the unsafe.
Uh I I guess I don't need a decorator. I don't know what they call it, a rust
and then
sent it out to the world and people started looking at this, they were like,
whoa look at all this unsafe code, we shouldn't do this.
And the developer was basically like, it's fine, everything's fine, it's fine.
And then people of course, did a bunch of testing and they kind of fuzzed it,
it sounds like.
And you can imagine what happened right
now. Here's what I will say.
I think at this point, the developer can say it's fine.
The developer can say
I don't want to fix it,
but people started submitting patches
and the developer said,
no,
I don't want your patches that fix these bugs so well In fairness though,
I've seen people submit patches that are horrifically bad
and some of them probably were,
I'm not talking about this specific issue, but in general,
I've seen people try and submit patches and it's like
your patch is bad.
It makes but Kurt, no, no, no, no, I don't, I don't want to do this because you're,
you're, you're distracting us from the actual problem.
Some of the patches were garbage. I guarantee it,
not all of them were right. This is
if you read the story,
this is clearly an issue of a developer who either didn't
want to admit fault or didn't want to do the work
and they were unwilling to turn their project into a community
project and they were hanging on to it by themselves.
And this is the thing
where I say, do you owe someone? Anything
that I think
this is where the open source concept sort of falls apart,
but sort of not because there's the concept of forking, that's part of it.
Well, I was about to say, I mean, worst case scenario,
somebody could fork this open source project, call it.
You know,
the thing that the code formerly known as act
and with a little
symbol but
is tricky. And I agree it's where this is going to end up. I have no doubt.
And additionally
running an open source project is really hard. Right.
Forking runs to the Wikipedia problem is the problem with Wikipedia is not that,
you know, it's great that everybody can have a copy of Wikipedia.
But if Wikipedia were to shut down,
where do we all go to keep editing it and keep it up to date
when there's like 700 copies floating around?
And that's one of the problems with forks is sort of, well, OK.
So this software got fork, there's like three or four major forks, which one is
the winner as it were.
And that's where that,
that's where you really do want the original developer's involvement
so that they can either officially bless the fork or
actually I'm just looking what happened with
Aix Web is
the original developer handed the project over to another person
to be project leader.
And so that hopefully,
now that person becomes more active and accepts patches and life goes on.
Right. Right.
And we can hope and now, but so here's, here's where that gets,
gets tricky and I'm going to, I'm going to kind of, there's a project in the node
Js world called low dash. And
I'm going to throw them under the bus a little bit here because I can
is so low dash is used in an enormous number of node dependencies.
If you do an NPM install of almost anything,
there is a very high probability low dash is going to come in with it.
And it's,
it's this,
this library that kind of adds functional programming like behavior to your,
your javascript project is basically what it is.
And it's a really cool library and it does some really neat things,
but the way it works, it has some very sharp edges and I've in fact is,
is I didn't try to do this. But I had multiple people come to me saying
I tried to raise some of these issues with low dash and the developer basically said
it's supposed to work that way.
And this is like this is like, you know,
to open your garage door and it lights on fire type stuff, right?
This is things that a reasonable person would not expect to be normal behavior.
Well, I'm just looking at that, that link you sent me and it's
Yeah.
Yeah. So it's pretty scary.
Yeah, I will,
I'll put a link to one or more issues.
I, I I'll, I'll decide how many I want to link because there's more than one
that are just some bugs
kind of detailing some of these issues. And the developer saying
I, I don't most of the time he says I'm too busy to do anything about this
and
see and that right there. But right there that says to me that,
OK, cool. You're too busy to do anything.
So are you going to accept help from the community members and actually, you know,
promote them to be
project
leadership admins or whatever you want to call it?
That's exactly kind of where I was hoping
to go with this because something like LO dash
is basically so embedded into the node ecosystem.
I think forking it is not going to be useful because so much
other stuff is already using it that I think replacing it would be
a monumental effort.
Well, actually it's interesting, there's actually some data on that Cloud Flare
blog just had an article on
javascript libraries are almost never updated once installed. The
Jquery Blog, I saw that
I am,
I am I for one am shocked, shocked, I tell you, you're right,
you know, like,
and this isn't just because you and I both
work for a software vendor where the idea was,
you know, take a piece of software and freeze it in time in Amber for 13 years.
No, like this is actually
this is actually quite normal.
Like for people like to be blunt, once you pull in something,
why would you update it?
It's only gonna maybe break stuff, you know,
like I'm really proud of my devs because they, they stay on the bleeding edge
and, yeah, they encounter Brokenness stuff all the time
but
they, they don't increase that delta between us and reality as much, you know, by,
by using the same thing for four years.
But, um, and especially, you know,
and it's one thing like pulling in a new version of something is
painful but like changing all those low dash to point to the,
the software formerly known as low dash,
right? That's just not gonna happen. No, it, it, it won't. I agree.
I agree. And then
it, it becomes very problematic.
And additionally, I think one of the other tricky things is so like, for example,
I have lots of crappy little github
projects that no one wants to help me with.
People, send me like drive by patches every now and then.
Actually, there, there's one project I have called
Yarn, which is an old net
hack style game
that is from, it's from a million years ago.
And for whatever reason I ended up with it,
I think it's because the old maintainer didn't care.
I sent a patches. You're like, I don't want this. Do you want it?
I'm like, yeah, I'll take it.
So anyway, I put it on github
and like,
yeah, someone sent me three patches one time.
I was like, do you just want commit privilege?
Because I'm sick of like, you know, taking your
request and adding it. I was like, oh yeah, that's cool.
And he did a few more and now, like, we haven't updated it in like,
five years and every now and then I'll get a bug report and I'm like, oh, ok,
I'll do something here and, you know, I'll maybe fix it or whatever.
But, like, it is,
it is one thing I think when it's just like,
crap little projects in Josh's github repos.
And it's another thing when, like, this is a
functional piece of software that is depended upon by an enormous number of people.
I think the phrase you're looking for, it's a key component of the ecosystem. Yeah.
That's fair. Right? Like we can't just get rid of all the worms.
And I think in a case like that
saying as an open source maintainer, you owe people nothing.
I won't say that's untrue, but I would say what you owe the world is a community.
And if people are willing to help you and willing to work with you in your community,
well, I wouldn't say you owe them a community.
I would say you owe them
the right to allow them to build a community. Yeah, that's fair. OK. I'll buy that.
But, you know, I mean, same idea. Right.
That's, I mean, I tried that with DW when people wanted to get involved, I was like,
hell, yeah, please do.
And of course they didn't really, and when I shut it down, they were all like, oh,
I would have helped And I'm like, no,
no, you wouldn't know because if you would have helped, you would have helped.
And that's ok too because I think you shutting it down
was the right move instead of keeping it barely alive,
which is not the right move.
Yeah. Just put things down
and there was a reasonable replacement for it. That's the other thing. Right.
Yes, that is true because CD E fixed a lot of their problems, you mean miter?
Sure,
whatever.
So anyways back
to this though,
I would say,
I think this actually there's a lot of real world analogs in the, for example,
it's not up to me or it's not my job to create community where I live.
But for example, I would say it would be a real dick move
to prevent other people from forming and creating a healthy community,
right?
To actively get in people's ways who want to
organize and make the world a better place.
That's kind of rude.
That's really interesting actually,
that you bring that up because I've seen things like this happen before.
And my favorite example is always when
you have like a group of especially young people trying to do something,
say at the park
and you'll have like this, it's always a grumpy old person for whatever reason,
they're throwing the ball too much and they're running
like one of my personal goals is to make sure that it's never me but you know. Right.
They're complaining about things and it's like just
there is literally nothing wrong with this event.
You need to just stay away, but they don't, right. They like, they actively try
to make it worse and they end up making themselves worse.
Well, or they impose rules or, oh, you're playing it wrong.
Like, literally, I,
I actually had to intervene once at the playground
because this adult was yelling at somebody else's kids
and,
and I was like,
and I literally the the parent was trying to intervene
and he was yelling at her and I'm like,
buddy, like a
complete stranger is intervening now in your behavior,
like you need to think about this.
And like, I, I literally, I hate to invoke this but like, you know, I
to become a scouting candidate, you have to take a bunch of training
and like the training explicitly covers dealing with people like this
because it's seen as such a threat and a problem, right?
And so I literally, and you know what the problem was,
this kid was,
he was basically accusing this person's kid of quote unquote cheating.
They were playing,
um it's whatever it's called grounders or something where you're supposed to,
one kid is supposed to keep their eyes closed while they
kind of try and find the other kids kind of thing.
And he was accused of cheating and opening
his eyes because he was like wearing sunglasses or
whatever and he couldn't see his eyes and he
wouldn't take his sunglasses off or whatever anyway.
So I spoke with this guy and he left in a huff because I was like,
I'm going to call the police in about a minute here.
Right? Because this is like, I feel physically unsafe and I'm 6 ft two
and you are literally behaving like a crazy person, you know.
And, um,
yeah,
it turns out the kid is wearing sunglasses because he just has an eye
condition and he can't be exposed to bright light without it hurting a lot.
You know,
more to the point too, if somebody else's kid is quote unquote cheating a bit. Like,
so what,
like that's part of life, that's part of learning about life. Like people,
I'm not saying it's good and you should cheat at games to be clear.
But at the same time,
let the kids learn how to handle it and only intervene if necessary. Right?
Like right now I'm at the stage with my kids.
They're nine years old and I'm like, I do as little as possible for them until
either they ask for help or they actually need help or a safety
because
how are they going to learn to do this?
And I see so many
other kids,
like literally, I have kids walk up to me at the playground and they're like,
can I play with him?
I'm like, I don't know, like who
is Kim? Like
I don't, I'm not I'm not the boss of Felix of Wolfgang. Like, I mean, I am but
you're, you're going to jail if they do something bad enough, right?
You know,
like, I, I don't know if Felix wants to play with you. Like
Kim. Yeah.
No, I, I
hear you back to the open source thing. I, I think,
for example, I mean, well,
I think part of the problem is people tend to really self
identify with the projects and especially the code they make because I,
and I think there is a bigger piece of artistry
to code than a lot of people want to admit,
right?
People become heavily emotionally invested in code they write.
And I actually have a parallel to this that
I, I will, I've been thinking about as well is
one of the things I've noticed in the security world especially is
we are notorious for viciously guarding our work of that's mine.
You can't do it. I'm working on that. Go away. No, you can't change that.
I'm working on it. That's my project.
And this is one of the things I have been working. I, I used to be like that.
Mind you, I know I was, we
were.
Yeah. And many of us still are.
And if you say you aren't,
you're just in denial
maybe. But this is part of the human condition, man.
I agree.
You know what I always think of actually when this happens is like when
I write a blog post or something and an editor gets at it.
I'm like, oh, my goodness.
I either feel angry because they took my voice away
or I'm embarrassed because I feel like I'm illiterate.
But
it's usually one of those two.
It's never like, oh, yes,
this is very reasonable commentary on the piece I just wrote,
I got over that because I wrote a monthly magazine column for Linux
journal. And like, yeah, the first few times I was like,
oh,
well, I know
I keep it to myself now. Right? I used to like lash out now. I'm good about it.
But, but here's my point, right is especially insecure.
We're, we're notorious for that, that ownership concept of
i it's mine. You can't touch it. Well, I would say unhealthy ownership. Yes. Yes.
Exactly. And I feel like this is, you see this in open source a lot where people are,
if you let it go,
it can grow into something so much bigger than you can imagine.
But if you, if you insist on maintaining control,
like the absolute best you're going to get
is something that barely lives. Well, I mean, back to, you know, I think
allowing the marketplace to speak is important
and consciously choosing to ignore what the market wants. Yeah, you can do that, but
then you're not going to be giving the market what they want, you're going, you know,
and in this case, you can actually be harming the market.
Right. There's
you refusing to accept patches and make the
software better actually has a real world cost potentially
in that.
Now,
these people have a lot of extra bugs and just general crappiness to
deal with that could easily be fixed in the case of Lo Dash.
These bugs allow for remote code execution in your No Js projects.
Like that's a big frigging deal. I mean,
RC,
that's what we talked about last week or two weeks ago.
I think it was with the Citrix remote code.
Like that's literally the worst possible problem you can have.
And is it technically low dash's fault?
Technically,
the project should have sanitized their inputs before they
did the perfectly reasonable thing with low dash.
But the reality is it's kind of like one of those things of saying,
oh,
you have to flip the don't explode switch before you flip
the turn on the light switch even worse than that.
If you have a library that accepts data and
potentially accepts dangerous data
and more to the point. If you can fix it in one spot at the library, why wouldn't you?
Yes, you should. Absolutely. And look defense in depth, right?
Multiple layers don't say, oh, you should only do that here.
No, like you should be sanitizing your inputs everywhere,
everywhere you can sanitize and sanitize them not in one place.
Well,
and you should also be assuming that the stuff that was supposed
to sanitize inputs didn't necessarily do it exactly in the real world.
That's kind of how that works. Sadly, that is exactly how it works.
Like all the time, every time, what always gets me is what these frameworks,
you can fix it.
A one spot for everybody for all time.
Why wouldn't you?
Right.
So I, I will, I will pick on one other thing and this is an interesting point as well.
If you look at the low dash uh like commit the activity graph in github,
there's a point where it, it dramatically falls.
And my assumption is the author either either had a job where they were working
on low dash as part of their job or they maybe got a new job.
You know what I mean? Like, there was some sort of probably life event
that has drastically altered the amount of time they can invest in this project.
And I mean, that's
I get it right. That, that's part of just life that happens to everybody.
I have many things that fall under that umbrella where I was doing certain things.
And I was like, like my blog is a great example. I used to write constantly and I just
due to a variety of events that have happened in life, I,
I write like a couple of times a year now instead of basically once a week.
And that's OK. Well, but here's a perfect example. He
when, when those things happen, the person can tell the community.
Well. Right. That's part of it. And I think
that is the thing I keep coming back to and kind of the,
the one message for anyone who hasn't turned this
podcast off and discussed up to this point yet.
Like the one thing I keep thinking of is
when you are part of making something with open source. And this is like
github
made this so easy, but it's not about you and it's not about your project.
It's about building up a community around what you're doing.
There's nothing wrong with being a community of one.
But if you have the ability to become a community of
multiple people,
it's so much more powerful. And like that is that is the point, right?
Like not to get all weird or anything.
But I mean,
the human condition is all about being part of a
community but being part of something bigger than yourself.
And like that is just open source. Well, to be blunt, nobody can survive on their own
unless they're like some crazy prepper who spent, you know,
years buying canned food so they could survive on their own.
Dude. You send me youtube videos like weekly
people that knew just that like,
right.
But I mean, the only reason they can survive on their own is because the the you know,
they had access to this massive everything to buy like a pallet of canned soup.
OK? That, that is fair and I will not disagree with you at all. And I think
that is, that's part of the story is if you are,
if you're developing software and github
and you're releasing it as open source,
you are standing on the shoulders of giants and
like letting people stand next to you or even stand
on top of your shoulders is extremely powerful and very
rewarding or kick you out of the way and take over it if they want to do a better job.
No. Really? Like because that does happen. Like, I,
well, for example,
I remember this one poor guy who started contributing to a major
library by doing documentation and then like six months later they're like,
yeah, cool.
I don't want to handle this. Do you want it?
And the guy's like, sure because he didn't know any better,
you know. So he said yes.
And then this thing had a major security flaw and he was like,
panicking because it had like 10 million installs.
It was a Ruby jam
and I'm like, no, you're not going to get sued. You'll be fine. I remember this. Yeah.
And you know, the poor guy was just freaked out but like, and he,
but the difference being is, you know,
rather than getting all crazy and defensive or whatever,
he actually reached out for help and it was fine,
but a lot of people do not want to accept help or they,
or maybe they feel like accepting help is a sign of weakness
because they feel like they should be able to do it themselves.
And
again,
yeah, that can sort of work for a while. But, like, even Lini Torvald
started accepting patches pretty early on
and, I mean, it seems to have worked out for him and he's like,
the least agreeable person anyone knows.
So,
yes and no, I actually have met people who are more disagreeable.
Yeah, that's probably true.
And they're in charge of open source projects that are much less successful.
Weirdly enough.
No.
And you know who I'm
talking? I know exactly who you're talking about.
So, anyway.
Uh,
yeah.
Right. Right. I, I agree. I, I, so
this to me is fundamentally part of the real world example of, you know,
people,
there are definitely benefits to learning how to behave with
and around other people and learning to cooper,
which oddly enough I seem to remember a lot.
It's being covered in kindergarten.
It's nice to be nice.
And that would be my takeaway. That's right. It's not so much nice to be nice.
It's, you're going to get punched in the face a lot less if you're nice.
Yeah, that's probably true.
And I don't mean, like, physically punched in the face but, I mean, metaphorically,
either way, probably both are true.
Yeah. Well, yeah, actually now that I think about it, yeah.
So I guess my key takeaway here is,
you know, if you're in charge of an open source project,
make sure you're behaving at least as well as a kindergartner.
So you get that gold star. It's a pretty high borrower set in there.
Sadly. Yeah, it is. It, for some of these people. It is. No, it is. I agree. And
I will,
I will always be more than happy to admit that many years ago. I was a terrible person
and I have a great deal of regret for the way I once acted.
And I feel like shows like this
and topics like this
are part of my penance
to try to help make sure it is not a,
a problem that persists even though I suspect it will.
But if even one person listens and understands,
I consider that a success because none of us are as cool as we think we are
and that's
pretty much how it goes.
Well, one thing I, I try to use and I've been trying to teach my kids is, you know,
if you can learn from the mistakes of others, it's going to be far less painful than
learn from your mistakes.
I know so many people that make the same mistake over and over and over again.
It's like just
please learn like please.
But anyway, I
think it's just part of the human condition. Yes. Yes, indeed.
We are squishy annoying. Begged me.
So. All right man. I'm calling it. Thank you. Thank you, Kurt.
This was this was a lovely conversation and it, of course,
I had no idea where we'd end up.
I think this is a very nice place and I,
hopefully we haven't angered anybody too greatly.
And as these things always go, if you are part of a project and you need help, like,
ask for it or just accept it when it comes, it's, it's,
it sounds,
it sounds easy but I know it can be hard but it's ok.
All right. So, thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up the show notes, you
pound Os S podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media
and Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.