Welcome to a special edition of the open source security podcast.
It's the news edition
coming to you live from the internet. It's myself, Kurt Siefried
-- and Josh Bresser
-- from the internet.
That's exciting.
No, this is fun.
Uh
We decided to do a special news podcast because
the last podcast we just did was kind of the, the open SSL show and there was honestly,
we probably could have talked about that for, for hours,
but we didn't wanna torture anyone.
So we decided it would make more sense to just
do two short shows instead of one incredibly long,
probably boring show.
So, Kurt, what's new man since, since yesterday? Right.
Uh New, since yesterday or new. More recently,
there's this one story I love to death and it is
the Canadian Mint.
Uh They make coins and commemorative gold coins and, you know,
all sorts of precious metals are smelted and minted into things
and one of their employees was caught stealing a whole
bunch of gold over a period of several years.
And, and here's my favorite part. Well, there's two favorite parts.
I have number one. My favorite part is
his
current defense from his lawyer is that
my client didn't do it because the mint hasn't reported anything stolen
because their inventory control is so weak. They,
they haven't complained yet.
I'm gonna guess that's not a valid defense.
Well, but it does raise a question of how do you prove he's like, if,
if you can't account for these missing gold,
they're like apparently these gold pucks that are
round and apparently small enough that they fit
in certain parts of the human body.
I'm not gonna ask for details of that. But so here's fundamentally, the question is
I assume
-- they caught him with items on his person. Right?
-- No,
no.
You know how they caught him,
how
that
his bank became a little bit concerned because he kept
depositing these huge checks from a gold sales place.
Like he would smuggle out a pack of gold, take it to the mall, sell it to a jeweler,
get it, uh, like get a check for it, like
a, a
cashier's check or whatever,
then he would take it to his bank account at a bank at the same mall
and deposit it. And these checks were like several $1000
and this was happening, you know, repeatedly over a period of a few years.
And the bank teller actually got a
little suspicious and concerned because she's like,
well,
hm,
he's depositing these big checks from the jewelry store
and I know he works for the mint.
Maybe I should tell our security officer.
So the,
the bank security officer got involved and of course they looked at this and went,
yeah, that, that looks really kind of weird.
So they told the mint and then the mint suspended him.
But as of yet, there's been no, uh
well, they haven't publicly stated how much was stolen or anything.
Now,
I will say this comes back to the human
angle of people often are good at seeing problems
that don't quite make sense
and, and this always comes up in news stories. But
man, this is, this is wild.
Well, it's also, it's one of those things to me where, you know, in hindsight,
connecting the dots, it's really obvious, right guy works at the gold mint.
Guy deposits big checks from a jewelry store on a regular basis.
You know, guy lives above his means.
But what really blows me is you think, I mean,
in general
banks and mining companies, people that deal with precious metals
are good at not getting robbed because we've, you know,
they've been being robbed for several 1000 years.
Yeah, I mean,
I would expect the mint to have some sort of inventory of what's going on.
And I will say that if they cannot show
that they're missing inventory,
they probably have multiple huge problems just like this. And this guy is
without a doubt.
Well, I shouldn't say without a doubt but it,
it's probably one of their smaller problems if I had to guess.
Well, and, but inventory can be very difficult, especially with, you know,
physical process because um I know firsthand account, um,
-- grocery
-- stores can do inventory
but they
don't have
those things have barcodes and gold doesn't have barcodes.
A perfect example of this is uh one of the local, well,
not local to me but local and Canada uranium producers
did a massive inventory after 911.
Right, because there was a whole bunch of panics about,
you know, these kind of things
and they came up several 100 kg short
and
uh well, of, of yellow cake powder uranium, right?
So stuff that had been started to be processed and wasn't fully processed.
Yeah. And, and of course, you know, oh my God, that's not good.
Well, it turns out it was the,
it was the exact same problem that remember in breaking bad,
right. There's just crud and junk collecting in the tanks at the bottom,
right.
So they started to basically open up these tanks and poke around the bottom of
them and they found all this built up crud and gunk and they're like,
oh, ok, there it is.
But the cost of cleaning it out, you know,
it's just such a nightmare to clean this stuff out there.
Just like, yeah, whatever
man,
that's close
enough
and that's industrial process for you.
Yeah. But when you're dealing with
valuable items,
whatever the definition of valuable is,
I think you,
if you're not paying attention to that degree. I, I feel like that's a failure.
Well, but if you're making money and you're, I mean, if, if the cost of the loss is,
is acceptable, then,
you know, grocery stores don't have perfect security people.
Like I know locally now, uh, there's a big thing with meat theft at grocery stores.
You know, people go in and steal meat and cheese because it's,
it's pretty expensive now too.
I mean, that's fair. That's fair. It's
so like Costco, for example, actually has an employee standing at the meat counter,
like just standing at the meat counter. I'm like,
just staring at all of us, you know.
Oh, my goodness. This,
I don't even know what to think of it. I mean, so on one side, I feel like
there's reasonable doubt.
Ok.
And, and obviously in, in any free society, you need that holy, guilty,
beyond a reasonable doubt.
But at the same time, if you work for the mint
and
you are consistently going to a gold,
um, purchasing company, I don't even know what they're called, you know,
gold dealer maybe.
And you're selling gold
regularly
and you can't explain to the investigators where did all this gold come from?
I keep selling,
I think there
that I, I, if I was on a jury, I would say that is a, a
reasonable doubt or rather isn't a reasonable doubt.
Like this person is almost certainly stealing from work.
It'd be like, if,
if, imagine if I was suddenly, you know, selling laptops
and,
and people are, like, where are these coming from?
And I just, whatever I'm finding them, you know? No, no, certainly not.
You're, you're probably stealing them from work and
you're bringing them somewhere and selling them. I mean, come on.
-- Nobody would even think twice about that.
-- Right.
Well, see, to me, I, I would say two arguments.
Number one,
if they can't actually prove beyond a reasonable doubt that he's guilty, then they,
they, they have failed. I mean, both the mint and
the police.
And secondly, I would say, you know, it's people will bring up, you know,
these slippery slope arguments.
Well, what if he has like a secret gold mine that he does want to disclose?
You know, what if
he has
a secret
stash
of Nazi?
No way,
no way, man.
Because if he has a secret gold mine or his secret Nazi gold stash or whatever,
like the goose that poops eggs,
you just, you show it to them. You say I have this, let me show you.
So I don't have to go to jail,
right?
You don't say, oh I have, you know, a magic death ray that,
that turns people into gold.
That no, that's not a defense. I mean,
you could make insane defenses against literally everything.
Then where it's like no, I
have
a transporter
-- and it transported the goods to my house. I didn't steal them. You know,
-- it's like,
no,
you know, that would be the job of the prosecution to disprove that.
You know, like I said, in my mind, as much like this case,
I hate to say, you know,
I,
to me innocent until proven guilty is a very important concept.
And in this case, you know, there's a big part of me that's like, yeah.
No, he's not innocent. Like he is definitely guilty. Like, come on
at
the same time, I wanna, you know,
I don't want to lose that, that cornerstone of our justice system.
We're in such a rattle.
Let's do this.
Human beings
are the most effective
security mechanism we have today in many organizations.
Let's just leave it at that. Ok.
Well, and I think a big thing would be teaching people if you see something weird,
please mention it. You know, we get that all the time like with uh with sec
alert dot Red Hat, the product security team, right?
Where people will literally, I'll be on the phone with them and they'll be like, oh,
by the way,
our QE guy noticed this weird little thing and I'm like, oh my God
loosely sink ships, man.
Yeah.
And so, you know, it's, it's people spot things and please, you know,
mention it to somebody because
yeah,
it might be nothing and I would much rather deal with something that
turns out to be nothing than to have those things that are a problem
-- just quietly lurking.
-- It is true. It is true.
All right, let's, let's keep going. I, I love the next story about
plugging in USB sticks.
Yeah. Yeah. I, ah, jeez, I mean,
the, the whole USB thing, you know what, it really reminds me of his email,
remember 20 years ago where we were, like,
you know, a virus by email.
Well, don't open that dot exe and run it, you know, of course,
you can't get a virus from just receiving an email,
you know,
and of course now,
and, and it used to be true now it's really not true anymore. Um
And I feel like USB is the same way like it used to be like, yeah,
you can plug like random USB junk in your computer.
What could possibly go wrong? And now we have,
you know,
we have those guys who made those usb kill sticks
with capacitors that like taser your system to death.
Um And it even happens unintentionally.
Do you remember that guy, the Google guy that was testing all those USB C cables,
-- right?
-- And one of them like fried his laptop.
Yes.
II, I think about that all the time when I buy a new cable and I'm like, man,
I hope this doesn't ruin anything.
This is why I use an external USB hub,
right? Like, because I don't wanna fry the,
I don't wanna fry the USB ports on my computer.
So, ok, so we've definitely got the super malicious, like,
you know, taser USB key thing.
So, you know, and, and how do you test that right short of plugging it into something.
-- Um, then we've also got the USB keys.
-- You don't test that, you don't plug in
USB crap you find in the ground. I mean, there's been the,
all those,
uh, uh, studies done where people, like,
dropped a bunch of USB drives in a parking lot and something like 70% of
them got plugged in because they had malware on them that phone home essentially.
I mean, that's crazy.
Yeah. No, it's um
but I mean, we've been taught that it's safe to do this, you know,
because up until recently it has been safe to
USB.
I
think
it's human nature, it's
kind
of,
and, and additionally,
if you want me to do something, tell me not to.
So there's kind of that part of it too.
Yeah.
And then what's really interesting to me is those guys that manage to stuff a,
you know, a human interface device like a keyboard into a USB drive.
So that when you plug the USB drive into your machine,
it sends keyboard commands to your machine.
So like on a Windows machine, it would send, I think, what is it like a
command C or a Windows key C for the to open up a command prompt
and then it would like type in a bunch of shell commands like add a user,
make them privileged,
you know, and then like phone home to tell, you know,
the attacker that this computer now has,
-- you know, been compromised.
-- So here's the real question is, could you write
a
string of keyboard commands
that could work universally on Windows? Linux
and Mac Os
trick question, you don't have to,
right? Because you just, you just cycle through them.
Yeah.
But as a, a person sitting at the keyboard,
I might notice if it takes 10 seconds to cycle through.
Whereas if there's one string
and I mean, this,
this is obviously purely academic because no one's really gonna do it.
But, and let's face it too.
The vast majority of users are on windows,
right? If, if you're gonna target a platform, you're gonna target windows.
You know, I'm wondering if the USB key could be smart enough to recognize the USB.
Do the USB host hubs, don't they have like an identifier that they send?
Because I know USB devices that I plug in all have an identifier.
Ah, that's a good question. I have no idea
because in that case, you could just use that string to, you know, oh,
I'm talking to a Mac.
Send this, oh, I'm talking to a Well,
Adele send this.
It's interesting. All right. So, uh all you USB security researchers out there,
let us know how this works and, and uh send some demos to Kurt.
He'd love to test them out.
Yeah.
Yeah, I'll have to get a sacrificial laptop.
Right. Right
now, I will say though, there, there is one cool thing that's,
that's happening right now is, you know, you've got a note here about, you know,
glue the, the pork shop, which is still the best option without a doubt,
but there's something being worked on in Fedora right now called USB Guard.
And it lets you define policy for what you want to plug in.
And so, for example,
you could say that uh user Curt can't plug in USB
flash drives and user Josh isn't allowed to plug in keyboards,
which is, yeah, it's kind of cool actually.
And so, and not only that if you run the Applet, which I,
I have running because I've been, I've been doing,
I'm putting a presentation together that, that involves this is
when I plug in a USB device, it pops up a little window that says, you know, hey,
you're plugging in, you know, a joystick.
Is it a allow? And I remember type questions?
And so I can basically make it not work, which is kind of cool, but that of course,
doesn't solve the problem of
like literally malicious sticks that cook things, right?
Because if you have the, the fry, the computer stick in USB
is not gonna save the day there.
Yeah, I've kind of wondered about that because I mean,
it would be a great way for a computer store to generate business
moving on.
-- Please don't blame me if you do that,
-- please don't do that.
Yeah.
All right, man. What's next?
Well, I think the, uh, the terra bit denial of service from security cameras.
Oh, man.
-- The world's largest analog service attack. Thanks to security cameras.
-- That
man, it's,
well, security cameras are the start. Right.
It's,
it's going to continue to get worse just because there's so
much iot crap out there and a lot of it is Punt
or will be because it's never gonna see updates
and,
and this denial and, oh, man, I just, I don't even know to
even more.
It's not that it doesn't see,
it doesn't even see management or maintenance. Like,
uh, a friend of mine lives in a condo and they just had their, uh, a GM and
it turns out they spent 60 grand on their, uh,
their camera security system like 10 years ago
and now it's a potato.
Yeah, basically.
Like they, they actually had to post of, uh, uh,
an image of some guy who was stealing mail and it was potato quality.
Like, it was seriously,
quite, quite hysterically terrible.
Uh, but the point is this,
this system has been there for 10 years
and it is not like they have like an on site it, or, you know,
they're not like here's what's interesting to me.
-- Is,
-- is it hooked up to the internet?
Probably so you can check it remotely. Right.
Because how else are you going to check this?
And, but here's the thing that's interesting to me is there's, there's,
as far as I know, there's no legal requirement anywhere
in North America for security systems to have like, maintenance contracts.
Like, say, unlike things, like, say elevators or escalators where you, like,
in most jurisdictions legally have to have somebody maintaining it.
So it doesn't, like, kill anybody.
But as far as I know for security systems, there's no,
you know, people get home security systems all the time with monitoring but not
-- like a maintenance contract.
-- Yeah.
But your, your home security system isn't going to kill you when it stops working.
Well, if it doesn't, you know, sound the fire alarm, it might,
it has like a, a gun at the, at the door. Right.
But, uh, so, yeah, I mean,
the rea, I, I think, you know, these are, it always goes back to that lowest.
The problem I think is, so this denial of service went after Ryan Krebs's website.
And Krebs is a
security reporter who has
often
had the ire of the underbelly of security on his case.
And this guy, if you, if you look through his history, there are a number of
insane things that have happened to him
in the past,
right? And
he's a good guy.
So no one's gonna deny that.
But the bad guys don't like him because
he keeps showing people what they're doing and,
and that's I think historically speaking,
that is a common occurrence, right?
And so obviously some group of bad people decided to denial of services website,
which I still maintain
is a rather silly way to burn your botnet.
-- But I don't think it's burned
-- though.
That's the sad thing.
And we should actually have him on the show to interview.
But I know a guy,
Zachary Wilson who specializes or used to specialize in iot security stuff
and he would be sending out emails, you know,
because he worked for a large provider sending out emails
to these people that were denial of servicing them saying,
you know,
please like every single one of your uh hotels
in your hotel chain is like attacking our site.
Please, you know,
you have this device on your thing. I can tell from the signature. Please go fix it
and, or you know, hospitals or you know, universities and
you know, and the response rate is man, it's not 100% that's for sure.
Is it 10 percent?
Yeah. You know, so I mean, when you say burn up, I think
that's what really worries me about these new botnets is
you can use them.
And I mean, here's the thing, Josh, if somebody phones your grandmother
somehow gets a hold of her phone number and says to her, look, I have proof that you,
you have a bunch of IOT devices in your house that are attacking my network.
I need it to stop,
dude, my grandma,
like she had an old rotary phone.
Yeah. So she's actually safe.
But I mean, or even, you know, even a 20 year old,
you, you try and convince, you know, I mean,
ok, so that's fair if, if say
my neighbor
who is moderately technical
got a phone call from a random person saying, you know,
your it devices are attacking me.
He would say,
I don't know what any of the words you just said are
right and that that would be the normal response for most people.
And so that part is fair, but I can see the the problem here is so I would imagine
that
all of the activity directed towards Krebs has been locked.
And so now there is a large collection of IP addresses
and I think
the future
is going to be,
there are going to be known bad IP addresses and there are going to be blacklists.
And so as soon as your device makes it on a list like that, it,
that data is going to fall apart and be dropped.
Now,
one of the issues you're gonna have is things like the big routers on the internet
already struggle with memory pressure.
And so trying to add a big blacklist would be a challenge. But I think,
I think it is inevitable
that some sort of infrastructure ends up in place
that gives us the ability to essentially black hole
individual IP addresses because of stuff like this because this
is going to become a bigger and bigger problem.
I think.
I, I agree in theory, but my concern is that to properly, you know,
to properly block these attacks, you have to get as close to the source as possible.
Right. That's, that's where the blocking works best.
And the problem there is two fold. Number one, that's a lot of money,
you know, for these providers to spend on ids or IP S or whatever machines.
And number two,
it begins, you know, the, at least in the US and Canada,
they've always trumpeted their, their common carrier status.
You know, we just carry the traffic. We don't know what's in it.
We don't care, it's, you know what I mean? Unless it's music.
Yeah, or, you know, streaming video or
youtube or
any of those other sites that we're competing with.
And so
I think fundamentally, uh you know, unless there's some legislation that
the problem is the people, they're gonna end up eating the cost like Krebs,
you know, the industry,
like the ISP industry has historically shown that
they're ok with passing costs to random people.
I mean,
look at their attempts to claw back like this whole thing
with uh charging youtube to send traffic over their networks,
right?
And I was trying to explain to people they're like, oh,
it's not fair that youtube gets to send traffic for free over, you know,
my IP network and I'm like,
well,
that's not how that works because that,
that traffic was already paid for and they're like, well, who paid for it?
And I'm like, well, you did, you know,
you paid for the bandwidth that you then used and requested this service
and you're like, oh, right. Oh, yeah,
I'm like, because it's not like youtube just randomly streams video to people
didn't ask for it.
This
connection is brought to you by Pepsi Cola.
Exactly. So, I think the unfortunate part is, uh,
as well, even if we had legislation and even if we had good blocking devices,
the rate of IOT is going to vastly
it's gonna grow faster than we can handle it.
Especially when you start thinking about things like, like driverless cars
and all the stuff on wireless networks that's physically gonna be moving around,
you know?
It's,
yeah, I mean, how do you do IP tracking when the IP S keep changing?
The bigger problem there will be with I PV six
is
you could potentially have a one terabyte blacklist
and that's not something that's going to be reasonable.
Yeah.
Yeah. Even if you do networks and not just individual IP S at the I PV six level.
That's,
yeah, it's just too much.
We're all doomed
and that is all
which I guess actually that brings us to, this is a good segue to the next story,
which is
something from Schneier
about the cost
of security
and the fact is that it sounds like
cyber attacks don't cost as much as a lot of people think.
And
I think one of the great challenges we have with security is justifying
what we spend
versus how effective it is. And today we kind of suck at that.
And this is one of the, the things where that it's, I think it's going to be solved,
but let's face it. You look at
virtually everyone out there
and their security isn't very good,
but like their business is still functioning for the most part, things are going ok?
And so, and, and ransomware falls into this,
it is generally cheaper to just pay the ransomware than
it is to actually have a proper security infrastructure.
I mean,
it as a security person, as much as it pains me to say this, that's kind of a no brainer.
And if the bad guys are smart,
they're going to make sure that whatever it costs to
deal with what they're doing is less than doing security,
right?
And if they keep that in mind and I think they
are because these guys are like they're running a business now.
I suspect they're gonna keep this in mind
and it is going to mean that security will always be starved for funding,
which by definition means that the bad guys will always be ahead in this game.
Yeah, my concern there is, you know, you enter into that dimension where,
ok, economically. Yeah.
Maybe it's cheaper to deal with $10 million a year in fraud
than it is to spend $100 million a year preventing it.
But
then you potentially end up like,
so a great example is kidnapping in the US and Canada, right?
It just doesn't happen very often
because the police and especially the FBI made it
impossible. Right? They will track you down to the ends of the earth.
Even if it's not economically viable,
they will do it because kidnapping is not a problem in the US and Canada right now.
And you look at other countries like some
South American countries or some Eastern European countries,
right?
And, you know, it's an endemic problem, right?
And that's kind of my concern is that I don't
want the internet to be this place where it's like,
oh, you got kidnapped?
Yeah. Ok. Fine. We'll push lunch back to 2 p.m.
-- You know,
-- your, your analogy breaks down
because
imagine if someone from Russia could kidnap you without going to Canada first.
And that's the internet.
Yeah. Oh,
totally.
And I mean, and until we get, you know, International Cooper,
that will always be the case.
You know, and, and the reality is we never will have true International Cooper,
-- right? Because all these countries hate each other.
-- Are you familiar with the UN?
Yeah, exactly.
So
then, and, and so I, you know, the realist,
the realist in me has to acknowledge that and
say, Well, you know, reality often isn't how we want it to be. So, and
it is the way it is. So, you know, how do we productively deal with the way it is? And,
and quite honestly, like you said, I mean,
yeah,
paying the ransomware guys might be the best way to
deal with reality being the way that it is currently.
You know, you know what the, the true stink in me always comes back to is
I, I,
are we going to reach the point
where
the ransomware
we'll say company
has
when you pay the ransomware,
they also guarantee one of their competing ransom wares won't be able to get in
and infect your system because you're now paying them the protection money
to
the
recurring revenue streams. I mean,
how
do you think that, that,
that may be a reasonable conclusion to this whole crazy universe of ransomware?
Do you know what it sounds like you've
just described to some degree as the antivirus?
I know, I mean,
quite frankly what you know, like,
yeah.
Yeah, I just,
uh, I, I pity, I pity normal internet users.
And quite frankly, I think this is one of the reasons I'm at the point where,
you know, when people ask me what computer should I buy and I'm like a smartphone.
Well, although like chromebooks are pretty solid. These
trees, my,
my son just got one at school and I'm impressed by how usable the thing really is.
Yeah,
I think that's a lot of the future because the reality too is these,
these devices are actually quite powerful now.
Right. Like,
I mean, it's true,
you know, I, I'm doing web surfing on my phone.
I can ssh from it, I can run, you know, games that have slight 3d capabilities.
I mean, it's,
you know, this thing has like, 32 gigs of storage, I think.
I don't even know or care anymore.
Like, just don't get the 16 gig one is the only rule I have,
you know, never buy the 16 gig.
Yeah, exactly.
How much free space do you have on your phone? Who cares?
Yeah.
I
mean, my favorite of this is, uh, I got someone, um, a Cobo
Ereader
and it's got like two gigs of built in storage and an SD card slot.
And I'm like, why, why do I need an SD card slot?
Like two gigs of text books is
-- more than I'll ever read in a lifetime. But
-- people love that stuff.
People like their SD slots. All right. I have, uh, 15 gigs free
on my 32 gig phone.
So, yeah, I have, I have no idea.
Whatever
it works. Don't
care.
Yeah. So, no, I think I,
and, you know,
because there was also an FBI report I read a long time
ago talking about how we'll probably never have a crime free society because
even if you can make crime,
not pay which, in many cases, you know, for a lot of crime, it really, like,
like that whole thing with drug dealers that earn less than minimum wage, you know,
they'd be better off going to mcdonald's.
Um,
but there's just that certain
elements and groups and people in society that will think it's,
it's a better way to make a living by, say,
shoplifting and selling meat on the corner.
Uh, you know, or, you know,
those guys that sell speakers out of the back of a van because like,
honestly how much money can those guys make?
Like
it can't be a lot.
And so you know that,
but these people will continue doing that and we just
have to live with it and minimize it where possible.
Yeah, that's, I mean, heck man, even in Star Trek,
there are villains,
right? People committing crimes.
It's
although, although
I wonder if we had
kind of the post
scarcity economy where you had something like maybe a universal basic income or,
you know, easy access to goods, what that will do to crime?
I think it would definitely help because, you know, a lot of crime is,
it's not people being evil, it's people being desperate and needing money,
you know, for their,
for their drug habit or their alcohol or, but the challenge is there's, there's,
again, there's people, for example, people with a gambling problem,
right? You can give these people a billion dollars
and they'd burn through it,
I mean, well, like a classic example, like, look at all these lottery winners,
right?
These people win the lottery and they just wreck their lives, you know,
something like 80%
end up going bankrupt or something stupid. Like, it's just horrifying.
Well, I mean, I guess
now on that note though, like,
if you're the kind of person who plays the lottery in the first place,
you probably don't
have the ability to make good decisions on a regular basis.
I mean, let's just face that. Right.
Well, you're not,
you're not definitely not making good statistical decisions
and probably not good long term decisions.
And yeah, and I mean,
these things matter when you have like a million or a billion dollars to deal with.
And,
and so I think the reality is with a post scarcity economy.
It would have to also be combined with things like mental health care.
Uh you know, some sort of new drug policy, new new crime policies.
Um because, and then the thing is to remember too, there's also crime, you know,
there's crimes of passion, there's crimes of, you know, having power over people
and no amount of money or goods will, will solve that.
Yeah, I mean, that's fair. That's fair.
So
in summary,
we have no idea.
Yeah,
that is all.
Yeah, I, I think the biggest thing, you know, honestly,
the biggest reason I wanna see basic income
is an end of bureaucracy,
whatever man,
you know, they're gonna find a way to make it crazy.
Hopefully not. But, uh,
yeah, I mean,
because when you think about what poor people have to go through to get the,
the help and the assistance that they need,
you know, like, think about computer users, right? The same thing, right?
Like somebody, my laptop's slow,
right? Oh, ok. I need to go.
Yeah.
You know, I need to, you need to malware bites it.
You need to antivirus it, you need to a
block it. You need to.
Yeah.
Yeah. So,
you know, and, and quite often the new laptop is actually
cheaper now than like two or three hours of a technician's time.
-- Seriously,
-- man,
especially if you're using something like a chromebook
which ironically will probably have far fewer problems.
But,
yeah, I mean, chromebooks are what, like, 2 5300 bucks usually and
paying a dude to look at your computer is probably 100 bucks an hour at least.
Yeah.
I've, uh, the last time I actually had to get a computer fixed, I looked online and,
yeah, and I think it was 100 and $50
was sort of the, the cheapest,
like,
like
there were places that were cheaper but they were pretty dodgy looking, you know,
like, it was like a guy
with
Drake
and computer repair.
Yeah. Well, or, you know, probably a student or something. Right.
Trying to make some money on KGG. That's the Canadian version of Craigslist.
So, just to clear that up
because nobody outside can,
yeah, nobody outside. Yeah, Craigslist, like, just cratered out in Canada.
So,
Gigi even mean,
what does
Amazon mean?
What is,
-- well, ok. Craigslist is actually crazy. How do I,
-- how do I spell
this? I
want to look this up.
Uh, hang on a sec. I don't know.
Uh, I just,
I just, I start typing,
start typing KJKJ, I into Google
and it'll figure it out. I'm sure.
Oh, K
looks like Kijij. I
pres in Canada.
Yeah,
it looks
a
lot like Craigslist.
It's
basically
the exact same thing.
I'm not sure. That's a good question.
I wouldn't be surprised if they do.
Uh, is there an, about,
about
Kaji?
Pronounced
kgggggg?
Oh, it means Village in Swahili.
And,
yes,
reading websites on a podcast is by far one
of the more interesting things you could do,
but
55% of Canadians use
GGG on a monthly basis.
Wow,
it's
a
lot, it's a fully owned subsidiary of ebay.
-- Ah, I see. So
-- that
makes sense.
Making sure Craigslist stays out.
Yeah.
But, uh, yeah, it's weird to me these regional variations. Like
all, no, we're not going down this rat hole. I'm gonna stop us now.
I
don't want to know we're gonna end up if we, if we start talking about this. But,
all right, man.
What else are we gonna talk about? A few other stories here?
Uh, let's see. I think there was, well, there was someone, it's not.
Oh, here's another good one. The world of vnc.net.
Uh this is very iot related.
Yeah.
So I don't know if um well, let's back up a, a step first.
Uh I don't know if our, our listeners have heard about Show Dan Shodan.
Uh but show Dan is basically a search engine
that goes looking for stuff on the internet and by stuff, I mean,
like servers and cameras and you know, network attached storage devices
and it offers a really nice search interface and that you can basically go like,
I want to see all of like this model of network
camera from some company because I know it has a flaw
and world of VNC is an even more specific one where basically they, I mean,
because the reality now is you can scan the entire I PV four space of the internet in,
you know, several tens of minutes off of a fast connection, right?
So scanning for, what is it? I think port 5900 by default for VNC.
And so it's BNC is
uh
stands for virtual network computer and it's
basically like remote desktop for computers.
And
so
when
that came
out,
uh I remember when it was like,
yeah,
some AT&T lab in the UK came up with it and gave it away for free or something.
I don't know so long ago.
And yeah, so anyway,
so these guys basically trolled the entire internet for VNC servers and then,
you know, made a search engine for them
and like these,
I mean, some are, you know, ok, it's like a,
it's like a restaurant point of sale system or it's, you know,
but some of them are like, mildly terrifying, you know,
like building control systems and,
you know,
just all sorts of random stuff and what I love is they have these screenshots,
you know, and you can, it's just so
it's like those, uh, search engines for people's cameras in their homes, you know,
and you can just watch people sleeping.
So
you bring that up and I,
I'm browsing these screenshots and I just hit one that is clearly
someone's like home entertainment system and it shows a picture of their car
which I assume is a security camera pointed at their car outside.
Awesome.
Yeah. So,
yeah, because there was a recent thing in the paper actually where some lady was on,
decided to look for one of these, um,
for some reason was looking at one of those, you know, uh,
camera search engine things
and, uh, found, uh, like a bedroom with some furniture she recognized as being like,
you know, from, um, like a local brand or something
and then, you know, posted it to Facebook and it turns out, you know,
somebody's baby monitor or whatever.
Um, you know, just,
but, uh,
not like I know a friend of ours they just had
a baby and she posted a picture of herself at Starbucks
with what looks like a little tablet.
And it's a, it's a specific, like it's a tablet specific to her
baby camera
so she can carry this little tablet device
around and watch her baby sleeping at home.
Well, obviously this thing is talking to me and I'm sure that is.
I, you know. Yeah.
And I, I, how do you even begin to explain to somebody, you know, that like,
-- well, so
-- it's even more than that.
I was at a security conference this summer and of course, they've got, you know,
like the wall of sheep where they're,
they're sniffing all the internet traffic and all that kind of stuff
and somebody connected to their home
security system and was streaming video and so you could see
the video what's happening in their house on the screen.
It's like this is a freaking security conference.
Like what the hell's wrong with you people?
Like, if there's no hope of security guys, everyone else is doomed. End of story.
Yeah.
I, I sometimes wonder, you know, like people are frustrated that for example, both,
you know,
Apple and Windows are sort of taking away a bit
of choice and a bit of control from consumers.
And
for example, Windows is apparently now going to be forcing updates on people.
And part of me is like, you know,
I have no problem with that.
Yeah, I'm not so sure. That's a bad thing.
I mean, it, it kind of sucks if you have software that fails. But, um,
no, however, I would imagine if you're an enterprise customer,
-- you have the ability to disable that
-- functional.
You do as an enterprise customer.
But think about all those, the people who, for example,
bought like AC NC milling machine with a windows machine attached to it.
Uh, you know.
Yeah, I mean,
if it's on the internet though, which it obviously is,
if it's receiving automatic updates,
you need to update that stuff.
Right? And, and especially
in the case of like a piece of actual physical gear,
somebody could get hurt or die if there is a malicious insider in the device.
So I totally am ok with that.
Of course,
I'm sure it's running some software that's never going to be updated and it,
it's beyond terrible as far as security goes, but it at
least windows will be ok.
Yeah.
And, and part of me thinks it's kind of like the whole vaccination argument,
you know, like,
unless you have in my mind some very specific medical reason not to vaccinate
you, you have to vaccinate
that, you know, that's just part of living in polite society.
You're gonna get so much hate mail. Now,
-- I agree with you. But mail curt everybody, not
-- me.
Yeah, I just found the weirdest thing on the VNC browser, by the way,
a Linux machine booting
the actual text part of it.
Ok.
No, I, I wonder if it could be,
or it could be something like when you connect to this port,
turn on the computer sort of thing. Right. Like, like a sort of port knocking magic
to
boot
the
boot screen. It's not completed booting.
Right. Right. No, no, I'm saying. Oh,
but I seen one here that says booting from hard disk, boot field. Not a boo,
I
keep clicking through. This is like fascinating. Um I
know
it but, but
if I had to guess
and this is something I think about a lot actually is
what, what if you set up a system? So when you connect to it, it turns on
and,
and I especially want this for Minecraft servers because
my kids have a bunch of Minecraft servers and
I keep thinking what if I put them all
in a container or rather one container per server
and then set it up because you, you know,
I think this is possible with system D which is everyone's favorite in it system
but have system D
well, it does basically the same thing
but when you can, right, you connect to the port,
it spins up the container starts the Minecraft server and then
you play your, your, you know, do your thing.
And then obviously after there's a certain amount of no connections,
it just powers it down.
OK? So I have to say this because it's too perfect a marketing opportunity.
But Openshift Enterprise does exactly this.
Uh, yeah.
Ok.
-- That's cool.
-- But it might be overkill for your needs.
It is probably overkill for my needs.
And, like, I, I know certain things can do this kind of stuff,
but I'm also more just because I'm weird.
I want to do it myself. Right. I don't,
I don't want to let someone do it for me because my time is obviously worthless.
It's funny because to me, I, I've gone the opposite way.
Like,
I'm seriously considering getting my kids Xbox accounts so that they can play
Minecraft on Microsoft servers and I just don't have to deal with anything.
And part of me is just, like, feel so icky.
-- And then another part of me, it's just like, I
-- don't have to
do
that
though. I mean, it's, it's expensive enough that I am too cheap
to get it
if,
if I, I just, and the thing is too, like,
my kids will play Minecraft for a month like crazy.
And then they take two months off and they don't touch it again.
And so I'm not paying Microsoft
for nobody to be using their stuff. Right.
Yeah.
No, it's the whole, these,
these economics of security are tough because the other thing
and I don't know if you saw that email but,
uh, somebody was asking me about,
um,
sort of the science behind information security and I was like, we don't have any.
I mean, we don't even have a basic vocabulary, let alone
I think saying we have witch doctors would be optimistic at this point.
Oh, that would be such an improvement.
And you know, I I've done some writing on this in the past is
this is one of the challenges we have.
We have a number of experts in this field and, and you and I
are familiar with this is where did, how did we start?
We started with pain and suffering is everything we learned.
We essentially had to teach ourselves. There were very few people to talk to
that you could learn. I mean, there were a handful, right? Don't get me wrong. But
fundamentally,
we taught ourselves almost everything we know and
it is a lifetime's worth of knowledge.
And this isn't the sort of thing that like if a
new person wanted to start and they were saying in their,
their middle of their life or the middle of their career
and they said I want to be a security guy,
I'd be like,
like good luck. I, I don't know what to tell you.
There's just, there's not an easy way to do this stuff.
And when you're young and you have
in your limitless amount of time,
you can spend a week learning how buffer overflows work and
learning how to write shell code and all this stuff.
But like at this point in my life, if I have to learn a new skill.
There's not a lot of time to do it,
right. It is definitely a challenge.
But however,
now I will say that this is a huge problem security has I think is
we do not have a nice way to pass our knowledge to the next generation.
Well,
especially
termites do this
and we don't.
Well, what's frustrating to me is we have,
there's a huge number of certifications around, for example,
development and system administration and stuff that are actually pretty decent,
you know,
um, in the windows ecosystem in the red hat ecosystem
in the security ecosystem,
we have some sort of these sort of more generic if you will,
things like the Cissp, which don't get me wrong.
I actually am really glad I wrote the Cissp about a decade, decade and a half ago
because it gave me the sort of management view of security, right?
Because I mean, part of the problem is the technical side of security is so
it's changing constantly.
And, you know, for example,
what's available to an enterprise customer versus what's available to, you know,
a small business versus what's available to your,
your friend who has a laptop that they want to use to get work done.
You know, I, I don't, there's not one set of advice that, you know, fits for all,
apart from some very basic,
you know, things like, uh,
maybe don't send money to those guys in Nigeria that you know,
need some help out freeing up that, you know, shipment of gold or whatever.
Yes.
And
I mean,
so you made a point
and at the beginning of, of what you just explained that I think is important is
the knowledge we have isn't good for very long,
which makes it very difficult to teach
and it's very temporal
now at the same.
And I guess so here's,
here's where my thought process always goes is things like having an Rh
Ce or having an M CS E or whatever Microsoft calls it now
is that is very similar where every couple of years they need to update what's
going on and what you learned say five years ago isn't necessarily valid today.
Security kind of has its problem as well.
But I think one of our challenges is it's already
such a small group of people that have this knowledge
and most of them for one thing are, are just bad at talking to other people.
And I'm comfortable saying that,
but
who's going to build the information
that's going to teach the next group of people
and you need to constantly update that and constantly add to it.
And so that's kind of the challenge there. And
now
I'm not gonna say it's impossible because I think we need to figure this out,
but I do not know how we can do that in a reasonable way.
And of course, there's always people who talk about, oh well,
this university is doing this or there's this certification here,
there's this training program here.
And I'm not,
none of those are bad.
But if you look at the people who are truly leading this industry,
like that's not where they started.
And I think a lot of this stuff has been around long enough that if
it was truly effective at conveying knowledge and the way we need it done,
we would see more leaders
and more, I guess just impressive talent
that talk would talk about, hey, this is where I came from, but I,
I have not yet seen an instance of that and if someone can prove me wrong, please do.
I would love to know.
Well, you know, recently this reminds me of,
I started watching woodworking videos on youtube
and there are amazing woodwork like how to make
a dovetail joint like a 10 minute video where
not only do they talk about like how you do
it in the basics but like all those hidden gas,
like talking about how you can dry the wood out so that
you can then fit the wood together and then let it,
you know,
come back up to whatever level of humidity is
normal.
You know, all these little tricks and tips that, you know,
it's that extra five or 10% that really,
you know, that's what makes people an expert, right? And, and so, but this is like,
and we don't have anything like that.
Well, but now in defense of us, wood working has been around for, you know,
a couple of 1000 years.
So they have that going for them, right.
But I, I also think that it is,
it could be worth saying that there are
some fundamentals of woodworking that have always existed,
right? Like
you could take a guy from 200 years ago
who was a, a professional woodworker
and they understand certain rules about how it works
right now. If you handed him a table, saw he'd chop his arm off. Right. No,
no questions asked.
But there's still some fundamentals.
And you could take a woodworker from today,
a woodworker him 200 years ago and
they could probably have a meaningful discussion.
What is the thing in security that binds us all?
And I don't think we can easily answer that today, but that's,
that's what we need to find out and that's what you need to learn.
And then the rest, once you have that,
that foundational knowledge you can build on top of it.
But we don't even know what that is today because
I bet if I ask you what the foundational knowledge is
and then I call someone else up in 10 minutes and ask them,
I'm going to get two answers that are so different.
You wouldn't even guess it was the same industry.
I would even go one further to say that I've never actually
seen a good statement of what like when you wrote about it,
why do we do security?
Like literally,
is it, is it a cost control measure
to, you know, prevent,
you know, from people from taking off with everything or is it like
because we have a moral and an ethical duty, for example,
to protect people's personal information, which by the way,
I believe that we do have,
-- um, you know, is it because it's, is it
-- mo most organizations will disagree with you?
However, that's where compliance and regulation I think can make a big difference.
Yeah,
so I, you know that that's what gets me is if you ask people, what,
why are you securing this?
Like what, what is the framework for why you're securing this?
Like how you assign costs and benefits?
And I've never seen a good one.
And
yeah, in 20 plus years now,
I don't know, man, but I think this is one of the great challenges
we have to deal with.
Well, here's an idea.
If you want, you can write into us and tell us why do you do security?
You know, I, I would actually like to know from people why they do security.
That is
fantastic. In fact, we
going
to be,
I I didn't do it on the last episode, I just realized, but on the bottom,
if you go to the open source security podcast.com and you click on the episode link,
there will be a link at the bottom to send Kurt and I A
Twitter message and Twitter is by far the best way to contact us.
Finding our email addresses isn't difficult, but I already get too much email.
So the odds of me replying to you are probably very low. But Twitter is
my guilty pleasure when I need to waste time during the day.
So I will certainly look at that and get back to you.
Yeah.
All right, man.
I think we can wrap it up there.
That, that, that's enough talk about horrible,
crazy problems that nobody can solve.
I just wonder how many people are going to spend a couple of hours on world of VNC.
I, I, my day is ruined. Kurt. I,
I don't think I'll get anything else done today.
I
mean,
it, it was a pleasure as always. Thank you everyone for listening.
I really appreciate it. Until next time. Stay
shiny,
shiny.