Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast
with myself, Kurt Siefried and my partner and Thought Crime. Josh Bresser.
Today we're joined with Chris Wayland,
who's the co-chair of Restore the Fourth Minnesota.
Say hello, Chris.
-- Hey,
-- awesome. Thanks for being here, man.
Thanks for having me.
And also thank you for constantly opening up your podcast with
a reference to one of my favorite books of all time.
1994.
-- So, well, my first question is ok, what is the fourth, the
-- fourth amendment?
That's right. You're Canadian, aren't you? So that doesn't apply?
Oh, I, I know most of your amendments in government,
we should clarify before we kind of get moving too much.
About half of our audience is not in North America. Fascinating.
So we should make sure any, any references we have to, we'll say North
American political,
whatever we we we probably should make sure we clarify. That makes sense.
Yeah,
and I'm extremely proud of that fact as
well because I think it's awesome having an audience
-- in all kinds of awesome places.
-- Indeed.
And the it makes sense too because all of
our digital infrastructure makes it much easier to do
global activism type stuff with.
And uh so, yeah, for folks who aren't aware
of what the fourth amendment is.
The fourth amendment of the United States constitution
is what protects citizens from unreasonable search and seizure
without a
affidavit or from,
you know,
without there being particularity and specificity involved with
law enforcement wanting to perform the search.
It's what makes it so that
law enforcement can't just willy nilly decide to say
tap everybody's phones or just read everybody's emails.
Yeah.
And our whole organization sort of got off the ground
after the snowden revelations revealed that NSA was doing pretty much
that
-- one
-- stupid question because I was watching some cops the other day
and there was an agricultural inspection station episode which the summary is,
you better stop for them and let them look in your car.
Otherwise the cops are gonna
do it for you.
But what defines law enforcement in America? Because
one thing I've noticed is in a lot of countries
like law enforcement, police is very, very clearly defined.
Like in Canada, we have, you know, peace officers
and we don't have, for example, bounty hunters,
we don't have, you know,
like there's a whole bunch of stuff that's specific to America
where I feel like there's,
are they law enforcement or not like bounty hunters or you know,
us agricultural inspection
agency employees? Because apparently they can look through your car for fruit.
Like, and like if you don't like it. That's too bad.
There's also ice and customs and border and,
ok,
what's ice is immigrations and customs enforcement and they're just one of a myriad
of thousands of different bureaucratic entities in the
United States that do quote unquote law enforcement.
And
unfortunately, the judiciary, the judiciary has not kept pace with
the federal government's ability to utilize,
uh, technology and frankly ability to get subpoenas from,
get data from third parties like Amazon and private corporations
to sort of subvert the intent of the fourth amendment,
which was to protect us from sort of general warrants.
And there's a lot of interesting history there.
-- But,
-- well,
if there's one thing I've learned from reading the
US Constitution a bit and the history around it,
like, what's really fascinating to me is the order of the amendments, right?
Because the first amendment being the freedom of speech,
um, the second amendment, the right to keep and bear arms the third,
which is my favorite.
By the way, the,
you can't quarter soldiers in private
homes because everybody forgets that constantly.
And I, so I just love it because it's just, it's such an, like,
that must have been a problem if that's like the
-- thing they covered
-- it was, uh,
it's one of the things that caused the revolution in the first place was
the, you know, British soldiers needed lodging and just like, oh, well,
just lodge with the, with the colonists.
But the fourth, I find, well, I live in a country where, like,
we don't have 1/4 amendment.
I mean, we, we obviously, we have some protections but,
uh, you know, it's, it's complicated
and it's interesting to me that the US Constitution spells this out, like, very,
like, it's the fourth amendment.
It's, that's, and there's a specific reason behind that because
of what are called, um, writs of assistance
or these, or general warrants and what these are is
there's a lot of smuggling going on back
in the early days of the American revolution.
Um You know, Britain wanted to crack down on the smuggling.
So they gave these just general warrants to which enabled
inspections of basically anybody's house
and for not for even the slightest and oh, we're just gonna go door to door,
looking through people's houses.
And this sparked a great deal of resentment
because there was this long tradition of a man's home is supposed to be his castle.
There was
a long tradition in British common law around that notion.
And,
you know,
that's one of the things that cheesed off the
founding fathers so much that they wanted it.
They wanted to make sure that
that right was enumerated.
And in fact, a lot of the power,
a lot of the rights and protections in the bill of rights specifically tried to deal
with limiting the power of the federal government
when it comes to law enforcement stuff.
Um, you know, the Fifth amendment, things like that.
What is the Fifth Amendment self incrimination?
-- So, the right
-- to shut up.
Yeah.
Which means that you don't have to turn
over your passwords for your encrypted devices,
but they can touch your finger to your device
to unlock it.
That's not testimonial.
Which again,
I think harkens to your earlier comment about how the laws have
not kept up with technology in a lot of these instances.
Well, your, your comment was what the judiciary, right,
where that's the judges interpreting
the laws
and the constitution, I guess for that matter.
Yeah, I think that there is a pretty strong argument to make that the constitution
would and that the founding fathers would and what their
intent behind what the fourth amendment entails covers a lot of
what the federal government and what state
governments and what local police units are,
what they're doing with technology to sort of do.
I feel like the framers would be super cheesed off about that.
That's the judiciary. The judiciary could interpret the fourth amendment to cover
those technology uses like they did in
us V Carpenter,
which, um, was a supreme court case that I forget the name, the technical name of it,
but it's, uh, similar to ge offense warrants where they get data from cell towers,
cell tower dumps.
Um. Right. Right.
And they did that without a warrant and they said no,
you got to get a warrant for that data.
It's funny.
That you mentioned this because I literally just
yesterday were talking with our new password manager vendor
and they explicitly have a travel mode which locks you
out of like a whole pile of your password faults
until the like you basically call,
you literally call home and have the admin re enable it so that you
when you're at a border, right?
Because one of the challenges as I understand it is
most countries have laws that say at the border,
we have the right to search through your papers and your
goods, which
again, you know, back in the day when they made these laws, obviously,
we didn't have phones, which are like a literal extension of people's brains.
You know, it's like your, your super personal life is in there like everything.
And um
so literally, they have a travel mode where you enable that and, you know,
until I get a call from Bob that he's safe in Germany or whatever
he doesn't have, he just,
he cannot have access to that stuff like it's out of his hands.
-- Now,
-- that's a great example of
one of the,
one of the ways that people can sort of fight back
against the encroachment of the surveillance state and against this like ever
increasing encroachment into privacy is we can use technology to sort of
grab back some of our privacy and grab back some of our
data autonomy.
Um And that's great and that's fantastic,
but
you know, there's a reason why I spend,
why I'm part of the store of the Fourth Minnesota and why I'm,
I get involved with the eff and the AC lu
and all these other political activism works because I think that
the ability of an individual or even some institutions to sort of
claw back some of their privacy from
uh large Silicon Valley corporations are from the federal government.
That's a losing battle for people on an individual basis.
The only, the only real way,
the only real way that we're going to get back our privacy is if we
convince politicians that
we deserve it.
And here's a question I've heard us before but I want to get your take on it.
Why is privacy important?
That's,
yeah, there are all kinds of py
responses to that like Snowden says,
you know, people who say you don't need to be private are like, what's that Pli
-- Snowden response? Uh
-- If you have nothing to hide, you have nothing to fear.
-- Saying
-- if you have nothing to hide, you have nothing to fear is like
saying that you don't need freedom of speech because you have nothing to say,
everybody has something to hide.
Everybody has something to everybody has something to say.
And especially when you're dealing with
the number of federal laws on the books,
it is impossible to exist nowadays without accidentally breaking some kind of law.
Well, it's my understanding the actual,
the just the size of the US federal code is not known at this point.
Yep. Um, because I was trying to look something up and it, it basically came up.
It's not even that they don't know all the content of it.
They don't even have
the rough size estimate of it is gone at this point.
-- Like it's just gotten out of control.
-- Yeah.
And even if you somehow miraculously managed to avoid breaking,
not to avoid breaking all those laws, state and local federal.
It's amazing what kind of terrible story you can tell about an individual.
If you have access to all of their data,
like you can paint a terrible picture about people.
Well, and I mean, that's been, I think
something that the media has done for a long time is if they want you,
you can make a bad person look good and you can make a good person look bad, right?
I mean, that's been like the whole political smear industrial complex for, well,
hundreds of years.
Really? That's not new.
Yeah. And in fact, it's as old as carton
Richelieu.
OK. I want to reel this back a little bit
and kind of start from the beginning because as, as always,
we've gotten marvelously off topic, I think a little bit.
So we brought you here because you reached out saying, you know,
I'm part of this privacy organization and,
and I'd really like to come talk to you guys and you're, in fact,
connecting us with some other groups like the eff which I'm
super excited about as well and that'll be in the future.
So it's no secret that Kurt and I are,
we'll say huge proponents of this whole concept
of like digital privacy and digital rights and,
and all of that.
And so explain to me what the Fourth Amendment Minnesota group is,
is kind of what is its purpose and what is it doing?
And then we can kind of work our way into, you know,
what can we do as people and how can we help?
Yeah, that's a great,
yeah, that's good.
So restore the Fourth Minnesota is the Minnesota
chapter of the Restore the Fourth National Organization.
-- OK. So this is something that exists all over the United States.
-- Yes. And in fact, if
I think we have 13 chapters
in the United States, and I think there's
one in the UK too, although it might be defunct.
But the whole idea of it is that we are,
you know, after the Snowden revelations,
there was a whole bunch, there was a subreddit,
more formed and there were a whole bunch of protests and
the people who started those protests sort
of coalesced into these local chapters that
fight for reform on the local level and then also work together with
as like collectively nationally to advocate for change at the federal level.
And so,
for example, in the, in the Minnesota chapter, for example, we recently,
just earlier this year
passed a facial recognition moratorium in the city of Minneapolis.
Our legislature is actually still in, in special session,
but we were able to convince
the, the governor asked for a whole bunch of money
to fund fusion centers,
which are these sort of,
you mentioned them during the last podcast.
Actually,
there's like these places where there's a lot of joined
up surveillance information gets coalesced from federal and local.
They were just going to throw a couple million
bucks at our local fusion center and as an anti
surveillance organization, we're not big fans of fusion centers.
And so we were able to get that
additional funding removed by saying, look, if you're gonna have,
if you're gonna give them all this extra money,
you should at least put on some guide rails and
some barriers and some enforce some transparency or something.
And
then we all we do things like trying to get better drone policies
and we're trying to get a face recognition band in Saint Paul.
We're big fans of what's called C Cops,
which is like this ordinance or idea pushed by the eclu that would
say any time a municipality wants to or like a law enforcement,
local law enforcement agency wants to use a piece of surveillance technology.
They have to get a affirmative vote from the city council before they can buy it
and then have some regular reporting around how often they use it.
You'd be amazed how often
local police departments and sheriff departments
just buy secretive surveillance tech
and then no one knows about it until there's some horror story that gets published.
-- Oh,
-- we just had that happen in Canada with the RC MP.
Use of the uh the clear view, you know,
it's that company that scraped all the social media globally.
Yeah, I love Clearview and yeah,
and then they provide facial recognition to name matching.
They're so nakedly evil that it makes doing my job a lot easier.
I can just point at them and say, look how nakedly evil they are.
Well, yeah, our, our,
our chief privacy or the privacy officer had some rather harsh words for them.
It's, it's funny when you say something like they're so nakedly evil,
but one of the arguments you always get out of these groups, there's, oh,
it's safety.
Oh, and think of the Children and oh, we're stopping bad people and whatever.
There's a million. How do you,
how do you comment? Like, how do you bring a coherent argument to that?
Because I often feel like you've got one side just spouting
this string of nonsensical words that are meant to scare people,
right?
And you've got the people that are like, oh my goodness, you know,
they're the bad people are going to come and blow us up or whatever.
And then there's, there's people like you trying to stand in the middle and I guess,
be coherent.
How do you, how do you do that? That's a really hard problem.
It is. You are absolutely right. It is very hard. It's just a, oh, that's right.
I don't need, I hopefully don't need to explain what Oan
is, but it's, you do your research ahead of time and you figure out
and you figure out what your messaging strategy ahead of time.
You just need to target your message towards the
particular when you know your audience and you know,
the politician, you're lobbying.
If they're, if they're more conservative leaning, you talk about how data,
how like, no matter how much you trust your local law enforcement agency,
this data is going to get taken by the feds and,
you know,
there's no, you know, we don't trust the feds
and you shouldn't trust the feds
and conservatives are more receptive to that argument.
And if you're, if you're liberal that you make the argument that a
lot of times it's about the racial
disparities inherent in the use of this technology
and how this technology is often now how
surveillance is often targeted towards minority communities.
That's, that's usually how you get more.
That's how, that's the argument that we used to sway the Minneapolis City Council,
for example, we were able to point to their,
I'm blanking on what they called it.
But like they have this whole,
they have this whole framework for racial justice and all that stuff.
And so it's just a matter of knowing your audience.
So OK, so you're targeting politicians primarily.
-- That's,
-- that's the goal
-- I like that.
-- Yeah, because,
and this is something that I would heavily encourage your audience to do as well.
And that's kind of why I was so excited to get the opportunity to talk here because
I feel like in the
people who are technologists and who work in it
and in particular people who work in
uh for for reasons that don't just relate to privacy,
but that relate to all of the ransomware expletive that has been going on in
recent history has I feel like it is
vitally important that technologists get more involved with
politics and policy because
because
society and
the lines between society and technology are
are blurring to the point of nonexistence
and I don't
exist, they're gone.
The idea that we can somehow
as engineers and as technologists who are building
this new reality that we are not going
to engage in the political system that governs that has a say over how it gets
like there will be bad laws passed. If we do not get involved in this,
there are bad laws now,
there will be worse laws
is
-- perhaps a better way of putting that
-- now that you say this. It's one of the
Yes, of course,
but I didn't kind of realize it before and I feel like being a child
of the nineties and then we'll say coming to age in the early two thousands.
I feel like there was this
pervasive attitude amongst technologists of we don't need laws. We got this and
I guess looking at everything you're describing, I feel like
we are seeing the results of that attitude now.
Yeah,
I mean,
we still have it in the Cryptocurrency space where they're like we're going
to build a Cryptocurrency and it's not going to be beholden to laws.
It turns out
when you have an asset that is worth money
and you resign a jurisdiction that likes to tax stuff.
Yeah, it, you have to listen to your government
or like the alternative, which is anarchy, which is, you know,
some folks are into that.
But personally, I'm not,
we,
we've all read Lord of the Flies, right? Like that's just not gonna work.
One thing that I would highly encourage folks to do is
another great book called Click Here To Kill Everybody by Bruce Schneier
who's actually a resident of Minneapolis as well. Oh, nice. Yeah.
And he has,
he also has a great defcon speech about how important
it is for pe for technologists to get it or
public interest technologists.
It is hard to understate the power and this is true more broadly,
but in particular of people who are engineers and who are technologists,
your experts in this field. If you go and talk to your city council member about
whatever issue that whatever technology related issue that you're concerned
about whether even if it's things like broadband access,
if you go and you can,
anyone can pick up the phone and get a meeting with your local council member,
with your local, with your local legislator with your,
their job is to get re-elected.
They're not just going to ignore you out of hand.
That's been my experience anyway.
And especially if you can get a group of people together
and get a group of like just
11 interesting
idea that was floated past me was get a bunch of friends together and
say, all right, we're going to do a letter writing party
and we're, we're gonna, we're gonna drink
and we're just gonna get progressively drunker as the night goes on.
But at the end of the night, we have to send this open letter.
I haven't actually tried that, but it does sound like a lot of fun.
Maybe. I mean, uh
-- that could go horribly wrong,
-- could actually
like,
or even just
um one of the best things that in Minnesota, for example,
we put together this whole coalition in partnership with the Eclu
and the Jewish Community Action and Council on
American Islamic Relations and a whole bunch of local
activist orgs who deal with
not surveillance or privacy issues, but just like local but other issues.
But who are still concerned about this.
Get together with them and we put together a website
and you know,
throwing together a website is fairly easy for folks in our group. And
that can be very persuasive
putting
visualize, having data,
visualized in a simple way and just bringing it to your representative and saying
this is what this is important, you need to pay attention to this.
Um And then also plug for the eff there's they have this great
network of organization of like
uh called the E FA the Electronic Frontier Alliance.
And if you put together a group of people, I would and you live in the United States,
I'm not actually sure if they do outside the United States, but
like you can, we're part of the electronic Interior Alliance and they have these,
it's a great way to get connected with experts and they have trainings and
um they have people, you know, you can, hey, is there any examples of
petitions or open letters or draft bills
if you're willing? The biggest, the biggest thing is just try it and get started.
There are resources out there.
And frankly,
you can reach out to me or anyone at the eff and we'll
get back to you and help you out with that because it's,
it's important that this stuff gets, gets done.
-- And,
-- and I would like to include
that
anyone listening joining the eff is a marvelous use of
money and you can get a t-shirt and like,
I'll do anything for a t-shirt.
So like I was in
so one question for you is
I'm just thinking how much of, uh sort of, how much of these bad laws would you say
are sort of less malicious and more
the lawmakers just really not understanding
the technology and thus not understanding, you know, the 2nd and 3rd order effects
of the laws that they're looking at passing or not passing.
Like how much of this is an education issue
more than, you know, they're out trying to actually create a surveillance state.
I think that
it is
partially a legislation or sorry, and it's partially an education issue,
but a big part of it is that
law enforcement
has a vested interest in
surveillance powers for an understandable reason. It helps them do their job.
Like it's, it's hard to,
you know,
if law enforcement could,
you know, send every,
just randomly search people's houses and randomly
pull people over and ask questions,
you could, you could probably argue that they'd be a lot better at solving crime.
But, you know, there's a reason why we draw that those lines
and,
but so they have a significant lobby and they have a significant amount of sway
and it's very hard to get up if you're a politician
and you want to make the changes that you wanna, you know,
your goal isn't just privacy and surveillance stuff.
You wanna,
you have a whole political agenda that you want to advance and you
want to get re-elected and it's hard to get re-elected if you're,
if you can be painted as anti law enforcement.
Um, and so it's not
just an education issue.
It's also, they're being lobbied really hard by law enforcement. And
on the other side of the, on the other side of the aisle,
on the other side of the scales,
you have a small,
like the, the voices of pro privacy and anti mass surveillance,
everybody kind of likes those, but it's, there's not a lot of heat behind it.
-- You know, the
-- thing I keep coming back to is for the pro privacy argument and groups,
like there's no money to be made there. So, yeah, it's kind of hard to,
to sustain it and hard to push it.
Whereas, you know, the, the anti privacy, well,
like Facebook being in one extreme example of
what happens when privacy goes out the window
and, you know, and they, they make obscene amounts of money,
you know, and same thing with the police, right? They want to do their job better.
They have funding
-- so they can afford to lobby.
-- Indeed.
Well, I mean, now the counter to that,
I think if we look at the current Apple advertising,
they, I mean,
I think they fell into this accidentally but they're like
privacy is their thing now where they're basically the,
you know, we aren't spying on every single thing you do.
So I think privacy is becoming a topic.
People are understanding, I think we have a long way to go but I feel like this is the,
the beginning.
I completely agree and
the proliferation of services like proton
Mail and um
next cloud and there's a whole bunch of
like third party services that cater and, you know, VPN S are
for
issues that I would, you know, you
are starting to be big business now.
And
I would argue somewhat in a somewhat shady fashion,
you know, uh putting on my 10 ft
hat, that would be very, I would be,
I would be not at all surprised if there were a whole
bunch of VPN companies that were founded by various intelligence agencies.
But we'll, we'll see how that, if that turns out
um
privacy is becoming something that people are willing to pay for
and that is a very good thing.
But at the same time,
it would be better if it would, it, it was just a default. And
I feel like given the,
I feel like given the opportunity costs and the amount of money that can be made
with from information and frankly the amount of
influence and power that comes from information,
if we don't start both engineering systems that have privacy as the default,
but also lobbying to ensure that also lobbying the government to ensure that those
that, that the, that privacy is a requirement.
I feel like we're pretty screwed.
I,
I agree. Right.
Well,
it's back to the topic of the technologists
can't solve this by ignoring the government.
So, ok,
I want to bring this all home kind of advice from you for anyone kind of interested in,
in getting involved in, in any of this. Because I think it is, it's easy to tell people
get involved, but that's, that doesn't mean anything, right? If I'm a person,
what can I actually do
to start
getting involved in this and trying to see real change happen?
Step one is decide if you want to start a new initiative
or join an existing one. There are pros and cons to both of those and
it's usually easier to partner or join
an existing group. And you can go, you can just Google Effe fa
and look for like, look for local organizations
in your or just look around for a local AC lu chapter or a local group and
volunteer and get involved with them.
Yeah, that's, that can be a great way of getting started. But another thing,
the o another option is if that either if that doesn't
interest you or if that isn't available to you just because
where you live there doesn't happen to be any group like that.
You can, you can and should
make a list of local politicians.
Make a list, figure out what your ask is
and reach out to them and say, hey, I am a constituent or I'm not a constituent.
I'm an expert.
This is the policy change.
I would like to say,
can we can do you have 2030 minutes where we can sit and chat about it?
Now, now this one I think is really important because
I feel like we are often tempted to send an email.
-- That's not enough.
-- Right.
Well, I can like,
I would never tell people not to send an email about something that like if you,
if you don't have capacity to have meetings, sending an email is useful,
retweeting things is useful.
It's useful in the way that a drop in the bucket is useful.
A
getting a meeting is what is should be,
is is what's really impactful getting a meeting with information
with draft language that you can share with infographics, you know,
fill the whole nine yards
getting that meeting and forcing that information in front of their faces.
Ok?
We were saying you were, you're talking about talking to local politicians,
what what else can we do?
There's talking to local politicians and then
if you can get a group of people together
and have a and especially other starting coalitions with
other local organizations doesn't necessarily have to be,
for example, a lot of the groups in our anti surveillance,
the safety not surveillance coalition in Minnesota.
A lot of them don't have like privacy and technology or as like their explicit goal
and
you, but just having
an open letter or a petition is a fantastic way of
getting local news or express.
For example,
we just signed on to an open letter
yelling at paypal for uh essentially banning someone
from their account because they were funding a tour node.
Yeah, a whole bunch of uh civil society organization came together,
signed this open letter
and it got press and
that,
you know, that's an another example of getting open,
getting people to sign open letters and petitions
and showing it to a politician saying your constituency cares about this issue.
-- One
-- comment there.
So that's,
that's one of the few times I've heard
pri the importance of privacy explained which is
privacy is important because we need to have
speech that is unpopular and subversive and new
so that we can have change in society like letting women vote or, you know,
maybe slavery is not such a great thing and we should ban it.
And that's one thing that
I keep seeing with all these organizations pushing for societal changes.
You know, if you look at the history of, well, pretty much every country, right?
They've many governments have done their best to stomp out any quote unquote,
subversive activity which, you know, in hindsight,
well, the civil rights movement, you know, kind of was an important thing.
And so I think that's one thing I found
that helps people understand why privacy and why,
for example, the ability to meet and talk privately is so important.
Yes. And it, it is the realm of uh what is it?
Glenn Greenwald had a great ted talk on this topic about why privacy matters.
But it is this realm of privacy.
It is the zone of privacy that allows
these subversive talk that allows subversive planning,
subversive
communication, subversive politics that has to happen,
that has to happen in private
first before it can grow into a real movement. Yeah,
you, you've given me so much to think about Chris.
I I have to just personally thank you for that and,
and I have no doubt the audience has, has
found this to be an absolute treat. I will give you the floor for kind of the last word.
What do you, what do you want us to all know and remember?
Sure. Well,
if you're interested in learning more about us,
are you are you can check out our website.
-- It's at,
-- I will put,
I will put links in the show notes to all of the things you
you talked about or or will say in the next couple of minutes.
So no worries about trying to remember URL S and all that.
Well, actually, our URL is really easy to remember. I made sure to snack a
real simple one. But um
one of the things that technologist,
advantage technologists have over like radio activists is that
we know things like get a short domain name.
Damn it.
Yeah.
The last thing I'd say is it's not just privacy and surveillance, that's important.
The reasons to get involved in local politics is not just privacy and surveillance.
First Schneier's book,
click here to kill everything sort of really hit this home for me.
It's that
the more agency we give machines,
the more,
the more the lines become blurred between technology and society,
the harms that can come from,
the harms that can come from. This stuff is no longer
just,
you know, data breaches and money lost and eco economy, tanking and
pipeline shutting down.
We are fast approaching the world where we will have cars that can be ransom wared
while they're driving down the street where we
have infrastructure that can be exploded and people
and if we don't, it's not just
information,
that's the problem anymore. It's,
you know, people are gonna die if we don't get this stuff. Right?
And it's very rare in life that we can point to say, yeah,
pretty soon. If we don't start
really thinking about
these issues, people are gonna die.
So, yeah, that's what I would say is
privacy and anti surveillance stuff. Yes, that's all great.
Let's fight for that too. But don't forget like
the drones are coming for us all.
Oh, my goodness.
All right. I'm,
I'm gonna end it. Thank you so much. This has been a fantastic conversation.
I've truly enjoyed it. So, thank you, Chris. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. Go to open
source security podcast.com.
That's where I'll have all the show notes
for all the things we've talked about today.
Use a
pound
to
podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media.
-- Kurt and Chris have marvelous rest of your days. You too.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the.