Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast
with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner and looking for exploit code for CV S Josh Pressers.
I don't do that very actually. Ok. You know what I, I sort of did that just now.
So I, I have a, I have a story to tell that's completely related to the topic,
which is odd for me.
But
so
obviously I, I work in a
core and we have a vulnerability scanner called Gripe NVD collapsed
-- and it didn't
-- collapse. It's just having a nap.
Yeah, it's pining for the fjords.
Exactly.
-- So
-- just very quietly
we're doing all this work on vulnerability data,
like all over the place to make sure that it's as good as we it could be and,
and for lots of reasons, but we needed, we, we got some false negative reports.
Negative being a vulnerability exists and gripe isn't detecting it
against tomcat, which is some Java
web framework thing. I don't even know what to call it
anyway.
-- We use github's data
-- to
interrupt. Isn't everything in Java basically a framework.
It might be, I don't know
-- middleware, call it middleware. Like I
-- don't think is there anything small in Java?
No, no, there is not.
So anyway, github
has all these tomcat vulnerabilities labeled against tomcat the Tomcat jar.
But the way detecting vulnerabilities in Java works is you look for a jar
and then you look for vulnerabilities affecting that jar, right?
That's how that, how that is. And I mean, that's
-- just how like Maven works
-- at
all
and that jar might be like eight layers deep
ignoring that
there is no tomcat jar.
There is, you can install Tomcat with Maven, but you don't get a tomcat jar.
It just, it's like uh what are those pseudo packages in, in Linux distributions?
Right? Where it just installs all the real crap
anyway, there's no Tom Kar.
So there's 100 and 44 Tom Cat vulnerabilities in github
against Tom Cat which don't match anything because there's no Tom Kar.
So I went through them all and the old stuff was shockingly difficult to research
where I'm basically looking for patches to say this affects that jar, right?
And I can prove it because this patch is for that thing.
And as much as you want to complain
about like vulnerabilities and things like that today,
when you're looking at things from like 2004, like the, the early two thousands,
-- the, the half the links don't work because they're all dead.
-- Well, Roots
show.com
-- sun.com,
-- this isn't even that this is like this is Apache stuff, right?
Like the Apache has changed URL S that just 404. Now
it links to source code repositories. It don't exist anymore.
Fun fact,
I pushed ages ago for us for the CV project
to start mirroring that stuff because I was like,
it will go away.
Yeah. And it totally is.
Now what, what was wild is in a bunch of the CV ES.
The links were to archive.org so somebody had gone in and
changed the reference links from whatever it was to archive.org,
which I thought was pretty cool.
But anyway, I got through, I bet
100 and 20 or so I could figure out.
And the other ones, I'm like, whatever, I'm, they're, they're so old. Like if you
running to
camp three at this point, you're doomed.
Like,
-- scanning for vulnerabilities is pointless
-- when people
ask me about that kind of thing.
I'm like, basically, if your software is more than a year out of date,
like you said,
you're doomed and it's not just because it's a year
out of date and there's probably a vulnerability in it.
It's, you're doomed because it's a year out of date and you can't update it.
Like this proves that you can't update it because it's a year out of date.
Well, and, and here's the other great part is just finding
a, a Tomcat three TGZ I could download to poke around at, to get a,
like, like, what, what even is this thing anymore?
It took me a really long time just to find Tomcat three to download.
It's there in Apache to their credit, have archives of this stuff hidden away,
but it is not easy to find and you can't just type into Google like Tomcat three.
Download. Oh, no, that does not work. Anyway,
we have a vastly more interesting topic today
and it is around that paper that came out, uh, maybe a week ago.
-- give or take from the time we're recording this 17th of
-- April.
Yeah, exactly a week. Right.
Anyway, so,
well, exactly a week for us.
So it's called LLM agents can autonomously exploit one day vulnerabilities.
So basically,
and I assume what they mean by one day is like this is now in public for one day.
It's public stuff. Yeah.
Yeah.
And
well, yes, that's, yes. LL MS can absolutely do that.
Just like people with very low skill can do.
Well, I don't think people with low skill. Well, sort of,
I
think it,
so here's the,
there are vulnerabilities,
there are vulnerabilities for which we know
that the vulnerability is definitely exploitable.
But actually building the exploit to do it
can be very, very difficult.
And then there are vulnerabilities like cross site scripting is one
of my favorites that are really easy to test and to show
and to exploit. Like you put in
a bunch of code into like the login box and it spits out
Java Alert saying hello and welcome to the world
or same thing for uh like SQL injection,
right?
You just put in an extra quote and then the whole thing, Barfs.
And so, you know that it,
I want to talk about what these people said they did. So I read the paper.
It's not very long, it's like, what a dozen pages, maybe 20 pages.
It, it's very short. Anyway,
the paper has
annoyingly few details is
-- I will describe it as
-- I can tell you how they did it
because I can read between the lines because I've been doing this.
Well, I'm, I'm not worried about how they did it.
I think there's more interesting pieces to this than how they did it,
how they did. It is actually, here's the thing people are forgetting.
Do you know what I spend the vast majority of my time doing with a is, is thinking about
how do I currently do this work? How do I currently ask humans to do this work? And then
basically turning that into a prompt to feed to the A I.
And so a perfect example of this is that the CS A,
we want to have a support bot and I'm like,
we can't have a support bot because we don't have enough good support articles
that tell people what to do.
And we have a bunch of internal documentation that our support people use.
But more to the point, like many places,
there's a lot of stuff that's in people's heads
and it's not written down anywhere and that's fine
as long as they stay at where they work.
And so here, the funny thing is like constructing a prompt to say,
go to a website and basically figure out what it's running,
you know, get, get the headers, do this, do that
totally doable.
And then OK, so now you know what it's running now,
constructing a prompt to go search the
CV database for vulnerabilities in that stuff.
And then the third thing is OK, go read the CV entry.
And for example, some of them even linked to exploit code or at the very minimum,
they've linked to a code patch.
If it's open source, ideally
especially you'll notice this,
this paper
mostly talks about XSS and SQL injection and stuff where,
-- yeah, it's the really easy stuff. Right.
-- Well, no, no, it's not just the easy stuff.
It's the stuff where it's a one line change,
-- like adding html, special cares in a PHP.
-- I probably, I'm sure it's simple,
right?
I, I looked at a few of them and they're all kind of those. They're all the classic.
-- Oh,
-- you looked at, oh, I didn't look at the patches for the C
because they do specify what do they have there? 87% out of it's like 20 CD ES.
They did the research on 15. OK?
It's not a ton
but OK. So here's, here's the thing,
right. Let's just kind of start at the beginning.
And papers like this
are shocking quite often
because it, it upends a lot of what we think.
Right.
Well, people think exploiting vulnerabilities is hard and I'm like,
some are hard, like, like
to own and, and hijacking an iphone. Yes, that is hard.
And when, when an LLM can do that, I will panic.
But when an LLM is exploiting a cross site scripting vulnerability. Yeah.
-- No, that's it.
-- It's very simple and there's tons of examples. And
so here's what they said they did
and let's just kind of explain what happened, right? They,
they pointed GP D four, they said no other LL MS could do this
-- only check GP T four was capable.
-- That's wrong.
-- I think the other ones could.
-- No, no, no, because I've done,
-- I've done similar work.
-- They need different prompts, right?
-- What they're really saying is well
-- and also some
of them have better and worse guard rails.
-- And so you need other ways to get around the guard rails for
-- sure.
So they send a prompt to
Chai PT four
and they said the prompts are available upon request, but that
chat open A I asked them not to publish the prompts, which whatever, that's fine.
And then there are multiple steps
along the way where obviously, like you mentioned already, you know, it,
it read the CV E, it probably had to understand some code.
It had to look at certain things, whatever.
And they have a table and most of these took like 20 ish steps,
give or take 1520 along the path to exploit the vulnerability.
And then
they're also not particularly clear of like, what are these steps?
Why did some take 20? Why did some take 15?
-- So
-- it would have been generally narrowing it down and redirecting it to
probably,
but they're not clear
about this at all.
We don't understand like what is their bar for exploitation?
What counted as exploitation? That's not particularly clear.
I think the authors of this paper could have definitely been more clear.
But regardless, I think
that the point is this is extremely doable
and almost anyone could accomplish similar things.
-- So
-- uh one thing I just trig my memory,
one of the reasons they're saying that only chat GP T can do
this is technically they are correct that only chat GP T can do this
because only
GP T can access the weapon, download stuff, Google Gemini and clawed A I.
Oh They don't download things. They do not have a built
in capability to go download stuff. But
I've heard it is possible to download a web page using
Python or a script or a web browser and then feed it
into the A I and I'm being facetious because I've actually
fed the A I like over 10,000 web pages at this point
and I have scripts that mass do this. So So technically, they're correct.
They clawed
and Gemini can't do this natively,
but you could
just have a Python wrapper script that goes and gets
the content and feeds it into the A I.
Now, the other thing that I found very interesting is they claimed by not giving
Chet GP T for any of the, the CV E description.
It sounds like they, they basically just gave it the description.
I assume the reference links as well.
I, I don't, I don't remember reading if they specifically mentioned that point.
Anyway,
they said if they don't give it the description,
it was successful 7% of the time instead of what, 87% of the time,
which I think that is the vastly more
interesting aspect of this because that tells me they
had an LLM looking at a source code base
and it basically constructed a vulnerability from code.
It found
-- that looked suspect
-- I use all three A is primarily open A I and clawed.
And I'm,
but I'm starting to use Google Gemini more now that they finally released a good one.
But for example, I use
a software Python code especially all the time.
And
literally, I have at one point,
I had it right away server component thing and I
noticed it didn't do it very securely and I realized,
well, I didn't ask it to do it securely.
So I cut and paste the prompt into a new session
with
write this securely basically added to it and you know what it did,
it wrote it securely.
It actually added a whole bunch of checks and stuff that I, I was like, oh, yeah, I, I,
like, I would have forgotten to do that because it's kind of one of those like, yeah,
you should do that,
but you don't have to things and it literally added
a whole bunch of security steps and checks and proofs
that made for very robust code.
And
in my experience, this is exactly what happens with humans, right?
You ask a human to write a software feature,
they write a software feature,
they don't write the software feature securely because like,
well, that takes extra time and effort and they have a million things to do.
Sure.
Now, here's, I think the, the most interesting piece of that,
what is going to stop an attacker from pointing an LLM at a code base
and just letting it rip. They're, they're doing it now. I guarantee it.
Well, no, I've done it. It's,
-- yeah, it's,
-- where is your CV E Kurt?
I, I don't really do CV S anymore. I've given up on that.
Did you report the vulnerability upstream?
No,
but
I had to look at stuff and it will find suspicious looking code
where I glance at it and I didn't do a deep validation,
but it's like
it, it'll spot things now.
It'll also spot a lot of false positives or false negatives. But so will humans.
Yes.
And, but this is where building the exploit, like building that end to end is the key.
And this happens with humans. If you report a bug to a bug bounty
and you say I found a bug in this code,
90% of the time they're going to be like whatever clothes.
But if you say I found this bug and here's an exploit demonstrating the bug,
you're going to get vastly more attention
-- than you would. Otherwise
-- that leads to something I've been working on now.
And that is validation of A I results. And
an exploit code is a perfect example of a strong validation of, you know, I,
like I say that this is exploitable and my validation,
my proof is here's an exploit code that gets me rude on your boss
like
that's
you, you just can't argue with that,
you know, like it's that strong validation.
Whereas like there's other things where like OK,
I summarized this document and you know,
I had somebody else summarize the document and they look the same.
So it's
probably the correct summary, roughly speaking, right?
And so one thing I've been looking at is no matter what you do with A I
and how you do it with A I,
you
want to generally be able to validate the results to some degree if nothing else,
not so much for correctness,
but to determine if you're making changes that make it better or worse.
I mean, obviously here's a perfect example of if I can for the sake of argument,
let's simplify the problem.
Let's just say I have the LLM look at a CV E and develop an exploit code for it,
right? Let's take a few moving pieces
out of the equation.
So I feed it the CV E, it downloads the CV E,
it goes to github traverses looks at the patches.
Can it generate an exploit code? Yes, probably can.
But that's the thing from a validation perspective.
If it generates a working exploit code,
that does what it's supposed to like a cross site scripting
or an SQL injection or it gets rude on the box,
you've validated the A is output basically.
And ironically,
you might actually end up with a new vulnerability where it finds something
different.
So you actually do still have to check because I've seen people do that, right.
That is one of the things I was wondering is how many of these are different
and the researchers couldn't or didn't verify that
the exploit being hit was actually the exploit
that they were pointed at.
I mean, how many times have we seen people look at a CV,
write an exploit code for it and go
the CV,
fix this exploit code. And it's like, yeah, you found something new.
-- Oops,
-- this is something that they didn't talk about in the paper
where they should have also installed the fixed version
and ensured their vulnerability didn't work on the new version to verify that one,
it was fixed because we also see instances where
developers think they fix something and they actually didn't,
which is again one of the enormous values of a demo exploit, right?
What was that Cisco one where they just looked
for user agent curl and then blocked it?
-- Oh, yeah, that was, I remember that. That was amazing.
-- At
first I thought it was a meme but I'm like, oh no, they, they actually did that. Wow.
Yeah. It uh it did what? That's, it did what we were told,
like the exploit doesn't work anymore. That's fine. But anyway,
I mean, here's what I keep rattling around in my brain
when I read this and I think about this,
there's a statistic that's been thrown around a lot that
says something like only 3% of CD ES are exploited.
And it's, it's a really low number and I know that. Right.
Well, but, well, let's pause for a moment because
so for example, we know some CV S are exploited because we have like,
like log for J like log for J we know got exploited.
But the problem is even if you go with the CIA S
known exploited vulnerabilities catalog,
we don't know how widely exploited it is.
And I know for a fact I know a bunch of pen testers and they all write exploits for CV ES.
Yeah,
because like why would you, like,
you can start with original research or you could just start
with a CV and just crank one out in an hour.
Yeah.
I mean, this is so, it's funny, I, I've seen use cases where red teams are buying,
like, s
bomb scanners, they scan the application
and then they scan it for vulnerabilities and
that's where they start because it's like,
it's already got these bugs.
-- Like, let's look at these bugs. Well,
-- yeah, I mean, it's, it's
-- a no brainer.
-- Yeah.
Like, why would you look for new stuff when they left the front door open? Right.
Right. And that does happen a lot.
This is such a weird and interesting new threat that it, it,
it should shock no one who's been paying attention that this would happen.
-- Eventually.
-- It's not a new threat.
What it is is it's, it's lowering the cost of something.
So, a perfect example is, let's say I wanted to track you in 1950.
I would have had to pay a bunch of people to drive around and track.
Oh, let's, let's rephrase. I want to track you without, you know.
Right.
And nowadays I just stick a GPS transmitter on your car
and have a guy with a drone follow you.
Right.
And so the technology has changed significantly.
Like, what I'm trying to point out is a, I,
like, open source makes things vastly easier. I use a Troy software all the time.
Mostly software that I could write myself. But sometimes,
like I had to do some really clever stuff
with pandas and numpy and clustering of data values,
which
I
sort of conceptually understand how it works.
But if you actually asked me to write it in panda,
I would take six months to understand it well enough.
-- So
-- I wanna, I wanna pick on this point a little bit because it is easy to poop on A I
-- and claim its code is bad and it kind of is like
-- it's not, it depends what you ask for.
-- No,
-- it it can write simple things pretty well,
but it can't write overly complicated things in a maintainable way.
I'm gonna disagree with you there because I've already done it.
No, Kurt, you haven't written like tens of thousands of lines of code,
Weinger dot IO. Who do you think wrote?
-- How
-- many lines of code is web finger dot IO 100 200 maybe.
Now, I want you to tell the A I to write 20 30,000 lines of code.
No, it's, it's no, no one, no one.
I've heard that is a, a honest real developer working in the space today.
Agrees with that statement.
And if you are and you disagree with me, please at me and go ahead,
Kurt's typing furiously now and his key.
No, no, no. It's just, for example, I've seen people write Mobile
-- A
-- is are very good at analyzing piles of code,
analyzing something like a vulnerability description and then output
a a small thing like most exploit code is very small, right? You're talking
tens of lines of code or, or a file
that,
that triggers a condition, whatever
we're not talking about an enormous amount.
And so I think this is like the perfect use
for this kind of tool.
And the thing that scares the bejesus out of me is what happens when security
researchers just start generating exploits for 50% of CV ES or 80% of CD ES.
But then more importantly is they're going to get sick of CV ES
and they're just gonna point it at a code base and say
there is a cross site scripting flaw in this code base.
I want you to analyze it and find the cross site
scripting flaw and then generate an exploit that triggers the cross
-- cryptic flaw.
-- All the pen testers I know are already doing this
-- and they probably are. Yeah.
-- No, not probably they are.
I talk with them and they're like, oh Kurt, I did this, you know, I'm like, cool.
The thing that people don't understand and that you were touching on is a,
is have a context size that they can hold
anywhere from like a couple of 1000 tokens maybe for a small local LM
to Google Gemini claims a million tokens.
Yeah, it's like hundreds of thousands from the big ones. Now
200,000 dish for Claude
whatever. But the point is for you to just read
a million tokens worth of code
would take a very long time
and for you to then construct a mental model
of how that works and interrelate and behaves.
And you can remember the previous function call
kind of can. But it's, it's,
yeah, the computer is better,
right. It's
the same thing with square roots. Like, yes, you could work out a square root on paper
or, or you could just use a calculator
because I'm not oiler and I don't need to, like,
what gets me is people are always like, oh, the computer can never X and it's like,
and then the computer does X and then eventually does it like chess is
my favorite because stockfish running on a PC plays at about 3600 elo now.
And like, that's a couple 100 points better than the best human player.
-- Yeah. Now, but it also took us, what, 20 plus years of hard work to get there.
-- Yeah.
-- Well, 20 years is not that far away.
-- It isn't. No, no, for sure, for sure.
And, and then LL MS will get larger token. Well, they might, we don't know.
-- I
-- mean, no, the, the,
the LL MS have already gone from context windows
of like 48,000 now to claw being at the,
the 200,000.
Although some people say effectively,
it peaks at about 70,000 and then it starts to get worse results.
But whatever, ignoring that still 70,000 tokens or 50,000 tokens is
a lot. Well, here's the dirty thing.
It can read the code tokenize it and understand it and kind of hold a mental model of it
and I know that's the wrong term to use, but we'll just go with that
in tens of seconds.
A human cannot even like open the files in tens of
seconds and let alone start reading them and understanding them.
The Lord of the Rings book
has like a, a little under 500,000 words in it.
And that's considered like one of the gigantic books of the, of the universe.
And so if you're talking token sizes of a million,
that's a lot of text, like a lot of text
that, that the
-- LM can hold.
-- What is one form of text that is widely available to train A is on?
-- I mean, I assume you mean code,
-- right?
-- Open source
-- code because of open source.
Ok? I, I want to back up from one point.
You said there's pen testers doing this today,
if they're finding new exploits and they're not reporting them.
Your pen tester friends are dirtbags. So you need to tell them to do that.
So here's the problem, I've spoken with them about that.
And here's the problem under virtually every pen testing contract on the planet
when a pen testing firm does a pen test for company
A,
they report the findings to company a and it's like the
company a to decide what to do with those findings.
And so I've explicitly asked, like,
what happens when you find a new exploit in an open source?
Lir he's like, well, we tell company a
and they decide what to do with it. I'm like, do you tell them to get a CV or anything?
-- He's like, no, that's, they don't want it.
-- I bet they don't. I bet they do nothing.
Now, some of them are mature enough in that they're hiring a pen tester.
So that's, that's a sign of maturity right there. Right.
Like they're spending good money on these. Some of them do go upstream and then,
you know, because they're smart enough to be like red hat and say,
we don't want to maintain a patch set to fix the security vulnerability.
We'd rather upstream, fix it and then we install the patch or the update.
-- Rather
-- if you're a company that does this, please, for the love of all,
send the patches upstream.
Well, and so unfortunately,
the economic incentives of this are such that the pen testing firms don't.
No, not the pen testing firms.
If you, if the pen testing firm has it in the contract,
they can't send the patch upstream, whatever contracts, it's how it works.
But if you're a company receiving it, please, please, please, please,
please send those upstream.
And if you don't know what that means, like, send me an email and I will help you
and here's the dirty secret, right?
How many pen testing firms are CV, numbering authorities?
And the answer should be all of them. But the answer is really, there's about two
and in total, how many CV S have they actually issued?
And there was one pen testing firm that issued a bunch one year
and then went silent. I'm not surprised.
Yeah, the economics of pen testing and open source are not,
they don't allow,
I'm sure they don't, they don't
whatever it is what it is.
I
want to bring us back to the point tons
of CV ES could suddenly pick up working exploits,
right?
Which would be problematic for a variety of
reasons because there are tons of organizations that rank
CBES with vulnerabilities as being higher risk than those without.
And that is a reasonable assumption, I would say,
well, that's CV SS scoring, right? The CV SS scoring of exploit availability
-- uh
-- base. Well, Epss does that CV CV. SS does not take exploit ability into account.
No, no, no. But if there's exploit code is
like the temporal stuff that no one uses.
Here's the thing to remember too is number one,
somebody actually has to write an exploit.
Number two, the exploit actually has to work.
Number three, then for this kind of matter, they need to publish the exploit.
-- I can do that all magically now. No,
-- no, I know. I know. I know.
But the thing is,
there's provably a lot more exploit code running around than is public probably.
Yeah.
Well, by definition, there's at least one copy of a project
somewhere for sure, for sure.
And it's probably more than one. It's not one.
I wish it was. Oh, my God. Life would be easy.
So,
so we have to write the exploit. The exploit has to work, it has to be published.
And then there's 1/4 step that people forget, which is it has to be used.
And so for it to be used,
people need to actually, you know, kind of
go out and use it
and have an incentive to use it.
And so
like a lot of cross site scripting flaws.
Yeah, like they're good in a targeted attack.
But as like a large scale attack goes, they're not super duper useful.
-- I mean, that's fair, that's fair versus
-- like the ping of death that, you know,
affected everybody where you asked for a ping pack of
and then,
you know, 65,500 whatever bites and like, yeah, your machine would just
all
over.
And that,
that was actually the week where I put my Linux
box in front of my NT four box on the internet
because anyway, OK, so we've got CD ES, let's say a bunch of CD ES pick up V uh
-- working exploits,
-- you know what this is going to break the most is like,
it's all those corporate people where once something gets a CV E,
it's a ticking clock, 30 days, 90 days and all those people,
we've already seen what happens with the
Linux kernel where people are freaking out.
Oh,
yeah,
that, like, I have a,
these vulnerabilities I can't ignore because they have a CV E and it's like,
so you're saying you don't want them to have a CV, so you can ignore them.
Yes, they do. Literally that because my incentive isn't about security.
It's about box ticking anyway. But here's the thing, here's the thing.
There are all these vulnerabilities without CV ES.
We know there are millions of vulnerabilities that don't have CV ES, right?
What happens when some research institution? They, they take a system like
this,
they pointed at
a bunch of repos
and they let it rip and they're like,
I have 100 and 50,000 vulnerabilities without CD ES.
-- What should I do with them? Well,
-- Larry Cash,
Daler did it that one.
-- You
-- remember, Larry was small potatoes compared to what this could be.
-- Well, it was a couple of 100 but back then he basically broke CV
-- E. Yes, he did.
And, and Larry was one person,
right? We even had him on the show. Remember episode 2, 19? Oh, my goodness.
-- That was four years ago. That
-- was what? Really? Oh, my goodness.
That feels like it was. I would have guessed like a couple of weeks max.
But no.
So that's a good example is here's the thing, if,
what if 100 people decide to do what Larry Cash
Dollar did? Well, then that would be a problem.
But now the problem is one person who builds essentially a good pro, a set of prompts,
a good set of guidance and a good set of evaluation,
right? Can just
like because I do this all the time where I have bashed jobs
that run for five or six hours clearing the A I through the API
and I'm, I'm processing thousands of pieces of information, summarizing,
contextualizing, judging them.
Could I do that with source code to look for vulnerabilities? Yeah.
-- Right.
-- II, I could, I, I wouldn't because it's not my job,
-- it's not going to be cheap today.
-- Um
-- I have bad news for you. It's like you don't
-- know you're making
-- crap
-- up.
It's 15, no to send in a million tokens
to say Claude three
opus is like $15
and a million tokens back is like $75.
And as you said,
there's a lot more going in that there is coming out like I'm sending in a code base,
right?
It would definitely be lopsided.
But we're talking about like the entirety of open source cart,
but we're talking about literally dollars to tens of dollars per project.
-- And I don't need to do all the projects. Just the top 100
-- in the paper.
-- They say it was like $3 in change per, per exploit. I guess
-- that sounds about right.
And II, I agree. But now $3 times 9 million
open
source,
-- but you don't need to do 9 million.
-- No, I know, I know you can pick the popular one.
But the point is, here's the thing though.
You say this all the time, like making,
making something cost a penny is too much for most people and it is.
And so
I'm not saying this is going to break the bank of a large corporation.
But I do think like doing the,
the level of research we're talking about across like finding
millions of vulnerabilities is not free and it would not,
it would be more expensive than many people could afford.
-- Which is unfortunate.
-- I have good news for you though.
I have good news for you though. There are already a
several really, either well trained or fine tuned models,
especially in the 8 billion to 3 billion token set.
-- So that's the stuff that will run on a laptop.
-- Yeah.
-- Oh, yeah. Yeah. No, you can do it on your own hardware
-- for sure.
This is absolutely if somebody wanted to fine
tune or actually train a model from scratch,
this is, this would be the perfect
example because
you have a quarter million CV ES
with
-- anywhere, maybe a quarter of them linking to source code patches.
-- A lot of them.
-- I don't know if it's a quarter but it's a lot, it's,
-- it's at least 10,000. At least
that's a training set right there. Or at least a fine tuning set for a coding A I
and so the good news is, is you can, absolutely, this is the,
this is a perfect use case for building and training or fine tuning an A I
that can run locally on your laptop or PC or whatever. Yeah, it could. Definitely.
And just grind 24 7. Yeah, your electricity bill will be a bit higher.
-- If you're a college student, you get free electricity. Yeah,
-- exactly.
Yeah.
And so like this is the kind of thing where, and here's the scary part.
What happens when somebody releases that model?
And what happens when somebody releases those prompts?
And what happens when literally all you got to do is type run
this and take these N PM packages or these top 1000 or?
Ok.
So I'm gonna, we're gonna end this show on what will happen
today and today it will crush the system because we are
completely unprepared for the results of a project like this.
We see what, what's like NVD is pining for the fjords,
not, not collapsed,
but
like it, it got crushed by a, a very human amount of vulnerabilities.
And we're talking about an inhuman amount of vulnerabilities. Now,
the, the way
out is to rethink how we handle vulnerabilities and risk and all of this stuff.
And there, there's a lot of people who've been talking about this for a long time.
It's like the whole cult of zero CV. E.
Yeah. Good luck with that. When there's a million CV ES a year.
I remember when I was at Red Hat,
I downloaded all of pie pie and I looked through it for
temporary file vulnerabilities and about a third of them had it.
-- Oh, my
-- goodness. You and your temporary file vulnerabilities.
Well, no, no,
but because they're easy to find and they're technically a vulnerability.
And so I looked at this
and I went, OK, I have like 20,000 vulnerabilities
and I just deleted the directory because what else am I going to do with it?
And so that's the interesting thing is we're,
we're now on to the shoe firmly on the attacker's foot right now with the use of A I
mostly because the defenders are not willing to use A I.
There's like, oh A I is bad. It generates bad results, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
I don't know if that's inaccurate statement necessarily.
I think there's plenty of defenders using it.
I think the problem is we are currently conf
by an enormous number of processes that were outdated before
LL MS existed and now they're hilariously outdated in the,
in the age of LL MS for this kind of stuff.
There's too much obsession with vulnerabilities in box ticking.
-- Gen two has banned A I created contributions.
-- I
don't care about what gen two thinks.
-- But
-- this is the trend I'm seeing in open source is
everybody's essentially saying we don't want to accept A I contributions.
-- We don't want to have anything to do with it.
-- They're allowed to do that.
It's open source.
It's their decision if they want to do that, who cares?
-- It's not our problem
-- when I was saying that the,
the shoe is firmly on the attacker's foot right now.
As far as A I use of A I goes,
what's fascinating to me is to see open source saying
we're not going to allow the use of A I.
And so they're not going to be able to benefit from it and they're
not going to learn how to use it in ways that are actually helpful.
All right. Look, I'm going to get on a soapbox and I'm just going to say it. A
lot of the people talking about A I now are just literally
full of
shit. They're shit pedaling shit weasels and that's why people don't want to use it.
It has value and it can do amazing things but
it can't do everything and it can't do anything.
And that's the problem.
This is like any new technology, you have the hype cycle,
you have the shit peddlers and a bunch of normal people are like, fuck it.
I don't even want to deal with it.
-- That's gonna be a lot of bleeps.
-- I mean, pets.com, right.
We went through this with the.com thing
and in many ways, the.com crash
was far more forgiving than it should have been.
And yet here we are 20 years later where I think we
can all agree that life kind of went to online web commerce.
It's the Cory Doctorow.
He wrote the, what,
you know what's left behind after the bubble burst or something like that.
I'll, I'll look it up and I'll put it in the show notes.
But like the.com to bust left a lot of things behind the NFT bust left nothing behind
the A I bust, which I think is starting now
is probably going to leave some things behind because the technology is useful,
but it has been over hyped and I understand why
a lot of people have reacted negatively to it.
Every technology gets overhyped. That's the human condition.
Yeah. Yeah.
-- And people react negatively to it like
-- I'm sure
fire was overhyped and then somebody burned themselves on.
It was like,
I
don't like this
anyway.
Anyway, the point is this is going to change everything in the vulnerability space.
I don't know what the answer is,
but I assure you what one of the things the
answer isn't is the way we do vulnerability handling today.
Well, I would take it a step further. A I is just data processing
and what makes it very unique is its data processing
like a human
and humans are historically very expensive to hire to train and to get to do
work because they want to sleep and eat and have family time va doesn't.
And so
what's like any new technology? We're gonna find ways to actually use A I.
Well, and Attackers have a huge incentive to be more efficient and more effective.
Well, in his cat and mouse man, like defenders are, are chasing
the defenders.
I there's already people thinking about this, you know, like at the CS A,
we're writing papers on this and I know Microsoft is working on defender stuff,
security copilot and all that.
And what's fascinating to me is to it.
I'm very much reminded of like, yes, there is a I hype. Absolutely.
But
there are, I'm seeing people saying no A I,
what's gonna happen is those companies, well,
you don't remember who the companies that didn't do the
web are because they don't exist anymore by and large.
Sure. But I don't even care about that. I just, I care about the fact that this work
is going to change the vulnerability landscape.
We don't know how yet.
We don't know how we're going to react to it, which is a little terrifying sometimes,
but something is going to change because it has to,
there's only one real, one of the reactions will have to be defenders have to use A I,
we can't, we can't fix this with humans.
You don't know that it, it might be, that's your bias towards A I,
the reality is the vulnerability handling we have today
can't even keep up with the load we have today
and LL MS are going to make it crushingly magnitudes larger
how we deal with that. I do not know today, we do not know the answer, the answer.
You can't just like throw a I into the air and claim it the answer.
We don't know, we have to invent the future. That is the reality.
Well, I mean, one possibility is people step back and go, hey,
maybe these vulnerabilities aren't as bad as, you know, we,
we thought there's probably some of that for sure.
-- And we can ignore a lot of them.
-- But, well, and this also goes back to Tama
Pierre's whole whole talking points of like,
we need tools that solve a lot of
these problems because these are like systemic human
programming problems and expecting us to like individually
fix all these bugs is probably not realistic.
I just,
I keep coming back to bulldozers and Hydro
VC. We don't have like, we so rarely have people with a shovel digging a big hole now.
-- Yeah. Right.
-- Because it would be stupid
and I'll leave you on that. Yes.
Yeah, I know. But, but you think the, the bulldozer is A I,
and I'm saying, I don't know what the bulldozer is.
That's the only difference I haven't made up my mind yet.
-- I'm gonna say the answer is not more people it
-- isn't more people.
I, we can agree on that point
but what the bulldozer is made of, I do not know
and I am unwilling
to claim it's A I
at this point, maybe it is
as long as it's not people. And we don't think just whipping harder is the answer.
-- That'll make me happy.
-- Well, here's the thing A I fits this unique category of it.
Lets you implement
the solutions you want to implement with humans with A I and it basically
allows you to whip harder but with an A I instead of people complaining,
oh,
I
mean, I, you know, I use A I to do horrible things that if I asked a human to do them,
they would quit on the spot.
Maybe that's different. That's a different problem.
All right, I'm calling this one because I don't want to go down this path.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening. Go to put
our security podcast.com at the show, Not
Pound do says podcast. Hashtag and Mastodon Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.