Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 66 with myself,
Kurt Siefried
and my partner in Thought Crime. Josh Bresser.
Do you know Kurt that every time we finish an episode?
I think maybe nothing exciting will happen this week
and there just won't be anything to talk about next.
-- And I have never been disappointed yet.
-- I think the only way that will happen is if
we lose internet connectivity and cell and power and
-- basically, if one of us spends a week in the woods,
-- maybe the end of the world,
although maybe if I spent a week in the woods,
I bet I'd have all kinds of fun stuff to talk about.
Right.
I don't even know where to. Like,
there's just so much that's wrong.
Like, well, how about we get the quick stuff out of the way? So,
you heard the latest eco fact bits
-- fill me in. Let's see if I've heard
-- them.
-- It looks like it might have been state sponsored hacking from China.
-- Right.
Good for them.
I can't imagine what, what they need. Maybe, I don't know.
Well, I'm thinking for so, for example, Facebook has a social graph of,
at this point, the world
right to the point where it's creepy. I was reading up on it and, like,
they're linking people who are blood relatives, like biological,
uh, relations
but, like,
didn't know about each other.
Yeah, I read about that and,
and they were far enough removed outside of Facebook
and there was no known internet connection between the people
and, and yet it figured it out, which is crazy.
And then there's other cases where, you know,
people who want to have multiple identities online, for example, sex workers,
you know, have their profiles being linked and, and well,
that's kind of an easy one because any, any sort of
uh for example, I use the same profile photo on everything,
right?
So it's,
it's really easy to find me because you just do like a Google reverse image search and
you'll find everything, plug my name in.
Um
But yeah, so it's, it's uh I
I'm, I'm wondering if this is sort of part of
reconnaissance slash building a picture of the US, like who,
you know, who's vulnerable to blackmail, who knows who,
you know.
And also the thing is if you're, if you're planning an advanced, you know, uh
like if you're doing an attack,
an advanced persistent threat type of attack where you, you know,
your goal is to like break into swift uh at a bank and steal $60 million or, you know,
shut down a power grid in the Ukraine or whatever chances are, you know,
that's really valuable when names come up to be able to search
for them in your little database and know stuff about these people
that could be, that could be what you describe is certainly plausible.
I, I don't know, man, this one's gonna be,
I imagine it's going to be playing out for a long time.
Well, this type of thing, I mean, because it's not like we can stop this,
right? How many companies hold data on us? Basically,
you know, the number of companies I deal with where they they ask for like
really personal information.
Like one thing that drives me nuts is companies that ask for postal codes
because
-- they know
-- that. Right.
Well, in, in the US it's less terrible with your five number
uh zip code, right?
But if you get the extra four numbers then it's basically your house,
you know, or like my parents' postal code is like, I think it's 10 or 13 houses,
right? So, you know, it's,
yeah.
Um and you know, so I'm, I'm shopping and like they're like, oh,
can we get your postal code?
And I'm like, no,
you mean like it's funny because they used to like give me a weird look
and now they're just like, ok and they type 0000 or whatever, you know.
Um So it's, it's definitely, I think people are
getting used to refusing to give that information
back in the day.
If you refuse to give information, people looked at you were like,
when I called up the phone, when you get my DS L and they're like,
you know, uh we need your driver's license number and I'm like, not super Ken on that,
but sure.
Right.
Because they want, you know, see if I'm really mean and then they're like,
can we have your social insurance number?
And I'm like, no,
and they're like, we need two forms of government ID to sell your DS L
Sweet.
I, I do remember that though and when I remember there was a time
when
it felt like everyone was asking for my social security number,
like everywhere I went
and I of course, wouldn't give it to anybody.
And, and yeah, they looked at me like I was some sort of weirdo
and my suspicion is today if you did that, nobody would think you're weird.
Thank you Equifax.
Unfortunately, the problem is those social security numbers,
social insurance numbers, addresses, names, all that stuff is in, you know,
16,000 different places with, you know, data brokers reselling that data on.
Yeah, good luck. I mean,
anyway, so that, that's the Equifax big news.
Um Do we want to talk about Kaspersky and the shenanigans going on there?
-- Apparently
-- that, that whole thing is just
my brain doesn't know it is,
it's a badly written movie is what I feel like that is it it's like some terrible
for
real. I mean,
yes, to a degree. But this particular story is just
ridiculous and, and it's one of those things where,
well, how about you fill in
-- our listeners.
-- So, what's the latest thing?
The latest thing now as it sounds like Israel was hacking Kaspersky and found out
that the Russians were also hacking Kaspersky and
had access to us intelligence or something.
And then Israel told the US and it's just
some NSA tooling or something was found on
Kaspersky computers.
So the current theory is that some NSA contractor took stuff home that they
really shouldn't have had Kaspersky on their machine and that leaked it up or,
or intentionally was used.
And I mean, that's part of, you know, that's part of the brute, like the reality of,
of anything is that, you know,
if you're in a jurisdiction and guys with guns show up and tell you to do something,
-- you're, you're gonna kind of have to do it.
-- Oh, seriously. I agree completely.
And I think that's certainly something
that, that people should keep in mind is
Kaspersky is a Russian company.
And
what I love is all the people saying, oh, you know,
we don't know what's going on and it's like
given the history of everything that's happened between the
US and Russia and what is happening today.
If, if Russia isn't leveraging Kaspersky for their advantages,
they're a bunch of idiots.
I mean,
-- they're
-- clearly not a bunch of idiots.
Right. Exactly. Exactly. So, I, I think
anyone pretending this isn't real is,
is running around with bananas in their ears just
for
real. And, and, you know, it's frustrating for me. Right. Because,
so
this raises one issue for me, which is like, how, how much can I,
or do I trust the software running on my computer?
Right.
For example, I have a bunch of third party apps that some of them have, you know,
relatively high access, like, say the firewall app or whatever, right?
And um
yeah, I mean, at some point, OK.
Fundamentally,
I have to trust my operating system and the hardware it's running on at a minimum,
right?
And then, you know, the add on stuff like uh I use Google Chrome as my web browser.
Uh So Google Chrome May for the sake of argument,
even if it doesn't have access to my system,
it's got access to all the web stuff I do, which is like in the modern world,
that's like 90% of your computer use.
Basically.
Actually, I was,
I was thinking about that the other day is
I am building what I'm calling the container zoo where I'm on my, on my desk,
on my laptop.
I'm sorry,
I'm going to set it up.
So any time I run a shell command, it's going to run in a container
and I started like paying attention to my history and stuff.
I do remarkably little in the shell. And I do like 99% of my work in a web browser now.
It's crazy.
Yeah.
No, it's um, and I was thinking about that, like, do we containerize
the web?
You know, Firefox has that now with that multiple personalities thing?
-- So you could have like a work persona, a personal persona. Maybe you could
-- do
that.
I do that in Chrome now where I have, I have basically like two web browsers running
where one is for work and one is for home and, and what are they
or something?
Segmenting it even more. So, yeah, I do the same. I have personal profile.
I have work profiles, blah, blah, blah.
But I mean, so within my personal profile, you know, being able to say separate,
separate
out, you know, the news I read from what I shop at Amazon,
I see what you're saying, you know, or if I were to use Facebook,
I would prefer for that to probably be separate because, you know,
Facebook tracking across the web is a
thing they know anyway, don't kid yourself.
Yeah. So
yeah, I don't know. I mean, at this point because
segmenting everything properly is just such a colossal pain.
Well, it's not just a pain,
it's almost certainly impossible because even if
you're using a different web browser,
I mean, even if you say open an incognito window for everything you did,
they know how to find you,
right. You can't get away from it.
Oh yeah.
No, like, I mean in HTML five,
there's so many things you can use to track people like the canvas,
the local storage, the
heck you can use HSTS headers to track people uniquely.
-- Right.
-- There's, it's crazy, man.
And, but so from my perspective, I guess what,
what I keep thinking of is less the tracking
because I really can't do anything about that.
But what I feel like I can do is maybe start thinking
about what am I doing and how am I doing it?
And what can I segment from other things? And, and it's occurred to me now that like
when I'm running a web browser that is unquestionably
my biggest threat
on my system.
Right. Because it's just, it does everything.
Yeah.
No, I mean, banking bill's correspondence, email, uh recording this podcast.
I am not recording it in the web browser,
web
browser.
We do. I know it's crazy, man. Right. Right.
Why can't Google just record it and send us the copy?
Maybe they are.
Yeah.
So, yeah.
II I think honestly at the point and you know what always
drives me nuts is so because it was like the thing,
you know, that, that article about the sex worker being kind of
outed to herself on Facebook and people are like, oh,
people should just take ownership of their data and
not use things like Facebook and it's like,
well, exactly. It's like I don't like cars but
I have a driver's license and I own a car because,
yeah, I live in North America. That's how that works.
You know? Exactly.
And there's just certain things you can't, you can't avoid, I mean,
family coordinating, family stuff,
like a bunch of my extended family uses Facebook.
Even ignore
that though, saying, you know, you should own your data is,
is a very naive way to think about this stuff because I mean,
your freaking grocery store knows who you are.
I mean, how are you going to control that?
How are you going to control the fact that other people on Facebook talk about you.
Even if you don't have
a
Facebook
account
pay with
cash.
Yeah, that, that'll work out really well. Right.
They're going to keep calling the cops.
Always bring, bring a note to the bank and hand it to the teller.
Yeah.
Yeah. I mean, that's the reality is, it's, you know,
we can't opt out of these systems unless you literally,
I don't know, maybe you send a 12 year old to the store to buy
and then, you know, they're tracking the kids, they just pretend they aren't.
I mean, come on, let's face it.
Yeah. I, I don't, I think the answer fundamentally is that this is going to, to
continue because it's just companies feel it's valuable.
What drives me nuts though is,
is they've really worked hard to shift the burden on to the consumer.
So it's,
it's no longer bank fraud. It's identity theft, right?
And so it's your problem when your identity gets stolen
and it's your problem that you have to sort out,
you know, and prove to these companies that no, you know,
there, there's been cases where people, you know,
had their identity stolen as a child,
they weren't even 18 and, you know, they're having to prove
to credit card companies that, like,
legally you couldn't have done this anyway,
even if it was me,
you know, I wasn't 18.
And
so part of me thinks maybe we should just have like a AAA registry of, you know,
basic facts about everybody.
Like, uh for example, was it Finland or Norway?
Uh everybody's tax returns are published publicly.
Interesting, right? It's part of their transparency and their,
their sort of um
their culture, you know, of openness
and um
part of me thinks, you know, why not do that, right? You know, so that
if I do have to disprove something, it might actually be a bit easier.
Uh And on the flip side by having all this information out in public, you know,
anybody that's going to abuse it
will
so easily that hopefully these companies will, you know,
rebuild their systems or change their systems. So they're not so easily abused.
This might not be a completely insane idea.
So, you know what this always makes me think of is
when I've always had a job at a company.
I have never made my cell phone number a secret.
And I did this knowingly for a reason though is because I, I actually, I,
I won't tell the story of how I came to this
conclusion because it's probably it could put me in jail,
I suspect.
But,
but the point is when,
when you do something for people very willingly
or you give them information very willingly,
I feel like
they, they put a burden of guilt on themselves to not abuse it.
Whereas if it's a secret now all of a sudden it's,
I have something and someone else doesn't.
So I'm going to use it to my advantage.
Well, I mean, that's the thing. Right. You can't blackmail.
Well, a great example being, you know, all the, the,
the homosexuals and past the were blackmailed because homosexuality was seen,
you know, in such a negative light now, it's kind of like,
like, and
cares.
Yeah, it's like, so are we having sandwiches for lunch? Like,
I don't get it. What's the big deal? You know?
-- Um,
-- well, although,
although we shouldn't downplay that because there are certainly
places where it's a huge deal
-- where
-- it's legal. Right. Right. Well, not even where it's a legal man.
I mean, there are places in the United States where,
where you don't out yourself because you're gonna have a bad day.
You know, luckily neither of us live in those places. But
they, they do exist.
True.
Uh But part of it is, I mean,
it, it kind of comes back to that. It's like Chaos Monkey at Netflix, right?
If we create like a baseline of chaos, then when real bad stuff happens,
it's just normal.
Um You know, if you, yeah, I mean, outing yourself is definitely not
always an easy thing for people to do, especially if they live in certain places.
Uh Even in North America,
the whole world is chaos monkey. Now,
I,
I think that's,
this is something actually, I,
so I just moved my blog actually to uh a CSO online
uh today it was, and, and I published an article and,
and it was talking about the fact that maybe things aren't as bad as we think they are
and, and you're talking about everything is so bad
but, but it's not right, like the world is functioning.
Equifax got hacked and Equifax is still running as a business.
-- Like explain that to me, right? What, what, what
-- happened?
Who could put them out of business?
It's not like their customers can just suddenly stop.
It's not like their customers data was stolen, right?
I mean, that's the reality of it.
Their customers don't care, they didn't lose anything.
And, and that's the thing, right?
Is like this is what I feel like the world is turning into is
this is just the way stuff is and you know what, it's not bad enough to change it. Yet.
I'm not sure it will be.
Yes. I think that's
the,
that's part of what really gets me because, like,
there are so many things wrong with the world that we just accept.
Like, um, tens of thousands of people die every year in car accidents.
We,
here's what blows me away, for example, cancer. Right.
We've spent hundreds of billions of dollars on research into curing cancer and,
you know,
made a lot of progress but not completely,
you know, I have to imagine self driving cars.
That's easily several, tens of thousands of people a year in North America,
not dying.
And more importantly, you know,
-- hundreds of thousands of people not being injured sometimes really severely.
-- Oh,
yeah.
Well, not just that you think pollution and,
and there's so many other aspects to that,
it's going to be unbelievable what it does.
Yeah, the number of negative externalities.
But
here's an important point on, on this though is
cars come with many downsides,
but we aren't looking to build self driving cars
to remove the negative aspects of regular cars.
We want self driving cars for other reasons.
And what this really makes me think of is, I read a quote once that said
the stone age didn't end because we ran out of stone. Right.
And that's kind of what I feel like here and in
my suspicion is computer security is going to be the same that
we're going to end up fixing security
not for the sake of fixing security, but rather because there's something better
-- that we're doing
-- instead if we were going to
fix security for the sake of fixing security,
it would have happened sometime in the last three years.
And
that's completely true, isn't it? People actually cared.
We would have done something by now,
you know, and,
and a lot of people are doing a lot like a great example being like Google's fuzzing,
it's like,
do we, you know, I
security issues are bad.
Crashes in a web browser in general are bad and quite annoying.
Um You know,
let's make sure that the web browser is stable and if we happen
to fix a big pile of security flaws while we're doing that,
you know?
Awesome.
Yeah.
Yeah,
I mean, that's,
that is a fair point. But now at the same time, I also wonder
are, are things like Google's fuzzing projects
are those helping to keep things just barely good enough?
Whereas if we just gave up and let everything burn down, we'd,
we'd get to fix it faster.
But here's the thing, how would we fix it?
We go back to that poll if I give you a billion, if I give you a billion dollars to,
let's let's narrow the problem down.
Not just not fix security but just build me a secure web browser,
here's a billion dollars.
Yeah, I would, we'd still have to, we have to define security, right?
So ok, it never runs code improperly great.
But it still lets people be tracked online, which some people would say is a problem.
I would just take your money and live very well
like that. That's the reality of it.
And that's basically how most of, most of it works today. I think.
So. I, you know, I, I tend to agree.
I don't think security will get fixed for the sake of fixing security.
But yeah, definitely better things will come along, you know.
Well, a great example, memory management, right? Let's face it.
Most people
can't write code that manages its own memory
C++ being a very solid example of this.
So languages that do garbage collection and memory management, you know,
say Python is one of my favorites,
just take away a whole class of problems,
not because they're trying to make better security,
but because they're just trying to make,
you know, more efficient programming languages that work better. That's a
very
good, you know, certain types of problems.
Uh and to be clear, like C and C++ have a place on the planet,
but like you probably shouldn't be building, you know, web servers in them
-- anymore. And,
-- and all the web servers are still written in
C,
you know, or building shell tools, maybe, I don't know.
There's just, there's so much stuff that really, you know,
very few people should actually be allowed to write in
C and C++ is basically what my point would be,
you should have like a special license.
I'm not even going to go there.
Well, you know, you, you remind me too.
So that this container Zoo thing I started working on
is I started writing some of the tools in shell
and after spending about two hours trying to get a raise working right in bash,
which is, of course impossible.
I was just like, screw it. I'm doing it in Python
and, and it's, it's the same deal right? Where
the world is so much better when you're using a language like Python,
ignoring security.
There's so many other reasons to do it.
No.
And I think that's, you know, fundamentally people, if you give a develop, well,
if you give a project manager a choice between,
here's something that will make it more secure
and here's something that'll let you add features, faster
-- features,
-- man,
features always win guaranteed.
So,
yeah, I, I, and the good news is, you know,
programming languages are getting a lot better.
Like some of the newer ones are actually quite amazing, like from a
security point of view and just a general ease of use and, you know.
Yeah.
Oh, totally. I mean, look at go go lang
is a great example.
It,
it does a bunch of really clever and interesting things and
I've heard a lot of good things about Rust from Mozilla,
even though I admit I've never used it.
01 thing I like about go is you actually
can't create temporary files insecurely like they just,
it just the default temporary file creation capability is secure end of story.
But at the same time those doofuses
screwed up random number generation
where there's the secure and insecure random number generators.
It's like why, why even have an insecure?
Nobody knew
that.
Well, I'm sure it's faster. But
yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
But rngs in general are sorry. Pr ngs in general are quite,
quite fast.
Yes.
And I,
I don't know why they have two and I feel like I
filed a bug or something at one point that was ignored.
And my suspicion is they know they screwed it up and they're just embarrassed.
It, it's kind of like, you know, when you've got that, that uncle
that
you have to invite him over for Christmas, but you don't want to
sort of thing.
Yeah.
See what's weird to me is you could just,
couldn't you replace the insecure random number generator with a secure one?
And, and
theoretically speaking,
-- nobody would notice
-- my suspicion is that would be frowned upon by language
designers because typically what happens is when
you use a random number generator,
you see it
well, in some instances, not all.
And, and,
oh. Right.
That's what it is, is I believe it's, if you use a random number generator,
it's seeded with zero by default,
which means. Right. Right. And it's like, why did you do this?
Why just there, there's no reason for this and my guess is 99% plus
instances where the random number generator is used.
Nobody cares what the seed is.
And in fact, having, having the same seed is probably bad
but
whatever, you know how it is, man. And, and for like those six people that it affects.
Lord forbid we fix it.
Yeah. I don't know.
I,
yeah. Well, and we've seen that in like open
sell is a great example, right? It doesn't by default, do
uh host name checks,
right? And same with Python.
Python didn't do that for a very long time until pep whatever it was a few years ago.
You know, one of the arguments was this is going to break all the code and it,
and it will because,
well, it's, it's not even just that this is,
this is something hard to do actually because I,
I'm dealing with some TLS issues now now at work,
but like
they didn't know which cas to ship.
And so rather than trying to make decisions, they just took the easy way out.
And in part of me is sympathetic to that because TLS is really freaking hard to do.
Right.
-- It's, it's such a huge pain,
-- man. Why wouldn't you just use a system trust store?
Well, because not everything has a system trust store, right?
Like when you're on a Linux system, there isn't a system trust store.
There can be like four locations.
Well,
although it's better now because I think the
distro have settled on some C certificates,
um, similarities.
But, like, you know, 10 years ago it was, it was crazy to,
you know.
That's true.
Right. And if you've never done it you should try maintaining your own ca
store.
It's, it's terrible.
I've written articles about it. It's quite a pain.
It's such a gong show and, like, I feel super bad always for the people,
like Mozilla and Google who have to maintain these and you have to deal with these
cas and you have to determine trust and kicking one out is terrible to do.
It's so hard.
Yeah. No. Aren't they just in the process of kicking out? I think it's
Semantic
Symantec
and what wasn't it? Also? Startcom
Stock
has been gone for a while, I think.
But, but Symantec is the latest one where
I think Google was kicking them out and then didn't,
I think they sold their C A business to someone else who's going to try to fix it now.
And it's just,
it's crazy town. I mean, there, there aren't good answers to most of this stuff.
Well, I mean, the C A market is literally a way to print money.
Like it is a very low overhead
and people are paying you 400 bucks a year for certificates or whatever.
Well, it used to be. I mean, I think thanks to lets encrypt
and some of the bottom has fallen out of that one.
Yeah, that's true. Um, well, I feel like there's still a lot of corporations that
don't use. Lets encrypt. No,
there's, there's lots of them.
I,
I've talked to more than one where they have
a variety of reasons and in all seriousness,
some of them are valid but most of them aren't
where they, they don't want to use. Let's encrypt
and, and you know what I guess, whatever,
if,
if that's your prerogative and you don't mind spending a couple of 100 bucks a year.
Good for you.
Yeah, I don't know. I, yeah, cas are a great example because how do we fix this?
How, like, and I don't mean by just booting them, but, I mean,
how do we get the CAS to want to
behave properly and be secure and not miss issue certificates
because banning them apparently isn't enough of
a
punishment to,
you know,
I mean, banning AC A is going to be, that's the end of them.
Right. There's, there's no, I mean, was it, did you not,
were the ones who had the issue and they were
kicked out quickly just because of how bad things were
and it ended the business and, and it's going to end it. But of course,
it's not as easy as just saying. All right, I don't like you anymore.
You're kicked out because
if you look at someone like Symantec a,
a substantial portion of the internet is signed by their C A.
So if you kick them out now you've actually made the
experience worse for users and in some cases even more dangerous.
Yeah.
No, it's, I, I don't know,
I, the whole, I,
I get that we want to definitely encrypt all our
traffic and part of that is that we have to
have some form of C A or something because, you know,
is this walmart.com actually walmart.com or is it Bob?
You know, and ideally as a further extension of that, is this, you know,
TD Canada trust.com actually like my bank or just, you know,
Ted and Dan's Canada Trust Fall company
sleet, you know, happens to have my bank login web page.
Um,
yeah, and, and fundamentally there's no easy answers to this.
The best we've done is, you know, the whole ca
thing.
-- Ok.
-- But here's the thing we're back to the discussion from the very beginning is,
yes, this all sucks. But it basically works.
I mean, it's not so bad that society can't function
and because of that, it is good enough and nothing drastic is going to change.
Like that's the reality of it.
Yeah. No, I mean, I just ran into, uh fedex.com. The secure website has a,
uh,
it has the certificate for WW
uh, www.fedex.com,
-- but
-- not just fedex.com.
Exactly.
So, fundamentally,
yes, classically that's a se
like that's an operational security error, you know,
but realistically who cares?
This is why they should just get AAA cert for star.fedex.com, right?
-- Just put that thing on everything
-- I
-- was
-- thinking maybe they don't
uh maybe they're worried about clients that don't have SN I support, you know,
server name, identification support.
So like literally the people running windows XP still because they're still there,
face it, there's still grandmas
and
well, I mean, I just had that experience last week of I um my computer,
the little office 365 update popped up, which I've seen before.
But this time I actually looked at the numbers, like, for each update size
and it was over 900 megabytes.
That's awesome.
Right. And that happens about once every month or two.
So, like, you know, yeah, I live in North America.
I have a couple of, you know, high speed internet connections, but
not all the world has that.
Right.
Well, I mean, even think about updating any operating system,
be it Linux or Os X or Windows.
It's, those updates are hundreds of megabytes.
Yeah. I don't know.
I,
I suspect people will fix these things but it'll be fixed
in a way that doesn't even look like a solution.
-- It'll be, you know, like we fix the horse boot problem by inventing cars.
-- Right.
Right.
I, I do love, there is a futurist who made a comment about
the,
the problem with New York City's growth will be where to put all the horse manure.
Yeah. Good job, buddy.
You got that one. Right.
Yeah.
Well, that's what I,
that's one thing I'm really curious to see how augmented
reality and virtual reality changes the world because I,
I, you know,
I would have never guessed smartphones would have
resulted in so much texting and driving.
Uh, yeah, I guess that's one of the negative downsides of it, but at the same time, so,
so, actually I'm, I'm, I'm going on an airplane soon
and
for some reason,
I can't use my phone for the ticket and I had to print off paper tickets
and I feel like a cave person now. Right?
I haven't used a paper ticket in, in like five years.
Yeah.
And you think smartphones have literally existed for what, 10 years at this point?
-- Ok.
-- 11 years. That's insane.
The difference it has made in, in just the state of humanity in 11 years.
Well, you know, I was talking with my parents about this and pointing out that like,
I don't
have to worry about not knowing something ever because by definition,
if I can't find it in Google in 30 seconds,
nobody knows the answer. Yes.
And,
and part of me is sad by that because I remember staying
up very late drinking beer with friends and arguing about the dumbest things
and, and the next day, we didn't even remember what we were arguing about.
But, but now when we talk and someone asks a question,
we just look it up in Google and then that's all.
Yeah, I, I, yeah, it's, yeah. No, the world has definitely changed and,
yeah.
Well, yeah, I mean, the security, there was a,
there was actually a good article this week about hacking power grids and why
it's actually quite difficult to accomplish something
like an actual shutdown of the grid.
Um,
and I suspect part of that too is a lot of these systems. The security of them is
partly just due to their obscurity and, and painfulness.
I,
I would bet it's not unlike the election system where every power plant
-- and every power station is running a different version of software or
-- maybe
in your country.
Ok.
Maybe. But
in Canada we have a federal election board. That's,
00, you mean for the elections? Right? And you guys use
federal elections. We have one standard
provincially and citywide.
Of course,
-- then there's all sorts of different standards
-- and
tell me about your power grid though.
Is your power grid?
Well, basically they were pointing out that to break into a power grid is, you know,
that's step one.
But actually,
you know, if you turn this breaker off. Ok. Yeah, that turns something off.
But does it
actually like, is it difficult to turn back on, is it break something, you know,
to actually do something to the power grid
that results in significant damage or an actual,
like widespread outage
is quite difficult?
I, I totally believe that, I bet you would have to take over a lot of the power grid.
Although, although
I know there are places with huge control centers for the power grid
in the locality.
And so if you could take over one of those, you could probably do some damage.
Well, there was the case of it was a Belgian nuclear power plant
and they basically managed to drain all the oil
from the turbines and so the turbines wrecked themselves.
Right. And those things are not cheap.
Right. Well, in, in any time the word nuclear is in the name,
you know, it's going to be sensational,
whatever gets talked about.
Uh,
oh, they've actually
charged some people with this now. Interesting.
-- What, what country are they from?
-- This is in Belgium. Uh,
the
what?
Oh, interesting.
Anyways. Um, yeah. So it's,
you know, that's a case of where, yeah,
you take all the lubricating oil out of something that spins at high, high speed,
you're gonna have a bad day.
Um, but again, those things, you know,
are not super easy to do
or
ideally they're also relatively easy to prevent and fix.
Right.
Well, not only that,
so they did this in Belgium and I assume the country of Belgium still has power.
Right.
And, and so
how, how do you do this in a way
that is
irreparably dangerous
to, or, or, I guess off putting to the country,
right.
It's,
yeah,
I guess at the same time this is not unlike
the internet
where we talk about how terrible security is
and how everything's going to light on fire.
But the reality is, I bet, I bet shutting down the internet these days,
I bet it would not be a simple task and, and please do not take that as a challenge.
Anyone listening.
Well, and something to remember too is the internet is, it's not just the internet.
Right? It's a network of networks,
right.
You know,
so you could shut down the internet.
But,
I mean, I'm assuming tell us would still be up and running and that would basically,
you'd have
-- a Canadian internet.
-- Let's face it. If you, if you could shut down Google,
I, I think that would count as
-- on the internet for the vast majority of people.
-- Well, here's a thought exercise.
Remember the D
OS attacks on D DNS that caused all sorts of problems.
-- They were the, the DNS for a lot of service.
-- That was what Mira
Botnet, right.
And that was used
to attack. Was it Krebs or something?
Yeah. Yeah.
Um, but I mean, what would, like,
what would be the maximal damage taking out the root name servers?
Um, I guess you could maybe hose, routing tables,
routing tables would definitely be a pain in the butt.
Yeah. B GP is relatively unguarded but even then
people would figure out quickly that the B GP tables are whack and they should just
turn off B GP route updates and that would probably take care of some of that.
Yeah,
it would be, it would be hard.
I mean, like, even the root name servers, which I think would be
the most
heavily
through any cast.
-- So they are good
-- luck.
Yeah.
The only thing I can and, like, you think about, like,
let's say Google or Amazon or something.
I mean, I remember when people tried to
DDOS Amazon
and they couldn't
because, and that was what, 5,
10 years ago before Amazon was near as big as they are now.
And, I mean, I, I bet you couldn't DDOS
Amazon if you wanted to,
-- unless you used Amazon. Right. To d
-- do
you have to, well, you'd have to be clever about it.
It couldn't just like sin flood them into submission
like you could back in the old days,
-- you know?
-- Right. Right.
But yeah, or you'd have to do some, like, clever high level attack,
like some sort of api that,
uh, you know, like the airline seat attack, right.
Where, you know, you can, you can easily doss a lot of, uh,
travel sites by reserving airline seats. Right.
And it, it reserves them for 10 or 15 minutes at a time.
You know, if you do this repeatedly and whatnot, then you can really
kind of make things annoying.
Um,
I've just had the experience of trying to
buy tickets online for an event through Ticketmaster.
And, yeah, I, I got quite grumpy at one point and thought about, like, writing a bot
to basically go reserve a big pile of seats so I can actually compare them. All
right.
-- That doesn't sound illegal in any way.
-- No.
Well, and then the US, you guys have that new act that was passed or is passing,
that makes it illegal to use bots to buy tickets online.
But I'm sure that's going to stop people. Right.
Everyone knows that once you pass a law, the problem is fixed.
Right? So,
yeah, I don't know. I think part of it, well, and
there are things like Puerto Rico, right?
You have a hurricane that just clobbers the place,
you know, but of course,
at that scale now we're literally talking about
like acts of God and natural disasters.
Right. Right. Right.
And, and
-- you can't plan for that level of devastation,
-- not, not reasonably like, I mean,
the cost involved is,
you know, it always struck me as like nuclear defense.
It was like, I don't think this is going to work
or
we're gonna find out,
but hopefully we never do. Right.
No, II, I get what you're saying. I, I totally get what you're saying and
I, I don't know where we draw the line,
but I feel like the vast majority of systems that exist,
have drawn the line appropriately because things are still essentially working
-- and at the same
-- time, well, in effect, the market has spoken,
-- I don't even know if I maybe to the
-- market by the market,
I don't mean just the people using it but the Attackers, right,
the Attackers aren't willing to put in the money to do this because
there's, I guess no,
-- there's not enough gain.
-- That's exactly right.
And, and I think you could look at something like the, the power power grid in the US.
What would the return on investment be?
I mean, how many organizations would be willing to go through that?
And what would they gain from it? And my suspicion is,
let's say a country attacks it and they shut it down for a day.
Like
what is that going to accomplish? Right.
No, it's
the whole thing. Just I, yeah, I, I fear that good enough is good enough and that
good enough
is good enough and it's always going to be good enough and,
and, and the question is really going to come down to
not, not kind of, when do we fix this, but you know, what is the,
what is the change that's coming?
And it's almost certainly not going to be driven
by security because security is kind of a,
a second order feature of, of the vast majority of systems.
Right.
It's, yeah.
Well, yeah,
very few systems are designed with security being an actual requirement upfront.
Other than the vague nebulous, we want it to be secure
features tend to trump
everything
and
let's face it. Right. Working code. Is kind of important.
Yeah.
And you can very easily have working code that's really insecure as well.
We found out over the last 4050 years of computing.
Yeah.
-- No, I, I know, man. I know.
-- So anything else crazy good happened this week
that we missed.
Uh I think my favorite thing is the iphone U I trick of the login from Apple.
Yeah.
Yeah, I, I will definitely say I've,
I've actually had my phone prompt me once or twice unexpectedly for my password.
And I was kind of like
being, you know, a completely crazy security person.
I actually was like, what, you know what's going on, right.
Um, normal people don't do that.
No, no, they just type in their password.
Well, I don't know how the iphone is but I know in OS X,
I feel like Apple asks me for my icloud password way too much.
So I just avoid all icloud stuff because it annoys me.
I, I get asked at set up time, but that's about it. I
get
all the time
and maybe I'm just a weirdo and maybe I'm doing dumb things. I don't care.
But
it,
it's one of those things you should get asked the password once and never again.
And if people see a password prompt, they should know something strange is going on.
And I feel like this, actually, this is one of the things that irks me is with gmail.
Gmail will,
you know, every 30 days or something,
log me out and every time that happens when I see the,
the window with the Gmail password prompt, I close that tab,
I open a new tab and I type in the Gmail
address just to make sure it's not a phishing attempt.
Yeah.
Well, and that would be one really good argument for, um,
two factor authentication, you know, or, or for example, the, uh,
with the Mac you can have, I think you can set it up so the watch will log you in.
-- I don't know if that'll work with your icloud
-- though. I don't know.
I don't care either.
I'm
not.
-- Well,
-- so, ok. Well, I don't know if we have time for this, but
so there's been apparently a bunch of proposals
to fix social security numbers in the US.
They're all crap and, you know, it,
well,
I, I feel like there's two big problems. Number one,
you have to get over the hurdle of replacing social security numbers, which,
you know,
how many tens of billions of dollars have been
-- invested in those numbers in software and
-- whatnot.
Just a regular expression. I'm sure it's fine.
Yeah, easy peasy.
Um, and then the second problem is coming up with something that
actually makes it better.
And so the, the one thing I keep seeing come up is, you know, public,
private key pairs, blah, blah, blah, which is, yeah,
in some ways would be better. But here's the problem,
the failure scenario for account recovery. Right.
People lose their ID and their wallets and all their
crap all the time or they get stolen or whatever.
So, how do you have a secure account recovery process?
You don't, and, and look, I'm, I'm gonna call it is I will bet you a beer,
nothing changes
because it's not bad.
That's a sucker bet. I mean, clearly,
even if it was on fire, even the effort of, you know, it's like the, for example,
the thought of changing from 10 digit phone numbers
to say 11 digit phone numbers in North America,
-- like, just, are
-- they 10 digits? Yeah, they are 10 digits, aren't they?
Yeah, that, that will not happen.
I don't even know. Right. I haven't typed that phone number in
-- forever,
-- but that's the thing. Right.
Like when, you know, people talk about changing phone numbers to make them longer,
it's kind of like,
-- no, that's really not an option. Just give
-- the US another country code. Right.
That would be way easier.
-- Yeah, I guess that would be one way to
-- do. That would be the only way to do it because
like,
I can't even think the number of places where social
security or insurance numbers in Canada are used is,
you know, it's staggering and, yeah,
the thought of getting everybody on board to actually change it.
I mean, look at no offense but the US with Chip and pin,
-- I mean, come on, we don't
-- have chip and pin, we have chip and inside, which is
dumb.
Ok.
Yeah, that basically proves my point.
If you guys can't do Chip and Pin.
-- How on earth are you going to roll out smart cards for everything?
-- I agree.
I agree completely. That, that's the perfect analogy right there.
You, you summed it up
and there's actually a legitimate, like,
good economic reasons to go to chip and pin, you know.
Um, although personally I, I prefer, uh,
whatever you call it tap and pay or whatever because like,
I don't have to touch things like a filthy caveman.
And I actually get really annoyed. Now when I have to punch in my PIN number,
I, I just wish I could get annoyed to punch in my PIN number.
It,
it makes me sad that I'm going to Europe soon
and I will have to apologize to the poor people working the cash register
as to why a receipt is gonna come out that I have to sign
because just like, I'm sorry, I apologize for my country
anyway.
But no, I think, I think that is actually the perfect analogy.
Once you guys get Chip and Pin working, maybe we can talk about
something.
So never. The answer is never.
Oh
my goodness. I,
anyway.
Right. So as the world continues to burn, do you, do you have any parting thoughts?
Horus Kurt,
maybe slow down once in a while and eat a nicely toasted bagel.
Yeah. You know, I used to do that every day and now, uh,
eating carbs in the morning gives me heartburn because I'm an old man.
It's, it's terrible. It annoys me. I love bagels so
good.
Actually, you know, we should,
we should do a show on getting old with technology because we're hitting that point.
Yes, we are
because I literally, for example, I've stopped keeping up with Minecraft.
They've made so many changes now to the game in the last three months.
It's better than ever. Well, some things are better,
but it's,
I, I don't understand like
the whole enchanting system properly.
-- I mean, I think I understand it but I probably don't, I
-- just don't,
I enchant as if I'm a cave person.
I,
I always have though,
if I put the things I need to in the enchanting table and then
I just take what's out and I know there's ways to influence that,
but I just don't care.
For example, my son showed me how you can make secret doorways with paintings.
Uh
Yes, that's new because paintings are,
-- are they were added not too long ago
-- actually.
No, we had paintings in Minecraft P for pocket edition. Did
you
about a year or two?
But now instead of just putting them on the wall, apparently,
you can do some funkiness with the door
to make them like a secret wall like you can walk through.
I've seen that.
Yeah. I, yeah. Again. Yeah. No, I'm getting old because, I don't know,
just getting old. I mean, part of it as well is the fact that, like, you have a job,
you don't have time to watch youtube all day to learn the new things in Minecraft
and don't get me wrong.
I wish my day was playing Minecraft. But it's not.
But I think we should do a show on that because I,
I suspect a lot of our viewers would sympathize.
-- Uh
-- It could be amusing if,
if nothing else and then I could complain about how my back hurts.
It would be great.
All right. Anyway, anyway. All right, thanks, Kurt. It was fun.
Thank you everyone for listening.
If you want any of the show notes for the things we talked about,
you can go to open source security podcast.com
and there you will find a link to a Facebook group.
You can hit us up on Twitter with the Pound Os S Podcast. Hashtag
And yeah, if nothing else, I guess Kurt,
you have a great rest of your day and I'll talk to you soon.
-- All right.
-- Thanks, folks.