Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siegfried
and my partner and getting older and occasionally sicker. Josh Bresser.
How many times have you started the show like that?
I suspect it's more than 10 at this point.
Like everyone knows we're old, we know we're old.
It's like three or four times a year. Usually about this time
when all the bugs are going around.
That's true.
You know, the sickness is going around,
which is actually directly that time of year
related to what we're going to talk about,
which is
things need maintenance and especially things connected to
the internet need to sort of be maintained.
I don't know if I would bucket like that. So the, the topic of the day,
Kurt found a hacker news discussion where someone said Kubernetes needs an LTs,
a long term support version,
which they apparently don't have.
I honestly don't track Kubernetes releases very much
because I just run whatever I'm handed.
But the idea being
Kubernetes is an open source project
and people are saying it needs
longer term support versus more bleeding edge,
which is how it works today where it's just kind of like YOLO
if you're, if you're trying to keep up. Right.
-- Yeah,
-- it looks like they're given about a year.
Ish.
That's not,
no, not a year. Sorry. Sorry.
Uh, this is weird. This is gonna, ok, so 126,
latest release was 2023. 1114, end of life is 2024 02.
So February, but when was the first release of 126?
Um, it looks to be about a year
ish.
-- Yeah,
-- but I bet you can't stay on like a version of 126 from a long time ago.
-- You need to keep up with the minor versions,
-- right?
Well, yeah. Yeah. Yeah. But in theory, the minor versions are safe to keep up with.
Right? That's
well and again, see and that's the beauty of this, right? Like again, OK.
So let's let's spherical cow the world a little bit
just to simplify things because otherwise we're gonna rattle.
So we're gonna go unlike us. Yeah.
So there's this idea of um
I'm spa,
you know what is Xyz versioning called again? Semantic versioning. Semantic.
Sorry,
I was just reading the thing about a guy
wrote a good article about pragmatic versioning anyway.
So semantic semantic versioning is XYZ and basically the promise is X
makes breaking changes.
Like if you go from 1 to 2,
we're gonna make breaking changes and give you cool new stuff
and, and possibly also get rid of stuff that you really need quite, quite likely.
Yes. Why so
dot Like 1.2 or 1.3 is like,
we are going to,
we're committing to supporting what we have
and
we might add new stuff moving forwards that
you have to do something to take advantage of
in the sense of like, if you don't change your configuration, it might break. Yep.
Yep. Right.
But nothing is going away
in theory. That's right. That's right.
And then there's the, the Z which is like, so 1.2 0.01 0.2 0.11 0.2 0.2 1.2 0.4006.
And the idea there is is that we're not making any breaking changes.
Like it's, it's air quotes safe to go from 1.2 0.3 to 1.2 0.4. And
basically, if you find a bug then
that needs to be fixed, that's an incompatibility.
Whereas if we go from like 1 to 2 and you're like,
it doesn't talk to this anymore. It's like, yeah. Well,
yeah, good luck with that. Go fix it.
That's right.
And the challenge, of course, like there's a, there's a lot of big issues,
but I'm just going to throw a few of the big ones out here first is
number one,
people forget that most people don't want software,
they want a solution for
sure.
Right. Exactly.
And that's the first thing that always blows my mind where, like like,
I don't want to maintain my light bulbs.
I'm buying light bulbs so I can have light
because I like maintaining software on light bulbs.
That's right. That's right. Same thing with my Wi Fi. I, I finally,
you know, I, I went and bought,
I think it's
Dlin,
-- you don't know. And it doesn't matter. I think
-- it's delink.
I enabled automatic updates.
I changed the time,
the automatic updates happened because that was a fun thing to find out
where I would just like,
I would be like working at 11 o'clock and my whole internet would like just
poo itself for 15 minutes.
Awesome.
So change that to like 3 a.m.
and like, I just, I want like, like that the washer by me has software on it,
but it's not internet connected.
So don't care.
Now if it was internet connected,
the manufacturer is going to want to make me update it and
turn that off. I don't.
Yeah, like it's like the I have two TV s that are quote unquote smart TV. S
they are not connected to the Wi Fi or anything. They are.
-- It's
-- like anyway, versioning, we're talking about versioning in LTs.
So the versioning well, but this is implicit to
sometimes I want
software that is updated and has new features
-- and sometimes I don't, I just want a solution. I,
-- I think, I think you're too simple.
I think in the context of Kubernetes,
Kubernetes is a giant monolithic monster,
right? Where you need a team of people, often to actually run and maintain
-- Kubernetes
-- or you need to
buy something like openshift,
which is Kubernetes under the hood with like a layer of stuff on top of it to
-- make it more usable in a
-- little bit, a little bit.
So
let's say I want to run Kubernetes.
This is true of like operating systems, right? Where
I, and let's just pretend Kubernetes is an operating system because I think it's,
I mean, I, I won't argue with that.
It's not,
it's a runtime environment anyway.
So
I
have,
know. Right. Exactly.
I have Kubernetes
and
and I deploy Kubernetes
and now I need to make sure that
it's working so other people can use Kubernetes to do the things they need to do.
Because fundamentally Kubernetes by itself is a useless application.
We need to run things on it
for.
Yes, I mean that operating system is a great example, right?
An operating system doing nothing is a paperweight. Who cares?
So I've got Kubernetes,
I install a version of Kubernetes and now I have to care and feed it right,
and
upgrading Kubernetes.
Why do we have to care and feed it?
No, seriously,
let's examine this assumption because this is kind of a big assumption
because I, I'm not carrying and feeding the software in my, my washer back there,
right? Because no one's using that.
Not like you would Ker
-- Neti,
-- I use that washer every day.
No, no, no. You misunderstand me
when I say care and feeding,
you have to do things like, make sure there's enough disk,
make sure there's enough nodes in my cluster.
-- Make sure I don't have pods or containers. I have to put soap
-- in that damn thing.
Right. That's using it.
OK?
But
-- I, I don't think this is a valid analogy and I think you're mudding the waters.
-- Ok.
Well, the Washington, but in general I'm, I'm gonna say,
but
I'm paying you to care and feed Kubernetes Kurt.
If you don't, I'm going to fire you and hire someone who actually does that job.
I think you misunderstand the question I'm saying,
why do we have to care and feed it and you're pointing out?
Right? Because for example, the disc fill up, right?
Like, unless people are, you know,
unless we have some job running automatically that nukes stuff,
which that's not going to be awesome either or for example, my favorite is, you know,
it's a useful solution. So more people want to use it.
And so you go from 100 users to 200 users and then they all complain it slow.
Well, yes, that's how it works when we go from 100 users to 200 users.
Like I need more budget for ra M and disk and CPU.
There's many things, a lot of, I find a lot of times people assume thing.
I'm just, I want to be clear on this, like
there are some good reasons as to why you have to maintain it.
And sometimes those reasons are things like we want
the machine to do twice as much work.
So, yeah, you're gonna have to change the oil twice as often
or
put in twice as much memory.
Right. Right.
Now, I am maintaining
Kernes. I have to install security updates. Occasionally.
There might be bug fixes I need,
there can be whatever reasons. Right.
And I'm gonna want to do as little work as possible
on operations that could potentially disrupt
the uptime of Mike
Kubernetes instance. Right.
I don't think anyone would argue with that.
And now what happens in, in things like the open source world,
it's very common for software to move very quickly.
And so it's conceivable you'll have a major version update once or twice a year.
Now,
if I'm operating something like Kubernetes and let's
say there's a version update that's downtime.
Right. That's not going to be a seamless magic upgrade.
I'm going to have to either stand up a new Kubernetes cluster
and migrate into it or
I'm gonna have to shut down the one I have do my work and then start it back up.
Well, and I think going back a step, it's worse than that.
It's an unknown amount of risk.
That's true too. Right. Like it's, it might be a really easy, quick update
and it might literally catch fire and the update breaks your server because reme
like we've seen that happen where software updates, you know,
don't install that redhead update on your Dells because um
-- it breaks your server.
-- Like I remember when I was a Cis
Edmund,
we would plan for major upgrades to infrastructure
and it would be like, we're going to start this Friday night,
we have all weekend to do it.
And sometimes by like 10 pm,
we were at the pub hanging out and sometimes by like 10 am Sunday, it's like, dear God,
please let this work.
I want to go home, you know,
and that is how it happened.
You never really knew if it was going to go well or going to go horribly,
horribly wrong.
And I mean, unless you have
budget to have like a double it infrastructure and have like
broad and a full working copy of tests that you can like
update and install and then cut over. But
realistically,
well, I was about to say, first of all, realistically, nobody has that
because you can,
you can't do that for like a network
like a major network. Sure, you
can
ask your boss to be like, hey, I,
you know, our network budget for last year, I would like to double that, please. Why,
you know, just to make upgrades easier.
Oh, no, you won't. Ok,
-- good
-- luck. And I think this is one of the reasons Cloud started to take off. Right.
Because that on demand,
it's like I can actually do this and stand it up for a few 1000 bucks.
But anyway,
back to this.
So, so the part of the problem is,
is there's this huge unknown risk and then the thing you forget too is
it's not like you upgrade it and all the problems show up right away.
Oh,
right. Yeah, for sure.
Because then you run your quarterly report and
the numbers are off
are the numbers off. They look weird. I'm not sure. What do we have a bad quarter?
Were they wrong before? Right.
So anyway, let's sum it all up. Ok.
-- And then we'll go on,
-- I want to say one important thing though
and something a lot of people forget
developers are almost never operational people despite the whole dese
ops thing. But I guarantee you, I'm gonna say something kind of mean
because I've had this experience at Red Hat,
the vast majority of developers working on software that runs at scale.
They have never run it at scale or even beyond
one or two systems. And even if they have run a test
like, oh we ran it on 1000 systems.
They haven't been responsible for running 24 7 like and I'm
talking like getting woken up at 3 a.m. if it doesn't
work, right?
And so I've literally had the case where the developer like, oh,
it works for me and I'm like, Well,
what about when the use case of 100,000 servers hit it?
And he's like, oh, that would probably be slow. And I'm like, that's the whole point.
It works fine on a thinkpad laptop.
That was actually word for word what he said.
I'm not surprised.
And I was like the use case for this product.
This is why we sell this product because 100,000 clients like
hit the server.
So let's let's bring it all together now, right?
You've got
an application,
you've got someone managing the application,
be it developers or operations or whoever, right, then
you have the forward march of time
and
a every application is going to see updates of some manner
and you have to decide when you are
going to install those updates in your infrastructure right
now.
Things like Kubernetes move very quickly.
A lot of applications now move very quickly because we're all like agile and DEV
ops and whatever
I have to make decisions about when I'm going to do my updates.
And if the application in question, especially an open source application
doesn't necessarily care about saying we're
going to support this particular version for
10 years or 20 years or whatever and they're like whatever YOLO,
we're just gonna steam right ahead and when we break things,
we just change the major version and you're going to deal with it and that's life.
So what's happening
is it is not an unreasonable, ask for someone to say,
wouldn't it be swell if there is a version of
Kernes that was supported for five years or 10
years or some relatively long amount of time,
right?
The fact is there is,
I know it's just not available as software, it's available as a service.
Well, not just that, I mean,
this is where you can do things like pay a company like Red Hat for openshift and,
and they maintain that for a long time.
-- Well,
-- they abstract it away.
They basically say we will give you this
nice openshift interface and under the hood,
sometimes it's going to be maintained, sometimes we're going to upgrade it,
but you're not going to have to worry.
Yeah, we're
taking care
of the last
day.
And this is the part where this goes back to
people want solutions
that are free because duh like for sure, for sure.
But that's just
the, the open source community can't always give you your free solution, right?
-- I mean,
-- look at the Linux kernel, right?
The Linux kernel used to have their long term support stream and
-- yeah,
-- and it turns out nobody was using them. So they're like
they, they got rid of.
Actually, I bet, I bet a lot of people were using it,
but no one wanted to work on it because it's, it's terrible.
Well, also nobody, well, more importantly, nobody wanted to pay for it.
That's probably fair, right? People pay Red Hat all the time.
But you're also, here's the thing
when you work with someone like Red Hat or really
any sort of large vendor that does a good job.
I don't say any vendor because there's a lot of bad vendors. But
like when you work with Red Hat,
you're not paying for Linux, you're paying for an experience.
Right.
They're giving you someone to call, they're giving you someone to blame,
they're giving you someone to talk to.
They're telling you
we're going to make sure this works for 10 years come hell or high water,
we're gonna make it happen
and then they employ people to
move mountains and, and work miracles sometimes to make this stuff work.
I mean, we were there, we saw behind the curtain like it's,
it's not always fun.
Yeah, it's not always fun, but we got it done, you know,
and, and that's, that's the whole thing.
And I think that's where when I'm a developer
working on an open source project like Kubernetes,
I'm not giving people an experience.
I'm doing something probably for someone else solving their problem, right?
It's a very different dynamic.
And so I think expecting open source or even asking
a lot of open source projects for long term support is
well outside of this
-- universe or even caring quite often,
-- I'm just going to go back to the market,
but the market has spoken here.
If somebody really, wow, this is fun. I want to do this,
it would be done
and it's not, it's absolutely not fun and amazing and exciting work.
So people don't want to do it.
And I, again, I get it, I get that you want your solution,
you want to turn your light bulbs on and just have them work.
You want to have your Kubernetes cluster and just have the darn thing work.
Your light bulbs are a perfect example.
Remember like you've been, what, two or three years now?
I think you had those horrible cheap
-- crap light bulbs
-- from Costco, those that were on the Wi Fi and they, they just,
if you turn them off and on a few,
too many times they would like reset and start blinking and just,
and,
and you ponied up and you paid Phillips for
bulbs that are probably 10 times as expensive,
but also just work.
I'm in the same boat. I paid Phillips a long time ago.
I pay an ungodly amount of money for a light bulb,
but it does exactly what I want it to do and it does it for 10 years.
-- So
-- great.
But so what's fascinating to me is
what gets me is I think a lot of the people asking for these LTs solutions
haven't really examined what they want.
I, I feel like a lot of them are stuck in this trap of, I, I need this solution.
I need to be stable. I need it to be boring
and they're Yeah, boring is great.
And they're, but then they're like, oh,
that means running it myself and doing it myself.
And sometimes if you want something stable and boring,
-- you outsource it to an expert at that
-- sometimes for sure.
I pay Epcor for my electricity. Could I have a generator on site?
Yeah, I looked at even having a whole home generator as a backup.
But then I'm like, oh, the power only cuts out like twice a year for 10 minutes.
So like,
right, like who cares?
And now, especially now, you know, I live in a neighborhood with underground lines.
It's super duper reliable.
I just feel like a lot of people are caught in
the trap of doing things the old way and doing it.
Like
let's dig harder faster
and the solution might be a bulldozer or the solution might be
like, we don't even need to dig this hole.
Maybe we just like send the package by airplane.
Like, you know what I'm saying? They leap frog to some other thing.
I've seen this happen where,
you know, people get stuck in these,
I have to incrementally fix this problem
and they don't step back and say what, what is the whole point of this?
And I feel like a lot of this LTs stuff,
maybe you don't need to run a full Linux kernel with a network ST
stack on this device if you truly want to.
Like there was this um discussion for, uh,
Linux kernel support for 50 or 100 year
old devices for pipelines and for things that,
like get thrown into the ocean at the bottom of the ocean and can't be serviced.
Right. That's right.
You know, not reasonably.
And look.
So here's, here's, I think the, the other end of the conversation, right is,
so
the hacker news thread goes to, it's, I think it's just a blog post article,
whatever doesn't matter.
And at the end,
this person talks about the
Kubernetes apparently had an LTs working group which is being
resurrected now.
And like this is a cool example of where open source if people actually want this
and they're willing to basically pay for it because you're
gonna have to send people to the LTs group.
It can happen,
but
it's not going to be easy and it's not going to be cheap
because you're gonna have to find people and basically pay them like that.
You're going to turn money into suffering is what an LTs program is.
Well, and I love the spherical cow world.
So I'm going to read straight from the blog posting.
I really hope the team seriously consider something like this.
It would be a massive benefit to operators of Kate Kernes
around the world to not have to be
in a state of constantly upgrading existing clusters.
It would simplify the third party ecosystem as well allowing for easier validation
against a known stable target that will be around for a little while.
It also encourages better workflows from cluster operators,
pushing them towards the correct answer of getting in the habit of
making new clusters at regular intervals versus keeping clusters around forever.
Yeah.
In a perfect cer
world that would absolutely happen. So
who's going to pay for it?
Well, and that's the thing, right? I mean, that's basically
the foundation of open source, right?
Where
if
there, there is open source people will do for free because it's fun.
There's people,
it scratches my itch and it's not that hard and
it goes like, I'm sure that's how,
like, literally, that's how stuff like N map and curl and Nessus start is like, I
my itch a little and then it just sort of got out of control.
Right. Right.
And sometimes it catches on and like we, you know,
we talked to Daniel a while back and he's getting paid to work on curl now.
That's great.
It is a complicated and difficult thing and it's easy to just say, oh,
just throw money at it because it's not even that simple.
If you want Kubernetes LTs. At this point, you need to find Kubernetes developers
that you can pay
-- that are going to work on old dead end code
-- or maybe
you need to take a step back and even consider training people
-- like taking a long term investment.
-- I would argue that right.
But you need to find a way to send people because you can't just send money. Right.
Like
it,
-- it, it's a hilariously complicated problem.
-- That's the thing too. Right.
Is, this is not a fungible problem. This is actually a very
skilled artisanal problem.
-- Yeah,
-- that's true too. It's really hard to keep some of this old stuff alive.
This, well, this is like we need to renovate the Sistine Chapel.
You don't just put out a tender and take the lows bitter.
-- So
-- actually,
it's funny you mentioned that a better example is Notre Dame Cathedral, right?
It had a fire.
It had
enormous losses.
And I, I've been like,
I love watching documentaries on public television in the United States.
It's like,
probably I don't watch a lot of TV,
but I bet 90% of it is PBS documentaries that I do watch or,
and Star Trek is the other 10%.
But
when,
when I watch it, they,
they had this documentary about how they were restoring Notre Dame.
And
yeah, like they,
they found artisans that did woodworking literally in the style it
was built in from hundreds and hundreds of years ago using
on it like the same trees from the same forest that orig like this is
bananas.
Well, that's like my cousin in Germany,
he's a proper carpenter and he's trained in the old ways of making things.
And so
like
ignoring all the disease issues,
you could drop him off in 1600 Germany he could build a barn.
That sounds bizarre and wild to some of us. But there's obviously a demand for this.
We live in countries
that are younger than a lot of the housing infrastructure stock.
That's true. That's
-- like,
-- right. Like, well, you figure,
I live in a house that is 100 years old and in
North America that is incredibly old for a house in Europe.
That's probably
-- not
-- old at all. That's new info
from,
you know, the last, last war.
Right.
And I'll tell you now, like, owning 100 year old house,
don't ever buy 100 year old house.
It's a terrible decision.
I love every time somebody buys a building more than 50 years old.
And they're like, and then we found asbestos
-- and it's like,
-- yes, I did find,
I didn't find it. It was wide open in the basement.
I got it removed and then I also had the basement removed in the place.
But that's another story. But
all right, I'm like, how do you not think that was an outcome?
I totally knew there would be, I knew the wiring every,
whatever everything was old and shot and most of it's been replaced.
I have a lot less money than I would have
bought
that.
But
yeah,
but anyway,
I just want windows 11 to stay the way it is with no major
changes because I hate change.
And,
you know, like,
but at the same time I also get that Microsoft
wants to move forward and not support Windows 95 forever.
And, and look, this is,
this is always going to be the
yearly fee for it. So that's
Windows.
You have to just run Linux,
-- like as cool
-- people probably end up in a Mac world
again because like the thing is like, I used to
need a Windows machine because to get this much CPU and ra M in an affordable package,
couldn't do it in the Mac world, right.
That's
a
little better now. Well, the,
the like the M series chips are,
-- that's
-- what
-- I keep hearing.
I still haven't used an M whatever chip and they're on what M three now,
-- I think
-- I
-- have
-- an M one
that's now about 34 years old and it still feels fast. That's
-- cool.
-- That's nice and
like never felt fast even from day one.
-- Yeah, like
-- it's,
I can't even imagine going
anyway.
-- Anyway,
-- I
tell
you what happened. This is part of it is like just with the
Ker Netti, especially by definition, nobody wants to run Ker
Netti.
They want the capability that Cooper
Netti provides.
That's it
like.
And so,
and that's an important capability for most people because the
alternative is running like virtual machines or God forbid,
bare metal servers, which if you thought managing Cooper Nets was bad.
That's true.
Just wait till you have to manage a fleet of 1000 bare metal servers.
I mean, that's a really good point because
there are worse alternatives. It,
I hadn't even thought of it in that context.
But right, if we want to talk about like LTs, this is why Red Hat
is supporting Red Hat Enterprise Linux for like 10 years
because is it 13 now? It,
it's been 13 for a long while. Oh, has it? I, I don't even know
why.
And, and, and this is the thing I always bring up with people that forget about
Red Hat has to support software for 13 years with an A B I
and API compatibility promise
that they have
and will never see
internal software written at some company.
A
Red Hat.
And if it breaks they'll scream at Red Hat
and Red Hat's like, what on earth are you talking about? Right. And that's,
well, they'll, they'll help them fix it. This is part of the experience. Right.
Well, but that's my point is Red Hat.
Not only has to support the software for 13 years, but they have to support,
use cases and
stuff
that they haven't even seen.
I mean, that's how Kubernetes works like that too though.
Like, that's just software.
But I think a lot of people forget this because they go, oh, well,
you should use Red Hat this way and not do that with it.
And it's like that's not what the customers decide.
I mean,
but, but again, like in that context, right, the reason people pay them and they,
they need that level of support is because, like,
racking and stacking and reinstalling operating systems is very, very difficult.
It's,
I mean, if we think Kubernetes is a pain in the butt,
imagine having to go and find a computer in a rack with 100 computers in it.
Right. Like, pick out the right one.
Hope you didn't turn off the wrong computer, which we've all done more than once.
They have indicator lights on the front now, typically.
Well, yeah, they're always supposed to,
but it's still easy to grab the wrong one when there's the indicator lights broken.
You've got 100 computers that all look the same and they're all like, you know, what,
2.5 centimeters high,
one 0.75 inches.
Yeah.
Right. Right.
But, like,
that is obscenely difficult.
And that's why people want operating systems that last for decades.
And fun fact, the hyper scalars now, the majority of them, if a server has a problem,
they don't pull it and fix it anymore, they pull it
and sell it.
-- Will
-- they wait for the rack to be like, what, 20% dead before they even look at it.
Stuff like that.
-- But
-- somebody was horrified to find out that they're just,
like selling the stuff as waste.
And it's like, but like, at that scale you can't,
-- it's not worth fixing it. It's really hard
-- to
fix.
You would need the infrastructure equivalent to a small country.
-- To do this at that scale.
-- Yeah. And, and what's wrong with the computer?
Is it the ra M is it the disk? Is it the processor? Is it the motherboard?
It could be any one of a million things that it's going to take? Yeah.
-- And
-- can you trust to put it back into rotation?
No,
that's like, honestly. So, you know, that reminds me of as well.
I love watching people on youtube like fix old hardware and stuff
and I just keep thinking like I watched this one guy was fixing
like Nintendo switches and saying he's going to sell them on ebay.
And I'm thinking I would never buy a
Nintendo switch repaired by like some guy on, on youtube.
Maybe that solder joint with that new capacitor is perfect and will last 100 years.
I don't know. And maybe it's a dry solder joint and it's just
for sure if you ever flex the board, it's gonna crack and poop.
-- But anyway,
-- anyway,
so we're running ourselves out of time and we're supposed to be talking about LT
si feel like if I was gonna kind of sum all of this up,
right?
I think
asking an open source project to do LTs
is a foolish ask.
I think you either need to do it
or deal with what you've got or alternatively
find someone like Red Hat has openshift,
you've got Google has Gke Amazon, what is Amazon
Cooper
called
Elastic?
That's an eck,
I don't know what that stands for.
The K is probably
Kernes.
But anyway,
like,
I, I think
this is where you either need to fund it yourself and do
the work or you just find someone else to deal with,
like, the crap you don't want to deal with.
-- You
-- know,
I'm gonna summarize everything you said. Which is,
if you want a solution you're gonna have to pay for it.
-- I mean,
-- yeah, I agree. Yeah, I think that's, that's exactly what it is.
I think you're right. I think,
like, it's,
what is the old JWZ saying? Linux is only free if your time is worthless.
And I think, like,
Kubernetes is the same deal where you can pay someone to deal with the crap.
Like, you can pay a company to deal with the crap.
You can pay someone who works for you to deal with the crap
or
that's it. Like those are pretty much the
stuff, stuff that's broken once in a while and
it probably won't be broken once in a while. I think it'll be broken a lot.
Right. I mean,
I think that's,
that is one of the things that I find
most interesting and bizarre about open source is we've
come to expect all of this amazing technology for free and for the most part it is,
but it's not actually free. Right.
Like we're trading something for what we're doing.
It could be, we're paying developers, we're paying red hat like somebody. Right.
I mean, we're also sometimes
in the,
in the beautiful circumstance of like curl where there's enough
people who are willing to pay and pony up that
-- I can absolutely be a free rider. And that's
-- ok.
And I, I think that is the nature of society though. Right. Society is
riddled with people,
people, you know, expect the,
you know,
it's funny to me every time the cost of the road infrastructure in Edmonton comes up,
it's in the billions of dollars that we spend
this
massive
road network, right?
Because while we would like fire trucks to be able to
-- get cars if it's burning down or the Amazon delivery
-- person,
society relies on like infrastructure,
infrastructure
like,
-- and
-- we all
benefit from it and it just blows my mind when people are like, but I don't pay,
I don't want to pay for those roads because I don't use them.
And I'm like, do you eat food?
Oh, man, you know, I've got a really good example of this. So where I live,
we get our water from Lake Michigan because there's,
there's actually this amazing amount of
like law in everything like who can use water from Lake Michigan,
how the Great Lakes work it, whatever.
And
-- oh man,
-- water rights are one of those things that, that goes back a long time.
It's, it's pretty wild.
But anyway,
I live in a place that can draw the water directly from Lake
Michigan because we're part of the basin or whatever they call it.
And
when they switched from these wells that were high in radium, so,
like the water was literally radioactive and the water bills
like doubled because they were piping water from Lake Michigan,
like literally hundreds of miles to the city because you have to get it like way
in the middle of the lake and all this crap and whatever I get it.
Right. It's expensive and hard.
They increase the water bills and all these people were like, oh,
this is ridiculous.
It's like you need water to be in a functional society in the old
water was radioactive, like shut up. This is just how it works.
There's actually,
it's funny because this is one of the ongoing sagas in Canadian politics where
a lot of the indigenous communities don't have access to clean safe water.
They kind of point out that like if this happened in Toronto
it get fixed.
Right. Right.
For sure. There was a community that lost their water many a decade or two ago.
And the, the member of parliament,
that area literally wrote a long article pointing out that one of the quickest,
fastest ways to kill a community is not have clean water.
Oh, I have no doubt.
Yeah. Yeah, you need water. I mean,
like water, sewer roads, power, internet now.
Like these are,
I wouldn't move
-- without any of those, you know,
-- logistics. Like
when I hear these small towns in the middle
of nowhere complaining that people won't ship to them.
It's like, well,
yeah,
it's hard. But,
but the
post office,
I mean, but this is another good example of where
the post office of a country usually lose money because it's the same,
like if I mail a letter across the street or I mail it across the country,
I pay the same amount,
but it obviously doesn't cost the same amount
to move that letter to those two places.
Well, and that's the thing.
Historically,
the post office was also one of the things that drew the country together.
It helped glue the country together.
It's one of the things that defined you as a country as having a proper post office,
just like having a military or law enforcement or a judiciary system.
Now, here's how I wanna, here's how I'm gonna end this. This is my last word. I think
a lot of open source is becoming
infrastructure.
It
does, it
-- is,
-- it is infrastructure
and I think
it is
in a similar manner to how we fund
our infrastructure through taxes and other things.
I, I'm not saying we should be taxed, the open source tax or something.
But like, I think this is where,
like the governments of the world need to start recognizing that
this is infrastructure
and we can't just ignore it.
And I don't know what that looks like and I don't know what that means,
-- or
-- we ignore it and hope somebody else fixes it.
That's probably what's going to happen.
-- But, because
-- that has worked in the past for almost every other problem.
It, it often does until
it,
whatever lights on fire.
All right, I'm, I'm calling this one.
This is a wild man. I don't know.
-- Or
-- somebody sinks a barge full of oil next to your intake pipe.
It's fine.
Everything's fine.
I don't, I don't know. We'll see.
I, I, I'll be interested to see what this Kubernetes LTs working group does in,
in six months or a year.
I don't think it's gonna happen because it's,
it's the thing people forget is it's not a lot of work.
-- It's a lot of work on an ongoing basis forever.
-- Well, and that's just it. Right.
It's easy to start. It's hard to keep going
and that'll be the trick
like it's like getting six cats
right, start it now and talk to me in a year, right? Or five years. That'll be. Well,
that's true. Probably. I mean, five years is the true test. But
yeah, I get it. I get it. All right. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you for listening. Go
up social security podcast.com. Yup,
Podos
podcast. Hashtag I
Mastodon.
-- Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day. You too.
-- Thanks everybody. Thanks
everyone.
Bye bye.