Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
and my partner in Lightning Speed,
Josh Bresser.
So Kurt has some weird plan and I don't think it's going to
work just because history tells me if there's one thing we're good at,
it's getting off topic.
-- Uh
-- We still don't know that my Mars plan wouldn't work. No,
your,
the problem with your Mars plan wasn't whether it worked or not.
-- It made us all dumber. That was the fundamental problem, but
-- well rested,
whatever,
whatever I'm done with. No, I'm not.
No,
there's no,
-- nobody can hear you filling potholes
-- on Mars.
I don't have any good stories to tell right now. So we're just gonna jump right in.
So there was a tweet
that
made the rounds. Uh What was it? July 30th is the date
and it's very interesting because all it says is what's a concept in security
that is generally accepted as true, but is actually bullshit. And
there were some really good replies.
And so Kurt and I decided we're going to take the replies and work through them
and well, well, not all the replies.
There were a lot of replies,
like a lot of replies and I went through them all and picked up what, 10, I think,
or something on about 10.
And Kurt thinks he's going to keep us at three minutes per reply,
which we're already what a minute 20 into the podcast.
And so you'll have to subtract that from your, your list.
I'm sure, I'm sure we'll do this
anyway. Let's just jump right in, let's just jump right in.
Uh, the first one on my list
is, oh,
wait, play that noise again. That was very nice.
Uh, how do I rewind this?
You're wasting time.
Not now. There we go.
And is that, that's the go,
that's the boxing ring.
-- No, thank you, Kurt. Thank you. I
-- don't know, man.
Somebody's like, I live in Jersey City and I'm like, where is that?
And he's like, it's in New Jersey. I'm like, oh, ok, because
-- like, dude, there's an Edmonton in Kentucky. We're
-- already off topic. I'd love it,
you know,
I don't know where the hell they're probably a
Jersey City in California or Alaska or something.
-- Anyways, I bet
-- every state has a Jersey City
because Jersey was a location in England. But still,
I suppose,
I don't think the people of the island of
-- Jersey would like what you just
-- said is Jersey,
not in England.
Where's Jersey?
Jersey is an island
where south of, in the channel. It's one of the channel islands, like the Isle of man.
Ok.
Whatever.
Anyway,
sure.
Send your hm. To
let start.
This is what happen. This is why we can time ourselves.
Yeah. J
is an island.
It's the Bail
of Jersey. It's a crown dependency.
Cool. OK. II I actually didn't know that. I thought it was a city or something.
I'm, I'm
so I'll blame my American education.
Well, I mean, you haven't brought democracy to them. So how do you know where it is
anyway?
I'm going to start now with a tweet from Mark Lovelace. Simple nomad.
He was a guest on the show a long time ago
and his just says password. If they were secured, we wouldn't need a second factor.
Well, and that's the thing, even if you use a
like secure password stored in a secure password manager that will only
like you're still prone to fishing and stuff. There's, it's just too easy to misuse
and also passwords don't authenticate the server.
So if somebody hijacks the server, they can snarf your password.
And so then we end up with like things like
Kerberos which go, I mean,
go read the
Kerberos thought exercise of how to
create a password securely authenticating system.
And it's,
you know, it's, it's complicated.
So, yeah, no passwords on their own just aren't enough.
And so we need a second factor and more importantly, that second factor needs to be,
how do I put this nicely?
It needs to be something mediated by software that won't let the human do a bad thing.
-- The computer basically as it says,
-- no, I mean,
I think my argument is we shouldn't even have passwords.
It's not a matter of, of password. Plus second factor.
I think we, we, we're reaching a point where
just having that,
that kind of
magic second factor is,
is brilliant.
You know, because now you can use like just your phone or just your,
-- your U two F key
-- or whatever, just your phone, just your UTF key.
There's a lot of people in the world
that don't have that.
No, I know, I know.
I'm not saying it's coming soon,
-- but like it is Apple
-- and everybody's moving towards that
Fido slash apple pass key thing like that's
for the privileged of us. Yes, we will be able to get rid of most of our passwords.
Do single sign on
yada,
ya yada.
It'll be awesome.
I agree.
The problem is passwords are the lowest common
denominator and there's all that technical debt,
the size of Switzerland that is
passwords.
Absolutely. 100%. Alright.
Anyway, I don't think anyone's going to argue with this one to be honest and,
and if you want to argue, go argue with, with Mark and he'll destroy you.
Wow. That worked out well.
Even even with our pontificating,
you got three more seconds.
All right.
I did not know what really? That
-- next
-- round? Oh, it says ready. This is fantastic.
I love this. I'm sad. We don't have like a nice direct feed.
Anyway, the next one, a guy named Mark Manning
commit signing using G PG.
Yeah, I mean,
um
this is my favorite because
I it
commit signing,
commits with GP G does something but it doesn't do what everyone thinks it does.
The first reply to Mark says, how else are you supposed to verify a commit slash tag?
Actually came from a certain developer after it's been committed.
-- What
-- I'm not real clear on is what's the threat model where the attacker
can break into your
github or G
repo
but
not break into the developer's laptop in some way to sign that commit.
You know what I'm saying?
Like it's just if the attacker is that skilled,
chances are they can send up the the developer some PDF file that
right?
Well, no, no. OK. Look, there's, there's a different way to think of this.
So the way GIT works is you set your user name and email
in the client so I could set my user name and email to you
and then I could push a commit into a repo.
And basically anyone looking at that commit is going to believe it's you who did it?
Yeah, but that assumes that repo is essentially wide open for public,
right?
Exactly.
If your GIT repo is that wide open
get signing is not your problem.
That's
like GIT repos are locked, like have authentication basically.
So the attacker somehow
can break into the authentication but not, you know what I mean? Like it makes no
sense.
I think the more important part is
the GP G commit isn't. I think it's less about
provable identity because GP G doesn't really
even carry provable identity with it.
Actually fun fact.
Also this assumes they're storing their GP G key securely, which we don't know.
Well, yes
and no one does.
And, and the way github works as well is you add your GP G key into github
and then it can say like, oh, it'll give you a little check mark on the commit.
But if you ever remove that key, it takes all the check marks away.
And
if your key is ever needs to be revoked,
which like you and I revoked our GP G keys not too long ago,
like there's absolutely nothing
that you can do about that. And
github.
Well, and that's the problem is like if you have a repo that requires signed commits,
then what happens
because like one of the problems with signing stuff is like,
let's say you sign your email and then you revoke your key.
Well, that email at that time was signed correctly.
And depending on why you revoked your key,
like if you revoked your key because it was compromised,
maybe you should revoke the signature.
But if you revoked your key because it's like, hey, I'm done with this
and I'm burning it then,
then those emails are still signed.
That's right. But, but github doesn't deal with that correctly.
And so that's why the
correct way to deal with this. That's the problem.
-- There's different viewpoints.
-- Right.
That's fair. That's fair.
No, I agree. And I think this is one of those places that
like signing your commits is just a way to say that someone with this
-- key signs commit
-- and not even not a physical key but a software key.
And so I think maybe combining that with UB keys and like tokens might be better.
OK? Next one,
this is related, the next one comes from uh Richard Dick Brooks.
And it says people believing that a digital signature on a software package has
been applied by a software supplier and
guarantees the identity of the software supplier.
Well, I mean, as we've seen with Windows code signing certificates. Yeah, sure.
That's always true.
I mean, look, I bet you 99.9%
-- of digital signatures on software are part of an automated process
-- today.
So what they better be?
Yeah. Yeah, that's true.
This is what really makes me angry about it
isn't the whole point of it to automate stuff
with computers and software. Like
I'm
pretty sure this is what I was led to believe 20 some years ago.
Like a great example is my mother, she had to do a thesis and analyze a whole bunch of,
of data and basically the back of the envelope calculations were
4 to 5 years to do this on a mechanical calculator
or one or two years to learn how to program in FORTRAN. And then one year to
manipulate and analyze all the data and more likely have it done correctly.
Like this is back with punch cards, like you'd have a stack of punch cards you submit.
And so the point is like this digital signature thing.
Yeah, it bloody well, better be automated.
Well, the point is a digital signature again,
doesn't mean the software is necessarily trusted.
-- No, it means that that package was signed by that key.
-- That's right. That's right.
And
generally speaking, it can convey a certain amount of, of,
I guess trustworthiness, I would say trust specifically, but it,
-- it doesn't always the
-- one thing where digital signing really actually helps
was 20 years ago
when we didn't have reliable mirrors for software.
-- Uh
-- Yeah, I agree with that. That, that was a big deal
-- because
-- then I could download stuff from some random website and
be reasonably certain that it was indeed that Windows software package or
driver or Red Hat package or whatever that it claimed to be. Sure.
Sure. And, and even then it just means it came from Red Hat.
It doesn't mean there's any sort of trustworthiness
on everything prior to the signature being applied to the thing.
Red Hat put on a mirror.
Yep. Yep. This is
you. I love this one. Where people are like, oh, it's signed, it's fine. It's like,
maybe, maybe it's fine.
Well, and I would say kind of the converse is
if it's signed, it might be correct. And if it's not signed,
then it's probably a tire fire
in the sense of like, if this is a windows device driver, like
how many times have people, you know,
I've bought webcams where literally the instructions say go
to this IP address and grab this dot exe.
And I'm like, wow,
and I run through virus total and I'm the first one and I'm like, oh double, wow,
this is, you know,
this is good,
fine,
fine.
-- It's been running for a year. It's great.
-- Fine. Everything's fine. I know, I know.
Yeah,
whatever,
whatever. And, and now I will say though as well.
I think in the context of digital signatures,
I think let's encrypt and sync store are disruptive
forces in the industry and we're going to see real
good solutions come from those.
So the future does look nice.
-- They
-- acknowledge how reality actually works.
Absolutely.
All right. The next one comes from the Twitter name is unpronounceable.
It's imbeciles
Rex is their Twitter ID.
And it says humans are the weak link in any secure system.
No, they're one of the weak links.
Well, ok.
And
actually the first reply to this says, I blame Kevin Mitnick for that.
Here is here is the way I like to think about this.
Humans are predictably unpredictable
in all ways. And I think we have built
the vast majority of our it and security
pretending humans are predictable in predictable ways.
Well, back to the whole, you know, humans are rational economic actors.
No, no, they're really not as it turns out.
That's right.
And, and I mean, this is like this,
the fishing's on here as well, but it's kind of the similar thing of like,
if typical human behavior results in a failure of your system,
the problem isn't the people, like, you've architected a crappy system.
This is why when you look at things like
-- safety systems in industrial complexes and you look at
-- even in your
car, at cars.
Exactly.
And,
and even like kitchen utensils and our electrical systems and plumbing systems,
they are engineered in a way that accounts for
what I, I think we would just call human stupidity.
Well, not even stupidity, but like,
there are so many things for which I don't know how to safely, truly,
safely operate XY or Z.
-- But
-- even the things you do,
I took the safety guard off my table saw because I don't like it.
I know it should be there. I don't want it.
I took mine off too and I use the little hockey stick pusher.
But a perfect example is, you know, I have my little outdoor pool, a little 12 ft guy
and I have three sets of the solar heating panels
and three S pumps to push water through them.
And one day the GFC starts tripping. And so I'm like, ok. Well, that's not good.
I reset it, trips, reset it, trips, turn off the pumps, just reset it,
-- just tape it
-- down.
It'll be fine,
pretty much.
And so one of the,
one of the sump pumps had some electrical fault that tripped the GFC I, and I'm like,
I'm so glad I spent that 200 bucks on that GFC I breaker
because otherwise me and the kids would have gotten in the pool and died.
Safety systems have to ideally be passive and built in and,
and software and these complex systems move too fast.
-- Like, look at the rate of change in Cooper Neti or Aws or something. And it's
-- crazy.
I think that's an excuse. I think it's because we don't build
any sort of protections in generally speaking.
And we're like, oh, we'll fix it later,
-- but this assumes we know what would be protective. That's fair
-- too.
Like with these smart contracts, I'm seeing a lot of things like,
define what would actually be safe behavior with, say,
withdrawal limits and then you enter, you create new problems, right?
So I think part of the problem is we don't have enough
knowledge to know what is safe behavior other than this hand wavy,
you know, oh, it's secure and it doesn't do anything bad.
Ok. But no, no, no, no, no, I need you to narrow that down for me.
-- It didn't say ready go. I paused it
-- for a sec.
You can't pause it. That defeats the purpose.
Ok. Next one.
All right. The next one says what train have we got?
Which is what train today is the Twitter user name.
And I'll put all these in the show notes,
but it says using click through rates to
measure the effectiveness of your fishing training,
use reporting rates Instead people, you want people to report fishing emails,
don't you incentivize
that?
I agree.
So I've got the CS A email super lockdown.
Like we've got SPF we've got DKIM, we've got dear,
we've even got that stupid BMI logo that cost 1000 bucks a year, right?
And so like when you open up a CS A email,
it's got the logo next to it in your email client,
assuming it's not out lookout look doesn't support Biy,
of course, because they have the Microsoft standard that they do.
But anyways
we get
so that means you can't spoof email from clouds
lines.org.
And so we get these terrible Jilly Bo Bob Thornton at gmail.com saying, you know,
like, literally this is Jim and I'm like in a Mexican prison and they, you know,
I need a bunch of gift cards for a business function mailed to
like you need to phone this person and give them the codes,
right?
And it's like
luckily none of the CS A people are goofy enough to like fall for that.
Like, I don't want to blame the victim,
but sometimes when I do see these fishings and how weak they are.
And I'm like,
how did like this local college that changed a payment
for $9 million with apparently an oversight because they sent
it to a random bank account that was specified in
a random email that was not from the construction company.
And to me
back to this whole, like if the user can basically reply to an email and like,
bring down your company or change a payment
or do something horrific that like bankruptcy.
But that's
like your process is broken and it's gonna fail sooner or later. That's right.
That's not the user's fault.
Like there needs to be like if, if there's like,
if I can accidentally push a button at a factory and the whole thing blows up,
you need to put a guard around that button.
And, and I think that's the whole point is fishing training,
I think is
it, it has value for awareness purposes,
but I don't think it necessarily has value for a, like people learning a new skill.
-- It always strikes me as trying to pass the buck.
-- It kind of is, I agree with that.
It's your fault now and we're going to blame you and,
and then in a court of law later on when bad things happen,
it's not the company's fault.
We, you know, we take blank very seriously.
And we train our users about blank, very seriously. And
the behavior of user around blank does in no way represent the company 100 percent.
And, and I think that's again, you're getting what you measure, right?
Whereas I think the the intent of phishing awareness
training isn't to make people click less phishing links.
Necessarily it's to get them to report phishing emails
and, and
-- better to report something that isn't fishing. Stupid
-- question.
But when they report the phishing email, then what?
-- Well,
-- so if you're using like gmail, I know you can report fishing and then your,
your administrator can basically go through and if like, yes, it's fishing.
But then what? Well, if you say like, yes, this is fishing.
It will remove that fish from every account in your organization. It's quite nice.
Yeah, it's pretty clever actually. So, anyway. All right. Moving on, moving on.
Uh next 10, I love this one. This one, my favorite guy named Dan.
And it says
when securely wiping a disk, you must do more than one pass. Yeah.
So I think that myth actually comes down
to back in the day with mechanical hard drives
that were nowhere as sophisticated or
the tolerances that they have nowadays just back in the day they didn't have.
So, I mean,
you know, we're talking about the era of like one megabyte hard drives, you know,
the era where you could take cassette tape and like,
-- like inspect it with a microscope to read the ones and zeros.
-- You can, you can
do that with VHS tape. You can, you can literally like see the lines on the tape.
-- And
-- so coming from that era in that era,
yeah, you, you
better do more than one pass of the hard drive because the head wanders and it's
gonna leave data on the sides potentially that
could then literally be recovered without like a piece
of
microscope.
But and tapes. Exactly.
And so, but, but this is stuff from 3040 years ago and,
and now we're talking about like
the the density nowadays,
no one pass it's gone.
So there's also a second part to this, I think,
which is when you're working with S SDS
S sds don't work like mechanical hard disks do where you can
like seek the head to a certain spot and do a certain thing
like they're constantly moving around the blocks inside the disk.
So wiping like an SSD is almost meaningless
because when you think you're wiping a block,
the SSD could be like, oh time to shift this around.
And so your data could still be in one of the unused spaces on the disk,
-- which is really funny,
-- but trim and like 10% of the space is reserved for future use.
I mean, the,
the one thing I've noticed is all the videos from like Amazon
and Google where they talk about how they decommission the stuff,
they physically destroy it.
Well,
there's physical destruction and you know what the
other cool trick is that's seen as common.
The reason you want to encrypt your data at rest and not keep
the key on the disk is because then when you decommission the disk,
even if the disk goes away, if you don't have the encryption key,
that's as good as random data and no one can recover it.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, I like this one.
I think it's fun because I,
I know I'm notorious for wiping things like a million times.
Just it. Part of it amuses me.
Part of it is like it's that, like,
remember we talked about my GP GT and I live in like this alternate fantasy world
and I think wiping diss multiple times is
one of those like alternate fantasy things.
I just think it's like a now that
now nobody can find out what was on this disk before I got to it.
What also gets me about wiping disks,
especially on client system nowadays is all that stuff
gets remotely backed up to the cloud anyways.
So
I don't think this wiping is gonna do what you hope it does.
Especially on a client system.
It, it, it, yeah. And honestly, I don't feel like it comes up as much as it used to.
I think
1015 years ago, wiping disks felt like a big deal.
-- Uh,
-- it's still in every questionnaire we get is it
really?
Yeah. Like, how do you securely decommission hardware when you're done with it?
And I'm like, we don't
anyway.
All right.
Uh This is from
Alejo. It looks like Alex 91 Dohar.
Uh It says anything that tries to categorize
a vulnerability within a short list of categories.
The only thing that comes close to CWE and it has more than 1000 entries.
-- Actually,
-- it
-- doesn't.
-- How many does it
have?
CWE entries are not always vulnerabilities.
Some of them are like top 10 or top 25 lists
or categories. And I should know because I've actually, now just, I've submitted
10 or 11 New Cwes and gotten feedback on five of them. And I actually have
basically, I should be doing 2 to 3 of these a week if I was actually going at speed.
Yeah, CWE is comically
incomplete and every other list is even far shorter.
That seems
right. And I, and I say this as a member of the CWE board is that
I
would like to see more CWE si would like to see.
We probably need about 5 to 10,000 Cwes in total.
Well, probably, but then I think you also run into the
difficulty of how do you find them when there's that many?
Well,
and actually I brought this up on the board is if you
go to Amazon and try to buy like a ball pit ball,
you get like crush proof ball pit balls floating water,
happy for fun kids to play with BP A free non cancer causing.
And I'm like the problem like we don't need
that level of description for like buffer overflow,
but we do need
better search ability and discovery of the Cwes because like I
literally am now like I've learned like there's certain keywords like
-- instantiation or initialization.
-- I think this is one of those instances where
it would be lovely to have a robot that you like
pointed at the patch typed in the description of the bug.
-- And then the robot kind of said it's probably this one right here.
-- Yeah, exactly.
Because it's, it's a hard problem.
And what we really need CWE four is that we have a common vocabulary. So like
when we say buffer overflow, what do we mean?
And also for teaching, right?
And for not just teaching people but the scanners and the tools,
you know what I used to do back when I was really mean.
I remember when, when I'd interview someone and say,
explain a buffer overflow to me.
And if they did it first say stack or heat buffer overflow,
I failed them on that question.
But the reality is, I mean, it's kind of valid but it's kind of not,
I've just been a jerk I think.
But yeah, you're right.
It's, there's,
there's a lot of nuance and complexity and sometimes
you can just say buffer overflow and that's acceptable.
And sometimes stacker heap makes a difference.
-- And
-- even simpler, we need meta level stuff.
So like looking at the Nomad bridge that just got, you know,
packed for 100 and $90 million it's actually three vulnerabilities, right?
It's the first vulnerability is that they didn't have a
switch to put the thing into repair or upgrade mode.
So they used a magic value of all zeros, which led to the second problem of
they set the Merkel tree hash value to a manually set value of all zeros.
That's no longer a hash,
that's a human set value unless you get statistically improbably lucky.
And it actually hashes out to zero
and third.
And this is actually kind of in CWE is, it's actually finally sort of a logic bug,
but there's these things that came before it like an air crash
and we need more of that air crash level of investigation.
Here's one of my favorites.
Uh, a guy named Postmortem shouldn't say guy,
I don't know a person named Postmortem.
Uh It says wrist scores.
It's postmodern,
postmodern. Oh, sorry.
-- Oh, II, I do that a lot. Um Anyway,
-- have you been checked for dyslexia?
I, I have not been officially checked, but I'm certain I have a case of it.
I do this a lot where I switch a lot of letters around in words and it's,
it's sometimes terribly embarrassing.
So I mispronounce someone's name horribly and I'm
looking like literally at their name printed on,
on a name tag or something.
But anyway, anyway,
uh
risk scores too high level hand wavy,
thus not useful for identifying and fixing actual problems.
I love this one because we have things like CV SS,
we have things like all these scorecard things there's like in effect in this,
this specific one was called up multiple times in the context of C DS S like
scorecards for measuring like goodness of software or
software projects as well as like security scorecard,
the literal service that tries to measure like the,
the security goodness of a company.
And
my complaint about this, the complaint I have that I will, I will die on this hill.
Is that
all of the risk scores we use today are not scientific scores,
but rather things smart people thought were a good idea,
which is not without that scientific rigor,
we can't create like feedback loops that measure if it's working or not.
Yeah, because basically what you're, I think what you're saying is,
is there's definite correlation but is there causation?
That's
right. And you're right because now that I think about it like CV SS,
I've never seen a paper that rigorously like looks at the feedback loop like,
yeah. Does, is, is this what's actually important
because
CV SS? Yeah,
I
mean, you have to start somewhere. So I get what they started with.
It's kind of the same thing I would invent and I love that CV. SS two
are not too like as well as
it has the temporal and environmental score that nobody ever uses.
Yeah, because it's too complicated
and, and I think
again we come back to but, but I think the other,
the other thing that makes us really hard is
it not just stuff smart people thought was a good idea.
It's stuff smart people thought was a good idea.
And then they try to iterate on top of that and see
that as kind of progress instead of being able to say,
hold on, we need to like look at this, we need to understand like what, what works,
what doesn't work.
And this is any time you say, oh,
we're just gonna make up some rules and then we'll figure out if they work later,
you've already ruined your work because you will pick the,
you will cherry pick the data
that justifies the thing you made every time. It's just human nature.
-- It's how humans work honestly.
-- For me CV as
what the valuable down to is two things. Is it remote? Yes or no.
And does it require authentication? Yes or no.
And literally nothing else I really ever cared about.
That's basically the useful part of the data,
the number and everything like whatever,
but like those two facts,
that's what I really needed to know and having
those structured and easily read that was valuable.
And this is actually where I like what NIST is
doing because they have the bugs framework and the V
ontology work where I think once you start combining like
some of the actual real facts and data about vulnerabilities,
now we can extrapolate
more information on them and like fundamentally all everything we do,
like the reason it's made up crap is because we just don't have good data.
Like that is our problem in security is we lack the data to conduct the research,
to create conclusions and concept.
I would say it's worse than that. We lack the ability to even get good data.
It's not like people are lazy and just haven't assembled the data.
We don't even have the techniques and methods to assemble the data.
Well, I mean, that, that's just part of the scientific rigor,
you know,
and that's what we're trying with the global Security database is actually build a
thing that can then build the data that we can then use to.
Like,
like do we need to care about N PM or just keep like it's like with my devs at the CS A,
I'm like you guys ship this thing and update it twice a week.
Cool, close enough.
I'm like, I'm, you don't need to track CV specifically just keep it up to date
and I it seems to work.
No, like I have one data point which is, I don't think we've been hacked.
At least not to the best of my knowledge.
-- I say that and your
-- single data point is not reproducible in any meaningful way.
No, my favorite was a slash talk. Quote. The plural of anecdote is not data.
The plural of anecdote is not data like
two anecdotes. Five anecdotes. That's still not data.
Data is something totally different.
-- That is true.
-- Right. Like
it's,
that seems remarkably intelligent for slash
it was, it was a long time ago,
like 1015 years anyway.
All right. Excellent. Uh Robert CC
cord
use STRN copy instead of STR copy.
I don't, I disagree with this one but not for the reason everyone thinks
and that's what amuses me. So I'll give some background here
in C
there are
in the good old days, there was this thing called Stir
Copy, strcpy.
And it basically you put a string in and you copied one string into another.
And this particular function is probably
responsible for 90% of Buffalo overflows in
the early days of Sea because it did zero checking if you had
a 200 character string
and you told it, copy this 200 character string into this seven character buffer,
it would totally do it, no questions asked.
And then STRN copy comes along and that in that you basically say, all right,
here's the string, I need to put it in this buffer.
And here's how big this buffer is. And the idea being that you would
put the correct amount of bites. A buffer is
and then STRN copy would fail if you tried to put too much data into too small a string,
right?
It is easy to make the argument that this is
good programming
could make stern copying
my head here because you're still fundamentally making the
programmer responsible for knowing how big the buffer is.
-- And that's complicated. And,
-- and here's the thing. So
the, the challenge here isn't whether the function is necessarily better or worse.
Well, we know it's better but
that what happens is when developers have to start doing, taking this extra step,
they ha they think about the size of their buffer and it slows them down for a minute.
And actually
Microsoft discusses this in,
in their, one of their SS DLC books,
one of the very early books and I forget who the author was.
I apologize in advance.
I have a copy of it somewhere in a box.
But basically they talk about like Microsoft made a rule like no ST copy,
you can only use STRN copy internally.
And,
and in fact, the one they,
they created in Windows was even more complicated because you also had
to include the size of the buffer you were coming from.
And the reason they did this wasn't to add security specifically,
it
is to slow the developer down and make them think for a second.
But what am I actually doing here?
And that was what made it effective more so
than the protections because there's nothing stopping a developer
from just being like f it like put a bunch of nines in this, this spot or whatever.
You know what I mean?
I just think fundamentally making a developer
not only making them responsible for memory management,
but in
a
system where off by one matters,
you're, you're bound to fail. Like come on, what else is going to happen?
-- C has a lot of
-- problems.
Well,
not just C like there's other languages but C
-- is obviously the poster child for this
-- CC is.
But, but the point is like all of this,
it's less about the function itself and it's more about the behavior changes.
And I think that's a powerful concept,
especially when you're working with kind of people of any sort,
making them slow down sometimes and take a breath and
think about what's going on can be very valuable,
especially in security.
All right. All right, let's keep going.
-- Also
-- just an amusing comment on that tweet Google or Twitter offers to translate it.
So I hit translate it and it gave me the exact same string,
you string copy instead of steal a copy.
Awesome. Awesome. All right. Excellent. Uh
Yyp.
-- I apologize if I,
-- I
don't even know how to pronounce it, but I'm pretty sure that was wrong.
The one thing I know is whatever.
I think a name is pronounced as is definitely not the correct pronunciation.
-- That is basically my rule.
-- So
anyway,
I've given up
you know what's funny is we've been working together for how many, like,
literally decades at this point,
I cannot spell your last name.
I have to look it up and then, like, type it while I'm looking at it
every time, every time, Kurt, I, sometimes I get embarrassed and I'm like,
whatever I've given up anyway,
I've had to look up. Is it pressor or pressor?
It does have an,
it does have an SS it doesn't matter anyway.
Alright. If SSH tells you the host key people, we'll verify it.
Absolutely. Just like it.
Like, like when you have to sign off on a code change, people always check those
and absolutely make sure that they are correct.
And what drives me nuts here is, yeah, of course, people don't do that like,
and more to the point when I connect to a server for the first time, how am I,
how am I supposed to check the key against what?
Ok. No, no. So
you're supposed to have the key documented somewhere,
-- but I just instantiated the server
-- because you should be contacting
the server owner prior to connecting so they can get.
But that's me. I know.
See this is every time when Windows throws up an error
message saying contact your administrator for help and I'm like,
well, damn it, that's me and that's not very helpful. Now, is it
right?
That's pretty good.
So I, I agree with you.
There,
there is SSH has host keys and there's no functional way to actually verify the key.
Yes, there is. They have host key signing. They've had it for over a decade.
They, they have and no one uses it because it's, but,
but once you start host key signing now you're in,
you have key management problems and you know what I mean?
-- Like these, these,
-- well, you already have key management problems if you're doing
that.
That's true.
That's true. That's true.
It's, but, but ok, so here's the thing,
ssh host keys have value.
But again, we come back to one of those like people don't,
it doesn't do what people think it does.
And the reason I like SSH host keys
is I connect to a host. I have no way to verify if it's actually correct or not.
So I just say yes and I connect to it.
But then if there's ever anything that changes like in
between me and that host from that point forward,
I know something different has happened and this can have value in the
positive and negative direction where if someone man in the middle is me,
I'm gonna get a warning, right? Or
conversely, if someone unmanned in the middle of me, I'm gonna get a warning
and that gives me the ability to now go and check on what happened.
So, and basically,
if this is a host,
you're going to connect to for long periods of time and connect
you many times if someone is man in the middle of you,
they have to keep man in the middle in you
forever or you're going to figure out something is wrong.
-- Well,
-- and hopefully you notice that something's wrong and do something about it.
But again,
the thing to remember is all this stuff came like this is 20 plus
year old technology at this point and we didn't have any other options.
When did SSH is from the early nineties? Right.
I mean, I bet I started using it in like 90
-- 4, 95.
-- This is one of the things like, is it a terrible solution? Yes.
But it's a 25 or more year old solution.
-- It's
-- like GP G signatures. How do you verify someone's key?
It's actually really hard to do.
So, what we actually do is we just say, oh, Kurt, here's my new key.
And you say thanks, Josh, that's great.
Pretty much
and send it via email. So I don't have to cut and paste it, please.
Yeah. Totally. Totally. Absolutely. Right. Right.
Or heck, it doesn't even now.
I mean, with key servers, it's more like, oh, just download the new key. It's fine
using the short ID because it's hard to type the whole thing in. That's right.
Short I DS.
That's right. Those are just fine too
for that now. It's only 20 years late, but we're getting there. No use of
its use of partial hash value. Like you can't use part of a hash value.
You have to use the whole thing. Like,
we might have ac we for it in the next few months. Finally.
Anyway.
Now again,
I think this comes back to things like let's encrypt and
cigar are helping with a lot of these problems
and
we're not there yet.
We may never get there in some cases because SSH is still weird but it's,
it's getting better.
I mean, these are hard problems. It's taken a long time to sort out.
So, anyway, anyway, now I have to ask,
have you ever verified an SSH host key ever in your entire career?
-- A few times?
-- Yeah. Actually, I don't think I have ever,
-- ever
-- part of it is, I mean, I, uh,
one thing I used to do is we had like an
internal web server that listed all our SSH keys or rather,
I just, I think I made a config
file.
See, you, you started this conversation asking you where you'd get the key from?
That's where you get it.
How do you get to the web server? Securely? Blah, blah, blah.
-- Right. Chicken egg.
-- Well, that's TLS. That's a different problem.
-- That's someone else's
-- dude. We didn't have TLS back then.
All right. Well,
I couldn't afford it.
My first TLS server.
Well, TLS wasn't even around when I bought my, I bought,
I bought a copy of Red Hat Stronghold Server for 500 bucks.
Like, and I bought a certificate for it.
Which again, you know,
as that story goes like that poor company was
very confused as to why I was buying that.
Right. Oh, that's
right.
You know, but I wanted to set this up and learn how it works and
well, how else was I going to do it?
There was no open
source secure
server.
You could self sign a certificate and there was an open
source web server because Stronghold was based off of
just the Apache bits and pieces. You, you could cobble them together yourself.
Sort of,
it was hard because I did it and it was
not easy and then we would self signed certificates.
-- But
-- part of it is I wanted to know how to actually run like a real
secure web server. Like a product.
Not like, yeah, I cobbled like on my resume, I figured like, yeah,
I cobbled this thing together versus like red hats.
-- You know what I mean?
-- Yeah, that's fair. That's fair. I'll buy
that.
And then of course, I never became assistant M so it all panned out fine.
Is it, is your timer broken?
-- I turned it off. Well,
-- why did you turn it off?
Because it was like on the last round.
-- It's not the last round. We got one more tweet still.
-- I miscounted.
-- Apparently I was off by one last
-- tweet. Best for last
Macs are secure.
Um You know what
with the M one and M two chips they're getting there.
No,
like they basically are adopting the phone model
of like hard drive's encrypted secure enclave.
We don't care. Like you want to put a four digit pin in. Sure, do that.
But you want to, like, lock it to your icloud account and make it secure, do that.
The thing that annoys me about Max is like, you,
they're no better or worse really than windows and yet somehow the majority
of Mac users don't run antivirus and are kind of doing ok.
Well, I, I think you could accomplish the same thing on Windows.
I think the web browsers have gotten better.
I think the the real problem is if you look back in time, probably 10 years ago,
Windows was the dominant operating system.
All of the malware was on Windows.
And if you ran Linux or Mac, you didn't have malware, not because they were good,
-- but just because there wasn't malware for,
-- there was a small amount of malware.
It was very tiny and it was very hard to get. And the reality is
the Attackers were going after windows. And so I think
that attitude has carried
you also had different ecosystems like
the shareware ecosystem for Windows back in the late nineties, early aughts.
Yeah, that's true. That was a very download and run this ecosystem.
Remember when they started scanning that stuff for viruses and what happened
was,
I can't, I can't even imagine,
like, let me put it this way. I'm old enough to remember two cows
when they weren't at DNS register.
That's true. They were a software provider
and then was it,
was it Source Forge that was injecting crap into executables at one point?
Like
the whole thing
anyway.
So, and the fun thing is like, I actually, because I can,
I can speak authoritatively,
like I actually run Microsoft Defender 365 on both my Macs and it
actually works really well and it's not intrusive and it doesn't break anything.
And it's really cute because I get like these warning emails that my Macs were
not upgraded on the US and I actually forgot to turn the firewall on one.
Yeah, it's, I would actually argue that
Macs generally are a bit more secure than windows
because there's a couple of common failure scenarios that don't occur.
Like I, I don't need to download as many dodgy device drivers.
All right, I'm gonna, we're gonna end this because we're,
this episode's already way too long.
I, I'm, I'm, I'm putting in the last word.
Macs aren't secure,
windows aren't secure. Linux isn't secure.
That is all
all right. Thank you, everyone. Thank you, Kurt. This was fun.
This is long, but it was fun. Go to open
source security podcast.com.
I'll put links to all the tweets and stuff and yeah,
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You
-- too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.
The