Hello and welcome to the Open source Security podcast episode.
100 and 24 with myself Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Pressers.
So I got a new desk.
I'm standing up right now, which is kind of a new thing and,
and I guess I should also apologize.
I'm in a new office and it's probably more echoey
than usual because I haven't put any sound prevention.
Anything
-- in here. No,
-- I'm fine.
I,
I actually have a sit stand desk that I had to unplug because
my one kid likes making it go up and down and up and down
and up and down.
Right. It is cool.
Yeah.
-- Something magical about simple machines.
-- I, I, I agree.
Although in all seriousness, like,
my goal is to basically leave it up forever at this point.
And it, it's been a little over a week and I'm doing ok. I can make it most of the day now.
So
-- we're getting there. Here's
-- the funny thing.
I found that I like the most about a sit stand desk.
It was really easy. It's like if you want to adjust the height for, to,
it's perfect. Where you're sitting,
you can do that.
And I realized like,
this would be really nice for like a dining room table or something because,
you know, wouldn't it be nice once in a while?
No, like sometimes you're eating dinner sometimes if you want to go do crafts
or, you know, like my parents come over and my mom's short. Right? Like,
it's just, you know, having furniture that is adjustable,
only office furniture does that.
So it it's funny you
that because I'm going to tie this back to a conversation we're
going to end up with on the topic of the day.
But uh the return on investment on that and
the number of people who care is basically zero,
right?
Because like good enough is having a table that just
works and you don't have to worry about replacing a
motor in it every 20 years or probably every five
because your kids will play with it and burn it.
Do IKEA tables last 20 years. I feel like they don't,
not an IKEA table man.
I've been surprised an IKEA table last like, like here's the deal.
So actually I've got a bunch of IKEA stuff in my office because IKEA stuff is cool
but it's, it's not super high quality. But at the same time, I feel like
there's,
there's one thing to be said about buying some furniture that lasts forever, like,
like a dining room table.
I'm cool with that. Right?
Whereas something like a, a couch. I don't want a couch the last 20 years.
Like my in-laws have, have a literally a 30 year old couch. I
think it's gonna be 40 years old now.
And I'm like, this thing is, but freaking ugly. Like, don't get me wrong.
It's very comfortable but it is the ugliest freaking couch in the world.
It's like throw this thing away and buy a new one.
My parents actually had their coach,
their coaches professionally recovered
-- but,
-- but at the same time, they probably paid as much for that is like new coach
costs,
right?
So
like at that point, just buy a new couch
anyway. Anyway. All right.
So,
so the topic of the day is cloud flare has
built magic workers on the edge that are running V eight
V,
right? Running on V eight. That's fair,
which is the, the Javascript engine inside Chrome.
And the reason
I think it's most interesting is they announced this and nearly every security
person I know started going on and on about how insecure this is
and
my take on this and, and my, my quick take is,
uh, it probably is more insecure than a container or a VM.
But the reality is it's going to be so freaking cheap.
-- Nobody,
-- I'm actually gonna disagree with you
and, and we can argue about that later.
-- But
-- no, I have numbers.
It doesn't matter either way because it's going to be so freaking cheap,
it isn't going to matter at the end of the day.
Well,
that's so that's the thing cloud flare really
drove home in their blog is the density,
right?
Like when you think about density of physical servers,
1 to 1 density of virtual machines,
maybe a 10 to 1,
if you're, it depends on the workload,
right? We'll say 10 to 1.
-- But with
-- provision and and provisioning tools are getting better and more dynamic.
But and that's part of the problem VM workloads, not super dynamic like yeah,
there's V MS that support hot migration and stuff, but
that's kind of a kind of difficult
uh containers definitely denser and definitely easier to move
around because if the container is built properly,
it's
you, you turn it on, it does its work, you turn it off
and, and I'm guilty of this.
I have a bunch of containers that are basically V MS because
I haven't,
you know, I haven't properly containerized.
I was gonna guess I bet more than half probably closer
to 80% of containers are just V MS because in fact,
I,
I can't think of a single container workload I've ever deployed.
That is a true microservice. They're all just like small V MS.
The reality is if you're not doing containers with AC
I CD system continuously building them and deploying them,
then you're not doing containers, right?
Like you're really not using them
as they should can and should be used. Right. You're essentially doing VM.
So, which, you know, it's fine.
It's, it's, it's honestly, there's nothing wrong with that.
Docker V MS are a lot less painful than like
building of uh uh VM Ware cluster. Oh, my goodness. Yes.
So, you know, sorry, sorry VM Ware people.
But then the thing is,
well, but there are, there what's lighter weight than a container and
force sort of forcibly, more, more
mobile and dynamic in as far as it runs here, then it runs over there,
then it runs on this machine.
And that is essentially serverless computing,
right? With serverless computing.
And see this is where Google cloud went wrong at first, right?
They built an awesome product
for engineers
that for example, didn't have local file system state.
And so the problem was no normal person could use it
because they're like,
what do you mean?
I can't write to the file system and save those changes like my app like
everything just breaks
and Google of course is like, yeah,
but you just like big table and this and that and
all these other cool things and message buses and all that.
And, and of course, you know, normal people are like, but,
but I want to write to my local file,
you know, that's
right.
And so
the thing is, you know,
it's one of those classic like Google built it before kind of everybody could,
could use it or, or, you know, really embrace it,
but we're getting there now. And part of it is,
you know, people devs are finally, are not just being trained technically
on how to do this, but sort of the culture piece,
why would you, you know, instead of having local state use a
centralized database that, you know, all your workers
or better yet, you know,
don't do that and use some other magical system like
uh no SQL or some sort of shared state table,
whatever.
Right. Right. And
the thing is so
the density cloud flare can get from this is basically 100%
right. They can get 100% utilization of their servers
because
if they can't run a workload on an edge on a specific edge node,
that's basically OK because they can just route it somewhere else.
So for a latency problem
but and see that's the thing people don't get like about Amazon, right?
Amazon has three pricing tiers. You can pay by the hour
and get guaranteed resources assuming they're available,
you can pay upfront and reserve resources so that when you do need them later on,
you definitely get them.
Right.
So for like the disaster recovery people or if you're running a long term workload,
that absolutely must run
and then they can pad out the rest
of their infrastructure usage with spot instances that,
you know,
they're very cheap and they might get killed
randomly
because somebody else is willing to pay more for that compute time,
right.
And that's what Cloudflare is doing is
essentially building this business model where?
Oh, yeah, we can just run all our servers at 100%.
And as we need more capacity, we'll add it because people are paying for it.
Right. So we'll have very little unused capacity,
right? Ok.
So we should back up for a second and just explain what the hack,
a Claude flair service worker is
that way there, there's good, let's face it.
Not everyone pays this close of attention to a lot of this stuff and, and someday,
maybe Claude Flair has failed.
And, and our future historians are,
are wondering where society went wrong and they're studying us.
And, and so anyway, cloud flare and, and here's the crazy thing.
They're,
they're very specific in their fact that it is called a cloud flare service worker,
not a cloud flare worker because apparently they're
intending on having more of these things exist.
And this first one is the service worker where they
Right. Right.
And I don't blame him either.
So essentially what they did is there is something called
the service worker in javascript which lets you kind of
think of it as like intercepting an HTTP request
and doing stuff and then sending it along,
right?
And like this is built into javascript.
And so basically what they did is they've made this API available on the edge.
So if you're using cloud flare, you can write a script to do something like the,
one of their examples is
you can basically look at the request. And if there is a cookie,
don't, don't go to the cache.
If there's no cookie just send people to the cache.
Because you're assuming, you know, they're just gonna get their
page or whatever. Exactly. Exactly.
And like that makes a lot of sense. Right.
Because essentially the way it probably works in
most instances is you hit a website,
it says, oh, you don't have a cookie.
Uh I'll serve you the static page or, oh, you do have a cookie.
Let me figure out what to do. Just like reddit does. Right. Right. Exactly.
And so by not hitting the website and going to the cache instead,
you obviously number one, save a ton on traffic and compute in your,
your server room or server whatever.
And, and on the other side it's, it's wicked fast for people who aren't using.
Well, that's the thing people forget. Right.
When you, when you can serve something from a cloud flare edge,
hang on a sec. Let me see how close my cloud flare edge is. Uh 19 milliseconds.
That's pretty solid, man. Right. And that's the, well,
cre.org is hosted at a cloud flare. So 19 milliseconds.
That's
nice. That's very fast. That's actually a lot faster than I was expecting.
Right.
Right. So, yeah. And most
so that's the thing people forget.
Right is,
is if you're talking to a cloud flare edge that is only 20 milliseconds away and
that cloud flare edge is returning the content to you.
You're going to get the web page in
2, 300 milliseconds instantaneous versus going to the back end. Logging in
blah, blah, blah, half a second, a second, two seconds.
Whatever.
That's right.
The other thing that people forget is that on the back end then you have a server.
Uh, Yes or right, because with these cloud flare workers, as I understand it,
there's not really any limits to what you can do.
Like if you can build it in javascript, you can do it.
-- Uh
-- I mean, it, it sounds like it's not really designed to replace, you know,
kind of uh server side generated websites.
It's more for simple tasks at, at this moment from what I've seen. Right? It's, it's,
it,
it seems like it's more of a let's intercept
this http call and do stuff and granted you,
you could in theory like pre
render a website and do other crazy things like that. But I have a suspicion.
That's not the goal here, right? The goal is to just do speedy content delivery.
-- Yeah. For
-- free, you get five milliseconds of CPU time.
For pro you get 10 milliseconds for business, you get 50 milliseconds
and for enterprise, you get 50 milliseconds plus depending on the contract.
-- So you, you can build, I mean, if, if,
-- and, and that's per request.
Yes.
And so, I mean, that's, you know,
javascript running for 50 milliseconds can do quite a
bit of stuff or 50 milliseconds of CPU time.
Anything running for 50 milliseconds,
right?
That's like 200 years uh 10 years ago and CPU
-- time
-- and then a worker must make all of its subs
within the 1st 15 seconds of its execution.
And that's a soft limit after that period.
No new sub requests can be made by the script. So essentially,
yeah, you, you can't build super heavy
things that like are going on multiple backend databases and whatnot. But
you could definitely build something like
equivalent to wordpress in these without,
you know,
straining on the CPU limits too much.
Sure,
maybe I don't know.
But whatever the point is this,
this is a super cool service where essentially cloud flare is running it.
It's dirt freaking cheap,
which is worth noting as well. I read somewhere.
It's a third the price of similar services in Aws
and, and now they're doing something
insanely clever with this and it's what gets them the cheapness,
which is because they have incredible density is they're,
they're relying on
the,
the V eight javascript interpreter itself to do the
process segregation and it's called V eight isolates.
And this is really never been done
quite like this before because generally speaking,
the attitude has always been well, OK, I shouldn't say that
-- this has never been done securely before.
-- Well, on server side, more on client side
like this is what gets me right, the V eight engine
is used in your web browser chrome. Well, I assume most people run Chrome now.
Um but anyways
and the amount of toxic junk that the average web browser sees online is over 9000.
And and I suspect part of the problem here is a lot of security.
People forget how completely ridiculously toxic the
internet has become for web surfing.
-- It's so bad
-- because they use an ad blocker, right?
The minute you start using an ad blocker boom, like 99% of your exposure is gone,
right?
Because most of these attacks are coming in through ads or ad network compromises or
whatever.
So I was looking at the CV stats and, and they're remarkably uh
consistent for the last 56 years. So
2013, we had uh 11 chrome V eight vulnerabilities in 2014, we had 22.
-- Now,
-- is this just V eight or chrome
itself? This is V eight
in Google Chrome.
Uh So 22 in 2014, 25 in 2015, 27 in 2016, 22 in 2015.
And then here's where it got interesting five in 2018.
And I know at first I was wondering
like maybe they started labeling them differently.
So I actually went through the CV database for
2018 for Google Chrome vulnerabilities and V eight.
No, that, that's five.
And I'm beginning to wonder, like, because they have spent quite a lot of
bounty money, you know, bounty money with P to own. Um,
they've, uh, you know, had their project zero.
they've been fuzzing the bejesus out of all of this stuff
and I kind of wonder if they're getting to that point now where,
you know, it's like if you eat healthy and go to the gym and then one day it's like, oh,
you know, you can lift that heavy thing without hurting yourself.
Right.
And, and I, I'm beginning to think maybe that's V eight chrome got there.
Um, because the thing to remember, right, is,
is Google can basically see all the malware being served on the planet.
And
that's true because they run virus total.
so, well, well, not only that they, they literally crawl the internet. So
-- if it's on the internet, they, they
-- have it. Yeah.
Well, remember when they did that PDF
project and they're like, oh, so we just decided to build corpus of every possible,
you know, PDF thing that would exercise every possible PDF code path,
right? It's like 23 terabytes of data.
So what, you know, that's a rounding error for them.
And so I'm, I'm really beginning to think, you know,
traditionally,
one of the ways we pick technologies is we pick a
company that is big and puts a lot of resources into the
into the technology because even if it's not very good
right now it'll continue to improve and be supported.
Sure.
And I can't help but think as, you know, as far as a run time goes,
right, a run time to run some code securely
but picking something backed by a giant browser, you know, mega company.
Yeah, that, that might be the way to go.
-- Uh
-- It, it, maybe, maybe I'm, I'm not, I, I guess let's let's even
step aside from this because I, I have a suspicion. You're right.
Like I haven't looked at the data you you've looked at, but
it,
it wouldn't shock me because these guys have been
doing enormous amounts of work on securing chrome.
And obviously when, when I,
I used to work with the Firefox people on security flaws and basically
javascript is the problem.
So
-- everything comes back to javascript
-- turing complete junk
from some random stranger running on your computer.
What could go wrong?
Now,
now here's the thing
I keep thinking of is all security people are saying, oh my goodness,
you can't run a system like this.
It's going to be too insecure,
there's going to be side channel attacks and there's going to be people
breaking out of their containment and there's going to be people doing,
serving man
doing things they shouldn't do. And
we've already had that with the browsers, right?
We took away the high frequency timers,
you know, to prevent that side
channel like
-- which
-- is,
which is awesome. We've already, you know,
all of these problems that security people are complaining about
V eights already been through that.
Like V eight is not a child. It's,
but here's, here's the thing.
I, I agree with you 100% but I wanna,
I wanna go even farther away from this conversation and say,
even if it's insecure,
even if it is,
I don't think it matters because at the end of the day,
the things that win is price and I'm gonna, I mean,
this comes back to like the conversations we've had about like if I go buy
an IOT light bulb and one says super secure and it's $20 and one's like,
eh, whatever and it's $1 I'm buying the $1 light bulb, right?
Don't
care. It's insecure.
I have this skylink net system and so the ring doorbell I bought,
I just got a ring doorbell.
You, you know, you pay money for them to store the video in the cloud.
That makes sense, right?
My skylink net system,
I can remotely view the video from my
skylink camera, but I have no idea. I need to go check.
Like, is it going to a server in China? Is it somehow because like
it can't the cameras behind a firewall on a like
not a real, you know, on a reserve IP address? Like an internal network IP address?
So like
-- how does that video get from there to my phone.
-- Magic. Don't ask.
-- Like, I really don't, haven't, I haven't bothered to look and I
-- just, you know, it,
it's super insecure.
Oh, totally, totally insecure. Right.
This is,
this is like that pain in your side that you don't want to
go to the doctor because you're worried it might be something bad.
Yeah, same thing.
Just don't look. It's easier.
But anyway, I mean, so that's my point. Right. Is
maybe it is more insecure.
It doesn't matter because it's cheaper.
-- And here's the most important thing.
-- That's the thing.
It's, it's not just cheaper, it's better.
That's true. Cheaper and better. That's true. That's a very good point
because, well, that's actually fair.
And, and that's another part of kind of economics that, that I think is worth,
worth talking about is the fact that
in, in many, in many organizations, people assume
that you can be more expensive and better or you can just be
cheaper and the same cheaper and the same is never enough incentive.
You need to be cheaper and better, basically better. You need to be better. Right.
You can be more expensive and better and win. You can be cheaper and better than win.
But if you're only cheaper, you're not gonna win.
Right. And so
that's part of it,
the cost of switching is high
and here's the other thing that I think people forget all the time.
Cloud flare is going to roll this out.
Cloud flare is an organization with resources.
Even if this thing completely sucks for the first year,
they're going to invest in it and they're going to make it better.
And let's face it like this is how javascript got better.
Javascript got better because people used it and it sucked and
they kept fixing it and now we've reached a point where,
same as PHP.
No, PHP still sucks.
-- Horrendously
-- widely deployed.
It totally is.
And actually in all seriousness, even PHP has gotten way better than it used to
and now it's no Js. Right. Right. Exactly. And now no Js is a winner. Right?
And no Js is going to get incrementally better over time
and, and like this is going to be part of that story.
-- I have
-- no doubt here's the other thing that I find interesting. And
so I'm just trying to think about how I can phrase this without offending anybody.
So a lot of these cloud providers have realized they can build things that they need
that they can then sell on to customers.
And this is a classic thing, especially with certain types of um like
just basically content provision where you provide highly
specialized content to people who kind of pay for it upfront.
And in this case, it's
quite often internal people that need this right.
We need this service or this capability to actually build
the thing that we want to provide to customers.
But then being able to very, to take.
So you've, you've sunk all that cost into building this thing
and, well, now you can sell it on to
the rest of the world at five cents a pop.
Right. Which,
and let's face it when you're reselling compute time.
That's what kills me about Amazon.
I, I was trying to figure out some of Amazon's margins
and so for like EC2, right?
They're selling compute time, whatever, But like for elastic load bouncer,
they're, they're still charging you like,
what is it like four cents an hour for an ELB?
And those El Bs are like, basically doing nothing most of the time.
And even when they are doing something, it's, it's pretty lightweight computing,
like it's
packet shuffling,
you know, it's not deep analysis.
And so they've essentially built value on
top of that kind of raw infrastructure that
allows them to charge a premium. And that's what these Cloudflare workers
allow, you know,
they even a premium of 10 or 20% on what is essentially free compute time.
That's, that's a huge amount of money potentially.
Sure. And it wouldn't shock me if these edge systems
are already exist and are doing relatively nothing
because they're just moving packets around and like,
let's face it.
We've gotten really good at shuffling packets, right?
So what do you do for the rest of the time?
-- You
-- know, as I understand it, they deploy, you know, they deploy to um
what is it now 100 and 55 data centers around the world,
they have like a rack of stuff
and I would assume they're just soaking up all
the extra compute time on all those systems.
Sure.
-- That's cool. You know, because that's what I would shoot for. Right.
-- Right.
And, and that's the right. That's the dream. Right?
Is that if you have a machine deployed somewhere,
you're utilizing 100% of the hardware,
you're having people pay to utilize 100% of the hardware,
right? No, no, that's,
I've seen a lot of places where they get that kind of they,
they miss that second part about the payment.
You know,
they have their machines doing stuff but not stuff that people actually pay for.
Look,
look at all these
Bitcoins.
Oh no. Iii I saw somebody seriously propose that,
you know, that we just
soak up all the
time, all the and no. Yeah.
So
I, and,
and this ties actually back to a conversation you and I were having is that you can't,
you can teach people new things
but you, it's really hard to force people to
unlearn old things and replace them with new things.
Like basically you can add to a person's knowledge relatively easily,
but to sort of replace or supplement core knowledge
is difficult. That's why, for example, we still have that
all that shenanigans around passwords, even though the n
people have apologized and said we were wrong,
right. But people have internalized that to such a degree that it's like,
you know, it's like calling their baby ugly.
So actually,
I have a great analogy for this because I
was actually discussing this with one of my kids
for an unrelated reason and it came so,
so the reason that that kind of came up recently in a conversation is
I don't remember the context of it. Oh, no, it was Tavis Ormandy.
Somebody made a, I'll look across the link in Twitter where somebody made
was it was it Troy?
Who did the flow chart that basically said like you need antivirus.
And then Tavis did one that basically said antivirus is dumb use whitelisting.
Oh, sorry, that one. Yeah, that was Tavis and
I
Right. OK. It's Tavis and I forget the other guy. I'll put it in Twitter. So it's fine.
So anyway, anyway,
and, and essentially I, I kind of wrote a little thing up on Twitter that said, OK,
look.
So
as funny as this is, as much as I want to agree with Tavis,
I'm going to take an objective view here and say
we don't know
if antivirus or whitelisting
are more economical and the way I see it is there's kind of three
options and I would love it if someone did some studies on this is so
you have nothing on your machine.
What does that cost you?
There is obviously going to be a cost because
you're going to assume users will get malware,
you have to clean it up and I'd love it.
If someone with the resources would look at that,
then you have a group of users with antivirus. What is?
There's obviously the cost of antivirus?
Plus, there's still going to be some cleanup because let's face an antivirus,
lets things through
and then there's whitelisting which again has a
cost because like managing the whitelists is nontrivial.
And, and of course,
I'm sure in some manner they're going to get some
malware somehow just because that's the nature of the universe.
Well, PDF. Right.
And
right.
So anyway, think of it as you have three costs and,
and I think three is too many for people to hold in their head and imagine.
So here's a better example. And this is where my conversation came from with my kids
is.
So they have in my city there is what's called the large
item drop off where you can basically take like large things.
And for example, my, my glorious old desk that I'm, I'm throwing away slowly.
It has several, several pieces.
I took one of the pieces.
I brought it to the large item drop off and basically you throw it in the trash, right?
And now there's like a big bin for metal. So it's getting recycled.
But, but anyway, you get the idea, right?
And it used to be, you just drive up,
you throw your stuff and you leave and now they have a guy sitting there who
checks your ID to make sure you're a city resident
because apparently there were people who weren't residents
that were dropping things off.
And like, this is a perfect example though. So,
like the city knows how much they're paying someone to sit there.
And obviously I'm sure it's a nontrivial amount of money
versus they know how much they were paying to have all this crap hauled away.
Even when people were breaking the rules who didn't live in town. Right.
This is super simple. If the amount you're paying,
you haul away the crap, you know how much that costs now you have to haul away,
we'll say slightly less crap.
Plus pay somebody. Which number is bigger, right?
If it's cheaper to just let people cheat, freaking let him cheat. Right.
But the problem is somebody might have been throwing hazardous chemicals away
or tires. Right. Because here, for example, there's a tire recycling fee
and so
people will, you know, try and
yeah, but they've got video cameras and all that stuff. So
they're
going to get your license plate and whatnot and, and let's face it like this guy,
he's not looking at what I'm doing.
I could, I could probably have a 50 gallon drum of toxic waste and jump, dump it off.
No problem.
Because this guy I, I pull up, I show him my ID, he's like, oh, great.
And he goes and sits back in his truck to probably play games on his phone.
-- Right. I could literally do anything.
-- Well, because I have a similar thing.
There's a, there's a garbage dump out by my parents' cabin that's open like,
four days a week and there's a guy there
and it's actually kind of nice because he, he's like, oh, you know,
dump that over there, dump that over there and dump that over there, right,
and be careful of that, you know, whatever.
And that's awesome. And he also
part of it too is, is he kind of keeps a log of how many people are using the dump?
Like, do we need to be open more days? Because for example,
uh, my local skating rink last year,
they kept numbers on how many people use the skating rink
and it was essentially, there was less than 1000 total uses of the skating rink.
And so they're like, yeah, we're not opening it this year because, like,
really people, you know,
and, and so there might be some of that. But yeah, fundamentally, I agree. Like,
I've looked for that data
off and on for ages and my
take on it has been, you know, I, I don't use, I don't run a V on my Mac
or any of my systems. Uh,
I do run them, uh, the one mail server I run, I do run a V
because not because it catches viruses but because if I don't run a
V and a virus gets through and somebody complains then I get three.
Right. And that's, and that's a lot of these things are sort of like
looking at, you know, a lot of PC I compliance.
You have to have an antivirus, you know, scanner on all your servers.
It's like, but this is like a, my,
a Linux database server. Like it. What?
No, that's not how this works.
I
know
we'll have to exclude the database tables anyways
because if the antivirus touches them they'll break.
Right.
Like, it's not like it's going to be smart enough to like, oh,
there's a record with a virus in here.
We'll just sniff that out.
-- It, it.
-- Right. Right. Right. Exactly.
And, and so anyway, this is, this is kind of one of the failings in security I think is,
well, we don't measure anything.
-- We just
-- don't, we, we don't measure, we don't know what's cheaper.
And, and I guess this is where, like,
what Clown Flare is doing is going to win because it's cheaper.
Nobody's going to say, is it more secure? They're just going to say my bill is less.
If I use this, let's use this full stop.
Well, and back to the better two, not only is my bill less but,
you know, I run c.org out of an S3 bucket. My total bill is like between three and $3.50
a month
and S3 is wicked fast to serve static content through, you know,
cloud front and cloud flare.
Like
-- it's just crazy fast.
-- Yeah, I need, I keep meaning to do that.
I've got, my website is still running off of a AVM
somewhere. I don't remember.
And anyway, it's like five bucks a month and the thing is,
it's cheap enough and it works.
And I'm like,
hey, I
don't think I care enough.
See, for me,
I specifically went to this so it couldn't really be hacked because like,
unless you somehow get my credentials and get into the S3 bucket,
you can't modify the content. You can't like, you just can't monkey with it.
That, that's it.
Right. And, and
I, I kind of agree with that, I guess at the same time I,
I'm not terribly concerned because this server is
literally running Ssh and Apache and that's it.
Like I've turned off every single Apache
extension because it's only serving static content.
And so it's like,
I, I think until the day comes where I, I like,
have to do something because either some egregious
security issue or they've end of life,
the operating system or, or whatever,
or like the company goes out of business,
that's the day I will probably care.
And until then I'll just keep saying I should
probably put that in S3 about every two months.
Honestly, the,
the main reason I did it is I zero admin costs.
Now I just pay my $3.03 dollars and 50 cents.
I have zero admin costs because I completely ignore the machine
that is one way to achieve
-- costs are also
-- zero, valid way to do it. And that's a minor risk.
And in your case, probably so close to zero that we,
it would be difficult to measure.
I'm right. Right.
If I was, in fact, that's the reason I turned off,
like all of the PHP script type things I
had running is because by turning everything off,
my, my risk goes to fundamentally zero
and, and yeah, I just,
so anyway, someday the risk won't be zero.
And I acknowledge that and that's where obviously something like S3 is nice
because Amazon will take care of the security updates for whatever it's running S3
and, and I mean, let's face it. That's the magic of it as a service.
And heck, that's even going to be an advantage of this
service is if there's a javascript security flaw, they're gonna fix it.
Right.
Whereas if, if I'm running, you know, let's say a node application,
I have to deal with upgrading everything and, and let's face it.
I'm probably busy and I'm not going to do it quickly.
Well, that's assuming you even know about it in most cases.
Right. Cloud Flare has a dedicated security team
that too, I suppose that's fair.
It would not shock me if they have people actually working with upstream
on this kind of stuff because they'd be dumb if they don't.
I mean, you need that level of competence.
And, yeah, the way you get that level of competence is by doing it.
That's, see, that's the ugly truth in security. Right.
The way you get competent at security is you go do it. That's it.
That's kind of how everything works. Right. Like security or, like cooking
some things, you can kind of learn from a book and get a good basis.
-- Like what I'm skeptical this
-- is
-- true,
-- Rubik's cube solving.
I read the online tutorial and then II I solved my son's Rubik's cube form.
It's, it's something where you can s
you can follow simple mechanical instructions.
Yeah, that's probably fair.
So for example, a game like chess, chess is a really well understood game, right?
Because we've invested,
even before deep blue, we invested like that.
I remember reading chess books as a kid,
right? Like the, the public library had a good couple of feet of chess books,
-- you know. So reading
-- about, of, of all the incredibly darky things I've done.
I have never read a book of chess. Maybe it's why I'm not good at chess.
Ok.
Well, I've maybe read several but, and I'm, I'm a pretty,
I'm still a very weak chess player because I, I don't have the patience for it.
But fundamentally with chess,
like if you read three or four chess books and
just sort of mechanically follow what they say to do,
you will like stomp 99% of chess players.
Uh that,
-- that doesn't surprise me
-- and my numbers are probably wrong because they're made up.
But, but fundamentally the problem is chess is
it's a well understood static game. The rules don't change
-- the rules,
-- right?
Same thing with the Rubik's
cube, right?
Cube doesn't change.
On the other hand,
it'd be like comparing, oh man,
that's a great analogy. Like we, someone, someone needs to build a Rubik's
cube that changes colors as you play. And like that is security.
-- Well,
-- and also once in a while, a spike comes out of it,
I know I'm thinking about this.
-- It'd be fun.
-- So you better be paying attention like
you
and, or once in a while it sprays a bit of mace out,
right? And, or it gets too hot to hold
or, or it's, it, it won't let you move it in certain ways.
Like there's like little gears to keep it from moving certain ways
random. There's like a random timer in there,
you know, plus it's connected to the internet
-- that does
-- sum things up nicely.
All right. That's,
of course it is. That, that's actually a very apt
I'm going to think about this one a little more because I think we
could take that somewhere and I think people might be able to understand it
and that's the problem with security, right?
Is, is fundamentally, everything keeps changing so fundamentally like,
I remember when containers came out, everybody, like that's not going to be secure.
And I'm like, yeah, it won't be,
but they will make it secure because they have to make
it secure because they want to sell it to enterprise.
Yep. Yep.
That's right.
And hey, look at now we're like, and that,
that's one of the things that I chuckled at is
some of the people I remember complaining about container security,
we're talking about how much more secure
containers are than this cloud flare thing.
I'm like,
I would, I would point this out to you but I don't want to get enough.
So,
uh,
so anyway, anyway. All right, man, I think it's time to bring this one home.
So I guess, yeah, our verdict is, uh,
I guess two thumbs up for cloud flare service workers.
Good job. Cloud flare.
We, we, we should like, they, they need to send us t-shirts or something.
I think we've given them enough free advertising. Right.
Well, you know,
I think they're fundamentally one of those cool companies like back, like Mozilla
used to be in the day or, you know, these companies that, that,
yeah, that's fair. That pushed
not just a product but they pushed the entire industry forwards.
Yep, I agree with that 100% there.
I think the things they're doing are redefining
the way we think about nearly everything,
which is awesome.
So, good job
Kloer. All right, sweet. I'm gonna say thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com, grab the show
notes.
You can use the Pound Os S podcast hashtag to hit
us up on social media and thank you everyone for listening.
-- I hope you all have fantastic
-- days. Thanks everybody.