Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast.
Episode zero with myself Kurtz Fried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Pressers. Is it episode zero? Yeah, it would be zero, wouldn't it?
Yeah, it's zero.
Assuming we have an eight bit counter, we started counting at one. Now we're at 256.
So it's zero. Yeah,
eight bit counter.
It would, it would wrap around because if we're,
if we're counting an eight bit integer, that means we are unsigned.
So it does not support negative values. So happy episode 256 everybody.
You mean zero? It depends how many bits I can't count that high. I have nine bits.
Now you're a nine bit episode Kurt. Oh, we're trinary.
Trinary is hot.
Is trinary hot.
I've, I've, I'm no, the Russians experimented with it and there's been some,
some stuff with like data storage.
What is trinary for anyone who has no idea what you just said?
Oh, it's three, it's three bit computing instead of two bit computing. No, no, no.
Well, ok. Sort of
three bits means, but three bits means something a bit is a zero or a one. Well, ok.
Sorry, sorry. Three states.
Yes. Sorry. States not bits. I'm, I'm so used to a bit.
Yeah.
So, the idea is in, in, well,
basically it boils down to what's the smallest piece of information.
Yes. No. Cold hot on off
two states.
Right?
Because one state is, well,
you can't change state and that makes your computer slightly useless.
And so the idea with trinary computing was that
you'd have a possibility of three states and you
could hold bigger numbers and less space and blah, blah, blah.
And it turns out, yeah, it's just not a great idea. It had some physical limitations.
I looked into this when I was in college because
it came up in one of my engineering courses.
And I'm like, wow, this sounds amazing. And then I was like, nope, just, no.
Anyway, and I apologize. It's not
trinary, it's
ternary,
whatever. Who cares? Nerds.
Yeah.
So, anyway,
I am so excited that we made it to nine bits of episode numbers.
But however, well, technically, I mean, if we get hit by a bus after this episode,
we never made it to nine bits.
But next time
I will make sure I edit and stage it quickly.
So there will be minimal chances of that happening.
I think just after the pneumonia, I'm a little bit more aware of my mortality.
Yeah. Right. I could have gone all the way wrong. I need a backup podcast host.
Now, that's what we need.
I'm pretty sure you could just rehash recordings of me through an A IML
thing and love it and then it could just be like
a random noise generator or something. It sounds great.
I believe I already qualify as one of them. I
want my co host to be a speak and spell. There you go. Oh, like Toy Story.
So, actually I have a speak and spell one of the originals. They, they re releases it
and the voice is different and they're like, oh original voice live.
And the thing is,
I love like the terribleness of the voice because it's so hilariously awesome.
I remember using speech recognition software dragon dictate 20 years ago
when you, you know,
bought a special headset with a special microphone and
it was terrible and useless and speech generation.
Of course, you know, oh, I, my first sound cards came with doctor Spa.
So, you know, dad and me how you feel. Those are awesome.
I love the voice of the, the text to speech. Anyway. Anyway,
we're not talking about synthesized speech today. Maybe another day.
I keep meaning to hack my speak and spell,
but we should do a deep fakes episode at some
point because that has really gone all the way wild.
It's fascinating. I keep meaning to try to deep fake you someday, but I'm lazy.
So it doesn't happen if anyone wants to be podcast famous, just deep fake.
Kurt send it to us. There you go.
Please don't make it too embarrassing.
We'll mention you potentially on one or more episodes.
No, I mean, technically I'll be mentioning them whether I like it or not.
Anyway. Anyway,
I'm excited to talk about eight bits and this sounds like a weird topic,
but it is something close to my heart for a variety of reasons.
And most importantly, we are now at 256 episodes.
And you know what I keep thinking of in my brain
is when you zero index something because obviously when you have eight bits,
you can actually represent the numbers 0 to 255.
And so I like,
I've literally been thinking about this all week is
should we have done this in episode 255?
Instead,
I'm like
too late. It doesn't matter, it's too late because it's 256 day.
And that's one thing I love is I,
I think I actually successfully explained counting from zero versus one
to my son. Basically saying, look in classic math terms,
you're counting the end of an object. I have one apple, I have two apples.
But in computer terms, we're, we're basically,
it's more like a street address in that I need to go there and then
read or put something, which is why we start at zero.
I'm not talking about a ray addressing this episode.
This ties into the thing I like about eight bit computing is,
it's something a human can actually understand versus a modern CPU.
No. Like if you pretend to understand a modern computer
the other day, I, I hit the keyboard combo function.
Sound up to turn up the volume on the computer and on my computer when you do that,
it brings up the volume thing and whatever is currently playing noise.
So if like youtube's on playing noise, it,
it shows youtube and I can pause and start it using the mouse.
Like it brings that up in the corner anyways, it brought up Spotify.
I'm like, but I'm not playing Spotify on my computer.
But then I realized I had been playing Spotify on my phone while I
was in the car and I just paused it and walked in the house.
So the computer basically talked to the Spotify app,
Spotify app knew that I was playing Spotify on another device and was like,
do you want to continue playing your music?
And I'm like, yeah, hit play magic.
We're talking networks, we're talking wireless, we're talking
two completely different computing platforms plus whatever's on the server side.
I don't know.
So that I can basically hit volume up and be like, oh yeah,
I want to keep hearing my music.
It's all magic
that, that's too complicated for me to understand.
I would be shocked if any one person could explain how that works.
I think there's lots of people who think they could. But I bet you realistically.
No, no, you can't.
So, anyway, but eight bit computing, you can totally explain that. Right.
Well, you can build it on a breadboard yourself.
Well, ok, there's that I was even, I wasn't even thinking of that aspect of it.
I was thinking if you look at this in the context
of like the Commodore 64 or the Nintendo Entertainment system or,
you know, pick one of these really old
just computing platforms.
And I'm going to,
I'm going to pick on the Nintendo entertainment system
here just because I have much knowledge in this
space because I love learning about it because that
was my first console when I was a kid.
That's how old I am. Everybody.
The thing is so one of the really cool things that's starting to happen now in this
space is there's all these games and I'm going to pick on the legend of
Zelda because I literally watched a video about this last night is so for example,
when you play the game, the legend of Zelda and you defeating enemies,
enemies sometimes drop money or life or whatever, right?
Random drops, drop loot,
you know, loot. Yeah, we call it loot today.
I thought we called, no, it's been called Loot since D and D
it was, did we ever call it loot? I don't know if you ever called it loot.
Well, I didn't but sure
it doesn't matter. And,
and D and D came out at what, like 7775 probably give or take.
It was
different.
But, yeah.
Right. Right.
Anyway, anyway,
so what these people have done now is they're taking
these old eight bit programs and they're doing this amazing
analysis of them to say this is exactly what is
happening inside of the application while it is running.
And it's absolutely fascinating because they've got
these emulators and you can put information
up on the screen and you can pay attention to certain memory addresses.
You can.
And it's super easy to understand what's going on. Which I think from
the angle of I want to say, write an exploit that runs machine code.
This kind of knowledge is invaluable. I, I've been playing,
I have six on my computer and I have a pretty beefy computer
and it still takes a while for each turn
to complete like the computer is doing and I check
my CPU graphs and like all eight cores are like at 80% and you're playing on easy mode,
right?
Prints or Chieftain or whatever.
But yeah, basically three levels up from like I'm a child and on hard mode.
I don't even want to think about how long a turn will take on hard mode. I
assuming you just don't die in the third round.
Yeah, the,
the A I is in civilization are freakishly smart. It is ridiculous.
And the bat played on an ipad and it runs the battery
down in an hour and then get a little surprised by that.
I've specifically warned my son, he wants to play it on his mobile devices.
I'm like this will kill your mobile device battery.
You need to play it plugged in and even then
the battery will slowly lose charge because it's using that much.
That's amazing.
Yeah, like my ipad gets warm to the touch. Like I got an ipad pro.
Like, it's not some old ipad.
So, yeah,
that's awesome.
That's awesome. No, I haven't played Civilization in years. It is.
Civilization is one of those games that I is,
is a danger because it will consume my life if I touch it.
And so I purposely avoid it at all costs.
The other thing that's annoying is you watch, like,
the spiffing brit play it and he just abuses the heck out of the game and wins,
you know, with one city and not doing anything other than
some game hack. I'm ok with abuse. That's
fine. It's, you're just hacking the game, right? That's, that's cool.
But it's also really hard because you have to learn a lot of weird tricks
that no normal person would ever do.
So anyway, we're talking about eight bit computing today and back to the,
actually understanding the entire state of the system.
And that's one of the biggest things in security is
people think they understand the entire state of the system,
but there's some mismatch or some glitch somewhere or something,
not quite behaving as they expected.
Yeah. And, and then the attacker finds that in game over.
Let's just be clear, I think in any modern computing platform,
even what we would think of as the absolute simplest, it is impossible for any.
I would even say a single team to have a
grasp of what's actually happening in the environment because we've
just reached a point of complexity that you have to
draw a line and say I will care about every
from this line forward.
And I cannot like, do you know what kernel version you're running?
Do you know what the libraries are in your container orchestrator?
Do you have a container orchestrator? You know what I mean?
There's literally millions of questions.
How many people think they understand a bug, write a patch and it's not
the full solution. Oh my gosh, that's one of my favorite things I have.
I have one of my favorite stories I have on that is so I remember a long time ago I,
when fuzzing was brand new, I wrote my own fuzz
because it was the cool thing to do. And I started fuzzing fonts
and there's a font library in the Linux world called free type.
And so I start fuzzing fonts and I had
a ridiculous number of crashes and I did the right thing where I was like, OK,
this font crash is here.
This font crashes you know what I mean?
I was making sure they weren't duplicates because obviously when
you fuzz something you're gonna get lots of duplicates.
I tried to do the right thing and I send this incredibly detailed write up end of patch
to the free type people, right?
With basically like here's what I found,
here's reproduce or here's a patch that makes it go away step.
And they're like,
oh all of these problems are caused by a missing
check way over here in this particular bit of code.
Whereas it was obviously like three function calls beneath where I was at.
And I'm like,
they're all the same bug every one of them. And it was hilarious.
One good quote I heard was a programmer needs
to understand the abstraction above and below them.
In other words, you need to,
you have your little kingdom
and you go to the walls of your kingdom and talk to the other kingdom next to you.
And yeah, I like that. And so quite frankly, like,
I will never care about my colonel again.
I, no, I just won't. I mean, I barely, but I don't have to,
I run a mix of Windows,
Linux and Mac Os and you know what I don't care because they all support bash,
they all support
new set and a
they all support like the tools I actually want to run like chrome web browser,
Firefox,
uh an email. Well, I don't run an email client anymore. I use the webinar face to join.
It's magic. Yeah.
So why would I care what operating system I run when
I'm just sitting in a web browser all the time.
That is fair.
The only time I know what my kernel is is I own a pine
Book Pro which is a little arm laptop and it is always broken.
So
I have to pay attention to my kernel because it's like, oh,
I'm running this kernel now.
I need to downgrade to that kernel or whatever.
And it's really funny because it's, it's one of those things where like, I'll,
I'll turn it on and everything works and then I'll literally like,
turn it off and turn it back on a little while later and like, nothing
works.
And I'm like, I didn't even change anything on this stupid computer, which is,
it's very much like running Linux in the nineties.
You
no idea what's going to happen. I love it.
The other thing I love too is I'm running software
that runs seamlessly on three very different operating system platforms.
And actually I ordered a Mac M one, the Mac mini M one which has an arm chip,
exciting totally different architecture at the CPU level.
And I know that everything will just work.
Yeah. Well, everything I use will just work well.
But the beauty is here from a security point of view and
this has been proven many times is that by supporting multiple architectures.
You pop out weird bugs. That is very true.
I remember the GEN two crew was really good at this
back in the day because you not only had weird architecture,
it's,
but you also had weird combinations of things because with Gen two,
for those who don't know, Gen two was a Linux.
I think Gen two is still around. Oh Yeah. Yeah. Slack. We still around. That's true.
But
if
you
that actually died was the D razzle.
I don't even know.
But anyway,
so Gen two was a Linux distribution that you basically built everything yourself.
And so you could say like, oh, I want to support this but not that or this and that.
And so depending upon the features you would add to what was called your use flags,
you would build applications in different ways.
And so obviously you can end up with
these bizarre combinations of libraries that no one
ever imagined a contractor pointed out once he
loved Gen Two from a security point of view
because every single system, even if you configured them all the same,
every single one had different return addresses.
That's true. Now though, thanks to address space randomization.
Well, and now that nowadays that wouldn't matter,
but back in the day 20 some years ago, that it made a difference.
I mean, I guess you could argue that because, you know,
calm exploit codes would just fail on your Gen two machines all the time.
Well, they were hard coded to only work on, you know, one vendor package.
That's how things used to work.
Those were the good old days when ex flight writing was easy.
Yeah. No, that, that time is done. But I mean, while it was there it was,
yeah.
Two.
Yeah, that, I remember gen two,
like just the weirdest freaking bugs because of those weird combinations.
And
so, ok,
so I want to use this to pivot us back into eight
bit computing because that's what we're supposed to be talking about.
And
for some reason we got off topic. So OK. OK.
So I think you bring up an interesting point when you talk
about kind of weird combinations and different architectures and all this stuff.
And
so, I mean, you have to imagine so in the eight bit world,
a significant amount of what was done was written in assembly, right?
Which is
bananas to think about today. Well, because what other tool did they have?
I mean, there were, you could use C to a degree for some of this.
They had basic, actually,
most of the eight bit computers came with a basic interpreter
and a not like if you're into Commodore 60 fours,
a nontrivial amount of the software for the Commodore 64 was just literally
written in basic and then stored on a literal audio cassette tape.
Anyway. Anyway, and so you have to think about it. So today you have a web browser that
will work on
almost any computer you can touch.
And I don't even like calling it a web browser anymore.
Because for example, it has a virtual machine capable implementation
of
javascript. Like
you can run Linux in your web browser.
It's a higher level operating system, it is what it is.
But the point is so in the, in the, in the olden days in the eight bit universe, right?
Like
if you wrote a piece of software for say, the Nintendo Entertainment system,
the Nes, I'm just going to try to call it Nes from now on.
That's the only place it ran, right? You couldn't port it to something else.
Like when people ported software and this is, this is fascinating
when you ported software,
you didn't like start with a code and then make it work on another platform.
You usually looked at it, you took the graphics and you rewrote it from scratch.
Like there was no that, that, that's what we call parting. That was, that's bananas.
Yeah, but I mean,
well, a part of that is this whole ecosystem thing, right?
Like I looked into this in Rocketry and we had all
the ideas to make Rocketry work for quite a while.
But for example, we didn't have the alloys,
you know, to make engines that wouldn't melt
or we didn't have the flight control understanding to make things not veer off
course you mentioned alloy and I have
something fascinating for everyone to think about.
So I love space and I watch as much space content
and news and I listen to space podcasts and it's like,
it's my side hobby that I adore and
there was, I think it was,
I forget which
one of the up and coming commercial space companies was testing a rocket.
And in the video,
the fire was coming up green and the people were like, oh, look green fire,
that means it's burning itself up from the inside.
I'm like, that is,
that's wild. Like that old advice where, you know, you can throw your old night
a batteries in the fire to make pretty colors. Right.
But, yeah, I mean, they, they saw the green and of course,
they were super calm about it, which I think is always funny because
you're standing in a bunker at a safe distance, hopefully.
And the rocket is literally burning itself up for
inside and they're like, oh, it's green
and it was just like, ah, it's, it's one of those things that it,
until you hear someone say it, you're like, holy crap.
That's true. I mean, there's,
there's fire coming out of the bottom of this thing.
Of course, it's going to burn itself up.
Well,
not necessarily because they do clever hacks like alloys that don't melt as much,
or they run the fuel in a tube around the,
the nozzle to pre heat the fuel and to cool down the nozzle so it doesn't melt itself.
Like that's one thing they had to do with those, um, those, what are they slam jets?
You know,
the ones that basically just have an air engine intake that compresses the air,
they shoot the fuel and because the pressure is so high it auto ignites,
you know, we're talking speeds of mach 10 to 20
scramjet scramjets. Yeah. Anyways.
And so, you know,
they were doing things like running the fuel through the nose of the vehicle to
pre heat the fuel but to also prevent the nose of the vehicle from melting.
I remember learning of this when there was a
time in my youth when I adored conspiracy theories,
which I would not suggest anyone do anymore, but there was a,
supposedly an aircraft faster than the sr 71
that people were talking about at the time.
And I don't think it ever came out if there was or wasn't,
but it was fascinating to learn about all the crazy things
they have to do to run an aircraft at that speed.
I just love that the sr 71 fuel tanks can't be properly sealed.
So they just leak when it's on the ground and then once it gets up to speed,
the metal expands and it seals that whole
airplane and they build it with slide rules.
I mean, it's
ridiculous.
Well, and Titanium, you know,
purchased from the Russians through intermediaries, but everything's fine.
Here everybody.
It's,
yeah.
Well, on the 747 slide rules,
I know. I know. It's amazing. And I guess so, actually that's a good point.
Like you can do a lot with a bit computing if you know, you like the Apollo,
the Apollo missions.
I wonder, did they even have a bits?
I have no idea what that their computer was an amazing creation for sure.
And there's,
there's fascinating stories and videos about it out on the internet
that I'd encourage everyone to go just read 15 data bits
and one.
So, actually that's a funny topic to us.
So, back in the day of the eight bit universe,
it would not be uncommon for a computer to have a weird number of bits.
Like, I think there was an old mainframe that had 13 bits,
just like weird bizarre combinations and it was just because it was add a few bits.
It's fine. Right.
Well, look at your askew table. You actually only need half your
Asy table. Seven bits, man.
Yeah. Like, I remember finding out about the stuff above 128 and I was like, what?
It's
got the little smiley face who doesn't like that
and the bell, everyone liked the bell. Yeah.
And the pound sign and the little, the single and double lines to make your menus.
Oh, yes.
I remember those, like, straight up when I discovered that I was like, just,
it literally blew my mind, you just use dashes and pluses.
It's fine. Exactly. Ask you.
Oh,
my goodness.
That brings it back anyway. Anyway, a bit,
a bit.
I think it's the reason this is sort of important is by knowing where you come from.
It gives you an understanding of where we are and how
we got here because there's so many security things that have,
like, people complain about things, say with certificates and I'm like,
when they built this 20
years ago you couldn't do that 20 years ago
or more. Yeah.
Uh, you know, things like, oh,
you just want to run a website that's
globally available 100% of the time to everybody.
You couldn't do that 10 years ago with less than a billion dollars.
And now it's, I think you have to pay klopper
$0 a month
and I think you get the always on thing or maybe it's 20 bucks a month.
I mean, pretty much.
Ok. Ok. Here's what I want to talk about.
We talk about, you know, knowing where you came from,
being able to learn and do things.
And so I want to use this and I have a great example. What is the largest number you can,
I guess, just store
in eight bits, right?
You have eight bits.
Well, I mean, if you start counting in multiples of one then theoretically 256
right? But I know that you can go higher but, but well. Ok.
Yeah, you can combine the integers and bits and whatever. I don't care about that.
So, now that, but that's an unsigned integer, right? And
so there's signed and unsigned integers and signed integers I would
say are probably more common and useful to most people.
So, what's the largest signed integer you can represent with eight bits?
Well,
depending on where you start counting negative because it's going to be 127 or 128.
Yeah,
that's true because there's different ways to portray
negative numbers and we won't get into that.
Well, it also depends.
Do you negative 127 to positive 128 or negative 128 to positive 127 because
you've got that zero in the middle splitting it generally raps to the negative
largest number.
Well, what I'm saying is you can't have it 120 to 128 because you also need zero.
Well, is there a negative zero in your counting method as well? There are,
there's ways to represent numbers that have negative zero and positive zero, but
we're not going to get into that. We're not, we're going to pretend like normal,
we're just going to pretend it's fine, it's fine.
Like here's my favorite example, right
on an Nes Super Mario brothers, right
in level 3-1 there is a famous trick we call
turtle topping that lets you get essentially infinite lives.
So, if you can't have infinite lives because
guess what happens when you cross the 127 mark of number of lives you have,
you get negative lives, I guess for the game things when you have negative lives
game over. Yeah, same thing in SIV. Nuclear Gandhi.
Oh, nuclear Gandhi is the greatest bug in the history of video games.
Explain what that is for people who don't know in SI,
I forget, oh, this is SI five. Wow, that is a long time ago.
I forgot how long it was between these games. Anyway, in SI
51 of the characters is Gandhi. Although I think he's been a character since ever
and
Gandhi is, yeah, he's very peaceful. Very nice. Nice man.
Right. Exactly. His peace score increases
until it integer overflows and becomes
that one actually. Underflow. Oh, underflow. Sorry.
It's an aggression score and his is like zero.
Yeah.
Sorry and well, yeah, he basically goes from very, very, very nice to very, very,
very, not nice.
It basically goes from 0 to 255.
And usually at that point in the game he has nukes, right? And he nukes everybody.
Although in fairness, if you may, if you survive the game that long,
you're doing pretty well.
Yeah, but the bug is still there. I guess they was not a bug anymore.
It's like a feature
but there's still the ability for, for Gandhi to become like super aggressive,
which I think is one of the greatest features in any video game ever love it.
It makes me smile every time I think of it.
I just, I like that. It reflects the reality of things just sometimes go sideways.
But, and so here's the thing, right is when we talk about video games,
you can have these weird bugs, you can have integer, overflows, integer underflow,
whatever buffer overflows doesn't matter.
And it's funny,
well, you know, it does matter because like, for example,
it used to be people played against the computer and if you abuse the game cool.
I watch these massively multiplayer online role playing
games or like things like Rust or,
you know, escape from Tarko
and the cheaters make the game suck.
Yeah. Oh, yeah. Yeah, definitely.
You know, and so they get back banded or whatever. So I would argue
when you're just playing against your own
computer or fiddling against your own computer.
It's like a test lab situation. Who cares what you think? We're talking about.
Eight bit, eight bit video games, right? Big deal.
But, well, and that's the thing,
eight bit video games didn't have to deal with multiplayer games except
when you were playing Mario Kart with your little brother or something,
you know.
But
then he can just punch you in the arm. That's true.
Stop looking at my screen.
Oh, my favorite is all those ones where the people have the cardboard rigged up.
Like, I
never did that. But the first time I saw that I thought, why didn't I think of that?
Yeah.
So the deal is basically you just, you tape cardboard, like to the ends of the TV,
either horizontally or vertically to split the screen
and so that you can't be technically stream sniping, I guess
the time
for it now. Yeah, I guess, I guess anyway, anyway,
like
those kind of bugs are funny though, right?
Learn though as well.
Sometimes like I didn't even know what an integer
overflow was when I was playing Super Mario Brothers.
And then when you start understanding what this stuff means,
it's a fascinating way to learn what is happening inside of the computer, right?
In a way that you can understand because in 64 bit computing, when you overflow,
an integer, you're talking about like an unreasonably large number,
I just keep coming back to the whole
understanding what's going on also having language for it
and not just words for it, but what do those words mean?
And that's something I'm seeing with a lot of newer security stuff,
especially around.
Give me an example, what is an integer overflow?
Well,
there's a formal definition for that versus an integer underflow versus a buffer,
a buffer overflow versus buffer underflow versus
buffer overread versus buffer under read,
right?
Those four things in the buffer world are very, very different
and they're formally cataloged and classified, for example, in the CWE project.
But for example,
in the Blockchain space and the cloud space,
there's a whole bunch of stuff that we don't even have words for,
let alone definitions.
And so security's a bit of a disaster there because how do we even talk about
it? That's an interesting observation actually.
And I think it's a good point to kind of work ourselves out of
this on is you're correct when you don't have words to describe things,
it changes everything.
You can't fix a problem when you can't describe the problem.
I have something even more fascinating for you and I will try to dig this up.
There is a video, the internet where someone was discussing colors
and the names of colors. There is a group of people in, I think it's in Africa
that their native language doesn't have a name for. I think it's green or blue.
I forget which color.
And you can like, if you showed us a picture with like a bunch of green and blue on,
say a wheel, we'll instantly say like that one's blue, that one's green, right?
No questions asked.
And if you show this to these people, they'll tell you they're all the same color.
And so it's, it's looking like as you have names for things,
our brains change the way we even see them and understand them,
which is absolutely fascinating having names for things I think changes the entire
universe in the way we see it and how we interact with it.
Well, and so in western music it's mostly what,
like four time beat or maybe a three time beat,
if it's a waltz and I forget there's an
eastern European country where they have seven time music.
I've never heard of that.
And so, well, they did a study and essentially to us it sounds like noise
But to the people with that grew up with the seven time music,
not only do they understand and hear the seven time music,
but they can also very easily parse the four time music
because in a way it's very, it's simpler, interesting.
And so I, I like, like I keep coming back to this.
How do we discuss a problem, let alone try and solve a problem if we can't even discuss
the problem and have words to identify it.
You know, there's new words now that I have had to learn as an adult unconscious bias.
The, these are not words I grew up with, they didn't exist when I grew up. It's true.
And, and so it, I, I have had to change how I think about a lot of things in the world,
you know, and it's possible now I couldn't have done this 20 years ago because, well,
to go on 1984 you know, with Orwellian double
or what is it good speak or whatever it was.
Called, you can't discuss a revolution if you don't have the word revolution.
That is true.
And so I'm really glad to see now that we're,
we're aware of this problem and people are fixing it.
You know, people are coming out with these terms. What do they mean?
How do they apply?
You know, and in computer security we've had that happen right now,
20 years ago it was all Black magic and now there's courses and really nice books.
There are, there are, it's so easy now, compared to 20 years ago,
there is one thing I want to end this on that.
I've been thinking about a lot lately and this is,
this is related to open source licenses which we will discuss in the future.
But Kurt and I are still hashing out ideas.
But when we talk about language and we talk about
what the definition of things are and you know,
what, what the, what you mean by what the definition of is is sort of thing.
I know
I went there
for anybody under the age of 30
let them
look it up, let them look it up, look it up anyway.
So, but here's the thing, right? Is
there are powerful forces
in charge of almost everything now.
And this is if you look at basically every foundation on the planet,
look at the members, right?
It's all the same members and all the same
foundations and they're basically all driving the bus.
And I think this is one of the challenges for us as practitioners is
we have to be prepared to define things in a way that is accurate
and make sense.
Because there are other people who want to define
things in a way that accommodates their worldview.
You can absolutely manipulate language to get what you want. Exactly.
And we see that all the time in the news cycle,
you look at various news channels and the way they use words and how they,
and which words they use.
It's shocking
and security is no different.
There are things that aren't defined or are defined incorrectly or are used wrong.
And sometimes it's because people are confused and
sometimes it's because people have an agenda,
they're pushing marketing.
Right. I would say that's agenda you're pushing.
But. Right. Right. Exactly. And so it's a unique challenge we have. It's not unique.
It's, it's pretty global, I would say to everything.
It's the story of humans instead of creating
value and making the world a better place.
There's a bunch of people who just want to capture existing value and sit on it.
Yeah. And that's exactly right. Right. Change is hard.
And I guess that's,
and thank goodness we've changed from eight bit computing because holy crap,
it's, I love talking about it with nostalgia,
but I'm so really glad I don't develop on AIC computers.
I love that systems on a chip now that run on like a
watt of power are more powerful than my desktop 20 years ago.
They just run Linux
now. It's awesome.
Like my, my legal control brick boots up and says Linux kernel version,
some ridiculously small version and I'm like,
whatever. Exactly. I don't have to worry about.
Oh, this loop needs 1000 instructions, but I can only give it 800. So, how am I gonna?
Like, I don't care.
It doesn't matter. I have infinite resources at my disposal. Now.
Anyway, anyway, I'm, I'm going to call this.
This was a lovely trip down a bizarre memory lane. We'll call it. So, thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. Go to open source security podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes, use the Pound Os S Podcast.
Hashtag Do hit us up on social media and Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks everybody. Bye
-- bye.