Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself Kurtz Siefried
and my partner in fleeing Twitter from Mastodon, Josh Bresser.
Holy cow. Do we have a fun conversation today? So there's a thread
on infosec dot exchange that's all about kind of the M fa and, and
account setups and stuff. And it's just fascinating
that on the security instance,
-- there's only like 16% of people using
-- M fa, I mean, in fairness, my account,
I didn't even bother to enable M FA
because I have a strong password manager generated password
and I don't use that account like I have it like I was going to use it,
but then I ended up at Master Dawn dot social.
So I did the transfer thing of a jigger.
And so it's like, yeah, is that really a problem? I don't think so.
But yeah, it was kind of shocking. I think it was 16
percent or something
-- use M fa
-- which 16%. And I'm disappointed that you didn't, uh you know, invite me here.
I had to find out about this,
your direct messages
J Bell. Welcome to the show.
All right,
for anyone who doesn't know we've got Jerry here and he runs
Infosec dot Exchange and we are ecstatic to have you here,
Jerry.
-- Thank you. Absolutely
-- happy to be here. Thank you for having me.
-- So
-- why don't you set this one up for us?
Because you're actually the horse's mouth in this instance,
instead of us just repeating whatever we've read on various threads on Mastodon.
So
um
specific to two fa you know, there's been,
I think a lot of consternation slash disappointment
at the level of adoption of two fa
on, on our, on our uh infosec that exchange masted on instance, it's, um you know,
it started off at about 16% or so.
But the, you know, the reality is like we went, the instance is, you know,
five years old.
And so there's, there's quite a few old events in the
notes. And so if you
count that
and you only look at the people who have recently registered,
it's closer to the 25 to 30% range.
And even after, by the way, like badgering people to do it. And I know that there were
people who, who did go turn it on, it didn't really move the needle much.
I'm shocked like, OK, so here is, I think the, the,
the fundamental discussion that I was interested in having on this is
if you listen to security people,
we're all telling everyone to turn on multi factor authentication constantly,
right?
Like I, I feel like it's an underlying message in every discussion.
-- I
-- think
-- it's replaced that you have to install antivirus message from, like,
20 years ago.
Yeah, I'll take that.
But, like, so there's this underlying theme of, oh, you have to do this,
but we're not doing it.
I mean, even 30% feels
-- painfully low to me.
-- Absolutely.
Now, there's, you know, is, it is, it's come out, there's quite a few reasons.
There's some people who,
who don't think it's important to do in the context of a Mastodon account.
There's
people who didn't know that the setting even existed.
There are lots of people who registered through a
mobile app and the mobile app doesn't expose that.
There's um,
-- I,
-- I find the mobile apps are problematic in so many ways.
Like my feed is six items in my mobile app and
then I log in on the website and it's like bl,
you know,
yeah,
I don't know what the deal there is.
I know that there's a lot of people and II, I have a feeling it's,
you know, that Twitter kind of trained, trained us a certain
behavior. I've been
on, obviously been using Mastodon for, for quite some time
and I've tried
over the years, I've tried lots and lots of different
mobile apps and to be honest, I keep just coming back to the webinar
because it's so much
more reliable. It, uh more feature rich, I guess.
Well, and like, I noticed in some mobile apps,
they use different words for like they call it D MS
or they call it like they just use different verbiage.
And I was looking, I'm like,
is this, this is a master
app, right? Like, like this is not a
I it was,
yeah, I, I feel bad for normal people trying to use these things.
Anybody can go and create a, create an app and post it to the,
you know, to, to the app store, the Google Play Store. Like there's not a,
like there's no,
you know, authoritative
source for, for Mastodon or fevers
apps. So
that doesn't actually surprise me that much.
Who knew?
Ok, so here is one of my questions, I guess then for, for the two of you to,
to think about, I feel like
I'm not totally surprised that security people haven't enabled a lot
of two factor uh for many of the reasons we've described.
But I think the root of the problem is
that multi factor authentication is hard to use.
I think it's still too hard to use for normal people.
And
that feels like the crux of the issue to me.
I want to add to that.
I think it's worse than that because using two fa within a company where you
have like a concierge level of service to
recover your account if something goes wrong.
And even there we get pushed back on people using two fa
and like for myself using two fa, like, I have a bunch of tokens.
I still have to ferry one to the bank safe deposit box.
So, if my house burns down it's, you know, I have it.
Yeah, normal people aren't willing to do this, like, for their own account.
I just, I only do it because, you know, I preach it.
So I'm supposed to be doing it, I guess.
And,
yeah, I,
I can't help but think that it's just if
you use a good password and a password manager,
that's like 99% of your protection right there.
Right. I,
I'm making up that number but it seems about right.
It really depends on what you're,
what you're trying to guard against. But in general,
yes.
Uh, I, I will tell you a big problem.
People have, say internet properties in general have, is
people using the same password
across sites.
They have to like, if they don't use a password manager,
what else are they going to do?
I will say, by the way, you know, you, you brought up an interesting point there,
there are
people who have M fa enabled on, on our instance.
So it's, you know, a fair amount bar, none.
The most common request for help I get is
I locked myself out
a new phone, my phone broke,
you know, I have seen so many
different stories of what happened to people's phones
and, uh, it's, it's pretty funny
And um you know, so, so I would probably estimate I've, I've had to unlock
maybe 100
notes in the past month.
Now, how does that compare?
So,
obviously Mastodon has had an enormous influx of users
in the last like two months or so,
have most of those come recently or have they been spread out
-- evenly over the last five years or
-- in the first five years?
Maybe it happened twice?
Holy cow since it's all happened since October 27th.
Oh, my goodness. I mean, so this doesn't totally surprise me, I guess, but it also,
I think raises one of the enormous challenges.
So I don't want to, I want you to explain this in a way that doesn't make a mess for you.
But
when you,
how much verification are you doing? If someone says, oh, I lost my phone, like
what that,
because obviously you're kind of the guy who does
all the work here to verify and reset things.
So, so typically I, I
rely on their ability to,
um, to have access to their email account.
-- That makes sense. That's fair.
-- There's, there's, there's been a couple of
exceptional cases outside of that, like where,
um in particular somebody's registered an account on behalf, you know,
in somebody else's name.
And so we've, we've, I've had to go through some
inu
verification of who they are. But beyond that, it's,
you know, I've, I've relied on people's ability to access their email.
Well, that's, I mean,
that's every recovery system I've ever seen comes back to either their
email address or their phone number because what else can we do?
Like, there's no other way to push a message to them
and,
and there's nothing else that's unique,
right?
Their option would be just to tell, tell them, look,
you're out of luck and you got to go create
-- a new account which does
-- happen from time to time.
And this is so let's explain this because I don't think everyone understands what,
what we just talked about.
So when you
have an account on any service and you set up multi factor authentication,
you obviously have a user name, you have a password, which should be in a password
manager and then you have your multi factor, you could have a aub key,
you could have an authenticator app on your phone, whatever.
Right. There's that, that thing you have and
if you lose your phone or you lose your UI
key or whatever,
you have no way to get into your account
without contacting
somebody who can basically reset the multi factor authentication in the case of,
of or disable it.
Right. Right. Well, exactly, in the case of Infosec dot Exchange,
they have to contact Jerry and say Jerry,
please take pity on me and do this and this sounds simple, but it's not
because I mean, so let me ask how many people are in infosec that exchange now,
36,000.
Ok. And you've got 100 requests,
you grew to
360,000.
Well,
apart from probably not having anything else to
do in your life except manage the instance.
But now you'd be talking 1000 requests, right?
Like this, this generally scales linearly,
right?
That is not
a tenable situation.
-- Well, unless you automate it, we would
-- either have to automate it.
You know, there, there is a um
you know, that there is an api that I,
I could envision some way to automate it,
but that's, that's not super ideal.
Most likely I would have to enlist,
-- you know, volunteers to help and then
-- vet them
because,
well, we've learned from
in,
you know.
Right.
I know, I know. Right.
It's like, I'm, I'm definitely not, you know,
a Chinese national here offering to help you reset M fa S Jerry.
Like, you know,
it is a challenge that will continue to grow, right?
And, and by the way, that's one of the reasons I, I um
I, I made a post that was pretty provocative and controversial in the,
in the security community.
I, I
told people turn two fa on and put the two fa into a password manager.
And, and so which is what I do and, and, and it's not the pure,
you know, it's not the purest way of doing it because,
you know, like I don't have it on a, I mean, I do have a ya
key
but I use that for like accessing the underlying infrastructure.
But in terms of accessing, you know, like logging into websites and what not.
I have the, the two fa that the top pe the time based one time password
codes are in,
you know, in the profiles for my, my I DS and, and it's convenient because if I lose my,
if I lose my phone, I've got everything set up in my life, my laptop, my phone whatnot.
I've got everything set up in my life
that the device is ephemeral. I can lose my phone.
If you get a new phone,
I have to sign into a couple of things and I have all of my files.
I have all my passwords back.
I have to remember a couple of complicated passwords that
would let me get back into my Onedrive account,
my one password account and that's it.
So, so that's why that's what I'm trying to encourage people
to do because otherwise, you know, if you have an
a, you know, you have a,
an authenticator app on your phone
and it doesn't have the ability to sync to something else,
you have that problem like you will
eventually get a new phone and you will almost certainly forget to migrate them.
We had one of our devs get locked out of his Cloud Flower account and fun fact,
Cloud floor has that vision of your account is your account so
even I with control of the email domain was like they're like,
yeah, you can't do it like he has to fix it.
And
uh
yeah, it was a nightmare.
So I think what you said,
Jerry is good advice for normal people and
I'm sure security people are losing their minds.
But the,
the thing I have in the back of my head at the moment is I was a last pass customer
and my safe, it was probably stolen by an attacker. And so that's the one thing
that
scares me to death
about putting two factor off
-- into my password manager.
-- What's, what's more likely to happen?
Oh, II, I agree completely. I mean,
and for people I know for normal people,
100% put it in the password manager because you're going to lose your phone,
you're going to lose your UI
key. I mean, my daughter has a UI
key. I gave her on her birthday.
She has no idea where it is.
That's not a present.
Shut up. That's like giving them a shovel and like pointing at the garden.
But I, I can't help but wonder if one of the things that might really help here is, is,
you know, the apple pass key stuff that's just coming out because
like, yeah, II I too, like, I've
looked like we actually have policy at the CS A where, where possible,
please save your two of a into one password
because that way when you get clobbered by a bus or something, you know,
the organization can access the stuff,
you know, it's our stuff, not really your stuff. And on a personal level.
Well, I'm stuck using Google authenticator because I'm, anyways, I feel like the,
the sort of long term solution here is what Apple is doing,
which is to give people the ability to do certain things and let them pick,
kind of like what level of security you want.
Like
we can have the encryption keys too so we can recover your account or
if you really want to, you can, you know,
we don't have your encryption keys in your icloud stuff is really,
really encrypted and like
it's on you to make sure you have a recovery system set up for that
and then they offer some options there to make it a bit easier.
Like you can link it to this other account or I
feel like that's kind of the way to go long term.
And I mean, I think
Malo does a good job of
like it, you're forced to set up a TA
P first and then you can add hard rookies and
one thing it doesn't do, which I, I think it should is I've seen obviously
places that you register top people with,
it's like now enter a code to make sure you know that you actually set it up correctly.
I will say,
you know, Mastodon is uh it's it's free software
and, and I, I have, I have made, um, you know, quite a,
quite a number of um improvement requests including
in the area of two factor authentication.
And I mean,
I totally agree with you.
Everything you just said,
ok, I want to clarify something that Kurt
just mentioned in passing that I think is really cool.
So, in the Mastodon Universe,
when do you set up two factor authentication?
It supports uh what is it web
a then
Fido keys kind of whatever that I, I forget what they're calling it these days,
but
that's like a UB key for example, or a Google Titan key or one of those things.
But before you can do that, you have to set up like a atotp.
-- Uh I forget what totp stands for but
-- time something, the password. I mm
I don't know, I don't know, it doesn't matter
but like, like Google authenticator off
or something on your phone.
So you, you have to have a second kind of factor if you're using
the
Fido keys,
which I think is cool because those things are small and they're easy to lose.
Correct top P stands for time based one time password.
Just
there we go
vou two F which is what um
what Mastodon supports. And increasingly so
it's actually pretty cool because I,
I have a Lenovo laptop with which has the fingerprint
reader.
And what do you go up? And when you go set up a device, not only do I have my, my
uh
yi set up as a authenticator,
but also it will use the
because it has the T PM chip in it. It will actually use
the fingerprint reader as, as a, as an authentication device.
So when I go to log in to mass,
then all I have to do is touch the fingerprint reader and that's, that's handy.
I do think by the way,
in the future, we, we have to, we have to find a way away from passwords.
We're seeing
some innovation,
you know, from the likes of Microsoft and Apple.
And I don't know what standard will,
you know, I don't know where we're going to land in the next five or 10 years, but
I think where we're at right now
is just not a tenable place.
What I'm reminded of is, I think we're like,
passwords are kind of like the horse and the solution is not more horses,
like the solution to passwords is not password managers.
That's not,
that's not, you know, like we're going to end up like knee deep in horse poop.
We are knee deep in horse poop.
-- Yeah,
-- exactly.
And because I mean, what really gets me about passwords is, for example, you know,
I have one of my sons has autism.
Yeah. Passwords really do not work for that guy,
you know, but being that he has an Apple iphone and with a password, you know,
fingerprint scanner.
Yeah. Super awesome. Works just easy.
I mean, the one piece of good news is like Windows. Windows. Hello.
Now, not only supports you logging into your computer with your face,
but it supports web off then.
So actually I as an option, like when I'm setting up web off, then I'm presenting,
you know, do you want to use a security key?
Do you want to use your phone? Do you want to use your face?
Like it's, it's getting there slowly and it's,
it's certainly easier to set up like your face and your thumb
as opposed to like having multiple UB keys. Right?
And so I, I'm hopeful for the future. But yeah, like,
like you said, we're, I think we're still a ways away.
All right, I'm going to be the eternal pessimist here
and I, I think I put something I master it on about this a couple of weeks ago,
but
I have a suspicion the password of this office
is going to go well with the paperless office.
Well, Legacy software, right?
Like I have a, a person who I know who works for the government
and they're still using AD OS based insurance program
that's been mangled fire into doing some other,
you know, kind of payment system aspect for the government.
And it doesn't even actually support passwords, technically speaking,
like they stuck it behind a web firewall thing.
Yeah, I think, I think your point though is
as we move forward,
that the technology we're creating is just going to be
generating pass passwords at more passwords at a faster rate,
just like the paperless office has generated,
you know,
in, in fancy ways of creating paper at an alarming pace.
You know, one of the challenges that I think we just,
we have is passwords are the least common denominator.
And it, you know, it's every, every freaking app out there
has
a, has support for a password.
I mean, pretty much and,
and it's going to take us a really long time to get away from that.
And so we're going to be living with,
with password managers probably through my lifetime.
I bet.
Well, I mean, I guess
the good news is, it's, you know, it's built into your web browser,
it's built into your phone system.
It's Android ecosystem has it like.
So, II, I guess that's an improvement where it's built in by default.
Well, ok,
there's, I think a second piece to this is the three of us are not young gentlemen.
We'll say we, we've seen some stuff and back 20 plus years ago,
remember when everyone would roll their own authentication
where you just wrote your web app and you're like, oh,
I'll just put a password field here and we'll put it in the database and
maybe
you hashed it maybe,
probably not,
you know, and now all the web frameworks have,
we'll say strong password handling where it has the ability to do various resets.
It, it hashes the crap out of it using whatever n
latest algorithm is
like
it got easy
and I have a suspicion,
whatever comes next
is going, once it makes it into the web frameworks, then we will see traction.
But I think until it's default,
it's just not going to happen.
-- I think
-- you're right.
That's what's going to make the, the difference is make, making it, you know,
built into those frameworks like Lara
O
and you know what not. That's, that's what's
going to drive, drive things forward.
I'm shocked to learn that the default setting is the one people use.
All right. All right.
So, so we're kind of running ourselves out of time a little bit here with you,
Jerry and I figure since we have you and you're running,
we'll say the most popular security focused Mastodon instance on the planet.
And I'm comfortable saying that I don't think anyone can fact check me out of it.
But I'm, I'm just curious, you've been doing this for five years.
The last two months have been madness.
Like, tell me, tell me your thoughts on, on everything you see going on, the people,
you're seeing the, the ecosystem, the way the software is changing.
-- I'm, I'm just, I've got you here. So I got to ask,
-- it's been a wild ride.
You know, I, I set it up a long time ago.
I don't even remember why I set it up at the time.
It's just, I, I like to tinker and, um, you know, so it, it,
it had like 100 or 200 users for the first five years. And, um, you know, and
when, when Twitter started to fall apart, um, actually, which was in the spring,
not, not in the fall.
The first wave was in the spring and I was actually running the server on a VPs and, um,
it just fell over like there was a, there was a,
a little mini exodus from Twitter when Elon Musk announced that he was going,
he was going to purchase Twitter. And in this, in the server fell over.
And if you look at some of the up time, the long term uptime graphs of the server,
you'll see that it was down for like a week
and,
and, and at the time I was spending like a couple 100 bucks a month or sorry,
a couple 100 bucks a year on this vps.
And so I decided to like,
you know, I'm going to buy an actual or rent an actual server and I did and, and I,
I figured it would be,
I'll probably never have to upgrade this thing again.
And then, uh, and then, you know, the, the date
October 27th when, when Alan closed the deal, there was a, just a,
I was actually at the beach working and I kept seeing like pop ups on Twitter as I was.
Um,
you know, I, I wasn't advertising like I was just,
I was working,
kept seeing pop ups on my phone from Twitter and, and then, uh I took a look and,
you know, it was like 1000 or 2000 new accounts.
Anyway, we,
we grew from 100 and 80 users to about 36,000
over the course of about six or seven weeks.
Pretty exciting time at a macro level. It has been absolutely astounding
to watch kind of this vibrant ecosystem of smart security people, like pick up
and move
to a different platform
and not just on, on my, you know, on, on infosec exchange,
there's a bunch of other really cool,
um you know, security
instances, there's Defcon dot social and hacker
and hackers dot town and, and, you know, lots of really cool
uh places with, with great people, but just to watch that mass migration almost like
in total
pick up what, what they were doing
and then move
and
all the while
having
like a pretty strong bunch of naysayers just
all of the flaws. Oh my gosh, it doesn't have an end to end encryption.
Well, you know what? Neither does Twitter. And,
um and you know, you don't have quote tweets.
Yep, that's a, that's a problem and the search sucks and,
and whatnot. But despite all of that,
the community that has set up is just really cool and, and I Um
I don't know.
I, I, my, my hypothesis is
that Twitter
had some algorithmic
stuff going on that, that kind of put things
that were
not necessarily what you liked to see in front of your face because it drove
and as compared to, you know, that that doesn't exist
in
Masan, it's just totally,
you're chronological
or, you know, based on the, the, the hashtags that you follow and whatnot and, and the
people
are amazing.
Like they're so supportive,
they're kind
um
it's just been an amazing thing to be part of.
Well,
I can't help but wonder because it's funny to
me seeing this mass migration and I'm like,
oh, I've seen this before now, granted it took like a year or two instead of six weeks,
you know, for some of these platforms, like
when uh slash
dot died, you know, that was years, right?
Or dig or Irc you know, and
people migrated
off those platforms. But yeah, years, not six weeks.
And so I can't help but wonder because like a
lot of the people such as yourself running these instances,
I mean, you've been through this before, like,
you know what eternal September is we've lived in.
And the second thing I'm really,
what's fascinating to me is a couple of the big
hold on, hold on. Kurt. I need to interrupt you because
a lot of people don't know what eternal September is because they're,
they're not old enough to have been in Eternal September.
-- Uh
-- So basically Eternal September was the internet.
Uh where every September a fresh crop of, you know,
18 year olds would go to university and get internet for the first time.
And
you know,
this is amazing, right? And then uh Eternal September. AOL joined the internet.
Well, use net specific,
right? Because AOL was on the internet and then they opened use net up and
we'll say
the quality of use net became more questionable.
And the other thing I've seen is a couple of major proponents that like said Mastodon
cannot work for XY and Z reasons actually
recant and like write relatively long sort of
replies to themselves saying like I was wrong and
here's why I was wrong and I feel like Mastodon
is very fundamentally different than Twitter and not just
because it's not corporate and Federated and all that,
but I think it's,
there's just some aspect to it and I don't know what it is exactly,
but it's just very different.
So it, it,
it comes from a different place
and, and so it was, it's been really interesting watching, especially in the early,
the first few weeks after, you know, is,
is the security community was starting to make its,
its migration
to, to watch people saying, oh, it's not going to work and,
but like having been doing it for five years,
like, you know, it, it works like it,
you know, you can say that but we're over here, like, doing it and, and so that's,
that, it's, it's kind of an odd thing.
Malware Tech, by the way was one of the ones that was a pretty big detractor of it.
And he since wrote a, you know, pretty, pretty long piece about, you know, why he,
he thought that was wrong and that's, you know,
that's cool.
Um,
look, it isn't Twitter. Right. It isn't Twitter. It has Twitter like
capabilities, it has the ability to post messages and that people can see.
But it was, again, it comes from a different place. It was designed
with some of the, you know,
to address what people perceived as some of the downsides of,
of kind of mainstream social media,
which is like the ability for people to harass each other and, and whatnot.
So, so some of the things that are,
are not there like quote tweets in and robust search
and some of the other things were intentional design points
that,
you know, we're, we're, we're there to help mitigate or govern some of the, you know,
the the the problematic aspects of other social media, you know,
having said that like it also is in those things are
a bit of an inhibitor for from a usability standpoint.
So
like they, it wasn't accidental that twit
had those things, they were pretty damn handy.
Now, I'm going to say the no quote tweets bothered me for a while,
but I actually really like it because now I can't just like,
quote tweet someone and throw shade on them or whatever.
I have to actually reply and engage like a human.
And I definitely think more about what I'm doing
than
maybe some of the hot takes
we got in the past.
That's exactly it. Right. That is it.
That's the, that's the reason.
Yeah.
Yeah. Absolutely. All right, Jerry, one last thing I want to ask about.
So you're now running a pretty beefy instance. And I'm curious,
tell me about
how the community is helping kind of fund all this
because that this is the coolest part I think.
Yeah.
So, um I uh I just received my first bill from post,
what I call the post deflationary period.
And it was, uh it was 28 $900 for, for a month.
So,
yeah, it was, um now the thing to understand was
I,
you know, at the time, you know, I had about 100 and $10 a month server and I, you know,
I thought that that
will last me for quite some time or maybe forever
and, and it lasted till about 8000 users, which was not bad,
but I was, we were adding 2000 users a day
and
I was in this like constant firefighting mode of holy crap.
We're running out of file descriptors. Holy crap. We're out of memory. Holy crap.
We're out of this space. Holy and, and So I said this is enough.
And I went and I, you know, I rented some significant,
I had no idea when it was going to stop.
And, and so the community
has been amazing. I set up, it's called Libra Pay.
It gives you the ability to, to like make a,
a recurring commitment.
And um and so so between that and paypal, I'm able to cover, to cover the server costs.
I just moved from a self hosted media storage
to um
to a CD N and, and back plays S3. Uh So, so now I don't have to worry about
many o taking a dump in the middle of the night,
which it often did by the way.
And, but, you know, that's expensive.
Like I, I'm literally sitting at my desk and watching like, OK,
you know, 1.1 terabytes, 1.2 terabytes, 1.3 terabytes, 1.4 ter
like going out through the CD N and, and uh you know, I, I uh you prepay.
And so I'm like watching the, the money
that
I
that I put in
like decrement.
And so it's been, it's look, I, I didn't do this to make money.
I have a pretty
good job. I'm a really good job.
I did, I do this because II I believe in the community, but it's been really cool
to see the community come together and um
and support it financially so that I've been so
-- honored to be part of that.
-- Absolutely. It's,
I love it.
It feels like all of the right things,
all the things I read from you and all the other Mastodon server hosts and it's just,
it, it brings a smile
to my face every time I read about it.
And I will say like I was very beaten down for a long time
about just like the state of the internet and social media and everything.
And I think everything I've seen happening right now with,
with Mastodon and the fetters and everything like fills me with hope that like,
I don't think it's a lost cause anymore, which makes
it makes me so happy.
-- It's
-- uh you know, it's like,
uh it's like going from a dystopian world to like Star Trek.
You know, it's like,
well, I think what gets me is that this looks to be sustainable.
I mean, like three grand a month, that's a big server bill.
But when I think about like 20 years ago, what it cost to run a website,
we would have been so happy to only pay three grand a month, right?
And three grand a month to support 36,000 users. Granted, not all of them are active.
That's
I feel like that's actually sustainable, especially if people are,
-- you know, donating a bit of money.
-- Like, yeah, yeah.
All right. I'm gonna call this one, Jerry.
I want to thank you so much for, for showing up. And helping out.
I, I truly appreciate it. It's been uh it's been a treat. So. All right.
So, thank you, Kurt. Thank you, Jerry. Thank you ever for listening.
Go to open source Security podcast.com.
Head up the show notes, Suzie Pound to S Podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media.
01 last thing I, I should say before,
since we didn't give you like a proper intro because you snuck in.
Uh Jerry has a podcast called the Defensive Security Podcast,
which if you never listen to, you should totally listen to.
It's a fantastic show
and obviously
Mastodon instance, which people can find you at Jerry at infosec dot exchange.
And if you're a user donate, please
because
no matter which Mastodon instance you're on,
like those people are doing the work of the Lord for us, so like help them out.
But yeah, thank you so much, both of you. Thank you. Thanks everybody.
Thanks, everyone. Bye bye
the