Hello and welcome to episode 90 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Pressers.
I found the greatest story the other day
and,
and this is actually sent to me by one of my cousins which
which makes it even funnier is so apparently during the season of Lent,
the number of computer virus installs or I guess attacks,
whatever you want to call it, um compromises compromised might be the best word
goes down by infections. There you go. I like,
maybe I don't, I don't know,
I don't think about this anymore. So it makes me happy.
But anyway, the number of infections goes down drastically during Lent.
And do you know what the reasoning supposedly is?
No
that, that people are giving up looking at online porn during Lent,
which
like this website is totally dodgy and the story is incredibly questionable.
But it's like, I don't even care.
Like I want to believe this because it's funny,
it's even better than that because I just Googled Lent
to see when it was and when it was until.
So it's for those of you though. Don
um
lent is a 40 day thing
-- where people give up stuff, I guess, like
-- 49 days,
you don't, you don't even have to give things up.
It's just according to tradition, you often
give something up as a way of, I don't know,
connecting spiritually or I've never totally understood like,
the whole giving thing up portion of it.
But
anyway, you kind of, it's common for people to give something up
and then it starts on Ash Wednesday and it
ends on Easter and it's actually like 49 days,
but they don't count Sundays and there's some weird technicalities.
Well, like, like, of course, it's not religion if it doesn't have technicalities,
right?
But here's the best part. So just googling the word Lent
top stories,
computer virus levels drop during Lent because
Catholics give up porn on the observer and
giving up porn for Lent may have caused 17% drop in computer viruses on Newsweek.
-- So I'm calling it then. This is totally
-- true. It must be. I mean, Newsweek is re
reporting it.
Well, actually this is funny because this is,
I, I saw a news story once
and, and I'll, I'll see if I can dig this up and put it in the show notes.
But it was basically
somebody updated Wikipedia with a lie about somebody else
referencing an article
that the article then referenced Wikipedia
crazy circular reference.
And it's like,
that's,
that's kind of funny,
but it also makes you think like when something seems super crazy,
it's good to find maybe more than one source and I have a suspicion.
-- This story has one source.
-- The problem is that
journalism used to be about fact checking and confirming, you know,
and they would say
we were able to confirm with sources or anonymous sources
or we were not able to confirm with sources,
you know, or it is reported that, you know, when they, it was like second hand
and kind of all that has been thrown out now because, you know, everybody's like
basically all the online media, you're looking at 15 minute deadlines
because if somebody beats you by 15 minutes and gets that on Twitter,
you get zero traffic and you starve that month.
It really is that simple. Like when I worked, this is 20 years ago, mind you,
but back when I work for Security portal.com,
you know, I got the hang of how to get something slash dotted,
like how to write a headline and how to write an article
so that it would go on slash dot We'd get over 100,000 views.
And back then that was essentially, you know, that would be over $1000 in revenue
easily,
you know. So you can, I mean, II I
didn't write anything that was factually incorrect, but I may have, you know,
dressed, I may have, what's the phrase?
Sex it up a bit, you know,
maybe, you know, made it a little more interesting
and I, I did do a really good job once we got death threats, actually.
Um,
Clickbait today. Right.
You
wait, how did you get a death threat?
-- Writing an article about S si
-- essentially titled at the end of SSL and SSH.
And it was, uh, it was with respect to Doug, you remember Doug songs? Uh D
sniff
way back in the day.
So, yeah, folks go on Wikipedia. This is ancient history.
But, uh, yeah.
No, I mean, I mean, essentially, yeah, I got the hang of Clickbait articles and
I mean, yeah, some of those articles generated a lot of revenue for us.
-- That's awesome. It's nice to know nothing's changed.
-- No, absolutely not.
If anything, it's gotten much, much worse
or, or maybe you were, you were a pioneer,
right? You're the reason the world is bad now.
Like,
at least
I didn't send the first spam
and,
and Siegelman.
Oh, my goodness. Yes. Yes. Yes. So, so anyway, I guess
this story actually and the fact that we have a suspicion it's fake,
even though I don't care.
And I love it
kind of ties into the topic we were thinking of today is just kind of
hacking people,
right?
-- Which is kind of becoming a thing. Well, it's been a thing for thousands of years
-- but
people have always been hackable.
I mean, essentially fraud is, is a form of hacking people, right? You know,
but what's really interesting to me now, is this, it's,
it used to be like in the old days, if you wanted to hack a computer,
you had to go to that computer and hack it.
Now everything's attached to the internet.
And,
well, so is everybody,
everybody's attached to the internet in the form of we read online news,
Facebook news, cnn.com, whatever.
Not even that man.
Just you've got email and,
and Twitter and Facebook and like there's millions of ways to contact a person.
And in fact, I saw a message the other day,
I don't even remember where this came from,
which again is funny because I don't even know where I get some of this news.
It, it just goes in one hour and probably falls on the floor. But, but anyway, uh
there was a new malware that was basically looking at your email inbox,
finding a thread
and replying to threads with
malicious documents attached.
Right?
I bet they click through
sky high. Right.
Yeah, here's that PDF you asked for.
I literally don't remember what you're talking about.
I better open this up and see what it is.
Right. Exactly.
And depending upon who it comes from,
like there's obviously certain people I work with that if they send me a PDF,
like I'm just gonna look at it because I would assume
-- it's important if they're sending it to me in the middle of the thread.
-- Right.
That's brilliant.
And that's the problem. Right. Is like, you know,
again, it used to be that, you know, various levels of
information, kind of had various levels of reputation attached to them.
You know, that thing the Wall Street Journal says,
versus that thing your uncle says.
Yes. Yes,
-- I do not believe anything my uncle tells me,
-- but now that distinction is gone
and, and Right. Right. Right.
And, and my uncle has a platform because he's on Facebook
and,
right, his,
his crazy friends, like the things he put there
and
-- it's
-- great. Yeah. And that's the other thing too is it, it's, it's,
there's so much media available now. We can actually pick and choose.
Like I remember growing up, right, our, our newspaper,
like our town Edmonton had basically two newspapers with the Edmonton Journal
and the Edmonton Sun
one, you know, the Edmonton.
So was the one with the, uh the Sunshine Girl on page, whatever.
Um The Edmonton Journal was a little bit more highbrow.
And then, oh,
obviously you could get like the National Post if
you wanted like kind of a real newspaper.
Um But fundamentally you had those
three print news sources.
Uh And then, you know, we had what, three or four over the air channels,
two or three of them had news programming, one of which was the CBC,
the Canadian Broadcast Corporation which,
you know, as, as boring stable news organizations goes right up there.
And so, you know, essentially all the information you could get in
print or on the TV was,
you know, it came from very large organizations that generally,
uh, did their job reasonably well.
I mean, granted they had agendas like selling your eyeball to advertisers
but,
-- you know, they weren't, like, all owned by Rupert Murdoch back in the day.
-- Right.
Right. Right. And let's, let's tie this into
the, I guess the big story is Guccifer.
Right. Turns out we know who Guccifer is and, and shockingly
he's a Russian
-- or she, I should
-- say,
I mean, to be clear when that lone DNC hacker,
it was pretty clear to me it was like 90 let's
say 98% chance of being like a Russian state level actor,
-- I think with, with a 2% margin with
-- a 2% margin of error being some like maybe whack a
dod old conservatives in America who are competent,
you know, who wanted to embarrass the DNC?
I, I question, I question if, if the statement you just made.
But, um,
so, and I mean, this is a perfect example of, you know,
when this person or entity supposedly hacked the DNC and started
releasing those emails and embarrassing the hell out of them.
Ok. Well, why would somebody do that?
Because, you know, they believe in truth and justice in the American way.
Probably not so much.
Did they want to, like, hurt the Democratic Party? Yeah, clearly,
I, I always viewed it as kind of a Chaos Party
platform
where you can, you can kind of argue that with Wikileaks
where Wikileaks loves to release all this information
-- is, don't get me
-- wrong. I'm
right. Exactly. Ok. That's fair. Yeah, that's better than chaos, probably. But.
Right. Right. It's not that they even have a specific intent necessarily.
-- It's just
-- let's destabilize these Western democracies and weaken them.
Like, look at how much,
I mean, God bless America,
but look at how much time you guys have fucked
around now with your government basically being somewhat broken.
You've had a government shutdown.
You've had,
have you guys really passed any meaningful
legislation moved forwards on anything of substance?
-- The answer is not really.
-- I think we have trade tariffs.
Yeah, that's true. Yeah.
OK. True. No, the trade tariffs. That's a thing.
Not a good thing. Mind you, but
um just ignore what every single economist has ever said
in the last 50 years.
Um
But yeah, I mean, this is my point, right.
There's, there's countries out there that really don't have a lot to lose.
Like I was looking up Russian
economic stats and like
their biggest trading partner partner is the Netherlands.
It's Bonkers, their, their, their exports is like,
yeah, it just,
yeah. No, it's
uh they really don't have anything to lose
by destabilizing Western democracies and the world economy.
And
when you look at what the cost of it is to have, you know,
a couple of foreign intelligence officers
a million bucks a year, maybe 2 million bucks a year.
The damage they've done is, is a lot more than that.
Sure. No. And, and I guess that that ties into the overall theme then of
humans are incredibly gullible and, and let's face it, the
something,
something I've been thinking about and I've started writing
a blog post about this to a degree is
the, all the misinformation that we see these days
and the way things are going is uh I would
compare it to like a security exploit against social media,
right?
Where you're leveraging,
you're basically taking a platform that is expected to operate in a certain way
and you are are making it do something it was never intended to do,
which is basically how like security exploits work, right?
Where you make an application do something it's not supposed to do
fundamentally, any system
can be gamed.
Now,
the question is whether or not gaming it gets you some advantage and you want to do it.
I mean, a perfect example of this is,
I mean, you could go around breaking uh the windows at bus stops, you know,
bus stops that have those glass panes so you can stand out of the cold in the wind
and you could go around breaking them right
now. Most people don't do that because they're not jerks
fundamentally, right? Because there's, you don't really gain anything from that.
I mean, maybe unless you're the guy that provides the replacement windows.
Um, but, you know,
locally we had somebody doing that a few years ago,
they broke something like 40 or 50 bus stop
of these windows and, you know, they're quite expensive.
And luckily most people don't go on social media and
try to destabilize, you know, the world with
wonky news or made up news.
But for some people there is that motivation
and, yeah, we don't have good ways to deal with it.
Not at all.
But, but I, I guess my point is
that
there are accepted norms in any society
and anytime someone steps outside of those norms,
it, society often struggles to deal with them correctly. And
a great example is like you, people stand in line for something.
If someone runs to the front of the line and just stands there,
how often do is everyone just like, wow, that guy's a jerk and that's the end of it,
right?
It's not like there's, there's hard and fast rules that say don't do this.
You know, there's, there's the law
that if you break it, you have to deal with police and authorities and,
and possibly fines or prison.
And then there's like the rules of society. And that's something that
I, I think
we don't do, we don't know what to do when someone violates a lot of these norms.
And I think when we look at something like social media, especially,
we, we lack the ability to comprehend that even the norms are being violated. Right.
It's like you,
you're hacking people because people don't even know they're being hacked,
which is crazy.
Well, I mean, I see people sharing these stories that are clearly false or,
you know, driven by some crazy agenda
or,
or my favorite now is how many magazines have stuff that is very
subtly labeled as advertising but looks like the actual content of the magazine.
Oh,
my goodness. Nothing drives me crazier than that.
Yeah. No, it's, um,
it's worrying to me because I'm, I'm, you know,
I'm finding I'm really having to pay attention to what I'm reading and consuming.
You know, is this true? Is there an agenda behind this?
I mean, sometimes there clearly is like a great example is that, you know,
if I'm going to get married,
I really should be spending three months of my salary on a diamond ring.
Ok.
Well, clearly de beers has an agenda and what's really fascinating is,
and I've noticed this on the radio.
Somebody was commenting about this.
I remember when the radio ads
started and they were sort of against these manufactured diamonds.
Essentially the biggest diamond store locally was like, you know,
are we buy diamonds, blah, blah, blah, you know,
they're not like those fake diamonds that you make
and are not real diamonds pulled from the earth,
blah, blah, blah.
And now a few years later they're like, our
artisanal diamonds are better. They're like 25% bigger than the regular diamonds.
And somebody pointed out that essentially China is
manufacturing the bejesus out of these things,
selling them at quite a bit cheaper than the beers will sell you a diamond wholesale.
And so, yeah,
the jewelry stores are like, well, screw that we're on board with making more money.
Well, and not only that, I,
I read that de Beers is paying quite a lot of money right
now to researchers trying to figure out how can we identify these,
essentially lab made diamonds and they can't,
they're, they're so good, they can't figure it out, which is
hilarious.
Like,
well, the funny thing is actually that's,
that's one of the ways you can tell it's
a fake diamond is if there's no inclusions or flaws
because natural diamonds have, you know, impurities and stuff.
So, yeah, you can do that in the lab too.
Um,
I know in Canada there's like these diamonds you get and they have like a
little polar bear laser cut on them and I think it's a trademark thing.
That's how they enforce it,
you know, and so it's like, you know,
that these are good Canadian diamonds that didn't involve, you know, little
Children being used to mine them or sweatshops grinding them or whatever.
But, I mean, fundamentally, you know,
I'm supposed to spend three months of my salary on this stupid diamond ring.
Uh, yeah. Ok. It's pretty clear who and why
they have that agenda, you know.
But I mean, here's a great one, right? Like you stated on,
well,
you've privately stated on many occasions that you have
some very strict rules around uh foods and when,
and how you consume them.
Right?
Wait, do I,
which, which, which rules are those like?
Well, so for example, breakfast foods are for breakfast, not for dinner.
Uh Yes. No, that, that's just, I'm, I'm, I consider myself a crazy person.
Yeah, like bacon and eggs. Breakfast only, no questions asked.
Exactly. And well, why, why, why is it a breakfast only food?
I,
I assume I suffered some sort of traumatic
event involving breakfast food as a child at
maybe at lunchtime.
-- No,
-- it's just, that's how, that's, uh, that was marketed by some, uh, hang on a sec.
Um,
I, I blame my school cafeteria.
Actually, they used to serve breakfast for lunch and it was like abysmally bad.
And so now when I think of breakfast for lunch,
I immediately think of my school's cafeteria and like the terrible bacon
and the awful eggs.
Yeah, like the eggs you could have bunch the eggs on the ground, dude,
they were terrible.
So that's my suspicion as to why I feel this way.
Anyways, um,
Bernays got a doctor to agree that a protein rich heavy
breakfast of bacon and eggs was healthier than a light breakfast.
And then sent that statement to around 5000 doctors for their signatures he then got
newspapers to publish the results of his petition as it was a scientific study,
explains Carol that brought bacon and eggs back into fashion and added more weight
to the idea that breakfast was not only very important but medically recommended.
So essentially it was the egg and bacon.
Ok, let's start here. Uh,
first of all, breakfast is the dumbest meal of the day,
but I love bacon and eggs. So,
so I eat them. They are fantastic. There's nothing pleases me more.
Actually, that's one of the things,
one of my favorite things to do is I get up early on Saturday and
I cook like this massive breakfast with bacon and eggs and hash brown potatoes and,
-- oh,
-- you're
-- like
-- one of those people in the movies where it's like,
who the hell has time to make?
Like,
-- because
-- I get up really early
and then the kids grab a piece of toast on
everyone's, this is on Saturday mornings when we have nothing to do.
I will do this and I'll cook for like two hours
and it, I love it because at the end I get this marvelous breakfast and then, yeah, we,
we all eat it together and stuff, but again, only if there's nothing to do,
which is pretty rare.
Uh,
but anyway, no, no, I, I totally get that.
And that's something similar happened with, with, I think it was sugar.
Where,
where some,
what was it like the sugar industry paid off some
doctors to talk about how bad for you fats were,
but like, sugar is fine.
No, you're wrong too.
And so, like, in all seriousness, I, I take, you know,
this is a good point and this totally ties into our,
our conversation here is the fact that
I it's even difficult to trust certain medical advice because like,
where did it come from?
Right.
Well,
remember when cholesterol was good for you and then it was bad for you and
then certain types were good for you and certain types were bad for you.
I,
I
forget I, I just know that I'm not supposed to eat so much like schmaltz.
It's like rendered bacon fat
like that
on toast. It's delicious with a little cracked salt and a little cracked pepper.
You, you, you smear bacon fat on toast. That does sound nice.
Rendered bacon fat. It's like a spread.
It's basically bacon,
I
think crystal. But
out
of pigs,
-- that sounds delicious.
-- It's also good for,
I actually, I like to fry my eggs in bacon fat where I cook the bacon first
and then I take all the fat and I use that
to cook the eggs which makes the eggs way better.
Of course better for me. Maybe not. But
man, they're so delicious.
You can, you can go wrong with bacon fat.
Oh, I'll be danged. Uh Apparently our body also makes cholesterol.
Nothing surprises me. Right.
Your liver
So, yeah, we still, we're still on good versus bad.
So it seems we
out
on that.
But
I guess
here's the point and, and here's the craziness and all this with, with all,
like the online fake news
and online real news and, and what's true,
what's false and this is even true in the world of security.
Like,
remember when we thought changing your password every 30 days was more secure.
Right.
It,
it's so hard to figure out what is right and what
is wrong and who to trust and who not to trust.
And, and I feel like I see this more and more especially in the world of security where
where people hand out advice and it's like that is terrible advice. And
well, part of the problem too is a lot of this advice is not
general in the sense of, for example, are firewalls good or bad.
Well, depending on how your network
is configured in what it is,
they can be very good or they can be very bad. But for example,
um, you know, I deal with cloud security lines, we don't have any physical servers
to the best of my knowledge.
We have a office with a bunch of like half a dozen people in it.
It's all bring your own device, everything we use is in the cloud.
So are firewalls of any use to us.
And the answer is, well, traditional firewalls, absolutely not.
Um, like a firewall running on the host, like the built in, you know, your phone,
your laptop, whatever.
Sure. Yeah. Like whatever the default, you know, windows or Apple thing is.
But, you know,
am I going to go out and purchase some Cisco adaptive threat intelligence firewall?
Absolutely not.
Right. Because what would I do with it?
No, I, I get it, you know.
But is that, is that good advice for a university with a large campus land? Oh, yeah.
Yes,
you
damn well better have one of those things,
you know. Otherwise Lord only knows what you
-- do,
-- you know.
I read,
I read a news story the other day that some university installed a bunch
of ad blockers in their computers and their bandwidth went down by 40%.
I
can believe
that
it's crazy
even worse now, crypto mining,
-- right?
-- All those sites that run javascript to crypto mind in your browser, which is,
it's got to be the most inefficient way to crypto mine ever.
But hey, it's, it's free from the attacker's point of view basically.
Um
So, I mean, I, I imagine that would even have an impact on your electricity bill
potentially, you know, half a percent, which would add up.
Definitely
-- just see I making up numbers.
-- They're true.
Right.
And yeah,
that's, that's why this is so hard, man. I mean,
how do you, how do you decide what's right or wrong?
And, and I guess even from our perspective,
one of the challenges you run into is
it is difficult sometimes to have a coherent conversation
in a manner people can understand. And my example is gonna be password advice.
There is I'll put a link on Twitter where
uh there was some VPN provider that, that tweeted this advice of like here.
So you should create passwords and the advice is terrible. It is, it is awful advice.
And then they of course,
like pinged a whole bunch of important Twitter people to like, oh,
look what we did and they're getting tore up as they should,
right. Which is funny. That's, that's great. They haven't taken the tweet down yet.
I took a screenshot of it just in case.
But, but anyway, anyway, here's the thing though. II I replied and I was like,
so
I know this advice is wrong and it's bad.
But
like, like, what can we say? That's correct? Easy to understand.
It actually has some truth behind it.
Not just like crap I think is correct and that doesn't exist.
Well, it's, it's hard because it's like, it's,
I mean,
the problem too is sometimes uh health is a great example.
I'll give you two really solid pieces of health advice that are almost always true.
Number one, reduce your calorie intake. Number two, get some more exercise,
right?
But those things are so generic
as to be not super useful
because quite frankly,
if you could just cut your calorie intake by 10% you would have done it by now.
You know, it's like those people, like, well, and I'm one of those people.
Unfortunately, it's like, how did you quit smoking?
Well, I just quit one day and it didn't bother me. Sorry.
Like, I,
I almost feel guilty about how easy it was for me
to quit smoking and I have no cravings and I'm like,
I, I'm really sorry for all you people that do
work really hard at this and fail horribly at quitting smoking
because, yeah, for some people it's just not easy.
And, you know, security is the same way. I mean, it's,
it's one thing for me to be like, yeah, we have no servers, we have no land,
we have nothing like that.
So, like, I get to ignore a whole pile of problems
that's not going to happen for a fortune 500 company
or anyone who has infrastructure more than five years old. Right.
Yeah.
No, I, I get
it, but more importantly is,
I think this is one of the reasons that the security industry.
I, I would say, like, like in all seriousness hasn't really
-- moved forward drastically and
-- we
have
no, we don't. That's the thing, like you can say, all right, use a password manager
and I agree with that. Like, password managers are great.
You could say use a firewall except, oh, wait, that advice doesn't work anymore.
Right. You've got,
well, it's, or it's of this type of, you know,
use the firewall that's built into your operating system and enable.
I guess the more advice is don't turn off the firewall if it comes with one enabled.
Sure.
In other words, don't go out of your way to, like, don't leave your spare tire at home.
I mean, most manufacturers now are trying to do a, you know,
a much better job on their software.
Well, the operating system vendors, not, uh, not so much like the IOT but
I, I don't, yeah, use a, use a password manager and,
and I would actually tell people to install an ad blocker for two reasons.
Number one,
that the web will just load faster and look less ugly.
And number two is it will reduce the chance of like getting a virus or a drive by
download
and more to the point using an ad blocker has a,
there's hopefully less negative effects.
There actually is the positive effect of
like every time I use somebody else's computer
or something. I see the web with ads. It's just like, oh my God, this is, this is,
it's so bad, man. It's so bad,
you know.
So, yeah, folks go out there if you love your relatives and family,
go put ad blockers on their computers, please.
And,
but here's the thing like password manager and ad blocker
that's good for consumers.
But that doesn't solve that. That's like
a small slice of,
of the bigger problems.
Right, like the, the,
the new GDPR regulations coming in effect in a few months here and like, yeah,
as a Fortune 500 company, what do you do?
Well, you've got
not just technical debt but it's like, oh my God,
where do we actually have people's information?
Like, probably,
yeah, it's, it's gonna be crazy with, with, you
know,
like a great example of this is something we ran into as a recommendation is,
you know, the the marketing guys would send me badge scans,
uh spreadsheets of these badge scans from conventions, you know,
and it's like the person's name and email address and crap
to add to, you know, the the mailing list
and well, yeah, I don't need that. I just need the email addresses.
So under GDPR that's,
you know, it's not illegal per se, but it's the best practice to like
only give me the information. I actually need to do my job. Oh, ok.
No, that makes sense.
But
that's not
an easy thing to necessarily do because now you have to
map out all your information flows and who needs exactly what
and you know, we're back to that least privileged thing but to do least privilege,
you actually have to
like map everything out and really know what you're
doing and then do it and enforce it.
Well, in, in this is totally like the eat less calories advice,
like least privilege is really easy to say, but nobody knows what that means.
Just like saying, eat less food.
That doesn't mean anything.
I've, I've done least privilege a number of times and then discovered, oh,
backups failed.
Kind of important.
You know, if I have to pick between least privilege and having backups,
even as a security guy, I'm gonna pick backups.
Oh, totally, man. And there's, uh, it's just,
this is the thing that I guess annoys me about security is
I feel like this is a sign of the immaturity in our industry
-- that it, it, there's so many if, but if, but if, but
-- if
I,
I would say it's a combination of immaturity but also
a combination of how fast and how far we're going,
like look at cloud or, well,
a better smartphones 1012 years ago they did not exist cloud 67 years ago,
did not really exist
and now everybody has them,
you know, I wonder how did, how did we live before? Smartphones?
Like filthy savages.
Seriously, man. I mean, I think about, I was just on a trip recently
and I, I have no maps. I have no plane tickets. I have nothing.
And I remember before I'd go on a trip,
I'd print out my maps and I print out my plane tickets and I'd have, you know,
information about the hotel just in case they lost it.
And like,
I've got like three apps now and everything's in there. It's crazy.
I love it.
Yeah. The cloud has basically gone from zero to,
you know, if you're building a data center,
you better have a really specific reason for doing that as opposed to just
don't, don't build the data center.
Now, let me, let me move this conversation
back towards where it, where it started was.
Do you think the problem with our inability to get security?
Right is more because the people doing it come from
a different universe than the one we live in today.
Whereas you think young people are going to
have less trouble adapting and understanding these problems and solving them
than we necessarily do because
like we grew up running M sds on a computer.
Yes and no because my Children are going to grow up with augmented reality glasses.
What is, I mean,
you want to talk about privacy implications every time you look at somebody's face,
it pulls up their Facebook profile and tells you a whole bunch of stuff, right?
Like just the security problems we have like, I'm,
I'm not even thinking about like buffer overflows and remote code execution.
I'm talking about like,
you know,
you try to walk into a restaurant and they
refuse you service because like six months ago,
you left a negative review over a similar restaurant
and didn't black mirror covered this, right?
And in China they're now executing it.
Yeah, that's right because they've got your social score or
whatever
because
you said, you know, we were talking about this and, like, let's face it all secretly,
you know, somebody who's really disgusting or route on a plane.
Would we love to kick them off that plane and ban them from plane travel for a year?
Oh, my goodness. Yes,
absolutely.
But, but here's, so, here's the problem with this though
and, and
like, the part of me says, if you're a bad person and I don't like, you,
uh, get off my train, whatever, right?
However,
who decides what's good or bad
and see the worst thing is it doesn't necessarily have to even have that value.
It could just be we start attaching facts to people that then you can see, oh,
this person likes dogs.
Oh, this person is a smoker. Oh, this person
drinks, oh, this person eats meat
and for some people those are terrible things.
Yes. And, and I guess this is where we come back to the conversation of
in a free society.
The negatives far outweigh
or I'm sorry, the positives far outweigh the negatives even though in, in this,
this goes back to the very beginning
of our conversation about like hacking humanity
that
there are people who abuse the system and
there will always be people who abuse the system
but the benefits gained from existing in,
in the manner that people can abuse the system I think are,
are they tip the scales so far
that trying to lock some of this stuff down and trying to avoid it
isn't worth it.
However, I will say that I feel like in the world of online social media,
the scales aren't tipped as far,
necessitating the freedom that we enjoy. And I feel like we have to figure it out.
-- Well,
-- we're at the point where it's threatening democracy.
Yes.
Yes, that is very true.
And people's mental health, right.
They've done some studies and basically not super surprising
all the teenagers and indeed,
a lot of the people who spend a lot of time on social media are kind of miserable.
Now, we don't know about the causation factor.
Maybe it's people who are miserable are more drawn to social media
or, you know, so one theory I read was that essentially,
you know, you go on Facebook, you see the Facebook feed,
you see everybody else doing amazing stuff like all the time
and you feel inadequate, you know, kind of like if you watch TV, and watch, you know,
TV, families, they have,
you know,
they both work two low income jobs and they have this huge house
because you need to have a really big house on a TV.
Sitcom for the camera crew to move around in. Right? Like,
like the first time I watched the big bang theory, I'm like,
how does that waitress afford that apartment?
That is like, basically big enough to park a car in,
you know, every single room.
No.
And anyways, yeah, we don't know about the causation and that's part of the problem.
But
the reality is though, is, is, yeah, we've crossed the Rubicon, like,
oh,
all these people are going to drop
Facebook because of all the privacy implications.
Yeah. Even if, like, 10% did, even if 10% it wouldn't matter.
No, it isn't going to happen. Let's face it.
I mean, as much as I'd love to see Facebook get a, get a good punch in the gut.
They, they won't.
Facebook will at some point.
But it'll be, you know, people will move to a r augmented reality space or, you know?
Yeah. You remember when myspace was the big thing?
Yeah. Not anymore.
Is it even hang on a second.
It, it still exists
and it was actually,
it was, it was glorious. I was,
I was on a fishing trip recently.
We were, we were fishing on a lake and, and the guy, the, the captain says,
hey, here, I'll take your picture for myspace and we all laughed hysterically.
Right.
-- As soon as he said that
-- I'm just looking at the site,
I'm not even clear on what the site is.
Is it social media or is it news or is it
-- social media news?
-- I don't,
I, I think they're just, is it, like,
desperate to find love from whoever will give it to them?
Oh, it's dig looks almost identical. Ok.
-- So they're just some sort of news slash social media
-- blob.
They're, they're probably owned by the same company sucking up
latent traffic from people who don't know better or haven't updated their links.
No, it's,
and I, I don't know, I guess, I don't know the answer to this,
but I do feel like some of the problems we see in social media as well as
some of the problems we see in security as well as just problems with humanity are,
are vaguely related.
I would say one thing I think there's an even bigger problem is
that we don't even have a vocabulary to describe these things yet.
Like, I was looking up on Wikipedia
and we have terms like, you know,
the media echo chamber and the filter bubble
which are becoming more common and more understood.
But fundamentally like, what do you call something like
the Guccifer hacking the DNC to destabilize our,
uh, elections to muck around with it.
Like, I don't know if you saw the news but, um, Facebook has given, uh,
Canadian politicians like a special way to contact them to recover their
accounts if they get hacked because we have an upcoming election.
Nice.
I mean, I, I get the points for doing that.
Yeah, exactly. And we don't even have words to describe this.
We don't. And, and, but here again, I wonder if,
if we won't because we're the wrong generation.
But if the young people are going to be able to deal
with this just because they grew up as part of it.
Right.
So, II, I don't know, I guess it, it is, it will be interesting to watch this evolve.
And I certainly try to keep an open mind
when, when discussing the topics and trying to understand what's happening.
You know, I was just about to say, hey, teenagers,
if you could tweet at us and tell us what you think,
but I realized they're not on Twitter.
Twitter is for old people.
I, uh,
whatever, you know, Twitter is awesome.
And, and I wonder, do you think any, you think any young people listen to our podcast?
Uh, they might accidentally overhear it when their parents are?
That could be, that could be. Well, I don't mean this is one of those things like
I look at security and I remember when I was a kid,
like, I really wanted to get into security in a bad way and,
and I spent a lot of time reading and teaching myself and stuff and I, I don't,
I don't see the appeal with the youth like I feel like existed when I was a kid
and maybe I just don't notice because I'm an old person and don't hang out with them.
But,
but I do feel like this is, this is kind of an old,
-- it's the
-- way we're doing it as an old person industry,
the way the young people are doing it, it's called Agile Ops or what is it? Agile Dev
Ops
Dev
Ops. That's the
see
on Dev
Ops, which is something else.
I'm giving a talk at
OCON about Dev psychs
actually.
Have you
done
this?
I make up, I make up lots of things. No, no, in all seriousness. I mean, I,
I'm at elastic obviously and we have a very psych
ops culture and so
not psych
ops, Dev
ops
culture.
And so adding security in there is certainly that, that's something I'm very
sensitive to is I don't want to show up and
be the security person who's like you're doing it wrong,
do it this way.
But rather say if, if we did this
right?
And, and kind of, I, I'd like to talk about security as an MVP minimum viable product,
you know,
with security in mind because I think security is notorious
for trying to solve all of the problems at once,
which means we solve none of the problems
instead of saying let's do this one little thing
and then move on from there. But that, that's a topic for another day.
All right, man, I'm calling it.
It's, yeah, I don't know. Good, good luck, democracy and humanity in general.
That's the lesson of the day.
All right. So thank you, Kurt. Thank you for listening. You can go to open
source security podcast.com and find some links
to the various depressing topics of the day
and you can use the Pound Os S podcast hashtag to hit us up.
And I guess, yeah, if if you're a young person by all means, like,
let us know what you think
we would, we would be honored
to have insight from somebody who isn't geriatric.
So, yeah, nothing else. Thanks everybody. And thank you Kurt and have a great day.
You too. Thanks.