Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bruss,
man, you had a chance to fit something in with privacy.
I'm, I'm really excited today.
Well, I thought about saying privacy crime, but that's like that's Facebook's,
you know,
that's, that's why we're here today. I'm ecstatic. We have Hay Sukiya
legislative activist at the Electronic Frontier Foundation here
to talk to us about privacy in,
in this electronic age.
Haley. Thank you so much for joining us today.
-- Thank you for having me. I'm really excited to be here.
-- We are. You have no idea.
I'm giddy. It's, it's like Christmas.
So I guess let's just start at the very
beginning and why don't you explain who you are,
what the eff is and just kind of lay out the state of privacy.
And I know that's, that's a depressing topic.
But like, let's start with the sad things and then we'll talk about why there's hope,
of course happy to.
Um,
and you know, it is, it is depressing.
But, uh, you know, that's why we,
that's why we are here and why we keep doing this work.
So, yeah, so,
so, yeah, my name is Haley. I've been at the eff about three years and some change.
Now before that, I was a newspaper reporter in technology at the Washington Post.
And I bring that up because it's important as to how I got
into this job and why I think about privacy the way I do.
So basically what my job is is that I work on our activism team,
which is the team that kind of explains all of our positions and
tries to get people fired up for good things and you know,
fired up for bad things that we want to fight.
We call ourselves the propaganda arm of eff
we have a sense of humor.
So obviously, journalism to advocacy could be a really weird path.
But although I'm certainly not the only one who's taken it at eff, but basically,
I was at the post for eight years covering technology out of our business section.
And
I got into being in tech
technology. Well, both because I'm, you know, like
classic geek in terms of the,
the things that I bought and the things that I was interested in.
But also because I,
I was an intern,
a newspaper intern during the summer that
they were talking about the health care debate
in DC and got really interested in health
privacy and that kind of policy conversation.
And that grew into a larger interest in privacy policy in general.
Because I could see even then even when I had my feature phone,
that data and uh you know,
all of all data collection and data use were going to be big issues.
So got really interested in that.
And then, you know, like I said, I spent eight years at the post, I wore a lot of hats.
I did earnings reports. I did policy coverage. I did product reviews.
I did a lot of stuff
and
in the last couple of years just found myself getting really frustrated being like,
hey,
Facebook or Google or plug in your company had this
huge breach or they're doing this really shady thing.
And then two months later, having to be like, and they had the best earnings ever.
-- Yeah, everybody lived happily ever after.
-- Exactly.
And it was so frustrating to me because
not to mention that I would, you know,
I would have an inbox full of questions from people who are just like,
wait, they're doing what I don't understand. What should I be doing for myself?
What should I be doing for my Children? And I'm like,
I mean,
I'm a what, like a, at this point, like a 27 year old childless reporter.
Like, I don't know what you should do about your Children. I'm really sorry.
And I was like, gosh, this scenario that we're in is so hard and really,
I think there has to be some change
and I found myself wanting to do advocacy that just wasn't really
that appropriate for the journalism that I was trying to do.
So, I thought, ok, what if I just, instead of having no opinions
and being very neutral, went and had opinions for a living?
And so that is when I went to
e,
that's awesome.
So that's kind of the background on me and what I do and, you know,
and how I got here in terms of what I do day to day and the layout of privacy right now.
So privacy is in a really interesting position right now.
Right before I got to eff California passed the
California Consumer Privacy Act or the C CPA,
which is sort of a first of its kind privacy law.
It's
decent.
It's not perfect, but
I have definitely fought hard to defend it from getting worse
-- and then from
-- there,
you mean, like they were trying to repeal it or something?
Well, I mean, after it was passed,
you know, it, it sets up some basic rights.
So, you know, a right to know what information people have on you.
A right to delete it, a right to opt out of the sale of that information.
Some other things.
There was a year between when it passed and when it
went into effect and that was the year that I started
and everyone came out of the woodwork to try and gut this thing.
And like, those are pretty basic rights.
Yeah.
If you are asking somebody to borrow something or, you know,
if you're asking somebody, a friend of yours for something,
you would in fact ask them if you could have it first.
If you could, if you needed to share it with somebody,
you would ask them if you could share it, you would be happy if they,
if you would happily accept if they asked for it
back and yet somehow when it comes to our information,
we can't quite get on board with sort of what I think is really basic politeness.
Yeah,
I
guess I jumped ahead of myself a little bit.
But, yeah, so after C CPA passed,
um,
you know, obviously in, at the federal level, uh, you know,
they've been promising to be really serious about
federal privacy legislation since I believe I started reporting
and probably before that,
so there hasn't been a lot of movement on the federal level,
although I can talk about that about what we have seen as well,
but we have seen a lot of action in the States because people looked at California
and either they said,
oh,
I kind of want
those protections in my state or as we're actually seeing happen
more like, uh,
businesses and chambers of commerce and folks who want to keep
the status quo as it is when it comes to privacy,
said, oh, well, we can't let that law get out,
uh, out of its containment in California
and so
they have introduced really weak privacy bills across the country. Um that I spend
the bulk of my time right now
trying to stall uh improve
kill
or get alternatives to
so on privacy.
You know, it's,
it's a lot of part of the beauty of being a state level activist is that
you get to talk to people all across the country and um get to kind of articulate
these issues for them and, and you know, kind of hear what's happening in,
in places all across the country.
The frustrating thing is that I do repeat myself a lot because
I'm trying to influence policy debates in a number of states.
So, all right, let me, let me reel us back just a little bit first. So
what is the eff I'm sure many of us have heard of them, but I have a suspicion.
There's what a lot of us think the eff is and then there's what the eff really is,
right? We're not just a collection of cats talking about
about internet issues,
although, well, anyway,
sure, sorry, I got, I got way ahead of myself.
So eff the Electronic Frontier Foundation is a nonprofit dedicated to protecting
human and civil rights in the digital age. We were founded in 1990. Our principal.
Oh gosh, I sound like the Spanish inquisition. Sorry,
this is great.
This is great. I was going to say our principal issues are,
yeah,
are kind of the three pillars of our advocacy really are privacy.
So protecting privacy,
standing up against government surveillance and promoting innovation
under that very broad set of issues.
You know,
I'm just trying to think in terms of issues that we've dealt most with in the States.
You know, I mean, consumer privacy
obviously comes up a lot
uh anti-government surveillance. You know, we
call for bans on government use of
face recognition technology on the innovation side,
you know, that means things like broadband access,
that means things like copyright policy reform.
So, you know, we get involved in a lot of policy fights
and you know, we have a real kind of bottom up
philosophy of consumer protection and consumer rights.
In every case, we try to advocate for the user or the person, you know,
I like to think of them as people rather than users.
But,
but you know,
we advocate for the individual because obviously these are all
policy fights where there is a lot of money,
there are a lot of big businesses thrown around and
oftentimes the individual is the one who gets trampled first.
-- That's right, like the Lorax of the internet,
-- right?
That's what we should,
that's what we should call ourselves. Yeah,
I would buy that t-shirt just by the way.
But
I, I love t-shirts. I'm not wearing my eff shirt today, but
ok, cool. So now let's move ourselves over to privacy because I think privacy is
so important and more and more people are paying attention and
there's a lot going on that I think many of us don't even know about.
But obviously that's why you're here to tell us.
It's a big set up
where you want it.
Part of the fun.
Yeah.
So privacy obviously is, is,
is a huge issue and I think you're absolutely right that
it's risen in prominence in the past five or six years.
I would say more people are thinking about it,
more people are realizing they have to think about it.
You know, when I think of privacy,
it's, it's hard, it's a lot of things,
right? But I generally think of
the state of data collection, right? So how much information
companies are gathering about us with and without our knowledge,
I think about data use.
So how they're actually, you know, some companies do just sit on troves of data,
you know, smog
like just because they never want to delete it.
But
often they're using that information either to
build profiles about you um suggest,
you know,
things that you should be doing uh or products that you might
want to buy or services that you might need in your life.
Like Instagram for some reason, thinks I really need pillows.
I don't know what that says about what I've been doing on Instagram.
They're like you need to sleep Haley,
right?
To building profiles and making suggestions about things to do
and then also how they share and sell that information.
So how that information flows between companies
and that's where it gets really messy.
I mean, there are lots of places, I guess where it gets messy.
But when we get to the share and sale of information to me,
I find that to be the most opaque piece of this web, you know,
the part that we have the least insight into because it's a lot of, you know,
agreements between companies,
things that are in public and things that I can't get a public records request on.
But then of course,
each of those companies then uses data in their own way and stores
it in their own way and possibly shares it in their own way.
And so it gets really out of control for people very quickly and, you know,
in terms of so people are like, ok, so there's a lot of data,
I get it like people are collecting information about me, you know,
because every cookie wall that comes up, I'm like, yeah, whatever.
Just like, let me read the thing.
Yeah.
So what's the big deal? And that is,
it's both really difficult because as I said,
it's really opaque and harms can be very
societal.
So, you know, you have things like,
well, you know, when uh when companies are collecting information and they,
you know, are trying to guess, for example,
if you're worthy of a credit card or a business loan or a mortgage loan
and,
you know, they have decided, well, we,
we aren't going to look at race but what if we look
at zip code or place where you graduated from high school,
that kind of thing that, you know, Tobias definitely gets
into these
uh, profiles, um, and has like serious discriminatory risks and, you know,
that's kind of hard to uh
particularize down to the individual. Right? Because
you're like, well, but
it's because they have so much information, you know, it's hard to,
I mean, as with data breaches, right? It's like,
you know, your data was breached,
but it's hard for you to connect like a particular instance of, uh you know,
somebody maybe trying to use your credit card to a particular breach.
Like you can't be like, oh, I got this notice from Visa.
It's because of Target's Breach, right? It's hard to draw that line.
-- Well,
-- except when it's like Home Depot and it's millions of us.
Well, especially when it's like a bunch of really big breaches all at once.
It's like it could have been any of them.
You can't like, put a little ink tag on your, I mean, you know,
in your,
in your mind on the data that got breached out of Target
or Home Depot and see it come back to you unfortunately.
So that can be a little hard for people to conceptualize.
But people do get the idea of like weird ads that follow you on the
internet of like that weird ad maybe being seen by somebody else in your family.
There's the classic. Now example of,
I don't mean to pick on Target. It's just what's in my, it must be the Minnesota in me.
But, you know, there was a girl who was looking, she was pregnant.
She hadn't told anybody,
she particularly hadn't told her father who was upset when he got a mailer in, in his,
you know,
in the mail from Target saying someone in your house is
pregnant here are our deals and then got really mad,
told Target about it.
And then later had to be like, uh, so she's pregnant and she didn't tell me.
Right.
That's probably not how you want your parents to find out that you're pregnant.
There are definitely situations where that
would probably be actually really dangerous,
you know, to a person in that situation.
So
privacy is kind of all, all of these things.
It's, uh, it's related to advertising, it's related to data sharing agreements.
It's related to
the very web that we, uh, that we swim around in all day
and the kind of information that we shed.
So one thing I'm wondering because I mean, I've basically been involved, you know,
with like, for example, the cipher
punks, the eff since, well, the late nineties.
And honestly, I've sort of given up on privacy as
the way I think of privacy was, I think from, say roughly about 1950 to 1980
maybe 1990 ish.
But
just, especially with the internet being so heavily driven by advertising,
it seems there's this just ridiculous set of incentives for businesses
to
just be super anti privacy and,
you know, poorly monetize people's data through advertising, another
not very effective or efficient behaviors.
And
like, when I look at that, it's like, I just, how do we compete with that? Right.
I've seen many companies try to do privacy based offerings
and they've, like, all failed. And I guess like, so we have, do we legislate it?
Do we get the government to care? Because,
like, I don't think I've ever seen a company
voluntarily do the right thing.
Great
question. Yeah.
So I think, you know,
eff in general we're very wary about legislation but on consumer privacy, you know,
before I, before I got here they had a real shift because they said, ok,
how much more proof do we need that companies are? And you're absolutely right.
It's about incentives, right.
I,
I don't like to actually think of the companies
as being evil because I think that's not super helpful
in changing behavior. Right.
It's like, how do we get these companies incentives to change?
And you're right, right. Now, they're just
extractive, right?
I mean, the idea is that you just get all the information that you possibly can,
you monetize every little bit of it and you never let any of it go
and that is the profit model.
And so what we are trying to accomplish with legislation is, I mean, several things,
right?
But it's, it's getting
rules in place to just be like, look,
you shouldn't collect more information than you need to like,
do the thing that you're trying to do, right.
So to provide the good or service that you're, that you're trying to provide,
so that limits new information that comes in,
right? We're trying to get people to erase their information more, right?
The kind of set,
well, gosh, set retention periods in the first place,
but lower them in as many cases as possible.
And we're trying to get people to just, you know,
uh if you're going to sell or share the information,
just let me know and let me say yes or no,
I totally understand the sort of we call it privacy, nihilism.
And I have my days I tell you
that you're expressing, but the truth is that when it comes to advertising,
especially they're relying on new information, right?
They need new information all of the time.
And so we actually as consumers have more power than we think in,
in terms of controlling the inflow of that information.
And
you know, I mean, speaking for myself, like I'm 35.
So information on me even three years ago or, you know,
10 years ago would not be useful in terms of targeting me right now.
I lived a very different life.
And so, you know, they, they're all,
they always need new information to do the things that they're
doing otherwise they wouldn't be fighting my loss so hard.
So, III, I think you just said something that's really interesting
talking about the information from a couple of years ago.
So the eff has a podcast called How To Fix The Internet,
which I'll put a link in the show notes.
It's, and it's my favorite podcast by far.
And
the latest episode I listened to, I think I might be a couple behind.
I don't remember the title of it, but
the, the guest they had on was saying that
he was
an alcoholic in the past and the internet still is
trying to sell him alcohol even though he's clean and,
and doesn't drink anymore.
But like the, the ads are trying so hard, even though that's
in the past and not something he's interested in.
And I'd never really considered that.
But this concept of all this data that people have on you, I
should say people,
all this data companies have on you doesn't necessarily apply to who you are today.
-- And that's kind of horrifying in some ways. Yeah.
-- I mean, that is true.
I think, you know what we're seeing there is a, is a lag, right.
Obviously they're still collecting new
about him that, that, you know, could,
could maybe change the way that he likes it ads.
But you're absolutely right.
And that is,
that is to what we're talking about when
we're talking about building profiles of people.
So either outdated information can follow you around,
incorrect information can follow you around.
Um
Like Google used to guess that based on my love of
business news that I was like a 60 year old man,
which rude.
So I remember when GDPR came out and, you know, everybody in like,
was it
a
no, it was a Dutch privacy legislation predate GDPR.
Anyways, everybody in Holland got like these little cards in the mail,
you know, saying this company or this church or whatever has data on you.
Did you know that kind of thing?
And I'm just thinking like, for example,
I worked for a company that was acquired by a much bigger company and they
wanted to do background checks on everybody
and because I was Canadian not American,
you know, they couldn't just do it right.
They actually had to kind of get my permission and I'm like, ok, well,
I'll, I'll do it if I get to see the data and they're like, what?
And I'm like, I would like to make sure the date is correct. And
what was shocking is apparently nobody had ever asked this before to like
valid. You know what I mean? Like,
yeah, you can do a background check on me. Sure. I'm, I'm sure it's right. You know,
that's, which strikes me as insane
and, and there was actually a major factual error on it.
There was this weird $500 credit instrument that both myself and my bank had.
We, we could not figure out what they were talking about.
But I'm, I'm kind of wondering because that doesn't really scale, right?
Because if every single company that holds data
on me kind of asked me for permission,
you know, that's going to be 100 like I
don't want to spend time doing that.
Like I guess what I'm saying is II I kind
of don't want to force this on the individual because
like,
-- you know, I'd like to do other things with my life than manage my data.
-- Right?
And again, I think a totally valid point. So
yes,
-- ideally what we
-- like, how do we fix that?
Oh
I mean, I think no matter how we fix it,
you're right that there will be a really difficult period where people
are getting a ton of notices and I don't love that,
but that
is part of what comes with change.
But I think
so the way that we think about it is which right now we're basically an opt out
kind of society when it comes to data, right?
So people, right, you go to a site and they're like, hey,
we're collecting information on you.
If you don't like that, tell us to stop. I mean, if you even get that right?
And what we're hoping is that people will see the benefit of an opt
in now. There are still ways that
that is so, you know, so that they have to ask before they collect.
Um, and so in that way, over time, you know, you're at least not
making new relationships with companies you've never heard of, uh,
-- you know, without your knowledge.
-- Oh, yeah.
No, I got AAA data breach notice in the mail.
Uh, there was a thing in Canada where this,
so when you get a furnace like a furnace for your house,
the warranty stuff is actually sold off to like
a third party company that basically does like,
like it's like stock market level of tranches of reselling this.
You know what I mean? It's like a whole financial gobbledygook
thing.
And so this company I've never heard of got breached.
And well, I got a notice in the mail saying my data had been breached and I've,
I've never even heard of this company or never meant to do business with them.
You know, I just needed a furnace.
How dare you need a furnace
in Canada?
Yeah. So we are hoping to kind of flip to an opt
in regime or barring that because there's obviously a lot of political
unease shall we say about switching to that kind of model,
getting people to recognize things like browser signals so that, you know, I mean,
it's hard to use,
do not track as a as an example because to people who
know all about that long saga because obviously do not track,
did not live up to our hopes.
But there is a hope that we
do something like do not track in a browser signal to say,
OK, this signal I'm sending is saying that I,
you know, opt out of the sale or collection of my information
and that companies will have to recognize those
signals as opt out requests so that it's not
so much on the, on the individual to manage their privacy.
Because I think you're absolutely right,
kind of the way that the industry exists now
and the way that the solutions that are politically,
politically feasible to push through it still puts a
lot of burden on um on the individual,
which is a real concern I have as well.
Ok. So let's, let's talk about that for a minute because you're doing some work.
I, I read an article that you and some other folks from the eff wrote
about Washington State has a privacy bill
that
from what I read,
it is hilariously bad. I, I think, I mean, this is the challenge though, is
all of these organizations are
working their best to create these bills that make sure
no one gets real privacy.
That is true.
Um So the Microsoft bill that you point to, it's a, it's a couple of years old now,
but it just keeps coming back like,
like my least favorite zombie.
Um
And uh yeah, it's it's weak.
I mean, it is essentially um it was uh written in Washington State, which is,
of course the home of a lot of big tech companies, notably Microsoft,
which plays a very good state level state legislator ground game.
And
you know, they, they come in and they say, look, we understand the need to,
to address privacy.
You know, I can't, I,
I can't even tell you how many
like
really
awful businesses I've heard say,
but privacy is at the heart of everything we do and I'm like,
no managing risk is at the heart of everything you do.
You don't care about privacy.
That's right.
Anyway,
you know, and they come in and they say, look, we have this privacy bill.
It says it's a privacy protection act right at the top,
right. You know. Right.
Right in the head
and it proceeds to say like, you know,
yes, we will give you the rights to know,
know what
information we have on you.
And if you prove who you are, maybe we'll let you opt out if you ask us to delete it,
we will consider your request and let you know.
-- That's actually
-- a big thing because like,
I'm actually the deep like on the DPO for the Cloud Secure Alliance.
And I remember we have a person who works for the
CS A who actually used to be at a regulator.
And I remember asking him like, so if somebody sends a GDPR right?
To be forgotten request.
Like, from the email address they're asking us to delete. I'm like, that's easy.
Right. You know, Bob Smith at gmail.com, please delete my email. Cool.
But, you know,
if they ask for like, Bob Smith to be deleted, I'm like, how do we,
how do we verify that?
Because, like, I, I don't know what an Estonian passport looks like
and I don't want to ask for more info
and I'm like,
I'm just
like, what do we do? Right.
And he's like, ah, just do your best and, you know,
we'll just delete stuff because we don't really care.
We just want to get rid of it and,
you know, not annoy people but from a company's point of view.
Like, there's, well, I love this, there's actually four curtsy free
on the planet and all of us work in tech and
are roughly the same age and just basically white guys,
you know, there's one in California,
one in the Western US and one in Germany and myself.
And it's like,
yeah, I mean,
so I kind of get it from the company's perspective of
like, we can't just delete every Bob Smith in the database, right?
But I don't want to necessarily, like, send them my passport so I can
opt out of some online advertising.
And so how like, is there some balance there that is actually sane or is it just
like, is it one of those problems that's so hard. There is no good solution.
Let me see. I feel like it's somewhere in the middle.
But, I mean, I mean, you do raise a good point. I mean,
I am lucky in that. Or, or unlucky. I don't know, in that
I'm the only, as far as I can tell Haley Sky, I,
out there it's a very odd combination of
things.
But,
uh, you know, a lot of times when we, when we are talking about, you know,
this does come up and I mean, I tend to be a little glib,
but I do understand that there are compliance
issues and that those are real and that,
that people, um,
that companies in many cases would like to protect privacy
because they kind of like on an individual level,
get it, but don't know necessarily how to operationalize it.
So a lot of times when we are talking about opt out requests, I think,
you know, of course, it depends on the request.
Like if it's an opt out of sale or if it's a, you know, a question of deletion,
then I think,
you know, we are ok with, um,
certainly using the information you have on somebody.
So if you have an account or something, right, if it's tied to an account
to, uh, to verify and make sure that, you know, you're not deleting
something that, um,
that, you know, somebody Impersonating
someone would like you to delete, but generally when it comes to things like an
opt out of sale, right?
That's a pretty low, like the, the harm of getting it wrong is fairly low stakes,
right?
So,
uh or sorry, opt out of collection or yeah, or sale. So, um
that is kind of how we look at it because while I
am sympathetic that you have to verify who a person is.
We have seen companies um
under California's law say, ok, well,
if you want to opt out of the collection of data, then I need a notary,
I need you to like write this request and get a notary
and
that is a high bar.
Well, it's funny you mentioned that because actually two days ago, there was a,
a really big article here, essentially um old person.
Uh they got a power of attorney over the old person because you know,
they're going senile and they were trying to cancel a
credit card for this old person and the company wanted
notarized copies
and
the original copy of the power of attorney which like that's insane.
You, you cannot send the original document, right?
Like that's you're not letting that out of your control.
And what I loved is that the, the article pointed out, especially in Alberta,
like if you live in a small town, you
don't have a notary
like and I take that for granted, I live in a big city. I need a notary.
I can get one in like half an hour.
But, yeah, if you live in a small town or out in the sticks,
like you, you, you just can't do that
reasonably right.
Or if you live in Alaska, I kind of wonder,
is it sometimes are these companies doing this in good
faith or are they kind of playing those games to,
you know?
Oh, we, we made this reasonable request. That's really kind of not reasonable.
I mean,
I try not to assume malice in all cases, but I do think
that,
you know, often they're getting, I mean, I think,
you know, they're trying to cover their butts in the way that they think is,
is the safest for them.
In a lot of cases.
I think in a lot of cases, they are hoping that if they make the request, you know,
if they,
if they make the request complicated enough that most people aren't going to
pursue it and that means less work for them. As I said again, I try not to assume
malice.
I try not to say companies are evil, but I think there are,
they are motivated to set things up in ways that make it difficult to engage with
exercise of some of these rights.
And that is why when we're, you know,
when we're looking at crafting legislation that we really do try to be,
you don't want to be too prescriptive, right?
You don't want to be like you have to use this software which
will inevitably become obsolete two years after the passage of this law.
But
you do want to be as specific as you can to make sure that, you know,
people can't game the system either by trying to
be either by trying to be thorough or by,
you know,
just trying to make sure that people aren't really going to be able to use the,
the few rights that we are able to get through
-- the
-- classic beware of leopard problem. All right.
So I want to kind of steer us in, in two final directions.
First of all, I would like to understand, kind of,
we hinted at all this policy talk and regulation from the government.
And I'm curious like what is actually happening right now
that we should know about from the
just kind of the, the government policy, legislative perspective.
I alluded to not a lot of stuff going on at the federal level, you know,
in some ways that's fair, in some ways it's not, I think as a, as a DC, uh exile,
I have an interesting view of the city,
but, you know, uh
we are seeing better, at least drafts emerge.
I think we're seeing a lot of good, good ideas finally getting put into legislation.
So even if it doesn't have
a,
you know, a chance of passing imminently,
I think we are moving the needle a little bit.
And it's been really interesting to see, you know,
there's been a market backlash against big tech.
And it's been interesting to see,
you know, that's not always a good thing from our, from our issue set because I think,
uh, you see a lot of attempts to crack down on free expression and, you know,
a lot of like, weird security suggestions that come up.
They're like, anyway, I won't get into that.
But on privacy, I think we are seeing, you know,
people hearing lawmakers hearing from people
that, um, you know, they're really frustrated with the way that companies are
collecting and using their information and wanting to
kind of reset that balance a little bit.
And so there are some good ideas even if they are imminently passing.
Now, speaking of imminently passing,
this fight has really been at the state level for several years and right now,
like in a little bit of time, I'm going to go speak
Maryland. I sent a letter to Ohio this week.
Uh, you know, we're talking to Alaska, we're talking to my home state of Minnesota.
You know, we're,
we're talking to a lot of folks who are looking at privacy bills.
You know, some of them are these kinds of cynical, you know,
let's make this compliance focus,
let's make business friendly privacy legislation.
I'm sure there is some
world where business friendly privacy legislation lives,
but it is not the kind of models that they're putting forward, right?
What they're saying is we want what
they mean by business friendly privacy legislation is
businesses get to keep doing what they want, but they have to like,
say that they care about privacy, right?
They have to like give,
they have to do audits that nobody should see internally about the
privacy practices. You know, they
don't have to comply with this privacy law
if they comply with a totally different law,
that is not about privacy.
So
there are some,
a lot of tricks that we're seeing and we are seeing those pop up all over the place.
Last year in Virginia, we lost a really hard battle.
They, they brought up what they call the their privacy act. I think it's the VD CPA.
And I can't remember
there are a lot of CS and P's and A's in my acronym world
and I sometimes get mixed up about
whether they're privacy or protection or personal.
But Virginia passed a law
that was really bad. I wrote about it. I called it an empty privacy law.
I stand by that and we're seeing it pop
up in statehouses all over the country from some,
some lawmakers who say, well, I hear my constituents talking about privacy,
but I'm really
about what it means for businesses. And so I'm just going to run this Virginia law,
others saying like
I care, but I don't
know enough about privacy and this law exists. So I'm going to start here.
So we've had a lot of conversations. I mean, privacy is
really complicated, especially in law.
And, you know, we have some very clear
priorities of what we want, namely we want strong enforcement because I think we
think laws are only as good as their teeth. And so if somebody breaks them, we want,
you know, individuals to have the right to sue that company, you know,
if they violated the law, if they violated their privacy,
and we want that coupled with strong public enforcement.
So, you know, a, a well funded attorney general's office or in California,
we have a new privacy agency that's just getting off the ground.
-- It'll be really interesting to see how that goes. So,
-- ok, so
wrapping up,
I'm a normal person.
-- What can I do? So
-- certainly to change things, you can see, you know, I mean,
I hate to like plug our own site but you can see if uh
-- yeah, if
-- no way, plug away everyone listening, go
join the eff right now. It's like the greatest organization.
So there I did it for you.
Thank you. I appreciate that.
So, yeah, you know, we put up,
we put up actions all the time about things that are happening in,
in people's states.
If you see, for example, if you're in Ohio right now,
um it'd be great if you could tell them that the Ohio Personal Privacy Act is not good,
right? So you can, you can take actions like that.
Um We also to plug, um you know, to plug us again, we have the Electric
Electronic Frontier Alliance,
which is a loose federation of um of grassroots
groups across the country that we work with.
You know, there really are eyes and ears on the ground. In, in,
in States. I could not do my job without them.
Um If you're interested in, in that you can join that. And, you know, as,
as you hear, privacy come up probably on your
local news, right? Because as I said, this fight really is at the state level,
you know, get engaged, think about it. Um you know, send
emails to your lawmakers. It's amazing to me
how much a constituent email matters to a
lot of these particularly state lawmakers because they,
they don't get to hear from their own people that often and that, that goes far.
So if you are passionate about these issues,
engage it, it really is, it seems scary but
the the
there's a very low chance that it'll blow back on you in a,
in a bad way and there's a lot of chance that, um you know,
if you get the ear of your lawmaker
that and they are your uh they are your
representative that they will at least listen to you.
Absolutely. And I'm going to also plug, we actually you mentioned the,
what was it, the Electronic
Frontier Alliance? I think you called it
a
correct.
We, we the E fa we had a guest
it's been probably a year now. Uh, Chris Whelan from restore the Fourth Minnesota.
I'll put a link in the show notes to that,
which I'd highly recommend anyone go and listen to.
And I, I think we sometimes forget how powerful our voice can be at a local level.
Federally.
It probably is very quiet, but locally we can be very, very loud.
And so I love that advice and I feel like that is,
-- that's a great place for all of us
-- to start. A little bit. Goes a long way.
Absolutely.
Absolutely. This has been,
oh my goodness. I,
I
feel like I could talk to you for hours. I won't, but this has been
an absolute treat. Haley.
I want to thank you so very much for coming in and chatting with us.
This I, I'm, I'm, I'm ecstatic.
So, ok,
thank you everyone for listening.
There'll be a bunch of show notes, go hit those up, follow the links,
join the eff do all those things
and you can go to open source security podcast.com for the show notes.
You can use
a Podos as podcast. Hashtag hit us up on social media.
-- Haley and Kurt have marvelous, rest of your days. Thanks
-- for having me.
-- Thank
-- you everybody. Thanks
again Haley and thank you, everyone. Bye bye.