Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast. Door number five.
-- It is store number five.
-- So five reasons. You don't need 24 7 monitoring.
You don't, you,
you just said you don't.
Well,
ok, you know what?
-- No,
-- you do need you need,
you know
what,
at a metal level, I would argue.
You don't need 59,
24 7 monitoring because the system should automatically react to
it because even if you have 24 7 monitoring,
humans are slow.
Well, humans shouldn't be the ones doing the monitoring.
You should have a robot doing the monitoring.
Uh So, ok, five reasons. You need 24 7 robot monitoring.
And obviously door number one is like like Attackers don't
sleep and they come from different weird time zones.
Wait, how many door? Wait, we just opened door.
Number one, door, number one was like nonsensical stream of consciousness.
So anyways uh Attackers don't 9 to 5.
My favorite example of this is being the Swiss Air Force.
Remember they had that uh passenger jet crash but
they couldn't get any Swiss Air Force up because
what was the weekend?
I do not remember that.
But you will, you will give me the link and I'll put it in the show notes.
-- All right. So what are the five reasons?
-- Uh No, that was the only reason I had.
I thought we were going to debate it real quick. Um My, my other thought is like,
I don't like monitoring in the sense of
monitoring implies a reactive thing where something has gone
wrong and I need to then detect something has gone wrong and to go deal with it,
I would rather prevent the thing from going wrong in the
first place and just not have to deal with it.
Prevention doesn't work. So like for example,
user logging in correctly, no, you know what,
just make people use a password and multifactors authentication.
So that either they've kidnapped my person in which case,
whatever game over they win or it's actually them. Ok.
So I have a better example for this I think is so obviously,
I'm surrounded by monitoring stuff all day because obviously elastic search,
this is one things that it does and you deploy all this monitoring infrastructure
and then you obviously start collecting logs and everything.
And obviously you end up with problems like alert fatigue, you can log too much,
you can log too little, there's like a million problems.
But the point is when you do this right,
you have the ability to
essentially have a beautiful forensic trail you can use to
-- figure out what actually happened
-- and that's the thing.
There's a big difference between detection and prevention and
forensics because by the time you're doing forensics,
oh, we're looking at the black box and everybody's dead.
-- It's a bit late.
-- Well, and look, prevention can stop.
We'll say the most trivial of things.
Yeah. But prevention is never going to be 100%.
But you know what,
when you have good monitoring in place you can be close
to 100% of good monitoring data that you can then use
to figure out what say an attacker did or why your
infrastructure fell over or why the website is running slow or,
and step number two is then engineering that away like an airline crash, right?
You look at why the airline crash or the airplane crash and you fix it,
the same problem should never happen twice.
And if it does, you have failed,
you say that.
But again, there was that like,
what was it DC elevens with the cargo door that kept blowing out and like,
literally the, their, the air crash investigator was like,
we've seen this before. Oh, it's the exact same thing.
Oh, wait,
what do you mean they didn't implement our recommendations from the first crash?
Yeah, exactly.
The guy, like, it's, it's tragic because he's just like we, we figured this out,
we gave these recommendations and they were ignored.
That is unfortunate for sure. Yeah.
Well, I mean, but, you know, it, life's complicated. Stuff costs money to fix.
Right. It, it does.
And it depends how bad the problem is and what's going and there's a million things.
-- Right. It's, it's always difficult.
-- Sorry.
Uh, DC 10, the DC 10 had a cargo door that would just sort of like,
-- blow out once in a while until they fixed
-- it.
I have a suspicion. Very few people know the difference.
Fair
enough. I have no idea. Anyway. Anyway.
Right. Ok. So anyway, the point is
monitoring is marvelous. But you also can't have humans looking at your data.
Humans should only look when something horrible is going wrong.
And this is why you should have essentially robots
doing all of the work and you should have rules
set up saying these are the things we're going
to care about and when the bad thing happens,
then the human can show up and be like, oh,
the robot and it's run amok or the human can say something very bad is going on.
I'm gonna, I'm gonna disagree with you.
The humans should be involved when something new happens,
the same thing should never happen twice.
So the humans should be involved when something new happens and then they
-- figure it out and engineer around it and that's it.
-- Right. Well, exactly.
That's the idea.
Cool. I like it.
All right. I got to figure out what, what day is next six,
we will see you all on December 6th.