Hello and welcome to the open source Security podcast episode 58 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
What's New Kurt?
-- I spent a couple of days at the cabin. It was nice.
-- That sounds fantastic.
I, I have a terrible cold today, so I'm going to apologize in advance for my, no doubt,
silly sounding voice.
But, yeah, out of nowhere I woke up this morning and,
and I'm sick and it's summer and this is ridiculous.
I don't know what it is. I think it's
international air
travel or something because,
no,
seriously, I don't remember as a kid.
Anybody ever being sick except like in fall and spring.
Uh,
yeah. Yeah. Yeah. That, that seems about
right.
Nobody had colds in
summer.
I, I remember getting one once when I was very young and it was terrible.
It was probably some horrible plague or something.
Anyway. Anyway, I'll survive
no rest for the wicked. Right.
Oh, man. It has been a week, hasn't it?
Yeah.
Yeah. No, it's, uh,
where do you even start?
I guess with the guy who probably shouldn't have advertised and
sold hacking tools online and then made a big name for himself
and gone to the US.
You know, that one, I'm going,
there's still a lot of details to that story. I don't understand and, and
rather than necessarily pass judgment on anyone one way or the other, I,
I think we should wait and see how it plays out.
But I think that the one bit of commentary I would have here is
I,
I feel like the authorities could have done a slightly better job here of explaining
-- what the heck is going on because I feel like they've been very
-- quiet.
Why would they care?
-- I mean, our opinion literally does not matter.
-- Well, it does though.
And, and the reason is I, I think it was the GRG talked about this.
I, I don't remember for sure. So if it was someone else, I apologize. But
basically,
when you're looking at the way law
enforcement works today in the security universe,
there's a certain amount of trust and goodwill they need
to count on from the members of the community.
And when you do something like this,
even when it's for a good reason,
you can't just be quiet because you're burning your goodwill right now.
And so there's going to be people who aren't going to
work with them in the future for a variety of reasons
because of this.
-- And,
-- well, the problem is though legally though, you know,
you're in that sort of no comment phase,
but I don't even think they've done that.
It, it doesn't sound like they're, they're saying literally anything.
Well, I mean, there's a pretty, I mean, well, the indictment,
as I understand it is pretty clear.
It's for the, um, oh, what's the name of the tools again?
I
Kronos. Kronos.
Thank you, Kronos
with a K, that's what it was.
And, I mean, you know,
we have on the one side that people are like, well, you know,
if you write hacking tools, you shouldn't get arrested for that.
And on the other side, you know,
you have people who would cheerfully put everybody
who wrote anything remotely resembling a hack to
hacking tool into a tree chipper
and then, you know, somewhat more in the middle.
We have the, well,
maybe you shouldn't write hacking tools and advertise them as such
and, you know, be like, yeah, you can use these to break
the banks and stuff and like, here's the support number
it rings to my cell phone or, you know, or whatever. Right? Because
I
think in a lot of cases, a reasonable case could be made in front of a judge that,
you know, maybe you're not just kind of a, you know, blameless hacking tool maker,
but you're actually kind of,
-- uh, either colluding or, you know, getting really involved or,
-- right.
But you've already ventured into the realm of guilty,
not guilty versus just the fact that I don't feel like law
guilty or not guilty. I'm just pointing out that though.
It's, you know, there's, there's,
uh, like Theodore wrote N map.
Right. Awesome tool.
Probably one of the most used hack, quote unquote hacking tools out there. Right.
Because what's the first thing anybody does end map scan
good or bad. Right.
-- Yeah,
-- exactly.
You know, but, like, he's never,
I mean, I hate to say it but a lot of times, like, perception is reality,
it's
reality.
Yeah.
And so, you know, I wouldn't go out and advertise, you know, something is like,
you know, use this to break into banks and steal their money,
you know,
because that's just probably not going to end well ever.
But,
but we're still talking about guilty or not guilty versus the fact that I feel
like the law enforcement universe should be doing a slightly better job of a,
at least making sure people understand what's going on.
Yeah.
But the thing to remember too is, for example,
if they want your cooper operation in many jurisdictions, they can just compel it
with a warrant or a national security letter.
Yes. And what they didn't do that, they arrested a dude.
-- No, no,
-- no,
no, no, no, no, no,
we don't know that they haven't done it because again,
some of those things are by their nature.
Secret.
-- Ok.
-- Look
like we don't know. That's part of the problem we enter that rabbit hole of like,
maybe it's the lizard man or maybe it's just like, really poor pr, who knows?
I think if you've arrested someone, it's fair to say that
they're being pressured to cooper.
I, I don't think there's any denying that whether they do or not is another story.
But fundamentally,
I think when you have a dude who comes to the United States for a hacking conference,
he's relatively well known in the community and
you just up and arrest him and say nothing
that burns goodwill, whether right or wrong it burns goodwill.
And that's the truth of the matter, right?
Well, the thing too is we can't treat law enforcement like one single entity.
-- But
-- we do,
we do look at, look at, you know, even within,
say the FBI or within the US marshals or because that's, I mean,
there's the first thing, there's, there's multiple
entities in the US that enforce these, a
variety of these laws.
They all have different
agendas and, and cultures, for example.
Um And even within them, I mean, you look at some places like the FBI like,
uh I remember watching the, the documentary on Ruby Ridge, right?
It was this horrible mess of FBI meets, you know, kind of
uh family living in the wilderness in the cabin with
guns and it just went all the way south fast
and even within the FBI, you know, there's like the people are kind of like, well,
you know, he should have behaved himself and blah, blah, blah and,
and on the far other side, there's like the FBI people are like, wow,
we really screwed this one up.
Like I can't, like we did the worst possible job ever,
-- you know, and everything in between two.
-- Yes. And you're always going to have that.
However,
here's the difference is nobody is expecting the family members of the
Ruby Ridge people to ever help the FBI in the future,
the FBI or whatever organization may have picked this
guy up because even that isn't totally clear,
they're going to need help from the community at some point.
Be it employees,
be it help with figuring some botnet out or some piece of malware or something
and, and they're burning their goodwill and that's my whole point,
right or wrong, right? Just don't burn your goodwill.
But here's a question.
Do we know that the community is actually really
been helping law enforcement with this kind of stuff?
-- I can,
-- I
don't
know,
I
-- honestly don't know
-- there's a certain amount of cooper
that happens, I think and,
and I'm not saying they're like going out to black hats and saying, you know, hey,
dude, come help me out here.
But I do know that there's,
there's various organizations and various companies
that will help law enforcement.
I mean,
you always hear about like Microsoft working with
some group to take down some botnet or,
or some hacking group or whatever, right.
There's always something going on like that
and my point is that
if, if you burn enough goodwill and I'm not even saying they burned at all yet,
just if you burn enough,
you'll eventually hit a point where literally nobody wants to work with you.
Right.
I, well, I mean, look at one good extreme example of this would be the NSA.
They've burned quite a bit of goodwill as I understand it, you know,
with various spying programs and stuff
and they seem to be doing fine.
I have no idea. II, I didn't know how they were doing before this.
I don't know how they're doing afterwards. It's,
and maybe you're right. Maybe it doesn't matter
and, and maybe they can do this. But, but I feel like
they, they've made a tactical error on this one.
I think they certainly could have handled it
more gracefully.
Definitely.
But, I mean, I kind of wondered again, does it matter? I don't know. I really don't.
And, and I guess they must think it doesn't
if they,
or they're just, they made a mistake or somebody, you know,
because that's the other thing too is we're,
we're sort of ascribing intent to this when it could just be like,
just a clerical error,
like,
seriously
clerical error, man.
Well, you get what I'm saying, like in the sense of like,
we didn't do a proper press release to announce, you know, we've, it's possible,
you know, or the guy was sick that week or, you know, who knows? Right.
Like, I,
it always amazes me because I have worked for
the government for a brief period of six months.
And, like,
yeah, there, I mean, like, the fact that people think JFK could have been, you know,
assassinated and that kept a secret for, like, 40 years.
Like, are you kidding me?
Like,
like NASA faked the moon landings and, like,
nobody leaked
it.
-- No, that's not how large organizations work.
-- I know exactly what you mean.
You can't keep anything secret.
Well, like the whole look at the whole diesel exhaust thing, you know
the
the cheating on the diesel exhaust emissions tests and
all these things. Right? They, they eventually come to light typically.
Yeah,
always
-- it's
-- on the flip side,
there could be lizard been running everything
who actually are good at keeping secrets and
-- will never know if
-- there are like you guys could do a better job,
I think right now because I'm not happy with the state of things.
So
overlords like get your act together. Alright.
Alright. Anyway, let's move on, let's move on.
This is, well, I guess we'll find out,
I'm sure in the coming weeks we'll have more to discuss this
time.
Probably. Unfortunately I feel bad for anyone incarcerated because I'm
from, from what I've seen,
it's just like years of pain in many instances which isn't,
well, especially, I mean, he's, this is not his country
-- that too, right? He's from the UK. So
-- I'm not,
I, I couldn't imagine being arrested in a foreign country. It's got to be miserable
and it can't be fun and I imagine it's expensive.
I,
yeah. Right. I, I, right. Exactly.
Anyway, anyway,
how about something cheerful and happy, like, stealing credentials?
Have nothing cheerful and happy to ever talk about.
If we did it would, wouldn't be called, the security
-- is killing TLS.
-- That's
really good news. I'll agree with that. I am so excited to see them doing that. It's,
it made my day
when I read that.
I
mean,
-- the, the, you
-- know,
I mean TLS 1.0 and 1.1 are definitely better than SSL,
but they, they TLS 1.01 0.1 definitely
need to die.
And I think the email points out beautifully, like,
look open SSL has had this for like five years
and I mean, virtually all the other SSL,
NTLS implementations have had this for like the better part of half a decade now.
And so, yeah. No, it's time to say goodbye. I like
and II, I get that.
It's hard because there's some like older versions of
JA and stuff that don't have good support.
-- But I
-- disagree with you. Here's the thing.
If you need these horrible legacy protocols, you need to be taking
uh incredible steps to support those meaning you're sent standing up like virtual
networks and you're standing up old V MS locked down in certain ways.
This isn't one of those.
Oh, let's just support it because we can't,
because we used to think that way and we got ourselves in a ton of trouble.
Backwards compatibility to the point of insanity is
a terrible,
the thing is though,
I see a lot of software and hardware manufacturers that put stuff in the field
and nobody wants to spend money updating or upgrading it.
-- And that's
-- ok.
So
we're making
a decision
but you shouldn't be expected to be working flawlessly with a piece
of hardware or even an application that comes out next year.
So Microsoft is going to disable everything but
TLS 1.2 and up and say Microsoft edge browser
and everybody's going to lose their mind because they can no longer talk to their,
talk to their crappy little soho devices to, you know,
configure them through the web interface.
I'm ok with that.
Well,
but Microsoft support doesn't want to have to, you know,
hire 10 million more people
to explain this to these customers.
-- You know, like that doesn't work
-- that way though.
I mean, to call Microsoft support, you need a support agreement.
-- I mean, you can't just
-- call them people would be outraged.
-- I
-- I'm ok with that though, like,
but the thing is, are we doing more harm than good?
Because for example, yeah, don't get me wrong.
There would be a huge benefit to being like,
you know, what next Thursday
all everything will be TLS 1.2 or newer,
like that would like so many problems would just go away.
Right.
It would be wonderful
on the flip side
that does do economic damage in the sense of like
all these old soho routers and all these old
applications and stuff that can't talk these newer protocols.
-- What happens to them?
-- I'm, they're gonna have to die. Look, man.
I mean, we switched to
digital television
and, and people own devices that don't work anymore and, and there's,
you get a $50 digital TV converter
and you know what, I'm sure
someone could write an app that could be like a crappy insecure proxy or something.
Like
there are ways you can make
this general,
well, like with a soho device though, I can't run custom code on it easily,
sort of like reloading it with a WDR.
You
could run like a cram proxy on your local system that
would let you connect to it if you absolutely needed to.
Right.
But you're assuming these people running these
systems even have somebody capable of.
No, they
don't. And that's the whole reason these things should be like
and thrown away because these people are, you know, I hate to say it, but
they're a danger to society like they don't even know it.
I was just uh so I was upgrading my cable modem today because the old one is, well,
I realized it was probably four or five years old.
Had been running nonstop, you know, for half a decade
and it was starting to draw my internet connection for like,
one or two seconds every couple of hours, which gets really annoying.
And, um, I went and swapped it and while I was there, I actually asked, like,
what's the oldest thing you've seen come in?
And she's like, well, actually today we had one of the old silver PV RS and I'm like,
the what?
Nails?
She's like one of the, you know, and she just, I'm like, oh my God, I remember those,
like, from
1015 years ago,
you know, and that's the thing, right?
Like, there's the thing to remember now is it's not
computer systems aren't like a server running, you know,
data center somewhere.
It's, it's people like my accountant with a Dell machine
doing God knows what, I don't want to know. I just try not to think about it.
They do backups of it.
I checked on that.
But, you know, there's so much, like there's
so much stuff in people's houses, you know, uh PV RS and digital TV.
S whatsits that talk to the internet, you know,
uh, all these things and, you know,
replacing all this stuff does.
Actually, I mean,
it's tens of hundreds of millions of dollars to get rid of all this stuff.
Um,
part of me is like, yeah, that would be awesome.
I would love to have a rule that says, like, any electronics more than five years old.
You got to take them out back and shoot them
in some respects.
That wouldn't, I think, be a terrible thing now, ecologically,
it would be terrible.
I accept that.
But,
you know, like we just can't
force everybody to recycle
everything. You know.
How old is TLS? 12. Now, it's more than five years old. Right. There's,
this is lazy manufacturers that aren't supporting TLS 1.2.
Well, but no, no, the manufacturers don't write implementations.
At least I hope they don't, I hope they're using Open SSL because,
oh my God, if I found a vendor apart from like, say, you know,
like a Microsoft or an Apple or a, you know, like
the major
open SSL,
but I'm saying they probably cherry picked some
like 10 year old version five years ago,
you know what I mean?
So they were already running something that was too freaking old
and they were too lazy to make it work correctly,
you know, with the newer version.
Yeah, TLS 1.2 was defined in RFC 5246 in August of 2008.
Part of it to remember.
It's not like people just, oh, you know, you have a new encryption thing,
let's just hop on that, right.
You want to kind of make sure it's maybe not fatally flawed. Like, oh,
all the other old stuff.
See, that's the thing to remember too with this concretion, right? Is
Oh, all the old stuff is horribly broken. This new stuff. Totally fine.
It'll be fine forever except, you know, a year from now when we find out the
-- s 1.2 is horribly flawed.
-- What people used to think.
I, I dare say, but I don't think that's the case anymore.
I think we've come to recognize the fact that all of
these protocols are fatally flawed and we have to march forward
and this is really the whole reason we're seeing
this decision from Debian in the first place.
Right.
Well,
see the thing is Debian can make that
decision without incurring a significant cost to themselves.
Right. They don't have to worry about selling
systems.
They don't have to like, they don't have some of the concerns Microsoft has.
I mean, again, to be clear, I'm not arguing against this.
I'm just saying there are some significant costs around
making these decisions and it's a trade off.
It's not just simply like kill all the old stuff. Great.
I mean, I'm currently in the process of an IT renewal,
you know, in the last two weeks, I've got a new cable modem, a new Wi Fi because
I now have Wi Fi covering my entire desk.
Uh, two weeks ago, Wi Fi wasn't available on the left side of my desk,
but it kind of worked mostly on the right side of my desk.
I think it's part of the problem is all the
vents and stuff between me and the Wi Fi router.
But now I got one of those scary looking Asus things with like
too many antennas and it seems to work finite.
So, here's the thing to remember too.
This isn't like Debbie and is flipping a switch tomorrow. This isn't
true.
And, and the new,
the version of Debbie and stable just came out like
a month ago or a couple of months ago,
it's very new.
-- And so it's going to
-- be, can they
deprecated and stable though? Can they upgrade their?
I
-- don't think
-- they, because they don't have like an API or a B I guarantee do they?
I mean, I'm sure they technically could, but I'm saying they make
an effort,
but
my suspicion is they'll just wait and they'll, they'll let the current stable,
you know, just kind of phase out and, and the new version won't support it correctly.
And I, again,
I am perfectly ok with like crappy gear people have in their houses not working.
I, I am very pleased to say that it is going to happen.
Uh Sorry, I'm just reading this. So uh
as of July 2017.
So for our viewers or listeners,
uh we're currently just in August of 2017 right now as we speak
TLS, 1.3 is a working draft and details are provisional and incomplete.
So we're now at like
10 years between releases of TLS.
It's, it's been a long time
and 1.3 was expected earlier in the year.
But it sounds like there's some hooey going on with some of the reviewers.
-- So I don't know if we're
-- going to see, are they trying to show?
Because I know the financial industry,
a lot of it was not happy about like perfect forward secrecy being the default
-- because it means they can no longer sniff connection.
-- That's part of it.
And, and that's kind of one of the big ones.
And again, this is, this is one of those situations where I think
it is, it is imperative
that
especially security people,
we march forward with progress instead of trying to hold something
back because we're just going to end up breaking it.
I agree.
I mean, I personally, I think basically, and I've tweeted this before,
if you're like,
security profile depends on you behaving like
a nation state actor that is like intercepting
uh encrypted communications and like,
you know, looking at them,
uh basically all, pretty much all the other vendors are, you know,
working against that they're trying to prevent this stuff.
Um But more to the point, I mean, the problem though is you have the, well,
you have this ecosystem, right?
So
for example,
I know that there are specific pieces of legislation in various
parts of the world that say as a financial institution,
you have to have visibility into all
the network traffic going across your networks,
which means
you know, some schmuck with a mobile phone using your wi fi,
you have to be able to sniff that
-- and you
-- can't really do.
No.
But you, I mean, the problem is, you know, when the auditors come in,
you have to make a best effort, which means you have to do this stuff.
And,
I mean, that's, that's the part that really gets me is that
now we're talking about things like legislation which is going to take 5,
1020 years to change
if,
if that
maybe longer.
Yeah, assuming it can be changed.
Plus you've got multiple jurisdictions and, you know, even within like the US,
for example, I mean,
how many different pieces of security and privacy legislation? Are there?
-- Probably not enough? Like,
-- I know there's hi
a and socks and like there's a, there's
a
and, and
so I, I want to talk,
there was
a, a link that someone sent me on Twitter
about
it.
It was after the last episode because we were talking about some safety things and,
and I've forgotten the lady's name.
I will put the, the link in the show notes,
but she gave this talk at the o'reilly Security Conference.
I think it was last year or the year before.
And
basically she pointed out that regulating the auto industry
took nearly 100 years from the time kind of automobiles began until it, it became
a legitimate concern of people.
And, and in that case people were literally dying.
I mean, this wasn't being
horribly. Right. Right. And in fact they said that
today
the number of auto deaths is down substantially from what it used to be.
Even though there are way more vehicles on the road. Just because
in
most of the western world,
some other parts of the world it's still pretty terrible.
And, and so this is something I think about for security a lot is,
yeah, the,
the regulations are terrible and the compliance is awful and some of it
doesn't work and a lot of it could even be considered dangerous.
Like what the guy who created the n
password guidelines said last week, like that was the worst mistake I ever made.
-- Right.
-- Well, it was a good idea at the time though. Right?
I thought it was true.
Exactly. I thought it was,
I remember talking with a Netscape guy. This is like, oh Lord, probably 15 years ago
and I'd written
uh Doug song. Who? Wow, that's a name I haven't heard in a while anyways.
He wrote uh Ssh Sniff, remember
and as a cell sniff
and it was things to do, you know, man, in the middle proxy of SSH and SSL, which I mean,
1520 years ago was a big deal.
And uh so I wrote this article talking about, you know, is this the end of SL and
H I mean, obviously not, but hyperbole does get clicks
and you know this Netscape engineer was like, yeah,
if we'd had any idea what SSL would end up being used for.
-- Holy cow, we would have done it very differently, but
-- that's always the case.
All right, just to, just to call it out correctly.
Uh A guy named Fernando Montenegro. I apologize if I buttered your name.
And the,
the talk is by someone named Becky Base and I will be sure to put a link to all this in,
in the show notes.
But I, I would highly recommend everybody watch this because it was,
it, it's, it's hair raising
for
how it all works out and how horrible it is.
And I suspect, you know, we're, we're in the same boat because part of it too is,
I mean, the auto industry, at least
the cars have four wheels. Right. I mean,
my computer now fits in my pocket.
-- It doesn't have a keyboard, it's just got a glass screen.
-- It can't murder you yet.
Uh,
actually,
uh,
GPS driving navigation. It could,
you know, if I wasn't really paying attention to
the computer
and people do it and
-- stuff is,
-- is much different than, than someone hacking your gps.
Uh,
not having 911 service when I need
-- it.
-- I
won't disagree with you.
There,
there are certain things that could be done that would be terribly inconvenient.
But, but
yeah, but it's not going to, like, turn on.
Well, it's not like a car wash where it's going, like,
smush me with the arm or whatever.
Right.
Yeah.
As it turns out if you have heavy machinery controlled by poorly secured computers,
you're gonna have a bad time.
That's the thing. Right. Those are the things that are probably going to see
the most regulation and laws because people can,
people can understand what that means.
People don't understand what it means when they hack your gps on your iphone,
you know.
Right.
Well, there's been cases where people went.
Um, oh, what was that tragic case where the guy,
the gps basically showed a shortcut between two major roads
and it was like a logging path or something.
And they went out there in winter
and got their car stuck and the guy went for help and died and,
-- and it was like a tech guy. I remember it was some famous tech
-- guy.
It was a couple of years ago. I do remember that and, and his
-- kids stayed in the car and they did, which
-- is
absolutely what you're supposed to do.
Um,
but yeah, I mean, so no to say that, I mean, yeah, granted my phone can't like,
you know, cut me or like, explode in my hands.
But
no, you could, if I wasn't paying attention, you could definitely, you know,
-- ok,
-- but, but here's the thing is
what you're describing is extraordinary events.
Whereas back in the day, if you got in a car accident, you died. Right.
On your question.
-- You know, you got impaled.
-- Right.
It's, uh, did you ever see that video? It's, uh, it's on youtube. It's a Chevy Malibu.
Like an old one. I think it's a Chevy Malibu.
It's, anyways, it's like a 19 fifties car and then the modern version of it and they,
they crashed them head on offset and it's
-- horrifying.
-- It's crazy. Uh, it was, it impala, I forget who it
was.
-- Something like that. Yes.
-- Yes.
They took kind of the old and it was a car from when, like,
the N TSB was created versus a car today.
And actually I remember watching that because back
in the day people were always like,
oh, these old cars were all steeled.
They're much safer than the new cars.
And I remember I watched it, I thought, nope, those,
those old cars are not much safer than the new car.
They're much less.
It was a Chevrolet Bel Air
versus
a, a
2009. Chevrolet Malibu.
Yeah. Yeah. Well, it was an offset crash too, wasn't it? Which is like way worse?
Yeah. But I mean, in a modern, well, the modern car did pretty. Ok.
He said, I remember reading the story,
the person in the old car would have died instantly and
the person in the other car probably would have walked away.
Yeah,
that's crazy.
Well, it's, you know, we've learned a lot about how to make cars safer
-- and
-- unfortunately we, we learned it because lots of people died,
right? Do you want to hear something incredibly stupid or
up until about 20 years ago in Canada, in horse riding circles,
it wasn't actually required to wear your chin strap on your helmet.
Then why even wear a helmet?
Good question,
obviously
-- gonna fall,
-- right.
And here's the worst part,
there was a very famous writer called Ian Miller who
like went to the Olympics and everything hugely famous.
He never wears chin strap. And of course, you know, monkey see monkey do.
But yeah, I mean, like literally humans, we just,
I I've met people who don't want to wear a seat belt in a car because they think like,
because it's never going to happen to me, Kurt
-- or
-- because they're like, what if the car catches fire and I need to escape?
And I'm like,
yeah, it's, I mean,
it's statistically really unlikely like for
that specific scenario to happen where
-- you end up better off because you're not wearing your seat
-- bet.
So if you're one of those people and, and I'm totally serious,
uh you, you can buy these like special seatbelt knives you can put in your car,
like just give one and duct tape the thing to the freaking seatbelt, right?
Like that.
-- And
-- they also usually have like the little glass smasher so that
if you do manage to drive into a river or whatever,
-- you can smash the glass and get up and
-- and let's face it,
the vast majority of those people,
they just don't want to wear their seatbelt. Right. That's what it really is.
-- And they've made up some bizarre excuse
-- that people just
don't
confirm narrative.
Right.
Seriously. Who, what, like,
how many, how many groups can we offend today? Let's
-- probably all of them if we try. I'm sure
-- we can. I'm sure we can anyway.
Anyway, the point being we started with Debbie and, and we're ending with cars.
And it's really about the fact that I think
it is important to understand where the forward
march of progress is going to take you.
However,
the history of humanity says nobody is going to come along nicely.
-- We are going to be
-- dragged.
-- You can offer them some massive benefit, like,
-- even with massive benefit,
Kurt to get, get like auto regulations.
It was kicking and screaming the hallway,
right.
And, and even people were like, oh, I don't want to pay more for a car that, you know,
might save my life.
This is what it's going to be, is, is we are going to have to drag humanity
because I had this discussion with an older person where they're like, oh, old cars.
Yeah, they, when you're smashed up you could just fix the car.
And I'm like, I'm like, we don't actually want that. And she's like, what do you mean?
And I'm like,
how much does it cost to even just completely replace a car,
if it gets destroyed in a car accident.
Right. You're looking at 30 40 50 grand tops.
How much does one or two days in the IC U cost if you're in a bad car wreck?
Uh, I assume more than that.
Yeah, a lot more. Plus, say 10 years of physio for a messed up neck.
I totally agree.
And that's part of the problem is, you know,
we also need to look at like the bigger picture.
So like,
I'm just not convinced that because let's be honest, right? Most
very few Attackers attack the encryption
because
you can just hack the website and like suck down the the
the payments file or whatever,
you know.
And so that's one of, that's one basically,
that's the only reason I'm not sure that we'd be
-- that we should be aggressively sunsetting cryptography protocols
-- because no,
OK.
No, no, you, you've made a serious mistake in your assumption.
So TLS has been attacked successfully
many times over the years.
The encryption behind the TLS has never fallen.
It's always implementation problems that are attacked,
right? And, and so we, we've reached a point where like if you're running, say SSL two
people could literally man in the middle of you in real time with SSL.
I agree with something as old as SSL two. But for example, TLS 1.0 and 1.1
you know, nation states definitely are attacking this.
We've, we've seen evidence of that.
I'm certain of that and, and I think they have enough problems
and not only that, here's the bigger reason
is modern compliance says no TLS 10 or 11.
And so just turning it off is going to make that much, much easier to deal with as well.
Yeah,
I don't know. I'm comfortable with it, man.
I, I think we should, we should deprecate this old crap faster than we do.
I, well, I mean, in general,
if we build systems that could be upgraded more
-- easily with less hassle and
-- that's the thing,
-- right, then
-- we would just be better off.
That will be the inevitable outcome of, of things like this.
If, if people can't run something forever,
they're going to at least the manufacturers hopefully will start to think about how
can I make sure this is something people will still be wanting to use?
Although they,
they probably don't have an incentive to keep something alive for 10 years.
But
you get the idea right is,
oh, I've decided now I'm, I'm going to replace all my networking gear basically.
-- Every 3 to 4 years.
-- Mine like cooks itself every couple of years. So
that's
like I said, my,
my Wi Fi range was slowly starting to decrease in the house.
-- So
-- what it
is, what it is, in fact, my router funny enough, uh
I, I bought an Asus router
and
it died.
And so like it was one of those like I, I needed internet that day.
So I literally drove to Best Buy that minute, bought a new router, drove back home,
plugged it in
and then I, I looked it up and my old router was still under warranty.
So I sent it back and they sent me a new one.
And now the last one I bought just died like two weeks ago.
And I plugged in the old one, the old R MA router,
but unfortunately the other one was out of warranty.
So I thought it would have been hilarious if I
just continued some sort of bizarre warranty ping pong.
But, yeah, no, I, I get it.
And so now I keep thinking, I'm like,
I should buy a new router because I know this one is gonna die.
Yeah.
But you can get like, I mean, I got a top, well,
not a top line but a pretty high end ASIS one.
I mean, Amazon Prime will have that to you in a day or two.
And if you absolutely have to go to Best Buy, to pick it up,
-- you can be there and back in a few hours
-- unwilling to wait a day for a
new R,
like I need my internet now.
Well, see,
this is why I have two network connections at home
because it also forces me then to have like the,
I have actually two firewalls instead of a single firewall.
But if your Wi Fi dies what are you going to do?
Uh, swap in an old wi
fi access point?
-- Actually,
-- I do have another old one in the closet.
Really?
I have little like cockroaches, man.
They just, they, they get sick but they don't die. And so, like,
uh,
yeah, I guess that's true. The old one I have, I, it does technically work.
It's in a box. I'm gonna get rid of it. But anyway, anyway,
uh, we should talk about HBO perhaps,
which is not at all open source related but,
but why not?
Yeah, I mean, so, yeah.
Well, and I mean,
my feelings on HBO are somewhat conflicted because quite frankly
for me to get HBO legally where I live,
I'm looking at like, quite a lot of money.
I'm, I'm pleased to say that it is not a problem I suffer from.
I, I have HBO now, which is like $15 a month and it's fantastic.
I used to watch Game of Thrones which we
will not give out any game of Thrones spoilers,
but
I don't watch that show. So, you don't watch Game of Thrones?
I saw the first
dude. It's
good.
I
think
I just kind of lost interest
you should watch. Actually, the first season is a little weird.
-- I won't lie, but it gets, it gets solid. I really like it, it
-- was a lack of weird.
It wasn't weird.
I mean, it was just, I just didn't really, I don't know, fantasies, just
whatever
you,
I'm, I'm comfortable saying you're wrong.
So, anyway, anyway,
here's the important thing though is for those of you who don't know
HBO got hacked and I guess some of the scripts and,
-- and videos of Game of Thrones apparently
-- also
phone numbers of the actors and well see,
phone numbers of the actors is unfortunate,
although I imagine finding these people's phone numbers
isn't an insurmountable task if you're clever.
But, but the point being bad guys got it
and now they're trying to ransom it away
and, and I do feel like,
-- sorry, that's just so stupid.
-- It kind of is
who's gonna like, pay for a script or pay. Like,
I
feel like, like for all the, like, for example,
I really enjoy watching Black Mirror and if you offered me like all
the scripts for Black Mirror going forward for the next 10 years,
I'd be like, yeah.
No, thanks because quite frankly
I, yeah, I could read the scripts and I'm sure they'd be kind of interesting but
you know, they're scripts, they don't work as like reading material.
What about the video though? Imagine the videos because I,
the scripts are much less interesting than the actual video
I might watch maybe. But I mean,
here's, here's my more to the point I wouldn't,
I don't feel like HBO is gonna pay like a ransom to get,
I think they're lunatics if they do. And well, this happened in Netflix.
With orange is the new black and,
and this is where I kind of have a very open source viewpoint of,
-- of this problem is release,
-- early release
once the episode airs,
like it doesn't matter anymore.
You know, it's kind of like, I remember the old joke about
uh uh it was, I think the Apache guys,
I
don't think it happens like it used to but they used to
get an email about once a week where someone was like,
do you guys know your, your source code is leaked on this FTP site?
And they're
like,
yeah, yeah, we do. And, and, you know, it's kind of,
I feel like it's a bit like that. Right.
It's once the episode airs using the word air and air quotes here
like it. Now that information you, you're trying to ransom has no value.
Right. Oh, yeah. No, it's very
-- time sensitive but
-- HBO could do. That would be a hilarious finger
to, to these people big middle finger sticking up is just like,
release the episode early
just to be like, no,
your ransom has no place here. Right.
-- Yeah.
-- Well, I, I just, I can't imagine because even if you do pay the ransom,
it's not like this group is going to be doing
enough ransoms to want to have a good reputation,
you know, like some of those.
And not only that, the way this works is
I've already paid them for the month. Right. I can't,
even if I did pirate it, which I'm too lazy to do. I won't lie to you.
Even if I did though, like HBO doesn't make less money. Right.
I'm not gonna be like, oh,
I'm gonna cancel my subscription now that I can pirate early up.
-- No, like, screw that. I'm lazy and I want to watch them on my,
-- I
think honestly probably the biggest
negative outcome of this would be somebody
watching it and then posting spoilers on like
a popular Twitter feed or something and kind of ruining it for other people.
That's
probably the biggest negative outcome.
Sadly, you're right. And
I think
I can live with that.
It's
uh, yeah,
anyway,
whatever it's,
I, I think
I just part of me really hopes that these
companies don't pay because one of the beauties of,
for example, in America,
the FBI has made kidnapping just, it's not financially worth it,
right?
I mean, kidnappings happen,
but they're almost never financial in nature because the
FBI made sure to like Nip that in the bud
and then there's other countries where like, you know,
being kidnapped for money and all that is like essentially normal,
right?
You know, I like ransomware is a great example, right?
Ransomware has gotten to the point where, yeah, I mean, it's just what? Really?
Oh, I don't know if you saw the number for the wanna cry guys. Was it, uh, wanna crypt?
Sorry.
Which, which one am I thinking of now the one that did the, um,
the windows XP and whatnot stuff.
-- That's
-- the wanna cry one.
Anyways, apparently the total amount of Bitcoin paid to them was like,
somewhere in the neighborhood of just over 100 grand.
-- It's not that much. I mean, it's,
-- it's, oh,
for the amount of ruckus it caused,
it probably cost billions in all the nonsense.
Easily three or four orders of magnitude more than they are
and nothing.
Yeah.
And I mean, well, granted, we still have, for example, spam is a great example,
right?
Spam is a huge problem and, you know, we spend
billions if not tens of billions of dollars a year
preventing it.
You know,
and it just, it's,
I
just, I still don't understand how people can fall for spam
because humans are terrible at understanding how anything works.
It's like fishing, man, you can fish anybody.
It doesn't matter how much training you go. It doesn't matter who they are,
you can fish them
guaranteed
you and I are not immune to fishing.
And I'm quite comfortable saying that the answer is
just not to read any of your emails.
-- Well, that's why
-- I'm moving to a UB key for everything.
-- Good. That's a very good
-- choice
to help prevent myself from making stupid mistakes.
I carry three UI keys with me actually, which is hilarious.
I, you know what I use it for. Actually, I met the UI key guys.
I was talking to him at black hat
and I
pulled my G
on, I've got three of them. The guy's like, why do you have three?
And I said, uh I, I use them like HS MS actually, where I carry around,
I've got a whole bunch of, of uh GP G keys on my U key.
So essentially what you're saying is somebody needs to kidnap
you and then threaten you with a lead pipe.
-- They
-- can
-- have it.
They could just ask, look, look, if you like, you probably give them up for 100 bucks.
I'm not gonna lie to you. Right. Like,
and then I go home and I just generate new keys. Like,
seriously.
Yeah. Anyway, anyway,
uh Right.
I, I think we got this one and, and I guess lastly the,
the one other thing I'd like to talk about is the N PM thing,
I guess, sort of typo squatting. NP MP.
Well, it's not so much typo squatting as sort of who? Um,
well, part of it is typo squatting for sure, but some of it is also his name.
Space management
is, is NCM is the no Js package manager.
So essentially when you, when you have a node project and you,
you need to pull in like dependencies or something.
Uh N PM is the tool of choice to do that.
Yeah.
Right. Just for people who don't know, I'll assume somebody does.
And so, yeah, I mean,
the reality is people do make typos, you know,
import foo and spell it with three Os instead of two Os.
I took out what a dash and the, the one I read about it was something, dash something.
-- And he just took the dash out assuming people are going to mistakenly
-- every time I,
I reinstall a computer or something, you know.
And then I put chrome on it and then I have to go find the, um,
the ad blocker I use and it's like, is it you block origin? Is it you block
or like, you know, because there's like six different U block things now trying to,
you know, squat on the name of
forks or, and so I'm always like, you know, like
trying to find a different computer. So they,
well, I guess they all have the same one. I hope it's the right one.
There's really, you know,
because there's not like some central registry where I can check.
Yep. Yep. Yeah, same, same basic idea. However,
in your case, they're just selling ads.
In this case,
it sounds like the malicious code was stealing credentials from developers.
Which is really interesting because
now the natural question, the next question becomes, what are they, are,
is this someone just kind of hoarding this
or are they actively attacking the stuff or,
or what's, I guess what's next?
And I haven't heard anything about that but it's, it's interesting.
It could be, I mean, because one of my thoughts on is this,
you get that sort of wildfire problem where, you know, for example,
if I could hack five or six popular NP MS and get everybody using them to be hacked,
you could probably quickly infest the entire ecosystem
without a doubt.
You know, what was it? The, the guy, the, the right shift with
the seven lines of code left shift. Sorry,
the, what was it? Seven lines of code or
whatever anyways, you know, if that guy had been evil, who
I mean, but that's true of nearly anything.
I mean, if,
if Linus decided to sell out one day or the GCC guys decided or the chrome guys or,
-- you know, there's,
-- well, I mean, I'm less worried about people deciding to sell,
I'm more worried about, yeah, you know,
somebody somehow goofs their credentials and some, and a bad guy gets into their
whatever code project.
Um
I mean, the thing to remember too is like,
Linux has at least a reasonable set of checks and balances.
There are people doing code reviews but like a lot of these NP MS
-- are probably one developer. They, they
-- probably are.
And here's the scarier thing is what you're describing
is almost certainly going to happen someday because there's
checks and balances.
Remember when Ruby gems.org sort of got hacked
luckily by a well meaning person who didn't do anything evil. But, you know,
I do,
they, again,
that would have been if it had been a bad guy that
would have been every single person doing ruby development who like,
didn't read hacker news or whatever for a couple of hours.
The unknown
is,
this hasn't happened yet. I think it will someday
and it will be very interesting to see what the reaction ends up being.
Well, so I know some large organizations, for example, this is why they,
they have their own in house copies of these things that they basically download,
stabilize and the news because
partly because they just want something that works and is stable and boring.
But also because then they don't have to
have this external dependency that can be easily
modified in a malicious way. Right?
Well, in, in like I know for example, sun type does this as,
as kind of a business model as does a what is it J frog,
I think has something called artifact which very similar in in the same respect.
And
I think this is a discussion.
I'm I'm actually in the middle of with
some other people unrelated to this particular topic.
But the fact is
this is a problem when you're working with open source.
But literally everyone uses open source.
I mean, anyone who says he answers to quit using open source like, yeah,
you're in need.
All right, like that's, that's not an answer.
-- I
-- just cannot,
I would love to watch somebody try and write a modern browser or a modern
-- crypto implementation or do
-- anything, everything has,
it doesn't matter what it is
and, and just
anyone who doesn't realize that is, is out of touch.
I mean, that, that's the reality of it.
You, you're using open source, there's nothing you can do about it.
So, the question now becomes, how do we actually deal with this stuff? And
I, I don't know the answer today. I mean, there's various things that can be done.
None of them are very nice options.
I think a simple thing goes back to
and this is something generally speaking that people want anyways is,
is that sort of agile development
DEV
ops, you know, like just code agility in the sense of like, here's the reality
at some point, your code will have some horrible thing,
be it security or a denial of service or like whoops, we,
we put like a really rude word in the source code
and we need to fix it right now
and ship that fix out to everybody,
you know,
and, and like, there's, you know,
like there's all those infamous cases where like literally a whole
bunch of different people implemented a specification and they all did it
the wrong way, you know,
on a different.
-- So
-- my point is basically is that economically we,
we have to basically build systems where we can
quickly react to
things anyways. And
-- that basically solves this problem largely
-- sort of
what you describe I agree with for some other reasons, but not necessarily this one.
If you move slow and you're using an old version of, say a node package,
you're actually going to be ok when something gets pumped
-- because what's going to happen is
-- except for all the security flaws in the meantime,
that have been fixed in that package
there is that.
But the question becomes, how long do you think it's going to be from the time?
A bad guy backdoors a major package until it's actually noticed
by somebody and the word goes out.
Uh Well, there was that um
oh, was it on chrome
where the guys lost their uh chrome?
Uh what was it? What was it?
Yeah, someone hijacks a popular chrome extension, blah, blah,
blah Fishers have recently hacked an extension of Google Chrome after
compromising the Chrome web store account of German developer team,
a 99 software, blah, blah, blah,
dubbed Copy Fish, the extension blah, blah, blah,
blah.
And how long did it take before? Somebody figured that out?
I think it was on the order of a day or two.
And, and my suspicion is it will be less than a week but more than a day.
And yeah, here we go.
They got hacked on the 28th of July and they pushed out a new version on the 29th of July
and the new version on the 29th was the bad one.
Well, no, no, no, like they pushed.
Uh so the the bad guys pushed out a new version and then the,
the good guys pushed out a newer version to like,
you know, get rid of it
-- basically. Yeah.
-- And so
my suspicion is that's what you're going to see.
And so if you think about the, the greater ecosystem,
how many, how many projects are gonna do a release
that, that might fall on that, let's say,
let's say 10 or 20% which is still in the order of probably, you know,
millions or billions of projects.
But, but fundamentally, I think
what's going to happen is it's gonna be huge and people are gonna freak
out and there's gonna be tons of cycles that are spent on this.
But I bet you at the end of the day it's not a world ending problem.
And the hope I have is that it will incentivize people
to start cleaning up their act because I don't think anyone's going
to care or do anything about it until we see this happen.
So the second data point we have, remember the Handbrake for Mac Os Handbrake is um
uh let's see, like R DVD
S
-- they got
-- these guys. Was it Handbrake or was it
who, who got Neil by Handbrake? I remember this.
Well, anyways, they uh the Handbrake um
uh the server download dot Handbrake dot fr uh The file was replaced between
May 2nd and May 6th.
Uh They have a 5050 chance of their system being infected by a Trojan.
And um
yeah,
there was a mirror, right?
Yeah. And, and there, there are multiple instances of mirrors being attacked.
I mean, this happened, I think it happened a squirrel mail at one point as well.
I remember this.
Yeah, that rings a bell
and, and it happens, right? Like
mirrors have been, have been nailed.
Uh We've yet to see a source code management system get
nailed and somebody release like a legitimate back door like that.
But if I guess, I think something like the N PM ecosystem is probably a prime target,
-- especially now that some attacker somewhere
-- has
gems NP ma lot of these are, you know,
the reality is a lot of these have, you know,
like things where one or two devs have written stuff that is used really widely
and yeah, I mean, these guys may not have super awesome.
Well, there was that, what did that guy do? Um hang on a second N PM password audit.
There was a guy that or was it
github or something?
Anyways, this guy did like an audit of sort of all the N PM or something accounts
-- and found people using like 12345 six.
-- That doesn't surprise me even a little bit.
And, and in fact, I know I mentioned this more than once in the podcast, is github
changed it. So you can't look for private Rs A keys in github
anymore
because there's so many of them.
There,
here we go.
Yeah, it's uh
Gathering N PM credentials or how I obtained direct
publisher access to 14% of N PM packages.
-- What did that guy do? I remember this? But I don't recall. He
-- just basically um
he, how did he do it? Blah, blah, blah.
Uh There are 73,983 public packages from 17,088 accounts
about 14% of the whole N PM ecosystem. And that's a lot of packages.
It's huge
numbers, man.
So I believe you just tried
brute forcing.
Oh, he, yeah, like, wow, this is bad anyways, the the reality is like, you know,
given, well, here's the problem.
We're back into the law of large numbers,
right?
And so like it doesn't matter if we have 99.9% of these guys secure
if you have 100.
Well, no, wait, 14%. Yeah. So there's about like 100,000 accounts
that still leaves what 100 or so to be happy.
And here's,
here's the thing is we have a handful of
really good attacks that were done by good guys.
Mind you
against this ecosystem and nobody's really fixed anything.
Well, see, that's what drives me nuts is there's some really easy fixes for this,
like deploy two factor authentication ideally
-- because
-- what's going to happen is humanity doesn't change unless they have to.
Right?
See, well, and that's the thing, you can force it.
Like, look, you want your N PM thing published, uh you have six months to buy into the,
to go buy a UB key and start using it.
-- But
-- the N PM
and they obviously don't.
-- Yeah,
-- I mean,
well, and again, it comes back to that cost, right?
If we do start booting N PM packages like
shift, then oops, we just broke like a
suspicion is the N PM guys are probably overworked volunteers
for sure.
And so that, that becomes part of the challenge as well.
Is, is you want what you want, you want me to do more work.
And in fact, I see this all the time, right?
As a security guy is, I'll show up and say, hey, we should do this and they're like,
I'm too busy already.
I'm not doing that. It's like, right, it was fun talking to you all
someday. I'll be back. It won't be friendly
and, and yeah, then eventually they,
-- they get in trouble or something and then they come back in
-- and
here's, well, and this goes to, uh, mud,
you know, talking about, uh, having sort of automated software
safety stuff.
If we, for example, had, uh,
some sort of rating system on like how secure is this package?
You know, it could be things like
some of the metrics would be like, oh, you know, the,
the accounts associated with this use two factor authentication or they don't or,
you know, they,
they at least use source control management or they publish to multiple mirrors.
So if one gets hacked, it's gonna get noticed or, you know, things like that.
And if you could have this metric,
you know, published and then,
you know, it would be nice for me to be able to say, like, you know, look,
it's fine to use any software that has like a better than
50% security score and if it's less than 50% maybe notify me.
-- So I can take a
-- piece of ci I
badges project
is
exactly.
But, but even then it's, I don't, I haven't seen it really adopted widely yet
and, and we've already kind of got that infrastructure built in the form of CV S,
right?
If this package has CV S, they need to be dealt with. And so,
but here's the thing, what's the incentive, right?
-- If there's no incentive, nobody's going to do it, that's the reality.
-- I agree.
And, and we just, we do not have incentive for security in many instances. Not yet.
Well, we don't have incentives for really good security.
We have incentives for a lot of security theater because that gets
the managers and other people
to go away,
you know,
and people keep, you know, well, it's like with the whole TLS SSL thing,
the whole point,
you know, it's got a lock, you can plug your credit card number in safely.
I actually realized now, I,
I just so fundamentally don't care about my
credit card number being hacked because like,
it's just a non-event, like you just go get a new one.
-- Get stolen
-- so often. I don't, yeah, I don't care. Whatever. It doesn't even matter.
-- Like some dodgy website wants it. I'm like, don't care going
-- in.
It's like using hand sanitizer. You just, it's just
something, you know, it just happens.
No
-- big deal.
-- I hear you, man.
Um,
I care vaguely maybe about my personal information being
stolen from a website because I can't change that.
You know, even that I, I've had my identity stolen so many times at this point.
It's like anyone who wants it, it's not even hard to find.
It's just I give up, there's nothing I can do about it.
My credit's locked, that's the best I can do. I keep an eye on it. That's, that's it.
That, that's life, man.
Yeah. Well, and that's the thing, right? Like if
I
wish we could somehow sort of make some of
these hacking events basically into cheap non events.
Uh,
well, a lot of them are cheap non events though. I mean, let's face it.
My identity has been stolen. My credit card's been stolen.
How many dollars have I actually lost because of any of this? $0?
I've lost a couple of hours of my time. Yes. But like, fundamentally
I've lost relatively little
all
in all
and that
-- it's kind
-- of like the same thing with car crashes, right.
Like, I know locally now the cops will not go to a car accident unless there's,
you know, casualties.
Right. Otherwise they're like,
you phone the non
emergency number and they're like, dial six if you've, you know,
rear ended somebody dial seven if you ran a stop sign
and like, you literally just go fill out a report.
You have like, I think it's a day or two to go do it after the accident
-- and, and that's basically it. And then your insurance people
-- deal
with that,
man.
I mean,
well,
I think most jurisdictions in Canada are like that now because quite
frankly why would the cops come out to a car accident?
Everybody has smartphones, they take pictures of the thing,
you know,
unless like the other person is you think they're drunk or something you don't need,
like,
I don't need a cop out for some, you know, minor rear end
-- or whatever. I mean,
-- it's fair, man, I get it. It's,
I don't know, I, we've got growing up to do and I, I don't know how it's gonna end
but it's,
yeah,
I don't know.
I guess
I, I see no better place to end it than this because we have nothing to say. So,
do you, you want the last word?
Fundamentally, I want this to cost less money and hassle.
-- Uh
-- Yeah. Right. And, and that's, that's the intent, right?
Is someday we'll get there, but we're not there today today.
Doing nothing is easier than doing something. So nothing wins.
And that's just the way it's gonna be.
I
mean, well, and I think we really have to have like a really,
like a really massive cultural shift,
just like with cars right where they went from, like, denial and, you know,
like the smoking industry or the car industry or
all these other industries that have undergone massive shifts.
Security needs to do that because I'm pretty sure
that what we're doing right now isn't really awesome.
-- Like I'm pretty sure there's a much better answer out there
-- without a doubt.
I, I have no doubt
but yeah, I don't know, we're gonna find out,
right? Oh,
thanks, man.
-- It was fun. As always, I guess
-- tweet us the answer if you know
it.
Yes, please, by all means, let us know.
And on that note
you can find all the show notes as well as links to how to tweet us.
And we have a Facebook group you can hassle
us at or whatever at open source security podcast.com.
Uh Yeah, thanks, Kurt. Thanks everybody for listening. I certainly appreciate it.
And yeah. Have you guys have a, have a great day?
-- Enjoy the rest of summer
-- while it lasts.