Hello and welcome to the open source podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Extemporaneous podcasting.
-- Josh Bresser. We're
-- the open
source security pod.
You said the open
source podcast?
-- Oh,
-- whoops. I missed a word. Oh, you know what the stack?
My, my, I literally put a new word in the stack and it popped off an old one.
You filled your brain up and now one of the old words had to leave.
-- Which word was
-- that again?
The most important word of the name,
security, the open source Security podcast.
Sorry.
That's one of my favorite scenes from the ticket
is where the one guy gets electrocuted so much.
The other guy is like, you know, we're, we're worried about Dave because
he, he doesn't know about Tuesdays anymore.
Like he's, he's lost the concept of Tuesday.
She was like, oh, you'll be
fine.
-- Yeah,
-- that's, that feels like
-- right now.
-- Oh
my God. Yes.
Anyway,
I'm happy to say
our topic today is not log for Jay.
We might talk about it a little bit but fundamentally not log for Jay.
I'm very excited.
-- So, what are we talking about? Kurt?
-- Will there ever be
no security vulnerabilities.
The answer is no. Thanks for listening. Everyone.
-- Pretty
-- much. That's the show.
Unless you're willing to wait for the heat, death of the universe
-- anyway.
-- No, no.
II I, so there was a question posted to Reddit I found, oh,
it's been a couple of days I think.
And
the person asked it a legitimate and honest question of basically,
will we ever fix all the security vulnerabilities be it?
We have better technologies or whatever, right?
And I remember getting asked this 20 years ago when they were like, oh,
you're in security, what are you going to do when all the security bones were fixed?
And I was just like,
uh
I've never had that.
But anyway, it,
Kurt and I started chatting about it a little bit and I thought this is
a really good topic because I think there's kind of two pieces to it.
There's the, the part where you just
answer the question of why the answer is no.
And anyone in the industry says no laughs and then moves on.
But then also there's the question of how do you talk about this to a normal person?
Because I think this is actually a lot harder to answer than any of us think it is.
Well, and also to not to invoke the COVID pandemic.
But all the, all the research on messaging shows,
you can't just show people the bad news, you have to show them some hope or good news.
So the example
with COVID is like, here's what's going to happen with COVID rates
and if we mask
it will be X and better and if we mask and vaccinate, it will be even better.
And if we, you know what I mean?
Like here's a bunch of scenarios where the line doesn't
go shooting up into the right and things are better.
And I think that's part of the challenge here is like, ok, so you're saying
there will never be no security vulnerabilities? Cool.
So, like, thanks for the bad news. Moving along.
Yeah. Now what, like, yeah, exactly. Now what
and
-- why am I paying you? Yeah.
-- Right.
And so, but what, what good news or what hope can we offer them?
And the one thing I always come back to is like, look, I, as much as,
as bad as the security, like, for example, we had not
pia and that was by far one of the worst cyberattacks ever.
Like, it shut down entire companies, big companies like Maersk,
hold on, hold on.
Which, which one was that?
Not Petya
was the one where the Russian government infiltrated the Ukrainian
accounting firm and they wanted to basically target Ukrainian firms,
but it escaped outside of Ukraine and went Rawle
stomping through a bunch of unpatched networks.
Yeah, I would point out as bad as that stuff is,
like,
fundamentally the world is still chugging along working,
you know.
So it's it's like this log for G thing.
Everybody's like, oh, it's the end of the world.
It is the worst vulnerability in 20 years and it
is the worst vulnerability probably in 20 years and yet,
-- like, things are still here.
-- Christmas happened.
Yeah.
And so I think that's part of it is offering that, that, you know, uh,
like when they opened up Pandora's box, what, you know, what was the last thing that,
to come out of it?
Well, that didn't come out,
hope, didn't get out, hope was still in the box
-- anyway.
-- So
as, as quote
unquote, bad as things are it,
it's not the end of the world bad.
No, I, I agree. I agree. But, but that's not the point of the question.
The point of the question is,
will we ever have no security vulnerabilities
in
software?
But what I'm saying is that supposes that the question itself is correct and
useful and I'm not sure that the question is actually all that useful.
It doesn't matter. That's not the point.
The point is someone is going to ask the question and we have to answer it
and your rambling answer, but not p
you
isn't going to fly with normal people.
-- So,
-- well, my short answer is basically no,
there will always be security vulnerabilities
and that's ok because everything in life
has sort of these problems, you know, roads are never perfect.
The health care system is never, you know,
everybody's not healthy at any time in point.
-- And, and that's ok. You know, life goes on.
-- I think you're on the right path. But
I think the difference is
we understand roads, we understand you build a road and then
it's used by traffic
-- and there's free star cycles in certain places
-- and
put
salt on it and
it
makes everything better.
You know what I mean? And so we, we get that, we understand what that means.
But when we talk about security,
I think there's a lot of unknowns. I think it's an industry.
We've often not done a great job of explaining what's happening.
And I think to normal people they just think
-- why is, why can't you make it better? What is wrong with you?
-- Yeah.
Like, why can't you make a baby stroller that actually works or why can't you? Yeah.
No, I agree.
And
I, I think there's a number of things to consider. I think on, on one hand,
this is a very immature industry.
I mean, security really has only been a thing for what, like, kind of 20 years ish.
I mean, really?
Well, yeah, I mean, you look at the car companies, right?
And they weren't shamed into safety until the fifties and sixties.
Yeah, they exist
for almost 50 years before things actually started to get, like,
safer in that regard.
I mean,
you can almost view, uh, just technology in general.
I mean, think about the last 50 years of technology. I think
we've made enormous leaps and bounds and maybe it's time to start saying, ok,
we've made all this progress.
Maybe we need to start taking safety more seriously as part of these discussions,
which we're still not.
The problem is if a company starts to
take safety more seriously and slows down their future
sort of count and their future deployment,
a competitor won't
that competitor will eat their lunch.
And the market has shown consistently that
they, they will prize features over safety
outside of like three niche niche corner cases that basically don't matter.
That's right.
And I think you can,
the auto industry is a lovely parallel because I
think if you look at the auto industry,
this was completely true. If you would have said,
ok, I'm going to put seatbelts in my car,
but it's going to cost $1000 more because of all these seatbelts.
-- I'm putting in
-- it, not even $1000 more.
It's going to slow down the production of the car by a week.
Uh Sure, whatever you get, you get the idea though, right?
And the competitors like, no, I'm not doing that
and then
the consumer is going to show up.
And I mean, it's historically been proven time and time again
that price price drives consumers
-- in, in most situations
-- and safety behavior, right?
There's those us congressional hearings of people essentially saying, you know,
seatbelt mandates and laws are un American and the death of freedom as we know it.
That's right. That's right.
Like I,
I keep coming back to that seatbelt compliance chart of
numbers and it's nowhere near 100% in some cases.
It's like 40 or 50%.
That's right. That's right.
And now I think, let's frame this in another way. If we ask the question,
will we ever solve car accidents?
Uh, no, not collisions?
Ok. Whatever
the word matters.
Ok. Fine.
Let's say, will we ever solve collisions?
And I think even if we have computers driving our cars,
it isn't going to be zero,
we can make it a lot less, but it won't be zero.
Well,
but also cars now I love that people get in car accident
and complain about how much it costs to fix their car.
And I'm like, yeah, but you're fine. Right.
And they're like, yeah, I'm like dad,
exactly that $5000 bumper that ate all that impact
-- and you don't even have whiplash.
-- Right. Right. Exactly. And so I think this is,
this is a conversation about security and I think this
is how you can talk to normal people about it
is that
if you look at the industry,
we have a complete lack of regulation for the most
part and it's coming in some places I think,
and, and I also think we have to be careful because,
I mean, we talked to what the, the, the person from the R Street Institute.
Um, I don't remember her name now, but anyway, basically, like,
too much regulation is bad, too little regulation is bad.
-- And so it's really hard,
-- also bad, regulation is bad.
-- Right.
-- Exactly. Exactly. That
and,
and so while I always say, oh, I think regulation can help here,
I'm also very aware that there is,
you could make things much worse.
And so it was Catherine Walden.
And so a perfect example of this regulation making things worse. GDPR.
Like GDPR has objectively made the web worse with the cookie pop ups.
Is that GDPR though?
Yeah, the cookie stuff, the cookie warnings, I thought that was GDPR.
-- I don't know, but the cookies are stupid
-- anyway, the cookie stuff is garbage.
It's completely worth it.
And here's the thing, somebody pointed out to me,
all the massive companies like Facebook and linkedin, they
didn't care about GDPR. They were fine with it.
-- Well, yeah,
-- because they know how to get
around it.
Well, they have that, you know, automated systems in place.
And so the fact that
ostensibly what the companies that were supposed to
be targeted by GDPR are kind of like,
cool.
We don't, it doesn't scare us.
GDPR is not good regulation, in my opinion.
I mean,
it
primarily
raises the bar and punishes small and medium
sized firms with this just extremely expensive.
Like I know at the CS A it costs us well into the five figures to be GDPR. Compliance
and a lot of it is stuff we would have done anyway because like, Qantas,
we don't really want your data, but everyone knows this
and, and that's part of the problem though is, is
you're gonna get regulation.
Well, who's going to fund the lobbyists that will help craft it?
Well, the large companies, the companies with a vested interest in making sure
you want
to talk about regulation. I'm pulling us out of this hole. No more.
Talk of regulation.
The point is that
if we compare this all to the auto industry, right?
It is.
I think,
I think a lot of people can understand kind of what is going on where we are on the path.
We've made amazing progress with the technology.
And I think
a lot of security has been trying really hard,
like we're running as fast as we can in most cases and we still
can't quite keep up because I think everything is moving so very fast.
And even when security does keep up though, you have to deal with the users, you know,
that uh the thing with Google
deploying two factor authentication and forcing people into it.
And people are like, oh my God, no. And it's like, well,
you, you can't have it both ways.
Like if you want security, you can't rely on a user name and password. It just
like
the,
the what is it like eight or 12 or how many
of our billions of records and have I been pawned?
I think sort of would have put the password, argument to rest by now, but
-- apparently
-- not.
But, but again, this is normal people, normal people don't really care. I mean,
I think even today, if there was a car for $10,000 less expensive with no seatbelts,
I think people would buy it.
I really do
because most people would be like, hey, I've never been in an accident.
I'll probably be ok, except the one time you really need them.
You know,
it's,
well, even simpler.
Given a choice between,
would you like the product now or would you like the product
later with it being a bit more quote unquote safe or worse?
Would you be willing to give up features for safety and security?
And most people would not be willing to give up features
people.
But, but I think this is, so this is part of the problem is you pose this question
and everyone knows the correct answer is I would definitely pick the safe option.
I would definitely pick the more expensive option because it's safer. Right.
And I, I even want to say that in my head,
but
I think when, when the rubber meets the road
it's different and there's a lot of people
who don't understand any of this stuff either.
And you know what I mean?
And so I think that's, will we ever fix all the security vulnerabilities?
-- Obviously not
-- Well,
a really simple example of this is how
many people don't have carbon monoxide detectors.
It's more than zero.
And what's interesting is
when I, when I got my new furnace in AC and they did the virtual inspection remotely,
like using um,
some video app,
one of the things they checked was I had to have a carbon monoxide detector
that's required now and I, I for sure that didn't used to be required that,
that changed at some point in the last few years.
And so something as simple as a $20 carbon monoxide detector.
And yet how many people don't have one? I, I honestly don't know. I assume a lot.
Now, I will say when I got a bunch of
electrical work done in my house,
I had them install those magic smoke detectors that are like,
all connected and they all go off at the same time
and I had them put too many carbon
monoxide detectors in because the electricians were like,
oh, you don't need this many.
And I was like, yes, I do.
But again, like, we're talking a couple of 100 bucks. Right.
-- Which for
-- a lot of people is,
I
know
they don't have a couple 100 bucks
on fixing their car.
Yeah. Right. Right.
And, and
I,
I think that that is kind of the discussion and
that is where the whole security aspect comes in,
I think as well is
every organization on the planet has a limited budget?
Are you going to take your limited budget?
And are you going to spend it on security something
or are you going to add a feature that
will get you another sale that will increase your budget
well and worse. It's not just the money but the time, the time constraint,
you know, it's, it's not only does the safety feature take you time,
but that gives you your competitor time to push out that feature though.
Ok. Now let's change the conversation.
Let's say there's regulation that says you have to
add a reasonable amount of security to your products.
And let's say that starts happening.
Now, why aren't we, why are there still security vulnerabilities at that point?
So part of it is the industry is changing
and evolving so rapidly.
And I mean, fundamentally
the closest I could say it's like if the building
industry came up with new building materials every six months.
And I don't mean like a new type of brick, I mean, a fundamentally new substance.
You are correct.
But let's say we were still, let's say we freeze all the technology and and
we say no new technology,
no new technology, right? You don't have to worry about anything new.
We can spend all of our time fixing what we have.
We still couldn't get rid of all the security vulnerabilities.
I would say arguably that would be worse because then you
have this massive technical debt like as we've seen with say,
Rust and sea.
Let me put it this way. What, what do you think will,
what is more realistic taking all the sea
code and fixing the buffer overflows in it or rewriting that entire
-- pile of fire in rust in a memory safe language?
-- Rephrase this.
Let's say we have a computer language with no memory safety
issues with no temporary file issues with no escaping issues.
There would still be vulnerabilities
in the code humans. Right.
Well, and that's assuming also the specification and the, the, the,
the fundamental architectural ideas are correct.
Right.
That's well perfect. Like again,
all the hardware vulnerabilities in Intel many years
ago were because of all of that,
you know, in insanely cool Magic Intel did to make the CP us faster
and uh turns out there were security implications.
Right. Right.
Well, everyone knew this was always going to be possible.
We just figured you couldn't do it remotely so no one cared
and then they figured out how to do it over the network and we were all like, well,
crap,
roll hammer and whatnot.
So here is, here is the point to all of this I think
is
today,
human beings build software
and any time a human is involved,
they're going to make mistakes. It doesn't matter what it is.
This is true of building cars and building houses of cooking meals,
everything human beings make mistakes.
And so as long as human beings create software.
There are going to be security problems in the software
-- like that is basically the answer
-- at a minimum.
When you build a bridge,
you have the idea that it should carry this load without falling down.
We don't have that concept for most software.
-- What does not
-- falling down mean for software,
it doesn't matter. We don't care.
I, I think,
I, I think claiming the, the quality argument on software is a nonstarter
because
-- quality,
-- what I'm saying is we can't even define quality, let alone measure it.
How would you, I mean, I mean, that's what I'm saying, right? Like how,
how do you,
how do you define security
in software?
It does what it's supposed to do.
-- Well, that's what J and D I and log for J were doing.
-- I mean, in that particular case.
Yes. And, and again, though that comes back to humans, I think humans are
you, even if the humans aren't
building the software itself,
you're going to have a human architecting it somewhere
like humans are fundamentally the problem in this story.
Well,
and I think part of it is we need better
feedback loops so that when a problem is spotted,
is this
like a small one off problem or is this problem
an endemic systemic,
you know, is basically, is this piece of wood rot,
just a little piece of wood rot or do I have a leak in the roof?
-- And I need a new roof for my house.
-- You got to tear it apart to find out. Well, exactly.
That's one of the problems.
I mean, it,
I, I feel like we haven't answered this question.
I, I think this is so hard to answer
that we can't even do it and we keep going off
into these weird little nooks and crannies of the actual problem.
Perfect example. I found a mystery puddle of water in my basement the other day.
That's terrifying. I know.
I'm pretty sure I know what it is. It's, uh, related to the bathroom fan and whatnot.
But the point is,
does it matter in the sense of, do I need a house? That's perfect.
No, I have a house that has problems and as they kind of crop up we fix them,
well, every house has problems, you know, we had cracks in the foundation fixed
like
it's just what happens. Right. Stuff settles over 4050 years.
And so you ji I think it's some epoxy stuff gets jammed into the crack and well,
no more water leaks
and, and that's kind of how software is, is, it's ok to have these vulnerabilities
as long as we have some process for sort of dealing with them.
I mean, or, and you can choose to just to simply ignore them
that probably won't be so ideal long term. But
again,
how many, you know,
dry cleaners are there with a doss box running
their point of sale system still more than one.
Yeah, there are.
And in fairness they'd be much better off going to, like,
a square tablet and getting, you know, a whole bunch of new features and, like,
automatically emailing you when your dry cleaning is done.
Except that doesn't manage all the dry cleaning. I bet.
Well, you know what I'm saying? Right. There's, there's some probably real
anyways. The point is
infrastructure doesn't have to be perfect. Like,
as much as, ok,
I don't want bridges to fall down because generally people die when that happens.
Having potholes in the road is not the end of the world.
It's not ideal but it's not the end of the world.
I think it's expected
in my climate. Yes.
I think anyone anywhere recognizes roads will have potholes.
That's just how roads work.
But the problem is
in the security space,
what is a pothole and what is a gaping hole of, of lava?
Well, and more the point,
I think in the security space we treat everything like an airport runway and that it,
no, most things are not airport runways, they're just regular roads that, you know,
you can bounce around on a bit.
I mean, kind of, I, I don't, I don't think you're wrong.
It's,
but, but again, the question was,
will we ever fix all the security vulnerabilities?
And I think we're dancing around the answer because I think it's, it's really,
really hard to answer.
Well, like I said, I'm not sure. Well, it, I
think the answer is obviously no, based on the last 50 years
and we know that,
but
I also think that it's just, it's not that important.
Well,
I think what is important is, is I hate to use this term, but risk management.
-- I mean,
-- yes, that's exactly right. It's,
it's kind of like
how you inspect a bridge is different than how
you inspect the road in front of my house.
And it should be
because if the road in front of my house fails,
it doesn't really matter.
Right. What, what, what does that even mean? How would it fail? A big, big pothole?
Maybe
we had a big sinkhole in one intersection that's
-- taken forever to fix and
-- it's a cone in
it.
We're good enough for now
and, and in the su world, I, I think so part of this discussion now,
I think kind of brings us into,
we don't have a good way to even talk about a lot of these issues.
Like log for J is a great example. Right?
Where, what the fourth log for jcbe that just came out a little while ago.
The fourth one is like a complete trash CV E. It shouldn't have been a sign.
It's not a real problem,
but you end up in this situation where no one knows what's going on.
We're all just running around with hair on fire and it's really hard to communicate.
Like this doesn't matter, go, everyone go back to eating, you know,
turkey or whatever.
But, but we, we, we can't do that.
And so I think that's part of the
challenge is the only time people hear about security
is when it's on fire and it feels like it's on fire all the freaking time now.
Survivor bias. Right. And,
yeah. Yeah. I, I think part of this speaks to having better data
in that really one thing I keep coming back to is how big is this.
And I don't need a specific number.
I just want to know within two or three orders of magnitude.
Like for example,
how many remote code execution flaws do you think
there are in the Linux kernel right now?
You know, 1000 million a billion,
we'll never know.
But it's, it's not one.
Yeah, it's more than one, probably less than a trillion,
hopefully somewhere in the middle,
but more useful would be, you know, I,
I remember one of the colonel de saying basically
they wanted to get better cwe data on defining,
you know,
memory flaws because there were some old
memory kind of management patterns that are
dangerous, but he can't prove that they're dangerous and get people to fix them,
right.
You know,
he can't get people to spend the time and effort fixing
it because he can basically say like it's probably dangerous.
But, you know, if he had some actual data,
you know, if we fix this now,
it'll save us this much down the road of emergency response.
People would probably be
more willing to do. So,
maybe that one, that one's still pretty hard to push.
I think, I think prevention is, well, we all know it's better.
It's, it doesn't matter, the industry, it's always difficult for prevention.
-- I mean,
-- and that's
why I suspect long term the better option,
for example is to get all the drivers in the LS kernel rewritten and rust,
I mean. Sure. Right.
It's, it's the same way how we solve drunk driving and burning red lights
with self driving cars
that obey the law.
You know, I love that. Google.
Everybody's like, oh google cars keep getting rear ended.
They must not be safe and it's like, no,
because they actually report every accident.
Whereas humans are like,
-- you, you sort of just dinged me. No
-- biggie.
Oh man. When I owned a pickup truck and I didn't care what it looked like.
I got it every now and then I get rear ended by someone.
It's like, eh, I don't care, we're fine,
you know, like
it didn't, I didn't care. I didn't want their insurance to go up.
I don't want my insurance to go up. There was my, my truck was fine.
Their car was all messed up, but it's like, who cares? Like, not my problem.
It's always weird like that. It was always when I was sitting at like a stop sign
every time I've been rear ended at a red light or a stop sign or I got a yield sign.
I've never understood that. Well, I know it.
They're looking at their cell phones but
let's face it
anyway. Anyway.
Ok, we're,
I, I feel like we've come near an answer to this, but
I don't think we're, we're there yet.
And I think this is part of the problem with our industry is
I think if you asked
a, a civil engineer
to explain failure,
they would have no trouble doing it because
they have literally thousands of years of failure
that they can draw
well defined in the.
See, the problem is when software fails, it doesn't fall down.
It just like you restart the system.
-- I mean,
-- sometimes and, and we're also conditioned to say, turn it off,
turn it back on again.
I mean, this happens
all the time.
It works.
Yeah, it does.
And it's hilarious because my, my kids, actually, my, my daughter was,
I think it was, she wanted to use, we have an Oculus something or other VR headset.
I, it, it, the rift. I think it's a rift
anyway.
She says, oh, it's not working dad. I said, did you restart the computer?
No, go restart it and come back and talk to me if it doesn't work.
And then an hour later I'm like, did it work? She's like, oh, yeah, it worked fine,
you know, what I mean?
I mean,
you can't do that with a building.
You can't be like, oh, the building fell down, turn it off, turn it back on again.
Like, no, it fell down. That, that's all we're done now.
You know, I, I think that's a good point.
I, I think it changes the way we think of this, which makes
explaining this problem even harder,
which means when we talk about will we ever fix all security vulnerabilities?
We think of it in the context of turn it off and turn it back on again.
And it's, this is, this is a problem closer to buildings collapsing,
not to turn off the computer and make the VR headset work.
Yeah.
All right. I, I feel like
I feel like we've made progress.
I,
I was really excited about this one because I knew that we
were going to end in a strange place that I hadn't imagined.
And II, I think we're there.
I, I'm feeling better about this, this answer now a little bit.
I think,
I think here's how I want to think about this and here's what I want to add on is I
think the point of all this is if we think
about it in the context of let's say other engineering,
be it a mechanical engineer or a civil engineer
or even an electrical engineer to a degree,
you make a thing
and that thing has an expected lifespan, right? We don't have that in software.
So let's say I build a bridge, the bridge has an expected lifespan.
And what happens is during the life of it, it's going to be inspected for
problems because there could be an issue with how it was built.
And we know
we had a bridge that was repainted improperly and started rusting right away.
It's now been a court case for 15 years
-- and
-- so, but, but we, we know what to look for.
We don't know what to look for in software today.
I think that's something we have to start to figure out
and saying it's impossible is ridiculous. It's not impossible.
We just don't know how to do it yet. It's the problem.
So you had the ability to inspect things and as you inspect it,
you're, you recognize that there are expected wear and tear,
there is expected failures along the way, right?
Like bridges are gonna get potholes, bridge, you know. And so
you end up in this place that we know how to inspect this thing. We ha it has a life.
We know when it's co coming to the end of its life
and then something near the end of its life.
And now you have decisions, you can often repair
the original, which has a cost,
you can tear it down and build a new one which has
another cost or you could do nothing and suffer catastrophic failure.
Right?
And I think in the world of software we've often chosen,
do nothing and suffer catastrophic failure.
Well, I think in the world of software you often don't have any other choice.
I mean,
-- sometimes you don't.
-- Right.
Because, well, I, I, one thing I really feel for is all these government,
it systems that are legislated to behave a certain way
and replacing them and rewriting them may or
may not be possible based on the legislation.
I mean, some of it.
Yeah, like I know, for example, locally, the welfare uh it's not welfare,
but basically the welfare system uses a repurposed.
Uh I think it's an insurance program
that they basically over the last 20 or 30 years.
So hint you kind of know what software or like what operating system runs on now,
you know that they've basically beaten into shape.
But, and the problem is how do you extract all that
legal and regulatory
configuration and knowledge
to even define what the new system should do?
Sure. Sure. Now, now I think that is
a different problem.
What you're talking about there is that's building the James Webb space telescope,
-- right? That is a one off, but
-- it's a common case.
-- It's
-- a, it is not,
there's 50 states with 50 welfare systems. Yes.
And that is a problem in a different space.
I think you have everyone building their own thing.
Could they come together and build one? I mean, maybe, maybe not.
I don't know, but the point is
we're not just, we're not, I'm not talking, talking about one off software.
I'm talking about like things that scale, right?
You don't build one car and then redesign and build another one,
you build millions of the same car.
Speaking of scale, there can be a piece of software that, you know,
only essentially one copy of it exists but DNS
-- DNS server without that thing, the internet stops working well.
-- Right. Right.
And that, that all software happens at scale, right. I mean, fundamentally,
but I, I think that's another thing is we, we often fall into these traps of
talking about one off and talking about
mass market.
But
10% of the population uses that one off software.
It's not one off. If 10% uses a curt,
I'm talking about, see this is a problem like you don't even understand this is,
this is what makes it so hard.
Well, how are you defining one off? Because like literally that in
-- that insurance mangled program is one
-- off is the,
the welfare system used by one province or state
that's one off. They built it, they own it. There's nowhere else to go.
This is like at the James Love stays. Telescope has a problem.
NASA can't pick up the phone and ask for help.
There's no tech support for that telescope. Like it's, it, you are, it,
you have to solve the problem,
you know what I mean?
And so there's a difference between running Amazon web services
and running this Bespoke system that was written in 1978 in Cobalt.
Yeah.
And they're not comparable. And I think we have to be mindful of that
because one off silly things while that may be
a terrible decision made by someone long ago,
that is not the same thing as saying
we have this software run by millions of people
and it's insecure.
Why?
Yeah.
Anyway, and I feel like that was very ranty
-- but it, this is, this is so hard.
-- No, it's, it's a good point because
how do I put this? Simply we talk about the software industry
as a sort of single thing and it's, it's not at all homogeneous.
I mean,
you look at mobile apps versus apps written
50 years ago versus stuff written today versus log
for J versus
that insurance program versus
Windows 11. These,
the, the,
there, this is like talking about the animal kingdom and it's like, well, OK,
we've got everything from like
viruses to the blue whale and everything in between and they're all sort of the same.
Well, except
like, no, not really, like, there's some major, like, like things like tar
rates where it's like, oh, they, you know,
they play kind of by a different set of rules than zebras.
Right. Right. But, but
we don't even have a way to define the software industry very sensibly.
-- No, I agree. I agree. I think, I think that makes a
-- lot of sense.
Here's a simple question.
How do you define a software product versus something
that was written as consulting ware for one customer?
I mean,
and I don't even have an answer for that. I've done it.
No, I don't think there's a good answer today. I think that's part of the problem.
And I guess this is,
this is the difficulty of being in the industry that has to grow up.
That's what it really comes down to the security industry.
The time is now we have to grow up. And I think
this is where when I talk about like log for Jay right now,
if you think about it in the context of heartbleed happened, we were all like,
oh my goodness, we have to make sure this never happens again.
And then everyone got really excited for a little while and then it kind of
fizzled out, right?
And I think the reason is
we didn't have the tools or the know how to do anything after heartbeat,
right?
I think after log for Jay, we have a lot more tools and we have a lot more know how no,
it doesn't mean it isn't going to fizzle out or we're not going to screw this up.
But I think we are in a better place today
to make sure this doesn't happen again.
Then we were after, I think after heartbleed, there was no way we could fix it.
I think now we have a chance, we might not.
And if we don't, hopefully we'll be in a place when the next one happens,
that'll be it.
Well, and ironically part of it, assuming we have the tools and the willingness to,
to fix it,
it might become a self fulfilling prophecy in the sense of somebody starts looking,
finds a package that's, you know, used by 8% of everything in maven
and then goes digging around the source code and finds out,
you know, it's
whatever they,
they added this feature,
some
crazy, scary thing
and, and I can't help but wonder
essentially this will look worse because people, oh my God.
Now we're having a log for Jay every week
-- as people actually start to look for these and fix them. I, I,
-- I hope so.
I hope that happens
because that will also make us finally deal with this correctly.
Yeah,
I mean, you have no choice at that point.
-- Oh, no,
-- you have choices.
That's true.
There's one thing I've learned in life, it's that
you can point out to somebody that, you know,
like you need to stop smoking five packs a day and chugging a liter of vodka and
they might just keep doing it.
-- And
-- that sounds like a pretty good life to me right now.
Way better than,
you know, like it's
anyway.
All right. All right, I'm gonna, I'm gonna call this one. I think
I, I have a lot to think about and I'm pleased with this discussion and it always,
it brings a smile to my face
when I go into something, thinking we're going to talk about.
Like, I have my list of topics I want and I have my ideas and,
and it all got thrown away and I love it.
So.
All right. Well, thank,
thank you everyone for listening. Go to open social security podcast.com.
Head up the show note, Susie Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media.
Kurt, have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks
-- everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.