Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast. Holiday special. 2018.
I wanted you to call it the holiday spectacular car. Wait Christmas special.
We're gonna call it the Christmas special.
Oh, well, I don't think Christmas is all special.
Not anymore GDPR is gonna ruin it. Right.
Yeah, pretty much.
Oh, sweet. No.
So, anyway, the plan this year is, is in the past couple of years for Christmas,
we've done a silly show
and it's always been in the context of Santa Claus, hasn't it?
But anyway, this year,
basically what we did is we took GDPR and kind
of broke it down and decided we're going to talk about
how, and if GDPR is going to apply to Santa Claus because let's face it.
If there's anyone
that has more information on us than Google and Facebook, it's Santa Claus. Right.
I would agree.
I mean, it, it goes back to when I was a kid, right? Like,
not just me but my parents talk about it, you know.
-- That's right, man. You better behave or like Santa is watching,
-- right?
It's not going to bring you any stuff.
Uh Saint Nick. That's so confusing that, that's something.
Do you do Saint Nick in Canada? We do Saint Nick up here where I live.
My mother is German. So we did Saint Nick. Yes.
What is it like? December 5th or something?
Yeah, you put out your shoe, your clog and you leave out a carrot for his donkey.
Uh The Germans don't do slave pete. So it's a little bit less
terrible than, for example, maybe what
the Dutch,
the Dutch have. Saint Nick with slave Pete.
He's got
a,
he's basically got a slave. Right.
-- So, it's, yeah, it's,
-- uh, oh, well, he, I mean, he has an army of slaves,
I guess elves we call them.
But whatever. Anyway, whatever.
The, the man, I actually, you know what, I'll put a link in the show notes for this one.
There's
a
David Sedaris has a really funny bit.
He does where he kind of goes through a lot of the Santa mythos across Europe.
And of course, in his typical, humorous way, it's,
it's absolutely fantastic the way he picks on just some of the madness behind these,
these Santa myth.
Right. Right. Anyway, so on
with the
show
when you think about this stuff and I think that's where we're going to end up.
Let's not think too hard. All right.
If we think too hard we're going to ruin
what's already a show on extremely questionable ground.
Yeah. So, the GDPR.
Right. Right.
So, what I did and and this is actually something I'll,
I'll just put in as a side note is.
So I went through the GDPR.
It's got 99 articles and I thought about which ones of
these are worth talking about in the context of Santa Claus.
And
in all seriousness,
if you're in an organization that needs to care about this stump,
this was a really interesting thought exercise for me because I, it,
it made me frame things in a manner.
I've never done before and I've been through these terrible 99 articles in the
past and I didn't ever think of them the way I did this time.
So I guess just as a side note, if you need to do some sort of, I,
I guess
training or, or even
just, just
circling
up. Yeah. Right. Exactly. A thought exercise in GDPR.
Like a sand table exercise.
-- Yes.
-- There you go. There you go. Alright.
So, anyway, on with the show, I guess I've got,
uh, we'll start with articles one through 12.
I've noted those as boring details about GDPR. So we're just going to skip those.
Right.
Yeah,
pretty much.
And,
and we'll get to articles 13 and 14 is where we'll start and
these are basically the right to be told of what is collected.
And when, and so
we all know Santa has an extensive list that he apparently checks twice.
But the question is,
what is he collecting on us? And when is he getting it
and I, I have no idea.
So my understanding is at a minimum.
I mean, he would have to have your name and address
and whether you're naughty or nice.
Is that all he has? Actually, actually
in every Santa story I've ever seen,
he always knows details about the people he's speaking to.
So he clearly is collecting more than just if you're naughty or nice.
He's collecting information about your naughty and nice activities.
Well, it's funny, I was talking to somebody about this in terms of A I and for example,
can an A I come up with some sort of statement about a group of people,
for example, like, you know,
most of these people are women or most of these people are left handed or whatever
and then remember that but forget the data though it was fed to learn that
and be like GDPR and privacy compliant where you essentially say like, look,
we don't have the data,
we just have the the outcome or the results of the data
uh that's actually covered somewhere down lower if I recall correctly.
Yeah. Um but so in this case, clearly, that's not the case, right?
Because like you said, he knows details now that you Yeah,
yeah, you know, J Little Judy,
what about when you punched Little Billy in the face or whatever,
which now leads itself to the question?
Does Santa have a data protection officer?
Is it like the Elf on the shelf. Is it? I don't know,
I, I don't know of one.
I think the answer is we, we can't conclusively say yes or no
-- because additionally,
-- I guess you'd have to write to him. And
that is true. We could ask who their DPO is and,
and
I, I have not had any success getting Santa to acknowledge my GDPR request to date.
And maybe it's just because I live in North America. I'm not exactly sure.
That's a good point.
I would assume, based on, based on Santa's logistics expertise and chain,
I,
-- I would assume he's capable of having AD P
-- O.
You'd hope so.
Which actually because no offense if you can, if you can deliver globally
overnight,
-- then clearly you're, you're, you're not some like small town like two
-- bit
fair.
That's fair, which actually this kind of lends itself into article 15.
Now is there's
uh the right to be told how your data is being used
and it also kind of specifies, you know, how do we,
how do we ask for this and log a complaint?
Right? Which again, we, we have no idea.
I guess writing to Santa appears to be not working, maybe,
maybe we could go to the mall.
Well, no, no, no, he's, he's very explicit.
He uses the data to populate a naughty and nice list.
Uh
Yeah. OK.
I guess although, although he also knows what I want for Christmas,
which is an additional detail.
Right.
True.
And again, but that's explicit. He knows what you want for Christmas,
-- which I never freaking get.
-- And I'm hoping it's because you told him
uh maybe he's got some sort of, you know.
Yeah, the surveillance of the Elf on the shelf or something, collecting that data.
Stupid
-- Elf.
-- Actually, it's probably based on browser activity. I mean, I,
-- I'm
-- not
doing
anything.
I remember as a kid I'm
on
the.
Yeah. Yeah, just when I die, please delete my browser history.
Um,
but no, I remember as a kid going through catalogs looking at toys and, you know,
like the Sears catalog or Canadian tire catalog and
-- that kind of stuff.
-- The Canadian tire catalog. Does it have more than tires in it?
Yeah. They, they're like a quasi
department outdoor store
and
they basically sell a lot of useful stuff like toys,
outdoor camping gear. All your Christmas crap. Well, all the holiday,
you know?
Ok.
-- They even sell potato chips and candy
-- and tires. Do they sell tires?
Tell me they sell tires.
Yeah, that's actually where my winter tires because, well, I live, like,
across the street from a large Canadian tire.
So it's just easy to get my tires done.
-- Now, do they sell more than just tires at the shop or is it only tires
-- at the
everything? Yeah. No, it's all the auto parts. Like it's, it's the,
yeah,
they actually were the ones that did that where they
built a truck out of ice that actually works.
Um, it was an ad for, um, for a car battery, you know, that the,
the car battery works in cold weather.
So, well,
all right,
-- anyway, you live somewhere where
-- it gets,
it does get cold, but I've never
seen a truck built out of ice.
So, so there's that.
So I think Santa's sort of in the clear here because he's very explicit that you know,
he knows what you want for Christmas and he knows if you've been naughty or nice
-- and he knows the details.
-- Well, actually it's more complicated
because I should be able to ask him
these questions
and I don't have a way to do that. So we think we know it. He's
yeah, he doesn't reply,
right? For some reason
in
Canada,
he must be closer to the North Pole.
Yeah,
you just write to Santa postal code H zero H zero
-- H zero North Pole
-- and a reply comes back to you.
You should send him a GDPR request and see what happens.
-- I don't think Canada post is going to care for
-- that. This is important stuff.
Kurt, you need to do this because in America when we mail Santa,
we don't get replies usually,
right?
Unless someone replies,
right.
-- But anyway, anyway,
-- but wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, Santa,
he lives in like international waters.
Well, it doesn't matter
because actually this is,
this is also defined later on in the GDPR statutes or articles, I should say
where they basically say
-- we don't care where you are if you are in.
-- But he has no revenue.
That's actually a fair point because really the, the way this is enforced is,
is they're assuming
that nearly every company has some sort,
some sort of financial footprint in Europe.
And if you don't have any financial footprint in Europe
then
-- there's nothing they can do
-- to
-- you.
-- Yeah.
You know, he's like spacex,
his logistics chain
is like magic in the air. Like it's, you know, he doesn't have like,
spots at the airports in Europe or, or warehouses.
Yeah, you are right. He does however, use their airspace and
I wonder if they would go so far as to shoot him down
for, I'm gonna just go out
on a limb and say
the optics on that action would be, let's just say negative.
I think
that's a fair observation that,
that shooting down Santa Claus would be frowned upon
even if he is violating multiple international treaties.
Uh, a nightmare before Christmas they did that.
Uh That's right. They did. You're right.
They shot down Jack Skellington, although that wasn't actually Santa,
but they did think it was Santa.
So
we'll put it in the plausible camp, plausible
myth, plausible.
All right. So anyway, uh, right, to be forgotten and write to rectifications here.
So let's say
I'm on the naughty list and I don't think I should be, I guess first of all,
I need to send a submit a request.
Figure out I am on the naughty list and then I can say, oh, no, no.
Uh I didn't beat Kurt up at that party.
He slipped and fell and hit his head, for example, right
on your fist, right. Accidentally.
See,
I'm curious about this one because technically don't you
age out of the Santa system at 18,
do you? I don't know.
I'm
pretty
sure,
I don't know. The rules is, I mean, we could,
-- I
-- was
told
you were told that.
I think so. Well, it's, it's, that's, that's what I'm led to believe.
I, I have no idea that that's a good question.
Does he only collect data on Children and actually Children under 16 have special
rules as well versus Children over the age of 16 in the GDPR world?
So,
uh, Santa is only collecting data on Children. That's interesting.
Now, ah, ah, however, however,
having just watched multiple Santa Claus movies with my Children recently,
this is fresh in my mind.
Santa Claus consistently speaks to adults
and knows information about them, including, like,
what they maybe did or didn't get as Children or
in some cases what they did or didn't get,
you know, maybe in recent years suggesting he, he does not abandon adults.
Well, I'm not saying he abandons adults but he, he, he basically stops,
well,
-- he stops giving them presents or
-- maybe we're just all
on the naughty list automatically because we're terrible people,
-- which I, I won't argue with
-- most of.
Yeah, I was gonna say most adults I've met,
I was going to say with respect to article 16, the right to rectification.
All the,
all the situations I've seen with Santa
where he somehow had wrong information or something
he did correct it.
-- He does try to right his wrongs.
-- OK? Uh We could,
I'm trying to think of an example, but I, I think that's probably fair.
This isn't like dealing with the credit union or the, the Credit Reporting Bureau,
you know, where you have the right to correct your data.
But
good luck with that,
right?
You have to,
you have to write the the question or rather you have to
submit the request on the skin of a shaven yak and then
right. Right. Uh OK. OK.
Let's see.
Let's keep moving because we have,
we actually have quite a lot of these to get through.
So article 18 is basically the right to restriction of processing.
Uh This is essentially from what I read things like if
the data is wrong perhaps and they processed wrong data.
And, and that one, I won't lie to you.
That one was kind of less clear to me as to what it meant. But there's,
there's also in article 19 was interesting. So
this is where you obviously,
in most cases people are working or I should say people organizations
are working with other organizations and you're sharing data to a degree.
And for example, if, if you update data
based upon it being incorrect,
then you have to let other organizations that might have the bad data know, hey,
I've updated this
and you need to update your data too.
And so an instance I could think of here is when like one of Santa's helpers
maybe learn some new information about you being not naughty.
-- It would be his responsibility to let Santa know for example. So
-- I,
yeah,
and I would further say Santa does let us know by either we get presents or we don't.
-- That's our notification.
-- That's a crappy notification man.
That's like that's like saying the bank forgot to
tell you they're going to come foreclosing your house,
right?
Like that. Don't, don't do that. That's not, that's not cool.
No, I, I what the thing is, do they specify how notification happens?
Does it?
They are, I'm pretty sure they specified that you have to mail them something and
well, he's effectively not mailing you something,
but he's having a private courier in effect
it. I'm
pretty
-- sure and it's a non, no, I'm
-- gonna say that
-- I think legally
-- that no way, man, that,
that is not making it out
of the the there, there's like a group responsible for overseeing this.
They're not judges, they have a fancy name. I forget it off the top of my head.
But there's no way they're going to agree to that. No way. Right.
It's going to have to be like a proper
-- written notification.
-- Get
-- a card
-- with
-- your
-- gift.
-- There's a written card with your gift.
-- I never got cards. I had my name written.
I had my name written on a, on a box. Basically a wrap present for real.
You must have a fancy Santa up there in Canada.
All right. Well, we'll keep going. Keep going. Uh Let's see here.
We've got data portability is article 20
this needs to be in a machine readable format.
So I can essentially request my data and say, give it to me
-- and then I could theoretically bring it somewhere else.
-- Here's a thought.
So I have seen where parents have gotten whether or
not the kid is naughty or nice and told the child
under GDPR my understanding was that that essentially like
c
like the,
the legal guardian or legal parent or essentially whoever's acting in legal.
Uh I don't want to say control,
but essentially whoever's in legal control of that entity, if they're a child
would be the one that represents that child. Right? Sure.
And so I would say for this case, that's, that's no problem because
yeah,
adults regularly contact Santa to find out if the kid is on
the naughty or nice list and then they regularly tell their Children,
you know, oh, you're being naughty.
You're not going to get any presents for Christmas. It's not a machine.
It's a, well,
no, no, no, no, but the, the transaction with the parents
uh must be, I mean, I'm assuming they use email or text or something.
Uh
My reading of this was
no
where the, the data he has.
Although I wonder if data not stored in electronic format is subject to this as well.
That's
it is.
Hm,
I, I don't know the answer to that because like, like in every particular.
So wait, can you have a note from GDPR by basically being like, we don't even, we're,
we're so old fashioned, we don't even have it.
We don't even have punch cards. We just have like literally paper lists.
I feel like the answer to that is going to be no.
And I don't think they necessarily cover that situation.
In fact, now that you bring this up and I'm thinking about it, I don't recall
this sort of situation being explicitly covered, but at the same time, like,
nobody doesn't have electronic records.
Now, in, in every Santa movie I've seen, his list is written on paper.
It is, it is never or, or he knows it. It's in his head.
I, I've never seen Santa using a computer. I've just checked
Futurama.
He is a computer in Futurama.
-- Yes,
-- exactly.
So while, yeah,
while the drafters of the GDP are intended for it to be technology neutral,
the regulation only applies to two situations where processing
of personal data is conducted by quote automated means,
unquote.
And number two,
where processing of personal data is not conducted by automated means,
but the data forms part of a filing system or is intended for part of a filing system.
So clearly, Santa has a filing cabinet.
His list,
we've consisted, I've seen, no, I've seen
several movies where he has filing cabinets,
you know, and the, the files are organized alphabetically from A to Z.
Right. I mean, that's well known,
the Naughty and nice List. It's well known that it's alphabetically or
organized.
That's a filing system,
you know, I would have done it by date of birth. But what do I know?
So,
-- yeah. No, I would say that this definitely applies to him then.
-- Ok. Ok. That's fair.
I'm, I'm, I'm comfortable with that. I feel like that would be fair.
But at the same time
I would be extremely interested in knowing
of any organization not using electronic records.
Right. That would be madness.
Well, I mean, there's lots of organizations that use, you know,
paper and pen to put stuff down but
then hopefully it's getting into electronic records.
Like, oh, I don't know, the health industry.
Uh,
they, so actually I was,
I just went to the doctor and literally everything they do now is all on a computer.
They, they did not write anything down with a pen at all during my visit.
I know locally, like when the computer systems crash,
-- they go back to pen and paper because, well, you have to, uh,
-- that, that's fair.
I can understand that.
But again, it's going to probably make its way into electronics records.
So anyway, we got a lot to go. Let's keep going.
Uh, there is article 21 right to object.
This is obviously now, no,
this one was interesting because I know you've brought up in the past
on GDPR things like you can't ask your bank to forget about you.
And this covers that
you have a business reason
right
-- there is
-- if you have a clear business need to
know about this person
and, and there's even more uh it's,
it's covered somewhere else where things like they, they call it like,
0 23 has various restrictions like national security.
For example, you can't tell the police or, or whoever, you know, hey,
forget about me.
They're like, no,
definitely not.
Uh But 22 I thought was interesting.
This is the right not to be subjected to automated decision making
where obviously this, this actually goes back to your question about if the A I
decides a group of people is say men or women,
you can object to that and say, you know, you can't use my data for a purpose like this.
And now, now this begs the question,
does Santa have automated decision making for the Nadia?
Nice list or, or is this some sort of conscious effort
also
uh let's assume automated or non automated grading system.
-- Is it an arbitrary grading system or does he like grade on a
-- curve?
It's pretty arbitrary because I know some kids that should be on
the naughty list that got a whole lot of presents last year
and maybe he's grading on a curve.
So there's like a small group of kids at the tail end pulling it,
-- you know, the average up or
-- down.
And we all know that Santa prefers wealthy families to poor families, right?
In terms of delivering presents. So there's that also,
I suspect Santa's grading on a curve
because that would explain some of the disparity,
right?
Because there's kids that have objectively been just as terrible as other kids.
-- And that one is classified as naughty and one is classified as not right
-- now.
I would,
I would be willing to say that Futurama
Santa is using an automated decision making process,
right?
Unquestionably as he is a robot.
So by definition,
it's automated.
Well,
the Santa didn't do it. Remember he had a computer, the Naughty Nice
Ron or whatever it was called. We'll have to find a picture of it.
Yeah.
Knock, what is it?
Knock before you come in here,
I get Cinemax on this thing I think is what he yells at the end.
Yeah.
Oh man, that's such a good show. I need to re watch a
-- drama Christmas
-- episode. I'll have to add a link to what Cinemax was.
Right.
Uh You'll never know Children, you'll never know.
Uh OK. So, anyway, we talked about 23 some, some restrictions.
Uh article 25 talks about responsibilities of the controller.
So this is actually an interesting point to talk about.
There are, there's something called the controller,
-- you mean article 24 the responsibility
-- of?
Right. Right. Right.
This is part of this falls under what is known as chapter five in the GDPR.
There's a whole bunch of stuff here.
But anyway,
so the controller is the organization with the data and
then there's also a processor which is an organization that,
that the controller could use to process data. An example being,
you know,
let's say you send your billing off somewhere and they
do something with it and then send it back,
right?
You've got the controller holds the data,
the processor does something with the data and
generally would give it back to a controller.
Stupid question. But so I know Santa has
insourced manufacturing, he has LS for manufacturing
and in some movies, the elves have also I've seen them doing administrative work.
He would definitely be the controller and the processor unquestionably.
Right. Yeah. But I mean, well, no, no, no.
But I mean, is it purely just Santa or Santa and the elves? Is it an individual or
an, or an organization?
Uh I would say it is an organization
where you've got the equivalent of like Christmas Inc or something.
I don't know what it would be called.
What is Santa's legal entity name? That's a good question.
I believe it actually is Christmas Inc, that's, um,
-- there's a movie called
-- Incorporated. Yeah,
that's awesome.
But
where is he incorporated then? Is he incorporated in Europe? In the United States?
Is he incorporated?
I would assume he's flying a flag of
convenience because he's out in international waters.
So, probably Panama
maybe. I don't know. I don't know. I mean, can you, he could he incorporate?
Well, he'd have to have his own country and we don't consider it.
Nobody recognizes the North Pole as a country. So,
-- uh right.
-- It's a big chunk of ice.
That's true. There's no land is there?
No. That's right. It's all ice.
-- Not unless you count Greenland
-- or
their own countries
anyway.
So anyway, this is, this whole chapter revolves around
your data processors
and kind of protecting the data and,
and the controller and what that would mean and the rules around that.
And it's, it's quite frankly just a lot of
kind of boring stuff.
But the one I really like is article 32 and this is around protecting the data and
this is where we talk about things like
encryption and anonym organization and pseudo anonym organization,
which is the worst word in the word world to spell
and kind of. So here's a question is Santa protecting his data,
you know what I would say?
Yes,
because if he has a physical list that is not electronically accessible
and it's kept in a lock filing cabinet in a secure building.
I mean, you can't really ask for much more than that.
No computer hackers are getting in.
Uh,
I mean, that's, that's fair and that's reasonable and,
and protecting the data,
you don't necessarily have to encrypt it, it's a matter of,
depending upon your situation.
Are you keeping it safe in a reasonable manner? Right.
Whereas generally like if you're in the cloud, like, yeah,
encrypt that stuff because, you know, you don't really have control over it.
But
yeah, I, I think that's probably fair,
which then brings us to things like breach notification,
right? Which is kind of 33 and 34 talk about, you know, notifying
different groups. There's the supervisors
are basically like the countries that are in charge because every
-- country kind of has their own GDPR magic
-- supervisory authority thing.
Right. Right.
And then you also have to notify the person
who had their data breached and to my knowledge,
Santa has never had a data breach.
I'm, I'm trying to think of this and I can't think of an instance.
He,
I think he technically has because I have seen documentary movies where
people have broken in to look at the Naughty and Ice List
on
-- air.
-- Actually, that's a really good point.
And actually in Futurama,
the, the characters,
what they freeze Santa in ice and then they go to deliver presents
and so they basically have unfettered access to all of Santa's data.
So, ok, I, I think there may have been, although, although are those
movies and shows canon or are they viewed as fiction?
All of them are,
they're all
ok. Fair.
So that means Santa has unquestionably had data breaches. I'm
-- sure
-- the Spiderman movie just covered this one.
-- I didn't, I don't, I didn't see the Spiderman, the
-- Multiverse Spiderman.
-- Uh
-- I don't even know what you're talking about. I don't watch a lot of movies.
You'll have to forgive me.
-- Oh, no worries.
-- I didn't see it either.
-- I just saw an ad on it for youtube or an ad for it on youtube
-- anyway. Anyway.
So, ok, but here's the thing.
So we'll assume all of Santa's prior breaches have been pre GDPR.
So now we know post GDPR
that it is.
Now we're all going to get letters in the mail from Christmas Inc.
When
somebody breaks into Santa's layer, it's called a layer.
I'm calling it a layer when somebody breaks into
Santa's layer and gains access to the list.
Although at the same time, if someone's reading the list,
you only have to tell the people that were looked up, right?
You don't have to tell everybody
assuming he can prove who did or didn't look at certain parts of the list,
which
-- I don't know
-- every movie I've ever seen, they've been caught
reading it.
It's not like they, you know,
it's not mission impossible where they manage to get the knock list and get it clean.
Right.
Uh, that's, that's probably fair. That's fair. Anyway, we'll keep going.
Uh, let's see here. We've got,
uh, actually one thing interesting
that
I,
I had forgotten about article 36 where if you're doing high risk
processing where you kind of know the data is dangerous or,
you know, the data has been breached or something,
you actually need to gain consultation to say like I'm going to do this, you know,
help me do it right.
And I guess in Santa's case,
I don't know if he's ever had to process high risk data.
-- That's, that's a good question.
-- Uh
um I would say he does process high risk data because for example,
he knows your real name, right?
That's been firmly established.
Everybody knows that that's on the internet, whatever we have a podcast,
we're fine.
Well, no, no, no.
But I mean, I'm saying, for example,
if you're a spy in a foreign country living under assumed identity,
-- Santa knows where you live and what your real name is.
-- That's true.
He knows who the spies are. Oh man,
that's crazy.
He knows,
you know, like, and he also knows a lot of personal details,
like if you've been naughty or nice.
So like all the
anybody who makes a living killing other people,
he knows about this
witness protection programs, right? There's, there's countless
opportunities here for, for Santa to have extremely sensitive information.
Interesting. So that,
wow. Wow, that's wild.
Uh, now, now here's a question, let's say, uh, data is breached on, say,
someone in the witness protection program
who does he contact and how do you, do you, do you send it to their,
their persona and say, uh, someone accessed the naughty list. Wink, wink or,
I don't know,
assuming the timeline on breach notification is long enough and
you would just drop a note down your chimney,
I guess,
right?
Like just
when you're doing the rest of them, right? Like why, why do an extra delivery?
All right. So anyway, article Keep moving.
Article 37 38 39 talk about a data protection
officer and this is meant to be a person you
consult with when you have questions or you need to
start doing certain activities because you haven't had an incident
and,
and basically I sum this one up as uh they can't
be a bum and there are certain things they must do
and that seems fair. But the question being
uh we, we talked about this earlier, like Santa doesn't really have ad po
that we know of.
Yeah,
what we need to do
is create a new holiday character
called like George the DPO elf,
right? And, and he would be
the worst elf of them all. Nobody likes him.
So there we go. That could be our contribution to Christmas George, the DPO elf.
Right.
Anyway,
like the elf on the shelf, except he's the elf in the back room account.
That's the elf on the shelf. I hate that guy.
Anyway, anyway, we'll keep going.
So, uh, 4041 we're code of conduct, which is just be nice.
Right. Uh, actually I found articles 42 and 43 talk about certification,
but it's not mandatory.
It's encouraged you acquire certification, which I found kind of funny.
My assumption is they will change that someday.
And, and in that context again, uh is sent to GDPR compliant.
Probably not.
And it doesn't matter because he doesn't have to care.
Uh
Let's see, there was 44 and 50 talk about the transfer of data.
This is obviously a big deal for an organization because you might
need to move data somewhere else for a variety of reasons.
Be it? You sold it, you, you were sold yourself.
But in Santa's case, does he transfer data?
Now, now the question being like, do his helpers
have access to it? Like I'll say the mall, Santa,
does he acquire data
through?
Well, it wouldn't be a transfer though because you're not,
you're not permanently giving it away.
It would be potentially
a, a temporary
-- gift like
-- lending, it still counts as
transfer.
Ok. That's fair.
It's any movement of the data like it's because yeah, people quote
unquote rent lists of people for like
advertising purposes and that's a data transfer.
-- OK. That's fair. That's fair. Right. But
-- the data is,
the party B is now aware of the data.
They know the data, they,
it's been transferred into their brain or computer or whatever.
-- OK.
-- That's fair. That's fair. So anyway, we're going to keep going.
So we're running out of time here.
So there's articles 51 through 59 talk about supervisory authorities.
Again, this bring begs the question, where is Santa Incorporated,
-- which would kind of dictate some
-- of
it.
That would be some of it.
But I, I assume in this case, we would just take the pragmatic tact of, you know,
if somebody in Romania or somebody in Germany is affected, they,
they go to that country.
That's
true.
Actually, that's a fair point.
So I guess all of you country,
supervisory authorities were counting on you to crack down on Christmas inc
and, and their reign of terror.
Uh So anyway, again, it was kind of dry, not terribly exciting.
Uh article 60 to 62 talks about how the supervisory authorities need to cooper,
which I guess is fair, you know, spelling that out makes sense.
But again, I guess that kind of comes back to what you were saying,
where depending upon where the people are.
So maybe all of Europe could band together
to end Santa's reign of terror.
Uh
-- All of
-- Europe believes in Santa.
Yeah.
Although I would assume there's at least one person per country there must be so,
therefore, Santa exists in that country.
Right? I would hope so.
And, and the vast majority of the Santa Mythos is, you know,
solidly rooted in European culture
-- and, and
-- northern Europe,
the southern Europe. Not,
-- yeah,
-- they do.
-- But not to the degree, like I
-- thought even Greece had a similar character.
Yeah. But I mean, it's, it's more of a Scandinavian
northern European, like Germany
and
you need something happy in the winter,
right? Something to hope.
-- Hope, hope is all I have. It's snowing outside
-- because we don't have the sun.
That's right.
Oh, man. Actually the sun was out the other day and it burned my eyeballs off.
I thought I haven't seen this in so long. What is going on here? Yeah. I felt like,
I felt like when, like, in the movies, when that guy comes out of, like,
the prison he's been in for 100 years and he's like,
covering his eyes with his hand and, like, hunched over,
but that's totally what it looked like.
40 days in the hole.
That's right.
Uh, let's see here. We've got, the rest of this is pretty unexciting for the most part
and, and basically we've hit the, the meat of GDPR, the,
the rest of GDPR talks about things like punishments
which again, like the penalties now that,
that does beg the question because the penalty is heavily based on your revenue.
Does Santa have revenue? Right?
I don't know. So, where does he get his raw materials?
Well, yeah, exactly.
So,
does he have like an internal accounting system in Santa Box or does he actually just
transact business in us? Dollars like the rest of us
-- or does he use Santa coin?
-- It's easier to hide
Santa coin. If it's not, it should be. Right. It's a thing.
-- IC O
-- it's, it's, I'm Santa coin
is
a,
we should buy some Santa coin. We could, we could give it out as
I
bet it's very inexpensive right now. Coins
-- dot com.
-- Oh, no,
no, no. Santa coin is worth 40 cents roughly us per coin uh
-- coin.
-- What's the hashing algorithm? Does it say?
Uh let me just check dead coins
because I suspect
I feel like based on its volume and no, it's not listed on dead coins.
So it's technically alive but
like it's market cap
and um
oh that's a pretty flat line.
Whatever, man.
It's the decentralized future. It says
it has STC.
It uses S crypt which is a fair algorithm.
That's a shame because I still have my old Bitcoin gear in the basement.
It'd be nice if I could use that.
But the 24 hour volume basically hit like zero
good. We could probably mind a bunch of it and give it away as prizes.
This sounds great. Uh We should figure this out.
Uh
One Santa coin is 40 cents.
Uh That's only from the 15
volume is about 100 200 grand.
Uh, that's from like a year ago.
Yeah. Yeah, it's, it's alive barely
anyway. Anyway.
So, I
-- guess
-- here
we
established that Santa uses Cryptocurrency,
Cryptocurrency.
But
I
guess
that's
Cryptocurrency is currency as he can be fined.
Ok.
So the thing is, it talks about annual turnover. So,
depending on how they exactly define that.
I mean, because he's not selling this stuff,
he's just using money internally to pay his elves and pay his suppliers and
making money off,
I
assume
from him then,
I mean,
there's got to be some sort
-- and
-- sponsorship
licensing is likeness.
Uh Maybe
I
would be revenue
Coca
Cola,
Santa Claus
like this.
He licensed it to them.
Oh, man.
Ok. Maybe I'll, I'll, I'll go with this, I'll go with this. So we'll assume
-- he, you
-- think those he's not gonna cut of that sweet Mal Sound of money,
-- right.
-- That's right.
Every 10% of every mall Santa paycheck goes to Santa Claus right.
There you go.
Oh, man.
Anyway. So I guess in summary,
wait, do we,
do we have a summary like GDPR and Santa are probably grossly incompatible.
I don't see a way out of this or
I think GDPR and sound are entirely compatible and, but
it's kind of like I, I
here's how I view GDPR were Google and Facebook, terribly worried about it. No,
I suspect San is in the same boat as Facebook and
Google in that he can architect his way out of it,
either legally, financially technologically or otherwise.
So, you know, it's business as usual for him.
Uh,
you know what I think you're right, because since GDPR has become a thing,
I have seen no difference in the activities of Santa,
I'm, I'm willing to say that which is
clearly not that
he's, well, I'm still not getting anything. Right. It's my
browser history insurance. I'm never going on the nice list again.
But
right. So, no, I, yeah, I guess you're probably absolutely correct.
Is Santa doesn't care,
partially because he doesn't have to and partially because he's
just going to game the system to his advantage.
Now,
does that put Santa on the naughty list or,
or the Santa think the people who made GDPR belong in the naughty list?
I
think a bit of both.
I, I think Santa is nuanced enough to know. I, I,
to me GDPR is well intentioned but the execution and
especially like that Romanian journalist Kerfuffle currently going on.
Clearly,
there's some shenanigans going on here, some naughtiness
and the fact that Facebook isn't worried kind of really puts me on the whole,
I think GDPR was well intentioned.
But clearly if Facebook and Google aren't that worried, then it
really didn't accomplish what it was meant to.
-- Uh
-- That's fair. OK. So I guess
for now,
good, good luck, Santa keep up the good work, I guess. Um
Let, let me know how I can get back on the, on the good list.
I should, may maybe I wonder, I wonder,
could I send him
a GDPR request, demanding to know how to be put on the good list?
I wonder I should, I should try that.
Although I'll send you the letter because apparently Canadian Santa replies. So
maybe now, now, can I, I wonder if I can write Canadian Santa as a US citizen and have,
have him reply to me?
Interesting. I should try this.
Uh
Right. Anyway,
well, that was fun.
If you're still with us,
have a Merry Christmas and a happy holidays with whatever it is you.
That's right, happy whatever. And thank you for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com, hit up some show notes,
you can just pound Os S podcast hashtag to ask
us ridiculous questions or wonder where it all went wrong.
And yeah, I mean, Merry Christmas, Kurt have a great one, man. You too.
-- Happy New Year,
-- everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.