Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner Statistical Crime.
Josh Bresser
Statistical Crime. What is statistical crime even?
-- Well,
-- that's that, see,
that's the thing is we don't measure stuff enough or even really try it all.
So we don't know.
Ok.
-- Is that like future crime where I'm statistically proving sort
-- of, I mean,
it's funny because I now look at the Edmonton, you know,
the police service has their GIS data, like with, you know,
crime reports and the funny thing is they won't,
they don't make it easy to kind of scrape the site and get like,
sort of day by day things.
You can only kind of get it in chunks going back a certain amount of time
because I was trying to see if there's any
seasonality or whatever because in my neighborhood it's,
there's basically a two or three sort of assault and batteries at home,
like domestic disturbance type things.
Basically in the neighborhood
there's about a half a dozen car break ins or car thefts and usually, you know,
one or two burglaries like break ins to,
it sounds like garages reading between the lines
and it seems to be a remarkably stable amount.
Like I've checked over, you know, off,
off and on for the last few years and it's just
remarkably stable and other parts of the city I've checked seem to
be the same and it's just what interests me is when
you get to a certain scale things kind of flatten out.
Right. You get those trends in those patterns,
leads us directly into the discussion with the University of Minnesota.
I don't know that I want to call it research.
I don't think it meets the bar for research. To be honest, it was that bad.
It's research, it's just unethical. Terrible, ridiculous.
That's like saying kicking puppies is research.
It could be, I mean, I'm not telling anyone to do it,
but
-- I mean,
-- but I'm not sure it's research in the sense of what they actually,
even if they'd accomplished what they wanted to,
would they have gotten any actual useful data that could be analyzed?
Let's start at the beginning because there's a lot to unpack in this one.
So, well, some bright spark, you know what? We're not going to use their names.
They don't get to have names.
-- No,
-- no, we're not going to name people because I don't want to give them credit.
-- Nor do I want to draw more attention than they're already getting.
-- Yeah. So,
-- well, and also they might be under investigation for violating the C
-- FA.
That's true. It may be a criminal offense.
But, you know, and also the ethics board, no doubt is having a look into their stuff.
We'll get to that. Well, let's ignore all that for a moment.
So some bright spark had the idea.
Oh, open source takes code patches from people. Do they really vet these people?
Well, no, because,
like I, I've actually, I don't know that I've never seen Josh's ID.
-- You've never seen my ID
-- to the best of my knowledge. This is true.
I could be Michael Bertos
or something. I don't know. The idea was they were going to submit
malicious code patches to the long Colonel and see if they got in or not.
-- Not
-- just that the really important part here is
that they're submitting patches under the University of Minnesota
email address, which is you what? Umn.edu,
which, and,
and I think that is a really important part of this story
is when you see communications from what is functionally a trusted source,
right?
Something like a well known university, a well known company.
Like if the Linux kernel gets a patch from Red hat.com,
right?
That's different than a patch from like ZQ nine v.com or you know what I mean,
a completely unknown domain
-- or somebody at gmail.com.
-- So I think that's a super
-- important part of this story
-- to say they
handle it poorly would be an understatement.
-- Well, hold on, hold
-- on. They submit a bad patch. Why?
-- What is their purported purpose to this behavior.
-- What they have said
and the way they executed it is terrible.
But what they basically said was that we're going to submit
these patches and see if they get accepted or not.
And then kind of make sure they don't actually
get into the tree or into production or whatever.
And so
they basically deceived the community intentionally and they did get a bad patch in
which we're going to have a whole discussion about code quality in a moment.
Yes.
-- Essentially we know that this is possible.
-- OK.
Essentially what they did is they conducted a human based experiment
against the Linux kernel community without their knowledge or permission.
-- That is what happened.
-- Yeah.
-- And without appropriate safeguards
-- and they claim they didn't do this
on purpose or they claim they weren't doing human experimentation.
But here's my favorite part.
This is literally a quote from the people who did this first.
They said we checked with our, what do they call IB board?
What is it IRB.
OK.
After they'd done it, then they checked and the board said, oh,
I guess you didn't do a human experiment, but I'm going to read this word for word.
OK? Because it's too good. While our goal was to improve the security of Linux,
we now understand that it was hurtful to the
community to make it a subject of our research.
Like they admitted in the quote,
they made the community the subject of the research.
And it's like,
-- I don't even know what to say about this. This is just like, so
-- dumb.
We're going to ignore the whole because I don't
think these people are smart enough to be,
you know,
under a foreign direction and trying to insert back doors in the
limits kernel and this is their cover story if they get caught.
-- No way. Like,
-- no, that is a possibility. I
mean,
-- no, let's not, that's not a discussion
-- point,
but it's stupid and pointless because it doesn't matter because
any state level guy that wants to get patches in the
kernel is going to pay some hacker
-- to do it
-- right now. According to what these
have said,
none of the patches actually made it into the kernel because they came clean
when their patch was accepted. But before it was committed, right?
Which is obviously the way the Linux kernel workflow works is you send a patch,
someone vets the patch, someone signs off on the patch,
then the patch gets included into
and then eventually it will make it from the tree it was included into,
into the stable kernel tree.
And I don't know exactly where any of
these patches landed because like quite frankly,
we don't even know what the patches were at this point.
I thought had the link from, from the research I have done
at this point in time,
we do not know the commit hashes.
So of those 190 patches, we haven't determined, which was the malicious one yet.
That is my, that is my knowledge.
Again,
I hesitate to call this research because apparently their institutional
review board didn't vet it until after the fact.
And the methodology is weak.
-- There's like a data point, a single
-- digit is my understanding.
Well, and the thing is this isn't like a Black Swan thing. Where is this possible? Or?
That's not the question if, if it was a question of like, can we put a man on the moon?
And the answer of putting one man on the moon is well, yes, yes, we can do it.
But right. That's good enough, you know. Sure can I?
Yeah, perfect example. Can I factor this prime number in non polynomial time?
You only have to do it once?
Maybe you got lucky, maybe you didn't, I don't know,
but once would be enough to be like, whoa, that's a, that's an important result.
This is not an important result because here's the reality how
many programmers write code with security flaws that they then go?
Oh, whoops. I just, I just wrote a security flaw. I better fix that
them. No, no, no.
Here's where we need to start thinking about
numbers and measuring things because statistically this matters.
So OK, we've got number one.
How many security flaws do programmers themselves catch? Oh, it's small for sure.
And we don't necessarily know because nobody really measures it and
it is going to vary hugely from person to person.
Ok. So number two,
they write a code patch or a new code or whatever, one or more people review it.
-- How many of those reviews catch a security
-- flaw?
It's not zero, but we don't know the number at all.
Exactly, because we really measure it that well, we could in theory say, you know,
we look at the known security flaws that obviously made a pass code review and go, ok,
there's a data set.
Do they have anything in common and of interest? And? Well, that's what De
Bricht is doing with machine learning, right?
So we've got the second data set of the signed off problem, right?
How many false positives? How many false negatives, how many
true positives and true negatives were there in that signed off code?
And the answer is we have no idea because nobody really measures it. Ok.
So the code gets written,
it passes review of one or more people and it gets into a
code tree and does it get noticed at that point by anybody?
-- Probably not. Well, it needs
-- what?
Remember too, these were purposely, what is the term they called them? Not bogus.
Oh, I forget what they call it.
Let me look, the hypocrite commits, hypocrite commits. Thank you.
Like they were purposely created to deceive, right?
There's a difference between accidental and purposeful, right?
I mean, if you want to see the extreme example of that.
Go, go look at the Obfuscated C coding contest results.
Oh, my goodness. Yes. Yeah, like it's just
I, no,
anyways,
so here's what would have actually been a very interesting and useful research
project would have been to maybe talk to code developers and say,
look, you know,
can you fill out this form every time you kind of spot
a security flaw on your own and fix it on your own.
And also though we need to kind of get an idea
of how much you're working on because there's a big difference
between a person who works on one small thing and finds
a flaw in it once like one out of one versus,
you know, somebody who's doing 1000 patch,
11 out of 1000. Secondly, if they could have people do
doing the code reviews kind of log what they found.
Like I reviewed this code, it was good.
I reviewed this code. I thought I had a security flaw.
It turns out it didn't because I misunderstood X one thing in reading.
So with the code reverts and the B reverts or D reverts, whatever we're calling it. A
lot of this code obviously wasn't well reviewed because,
you know, they're coming up with like
this code chain is code change is just,
it doesn't do anything useful or it actually potentially causes a problem or
my favorite is where they're like this code patch makes no sense because,
and then they give out the specific technical reason of like we do a free beforehand.
So there's no possibility of an allocation error, blah, blah, blah, blah blah.
Well, OK, so that's the second part of the story though is so there's,
there's a couple of things that happen.
So this research paper comes out
and then Greg Kh gets incredibly angry and basically
just wholesale yanks all University of Minnesota patches.
Well, that's the same thing to do, right.
Hey, Josh, I put poison in one of your beverages in your fridge. Right.
-- Oh, absolutely. Yeah,
-- you're cleaning your fridge out.
Exactly. Exactly. 100%. I,
but I think his behavior is spot on and the exact right thing to do.
Then what happens is there's apparently like a second
research project being done by these people where they
claim they're running a static code analyzer on the
Linux kernel and some of the patches that are submitted
are
from their system and they don't, they didn't tell anyone they came from the system.
And a bunch of those are the ones that the Linux
kernel people reviewed were like this patch literally does nothing.
Why is this here?
And they're like, oh,
our automated static analyzers spit this out and they're like, why?
And of course, there's no answer and there probably never will be.
But it, it begs the question.
Is this just some bizarre continuation of
the first ridiculous project I don't know,
we don't know.
-- Yeah.
-- Well, and again, that's a great cover story.
You know, it goes back to the classic,
I didn't make a bad decision or do something evil.
The computer said so,
and it's funny that FTC and other organizations are now saying, you know, look,
if you're going to use a IML, it can't be discriminatory.
It has to be fair.
It has to, you know, because we accept that with some of these expert systems.
A IML, we, we can't actually know why it said that. Why is this picture? A,
you know, it just is according to the system,
if they'd actually done some gathering of statistical data,
that would have been useful because part of it is
to kind of vary hugely from person to person,
but we can start to get hopefully a bell curve right?
Like part of me hopes this fits a bell
curve because otherwise just that reality doesn't work anymore.
-- And I can't deal with it.
-- Have you paid attention to the last year and a half?
Reality doesn't work anymore
anyways?
No, it's, it's actually that's a great example of a bell curve.
It's just, it's a bit more to the left or the right than we thought it was
right with. Could you just wash your hands and wear a mask, please? No. Well,
wait a second. What do you mean? No, like what? We're just
just when you're
never mind anyway. Anyway,
done some good research that would have been incredibly
useful and more to the point part of this
is you're going to design a methodology and you're
not going to know if it works or not.
And you can improve that methodology though, once you have one right,
like once you have
AC ID pipeline, you can start fixing it.
For example, they could have done something incredibly useful,
like come up with a methodology for
essentially helping maybe them, you know, which,
which pieces of code and which types of
changes actually need real code review versus like,
yeah, whatever it looks like it won't catch fire.
Sign off. Yes.
And I love that it reveals quote unquote, air quotes problems like, oh, you know,
there's a fire hose of reviews and commits and
so people aren't giving it their full attention.
-- Well, yeah, because nobody has that much attention to spend
-- well and not just that,
not just that the University of Minnesota is an organization I would expect to have,
we'll say slightly above average quality
because you're dealing with an institution that
will say I would expect to have more rigor in what they're doing than,
-- you know, Kurt's bait shop and ice cream parlor.
-- Yeah. Ok. Ok.
Yeah.
-- When you're comparing them and stuff like that
-- right now,
now here's the other awesome part about that is there.
And I'm going to,
I've got a couple stories I'll put in the show notes is the Linux Foundation
sent a letter to the University of Minnesota
-- with some demands in it and we
-- haven't seen
though we
did
it.
-- Oh, sorry. Yeah,
-- there was a story on ZDNET SJVN published it, which is
awesome.
But anyway, the one thing that I think is most important about this is basically,
I think it was Greg Kh demanded this was they want
a list of every commit to every open source project ever.
That was,
this sort of
-- search may have been conducted against where it was known. That's
-- completely fair.
-- I
-- agree completely. But at the same time, it's like, did they do this somewhere else?
Does anyone know if they did this somewhere else? Like who's running this research?
Who's, you know what I mean? This is just holy cow.
It's clear at this point that the researchers were lacked oversight. Let's say,
-- I
-- think,
-- I think that would be a kind way to put it.
-- That's a reasonable statement.
Did they do this to somebody else like openssl or the no Js system that runs
the web nowadays?
And again,
like we know this is possible because here's the reality of it because we have a big
pile of known security flaws that created by
well intentioned people trying not to do this.
My favorite example of this of all time is the
open ssh flaw where you could reveal private key information
because they left a bunch of dead code in there
for years and years and years that was garbage code.
Nobody maintained it. One of the first precepts of all like secure programming is
get rid of stuff you don't need or use
because it's only going to cause problems.
That's
-- easy to say. But
-- I agree. It is easy to say. I just said it
and yet people, I mean, and if the open SSH people can make this mistake,
then everybody can.
Yeah, absolutely. 100%.
And so we know that you can get malicious code into software projects that again,
this isn't like, can this be done?
You know, if this had never been done before? The movie, the invention of lying.
If they invented lying, that would have been good research.
But we know that lying is possible,
right?
Uh So it just makes me angry because the cost in
wasted time and effort and maybe trying to prove a negative.
Like what other projects did you mess around with and break
is horrendous? And I just, yeah,
I mean,
so let me, let me ask you a question then let's let's change it a little bit.
Is, do you think that the Linux
Colonel banning all
past and future submissions from the University of Minnesota?
Is that an appropriate punishment for what has happened?
Well, they didn't ban all the past ones.
They reverted them with a like this needs to be shown to be good to be put back in.
-- OK, whatever, but you like going
-- forward and going forwards,
I'm ok with them being banned until they get their, uh,
I can't say that until they get their stuff
together and stop behaving like also a word.
I can't say stop behaving like jerks.
You know, I could just add beeps to those non naughty words. They make them sound bad.
They've proven, you know, that they've come clean and for example,
they're not going to be doing this type of research again in future or
I
have a strong suspicion, they will never do this sort of research again.
But
is that because they got caught and smacked or because the Minnesota IRB
and everything will actually ensure that this kind of thing doesn't happen again.
-- No, it's because they
-- got caught unquestionably if they didn't get caught,
I don't think it would have mattered.
I don't think anybody would have changed behavior.
And, and I think this is,
this is why this is hugely important is because we're entering this place in
security where I think a lot of research is starting to pay more attention.
We're going to see, we'll say misguided
hypotheses
from some of these places. Like that's what this certainly is.
-- And I think, well, it's
-- also easy research to do.
It's not hard compared to building an ML or a I model,
-- like writing a malicious code commit and inserting
-- it or building a giant, you know,
particle accelerator.
You know what I mean? Like? But anyway, I think
that
setting the bar for like
if you are going to do security research of this nature, you do not mess with people.
The bar has been set and I think set high
-- and I think it should stay high or
-- you explicitly
get their permission or even better yet you do it
in a way that doesn't abuse or cause these problems.
Right. That's true. Because you could easily be like here are 700 commits.
Would you like $20 to review a portion of these commits
and tell us if you think they're malicious or not,
you know what I mean?
My thought would be you get people who write in the same language but maybe, yeah,
a different project.
And that's actually one of the issues here is that
it's people think review
code commit means you read the code and say yes or no
and it's no, you have to understand the system that,
that code plugs into and to understand that
is nontrivial because how many people have,
you know,
tried to track down a bug and it's taken
forever to actually understand what the code really does.
I just trivially, for example,
I had a problem getting some software running and I
finally got all the java and gradel and whatnot,
dependencies sorted out which Josh is well aware of.
And now it comes down to by default, it fails because of lack of code signing.
It's like, OK, thank, thank goodness because like, now I know what the problem is.
I just have to,
-- I just have to set up code signing. That's easy. Yeah,
-- that's super easy.
Right.
-- It'll
-- be fun, you know, prior to that,
I, I was just getting these horrific, great old and Java errors where it's just like,
no, like, basically the system just looked at me and went.
-- No,
-- and look,
here's something a lot of people don't always
understand is the Linux kernel is written in C
but it's not C like we're used to when we think of writing code and C
you have, for example, the C library behind you, right?
Where you have like a print F statement, you have string copies and things like that.
The Linux kernel has some of that because they've implemented it.
But fundamentally speaking, the Linux kernel isn't C,
the way we think of C it's a special Linux language almost,
-- it doesn't have access to the ecosystem that a typical C program would have,
-- right?
Because it's a kernel. And so that makes it even more different. OK?
So I know C pretty well, I haven't used it in a while but I know it well enough.
If someone said, could you review this C code for me?
I would feel comfortable saying yes,
I would be happy to look at it if you handed me Linux kernel code and we're like,
can you review this?
I'd look at it and be like I have no idea what's happening here.
There's nothing I can do.
And I mean,
that's part of the challenge is you can't just pull a Rando off the street and say, oh,
can you review this Linux kernel code because they're going to look at it and be like,
I have no idea what's going on here.
Right.
-- Even if they know
-- c the number of people that have successfully implemented,
even like a toy operating system on their own is
vanishingly small. It used to be reasonably normal like it.
-- No, I mean, implementing your own, like micro.
-- Yeah, on an eight bit computer.
Yeah.
Well, and that's where I was about to go, but it was, I hate to say this.
-- It was in a much simpler time. Right?
-- You had 12 instructions.
Well, you didn't have to write an IPV six implementation because it didn't exist.
-- Exactly.
-- It's just,
it's a different problem.
Here's my biggest concern is that a bunch of researchers
see this and think that they can make a name for
themselves by kind of proving like this is basically me
proving that you can throw a brick through Josh's window.
We don't need to actually do it to know that it's possible.
So here's the thing I would have agreed with,
you had the Linux kernel not come down so hard on the university.
And I think because they came down so hard,
anyone at any sort of accredited institution is going to look at and be like,
I need to be really careful and it wouldn't shock
me if there's someone doing similar research right now.
That's like, oh, crap. Because
I feel like the bar has been set now it's up to these researchers
to pick their sides.
But again, if we had researchers going and throwing bricks at windows and saying,
oh ha ha, this window broke that nobody would condone that.
-- Right.
-- I agree completely. But, but here's the thing, right?
Any time you're talking about magic internet, anything, it's not a seen in that way.
Like if I break a window, there's obvious cost to that.
But if I send a bad commit to a project while there is a cost to that,
I think it is less understandable by most people.
Yeah, I mean, it's one of those classic things.
Oh, you know,
we had to spend an extra five hours massaging this spreadsheet to do blah, blah,
blah.
Right. Nobody cares.
-- Whereas a broken window, except
-- in this case, we,
we had some of the probably smartest Linux engineers on the planet obsessing
over a bunch of commits from a university for probably several days.
Right.
I bet, I bet this has an actual cost of several million dollars associated with it.
Well,
this has actually pushed back Linux kernel development
-- a couple of days easily
-- without question yet.
-- That's we've just lost one or 2% of this year's productivity,
-- which
that also begs the question will there
be any legal repercussions for this behavior?
-- Which I'm not a lawyer? I don't understand.
-- Do you mean civil or criminal either?
I mean, you know, I think from a civil perspective,
I feel like the Linux kernel, if they were to go after them could win,
I feel like more interestingly enough,
there are potential charges from a criminal, like the C FAA has specific,
has a specific statute.
I think it's number five where it talks about
getting code into systems that you're not supposed to.
I mean, I don't, again, I don't, I would not be shocked but I don't know,
they wrote a confession.
-- That's true.
-- It's, their behavior is well documented here.
This isn't a case of maybe, maybe not. What were the intentions?
It's like they wrote and sent an email saying it was our intention to
do Xy and Z I suspect there will not be criminal or civil charges.
However, I hope the IRB comes down on them.
And also at first I was like, how to the heck did the IRB pass this? Right?
Because this,
-- they didn't. Yeah.
-- Well, and yeah, and that's how it turns out. Is
that ok?
What's, what's an IRB?
I think there's a lot of people who don't understand what that means.
Institutional Review board. So it's like I want to go kick puppies
and they're like, ok, well, you're gonna have to wear like Crocs or something soft,
you know, to kick the puppies.
Right. You can't wear crampons when you kick the puppies. Oh, ok.
Yeah, we'll do that. We'll kick the puppies and then we'll take them to the vet.
-- This is
-- horrific example.
-- Well,
-- that's the point. Right.
That's,
that's why we have the IRB because if I gave
you the true examples of why we have the IRB.
Josh would have to censor this show and it would
be marked as some horrific level of you're going to need
therapy after. OK.
I'm just going to say Tuskegee syphilis experiment, for example,
which didn't wind down
until the late eighties.
You know,
like
we're not even going to put that in the
-- notes. You can google it if you don't know what it is.
-- It was highly unethical and
it
was,
it was
-- OK. Yeah, you're right, you're right. Absolutely.
-- Yeah.
And so this is why this is why we have things like I RBS. Now, I would hope that the I RBS
are take a more proactive approach maybe and kind
of make sure people aren't doing stupid things.
The IRB wasn't consulted until after the fact.
-- I mean, if you don't ask them
-- well, but the ecosystem surrounding it,
like the adviser, how did the graduate adviser not run this by the IRB first?
Yeah, I agree. It would not shock me if there's more happening here than we know.
It's pretty clear that they went and did something.
And then after the fact, we're like, Oh, whoops,
we need to get sign off if we want to
publish because you can't publish this stuff without IRB review.
That's part of my question is how much did people know?
And how much of this is just, we're going to throw these guys under the,
well, the three people definitely knew
and
it's pretty clear they didn't tell the RB till afterwards.
So I don't want to give the IRB a complete
pass because obviously the ecosystem at that university failed.
And the IRB does hold part of that as a problem,
you know, that,
that university as a whole has a sick ecosystem clearly
because three people decided they would go do this.
Maybe they have other teams doing this.
How do we know? They're the only one?
Right.
And part of me hopes that because
this is such an
regious example of bad behavior that it is rare enough, you know, like,
it's just one of those things where?
Oh, wow, this is so bad.
No, it actually turns out this is rare enough that it makes the news.
I certainly hope so.
It's not something common because what's funny is
you see all the people that are like,
oh, yeah, I thought about doing that kind of research, like 1015,
20 whatever years ago.
But then I decided, like, again, it's just not useful.
It's, we know you can get malicious code commits in because we do all the time.
Like we get not malicious code commits in,
but we get code commits that have security flaws in all
time. That's why INFOSEC is a thing.
That's it.
Now,
if we had some idea the statistics behind it and you
know what kind of actual tools and behaviors could help,
lower these numbers
-- that would be useful.
-- I agree.
I mean, that this is one of my frustrations is what activities we do actually matter.
And I feel like we don't know.
-- Most of the time
-- I've seen a couple clever attempts to
kind of fix the code sign off problem where OK,
number one, you require code, sign off on everything.
Well, yeah, and then it just becomes
smash that OK button,
right?
You know, there's, there's a web comic I saw the other day,
I don't remember who did it.
I'll see if I can find it.
I'm not, I don't, I don't know if I will,
but it was basically it showed like a code commit.
That's three lines has like 20 comments about it. A code commit.
That's 2000 lines just has looks good to me. You know,
-- I get that.
-- I honestly don't know what the answer is here.
I suspect it has something to do with a bit of machine learning.
And a I just,
even from a measurement point of view because having
people fill out a form are trying to,
you know, try
a code commit is that's not going to fly for most projects. No, not at all.
At least in this case,
here's a great example of where open source is good though is that we can say, OK,
here are all the, you know, u the commits from these email addresses,
we can at least find them and see what they were.
And if they come clean on the other email addresses they used, we can, you know,
figure that out part of it speaks to why, you know,
with the distributed weakness filing project, why we require a github
ID randoms walking off the street and make good CV requests. Cool.
But in general,
the majority of our CV requests are going to come from people where you click on their
github profile and you can just instantly by glancing at it for 10 seconds,
kind of tell if they're quote unquote legitimate or not.
It really is that easy most of the time?
Well, and look, if the account is three hours old when it,
when it submits, like there's nothing wrong with that, but it's also not like,
oh yes, I'm going to approve this person.
-- You know what I mean?
-- Well, let me put it this way.
I assigned 6000 cvs and people are like, but this one had a flaw and I'm like, I'm sure.
Yeah,
probably did.
I, I, and first of all, I'm like,
I have no idea what you're talking about because like one out of 6000
the nope.
But secondly,
I, I never spent more than about 30 seconds reviewing each one
because when you get to the law of large numbers, like if you go, I,
I challenge anybody to go to the LKML archives and read
-- a week of list traffic.
-- Oh my goodness, man.
I subscribe to it and I will glance, I will look for certain things and I use it most as
just an archive.
I can search every now and then I'll start reading a
thread because I find a particular patch interesting and it is,
it is unreadable.
I don't know how like the likes of Linus and Greg and you know,
-- al and some of these people,
-- they don't,
they sort of my understanding is that they sort of delegate and get like a, you know,
a condensed version.
I don't know, man. Like they've replied to the weirdest stuff though.
-- They read a lot
-- regardless. Last week was 8405 messages in
-- a
-- week.
Yeah.
-- And my
-- human is reading
that I'm going to pick another random week. 8244.
Uh 0, this one's lower 6628.
Is
that
all?
Oh, this
ouch. 10,552.
-- So if you spent, how many seconds in a week are there?
-- I don't know
the math.
Uh
oh, there's that song I should know this.
Um 60.
0, yeah. Sorry. Six
uh 604,800 seconds in a week. So divide.
So, yeah, if it takes a minute to read each message, you don't get to sleep that week,
-- it's
-- fine.
Everything's fine. Yeah.
Even just reading a, a
1% subset of that
and, and understanding those emails is still going to take multiple hours for sure.
Yeah.
Anyways, I think I'm, I'm glad that Greg set the bar because this is, as far as I know,
this is kind of the first time it's really publicly happened.
I mean, no doubt it's happened. But
for,
but no, I'm glad you set the bar this high. I think it's a good bar to set.
And I think part of the problem now is that
the u the university is also now broken trust,
especially around trust.
Yeah, like you said, with that their domain name 100% and in general,
because they can't be the only university that has
these lax controls and allows this kind of shenanigans.
I bet many, many university research departments are having,
we'll say heated meetings this week.
All right, I'm, I'm going to call this one. I feel like
it pleases me. We got to talk about this because I'm, I'm still super annoyed by this
and everything that happened.
It was bad, useless research. We know that this is possible.
-- You don't need to prove it.
-- Yep. Yep. Exactly. All right. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. Go to open source security podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes, use a Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks,
-- everyone. Bye bye
the.