Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
-- and my partner in Time travel, Josh Bresser.
-- It's not time travel.
It's a blast from the past. There's a difference. I
guess we're not moving.
Well, we are moving forward in time at a rate of one second per second.
But we're going to talk about the past. We are,
we move forward in time at a rate of one second per second.
Wait a minute, wait a minute. Because with relativity, the faster you move, the
time slows down to an observer.
So is a second. A second is Justin
as X number of steps or transitions for a season, madam. Right.
Right.
-- Oh, what speed
-- at the reference speed of wherever you're at, wherever you're at.
A second is a second.
Like you
observing me,
your,
-- your frame of reference would have a different one.
-- Ok. That makes sense.
So,
basically what you're arguing is like earth time would be UTC
time and me in a spaceship would be Kurt time.
Exactly.
Exactly. Like my 37 minute nap on Mars.
Oh, man, I forgot about, we don't have potholes
and I'm dumber than I ever,
well, I, well, I don't know. This Tar Fil thing's pretty dumb.
-- It's
-- pretty dumb. So it's, well,
it's not just dumb.
It's widespread. All right. So
there's going to be a lot to unpack in this one. And
let's just start with the CV E ID.
We're talking about CV E 2007. That's right. 2007 4559.
And it's not like it's a back ported CV, like
it was released in 2007. Like this is when it was
like,
-- there's links to Python mailing archives from 2007 which
-- we got
to dig back through and we got to see people,
we remember back then
-- adding bugs to stuff.
-- But like no, like people that were my boss at one point.
Uh That's true.
And this was 2007.
I would have been at Red Hat for three years
at this point doing all of this sort of work.
I started in 2000 and four.
Yeah, I wasn't there until 2010.
-- So
-- you weren't there yet. I started in 2004
doing
vulnerable
and, and one of the links,
I'll put the Red Hat bug in the show notes because it's actually really good.
-- And I don't blame Red Hat for this too much
-- Red
hat just rolled with it like the rest of it,
-- it
-- happens. I
it was a different time
and I mean, we'll talk about this but yeah, I mean,
-- basically to buck the trend is a pain. So
-- let's start at the beginning.
There is a story that
I found on the register. This has been a couple a week or two now, I think,
I don't know, remember how long it's been.
But anyway,
there's a story on the register that basically a security researcher in, what is it?
2022 a security researcher basically figured out that the Python Tar
file
module is susceptible to path traversal.
And this is something that
I feel like probably around 2007,
every single tar file handling whatever was being susceptible to
and we were fixing them all over the place.
And the idea is if I tar up a file with a path of dot dot slash dot dot
dot dot
dot
dot slash, which kind of slash the good slash da
slash,
there's only one slash the other slash is dumb dot
slash whatever. All the usual path traversal slash Etsy slash password
and
the root user un tars a tar file, it will overwrite
Etsy path
-- or any
-- file you want.
Essentially, it's a director traversal attack
and
tar files historically supported
dot dot slash because, well, things like symbolic links,
right? Like
there's, there's, this is one of the few times where there's
a
path.
This is one of the few times where there is an actual legitimate,
correct use case to support that
like on a web server and stuff. No, just, no,
the t
-- doesn't need this anymore.
-- Not anymore. No. But back in the day it never did.
Never did.
I'm saying it never did fight me, fight me
anyway. The path traversal issue is basically reported in 2007.
Well, ok, I'm sorry. So
back to 2022
2022 researcher finds it does some investigation
has demo exploits all that stuff and
finds out, oh,
we found this in 2007
and the people who developed Tar threw their hands
in the air and declared it not their problem.
Uh
Tar
file
tar
file, sorry.
Fun fact of history CV E 2001
dash 1267
directory traversal vulnerability in gene
uar 1.13 0.19 and early allows local users to overwrite arbitrary files during our
archive extraction via Tar file whose file name contains
dot dot
So tartar
fixed it like well in 2001. So like this is not unknown
variants of this have been found in
multiple times since 2001.
So there have been many, many different ways to exploit this.
Well, everything that basically does Tar at some point learns this the hard way.
Even the Tar program.
I I'm pretty sure if we did enough digging and we're not going to.
But if we did enough digging,
we would find examples of this fix multiple times
in the new Tar because there were different codings.
I remember there were different, like plugins, there was all this stuff.
There are different ways to extract anyway. It doesn't matter.
So,
a person in 2022 finds this realizes it's old
and also realizes that this affects 350,000 things.
-- Essentially.
-- Well, everything, I mean, tar files are kind of
your options are tar files and zip files.
Yeah, basically.
Uh,
they, they, they, they can. Yes.
Well, I wonder if the zip module in Python addresses this, it probably does
anyway, anyway, back to 2007. Now
this is found it gets reported. The tar file people have a patch
and then the author
or not the author.
But the maintainer of Tar file basically puts a message into the bug tracker.
That's like
after some thought and discussion, I decided this isn't a security vulnerability.
Like if you're un tarring files,
it is your job to check the file before you un tar it. I'm not fixing this
and I would
partly agree in the sense of ignoring the
dot dot directory traversal shenanigans tar files.
Well, depending on implementation, some of them can also have absolute paths,
right?
But basically ignoring that.
So let's ignore absolute paths if they're supported or not.
And let's ignore directory traversal issues if you, for example,
unpack a tar ball in your home directory.
Well, yeah, like you could over dot Ssh configure or something
like that.
Like I don't know, like, because I legitimately have a Tar Ball,
like with my dot SSH directory in it because I wanted to back it up,
back in the day. Right? Because like, yeah, I mean, how else am I going to back it up?
Ir sync my home directory somewhere else.
Well, but I mean, like I would tar it up and, you know, anyways, so there is a,
there is one argument to be made that is essentially
as if you are extracting data onto a file system,
either you need to be really careful or like do it kind of inside of
a,
when I say container, I don't mean like a new modern container.
I'm talking about like 20 years ago, like I'm talking like make dirt
CD, tamp,
-- unpack
-- it. But if it's got a bunch of dot dot slashes, you can still escape that.
Yeah. Yeah. So, and you know, and so if you want to be super paranoid, right?
You could like ch root it, you know,
because I know ch roots not a security thing because yeah, it's not,
but it's convenient.
But anyways or a free DJ or whatever the
point is if you want to unpack an archive safely
and, and this is ignoring dot dot slash and like
arbitrary path names,
it's still tricky because
you have to do it in like a directory where there's nothing that you care about
that other Attackers can't see.
So they can't exploit to talk to or simlink or whatever. But having said that if I make
dirt, temp CD, temp and unpack a file in there, I expect that file to stay in there.
-- Like not,
-- I agree. I, I would not expect it to escape
-- and
-- I shouldn't have to do stuff like ch root
or free BS D jail or all sorts of shenanigans.
It should just,
yeah, like when I right, click on something in windows and extract zip. I expect that
it's going to make a directory and then spew garbage all o all the way down.
I don't care. But in that directory and fun fact to bring up the zip
zip slip, zip already. Yeah. Also went through this.
-- Remember, I mean,
-- zip, well, zip slip is a copy and paste problem
is it? I thought it was
so zips,
the problem with zip slip is
the, the Java zip library
could be used unsafely.
It was there, there was an example on stack overflow that if you copy and pasted it,
you were vulnerable to zip slip, which was the literally the same problem.
It was the directory traversal.
And I guess it's harder to fix because now you have to fix
um
kajillions million instances and
Ty Magill
codes.
Well, so I mean, but here's the thing,
this is this the fix in this case is the same as the fix and zip slip
where you have to send a patch to every
project because according to the tar file authors,
the problem isn't tar file, the problem is you extracting untrusted TARS.
And the fun thing is there is a patch for this for Python Tar file to fix it.
-- There is which I don't know if that'll get added or not.
-- Well, here's the thing.
You could fix this on the system,
Python and then be done with it and you don't have to patch all the things using it.
That is the right way to fix it. And I'm hopeful, Python will change their mind.
Given it's been a decade,
almost two decades.
Let's thought experiment assume for a moment
that this is not a security vulnerability.
OK. Cool. What is the
side to fixing it?
-- Like, why not just fix it?
-- I agree with you. I don't, I don't think there is a downside.
I, I can construct a pathological use case where I do need dot dot Stuff to escape.
And it's
again like pathological and there's far better ways to do it.
And that's the point is it's such an extreme corner case that it's wrong.
I agree. So this isn't like I'm not saying, never do this.
I'm saying not only am I basically saying no,
do this but given even the use cases where I would say do this.
It's,
there's, it's wrong. It's, there's better ways to do it.
-- Add a flag to the function that says like I'm not smart or something, you know,
-- like,
yeah, like I really do want this crazy behavior
and that's the thing.
So,
and that is where I wanted to bring up open
SSL S host name checks when it's processing certificates.
So
I want you to tell me
-- when did Open SSL actually start checking host names by default
-- 2007,
let's say just because that's what you're already talking about.
Openness.
No, I don't think so. Well,
it's complicated. So
up until version 1.02 it didn't even have support for it
like you had to,
you had to build your own
and then they finally turned it on by default in 1.1 point. Oh, like that.
I mean, the openness of C 1.02 release was in, I looked this up and then of course,
I closed the tab
2015.
So in 2015 they gave you the possibility of checking it 2015.
-- I mean, I'm sorry, this should have been done in the, hold
-- on. Ok.
Wait, wait before you go. All judgy.
I want to address two important things. I think number one,
this was a very common mindset back in the, we'll say the odds,
-- the two thousands.
-- Well, up until 2015, apparently
and, and
open SSL has historically
held on to their mindset far longer than they ever should
countless times. So that's ok. But that, that's part of the open SSL group.
It's that's fine. That's fine.
Back in the arts and even the nineties,
this was the way it was where if you were going to use a live,
you had to be smart.
And there were multiple ways like this was a,
a twisty path on the side of a cliff with loose rocks everywhere and it was up to
you to watch your feet and not step on a loose rock and fall to your death.
Well, or get mauled by a mountain lion.
That's true. There were also mountain lions.
-- The problem
-- is not just that openness is held to this.
Everybody did this.
I I agree that look at this tar issue, Kirk,
this tar issue is literally that and there were many,
many especially security things that would fall in this kind of just mindset.
It, it, it was what it was and it was
dangerous to use a lot of this stuff and a lot of security problems over the last,
how many decades are the result of this?
Like do it right?
You moron when the reality is we should have made it hard to do it wrong.
Well, inherent safety. And here's my favorite thing
is in the open SSL stuff where they're talking about this. They
literally like,
oh we should like go grab the ruby implementation of this and
just use it like because Ruby wrote a whole bile of code
to do host name checks. Like and I guess I'm gonna say something kind of mean, but
somebody had to go first and I guess it wasn't open as a cell. That blows my mind.
That doesn't surprise me at all. No, no. And, and, well, even I remember in Python
there was no host name checking. You could enable it,
but it didn't work by default because you, they did,
Python didn't ship with C A certificates.
So there was no way for them to do any sort of verification.
So it was up to you to get some
C A certificates and then turn on verification manually.
Which again, that was the way it was. And, and here's the thing,
here's the thing.
We had all these weird problems and we look at it now and we're horrified this,
-- this feels like
-- this isn't even that long ago.
-- This is less than a decade. This is six years,
-- Kurt, this was 100 years
in normal dispute of history. Like this is 100 years ago.
This is like eating lead
in your cereal type stuff.
But again, we have survivorship bias sometimes where it's like, oh,
it wasn't that bad.
I survived. Honestly, I don't think it was that bad and I don't think,
I guess that's a thing. This didn't take anyone's life.
I'm
comfortable saying it did not take anyone's life.
I, from what I understand of some of the stuff coming out of the
anyways.
Um Here's a question in
the last five years,
but here's the thing. So for example,
in fairness back in 2000, how would you get all the root certificate, certificates
or sorry, root certificate, authority certificates.
And the answer is like good luck with that.
So no, you took them from
-- Mozilla. They published a nice list,
-- the Cab Forum.
So what does the Cab forum stand for? Again? I'm totally spacing on that
certification authority browser forum. And it's a voluntary consortium.
But I mean, it's basically like once,
like once Mozilla, like Chrome and Microsoft joined it was,
that's it that only started existing in 2005. But having said that
we've had the C A form and a
like a generally agreed upon list of root certificate, authority providers
since, well, 2005.
-- Well,
-- we had one before. It's just Mozilla did it.
So, yeah.
And then it took 11 years for people to actually like start checking host names.
Oh, see, here's the thing,
web browsers have been checking host names
correctly.
Well, basically since day one. Ok,
this is a good
segue
into something I've been thinking about a lot lately
that I don't have my thoughts completely formed.
But if you look at the world of web browsers, specifically,
web browsers have been under attack pretty much forever.
And I think the reason is they're actually like,
there's real money moving around generally so you can steal credit cards and stuff.
I was about to say they're, they're one of the few pieces of software that
-- normal people use to transact. Right.
-- Right. Right.
And so there's like, literally money, there's money in web browsers, literally. So
they've been attacked
opportunistically
since the beginning, pretty much.
And so they had to solve these problems because they were solving real problems.
Now, if you look at like host, name checking and Python scripts,
how many of those are legitimately going to be attacked?
The number is exceedingly small. We're talking probably a PT attack.
-- Yeah,
-- to a degree. But there's also, for example, the whole thing
where remember Ssh Sniff and SSL,
sniff and all those used to just magically work because it was so
trivial
-- to, for example, intercept like software updates.
-- No. OK. No, it wasn't trivial.
If you were in charge of a network, it was trivial.
But the, the reality is you sitting where you're sitting
and a software mirror sitting somewhere else,
the ability for an attacker to get between you. And that
is not simple.
The
back in the olden days on that local area network,
you could run arps spoof or whatever.
And
but, but
again, if someone's on your network, they can do many other shenanigans. I'm
generally speaking
well.
OK.
And that's the thing this is, but this is the use case for SSL and TLS.
-- This is the exact use case.
-- I know.
I know, but here's my point
browsers had real legitimate attacks and they had to solve these problems,
things like open SSL and Python, there really aren't a lot of legitimate attacks.
And even with this tar file thing,
like the reality is if this was actually being attacked in a significant way,
we would have found it and fixed it a long time ago.
The fact that it sat dormant for this long tells me it's
no
one
cares.
But for example, there's still a tunnel log for Jay that's not been fixed.
That's
not
like
I, I still see front page uh
scans
and I mean, front pages.
Uh Jeez, when did I use like
that was,
that was some old Microsoft technology from 20
years ago and people are still scanning for it
and walk for J now is like, well,
-- it,
-- it'll, yeah, it'll be around forever. But I'm not, I'm not making up an excuse.
I'm just pointing out the fact that
browsers had real problems. Python necessarily didn't, which is why
you don't see the kind of,
of progress in fast fixing
because it's just
you're, you're not solving like immediate in your face problem.
Well, I also wonder part of it is the widespread of it. Like to be blunt,
if you use Firefox,
you're using Firefox.
If you use Python.
Yes, we're using the same version of Python,
but I'm not using it the same way that you use it.
Like I'm writing terrible code to mangle up
Json files and you're writing
a thing to, you know, strip files out of youtube or something. Right.
Right. And,
and I think it's almost in a way worse because
to put it bluntly, like, back in the old days, like,
if you basically took a run at something you could almost always
fiddle with certificates and connections and get in there that way.
And
because it was sort of a targeted attack against kind of
one entity or one piece of software or maybe one library,
you know. Yeah, like even if they fix it, it doesn't fix it for everybody.
Whereas, yeah, like Firefox is, or you know,
most like those are really common pieces of software used in the same way.
So maybe that's part of it is that they're used in the same way.
And
yeah, I mean, this is the same,
like why did Windows have all the malware because it was completely ubiquitous?
-- Well,
-- it also had 80% of the market share.
Right. Well, yeah. Right. Right.
I'm gonna, you know, why do you rob banks? Because that's where they keep the money.
Like
it's, yeah, back to this. Like
just what blows my mind is, I'm going to say this, if you make tools
especially widely used popular tools and you
claim to care about engineering quality,
then
-- ideally your tools have to have some degree of inherent safety.
-- I agree. I agree.
-- This is like having a, a table saw with no guard on it, for example. Right.
-- Like,
-- and no locking nut. Right.
-- And back in the day that was fine.
-- But now that would be unthinkable.
-- Fingers are expensive. Uh,
they still are.
No, like, fingers are actually really expensive as it turns out,
like sewing them back on is tricky.
Just, I, I like having that.
My ability to work would be slightly diminished.
-- So
-- one time I was putting a screw and I wasn't wearing work gloves and
I was putting a screw and the drill slipped and I like punched my thumb.
Remember I showed you that picture of it. I do remember this.
I punched my thumb with a number two Robertson's bit and like, basically,
I pushed a bit of the nail and I kind of got stuck under.
So I had to go to emerge and it's funny or not emerge.
I went to urgent care and I of course, I have a Ziploc bag full of ice
on my hand because it's, it's pretty hurty. And I'm like, you know, I hurt my thumb.
I like bashed it with a drill bit basically or a
Yeah, screw it basically. It really hurts. And I'm like, oh they're like,
is your finger in the bag? I'm like, no.
And they're like, oh, ok, because we're gonna send you away
like I'm like, I'm like, no offense.
Like I'm sure you people are confident,
but like if I'm carrying a body part in a Ziploc bag, I am not going to urgent care.
I'm going to the real. It's
no, I bet that
-- happened before though.
-- Maybe. But
-- I feel like I might have also called an ambulance. I guarantee
-- that's happened
actually. Now that I bet you, I'm pretty sure this story is on an old podcast episode.
I'm not going to go look at it.
But if someone sends it to me, I'll give you a shout out in the next episode.
Wear your work gloves, folks,
especially when you're drilling at strange angles in a confined space anyway.
But so that's the thing, right? Like I'm holding my Swiss Army knife up here,
the blades do not lock open.
However, the use case for this knife is such that that is a reasonable thing to have.
Whereas this knife I'm holding up the blade locks and
it damn well better lock or you're going to slice
a finger off because of the way this knife is meant to be used and what it's used for.
Like it's not a Swiss army knife, it's like a big utility knife.
And so occasionally, like, like it's OK to not have everything be super, super safe,
but based on how the tool is expected and reasonably used,
it should be reasonably safe.
And I think unpacking a tar file
and for example, not running, you know, Tar space, hyphen TV, space
tar file name to like list what's in the file
and list the path and then examining it and going,
oh, there's a dot
slash here. I should probably not have
this,
-- you shove that thing through Tar XVF and like give her
-- Yeah, I agree.
I think that in the current environment we exist in
-- and the way developers work
-- uh since like 2000 easily,
I maybe, I
-- think since 2012 or 13,
-- I
feed
a file into a file parser.
It should be inherently safe.
-- It should not result in code execution or random weird file over right.
-- Tar
file isn't
a,
it's not a parser. It's, it's a library in a par
a
file and unpacks it
-- whatever. I'm
-- not
-- arguing
-- this with you.
I know it's a fine line but
let's ignore the past where we exist today.
This
lot, this, this module should not work this way.
Now, I'm sure in the Python land there are, are no less than 25 tar
handling modules you can install with pip.
I don't think it is acceptable for a,
a library in the core language
to suffer from a problem like this. I think that we are not there in 2007.
I think you could make that argument
in 2022.
You cannot make that argument any longer because developers writing things,
you can look in the documentation for this
and it has a section that's like, oh you be like don't unt
untrusted stuff like it.
You gotta check for your dot Dots and stuff that is no one is reading that
documentation anymore. Like that's not how people develop these days.
Well, I expect Tar Torn.
Here's a simple, very simple argument.
How much effort would it even today to be
to fix Tar file properly in the Python language?
The patch exists.
What I'm saying is the effort of fixing
the Python Tar file properly in the language is vastly smaller
than patching 350,000 applications like that's bonkers like because each of them,
let's just ballpark. Let's magically say it takes an hour.
I guarantee you, it's gonna take less than 350,000 hours to patch
all the major Python distributions.
-- Like.
-- Right.
-- That's a good way to look at it.
-- That's how I look at these things now, right?
Like that, that my tweet about the GDPR cookie warnings and stuff like,
like I'm sorry, but patching 350,000 programs
and it's not going to be an hour. It's gonna be like 5 to 10 hours, maybe more.
That is, wait, we're, we might actually kill somebody,
ok? At one hour.
That's 39.95 people years. So for every hour it takes to fix all of those programs,
you're killing a 40 year old person.
I'm a 40 year old person
now. I'm scared, I'm scared. It's
-- so
-- like that's, that's insane. That is a huge amount of time.
Like I said,
ignoring the security aspect of this from like just a pure economic efficiency.
What is the rational economic actor type thing to do?
Fix it once here well, and multiple places because obviously, you know,
like multiple Python distributions in operating systems.
But fundamentally, you fix maybe 100 of those
-- and you get like 80 90% of it versus trying to fix 350,000 applications.
-- I agree.
I agree. I think that is,
I mean, look, this is why if you look at Linux distributions like Red Hat,
they're very particular about making sure everything's
a library because there was a time
when Z li
was not a library included like a as a shared library.
It was just in all of the packages and there was some security vulnerability and
it took them like literally hundreds and hundreds of hours to find all of the Z
Libs
-- patch, all of the Z Libs and rebuild those packages.
-- And then the best part is
there's probably going to be another security flaw.
See, and that's the thing people forget.
Like it's not, it's like it's like log for J oh, we fixed log for J.
Well, yeah, except then there were those other CV S and log for J after the fact.
But let's ignore those.
Are you willing to bet a significant sum of money like a mortgage payment or
a car payment or whatever on the fact
that there will be no more vulnerabilities entire
in Python or no more vulnerabilities than log for J? Right. And no, of course not.
Here's the bet I am willing to make though.
I think this is esoteric enough and probably not
used widely enough that we're going to see a
like legitimate attack leveraging this.
And that's part of the challenge here and
in a way that's almost worse because it's just
now if somebody needs to pest something or is
a bad person who wants to break into stuff,
there's one more thing you have where like, you know, it's like that.
Uh oh, there's like this, I forget where it was there. It was this great
gist or whatever thing on github.
It was like a list of headers that you could fire off at all.
Web server and see kind of what bounces back and see where it's like puking on stuff
and it wouldn't actually exploit anything. But it was like, oh,
it's not handling this use case correctly. And that's the thing.
Like I, I used to have a tar file that was like all sorts of mangled or like the zip bomb,
right? That the
zip bomb. I had a copy of that zip bomb like all my
thing and I would point stuff at it like I still do this and, and this is horrible.
I will uh DD
uh debut random
into a file and then feed it into something.
So a great example, one password, one password is like, hey,
we can import your passwords from a file.
I'm like, oh, can you, let's see what happens and
because it,
like, basically because it parses it browser side and then
bundles it up and like, encrypts it and sends it to the server.
Um, yeah, we had to delete my account
because like, I totally
hosed it and I get it in that case.
Like, it's a, it's a client side issue, blah, blah, blah. But
like I do this all the time.
Like, that's how I used to detect when, oh, remember back in the day,
all those places using
nus
to scan your security
and there was a really easy tell which is you set your DNS
in chaos uh version
to binary data, like random binary data.
And they would,
and if it was N A,
it would puke in a certain way that would propagate up through their PDF reports.
And
I would be like, oh, you're using N A? Cool,
you know, and that's the thing like this is, it shouldn't be this easy.
Well, I, I, and I think generally speaking, we're getting a lot of this right? And
except for Tar
file.
Well, I, I look, I'm excited to see what Python does about this. If they ignore it,
I guarantee you 100% nothing because they'll use your argument of, well,
it's been 15 years.
No, that doesn't make it right.
But
that's not what I'm no.
If that's what anyone who has taken away from this conversation, please,
please please.
That is not the intent. What's the statue
of,
is there a statute of limitations on security vulnerabilities?
Of course not.
I'm look, no,
I'm, I'm just pointing out in 2007.
I think this argument was not completely bananas in 2022.
This argument is completely bananas.
There probably also wasn't 350,000 applications vulnerable in 2007.
And, and my suspicion also is there aren't really 350,000.
My guess is they search github.
They found 350,000 uses of this
and
90% of them is crap. Like what you and I build and throw in github
that like we use twice and never use again.
But my guess is it's probably hundreds to
thousands of legitimate things are affected by this.
So that's not a lot,
but it's still not something we should have to go
and fix in those say hundreds or thousands of projects
to the point. So you're saying that I am using a tar library to unpack a tar file.
And now I'm responsible for learning enough about Tar to do it
that
you're not going to do that.
In 2007, you might have done that
in 2022. That is not how people develop software you expect to take a library,
use a library,
do whatever thing you need it to do
and all you're going to do is copy and paste how to use it off stack overflow,
you aren't going to read a single line of documentation
-- and
-- especially when it's like a popular file format like JPEG
tar, these are common, common
file formats that have been around for literally decades.
But
yeah, I'm sorry. But if I like if
see it's, and, and again, a really good argument here is,
it's not like I'm choosing to use this library.
It's
I chose Python, this is what I'm stuck with by default.
And I would say like if it was a third party library,
uh
OK, maybe sort of kind of,
but I think once it gets into the core of a language and becomes like a default,
especially something like like this, like there's J
pig, there's tar, there's,
-- there's, we should,
-- I don't, I don't know if we've clarified this.
If you have Python, you have Tar
file like it is in the Python standard library,
-- you have this vulnerable version of Tar file. You
-- know. That's true.
Everyone has it. Literally everyone.
If you have Python, you have a vulnerable version
at the time of this recording. Hopefully that's not true
when this
episode
comes up.
-- No, it'll still be broken.
-- I
-- think
-- it'll
-- still
-- be
-- broken
-- anyway
-- anyway.
-- But again, like this is, I think again, it boils down to
if I'm going to use a tool in a reasonable
expected way that I'm supposed to use that tool,
which you know, un tarring a tar file is that's how you generally use tar libraries.
We know it just should work. And
again,
also, back to that rational economic argument, again, also back to the security of
V
AR
but again,
isn't the whole point of it to automate stuff and to take the knowledge
and
I'm kicking you off your soapbox right now.
This is the way it was done in 2007 and then we forgot,
someone found it again if Python doesn't fix this shame on them.
But the reality is the world changed. What used to be ok? Isn't ok. Now, what's ok?
Now isn't going to be ok in five years and 10 years in 20 years.
So, the reality is like, that's just the way it was whatever, fix it. Move on.
You know what?
Let's make a gentleman's bet in five years. Are we going to be talking about?
What was that, um, the library that you just mentioned today
on Slack?
Remember the one that in
Github
was like, we're getting too many security reports. We don't want to support this.
-- We give up.
-- Oh, that's
cerf
-- for M PM.
-- Yeah.
So
let's make a gentleman's bet in five years.
Or set a timer on my phone or something in five years.
You think people are still using sea surf?
Absolutely. 100%.
If you're willing to let me take the 100% people using the five year stand,
I will totally take this bet and I will bet you anything you want and I will.
-- That's
-- the
-- end
-- I
want.
So, we both want the same thing
because we both know
-- that we're
-- right.
But that's the thing. Right? Like,
yeah,
here we are.
-- It is
-- what it is and, and look,
here's how I want to end this and this is like the whole point of it.
All things change
-- and that's
-- ok. Expectations as well. Like what is
sort
of
ethical
even legal? Like
we do criminalize partner.
Huh? Canada? And it turned out ok,
and, and look, it, it is, it
is always shameful to me when
someone sticks by a decision they made 20 years ago, just, just to do it.
I also find it shameful when people criticize someone for changing their mind.
And I think both of those are equally dangerous.
I think this is one of those instances, like
I don't agree with what happened in 2007, but I get it times have changed,
fix the library and let's go back to doing whatever it
is we should be doing instead of talking about this,
I think.
Well, and that's one thing like is especially once you have new evidence or,
you know, just enough time has gone by that clearly,
the world has changed significantly.
Yeah, it's time to change your mind and yeah. Come
on something new.
I am really curious.
What do you think would happen if somebody tried to
reopen this bug in Red Hat or on Python we
find out.
Well, no, no, but I'm looking at the, I'm looking at the, uh, the red hat
and nobody's tried to reopen it there.
I'm looking at the, uh, the Python one. Well, that got moved to Github,
so I'll have to hunt that down. But,
but, I mean, based on the fact like
that Python hasn't made a statement that, yeah, we're going to fix this.
Well, we haven't gone looking for a statement either.
We've, we've only been looking at old things in 2007.
Like we haven't looked at new stuff and we conclude that we're not,
we're already out of time.
So I'm not, we're not going to dig into it at this moment.
-- I took a quick look earlier and didn't find anything
-- though.
Now, I will say that I'll end on this.
The way this should be handled is we should give this a 2022 CBE ID
and declare it a security issue and just fix it everywhere.
I don't know if that's going to happen. It wouldn't surprise me if CV E like insists.
-- No, because it already has one or something. But, well,
-- or they'll just argue.
It's not
a, it's not a gloom or
-- whatever.
-- All right, I'm, I'm ending this.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening. Go to open
to open
source Security podcast.com. Hit up the show notes.
I'll put links to all the fun stuff. I've, I've got a lot of them today right now.
But
-- yeah, uh, Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day,
-- man.
One quick note, the tar file in C Python is actually
actively being modified, like as late as June
this year. Like they
did, they fix this. No, no, no, but they're like adding
stuff to it and removing stuff and adding capabilities.
So
in a way that's almost worse because this thing is actually like,
it's not done and we just left it.
-- Of course,
-- it's never done. That's good. We want people touching it.
-- But
-- I mean, this thing is under active development with good commits,
then actively develop this patch.
All right, I'm ending it. Thank you, everybody. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.
That.