Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siegfried and my partner in trying to fix computers.
Josh Bresser.
-- I don't try to fix computers. I mostly don't fix computers.
-- I've actually have luck.
I've got the, uh, the backup server is reliably
backing up the other server
and now I need to figure out how to get tail scale with SSH,
so I can move the server to my parents' house.
-- Ah,
-- I see. I see. That's fair.
Yeah, because I,
I will cry if I have to go download like, 10 terabytes of data from the internet.
-- That is totally not copyright infringement.
-- Uh, do I have 10 terabytes?
No,
my backup I back up to S3 is like 2.5 terabytes of
stuff and then it goes into Glacier and it costs me,
like, $3 a month.
-- It's hilariously cheap.
-- Everybody on the show,
if you're in Apple, go to privacy.apple.com and if you're in Google, go to
the
search for Google, take out
and go download all your photos
because sometimes they get nuked and disappear and
go do that maybe once every year because you
probably will cry if you lose all your photos.
So I found a tool. I don't remember the name of it now.
And it's, oh, it's on my laptop actually. Um, let me, let me look at it.
I will tell you what it is.
Well, you know what I did, which is horrible. I enabled icloud Sync.
And then the trick is you just have to traverse and touch
every file to make sure it actually downloads and then you get
about 99.5% of your files and a few just don't come through.
Yeah, I, I used to do that. I found a tool called icloud PD, which is
it, it says a command line tool to download photos from
icloud or whatever.
Anyway, I run this and it downloads my photos into a directory which I then
obviously store and back up appropriately.
And I've never downloaded my backup thing from Apple.
I did get the one from Google more than once.
But yes,
losing all of my photos due to like Apple deciding I'm a bad person terrifies me.
-- Just a
-- little glitch. We fix the problem.
That's true.
Also, I've never had that particular thing happen to me,
but I have heard of many people who have their Google or Apple account canceled for,
they claim it's no reason
who knows. I mean, you know how it is.
It's like funny enough your opening was fixing computers.
It's when you go to like your, your uncle calls you. It's like a computer is broken.
It's like,
what'd you do? Nothing.
And like the, the case is bent and hanging open and there's a wire and it's like, yes,
clearly you did nothing to this case.
Well, my favorite is if you did nothing and you weren't using it,
how did you notice it was broken?
And they go, uh,
and I'm like, just be like, it's like a priest or a lawyer.
It's like, you know, I just, I need your honesty. So I like your doctor.
I need to know if you have a weird rash somewhere so I
can treat it because if you don't tell me about the weird rash,
your arm might fall off.
Yes. Well, except we're tech people and we
have no legal ramifications for
telling other people the horrible things we learned about you.
Whereas doctors and lawyers do have codes of ethics they have to follow.
Well, which funnily enough
-- is today's episode.
-- It kind of is, sadly.
All right.
So I'm going to start us out by reading the title of the register story for
anyone who doesn't know the register is a
new site that will say has sensationalist headlines.
-- No, they have British headlines. British.
-- Are they, are they British?
I don't even know
the
register.co.uk and then they rebranded to the register.com
a couple of years ago.
They have
British style of headlines that are very snarky. There's a lot of alliteration.
-- They're they're clever.
-- Yeah. Oh, yeah. Yeah.
-- Well, a little mean, very, I suppose it's very British.
-- Yeah, that's snarky.
Snarky is mean
-- a little mean.
-- Ok. So the, the, the title is Sisa Boss
Makers of Insecure software are enablers of the real villains.
Yeah.
Which
-- she's not wrong.
-- I mean,
I kind of, I, so this article, I,
I have not seen the talk that Jen Easterly gave Jen Easterly is the head of CISA
and the register captures a handful of things. But kind of the
we'll say summary of it all
is that Jen Easterly is blaming software developers.
No, my understanding was she was blaming the software vendors, the company,
the vendor,
the vendor.
That's an important distinction because that's
like you can
like it.
It's the difference between criticizing a person and
saying like the company you work for sucks.
I mean,
that's true because there are lots of people who work for
the phone company and we all hate the phone company,
but we like our neighbors.
Well, hopefully
there are a couple of nuggets in this article that I think are not terrible.
Like for example, she says, stop calling them security vulnerabilities.
I'm OK with that, you know, call them product defects essentially.
And I won't argue with that one.
-- Hey,
-- I mean, I just went through that like
is my engine blowing up a security problem?
No,
but like enough of these engines are blowing up that there's like a class
action lawsuit website and a process to get your engine swapped out with,
by the way, my car with a new engine.
So, Zippy,
it's a new engine cart. Of course, it is.
Like,
I've never had a new car with a new engine.
This is a first for me.
-- Right.
-- I'm in my late forties. I've never owned a new car.
I still, technically, I've never owned a new,
I have never owned a new car.
I will probably never own a new car because I'm a cheap skate. But,
and like, I've never seen a clean engine.
Well, I mean, my wife's had new cars so like Terra
Lee, I have, I guess anyway. Ok. But here's the thing.
So
I feel like this article along with a couple of other things c
has been doing lately is a cause for concern.
And I think that Cisa is starting to take a stance of just security,
harder nerds for solving some of this.
And I don't like that because it's kind of like, I don't, I don't know what to call it,
but I, the thing in my brain is like, reverse victim shaming,
right where? Instead of blaming the users, which thank goodness they're not,
they're saying, oh no, no.
The problem is lazy vendors and like the vendors could do more and we'll put,
could do more in quotes.
But I think it's more complicated than just blaming vendors.
Well, it kind of ignores like the market realities of
company A spends a million dollars on security.
Company B spends a million dollars on new features and sales. Which company wins.
-- Well, statistically, company B,
-- right, of course. I mean, Bruce Schneier
had an article he wrote about this, what he called it, the security market for lemons
that was decades ago, which is that famous economics paper about, you know, the,
-- the, the market for lemons where
-- you mean like cars that have engines blow up.
But how do you
know?
I mean, no, no, no, no, no, that's not what this is.
So what, what the the the I'll explain for anyone listening.
This was a, an economist, I believe that wrote this paper and they were,
they specifically focused on used cars
where
when you are the seller of a car like, you know, in theory, you know,
everything wrong with your car and as a buyer,
they are at a disadvantage. So let's say, for example, you have,
I am a car owner. Kurt is a car owner. I have never taken care of my car at all.
I barely changed the oil like the tires are pretty much bald. The car is in shambles.
Kurt on the other hand,
has meticulously changed his oil and taking care of everything you can
take care of on the car and it is in marvelous shape,
but from the outside, they look the same.
Now, if both of those cars are sitting on a lot.
In theory, my car should be priced low and Kurt's car should be priced high,
but that isn't how it works because the car sellers basically pick
like the midpoint and they will sell both cars for the same price
knowing that the buyer has no idea.
And I'm, I'm probably screwing this up. So I apologize to anyone who understands.
Well, no, no, no.
That, that also goes to information asymmetry,
which is especially a problem in real estate, for example of like
end up with noisy neighbors.
Sure.
The the point is that like the,
the the car dealership buying the used cars is not going to give ding me
necessarily in price and they're also not going to give Kurt a a higher price,
they're going to give us like this middle of the ground average.
-- Well,
-- the Kelly blue book value or whatever, right?
And that's kind of what
it,
it came down to and security is the same way where
if you do good security versus someone who does bad security,
it's still going to be like the middle
of the road price that wins because fundamentally
the buyers don't have enough information to correctly interpret what is
-- going on with these products
-- or they straight up don't care.
No, I don't like that either. I don't think that's a good attitude.
-- So
-- I for example, have bought several cars in the past and I have never
consciously cared about the quality of the engine.
I've never checked to see if there were recalls on that car and model
and I will do so from now on
because I've learned the hard way that there are cars that have been mass produced,
been around for 10 years that have engines that randomly blow up.
Even if you do oil changes and take care of it correctly.
Would that information have existed when you bought your car though? Yes.
The lawsuit that, yeah, that happened years ago and that's the thing is,
it's not that I didn't care in a sense of I was malicious or lazy or dumb.
It's, I didn't know I had to care.
I just sort of assumed if you're buying a proper brand name car,
like, if I was buying a Trabant, I would expect the engine to blow up because, like,
-- it was made in East Germany 40 years ago,
-- which is an awesome car, by the way.
Right.
Yeah, it's, I love that they can't be recycled because they're, the,
the body panels are made from recycled materials.
It was industrial cotton waste and oil and it was pressed into a form of plastic.
And so it's,
you can't recycle it, like you can just
-- chip it. Yeah. I'm like, they're super
-- weird.
If anyone ever goes to Berlin, you can drive the Treant.
They have like a tourist trap thing and I've done it before. It is
the most amazing car I've ever driven
-- for all of the wrong reasons.
-- I've seen an angry, uh, a person who owned a Trevan
and she was angry and she accidentally ripped the door handle off because she was,
like, open
it so angrily.
Ok. Anyway, I, I want, I want to get us back on the, on the path of security.
-- That's the thing
-- is like, I,
it's not that I didn't know or I didn't know I had to care because I assumed, hey,
these are like this is brand name software.
-- It should be safe,
-- right? I want to
separate that term. I think. So when you say they don't care
in my mind, I interpret, don't care is I know better, but I am actively choosing
the known bad thing for some other reason.
Be it price or my friend is selling it or whatever, right? Versus, I don't know.
-- Yeah.
-- No, this is, this is more of a rum smelled, unknown, unknowns.
Like another thing I've learned from driving different cars in the last month.
My Kia optima is the best car
for cup holders because they're the same size in the front and back.
So my water bottle fits in the front and back.
The Kia sport,
the Toyota Camry and the Toyota Rav four have smaller cup holders in the back.
My water bottle does not fit in them
-- so
-- just don't sit in the back, aren't you driving?
Well, my kids would like to drink some water maybe anyways.
But like again, I never cared about cup holders in a car because it,
like I've only ever apparently owned cars that have all of the same size cup holders,
-- which is apparently
-- ok.
We're done talking about cars.
No more cars.
I want to put us on the path of security and we're going to discuss security. Right.
So Sisa is taking this attitude that I'm going to call blaming the vendors
and I think it is
not completely incorrect. However,
I think this is one of those examples where vendors have virtually no regulation,
the tooling that exists is terrible and unsafe. We keep using it.
We have no incentive.
I mean, you're talking about market forces,
we have no incentive from the market to do things correctly.
We have minimal incentive from the governments to do things correctly.
The
investment in safe and reliable tooling is abysmal at
best and it feels like every single metric we
could have to point us in the right direction
has been like purposely pointed in the bad direction.
That's what I feel like here.
Well, I think it's also worse than that is, will this be effective?
And so a great example is writing secure tooling,
I think sadly,
will not be as effective as people hope because you still have to get people to use it.
And that's not
a small
-- cost
-- that is not.
And rust is the example right now, right,
where like no one's gonna switch to rust and we don't expect them to, but the point is
it exists
and there's so many other places like we just don't even have, you can say like, oh,
writing a secured alternative won't work.
Well, no, it doesn't exist.
But if it did, yes, it's not a silver bullet, but it's definitely
-- step one of a three 100 step journey.
-- Well, I think,
like,
I care less about security than I used to and I care more about process improvement,
I think would be the best way to put it.
I mean, I think that's a reasonable statement.
I feel like when we got into this space, it was all about like fix a vulnerability,
release, an update.
Like that's it.
And there's still a lot of places where that happens,
but it's also becoming more apparent that like
this stuff doesn't exist
kind of in, in a granular fashion. It's part of a larger system
and the larger system and the process with that system,
it's all very related and it all matters a ton.
Yeah,
I, I have a, I have a suspicion that security is an emergent property,
not kind of its own thing,
I expect that's true. And
uh so going to this, for example, the other thing I kind of wonder about is, well,
let's assume c is correct, right.
Let's just assume is what they're saying,
going to be effective or helpful.
No,
no,
I have a great example.
So there's a document I'm staring at from them that this one like wound me up to no end.
It's a, a secure design alert, which is a thing they have. Oh What now
Cisa has these things. They call them
your design alerts where they
whatever they, they have their secure
their pledge where everyone like pinky Swor is stop being insecure,
which totally works.
Anyway. This one is called eliminating cross state scripting vulnerabilities.
And they give like zero actionable advice inside of this thing.
It's just totally actionable review. Their
models,
ensure software validates input for both structures and meaning
they solve turing
that. Yes, good job, good job.
They solved it because
I'm sorry, uh use modern web frameworks, OK?
In fairness that actually should be emboldened at the top.
-- That
-- should be, that's the only thing you can do today.
And even with modern web frameworks,
there's still plenty of room that you can make dumb mistakes.
But yes,
-- they
-- also say you should conduct code reviews and so hit that
yes button because we're all fatigue and want to go for lunch.
LGTM.
And,
and this is my favorite and
implement aggressive adversarial product testing to ensure
the quality and security of the code throughout the development life cycle.
Sure, I'll just magic up a bag of money to pay for that. It's very easy, also
the expertise to do that. Sure, I it's very common like there's totally not
everybody with the ability to do this working already. For the pent testing firms.
Yeah, exactly.
I
mean, but this is
this is the problem, right? This is the advice we get from
-- security people
-- secure by design principles to follow.
Sounds reasonable principle one, take ownership of customer security outcomes.
Uh
No,
I'm not taking all my customers liability.
Uh Number two, embrace radical transparency and accountability.
Uh Pretty sure my lawyers are at this point screaming uh
three build organizational structure and leadership to achieve these goals.
I don't think that's gonna happen.
So the the radical change transparency is really if you read the text, it just says
-- use CV ES basically like issue CV ES for your product.
-- Yeah, that's
HP for example, straight up said we have products with automatic updates.
So there's not going to be any CV
S for them anymore because there's nothing actionable for
the customer to do and they're not technically wrong
because CV S are meant to be actionable.
You, you do something with them. Well, if automatic updates are your only choice
and they happen, whether you like it or not, there's nothing actionable anymore.
That is true. And a lot of
products are
SAS
and if you have a SAS product and it has cross site scripting,
we fixed it
there. Well, there may or may not be, I mean it, you might need to check your,
your data or something. But
well
as a concrete example,
Microsoft said they will do cloud vulnerability
CV S for vulnerabilities where the customer needs
to take an action such as using a newer version of the service or,
you know, retroactively
changing some configuration variable, whatever blah blah blah.
So
yeah, no, this whole thing is
uh in theory and principle, yes, but in practice, this isn't going to happen.
No, it's not.
And,
and so here's kind of my big takeaway from all of
this stuff that I because SISA also has this thing.
I put a link in the notes. Let me click it. So I get it. Exactly correct.
Uh It
is the secure by design pledge.
What an idiotic thing? I mean, come on.
No, you know what if you can't hold someone accountable,
making up this stupid pledge and saying, oh, I'm everyone's signing this pledge.
Like come on, that's
it.
-- If it was.
-- Oh,
that's true. Oh, it says pledge signers, check out our group list of pledge signers,
215 companies. Good job. Everyone. You fixed security. I mean,
so this is the thing like you are a freaking government agency.
Your job is to advise the government
on policy
that can have like real change. This is where we need compliance.
We need things that have teeth.
Now you could say, oh,
we can't have security compliance because we don't have the
security tools or the know how great invest in that.
Like, again,
part of your job is to make sure that we're actually doing the
research and we're understanding the problems and
we're creating viable solutions to this.
Instead,
we have these stupid alerts and these dumb pledges that have zero
meaning to the real world and it's infuriating like come on,
do your freaking job.
Um I actually am not clear what is the secure by design
pledge that you're signing up to because they say take the pledge today
if you're an enterprise software manufacturer and would like to join the pledge,
please email us.
-- Like, what, what
-- if you scroll down?
It says pledge goals and I'm not even going to
go through them because they're stupid and it doesn't matter.
-- No.
-- But that's, that's pledge goals. That's not the pledge itself.
Like what I'm saying is they're saying the Secure by design pledge,
what is it that these companies have actually agreed to?
-- Because that is not at all clear to me.
-- I assume the pledge goals.
-- It doesn't matter who cares. It's meaningless. That's the thing.
-- Right.
Well, that's what I'm saying. It's worse than that.
It's, I don't even know what these companies have signed up to.
They probably don't either.
And, and here's the thing,
I just took a pledge that I'm going to be secure if I don't do any of these things.
What happens to me?
Yeah. Nothing
again. Like
uh
all the goals are ok.
So goal within one year of signing the
pledge demonstrate transparency and vulnerability of burning.
Ok. So this is what they're actually signing up to. Ok?
Because this is not super clear.
No, it whatever. It doesn't matter. The point is
the job of Cisa should not be this fluffy crap. That doesn't matter.
The job of Cissa should not be to say the vendors are the bad guys.
Like we need real and concrete things that can be done.
-- I have an example actually, I want, I want to tell us
-- story actually,
simple question.
why isn't the security pledge a regulatory
-- requirement because
-- they don't have that ability,
the regulatory requirements have to come from another organization.
Sisa doesn't have that power
like you have to involve nist and lawmakers and things like that,
but like freaking do it.
You know what I mean?
CIA should be telling us you need to call your lawmakers and we
need you to put pressure on them so these things can happen.
Now, granted a lot of companies might be like, yeah,
we're going to lobby against that because we totally
don't want to have to care about it.
Security
and yeah, like lots of companies have done that.
Who cares your job is to do what needs to be done?
I actually have a minor success story there.
Uh Remember we were talking a few days ago
about and I was bringing up the NASA railroad safety
-- thing that they run, which is still like an
-- insane to me. But
yes.
Well, anyways,
the point is uh many train companies had pledged
to join after a series of disasters and,
and,
but actually a bunch of them did join in March of 2023.
And there has been some positive results and some of it's
like they actually have a, a PDF of success stories which I sent you a link to,
for example, some of the success stories are quite small like, oh, there was a,
a sign and an obstruction on the sign.
So we moved the obstruction so that now the train
drivers can see the sign and slow down and,
you know, there, there was a lot of very
small or sometimes subtle process improvements but like,
if that prevents one train from, like, going off the rails and smashing stuff
that will totally pay for the project.
-- Absolutely.
-- For a decade.
Right. Yeah.
And trains are an example of, like, horrific and expensive accidents for sure.
Yeah. Well, or where they burnt like a town down.
Like my, uh, I can't pronounce it. The, the one in Quebec.
-- Well, it's happened many places,
-- unfortunately.
I mean, I feel like this pledge is nice but I feel like, yeah,
wouldn't sis's effort maybe be better spent
making this more concrete.
I, I agree. I agree completely. I think celebrating wins
is one of the ways to do this and to show people there can be positive movement.
There are little things can matter,
like little things can matter. And I think we lose sight of that.
A lot where we obsess over, we have to remove all cross site scripting flaws. Like
you're not, it's not gonna happen.
We don't have the technology or they know how to do that.
Well, and this gets exactly to where I,
I don't care as much about security. I care more.
Are you doing process improvement as a consistent thing like
Kaizen in Japan?
And if you are cool then you're probably headed in the right direction,
right? And, and so this is actually one of the things
SISA has done
is there is a standard from
nn
the secure software development framework. It's NIST 800-2 18
and
SISA created a portal and they created a questionnaire.
So obviously, anytime you have a ni standard, it's very long and complicated and,
and how to
show your, your compliant is difficult
and Sisa created a form,
it's you fill it out and you basically say like these are the things I am doing
and then we uh you attach your evidence obviously showing like yes,
I'm doing the thing and it's all self at a station at the moment,
but they created this website and they're collecting these forms
and then government agencies can go and find the forms on.
This is a website like that is a concrete thing that
granted you can argue it has no more teeth than,
than the the pledge.
No, there's a big difference in the,
in the pledge. They're saying we will do this
and in the nist and
showcase, they're saying we have done this from a, like from a judge's point of view.
That's one that's like, oh, you, you lied about trying to do it, don't do that.
Versus you told the government
-- you did this, did you do this on,
-- on their form?
You have to sign it and it's very clear about like,
this is a government document you are signing and a testing
and I think I'm lying to the government is illegal.
It's fraud.
Yeah, I I don't think anyone
I suspect no one's going to go to jail over
the SSDF but like it definitely carries slightly more teeth.
And the point is the more important part of
this I think is SISA is collecting these documents.
And I think this is an example of collect a whole bunch of data
and now you can analyze the data and you can make decisions on the data.
Like that is important because you know what, when I submit my form to CISA,
I include all the evidence that shows how I am meeting a particular control.
Now the government could look at it and be like this is ridiculous.
You are not meeting the control by doing this thing, right? And
in my particular instance,
I hope that's not the case because I actually put a lot of work into this.
But you know what I mean? Like
this is the kind of stuff you can do.
Well,
I've actually done this type of work in the
last few weeks with all of our star entries.
I was looking at just a hair over 1000 star entries is
-- star.
-- Oh, sorry Security Trust Automation Registry.
And it basically is based on the, the consensus.
-- It's a cloud security alliance thing
-- assessment initiative questionnaire,
right?
And it's things like, you know, do you like, do you automate code deployment?
Yes or no.
Do you, you know, blah, blah, blah, a whole bunch of stuff.
And what's fascinating is the vast majority of these questions are about
99% of people say yes to them.
And there are some interesting
exceptions because for example, the,
do you do like a yearly test of your business continuity disaster and recovery plan
and guess what? The percentage of people who say yes to that is,
-- is
-- it i it's probably really high, I suspect no, you have to guess
if I was going to guess I'd guess 80% say yes. No.
Really? I'm impressed. They're not lying about 50.
I mean, 50 is 50 is what I would expect the actual number to be.
But I would assume a lot of people just say yes because
I've talked to people who do these questionnaires in the, in the past because like,
obviously we get a lot of them from big companies that are like,
please fill out this horrible form.
And what's really nice is the, the CS a cake.
I have one of those. I'll often be like, here's my cake.
They're like, oh, close enough. Never mind.
Ignore this horrible questionnaire I sent you. But anyway,
a lot of them said it is often that you will catch,
especially smaller companies just like egregiously lying on these forms.
Well,
they say yes to everything and that's a good
-- sign that they're
-- lying and that's just it.
They're like, if all the answers are yes, we think you're lying.
-- And I'm like, oh,
-- well,
yeah, because like a great example is I was,
I was looking at a couple of large entries, uh Amazon, for example, like,
I think we would all agree.
Amazon has a large mature security
mess,
right?
Well, they make their own silicon.
But anyways, their cake entry has quite a few nose
because technically they don't do it.
They provide a service that does it for the customers to do it.
So they themselves like a lot of stuff around encryption keys. They're like,
oh, no,
we don't technically kind of make sure your data is encrypted
at restaurant transit that's up to the customer to do.
And obviously they make it very easy and even the default in most cases,
but like they don't force it.
Right. So they can't say yes to it.
And, and so they're very honest and forthright, which is quite wonderful.
So, so looking at this, one of the biggest again, my takeaway from this is,
it's less about the security answers and more about the maturity of,
did they say, do they have a bunch of nos and
hopefully good explanations for why those are nos.
Like my favorite for some of them is like, do you do secure code practices, blah,
blah, blah.
And their answer is like, no, because we don't do that.
Like, we don't do secure coding stuff, you know,
we're like some kind of weird niche service that that's not an issue.
And so coming back to this whole CISA thing, I think if we're going to
chastise someone like ah here's what I'm gonna say,
it has to be constructive criticism.
I think that's basically my my summary of this whole show.
-- I mean,
-- I mean, I'm I'm OK with that
but I think more importantly than constructive criticism is you need,
you need like actionable real examples of things to do.
I disagree because that's not always possible because sometimes we don't
-- know yet like we
-- we and when we don't know,
say we don't know,
right? Like
that is it for example, this this whole cross a scripting thing, right?
The actionable guidance is to
use a web framework,
right? Which
I think we can all kind of agree with.
But there's more than that, it's not just use a web framework, right?
There's which web frameworks like it would be lovely if Sisa had
a document that says
if you're using these web frameworks.
Here are some best practices to avoid cross site scripting vulnerabilities.
Well,
here's a silly question is why has there never been a vendor or a service or a list of
here is a list of frameworks that are not great
and here are better replacements that are maybe ideally dropping
replacements even.
And that you should move to like essentially,
here's a list of software that is known to be kind of not great or bad.
-- And here's the better
-- solution.
I don't know that for web frameworks and I promise
-- you none of them are drop in replacements
-- well,
or maybe not necessarily drop in replacements but close enough.
So like a good example would be Apache and Engen
-- X.
-- Those are not web frameworks,
not a drop in replacement,
but there is a tool to convert your Apache config to Engen X reasonably correctly.
I would say changing web frameworks would be like saying
-- you should switch from Python to
-- Pearl. Yes.
But in some cases, that's the only answer because like using this one web framework,
it's so bad and so insecure and so poorly maintained that, that it can't,
it's like it's like the whole C versus rust argument, right?
We, we,
I think we finally learned and most people are not willing to admit it yet out loud,
but
some of us are and that is you can't secure C,
-- you
-- can't
secure
arguments
against
that, that particular talking point. It's so much fun.
Yeah.
But anyway, but here's the point.
So then Cisa should be investing in the research to figure out, like, let's
investigate web frameworks.
Let's figure out which ones are good or bad or in between or whatever, like,
yeah, no one's doing that because who's going to fund that?
-- That's not exciting
-- work and be vendor neutral and not, you know,
have referral links to get money.
Right. And that's the thing. like there's a lot of ignoring the technical
that and switching costs, there's a lot of greenfields projects of like, well, what
should I pick?
-- It's hard, it's very hard.
-- Yes.
When I pick a web server, I usually pick Apache because I know how to configure it,
I should probably make the switch to inject at
some point. But
most people don't even use web servers anymore, man.
Like when you're using, say for example, your web framework with N PM,
it's standing up a web server and then you're
just supposed to put something in front of it,
some sort of proxy
like, yeah, the world is so different and
and but here's the thing, right is let's talk about like web frameworks,
analyzing web frameworks are a great example.
Web frameworks were like super exciting and hot like a decade ago, right?
Because it was kind of a new and interesting thing.
No one talks about them anymore because there's a ton of them and you just,
it it's, it's not exciting Right.
Security is, I think one of the most notorious industries for chasing shiny objects
where the stuff we actually need to do is super boring
and you are going to get VC money to do it.
That's the reality. Something like rust
is boring
and
no venture capitalist is going to fund
like rust development.
This is where we like,
we literally need organizations like Cisa and the sovereign tech fund to fund this
stuff because it is boring and no one wants to pay for it,
right?
This is like
this is like fixing the roads, fixing roads is boring, right?
No one is key notting a conference about fixing roads, well,
-- maybe a road conference,
-- but I have a perfect example.
I literally just had
we we just had an STF call where we discussed the choices,
the rankings of the current crop projects for funding
and one of the projects that was most popular,
one of the things they want to do is document what's in the developers' heads so that
they can bring no so that they can
I
get
it
but they
-- so that they can on board new people to the project.
-- I get that 100%.
And I'm like, I was so excited when I read that because I'm like this,
this is exactly this is a sustainable long like
this is something that spending some money on.
Oh my God, the return on investment of this will be easily a factor of one.
But now the venture capital world would only fund that if you're building a device to
extract the brain from the developers and then turn it into an A I model,
-- you know, with,
-- with copyright
-- obviously. Yes.
-- But yeah, but that's the thing, right?
There's, and that's, and I keep coming back to this sort of kai
and constant improvement of
small stuff like looking at that railroads uh uh success report.
Like it was a lot of stuff like
we put up an extra sign so that when they were in a construction zone,
they knew that they had to maintain a low speed, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah,
like it's small,
but like you do enough of this and you don't
have a train going off the rails at some point.
That's just it, right? Like, like 1000 little things turn into a really big thing.
Yeah.
And eventually you don't even realize it. But suddenly you've changed the world
aspect too is by doing all these little things,
it reduces the noise and the kind of constant alarm, fatigue and stressors.
And you actually now have space and time to focus on the big things.
You
start to have strategic discussions because you can't have a strategic
discussion when the fire alarm is going off every 10 minutes
and security is nothing but fire alarms, like fire, fire after fire after fire.
Like, well, I just, this fire is
good enough. I'm going to the next one now. You know, it's not, they're never put out.
Yeah, it's small ring but probably won't catch.
Hopefully.
No, I know. And so anyway, I, I guess
we need to, we need to close this one out.
But, like, fundamentally, I think at the end of the day, all of this stuff, like
the job of SISA,
I think functionally at this point is we, we lay the foundation,
we need a foundation for doing all of this work.
And I think
a lot of the things I'm seeing
is chasing the shiny and that's not it. Like we need boring foundation work.
That is what we need more than anything in this space.
The one concern I have is this might kind of evolve, be all that they're capable of,
they might not be able to do long term
projects. They might, I, I don't know. Right.
I'm just spitballing but based on what they're doing,
I assume that's kind of what they're capable of doing.
And
-- that worries me.
-- I mean, it's certainly plausible.
I feel like though I've yet to see them talk about the fact that we need to
lay the foundation and I feel like they get
a very shiny object chasing mentality is what?
And, and maybe there's some foundation
work going on that I don't know about.
Well,
it might also be they're doing that because that's what
-- most of the market seems to want
-- that very well.
Could be too like you're right.
The market wants security people making bold ridiculous statements
with nothing backing it up and it gets lots of press,
which is traditionally the security market
anyway. Ok. Here's my happy thought.
I don't want to end on this note because I feel like I feel defeated.
The happy thought is go look at what the
sovereign tech fund is doing because holy crap,
I think they've cracked the code like
they're doing the boring, amazing work we need to do.
I'm also gonna give people a hint and it's not a hidden hint.
It's actually on their application form,
but you need to be focusing on sustainability and
making sure there's a lot of projects that seem to think
they want to get stf funding on it ongoing basis.
And that's not the point of this.
The point of this is to help people grow and stand up on their own.
All right,
I'm calling it. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you for listening.
Go to social security podcast.com. Head up the show note, Gz Podos
says podcast hashtag on Mastodon. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks everyone. Bye bye.