-- Whatever. Start the episode.
-- I'm gonna start eating popcorn again.
-- Yeah, the
-- episode start. No, you can't eat popcorn
anyway.
I'm leaving all that.
I'm leaving it all in. It's all staying
in.
Welcome to December 3rd. Everybody
says podcast door. Number three.
-- Number three.
-- Ok.
-- So,
-- actually I
felt some nightmares. This isn't an aim calendar.
I can't laugh and do this. Uh, a third of known computer security
flaws have no solution and I would argue
it's obviously much higher than that because
like the CV database, for example,
a lot of people think that CV S have to have
a security fix to go into the CV database and like,
no, no, they don't.
Uh, how do I put this nicely?
The vast majority of security flaws don't matter enough for
the project or vendor to actually actively go out and fix them.
Yeah, I think, I think that's the two sides of it.
Absolutely.
And so
the other thing is
when, uh, so known computer security flaws,
like there are lots of known computer security flaws.
Like perfect example, back in the day, the Linux,
the, the, whatever the cloud in it, stuff that, like, set up your cloud image.
Long story short
root had no password,
which was fine because you couldn't log in his route and you could su space dash.
You're rude.
And I remember seeing that and being like, oh, that's stupid. Whatever.
I better like either set a root password or disable pseudo blah, blah, blah.
And then like two years later, somebody reports it to Amazon.
Amazon reports it to Red Hat and it was an ungodly mess
because it actually mattered, right?
It was actually like a real problem for a lot of people and it got fixed.
But fundamentally, like I saw it two years earlier and was like, oh, this is stupid.
I'm just going to go set a password. I never thought to raise the alarm.
And that was actually the moment I learned the expression, if you see something,
say something, you know, like dial 911 really matters, like really super matters.
And so I suspect there's a lot of security flaws that are known to somebody,
but they didn't bother to file security flaw against the project.
There's, there's some of that I can,
I've got two great examples actually that just came up in recent,
recent history where so there was one node module named trim.
And generally speaking,
this is this is something that just takes whitespace out of strings
-- like it trims the whitespace is what you're saying,
-- right?
It's literally all it does.
And you're thinking, how does this possibly have a security issue.
Had a denial of service problem where you can give it a certain type.
They were using a regular expression that was broken. I know. I know.
Yeah, for real.
But anyway, basically what it ended up being is it was essentially in a
package and
I went to the node Upstreet or the N PM people.
-- Well,
-- because it's, it's a finished package in the sense of like,
does it trim whitespace?
Yes. Well, what else is it going to do? That's it, it trims whitespace.
-- The original
-- owner, like, didn't care.
And so it was like, ok,
we need to do something about this and eventually the NPM people took care of it,
but it, it definitely took some effort.
I mean, it was multi hours of work on part to get this sorted out,
which seems silly when you think about
it.
And so you've got an instance where you have
an upstream that either doesn't exist or doesn't care.
And likewise, there is also one where I submitted APR to the J Ruby folks
because there was, there's this thing they ship called web. It's a Ruby web server. J
Ruby contains a whole bunch of stuff from Ruby and like, they didn't even know Webre
had a problem
-- and it showed up and I'm like, you know what I'm, well, how
-- would they know?
-- Well,
-- exactly,
-- like, let's link to the show note on S bomb. Yeah.
-- Right.
And So, anyway, basically I just, I'm like, screw it.
I'm just going to send them a pull request because it's
less work than trying to even ask them if they care.
And,
and so I think,
I think it's higher than a third for sure.
And I think this is one of those instances where if people actually care,
people need to step up and do something about it.
Well, and no, I disagree.
They don't need to do something about it in the sense of they
need to fix it because that implies they're going to fix it.
People need to just step up and notify the project, file a bug.
-- Well, right. That's part of it. Exactly. That's what I'm saying.
-- Well, no, no, no.
-- But I just say do something about it makes it sound like they need to fix it.
-- No.
No, not the project me, like me. I care about Webre
all of a sudden it is my responsibility to see that to the end.
-- Or I say, I don't care whatever one or the other. Yeah.
-- Exactly. Yeah.
Either you care enough to at least tell them
and, or fix it or, yeah, fundamentally you see it, you ignore it.
Well, there's your answer. Yeah.
And then this is even more difficult now because of all
the automated scanners are flagging this crap all over the place.
And
I would bet you 95 to 99%
are in the, no one really needs the care category.
-- I'm
-- going
-- to close the episode out with this.
Do you think any of those automated scanners that are finding these things?
Make sure that they told the project or vendor about it?
They never tell them, they never do. And it's not, they don't care.
Their job is to hand you a phone book of a report to show their value.
That is their value.
Well, we'll, we'll put value in quotes.
-- But, yeah,
-- so the moral of the story is that, uh, yeah, I mean,
this is normal and it's ok.
I guess we'll see you on December 4th.