Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner on the opposite side of the spectrum.
-- Josh
-- Pressers. I mean, what spectrum is my opposite of you?
All of them. Maybe your rules about food and breakfast
compared to mine.
I mean,
I only have one rule about breakfast and that's you eat breakfast at breakfast time,
right? But what about breakfast at dinner time?
That's not breakfast time.
What happens when you fly internationally?
Then I eat whatever I want wherever I'm at.
I won't lie
like when I'm flying somewhere and I land at like 6 a.m. local time and I
don't even know what time it is because I've been awake for like 30 hours.
There is nothing that makes me happier than just like eating
a giant horrible hamburger that's like coated in Greece. It is, it is a true delight.
Hamburger
-- are nice,
-- especially when they're like extra greasy and foul.
And the best part is when you're
because obviously in an international airport terminal,
you can literally buy any food any time of day you want.
And it amuses me when at 6 a.m. I'm like
eating this gargantuan hamburger and everyone's looking at me like,
what's wrong with that person?
It's lovely.
Yeah. Anyway,
but yeah, that leads to today's show where there's a lot of binary thinking in,
in security you're either secure or not secure.
And I love how also it's not even like a sliding scale of like 0 to 1 for these people.
It's like you are either secure
and then there's everything else which is like basically a zero and you
might as well set yourself on fire and stop trying to live.
Let's set this up a little bit. So I'll put a link in the show notes.
But I basically asked a very simple question on Twitter the other day. That was,
-- this is not a simple question.
-- The question is the question I asked is simple.
The discussion that ensued was
so the all I wanted to know was
you often hear,
you know, coming off the heels of which, what's the name of the, the N PM package? I
don't, no I PC. Thank you.
Yeah,
there might be one before this gets published. I don't know.
But
so there was all this discussion around Note I PC and it amuses me because
you often hear one group of people saying you need
to pin all your dependencies and you should only upgrade,
you know, when you know it's safe,
-- which that's another discussion in itself
-- or when you know, you need to.
Sure.
And then you have another group that says, oh,
it just let it all float and let the c I'll pick it up and test it.
And all I wanted to know
was, is there data
that basically can construe
which of these two particular options from a purely security perspective?
Which one is lower risk, be it? Floating dependencies or pin dependencies?
And the discussion turned into this, like madhouse of people arguing.
You need to pin your dependencies or you're a terrible person
and pinning dependencies is dumb. Why would you do that?
-- And it was just like,
-- well,
what about the third group that pins some
-- of their dependencies but not everything and
-- that.
-- OK. That's the squishy middle. I'm OK with
What drives me nuts is
this actually kind of feeds back to that? Like what is open source?
What is the developer?
We're also talking about an N PM ecosystem where there's like literally
-- a million packages and as we're learning one point
-- 9 million.
OK.
So actually part of this now, obviously,
I didn't get any answers and the the thread became bizarre.
And so I thought there's clearly no data on this because if there was any,
someone would have come forward.
So II I put together a script to do so this is funny how this works.
Actually, just getting every N PM package name was shockingly difficult to do.
I have them. There's 1.9 million
and now as we speak, I'm it's gonna take like a week probably.
But I'm downloading all the metadata from all these packages and then
I'm going to do this analysis because I really want to know
and what I love is.
So, I mean, there are packages in there,
like my favorite to pick on is American date because it
literally converts a date from the normal format to American format
and it's like a dozen lines.
And when I looked at it, it hadn't been changed in four years. And I was like,
-- that's OK, like it's done. I,
-- I bet there's no less than 10 of those
probably.
-- But
-- the point is, I guess
I was thinking about this last night actually, what is,
what would be useful?
Let's go with the word useful metrics for a software project.
And you know, and there's i it's very difficult because
you can't look at the metrics.
You have to understand the why like has this not been updated for four years
because it's done or because the developer gave up on it and abandoned it.
We're going to figure that out once I have all this data,
I have a strong suspicion there will be more
than one white paper that comes out of this.
But that's, that's another story.
I want to set this up first before we get
too far into whatever unrelated tangent we end up on
is. So obviously, Kurt and I started discussing this like Wild Twitter thread
and the topic of security
practitioners often having strong opinions one way or the other
and it's, it's rarely anything in the middle.
It's generally speaking, you're either
100% for something or 100% against something
and compromise is difficult and rarely happens.
So I think the problem there is if you try to sit in the middle, like,
I often try to sit in the middle and try to understand it.
People at both sides yell at me, it's like get off the fence or you're wrong.
And it's like my favorite is, you know,
somebody used the term like that's not a vulnerability.
And I'm like, well, what, what exactly do you mean by vulnerability?
They're like, I'm using it in the, in the normal sense
-- of the word. And I'm like, what? No, like,
-- well,
-- ok, that one I can excuse, well,
-- no, no.
But my point is is that the people who have strong
opinions by definition have strong opinions and don't like the people
that
kind of are sitting on the fence as it were where I'm like, I want more data.
I want some facts. Like, why do you believe this? What is the grounding of your
opinion of your, is this an opinion or is this like a theory?
And, and that is
the crux of I think I,
I kept replying to people in this thread and I'm just like, I just want data,
please give me data, stop pretending your opinion is data.
I just want data,
you know what, even anecdotal data,
even anecdotal data at this point would be better than nothing.
And so for example, we have like colors dot Js and faker dot Js, right?
And here's the point. Uh Here's a good example of why anecdotal data matters.
Fact thought in the last six months,
I can only come up with three examples color dot Js Faker dot Js,
same developer and node I PC.
Well, clearly it's not that huge of a problem,
but I can only come up with three good examples.
Uh There have been a couple of others.
I don't remember them off the top of my head, but there's definitely
-- we're
-- in the, at the worst. We're in the low double digits,
I mean. Oh yeah. Yeah, it's, it's not a lot compared
to,
compared to
how many security vulnerabilities were fixed during the
last six months across the N PM ecosystem.
-- Yeah, we're going to find that out
-- probably more than 10 or
20.
I can't tell you I'm going to have a number in the very near future.
A literal actual real number. I'm very excited.
See, and this feeds into the No,
you won't because did these things get clearly identified as security fixes?
-- No, no, maybe,
-- maybe not. And what's the point?
That is another discussion because anytime you have 2 million packages,
-- uh my, my guess is the top 10% get vulnerability identifiers assigned
-- top 10%.
Try, top 1%.
-- Maybe
-- I, well, we're gonna know we're gonna find out, see this is why I love data.
Like we don't, we're guessing we're pulling this out of our butts right now.
And I think that is one of the,
the challenges when you're a very smart person
is I think oftentimes very smart people are right a lot and
sometimes they forget
that there is a difference between being right?
Because you have experience and data and being right because you think it's right,
well being right because you happen to pick,
you happen to pick heads or tails and flip the coin and be correct
and, and that that happens too for sure.
I mean, so my favorite example of this actually is
if you look at the,
there's a certain amount of security advice
going around right now about supply chains,
especially supply chains, especially how to build your software,
how to package your software, how to ship your software.
And
a surprising amount of it has zero data backing it up.
It's things smart people thought made sense.
And I remember I was talking to someone one time and I was basically like,
you're building these rules
on things you think makes sense. Like is that what we need data
to say if this is a good or vanity?
And they said, oh, we'll build the rules, then we'll look at the data.
And I'm like that is the most dangerous thing in
the world because you are going to cherry pick data
that backs up what you think is right?
As soon as you do this.
Yeah. So a quick thing, I have a bit of bad news.
If you search for node, you get 4000 plus results in the CV database.
But there's a lot of entries with like a node or a server node. You know what I mean?
And then if you search for N PM, there's only 526.
So I suspect your CV coverage of N PM is going to be
very sparse because I do know up until a few years ago,
there was like zero coverage of N PM
even back when it had over 100,000 packages. And,
and again,
I want to know this, I don't want to guess I want a real answer and
if it is only 1% and it might be, it won't shock me if it's less. Now,
that is
a horrifying thought.
Well, and that feeds into.
So, I mean, you know, now we're looking at things like statistics where OK,
so we do this like broad level overview of the N PM ecosystem and then maybe you pick,
you know,
10 packages at random and deep dive into them to
see kind of how many security fixes do they have.
Right.
And you know, and if your sample obviously 10 is not a great sample size, but you know,
at some point, you would have a sample size of 100 or 1000 or whatever,
where it would become statistically significant or you just cheat,
maybe do the top 20 or top 50
right?
And there are ways to kind of figure this out a bit.
But
I, again, I go back to this problem of,
we're trying to define something as kind of being the same.
So
like the way the CS A uses and builds our N PM app, you know,
for our main website is going to be vastly different than, you know, uh like a,
like a to use a traditional term like a.com kind of website, you know,
ecommerce,
uh whatever
uh
like
squares. Uh No, no, no. Um
Is it Shopify? I think they're big on rails, right?
Anyways uh versus, you know,
some internal app that they use to control the
toilets at a fortune 500 company or whatever,
right?
And that's part of the challenge is,
you know,
I, I hate that like,
basically what I'm trying to get across is there's like
1000 different kinds of applications in 1000 different kinds of companies
in 1000 different regulatory environments.
And we can't pretend that it's all just
a homogeneous spherical cow with a uniform density.
So what we can do is we can at least get, like you said, some data, some idea.
And I keep coming back to the fact that even if you can just
tell me the scope of the problem with one or two orders of magnitude.
That's far better than what, where we are right now.
I,
I agree 100% and I think that's one of the dangers of trying to take this very yes or no
model that we have in security.
And is when you, when you have strong opinions about something,
you will go to great lengths to justify your opinion. I mean,
like my favorite example, Kurt is when we did that show about Apple, when,
when was it when we completely hosed up the Apple copyright
-- thing? And
-- a couple of months ago, not that long ago,
I don't remember the exact details, but I remember someone it was,
was it they were using copyright against a researcher.
I don't even remember. Anyway, the point is
episode 300.
-- I remember
-- the first thing I did was trying to find the
news stories that we originally read that that backed up our views.
And then after all, I'm like, wait a minute,
even if I find them,
I'm wrong like
it doesn't matter, you know,
and that's one thing that's, I think really tough is the,
the mental ability to hold an opinion strongly but be willing to change.
So, a perfect example on a very personal level is spanking.
-- I was brought up with well spanking. That's just a thing. My mom's German.
-- Oh
man,
-- that was very normal when I was a kid
-- super normal when I had kids with my then wife,
now ex wife, she was like, I don't believe in spanking.
And I'm like, what do you mean? You don't believe in spanking?
Like, that's like not believing in black holes. It's just a thing, right?
Like sandwiches
and she's like, no, like all the studies show that spanking is, you know,
well, to add insult to injury, not only is it traumatic, it doesn't work,
right? Negative reinforcement as a training tool generally does not work.
And I'm like,
so
and so I google a bit, I'm like, oh,
yeah.
No,
you're right.
Ok. So, and I remember when my kid was about seven or 81 time at the playground and
some other kid was like, just being a, like,
right, not very well behaved and like, oh, wow.
If I behaved like that, I'd get a spanking and my kid went, what's spanking?
And I'm like, oh, ok. Right.
And I explained it to him and he's like, like, why would you hit me?
And I'm like, yeah, now that you say it like that.
Yeah.
You know.
Right.
And so, but that's the thing is like,
there's still a lot of people that think spanking is ok and normal and the thing is,
and here's the thing, like I said, I, ignoring the sort of hitting your child angle,
it doesn't work.
And that's what I find most offensive about a lot of these opinions is it's not
whether or not the opinion is morally or ethically correct or good or whatever it's,
is it like
to be blunt, is it utilitarian? Does it work?
And if it doesn't even work, it's like, well, damn it, like we need to
figure something else out.
No, I, I agree. I agree completely.
And that's where I come back to a lot of these things.
Like,
I don't care about the ethics or morality
of pinning or not pinning your dependencies.
Does it work?
And the answer is it depends on your environment
and it, but here's the thing
how many people have
like no real solid testing of their software,
the
the vast majority,
the vast vast majority.
So that means pinning
means things don't just mysteriously break.
Right. Right.
And, and look,
I will willfully acknowledge there are nonsecurity reasons
to pin software that we can understand.
But from my perspective, all I care about is
pinning versus not pinning.
What is the risk of each of those decisions?
Let me reframe the argument a bit because here's
how I view the pinning versus not pinning thing is
we have a current world state of software and my stuff.
And then there is a delta as time moves forward, right?
Every second that we move forward stuff in M PM gets updated and the world changes.
So a good example is uh uh a really good example is the chrome web browser,
the chrome web browser is like constantly updating as we all know that update button
and you're getting a delta
of from yourself to reality and
typically the smaller the delta,
the less pain it is when something breaks or you have to fix it.
And then the more delta, like,
you know,
five or six things that kind of break at the same time and
it looks like one giant problem when it's actually five separate problems.
And you know, that takes a lot of time and effort to solve, right?
Like basically let me put it this way,
it's easier to put out a small fire than like your entire house is on fire.
And so from my perspective, I don't care so much about the pinning or not pinning.
I care about
the management of that delta state that change state.
And for example,
that is why I religiously update my Apple devices and my windows desktops,
like
I at least one of them as soon as it comes out.
And for example,
we had that recent Apple Os update that of
all things broke full screen sharing in Google Chrome,
right? It affects that
it's affected a whole bunch of people at the CS A nu and here's the deal.
So, and even on my laptop, it only partially broke on my laptop,
which is super weird on my laptop.
I was able to go into settings, go into permissions and uncheck, you know,
the the screen recording feature and recheck it and then it started working.
What we have found is the only reliable way to fix this is to uninstall chrome. Reboot
uncheck. The setting like reboot reinstall chrome, reset the setting.
Like basically turn it all the way off and all the way on.
I have a funny story about that. So when I did that live stream for the CNCF,
I was gonna stream from my, my, my Macbook and I could not,
I couldn't get it to work because the streaming software that uses chrome.
Yeah, I like, I sprinted across the house to get my windows laptop at the LA.
I had like two minutes to spare and I'm like, holy God, this is ridiculous.
And here's the best part is full screen sharing
would typically work for these people in Zoom.
Zoom works fine. Safari would work.
So it was, it was straight up
weird permission
chrome. Like basically, I don't know if it's permission that you're not.
All I know is like, basically,
you have to turn it all the way off and turn it all the way on to fix it.
And so that's a great example of like you're gonna run
into that eventually and I would rather run into it soon,
document it and get it fixed.
OK? I want to rephrase this though. You say you want to find it
soon.
But if I'm running a
credit card processing facility,
I can't afford any downtime under any circumstances,
I want to find out under my own
on my own schedule.
So this is,
this actually came up on stack overflow about a decade
ago where people were asking about rebooting Linux servers.
And I said I actually intentionally reboot my Linux servers at least once a month
to make sure that they reboot.
That's it. That's, that's the only reason I reboot them.
It's not so much brought updates,
it's to reboot it and see if it actually comes back and to
do it on my time and my schedule when it's convenient for me,
like a Friday at five or whatever where I have like
48 hours to fix it if it doesn't come back,
you know,
do you remember when you were in like ext two file systems and after what,
100 days they had to be checked or something?
And I remember my server would crash
and I had, like, some ungodly amount of storage and it would take like,
six hours to check the disk.
And it's like, oh, my goodness. I should have done this over the weekend.
No, that's one of the actual reasons I picked, uh, free
nzfs was that, you know, the pool scrub stuff live. Right. Right.
But,
but
the modern files
need to be checked. Yeah.
So part of it is by, for example,
staying current running C I CD builds and trying it out,
you can break quickly and here's the thing
I, I'm gonna say you can roll back, you should be able to roll back
if you can't roll back. Holy geez.
You should probably go put that at the top of your to do list
alongside backups because I'm assuming if you can't roll back,
you probably don't have backups either.
But
my point is I want this to break on my terms, like,
kind of like I want to basically turn it off and on.
So I'm
like, if something's going to break, I'm mentally prepared for it.
I've got some, you know, time and space to deal with it and that's one aspect of this.
And so what I'm trying to say is for me,
it's less about the pinning and not pinning or partially pinning or whatever.
It's about
uh sort of trying to build that maintenance and operational
-- stuff into the system so that you don't get nasty surprises and,
-- and that's fine,
but we're off on a tangent already.
I mean,
this is one of the things I think this is really hard
to talk about because we're already not talking about security attitudes,
right? We're talking about practical reasons to not pin your software
where my original question was just,
which is, which explain the risk to me of each of these decisions. We, we don't know.
And, and I think
this is one of the things that makes it so hard is we often devolve
our conversations into places we understand and that
are completely unrelated to where we started.
And again,
I think I password guidance is one of
my favorites where Nist released password guidance,
someone did some research. It proved Nist's guidance were literally wrong.
The NIST people who did it were like, oh yeah, we just made this crap up
and then this literally said our original guidance was bad. Please do not do it.
Use this new guidance. And there are still people who will say,
-- I don't believe it.
-- Even the White House came up with their eo saying like
no more crappy passwords and no more two fa using S MS
people are still S MS two fa
-- all the way home
-- and, and not only that there are in the in the security universe,
there is an agreement about two factor S MS
I think
there are, I see many very smart people that I, I look to for advice that will say
it's, it's better than nothing.
And then there's other people that say it's worse than nothing. And I'm like,
I don't know what to think
I think
and I hate to say this but there are
specific cases where both statements are true and that,
that that could be fair too.
Like a great example is my, my, you know,
I use TD bank and they have a voice print security blah, blah, blah.
And I'm like, that's fantastic for normal people,
but there's like 300 hours of my voice recordings online.
Probably not so great for me.
I
have,
I have all the high quality because
I don't think you need high quality because this works over the phone.
Uh,
no, no, it doesn't.
-- I'm saying
-- the voice
thing works over the phone. So, like, I don't think you need high quality audio
more to the point. There was a, you know, V FX artist, uh, did a deep fake voice
where he actually cut together the guy's voice to accept the Ya
because it actually makes you accept the Ya. Like
hopefully.
And um, but he had enough recordings of the podcast.
The guy did to cut together, you know, like I
am accepting this
you
for,
you know, whatever, right?
-- Like out of sneakers, there's
-- like deep fake software now that I can take your voice,
I can dump it into the software
and then
you only need like, I, I think a
couple of hours it's no, you need,
-- you need quite
-- a
-- bit
-- depends on which phenoms and stuff, right?
There's,
there's tracks you can read where it kind of goes through all the weird noises.
-- But yeah,
-- like,
and you think I have, I have pristine tracks of you
hundreds of hours of that without me or anything else on that track.
So I'm just saying
-- I am your biggest
-- threat. We already saw. That was the lesson.
Can you remember the Russians put a deep fake of him being like, oh, you know,
what we should probably all give up and surrender.
Let's all be friends, everybody.
Right. Right.
And I mean, that's just kind of the world we live in.
-- But anyway, anyway, we're talking about security people. So
-- the P versus not P
I think part of the challenge is people are
also having this discussion and they haven't actually defined.
-- OK, let me put it this way. What do you define as pinning
-- in my opinion?
I would say it is when you hard lock your dependencies,
-- I know you can like in NP
-- ma specific version or
like specific versions,
no floating of any sort, not even the minor versions.
-- So
-- like no 2.3 point X, just 2.3 0.7 hard lock. OK.
Second question.
Does your pinning strategy involve or if you're not pinning,
does your strategy also involve keeping a copy of all those things
or do you rely on N PM js.org being available always,
-- I
-- mean, look in from the stuff I do, I just rely on N PM Js existing because I,
I'm not important.
I don't care.
But I also, I mean,
I think what you run into is the two places
people often end up is they pin their dependencies,
they never touch them again.
I'm completely guilty of this
and then they don't also don't keep copies of their stuff. So like
I'll never find this again if it disappears.
Yeah. Good luck getting that version 2.9 0.17 thing.
-- Yeah, whatever.
-- I'll just use
Google Drive with some of the dodgier drivers.
My hard work came with because remember I bought that one webcam where it's like,
go to this IP address slash and I'm like,
-- I, I chucked it through virus total. It's like clean. I'm like, ok,
-- good enough.
It's probably fine.
The other aspect is, for example, if you're talking about pinning,
are you forcing your dependencies to pin?
You can't, you don't really have a choice. So actually, you know, you can,
you can like force upgrade some of your dependencies,
things break all the time and it's a big mess.
This is my point is people talk about pinning or not pinning and it's kind of like, OK,
cool.
So that's the first level. What about the stuff below that?
And they're like, huh, what do you mean?
And it's like you can't have an opinion about pinning and not pinning.
If you actually haven't thought it through,
it's not that they have it wrong
incomplete.
It's, I mean, look, I think you,
you bring up a good point and the reality is
most of the things we do are highly complex.
And I mean, another one of my favorites are when you hear people go on and on about,
you absolutely should be signing all of your release artifacts.
And you know what I mean?
-- And like that's another one of I
-- would say now that salsa is available.
-- That's a possible, yes,
-- not salsa six door
six
star.
-- It is possible. Right. No, I, I agree. But there's still,
-- well, it's like http s
right before let's encrypt and everything I would have been like, uh,
-- whatever
-- that is not a reasonable comparison because today I can sign things,
I can give you something that's signed it.
You still have to take action to verify the signatures.
We need the ability to auto verify things.
Uh You need it like to be like a web browser where it just works
and throws up an air if it doesn't work.
Like, I mean, RP MS are my other favorite, right?
Like when I, when I install something on my Fedora system,
it verifies the signatures and if the signatures fail,
it doesn't work and then I just turn off
signature checking and install it anyway and it's fine,
right?
So,
well, no, you're right.
If I download a tar ball or whatever,
it's like uh and then I have to take additional steps to go figure out.
I mean,
I told this to someone one time.
If you had to estimate cart,
how many times have you verified the signature on a tar ball you've
-- downloaded off the internet
-- back in the olden days with open BS D.
Just total. Give me a ballpark number. A, a number. I don't want a story.
-- Just give me a
-- number, I would say even more importantly,
I gave up on this probably 15 years ago.
So you won't even give me a number.
My estimate is 55 times over the course of my entire career. I bet it's five.
I had some scripts that did it,
whatever
it was out of the open BS D ecosystem, which kind of
had more a culture of that, but more to the point I gave up on it like 15 years ago.
And so that's kind of like, I think that really proves your point that it's dead.
It's like email, it's like email encryption man.
Like you and I both gave up on P GP GP G. How many years ago
I wanted,
I
someday we need to do an episode just where I talk about how I secured my
P GP keys because it literally would take an entire episode to tell the story.
But like I'll add that to our list of shows someday.
But like
I was the biggest fan of P GP for the longest time and it
broke my heart when I had to finally acknowledge like this thing has failed.
Well, even P GP, like their email web appliance,
basically emails you a link to an HTPS site to read the message.
What is this?
So like the P GP email appliance will P GP encrypt
email outgoing if they have a P for that person,
which they almost never do.
So what they do is they email that person with a link to the to read the message,
right? Because what else are you gonna do? Right?
You need to get that email. So, but back to the pin versus not
pinning the other,
there's, there's so many dimensions to this
and some of those dimensions affect everybody and
some only affect a certain subset of people.
And most of these people aren't even aware of all the dimensions,
let alone if they are affected or not.
And they have
like a strong opinion on pinning versus not pinning.
And there's like a million,
like my favorite example of this kind of
type of argument is Blockchain where they're like,
oh blah, blah, blah, all this stuff is immutable and I'm like, cool.
That's great. That is, that is actually quite useful
and you know, and you can do like bank transactions to reverse stuff.
Ok, cool, great. So we can fix stuff. But I'm like,
what is your plan
if your Blockchain ends up with the legal data in it?
And I remember this one guy looked at me and went, what do you mean illegal data?
And I'm like, you know, like child pornography or like free Tibet now
and you're operating in China and he went,
oh, I hadn't thought about that.
It's immutable, you know,
and this guy works for like a major European energy provider where,
yeah, like,
oh, he, he had not thought about it at all, but it just hadn't occurred to him.
And the look on his face as he,
you could see him sort of mentally cogitating and he's like, he's like,
that's an awkward question. I'm like you. Yeah, it is. You know,
and,
and then he kind of walked away and didn't look very happy about it. But,
you know, I, I guess I helped anyways, there's a lot of this in pinning and, versus not
like that tweet where I'm like,
I didn't even know that this thing has a
hyphen. What is it? Hyphen hyphen install later than one week or whatever?
N PM UK.
-- Right. That's neat. I didn't know that either.
-- I think that
-- I bet you 99% of the people with opinions on pinning versus not pinning didn't
-- know.
I mean, look, I this,
this conversation has devolved into a pinning versus not fitting discussion,
which I think proves the contentiousness of it,
but I want to bring it back up to a level and just talk about the fact that
security people
are often highly opinionated about certain things. And I think
not just our lack of data, sometimes, not just our yes or no attitudes.
There's also the fact that I think
we often become tribal in many of these decisions and
it's not enough to say this is what I do.
This is why I do it. It's often do it my way or else. And that's not helpful either.
I think it's worse than that in that again.
It's ok to have a strong opinion
but
you need to be open to new data and new theories and change.
And a lot of these people are not.
It's uh I hate to bring this up but it's almost
like identity politics where literally these people self identify with.
I am a member of the passwords must change every 90 days tribe
and like the rest of you will burn in hell for not doing it.
Like because they are literally people within that basically say that like,
come on, we've met them.
Like there are literally people where this is like a core part of their like i
identity
-- and that is not healthy at all. You know, same thing with sports teams.
-- No, I, I agree.
You know,
that's a good point too.
You have to be mindful that you don't
turn these sort of things into your identity because
it can create problems.
-- Let's
-- say, well,
this is like your brand of tires being part of your identity or it's like,
it's a technical thing that
can and will change at some point like how many people have you met?
But then Cloud is some bs fa
quote unquote,
it's just another person's computer and when you try and talk to them about the,
oh, there's still a handful. Yeah.
And when you try and talk to them about the economics of it or the speed of it or the,
you know, the utility, the commodification of it and, and they're just like la, la,
you know, they just don't want to hear it, you know, on premises or dead.
I used to feel this way about uh,
Linux versus Windows and Mac of like Linux is the best and, and I,
I made Linux part of my identity and
I mean, I won't, I won't lie.
Like I, I open source definitely shaped who I am as a person.
But I do also feel like now I've, I've made some efforts to
distance my personal identity with
Linux and open source specifically because I found it, it, it,
it became damaging, especially to certain relationships because like,
I knew people who use windows and I was always like, oh, windows sucks.
You shouldn't use windows and they finally like, like, it's their freaking,
it's how their feet in their family, like, who cares?
You know,
I mean, I had sort of like, I was big into Linux since the age of 17,
but I also had like an M CS C and Windows NT four back in 2000 or 99 or something long,
long time ago.
And I remember people
would actually be kind of horrified in a way where they're like,
but you wrote the Linux Administrative of Security Guard and I'm like, yeah, I,
yeah, I did because like, Linux is awesome and they're like,
and you have an M CS E and I'm like, yeah, I freaking love Windows NT four.
The thing is awesome.
And they're like, but what, like,
you could just see them mentally melting down like that robot in Star Trek.
You know, like I am telling you a lie, you know, and they just, like,
the logic circuits are melting and it's just like, I, I just,
I watched that episode the other day. I watch Star Trek a lot.
It's on one of the local TV stations plays it in the evenings
and he had an episode with Nomad where Kirk outsmarts the computer.
I love that one. It's the space probe.
He outsmarts a lot of computers in that show. Actually, I should,
I should make note of it sometime and look into it. But
because he also what he outsmarts land
does he blow Landre up? Um,
the, the, the return of the icons. Uh,
anyway, whatever it doesn't matter.
-- Um, he does outsmart a lot of computers.
-- I think a lot of this boils down to his people.
Not only have this as a strong opinion and are unwilling to change their opinion.
Like, literally when the people who came up with this are, you know,
recanting like nist in the passwords.
Not only are they unwilling to, you know, change their mind,
but they then make it part of their kind of who they are.
And it just
like there are people I will no longer engage with
because
they just have some like,
literally,
they just start arguing about how terrible Mac Os and windows are, and I'm like,
I run them on my desktop and, like, yeah, I like them. Yeah.
And, and, and I think, I think that's it. That's what we'll go out on.
It's just the simple fact of, like,
don't let this kind of stuff be part of your identity.
It's, it's silly,
you know, it's, it's ok as a job and a career but not, it's not a lifestyle.
Yeah.
And I think that's the key to not,
not turning your security decisions into these very binary.
Yes or no
is if it's part of your identity,
there's no room. There's no wiggle room.
Well, you can't be wrong because then your identity is wrong.
Exactly.
-- 100
-- percent. Let's be blunt. Everybody's identity is wrong in at least one way.
Anyway.
All right, I'm gonna end it. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to open source security podcast.com.
Head up the show note, Suzie Pond do Os podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.