I here
record
-- December 17th. What
-- is vulnerability
response? That's a great question.
I have no idea. No,
that's what I do like every day, all day.
No, no, this is a great topic actually in all seriousness.
So the way I would describe this is if you have a
product or a service and it used to just be a product,
but now we have services.
What happens is
there are going to be security vulnerabilities in your stuff.
Be it again, a service or a product, something you wrote.
Well,
and it might be your stuff or it might be stuff that you pulled
in from somewhere else or it might be stuff you're running on top of
-- or an interaction,
-- right? There's basically anything.
And now the number one rule here that I
don't think everyone understands all the time but is,
is imperative is
if you ship it, you support it.
So just because I downloaded something off github doesn't
mean I can say it's not my problem.
It is my problem because I'm
using it and I'm shipping it.
And that's part of the beauty of having access to this open
source library is you get to make that trade off of,
we can build it in house and maintain it poorly or we
can download it and not maintain it at all and bite that,
you know, take that risk on.
-- So
-- what, what, what happens is obviously there's a security vulnerability
and maybe there's a CV E ID, maybe it doesn't, whatever. What do you do?
If you get a report from somewhere? It could be from a security researcher.
It could be from a bug bounty, it could
-- from a security scanner, I would
-- say at a minimum,
the two biggest things you try to do,
you push it upstream and you notify the user community.
Well, if you, if you can push it upstream, right,
which essentially is a polite way of saying pull the fire alarm.
I mean, no, no, no, no, no, no.
-- You should never say pull the fire alarm because there are no, no,
-- no, I mean, ok,
that's a bad now.
But what I'm trying to say is you make it known to the people who need to know.
Yeah, you tell people what they need to know. Absolutely. And I like to
on the side of just like obnoxiously full,
disclosing all of the information because the
reality is if you hold something back,
a someone who cares can find it
and what if, if you're hiding important details. That's a really big story.
Here's what I find super offensive about that
whole full versus not full disclosure thing is
if some one individual or team found that security flaw, then by definition,
it is findable and other people can do it.
Therefore, it cannot be.
I accept that in this universe, there are probably answers we cannot find,
you know, to the fundamental, you know, truth of physics or whatever.
And those are just things that cannot be found.
But by definition, if somebody found a security flaw,
somebody else can find that security flaw.
And we've seen this happen, you know, with the hardware vulnerabilities where
a team found it. And then a week later, independent discovery of it happened,
you know,
the same thing happened in science with
a whole bunch of radioactive related discovery,
you know, prior to world war, I, I, where the whole thing just took off.
So there's, if anyone listening,
-- nosy, I believe this phenomenon has a name. I've tried to find it and I
-- can't.
Well, independent discovery was my understanding.
I'm sure it has some fancier name than that. That's boring.
But, yeah, this happens all the time where like a great example is calculus, right?
You had
-- Leans and Newton both inventing calculus at the same time.
-- Ah,
multiple discovery. What's it called?
It's called multiple discovery or simultaneous invention.
-- Well, that's a stupid name. I want it to have a cool name.
-- Sorry.
Let's call it the secrecy paradox. That's its new name. OK.
The secrecy paradox. That's what I'm calling it.
There's no such thing as secrecy. That's the paradox.
But
anyway, anyway, like, yeah, this is, this is,
I've seen this so many times where one person reports a security vulnerability
and then like,
three days later someone else reports it and I remember there was one
time I thought it was the same person trying to mess with me
and, and finally I'm like, wait a minute, are you this guy? And they're like,
no, who's that? I'm like, holy crap.
And it was some, like, crazy, complicated security issue.
And I'm like, how did two people figure this out at the same time?
It was, it was insane. Yeah.
-- No,
-- by definition, if people can find these things,
then by definition people can find these things.
Yeah.
And I guess my advice for anyone doing this kind of work is just always err on the
side of openness because I think the historical mindset
and security was to err on the side of secrecy
and I don't think that has done anyone any favors and I am completely confident
-- that that attitude has held our industry back for decades.
-- Absolutely.
-- Yeah.
-- I mean, it's a hard problem
but whatever, whatever.
And I guess the one other thing while I don't think it is strictly imperative to do it.
Get a cve, I, if you can because it makes everyone else's life just so much easier.
Yeah.
I'm currently dealing with a major project where I want to get an inventory of all
security vulnerabilities that they fixed over the last year or two and they can't,
because they don't see v
and the response is, well,
it's in our bug tracker and sometimes there's a security tag,
but probably not always.
-- And I'm like, well, ok, there's my
-- answer.
I mean, right. The answer is you're bad at this. Right. That's the answer.
That's anyway. Anyway, what's the date today?
Uh. Right. Cool. All right.
That wraps up December 17th onto December 18th.