Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner and
I'm actually not really sure what this is today. Uh Josh
-- Reser,
-- it could be thought crime. Thought crime's pretty nonspecifi.
-- II, I dare say we both.
-- Well, I don't want to imply that a crime took place here.
-- Well,
-- we're both engaging in thought crime on a regular basis. I'm sure.
So,
-- what was that?
-- It's a beer
that seems appropriate.
I don't know how your first week of 2022 is gone, but I'm having a beer.
It's been a treat. I, uh,
that's good. That means editing. You later will be a, a joyful experience for me.
-- Well,
-- this is why I'm having the beer now and I didn't have it an hour ago
anyway.
It's actually when, for what it's worth when this episode comes out,
it will be the second full week of 2022.
So
the future us hopefully are having a much better week than we are at the moment.
I don't want to be all doom and gloom,
but with the way the charts look in school actually going back in tomorrow.
Yeah. That
too.
I hate to say this on to a happier topic.
A me
so first the disclaimer,
we're not going to go into the the gory details of this because
there's a whole bunch of gory details that actually are not all that germane
to what happened and the outfall or the consequences of it.
And I think the outfall and the consequences are the most interesting in many ways.
Yep. Yep.
Alright. Just spit it out. What happened.
A developer called Merrick is responsible for color dot Js and uh faker dot Js,
which are two very, very popular javascript packages.
Uh color dot Js does colors on the console,
which personally I don't get because I like my consoles.
-- Monochromatic colors
-- are awesome man.
-- Come on, I get that,
-- but I'm old and I like monochromatic whatever.
I love my color and faker dot Js is arguably quite useful. It generates fake data
for like testing stuff, so addresses names,
pets, whatever.
Right. Right.
Let's go with the simplified version of this.
He got fed up with fortune 500 companies and whatnot, you know,
strongly benefiting from this.
And so apparently at some point he tried to do sort
of software as a service version of faker dot Js,
you know, so essentially have it as a service.
Cool,
except then a large company literally just like Lock stock and barrel ripped
and stole it and did it as a service as a software.
Obviously more successful because a company versus an individual,
typically the company wins, you know, they have more marketing, more
sales, blah, blah, blah.
Right.
I'm sorry. That's just how it is. So basically,
let's go with you through a tantrum
and he
released new versions of faker Js and color dot Js version 6.6 0.6.
0,
and
I don't know if he did anything malicious in fake or Js, but in color dot Js,
he actually added an infinite loop like
and it's really obvious it's called infinite,
it says infinite loop
and it just loops infinitely.
And he basically broke the code and then the faker
dot Js and color dot Js Repos on github,
he basically wiped them. Now, the color dot Js Repo has been
restored. The faker dot Js Repo as of this time is still like wiped
and github
has apparently locked him out of his account and N
PM has apparently locked him out of his account and both
N PM has restored color dot Js and faker dot Js so that they kind of work now
because they both have faker dot Js had,
I think it was about 2500 and change dependent packages and
color dot Js had around it was 3100 something dependent packages,
right?
And I'll be curious to see if that number drops in the next week or two. I doubt it.
Uh
probably not like a handful but nothing meaningful.
It's not like half of them are going to move
to chalk or whatever other color library there is.
And so,
yeah, I mean, what's interesting to me is there's,
there's several dimensions to this.
Right. There's like, sort of the moral, ethical thing.
There's the practical and effective issue, there's
sort of the business, the community, the, well,
and the trust issue that especially the trust in upstream.
-- So, I guess where do you want to start? I want to
-- start by talking about P
ah, yeah.
Right. Ok.
Karen. It is.
If
any of our viewers familiar with Penny Arcade,
the whole P thing is not going to be a surprise.
We have listeners, not, not viewers. All right.
So there's a comic, I'm going to put in the show notes and
this is really old, like, it's from 2005
and
there's a web comic called Penny Arcade that will say is
a bit on the edgy side would be a polite description and, and even as they've aged,
-- they've maintained their just absurdity, which I love
-- his online anonymity.
An asshole cartoon is like,
-- I mean,
-- that, that's one of the best by far.
-- People are going to be studying that in 1000 years.
-- Oh, well, hopefully.
But, yes, yes, absolutely.
There's some amazing penny arcade comics that I, I adore. And anyway,
so what happened was
Will Wright is the person behind
like simcity and spo and Sim Ant and all those kind of weird simulation,
man. I totally forgot about Sim An.
Yeah. Right.
There's a bunch of them and they're,
they're amazing games and why we put the games in quotes.
Right.
So, anyways
Farm was a game. It was awesome. It was the best.
When Will Wright announced Four Penny Arcade created this
comic and I'm just gonna read it because it's,
it, I think it captures
an
aspect of this. I mean, we're just gonna read it. So this is Will Wright speaking
in uh in the Penny Arcade comic, right? It says, so this is my new game pee.
Basically,
I'm going to pee on every one of you and you're going to love every second of it.
That's my design
and you decide what you want to do with the pee. We're not telling you how to enjoy it.
I leave that up to you guys.
You're going to create your own unique experiences with my pee.
You're all going to do something different. Maybe I'll get some pee in your hair.
How will you react to that?
This guy,
he might get some pee in his eye that's completely different from pee in your hair.
And that's exciting to me as a game designer
and then it shows a crowd screaming will write, please pee on us.
Now, here's why I think this is relevant to the conversation.
Not only because I get to say the word pee over and over again,
but
I think from the context of kind of open source.
We like to always think of open source as
an entity in the universe
and we are kind of consuming it.
But I think open source is an experience
and it's up to each individual
company or person or whatever as to how they engage in that experience.
And in the context of this conversation,
if you're using, say N PM and all you're doing is sucking in latest as fast as you can.
What happened today is kind of what's gonna happen.
Yeah.
Well, and somebody's pointed out,
you know what if he'd put in like an RM hyphen RF slash star in there?
Yeah. Right.
Because I mean, you're executing this code, it can, it could wipe your hard drive,
it could
run a crypto miner, it could
whatever, all sorts of bad.
I mean, and that's,
I think part of the conversation but not something I want to focus on.
I think it's more so just the aspect of
in the open source universe,
things are going to happen that are outside of your control.
And if you're not doing anything about that,
eventually your stuff is going to break, it's going to light on fire and collapse.
This is, this speaks to the efficiency argument that I made some notes on.
So why did open source win? Well, open source one
because efficiency
and I don't mean just the efficiency of, oh, you know,
we need a web library that does this horrifically, oh,
horrifically complicated thing,
like downloading a web page which like if you do this from scratch and trust me,
you'll, it's complicated.
Curl is well worth the price of admission, which is zero.
And so
not only do you get,
like you get an amazing library that is
actively maintained has new features for well free.
And
it's more than that I remember back in the day I had
uh Linux box
and I had a copy of the Linux source code on it
because well, I had to, how else did I upgrade my Linux kernel?
And,
and I had to upgrade my Linux kernel because my
machine would crash on average every 15 to 20 minutes.
And then actually,
it started only crashing every couple of hours because
the uh the Ethernet drivers got a lot better,
but I had to maintain a copy of the source code locally.
For the simple reason is I,
I couldn't download all of it every time an update came out.
So I would download, you know, the dips. Remember they would
your 2490
600 bod, my friend had 2400 bod. So for my friend, it was actually faster
to compile a kernel on my system and then download the binary to his system.
This is right. You told this story on a fast episode, you'd use your bicycles to,
these aren't even bicycles, these are shoes full of sharp. Rocks.
Right.
Anyway, the point is
I, I had to keep a copy of the look of the source code because I just,
I literally didn't have the patience and time to
download it new every time because it took hours.
And
that has changed bandwidth.
I mean, right now,
the slowest internet I use is basically my cell phone
which is in the tens of megabits per second.
The Wi Fi at my house is somewhere in the 2
to 300 depending on where you are in the house.
And if you're wired in, it's like 970
megabits per second, right? It's basically gigabit.
And
so the world changed and
here's the thing,
even if I store one bit of data now I have to worry about backing it up.
I have to worry about deleting it. I have to worry about the safety of it.
I have to worry about the security of it.
Whereas if I have a build system that's just like go
suck down all this data every single time you run.
Yeah. Who cares anymore?
Uh Yeah. Yeah. Actually it's funny you say that.
So
a
acco the company I work for has these, we have these two tools called Sift and Gripe,
right? And Sift is a S bomb generator. Gripe is a vulnerability scanner.
And
every now and then we,
we kind of look at our download statistics and whatnot and
like they're obviously kind of bananas but at the same time.
It's like how many of these are just, you know, like C I pipelines literally red,
downloading it every time they need it.
-- And the answer is probably a lot,
-- probably 99%.
And, and part of it too is, is that's possible now because
like, I used to host
on a dedicated 14 4 dial up line.
Yeah,
I, I did the same thing. I,
I actually, I think I was on 2088 back in the day. But yeah, yeah,
I couldn't afford to rent a server
and you needed a dedicated phone line. You needed a
de,
you had to pay the ISP way more for a dedicated connection.
Like 300 bucks a month.
Well, I worked for the IP. So I think I got it for less than 100
and it was slip. No, we had PPP
at the one I was at.
Oh, well, yeah, I had P pe eventually but like that was the dream. I started with slip.
But anyways,
the point is like it hosting a megabyte of data
and serving it to a couple 100 people a month.
Not a day, not an hour, not a minute, but a month.
Used to be a major endeavor.
And then things like sourceforge
came along and well, unfortunately, created out.
But sourceforge was amazing because it's like, wait, wait, wait, wait,
I can release this 100 or 200 kilobyte tar ball
and like, you'll just host it and give it away for free for me.
Yeah.
And now, like github
complains slightly once you hit a 50 megabyte per file. And I think
the repos max out at a couple of gigs before they tell you to spend more money.
They won't tell you exactly where
that's one of their, like, secret metrics.
But, yeah, something like that.
So,
it's possible now, right, like, 20 years ago,
it would not have been possible to download
this stuff 20,000 times because the server hosting,
it would have died.
And there was no centralized services like the, well, there were,
but there were things like C
A the comprehensive Pearl archive network and I mean,
it was actually comprehensive because there was just so little.
So I, I, before we go on, I want to tell a great story about C
A
is
I remember
I would run CP pan to install.
Usually it was in my SQL module because that's
like the one thing I seem to use every time
and
every now and then C
A would decide the version of Pearl I had was too old
and it would download this Pearl source code and start building it.
And it's like, what are you doing? You psychopathic program?
And it was like, but that's just that, that, that
explains Pearl. I think better than anything else possibly could.
And back in the day this
like when you run brew on a modern Mac laptop on a modern internet feed and
Brew decides to update itself and download and
compile several 100 megabytes of source code.
That's fine on a modern laptop.
Except the problem is that modern laptop is equivalent to
pretty much all the compute power in North America.
Back in the nineties
building, Pearl
-- was like a 3.5 hour endeavor
-- building Linux kernel. I mean,
I remember having to build up DH CP DNS.
Anyway. Anyway, we're up on a business.
The point is the world has fundamentally changed where
the efficiency of open source, the fact that it's hosted for free,
the fact that you can just download it every time
and you don't even have to keep a local copy.
You don't even
bother to keep a local cash because who cares? Oh, it's an extra seven seconds.
Well, we care now because everything broke
well and it would have broke
in most cases.
This is for most people anyways because they also specify,
get me the latest version.
And that's the other thing, right? Software didn't used to change much.
Like I remember buying software on CD and getting updates quarterly or yearly and,
and that was fine.
Now you build us.
I'm making air quotes here,
a simple web app and it's thousands of dependencies that are getting updated
on average every couple of minutes
because thousands of dependencies being updated,
you know, every couple of days works out to
quite quick.
Statistically speaking, it's gonna be a lot.
And so if you pin dependencies, upgrading becomes basically impossible.
So you just have it say go latest and you hope it doesn't break.
And I mean, this is the world we live in now.
You know, this is the every like this is the ocean
and
changing it.
Ok.
Well, no, no, no, it's not though.
So here's where I think we get into this, that funny comic
is,
this is part of the treating open sources as
an experience versus open source is a thing.
So the experience you're talking about is just running latest
and accepting the fact that things are going to break.
Generally things don't break because the
maintainer decided to purposely break them.
Usually things break because
maybe an api changed or maybe the feature was added or taken away.
Oh, we just had one where they did a a semantic non major change,
-- but they made a major breaking change,
-- right?
It happens, right? It happens.
So you can decide
you're going to take the attitude of like what
Google does where when we talked to Dan Lawrence,
what it feels like seven years ago right now.
And I think it was a couple of months,
but
it was
a situation where Google is
pulling in all the source code and basically blessing it and saying this is
this is what you can use,
go and use it.
-- But that requires a degree of competency and operational maintenance that
-- Oh,
yeah.
Yeah. Yeah.
Like seven companies can do.
No, I absolutely.
And I mean,
this is the, the, but however I will say the options you have now are limited is
you can
say we can only use certain versions and now there's a
lot of tools that let you do stuff like that today.
I don't remember them off the top of my head, but like they exist,
you don't have to be Googled to do it.
-- You can go find some vendors and work with
-- them. Actually.
Not that much money and, and have all the artifacts copied and compiled and,
and arguably, I mean, that's what Red Hat did.
You just pay a company like
-- hat for this,
-- basically.
Well, you can't though, because Red Hat has a very limited supply.
Well, I mean, for stuff that Red Hat ships, you can do it.
You can just pay Red Hat and they,
but, yeah, but I think the world is way bigger than that now.
Like, if you're doing work in N PM,
you can't say,
uh, here's a list of N PM things I trust. Like that's just, that's not practical.
-- Yeah. Limit yourself to what rell ate shifts. Good luck. Yeah.
-- Right.
Right.
I don't even know if they have note in Brell anymore.
But
you, you kind of get the idea. Right. And, and so you,
you,
you've created this situation where now you have
to decide what is the open source experience?
I want my developers to have and
I think Wild West is cheapest and easiest, but things are gonna break.
-- I would say
-- it's not so much Wild West. I would say it's
whatever the defaults are,
that's what 99% of people will end up with because
they don't even know that something else is possible.
And I, I think that's
a viable excuse when we're talking about the general public.
But I think when you're talking about, say in enterprise,
they're never going to run the defaults.
They're going to tailor it to do exactly what they want it to do.
Yeah.
-- But
-- there's a ton of SM BS and consultant and, well, the thing you got to remember,
consultants are consultants going to do the right thing or do the cheap thing,
they're going to do what's best for them,
like whatever that means.
I, no, and here's the thing
is
the, one of the few arguments is that you don't have to use this stuff.
Like you can opt out like it's, it's open source. It's free.
You don't have to go use it.
The flip side to this argument though is that
no longer works because of the dependency chains?
-- No,
-- I, I agree.
I think saying you don't have to use open source is I,
I don't even know how you can make that argument.
Well, I don't mean that you have to or don't have to use open source, but, I mean,
specific packages, like, let's say you're a die hard chalk fan.
I think it's called chalk and you don't want to use Color dot Js.
Yeah. Too bad.
The minute you pull in a dependency, some,
one of those things is going to be in a chain where color dot Js gets yanked in,
I mean. Sure. But, right.
Do you really care about what a dependency of
a dependency of a dependency is pulling in?
Well, that's what I'm saying is even if you do care, you can't do, you can't, it,
it's too bad.
Sure. Right.
And so
that, that argument that you kind of get to pick and choose what open source you use
doesn't work in this world of 1000 or 10,000 whatever deep dependency chains.
I, I don't think anyone cares though either. I think here's the thing
if I'm writing an application and I say I want to use colors instead of chalk,
I'm gonna do that,
but it's something else I pull in uses chalk instead.
I don't care. Why would I care?
Uh I think there were some people with respect to what was it called? Log logging.
Something in Java for
Log
for Jay is a completely different story, I think.
And again, you're not gonna say, oh, I want to use this other log
library even though there isn't another one in Java. But like, you know what I mean?
You just, you're solving a problem with the dependency.
What exists beneath the dependency. You don't care.
Well, and that's what I mean is, it's, even if you did care,
you can't do anything about
it. And that, that's,
yeah, that's where we are.
You know, it's, it's like my car.
I bought a car and I'm sure there are parts in there from
some company I've never heard of who probably has a CEO that has,
you know, a worldview that I would disagree strongly with.
Well,
too bad. I don't get to know where my fasteners came from.
-- I
-- mean, and you don't care, like you bought a car, you didn't buy fasteners.
Yeah, open
source one because of efficiency
and, and this stuff when it works is horrifically amazingly efficient,
especially compared to, you know, the old school, close source style of behavior.
And what also gets me is just
like the accessibility in the sense of you can just grab it and go
and start building
and, and, you know, we've discussed this before where
you don't need to be an engineer.
You don't have to have certification and you can build something
like an amazing website that 10 billion people use by next Thursday.
And do we want to live in the world of boring, safe,
slow progression or in this insane world of, you know, where we are now?
I mean, look, everyone wants
the amazing speed
and efficiency we have today and I think
this is no
car crashes.
Well, I mean.
Yeah, no one wants to have car crashes but they're, they're gonna happen.
I mean,
but again, this comes back to,
it's up to you to make decisions about what you want your experience to be. Like,
if you want more safety than you get just running current,
you can do that. The options exist but they're not free.
-- They're gonna cost you money and
-- I'm gonna,
I'm gonna slightly disagree on. But
again, I think most people don't even know that that's a possibility.
And I agree with that. I think a lot. Well, they're gonna find out
but
the issue in github
with the number of people complaining and, you know,
being told to go to issue number 285, which is the sort of the, the first one
is Yeah. No, clearly like
it's, there's well and, and it,
what gets me is I keep coming back to, you know, this sort of boiling the ocean slash
like if a developer makes a breaking change in a popular open source package,
like the one person on hacker news pointed out
the amount of time and money spent
having this fire drill with this thing before N PM reverted the change and fixed it.
If all that money was collected up and paid to this guy,
he probably could have retired,
right?
You know,
I make the same argument in my log for J thing where it's like
by enabling this thing by default and forcing people to turn it off,
to make it safe, that
effort to not break backwards compatibility ended up costing
Lord knows how many millions of people hours and,
and dollars to, to deal with this thing when it finally blew up
and how many more features have been enabled by
default that are going to have the same outcome
like, well, all of them.
Yep. I think part of it is
this speaks to companies like Red Hat with their business model of.
We will take a bunch of open source and make it.
I don't want to use the word safe but make it more palatable.
But I don't know that that's gonna work in ecosystems like N PM where it's just
uh there's literally millions of packages.
I don't think it's the right way to think about this anymore.
Anyway, I think that was the attitude you needed
back in the day
because
you had things like Sun versus
Linux. And so
would say look at us, we're the, the big friendly company, we're safe.
You can come here and you don't have to worry about that scary open source over.
I mean, even something as simple as
I go through a company. So that when the for example, the faker dot js github
repo is still wiped like he basically as far as I can tell,
deleted the repo and then recreated it from scratch with one commit.
So all the commit history, all the issues, everything is gone.
You. Right.
And
there's like a million forks of it. Cool.
And I, you know, linked to one in the global security database entry.
But,
you know, you got to figure out which fork do you want to use as a trustworthy, blah,
blah, blah, blah, blah.
Right.
Sure.
And so
I,
I can't help but feel like maybe what we need to do
is just encourage people to add a layer of caching because honestly,
data storage is not super expensive anymore.
It's
caching wouldn't have mattered in this instance.
-- No,
-- no, no,
but caching would because I'd still have a copy
of the old one that before it got wiped.
But the old ones are still there. They're all on N PM.
Well, yeah, because N PM did a good job,
right?
But the problem is N PM had to roll it back because everybody specifies used latest
and so N PM had to take the action of removing version 6.6 0.6
and flipping it back to version 1.4 0.2 or something.
-- But I think that
-- in this case, N PM did the right thing for free and that's all
and kudos to them.
But what I'm saying is a company that does that as like
a matter of habit and maybe provides like a proxy interface.
So that kind of
you have all of this for sure. Not just
hopefully N PM does the right thing. Hopefully github does the right thing.
-- I
-- mean, I don't find that a cash would have mattered here.
I think here's, here's the problem is.
So let's say you have a system in place where you have a cash
and you have some sort of approval system.
-- So the new version of faker comes out, I, I don't
-- care, even if it's approved,
-- I just want to have copies of the old
-- data but the copies of the old data already exist.
Kurt, they're all on N PM.
They do. Those weren't deleted. What got deleted was github. Right?
But what happens next time if this is something outside of N PM
-- with an ecosystem that isn't as responsible?
-- I mean,
OK, but how, how are you going to cash it? Like, what are you gonna do?
Well, like,
like J frog and artifacts and all those things, do it just
when you download it, keep a copy of it.
Well, no, and I agree.
I think that's valuable,
but I'm just pointing out like in this particular instance,
what you're suggesting is irrelevant.
Well, the problem is that these, these programs assume,
ah, you know what it is, the, the, not the programs,
the language is basically assume that nothing will sort of
ever go malicious or disappear or otherwise kind of go wonky
and hang on a sec. Speaking of which there's a tweet that I uh
that's kind of relevant to this. It's from here we go, here we go.
From Daniel Stenberg. You know, you might have heard of him.
Um,
the Pike
World website has gone AWOL
straight up
Pior dot IO is, is gone.
Yeah. Well, no, it's back now.
Yeah, it came back.
I don't, I don't know if anyone said why it, it disappeared and came back.
It might have been, uh,
it might have been related to this.
-- It might have been something completely unrelated. We don't know
-- it's back.
But uh but that's the point is like, are we going to learn anything from this?
Probably not.
This is the kind of thing where, you know, well, I'll pick on CV,
CV E has a database with URL S
and this is before they removed all the dead stuff. Like
all of sun.com, half the links are still broken
a lot.
Yeah.
And some of that's like, and some of them and worse,
I know half the links are broken
and I know at least a big chunk of the,
the links that quote unquote do work actually go
to web pages without the information that you want.
So for example, there's one CN A
where all their links go to a marketing web page now
and the data is gone.
-- That's fine. Everything's fine,
-- you know,
and, and so that's what I say with,
with this sort of caching layer of at least you have a
copy of the data that was what you supposedly trust and used
and you can sort of start to recover from there.
And it's, it's going to be horrifically difficult and painful.
Like these people are showing all these things like, oh,
if you edit this dot whatever file you can like, overwrite the,
the color dot Js name and like redirect it to this
other directory with a copy of the thing where it works,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
And it's like, oh my God, this is, this is horrible,
like asking, you know, tens of thousands of people to do that.
No, the correct answer is N PM did the right thing and just boof, we magicked.
It works again.
That's definitely the right way to
good job N PM.
But like I said, there's ecosystems where stuff is not as mature and not as
like this happened over a weekend.
-- It always happens on the weekend, man. You
-- know what?
Yeah, actually it has, there's been a lot of Bad Fridays recently.
It's just the way it is.
Yeah, I don't know what the solution is but I,
no, I got the solution. It's, it's, it's peeing on things like it's the comic.
I, I legitimately, I've been thinking about this all day
and
I not peeing. Um
Anyway,
yes.
So,
-- II I truly believe though we're
-- professionals. Folks don't try this at home.
That's right.
If you're getting advice from us, I'm so sorry.
-- Where did it all go wrong? You know what
-- the worst thing is? Our advice probably is.
-- Statistically better than most.
-- I'm,
you're probably right anyway. But, but in all seriousness, I think
it is incorrect to think of open source as a collection of problems and solutions.
And
-- just to
-- use the label open source,
like,
I'm sorry, have you? Like, for example, there's Linus
Torvalds
and then there's the open BS D people
and they're both open source. But
like,
you know, like a sea slug
and a blue whale are both animals
and, and that's another problem. But I think fundamentally
this is where
you have to decide what open source means to you. And it could be a case of, I am an
un unwitting consumer of this
and I'm along for the ride and what happens, happens and that's the way to,
there's nothing wrong with that.
There are legitimate reasons to just say I'm going to run latest,
I'm going to stay up to date and I know things will break and that's ok.
That's life.
Well, but that also supposes that these people have some control over it.
You know, there's, I,
I know a lot of people running a product or service that they kind of have to use or,
or even legislated to use and it's, you know, it's terrible.
I mean,
but that's, that's a, that's a different kind of problem. Right?
When you're, when you're being told you have to do something
that's not an experience anymore. Right.
Well, it's an experience in the sense that jail is an experience.
-- It's like you're gonna go through this and you're going to do this this time.
-- I don't,
you know, that's not what we're talking about.
Well, no, no, no, but I'm saying it's, yeah. No, you're right.
It's where you're,
it's fundamentally different.
A
man,
you have the ability to make decisions and choices and no choice is a choice.
And I think sometimes we forget that and in the context of,
of the open source universe.
And
I mean, this is the freaking open source security podcast for crying out loud.
You know, it's time,
it's about time we earned. It
is
like this is, this is the reality, it is up to you
to decide what your open source experience is going to be.
And I think to date for the vast majority of us,
our open source experience has been that of an unwitting passenger
on a bus careening down the hill.
You know, it's funny, on a related note,
I've been watching a lot of videos on um
backup power supplies for houses and tying in,
you know, the, the cutover switches and automated ones and so on.
And I've decided consciously not to do it because
the number of power outages here are is,
it's in the single digits per year and like one
every time it happens, you're like, man, I wish I had that backup.
Um
But I also realized no, I have laptops and a cell phone.
So it's actually not that bad but,
but looking at it, you know,
yeah, people generally choose the default when it comes to electricity.
That is, they pay their provider and they get electricity most of the time.
And yeah,
unless you spend multiple thousands of dollars to
buy a power generator and a bunch of,
you know, fancy wiring and automated,
automated cutover switches and blah, blah, blah, blah.
I looked at it one time and you're basically anything under 20 grand
you're going to have problems with
like it is a crazy investment.
Basically anything under five grand and you might as well
just buy a generator and plug your fridge into it.
-- I mean,
-- and that is an option.
Like there's no
nothing wrong with that
-- unless you're not at home when it happens.
-- I mean, that
that is,
yes,
-- it is.
-- It is.
But, but the point is it's, it's, that's fine in the, you know,
the power generating world is generally quite mature and,
and places that have problems with power
generally know they have problems with power
and maybe that's the problem here is a lot of people using open source,
don't realize that there are any problems because it has
worked so well and so efficient for so long.
But quite literally like how often does, what happened this weekend, ha
or this week or whatever happened? Well,
-- this year, the last six months,
-- it's, it's like again,
it's in the single digits across an ecosystem of
-- tens of millions of packages and developers
-- and,
and in all seriousness, I would not be shocked
if, for the rest of the year, nothing much happens and if
nothing drastic changes because everyone's like e it's good enough, you know,
-- even
-- simpler.
I will bet a reasonably large sum of money but more closed
source companies will go bankrupt and
their software will stop being supported entirely
than, you know, open source developers who decide to delete their repos
and, and do shenanigans.
I mean,
that's not even a bet. That's just,
that's reality like that.
That feels like when people predict the future and
their prediction is just like literally following the trend line
-- to where it's going, you know.
-- Yes, it's like I predict it will be
actually,
it's a bad prediction because it's actually not supposed to be that cold tomorrow.
But yeah,
I predict
it will still be winter tomorrow,
not even in the middle of January. I think it's a safe bet.
And, and so anyway, OK, we're, we're at and out of time here and I, I feel like we've,
we've gone off into some silly places.
But I think fundamentally at the end of the day, we, we have 22 choices,
we either get to be a
passenger
on this great open
source experiment
or
we get to start making our own choices and, and we get to
decide what our open source experience is going to be and like to date,
we're mostly passengers,
maybe you'll stay that way. There's nothing wrong with that.
But if you don't want to keep being a passenger,
like the solution isn't to complain about open source or
to yell at M PM or to yell at github,
the solution is to figure it out and, and make it your own.
I would say even better than that.
There,
there's options that will hopefully involve sort
of next generation open source companies.
What Red hat did for Linux 20 years ago,
hopefully somebody looks at kind of what's going on
and does something a bit, you know,
so like there's various cloud companies that
are sort of strip mining open source currently
and, you know, very popular with it,
but hopefully, maybe there's some next generation companies
that do some
really cool things that also add to the sustainability of the ecosystem.
And I think that's a big part of it, right? Is that
it, it is, is that ecosystem sustainability and,
and here's the best part about that ecosystem sustainability is
most of these open source software authors will keep doing it no matter what.
So
we don't actually need, you know, billions of dollars to fund this and keep it going.
Um Which is fascinating because I don't know if you read that FTC
statement where they basically said the FTC is aware that this sort of reliance
on open source that's not funded is a problem and we're going to
do something about it and it's not clear what they're going to do.
I assume it involves congressional hearings and
stern words. But the point is
this
system already works amazingly well,
with no care and feeding realistically from major companies.
Well, and look, I mean, this is probably a topic for a whole another show but the, the,
the government will say
getting involved and I'll put that in quotes, scares the bejesus out of me
because they don't understand what's going on.
There's, there's literally no way you can fix a system. You don't understand.
Part of the problem is there's millions of different things going on
and
you know, like even just looking at N PM versus
well, C pan is still around and kicking, which kind of blows my mind.
C pan will never die. No. Pearl, sadly will never die.
I wish it kind of would like no offense. I loved Pearl. I used Pearl, but it is time
to move on. Like I don't speak Latin. That's ok.
-- I bet a frightening amount of infrastructure still runs on top of
-- Pearl.
This is true. Yeah.
No, you're right.
We need to call this one man.
I,
we should definitely talk about government intervention
and open source at some point.
Don't, you cannot use the term government intervention because we just,
-- I believe your country just finished one of those and it did not end
-- well.
Anyway. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone. For listening. Go to open source
security podcast.com. Hit up the show note, Suzy Pound
O says podcast hashtag
hit us up on social media. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too, everybody stay warm. Thanks. Bye.
Thanks, everyone. Bye bye.