Hello and welcome to episode 100 and six
of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
How are you doing, Kurt?
-- I'm doing really well.
-- Well, that's cool.
That's cool. I, I hear data is the new oil. Huh?
Yeah, pretty much.
Or possibly toxic waste.
Oily rags.
I like what doctor
said
about his comparison to Mark Zuckerberg's Empire is
a pile of oily rags in the garage.
Are
we talking about data in oily rags?
Well, I mean, Facebook is just a giant. Well,
actually I was, I was about to say Facebook is a giant data breach waiting to happen.
But no, that's not true because it already has happened. It's just
the companies that
conducted the data breaches paid for access to the data.
So it's technically not a data breach. They're a customer.
It's a good racket man.
Yeah.
You know, like uh somebody was pointing out that, yeah, I mean, it
is interesting that we arbitrarily um
define like, oh, a data breach is bad but hey,
selling all that information to some third party who then may sell it on.
That's fine. Um,
this actually came up, they were talking about, um,
Canadian and US border security and how
the US, of course, would like certain information, uh,
on Canadians from the Canadian government.
And of course, the guy was saying, you know,
once we give this information to the US government,
we have no control over what happens to it
or what is done with it.
Right. Good, bad and different storage, whatever.
So we need to be careful with that because, you know, once you give it away it's gone,
like you can't get
out, you can't control it.
And that's how I feel very much about, you know, linkedin and Facebook is
I've tried to minimize what I put in those things,
but I know other people that have like
-- literally dumped their lives into it.
-- Oh man, some people are crazy. I agree.
Well, it's also worth noting the real reason kind of this came up is
there was another fitness app
that
had an incident
-- and
-- again,
not an incident.
It's just, you know, they collect all this data and they didn't secure it very well.
Yeah, that's true. That's true. And, and basically the issue is that
if you look at some of this fitness tracker data and you
see like someone running circles in the middle of the desert,
-- that's probably a military base, for example.
-- Right.
Well, and what's more interesting is like there's enough correlation,
these things are accurate enough now that like you can correlate
which building they're coming in and going out of and,
you know, so they had cases.
Yeah, of like these Dutch intelligence officers jogging from, like,
work to their house, which, I mean, good for them for staying in shape but
maybe not so good for, like, recording all of this and then
giving it to some random, well,
not really random but giving it to a third
party website that may or may not protect it,
may or may not sell it.
Who knows? Right.
Right. Right. Oh, serious, because I've been thinking about bring your own device
and traditionally, I thought about bringing your own device in the context of like,
I want to bring my own phone and check my email from it.
And that was kind of traditionally how we think it would bring your own device.
But now, no, that's wrong. Like a person wearing a fitness tracker.
Well, they've brought their own device to work now
they're not going to interface it to the work network most likely. But
for example, it is tracking
where they are throughout the day
to, uh, you know, pretty reasonable degree of accuracy.
And
that information,
for example,
could be used to correlate what meetings or when they
go to meetings or when they go on lunch,
who else in the building they're talking to, you know,
all sorts of interesting things from a privacy aspect, especially if you want to,
you know, especially if it's an advanced persistent threat where somebody is,
like, actually targeting that person or that company.
Right. Right.
And so, I mean, I remember back in the day, remember the Furby, the original Furby,
you know, the NSA banned it because the furby, uh,
it learned by recording snippets of language and
then playing them back and mingling them together,
you know. And so
the Ns A's view on that is, well,
it's a recording device so it's not allowed on the premises which,
you know, everybody's like, oh, you're so paranoid, you're so crazy.
And now it's like, well
that Amazon Alexa,
that emailed out a chunk of conversation to a random contact in the ladies
address book. It's kind of like, oh. Right.
Hm. Yeah.
Yeah.
So I'm, I'm really beginning to wonder about this whole,
bring your own device to work.
Like, you know,
it's gonna have to be like prisons where like all
the phones get locked up when you go in,
-- in a little cabinet or whatever. No,
-- no, it's not. And, and this
is,
people aren't going to put up with that.
Right. Right. No one's no one's going to do that.
This is something I think about a lot.
And actually you and I were discussing on signal about this earlier is
we, you know,
the saying today is data is the new oil where people viewed all this data
as some vast resource that they can mine and extract value out of and,
and I feel like
data is nuclear waste
where we think it's keeping us warm,
but the reality is it's slowly killing us and we don't even realize it.
And, and I feel like
we, we talk about like bring your own device and, and what's going to happen,
what's the future of this?
And II,
I have a very strong suspicion
that
the only solution is going to be regulation. Like GDPR is a great example of this
and
what people track and what they do
is going to be regulated at some point because let's face it,
these companies are never going to do it right on their own.
I'm, I'm totally comfortable saying that
the really fundamental problem though is for a lot of these devices to have value.
They have to do things that are
intrusive from a privacy perspective to a degree. Yes.
Well,
but like my cell phone has to talk to base stations and
let them know where it is so I can receive incoming calls.
Yes. You know,
my fitness tracker,
it has to track my heart rate because that's the whole point of the damn thing.
You know,
ideally, you know,
especially if it's like a jogging related biker or whatever thing, you know,
I really do want it to track my location to
a high degree of accuracy because then I can correlate
my movement speed with my heart rate with, you know, that part was uphill,
that part was downhill,
you know.
So by definition,
that level of detail is that's a lot of data that's potentially dangerous
and, and there's just no way around it.
Well, let me rephrase, there would be in theory a way around it, you know,
having the device, keep it locally and only put it on your
thing.
Of
course, that's
out of the
question.
That's out of the question. I mean,
no, it
won't happen. It would be a disaster.
Right. It's,
I,
and I see some of this happening with IOT
where they're talking about edge computing and it's more,
obviously, it's not for privacy concerns.
It's more for just,
um,
for example, coalescing the amount of data being sent back because, you know,
you might have some remote site
that has a really slow link or, you know,
you just don't want to be sending all the data back all the time.
It's just like it's still 25 degrees inside.
Ok. Now it's 25.5.
Right. You don't need a temperature measure every five seconds.
Just tell me when it changes or
when you catch fire or whatever.
But
yeah, I,
but I think the real thing is, is that, well, it's like testing and driving. Right.
We've, we've been railing against, you know, oh, you shouldn't text and drive,
you shouldn't watch movies or play video games while you're driving and
that ship has sailed. It's done. People have decided they're gonna do that.
Despite the penalties and fines
and the reality is like, yeah,
outside of very few environments, people are not going to give up their,
their cell phone, their smartphone, their smartwatch, their fitness tracker,
their,
and I don't think we should expect them to,
outside
of a very few
constrained corner cases, like, say maximum security prisons,
people that work there.
That's,
that's about
it.
That's different.
I think that the most important thing to consider in all this and,
and the thing that I really think about a lot is that
it is easy
to say this is bad and we shouldn't do this and we shouldn't track it.
But like you said,
people want the data
and texting and driving is a great example. Everyone knows it's terrible for them.
Everyone still does it.
The solution though wasn't to make people stop texting and driving.
The solution was to make people stop driving,
which is a non intuitive solution to the problem.
Because when humans were trying to address this,
the primary means of addressing it wasn't
saying let's just stop letting people drive.
The solution was how can we make people stop texting and driving? Right.
Which is totally wrong. I feel like all this.
Exactly. And we can't
and all this data we have is exactly the same story we can't say, oh, Facebook quit,
quit tracking on my data because look it, it's,
it's totally their empire of oily rags and they're getting 1 to $2
a year from every user and they aren't going to stop doing that.
Right.
And so the question is, how do you solve these problems going forward
in unique ways
that don't involve anything from the past
because whatever we've done in the past doesn't
-- work and it isn't going to work no matter how much we want
-- it
to.
Not even that, it doesn't work.
It's just, it doesn't apply to this newer version of reality.
You know, it's, it's like bringing sharp rocks to
-- like a race car track,
-- right?
-- Like, throw them at the cars.
-- Yes. But, yeah, I mean, the world is
like, I've now gotten rid. I'm down to one server in my house and it's a Raspberry pi,
you know, I've, I've gotten rid of all my desktops.
My rule now is phone, first tablet, second
laptop. If it has to be a laptop. Like, I'm
not this week, but next, next week I will actually,
my goal is actually to spend an entire week working off my phone
and my tablet if I have to and not allowing myself to touch one of my laptops
and I think it'll actually work.
Are you going to use a keyboard of some sort?
Oh, yeah. Good Lord. Yes.
Yeah.
Keyboard.
I'm not insane.
Yeah. With,
without a keyboard. That sounds
super painful. But I mean, it looks like I should really, it shouldn't be that bad.
-- That's
-- cool, man.
Yeah. So I, I don't know.
I,
part of me wonders if we'll just end up redefining the
problem like privacy and what is privacy so that the,
you know,
yeah, it just doesn't exist anymore. All that data we have about you. That's,
that's just no, it's like my credit card.
I, I used to be really concerned about the security of my credit card.
Then I hired a local contractor to do something at the house
and he takes credit card as payment.
And what he does is he took my credit card physically from me.
I thought he was going to like,
whip it through like a phone stripe thing or square or whatever.
No, he like, puts it down his clipboard, puts the, the triplicate carbon paper form,
receipt thing over it
and like buffs it with his pen to get the imprint of the number.
And I'm kind of like, oh, that's kind of old school whatever. And
then he flips my card over and writes down the CV V code.
Yep. Yep.
And I'm like, that's really not what's supposed to happen but you know what?
Who cares
-- exactly. That's exactly right. Who cares?
-- I kept an eye on my credit card statement.
If he's planning to use it for nefarious things. He is apparently patient
and yeah,
he, he isn't going to and
this is something I think about sometimes because when you
and I were growing up there was no Facebook,
there was no anything right.
We had email. That was cool.
And now every single young person has
a million horribly inappropriate but not Facebook,
-- but
-- just
right.
They all have terribly inappropriate pictures of
themselves plastered all over the internet.
Right. And they all have it.
If you don't have it, you're a weirdo and
your
pictures
in them.
I
was reading
somebody was pointing out,
especially with facial recognition becoming better and better.
It's going to be really hard in the future for, you know, spies, false identities.
Like
it's going to become increasingly hard because there's that,
you know,
where, where are you? I mean, I guess we'll have to use the Amish.
Like they're the only people without Facebook profiles reliably.
Uh
Actually, so it's funny you mentioned that there was,
there was a book I read a long time ago called Project Mince Meat.
And it was about this operation during World War Two where the
allies hid documents on a body and dumped it in the water.
And one of the things they actually did
is they gave the the fake person
a history in a back story and they like had,
they had one of the people pretend to write
letters to and from other people as this guy
and like they did all this work to give
them kind of fake backgrounds and I had a suspicion
that it isn't going to be harder to be a spy. It just changes the dynamic of it.
And in a lot of ways it might actually get easier because now if
you're able to create these fake profiles and keep them going for a while,
you have
an immense tool you can use and say, look, I'm not a spy.
See, I've got Facebook going back 23 years
and they're like, oh, crap,
the problem being that they,
they pull up some picture of you with a different name attached to it
or the computer does,
-- you know?
-- That is true. Actually, that is a very good point.
And, and that's the thing, like we, we already have those systems.
Well, China, for example, is, you know, working very hard to,
to deploy that system to catch criminals
at train stations on the street, you know, uh,
the cops with the augmented reality glasses.
So, yeah.
Uh yeah, I, I think it will definitely, I mean, just everything will change
but just like everything has fundamentally changed over the last 2050 100 years.
I'm going to hope we don't view China as our Bell weather for privacy.
Right.
Well, like I said, I, I think privacy,
I think the problem might be solved by redefining the problem and,
and kind of to some degree, defining it away
-- to a degree.
-- I do think you're right.
I, I have a suspicion. You're correct
to a degree though.
I think there's still some of the problems you look at some of the things like what,
what Facebook
has done.
And
I think it's safe to say nobody wants to live in that world.
-- Right. Where,
-- where you can
get a choice on this.
We do.
I, I think we do right where
the, the, the ability of Facebook to target people and what they're doing with it is.
-- But
-- we've had that
question
with choice point and with all these other companies that, you know, collect
information on people for marketing purposes like that,
that's been a thing now for decades,
right? So,
uh like soaps on afternoon TV,
you know, aimed at housewives.
Uh I knew a guy that was working for a start up. This is like 1520 years ago
that was based on your,
uh it was a for a set top box.
So they would know what you were watching and when you were
watching it and kind of how you were watching it like volume and
if your channel surfing and stuff and based on that, they were,
they were able to determine who was watching quite reliably, like male, female,
approximate age,
things like that. They, they couldn't
surprise
me at all,
you know.
So there's just the reality is especially for marketing,
there's just too much value there potentially for like,
not, well, what's the old phrase?
You know, uh like half my marketing money is wasted. I just don't know which half
right.
And so, you know, if you can increase
click through or customer interaction rates by even single digits
that for most companies is a huge amount of money.
You know, I was at a music festival on the,
on the weekend that was sponsored by a real estate developer, you know,
for some new housing development on a fake lake or whatever.
And it's like if they sell even one
more house because of that sponsored music festival,
they'll
totally break even.
Oh, I'm sure
I have no doubt.
Definitely.
But, but I, I guess here's where
my, my thinking keeps coming back to
regulation though
is
if we leave this up to the market,
it will not solve itself because the market doesn't want it to solve itself.
Well,
the majority of the market doesn't want to solve it because the
majority of the market wants to make money off of it.
Right.
And the people that do want to solve it are, are generally trying to apply sort of
old timey thinking
like
GDPR is a great example.
You have to protect the data, you have to delete it if they ask, you have to, you know,
these are things that
are, it's the thinking of 1020 years ago
-- and,
-- and some of it makes sense, but I agree.
Are they going to protect the data they'll try? Are we still going to have breaches?
Absolutely
right.
PC ID, like every major credit card breach has been at a PC I complaint company.
Yes,
I agree with that. I agree with that. 100%. But I think some of the,
the fundamentals behind GDPR are not a terrible thing,
that's for sure.
Right.
I agree 100% with that. Right. I have no doubt.
But let me ask you this.
Do you think GDPR will fundamentally actually protect people's privacy and data?
No,
exactly.
It, not, not in the way it exists today.
But here, here is what I'm hoping GDPR has the effect of,
I'm hoping things like GDPR make people understand what's
happening because now when there's a data breach,
you have to tell people.
And so when people start getting emails up the wazoo
because their data has been stolen by who knows who is 700,000 times,
they might start saying hang on here, what's the deal? Right?
And so I think that has potential.
I think some of the ways GDPR wants to anonymize certain data has potential.
I mean, a great example is
everybody has
tons and tons of logs from people using their website, right?
And the way GDPR basically says is you can track this, but you can't track who it is.
If you are able to track who it is, you need to then be able to
honor or request of somebody to remove it.
You know,
that was, that's my understanding and that's one of the
problems with GDR is everybody's got a different understanding of it.
Yes. Yes, indeed.
So my understanding,
we can still try it. We just have to be willing to remove it if somebody asks.
Right. Well, that, that's part of it.
There's also storage of a personal identifiable information.
There's,
there's like a million things and whatever it
doesn't really matter because like we said,
it fundamentally isn't going to make a difference by itself.
My hope is it's just the first step in a long path
to having some semblance of, of sensible data privacy in the universe which
I don't know what that's going to look like. I'm not going to pretend I do.
But what I do know is the way a lot of these organizations are treating
data
is terrifying today because like I said,
it's not oil, it's, it's like spent nuclear fuel.
Well, there, I mean, when there's no downside to pollution, guess what?
-- Right. People pollute. Right.
-- Oh, that's perfect.
That's a perfect analogy, man, because
you're right.
Like Facebook is literally like throwing spent nuclear fuel into the street
and they're like, not my problem doesn't matter. Right. And it isn't their problem.
Well, it literally isn't their problem until like,
the Cambridge Analytica scandal happens.
And
-- as far as I know
-- there's been out there.
Exactly.
-- Yeah. Nothing of substance has occurred.
-- Right. Right. Exactly
is going to occur. Right.
-- Like what Zuckerberg showed up, he testified before Congress,
-- didn't,
he also refuse to testify before the British
-- House of, I
-- don't know if he ever went.
I know he was, he was saying he wouldn't go and he sent somebody else.
I don't know if that happened or not.
But, but the point is right
this,
they know they don't have to care.
They knew they just had to tough it out for a little while
and we would stop caring because the next circus story would appear,
which is we're about 20 deep at this point
and
nobody even remembers who came, which Analytica is or why we care.
Pretty much.
Speaking of new things. So
Bor it's a uh
uh it's an online um
Cryptocurrency exchange thing.
Oh, good.
Well, let me just read it.
Uh This is not today today but anyways
earlier today at approximately 0000 UTC Bancor experienced a security breach.
We take this incident very seriously, which is
probably
-- true
-- because
the actual
UT
C
every resource to resolving it,
getting the network back online and tracking down the criminals involved.
So yeah, they actually had to shut down their stuff and their
anyways, uh the details of the breach are still being investigated,
but we wanted to update the community with the facts that we have so far,
a wallet used to upgrade some smart contracts was compromised.
So for those of you that don't know some cryptocurrencies uh like Ethereum,
for example, support the idea of smart contracts.
And so a really simple example of a smart contract would be
Josh agrees to sell me his couch for 100 crypto coins
and so we put a smart contract that basically says that, that says essentially,
you know, he will sell me his couch for 100 crypto coins.
When I take receipt of the couch poop, the money goes to his, you know, wallet
end of story,
right?
And it's, you know,
it's an IOT couch pretty much. Yes. Exactly. Yeah. Who's it?
It does, it has, um, but sensing technology
so it knows who's sitting on it.
And um,
so yeah, so patent that
probably already is.
But in the Blockchain,
yeah,
smart contracts can obviously contain flaws because they're kind of
software and software is kind of prone to flaws.
Ok. No, it's more important than that though.
Smart contracts are almost all turn complete.
And if you have a turn complete smart contract, there is like by definition,
an infinite number of security flaws in your smart contract system.
Well, the halting problem and the will is actually execute and
it cannot be secured.
Yeah.
And,
and more to the point like business logic is
messy enough with courts to help enforce it.
When it goes sideways with smart contracts, you generally
don't have that option right now because it's gone, it's gone.
So anyways,
um,
they did manage to snake about a million
bucks worth of some Cryptocurrency called NPXS uh
about 25,000
Ethereum, which is about $12.5 million
and 3.2 million BNT. That's the
bor one worth about 10 million.
So the BNT they could obviously freeze,
which they did.
However,
uh the other two are like gone,
right? Because like that's how cryptocurrencies work. It's like
while it went to this wallet and it's gone.
Now, what they are trying to do is,
is work with other exchanges to essentially make it harder
for whoever has control of those coins to,
uh spend them to, you know, tumble, like to essentially clean and wash them and so on
and
you know, depending on
how many people are willing to help them with this, that may or may not work.
But what I find really fascinating is that,
you know, this was an attack
against a Cryptocurrency against an exchange using
like the Cryptocurrency itself, its capabilities,
the wallet and the smart contracts,
not like
this is what it sounds like.
You know, it doesn't sound like they broke into the website or that they fished,
you know, a senior admin and got a password and you know, whatever, right?
This was an actual
flaw within the,
the Cryptocurrency and its smart contracts and all that stuff itself.
Ok?
I mean, this isn't the first time this kind of happened though,
didn't Ethereum have this problem where they had to
-- actually fork the Blockchain and
-- that was no,
what happened there is they, the dow the distribute autonomous
organization, whatever that is called,
had
these, this implementation of smart contracts.
And they're like, well, that's how the dow is going to work.
You know, people can vote on what the dow does and blah, blah, blah,
and we'll never roll it back. It'll just keep moving forwards.
And of course, somebody clever found a flaw in the smart contract and, like,
sucked down like all the monies.
So, of course, they're like, well, yeah, remember how we said we would never like,
roll this back and fork it.
That's what exactly what we're doing.
So they did that and they essentially hard fork Ethereum. So the one stream
you have the stolen money situation and the other stream, the clean stream, you,
you rolled back before that and well,
tough,
right? That's just how that worked.
But what's interesting to me is, I mean,
this was obviously like you said, these smart contracts are turing complete,
right? There's been well, a great example. Crypto kitties,
right? Have you heard of crypto kitties?
I have no idea what you're
-- talking.
-- This is so stupid. It's true.
-- So
-- sweet. Crypto
kitties are
digital cats. It's a, it's a,
it's a Cryptocurrency.
Uh And the premise is,
is you have these adorable little cats that are like different colors,
different shapes, they have different abilities and powers
and you breed them together.
Essentially you do financial transactions to breed them together and stuff to
make more crypto kitties and you collect them and it's like trading cards
and you can get special powers and stuff and obviously you can
spend real money on this and so on and so forth and,
you know, I mean, that's the whole point of these things, right?
Is that you have this incredibly complicated
thing called Blockchain. And then on top of that, you're slapping a currency.
So we're already into like two extremely complicated levels of technology.
And then on top of that, yeah, you slap on t
complete smart contracts
which also conveniently
enough in many cases,
do not have the ability to be. Um
what's the word I want to use
to be like
uh replaced or superseded or negated? Like once they exist, they exist, you can't,
I mean, that would defeat the purpose of them, right? If you could,
-- that would be part of them
-- in any way.
I mean, you can update so in some of these ecosystems,
you can update the smart contract and sort of,
you know, we're not going to use the old one anymore, right?
The old one, all the transactions that went through it are valid, but
that old contract can no longer be used.
-- I
-- mean, I'm, I'm sure there could be ways to accomplish that if you really wanted to,
but I I'm not aware of any of that due today.
It's
more to the point.
Even if you have that capability,
you still have the problem of a bunch of like broken smart contracts,
fooling around waiting to be exploited.
You know, we're back to the software problem of yay,
we can patch security fixes and ship out updates.
Great. Awesome. Everything's still on fire.
But with no, with Cryptocurrency,
you can't ship out updates in many instances
because if you have to change the fundamental work
-- of the Cryptocurrency,
-- well,
what I meant was replacing these flawed smart contracts with
newer smart contracts so that you only get exploited once.
Right? And then you replace the smart contract with the smarter one,
but then you're back into whack a mole territory,
right? And that's, that's not how you win a game.
I hate smart contracts.
I, I think the, the idea in theory is great, but in reality, I,
I don't see smart contracts working anytime soon.
I think it'll work.
This is another one of those places we need like a fundamental breakthrough in
just technology.
Well, I think what will happen is smart contracts will work,
especially within more sort of private controlled Blockchain.
So for example, you could have,
um like Walmart has a Blockchain for food safety
and they could have smart contracts executing within there.
The difference being is, you know,
they have a very good idea of who their suppliers are and who
they're dealing with.
And if somebody dicks around with their smart contracts, you know,
they're going to sue them in real life or whatever.
Right. Right.
And, and that's, that's very different because in a lot of instances, I think the,
the selling point of Cryptocurrency is the
-- anonymous nature
-- and that's something I think
you're conflating is Blockchain with cryptocurrencies.
Yes.
Cryptocurrencies are a very big example currently of how we're using blockchains.
But I've been doing some research and there's like
a ton of real world blockchains and products,
like the Swedish government using their language.
It's about
Cryptocurrency,
like,
well, I mean, I guess the good news is, what is it?
Half of all cryptocurrencies fail in the first four months.
So, you know, with that kind of death rate, hopefully things will get better,
I guess.
No, no, it won't.
Oh, man, I don't even know what to say to Dan. I guess part of me isn't surprised.
And another part of me says
why
just anyway,
whatever, whatever it doesn't matter.
All right, man, I think, I think we should get ready to call it.
You got any, you got any parting thoughts,
cash
under the mattress.
It's probably your best bet at this point.
No, you don't earn interest on cash, buy gold, right?
Gold,
gold keeps up with inflation. Generally it's a better investment.
There we go.
So anyway, if you're going to bury, bury anything, don't bury cash, bury gold.
There.
We can remember where you, please don't do that and don't, don't listen,
don't listen to us, please.
You just put it in the Blockchain and then you'll be able to find it later.
But
anyway.
Very good. All right, cool.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Please don't use our terrible advice at the end,
if you want to contact us and tell us how dumb we are,
you can do so with the Pound Os S Podcast.
Hashtag We have a link to social media and our Facebook group on
Security podcast.com.
We'll have show notes and all that fun stuff there and if nothing else,
Kurt have a fabulous rest of your day.
-- You too.
-- Thanks.