Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Pressers.
All right. So I'm going to give some backstory in this one. We have a guest today.
We have Emile, who is the co founder and head of Data Science at
Debrecht. But this episode I think has been
more than six months in the making where Debrecht is doing some really
interesting things and I'll let Emile talk about that in a moment,
but every time we schedule is like something
ridiculous happened that prevented him from appearing.
So Emil, I'm so pleased that you're finally here. Welcome to the show.
-- Thank you,
-- Josh and Kurt.
Yeah,
it's been a long time in the making and I
really look forward to having this talk to you guys.
Yeah.
So I'm Emil and one of the actually not a co founder from the beginning,
but one of the earliest employees, it's actually quite recent.
I was acknowledged the co founder. So I'm happy about presenting that today as well.
What I do at the BRIC
is usually work a lot with all our data.
We do a lot of data collection in terms of open source vulnerabilities and a
lot of other interesting data in regards to all open source in the world.
In a short presentation. The BRIC
T is a software composition analysis tool
that's looking to
solve some challenges within open source management. Looking at
how you work with open source,
both from an intake uh perspective and how you understand what you're using and find
opportunities where you can possibly contribute back to
the open source you're using as well.
Nice.
And you are a Swedish company. Yes.
Yeah. So a start up based in
Mal, it's very close to Denmark
Mal
actually. Uh so I can actually see uh Copenhagen outside my window here.
Awesome.
That's exciting.
OK. OK. So let's just jump right in.
So the, the real reason I'm so excited to talk to Die
Bricht and this is a pain point,
Kurt and I have complained about at length and constantly is all of
the vulnerability databases that exist today are
these artisanal hand curated data sources.
And De
Brecht is taking a completely different view of
this and you're doing some amazing things.
So tell us what you're doing and why I'm so excited. Yeah.
So yeah, I'm really happy that you're excited about this. I'm too.
So what we're doing is we're trying to automate the collection
of vulnerabilities in a different way than looking at manually curated databases
and looking at those databases.
It takes a lot of work to maintain and analyze and understand vulnerabilities and
how they contextualized in different environments.
So what we are doing instead is that we're trying to
automatically with a lot of machine learning,
find vulnerabilities straight in the code in the
sources of the open source in the world.
So looking at for instance,
commits and the code changes and the raw code itself issues pull request
in different open source projects
and trying to map what is potentially security related or not.
And this has a couple of advantages compared to
the normal way of doing it with manual analysis,
public disclosure through NVD or something like that
is that we are,
our vulnerabilities are really close to the source to
the code and we can quite easily map out
if you, for instance, are using that code in both a static or a dynamic way,
which is quite cool.
-- That's
-- amazing.
So looking at, I usually like to think of it like this like of course, you know that
-- machine learning is not perfect
-- always.
That's not what I've been told, machine learning.
-- Does it all the only thing better is Blockchain?
-- Right.
Yeah, of course. Yeah, we should, we should try to incorporate that here as well.
No,
but uh yeah, we, we have a,
we have a quite high performing algorithm like the overall performance
is that we have an F one measure of about 85%.
What does, what does an F one measure mean, can you tell us?
So it's the, it's the harmonic mean between the recall and the precision.
So the precision is looking at the true positive rate.
So of the predictions, how many of those are true positives?
And that's about 8780 88% right now.
So that's quite cool.
That's crazy.
Yeah, it's better than most people.
-- It's
-- way better than people.
Yeah, that's really, really high.
We have and we realized when we experimented with different models, we,
we got that position when we aggregated all the different data sources,
like looking at both with N LP at the commit messages and the pull requests,
looking at the statistical properties of commits, how many lines were changing in
what type of files it was,
was the code shown in that commit and so on and also looking at the actual code itself.
But with that high performance, we, when we look at all the commits
in all the open source projects, we get quite a lot of false positives still. But
I think what we're doing here is
that we're collecting vulnerabilities that are really,
really easy and nice to contextualize to the software that you're using.
So
if you look at normal vulnerabilities that the ones
that you find in advisories such as NVD,
we know that those are actual vulnerabilities,
but the false positives are not in terms
of their vulnerabilities or not because we know that
the false positive rate comes from
whether you're using
that dependency, you may have mapped that wrong.
It's whether you're using the vulnerable code,
if it's only used during tests, if it's used during run time in an environment,
that is,
that makes you susceptible to that vulnerable
or not.
But mapping whether you're actually using a vulnerability
from those normal types of vulnerabilities is really,
really hard
because they're quite far from the code.
And, but looking at where we have analyzed the code itself and found
vulnerabilities that the risk is
rather that
you,
they may not be vulnerable vulnerabilities at
all because we have classified them wrong.
But
we know that you are 100% using that code that we have classified as a vulnerability.
So it's a completely other approach in terms
of how you view security and open source,
I'd say
I love this. I mean, this is one of my pet peeves of source composition analysis is
every single one I've seen today
just takes kind of like the stupid approach of you ship it you're vulnerable.
Whereas
a lot of these open source libraries do a lot
of things and you might only need one method.
-- So that's ah
-- that's so cool.
It's quite a fun challenge to work with both, both in terms of like,
yeah, but looking at both the machine learning parts and
the analysis of the code because then you really get to
dig deep into how different languages work like most
languages aren't maybe no languages built for static analysis but
but but,
but most language like most common languages are terrible in
in static analysis
such as Python or
and javascript. So looking at like dynamic runtime analysis rather
and what is actually called in, in production
and
analyzing that this is way more efficient there
than simply
mapping out to
the
-- dependency files or, or just looking at the static code.
-- OK.
So let me, let me understand this. You're saying
that
Dri
is, is watching the running application.
Do you watch it in production or do you watch it
during test runs or I guess how are you doing that?
So like currently we are, we're looking statically only
but we,
but we're working together with uh with some friends
of ours in the northern parts of Sweden,
not elastic search
but elastic,
quite close name there.
We are building out the functionality to do run time monitoring. Nice.
So then we will that we will use both in uh test environments to look at.
For for instance, we have this small plug in already for pi test
where we trace the full test graph
and we can map if you're calling a vulnerable functionality or not.
Oh Cool. But that of course, then depends on your, on your test coverage. So
right,
but we, we, but then again,
this will also work in a runtime
environment where we can monitor different functionalities
that we deem to be vulnerable and whether they are called or not.
So 11 thing I'm curious with this.
So it sounds like you're, you're trying to automate both the,
the finding of the,
let's call them the base flaws, right? So somebody makes a commit, makes a whoopsie.
But then you're also trying to automate the is this application this composed of,
you know, 1000 open source libraries
actually using this in a vulnerable way?
-- Yeah.
-- So exactly that can vary quite a lot in difficulty
for the simple cases where
you maybe have an injection type of vulnerability as an SQL injection.
Those are usually quite compartmentalized into maybe one
single function within that particular open source library.
And then we can map if you're using that function
is that if that function is ever called either statically,
for instance,
we are doing that with java or dynamically
during a run time environment where you can
install one of our plugins
later on than when it, when it's finished.
But install this plug in and we will monitor
whether that function is ever called or not.
And and when it's called, we will,
you will get uh you will get to know that in our tool and you can
make decisions accordingly to actually handle that risk.
Oh, that seems actually really self evident
now that you say no seriously like it, that you monitor your system for
what it does. And does it use some known vulnerable issue?
And then flake it and I've never heard anybody do that before,
which now I'm kind of embarrassed. I didn't think of it
when
we did this exercise a while ago internally
with our security team where we tried to think
of what are the different ways to reason
about false positives within vulnerabilities in open source.
And we actually divided it into four levels where most of
the tools are still at level one where you can,
where you simply incorrectly map vulnerabilities
to dependencies or create inaccurate S bombs
-- because we've never seen that happen before.
-- No, of course not.
We actually map all our ourselves and our competitors
in only in that regard.
It's quite interesting to look at how it differs so
much depending on the software that you're benchmarking on or
the language that you're working with and so on.
It's uh but it is a hard problem and uh and the indication that we're seeing is that
yeah, you can get better there, but
it's maybe not the right way to go at all because you're
not getting into other layers of false positives. So the second layer,
the level two of false positives.
So when you have the correct S bomb and you correctly map
those vulnerabilities to the dependencies,
it's the second layer is kind of similar to what I just described.
It's where it's a false positive if you're not using
the vulnerable functionality in a static way.
So it's not statically called and then we are looking at the third layer,
which is that the vulnerability is called
in a critical environment during run time.
Sure.
And then we look at the fourth and final layer is
that it's exploitable in a critical environment during run time.
I mean, that's,
it's, it's you say that out loud
and it's
completely obvious.
But I don't think we,
we don't always take that into consideration because most of
the composition tools just assume if you have it,
you're vulnerable right there,
there's zero intelligence regarding what the exploit actually is.
But,
but again, this is OK, this is such a crazy problem because so II,
I want to call something out that I suspect a lot of the audience isn't thinking of
is the vast majority of vulnerability information that exists today,
has virtually no usable machine information in it.
Like for example, all of the NVD data is just a prose description.
You're saying that you have the ability to take
what little data exists, figure out what part of the dependency it actually affects
because obviously you can't tell me I'm not
vulnerable because I'm not using the function.
If you don't know what the function is, you know what I mean?
And I think that is that is mind blowing because
there are hundreds of thousands of vulnerabilities,
there probably should be millions
and
-- obviously humans can't possibly do this.
-- No, no, of course not.
So, yeah,
that's uh this is actually like one of the essences of
of the problem here is that finding the vulnerable functionality,
right?
And looking at existing vulnerabilities, we do that for those as well.
That can be quite challenging.
Because then you have to first of all find automatically the software,
the open source project
and understand,
understand that open source project in a in
an automatic way which can be quite challenging
there. You can usually find information about what version ranges are vulnerable.
And from that you can derive if there is a safe version and a vulnerable version.
And you can look at the differences in the
code that were made during those version updates.
That was my life for about 12 years.
Yeah,
like every time bind released
or ISC you know, released a binder DH P update like 2 300 kilobytes of D
and then yeah, digging through that to find the vulnerable function and,
and humans are terrible at this work like we make tons of mistakes,
it and
even if they're good at it, it's hugely time consuming.
Yeah. And, and here's another thing that you're looking at, you're looking at a VD
where a version
D
may contain many commits,
usually usually quite a lot of them and then what functions were changed.
And when uh during that D
can vary from just a couple of them, three or four to many, many hundreds,
usually hundreds if it's a major or minor release.
And, and not a, not a, not a patch sure. And then if you're looking at that data, you,
you may, of course,
you can say that I found the vulnerable functionality but also
99 other non existing problems that you're mapping to what we're doing
here is that we're using our machine learning algorithm to look
at that set of commits that were made during that version update
and seeing if what are the highest probability commits that,
that fixed that vulnerability.
So we can narrow down those matches
of potential vulnerable functionalities quite a lot.
And, and instead of uh mapping
to hundreds of potentially vulnerable functionalities, we can f find
maybe the 3 to 4 to 5 highest candidates of functions that we think those,
these are the ones that we think are vulnerable.
You should,
if you're using those and where you're using those,
you should really look into that.
I love this. I mean,
one of my other long standing complaints about all this
is most of these scanners don't tell you what,
what you should like if,
if I was going to prioritize all these findings in a list and basically
start at the top at the most dangerous and work my way down.
They rarely take any of this into account. You just get this huge pile of stuff
and it's frustrating to me because obviously like
that, we have limited resources, we can't literally fix everything immediately.
We have to figure out what is important. What's
like, that's something I do now is I do this manually and it's like,
it's a horrible task.
-- Having a computer do. This sounds amazing to me.
-- Yeah. And like, first of all,
maybe a computer in this manner can probably do a lot.
But even if it can't, it can give you the information you want.
Sure to actually do that analysis yourself if you need to,
which is huge.
Well, that's the thing I keep finding right is,
is people like me and Josh have a lot of domain specific knowledge
that we can apply to looking at a vulnerability.
But, you know,
not everybody else has spent 20 years in the open source
world digging through thousands of vulnerabilities and to be honest,
nor should they.
It's insane.
And what drives me nuts is like, is this not the whole point of it to,
to automate stuff and to take human knowledge and shove it into a computer?
-- Yeah.
-- Yeah. Yeah. I completely agree with that.
And I know it's not easy but it,
it drives me nuts that we're stuck with all these scanning products that do things
in a way that I personally, I find it more painful than useful in most cases. Yeah.
I completely agree that we,
you should never consume more time than you give to the end
user and try to enable them to do a better job in,
in a faster manner and, uh, and more accurately.
Than you did before. And I agree that all scanners don't do that,
you may just be fed with false positives. And
like if you look at ourselves a couple of years ago, we were not there
and this way and by talking a lot to our users and
people that could tolerate us, but we wanted them to love us.
This is what they asked for. They wanted,
they wanted to be able to accurately reduce their
vulnerability risk in a manner and in a way
that they could perform this analysis and do this in
faster and save time and be very accurate in their work. And I think this is
the right way to go and the way the industry will help as well
in terms of managing open source vulnerabilities.
Well,
because because the one thing I've consistently
seen with respect to false positives is,
you know,
a lot of these scanning tools want to generate
a giant phone book sized report of results because,
you know, it looks very impressive.
We found 500 issues.
And then of course,
how many of those are actually legitimate or real is another question.
So
it seems to me like there's essentially two strategies here, right?
Sort of two reproductive strategies or one is to have a lot of a lot of Children
that are very low quality.
And the other one is while your approach to
have very few Children that are high quality,
like I just ran one of our code repositories through your scanner
and the results you give versus the github
depend
Abot alerts are
vastly different.
And from what I can tell the github
just goes straight off of the, the NVD data.
Whereas your data seems to have a bit more context.
That's, that's really great to hear actually. Thanks.
Yeah. And you actually, you have more stuff than the dependable
alerts. Which kind of worries me.
I
was sort of,
well, it depend a lot. It's free. Right? Why not? So we use it? It's free.
One of the rules I have now is I will not buy or
use a security tool that requires a significant amount of time and expertise
because we just, we don't have the time and effort to care and feed for these things.
Right. I, I don't have
basically, I don't want to buy tools that require me to hire more people.
Yeah.
Yeah. You know, it's
because in most cases these tools are not doing
things that are so amazing that it will,
you know, prevent all compromises of our system or whatever, you know,
if they did that guaranteed, then I would absolutely hire another person.
But,
well, that's the thing. Right. Even even if you
keep your software completely up to date, you're still not guaranteed. Right.
There's still your database will eventually find stuff because
I'm really curious about your comments about the,
the looking at commits.
Like just looking at commits and
sort of classifying them as security or not security, so to speak. Right.
And I'm wondering, sort of, have you found issues
that, you know, weren't publicly identified yet?
Yeah.
Yeah, we are, we have found quite a lot of them and, like,
there's one discussion to be had,
like, what should we do with those?
But we can,
-- we can pause that. We
-- won't talk about that on this show.
That is a very fascinating discussion for sure.
Yeah, because, well, I mean, we saw this a redhead all the time, right?
Like somebody would look at a five year old Linux
and be like, hey, guys, it's a security vulnerability.
And so, you know, we'd retroactively assign a CV for it and panic and fix it,
you know, five years later or hopefully we just pulled it in because it was so old
and I can't help but wonder, you know, how much of the open source world has that.
I mean, it has to happen, right? People accidentally fix stuff all the time. Yeah.
Yeah, it happens quite a lot and it's quite, it's interesting to
when we present the project and we, um internally, we say, OK,
we found this issue where we found or we found this commit and we say
that this is probably most likely a vulnerability and there's no CD assigned to it
when we, when we present it. A couple of months later, it's usually a CV
F assigned to it.
That's happened
many times now, which is really validating for the project.
Um
But I think it's actually like just to touch upon this.
Like, if we, let's say that we could accurately
find
a lot of undisclosed v
potential vulnerabilities in all open source,
how do we handle that in a way that's,
that's reasonable and,
and good for the community because we don't intend, intend to say that OK,
this is our vulnerabilities and no one else can look at this.
I
don't think that's a good way to handle that
at all. You should be open and just as the open source and,
and try to publicly disclose those,
but it's many hundreds of thousands that are potential
vulnerabilities right now that we find and how can
we do that in a way that so so that we don't spend all our time doing that,
but trying to maybe distribute that or
have bug bounty programs and not
make it
publicly available in a way that,
that it's not accessible to all open source consumers, but rather only to,
to the hackers.
And I, I don't know, it's a hard,
it's a tricky question that we haven't solved completely yet.
One of the biggest challenges I see there is is you get to the law of large numbers,
right?
You're no longer dealing with security issues.
You're dealing, you know, sort of policy and strategy,
right? Because one vulnerability, sure, 10 vulnerabilities, OK?
100 maybe 1000 10,000,
you know, 100,000, it's, it's a totally different thing
and I like, uh, again, me and Josh have dealt with this and it's,
well, it's,
you can't deal with it like you do
-- of
-- vulnerability. Artisanal data sets don't fly.
Right.
And artisanal everything, how it's communicated, you know,
using email to talk to people.
You can't do that when you have 100,000 issues. No.
And I,
I can't help but wonder this is part of where
the open source industry has to grow up too because,
well, we have this problem whether we like it or not.
Well, the, the whole industry I think, OK, so we're,
we're running ourselves out of time and I wanted to touch on one other.
I think important thing you mentioned way back at the beginning
was you are empowering people to become more involved in open source.
And I'm curious what you meant by that comment because that intrigues me.
Yeah. So
I think, I think that's actually a challenge today
that
open source project are not aware
what and how those projects are being used for. In reality.
We have uh a friend,
a friend of ours at the company of the former head of open source at Sony.
Usually when they needed to use an open
source project that had a non compliant license,
they,
they needed to talk to the open source project and see if they could
maybe release a dual license for them and see what they could do.
And the projects themselves were usually reacted according to him that,
oh my God, Sony is using the software I built, of course,
you can have any license you want.
And I think that kind of articulates a challenge
that
how, how does the how can the industry
be contribute more and more efficiently to open source projects
and coming and with the power of deeply understanding
code from similar systems as we've talked about of
both static and dynamic analysis,
we can also look at what open source projects are using, how much,
how much of each project are you using and
which is your most impactful project in your software
and linking that to
the overall project health for instance
and seeing where you can be most impactful in your contribution.
I mean, that makes that makes perfect sense.
It's I I feel like everything you've said today has been
one of those.
Well, it's so obvious now that you say it out loud,
but I guess I hadn't really thought of it before.
Yeah, but because when we,
when we talk to our customers and potential
users and like looking at their contribution strategy,
it's usually something that's quite new.
Only really, really large companies in my experience have,
have something a contribution strategy in mind.
Uh But it's usually so the projects that you
think are the ones you need to contribute to
that are top of mind. Tensorflow. Qbert
is the large ones that you're using a lot.
Those are not the ones that bear real risk always to your
organization because those are backed by Google and other large companies.
It's, it may be the smaller projects
that's not backed by any company
that may be trending down, that be,
that are very dependent on a very few active maintainers
and, and understanding like where,
where that future health risk of the project is
and what projects are actually impactful to your software.
Uh I think that's a really good opportunity here
and that's where I want to bring the brit
and see to it so that we can close the full, full chain of consuming using and
-- understanding and contributing back to open source.
-- That's amazing. I mean,
you know, what you just made me realize is there's,
I'm sure you've seen that XK CD Comic where it talks about, you know,
it shows like the stack and there's one little cube holding it up and it says,
you know, some guy in Nebraska or whatever you are,
I mean, you're in a position to identify that, that brick, right?
That's like literally one guy who's committing only on the weekends
and it's critical path for your application. Like that's,
that is really cool.
The thing that gets me is not just the critical path for the application,
but so much stuff gets pulled in.
Now, I'm not number one just having a list of it is amazing.
But number two, having
actually knowing roughly how important it is,
you know, how critical is this? Like how
like if this breaks or it has a security issue, how badly would my application break
that would be hugely helpful,
you know,
knowing where to focus because yeah, there's,
I I suspect most people have no idea.
No,
no, because this is a, I mean,
to understand software
is a really, really hard challenge uh in general. So I mean,
isolating the open source open source software in depth and
mapping that towards actual people contributing to those projects.
I mean, i
it is a hard challenge but I think it's,
it's so fun to work with and it's so cool to be part and try to understand
all the amazing people doing good stuff for software in the world.
Absolutely.
This is OK. I'm going,
I want to keep talking to you but I know we have to end this, which does make me sad, but
I will give you the last word emile. Why don't you
let us know the one thing you want everyone to take away from this this episode?
I think what I want to achieve is
I want to enable
all developers to simply use the open source.
-- They love
-- that is a lofty and admirable goal. Thank you so much.
Thank you for your patience in dealing with us in all the rescheduling.
We truly appreciate it. And
I feel like Debri
is one of the few companies doing this sort of
work that I feel like is on the right path.
So,
congratulations and I hope you the best
for sure. And so. All right. Thank you, everyone for listening.
Go to open source security podcast.com.
I'll have links in the show notes to all the stuff we talked about today. Use
a Pound
O
as podcast. Hashtag Get us up on social media.
-- Kurt and Emile have marvelous rest of your
-- days. Thank you. You too, Josh and
Kurt.
Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye
the.