Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
and my partner in cleaning. Josh
Pressers. Cleaning your
last
name.
-- I do have a
-- last name.
-- I sort of zoned out there for a sec. I was just like
-- Josh,
I need. Hold
on. I gotta shut my closet door here.
You know what? That's the wrong intro. It's my partner in tidying.
Tidying and cleaning are two very different things.
So,
you know, I recorded my closet and it's really freaking cold today.
-- It's, oh man, it's like
-- freezing
cold
or cold in your house.
Well, both. I mean, I own an old house. So,
-- ok, because
-- I'm like,
there's a certain amount of air that always leaks in. But anyway,
you're going to hear me
by the end of this, I think.
No, I've removed all the squirrels from my house. It was an effort and it's ongoing.
I have to, I have to keep all the trees trimmed back
so they can't get on the roof. But anyway, whatever, what are we talking about today?
Well, first of all, tidying,
not cleaning, cleaning and tidying are two different things.
That's one of the things I had to learn from Marie Kondo.
I'm not gonna argue
with you about it.
So, real quick cleaning is
to me, it's like sanitizing and wiping and you know, you can have an untidy,
like a cluttered environment that is, you know, it's been like
or bleach down,
I would define my office is that environment where there is lots of junk and,
but it is very clean
and then conversely, you can have tidy but unsanitary unclean, you know,
you can have somebody who lives in a
very minimalist home and has never cleaned their toilet
that
terrifies me.
So
we're going to be talking, not,
not about cleaning and I apologize for that intro but about tidying.
And so
Josh wouldn't let me mention this one style of cleaning that I like.
So we're going to go with the happier one. Marie Kondo's, does it spark joy?
I'm gonna, I'm gonna rat you up first. There's what is it called?
-- Like Swedish death cleaning or something? Swedish
-- death cleaning.
The idea,
you know,
clean up after yourself. So you're next of kin, don't have to.
That is not a topic I have any interest to talk
about and there's enough angst in the world right now.
-- So we're going to talk about happy things.
-- Marie Kondo's, does it spark joy?
And, and, and what I love about Marie Kondo's method is it basically boils down to,
it's very simple in your personal life, you know,
does this object, does this thing,
you know, a pair of pants or whatever? Does it spark joy?
And she literally says, look, just pick it up and, and
feel how your body feels about it. And to quote,
does it feel as if every part or cell of your body lifts up or
does it feel as if every part of your body feels like it weighs down?
If I was to pick you up, you'd be very heavy.
And,
and what I also love about her method of tidying is it's not just the practical stuff,
right?
Like, for example, I have a bunch of stuff.
I only use half the year and I have to keep it or I will buy like,
my snow boots and my snow pants.
Right? Like,
nor do they bring me joy because it's winter.
Well, they do bring me joy when I wear them outside and it's minus 30 my feet are warm.
Yeah, that, that's probably fair.
The thing I've always hated about these tidying systems or methods is
ok. There's like this continuum of like one.
You absolutely have to have it like a drawer of underwear and socks.
You, everybody has to have that.
You need
three
pairs of socks.
Yeah.
And then there's all the way to zero where obviously this is
like a piece of junk that was given to you that you
hate and you're allergic to and you just keep it in a
sealed box and just can't bring yourself to throw it out.
But you should.
But all the stuff in the middle where, ok, there's that continuum of like,
ok, well,
my winter gear I need because half the year I need to not die when I go outside,
you know, my swimsuits.
Well, yeah, in summer I need my swimsuit because, you know,
we go to the spray parks or the pool or whatever.
But what about that stuff?
So perfect example here is I have like an old
Nintendo wii still works because that Nintendo build quality.
-- Did
-- you
-- hack that thing? Hack. That thing, man, I
-- meant to but never got around to
it.
They're hacked. They're so good.
So what, I'm still not going to play it.
It's been sitting in a box for, I don't know,
over a decade and I realized I'm hanging on to it because I paid for it and it works.
Right? And so it doesn't really spark joy. I never play with it.
It's just sort of one more thing to keep on a shelf. This is a security podcast.
I'm
going to get to the, so a great example is I own a pair of really nice later Hosen,
right?
They're black with flower pattern. They're really nice
and they, I mean, I only wear them once a year at most, you know,
to like whatever local beer festival, right?
And then I get to make fun of the people wearing all the crappy fake later. Hosen.
-- Yeah. No, it's,
-- come
on, you're a later
snob.
Yes.
Yes, I am
100%.
And so
that's what I like about the Spark joy method is that it gives
you this excuse to keep stuff that maybe isn't practical or terribly useful.
But, you know, it does bring you joy. And so I was thinking about this in it terms
so perfect example in it, in terms back in the day at this,
at the Cloud Security alliance,
we had a mailing list server
because we had mailing list.
And so I had a machine running mailman and I had two postfix
servers in front of it and two post six postfix servers behind it,
you know, for incoming email and for outgoing email and blah, blah, blah, blah, blah
and did it spark joy. No, it sparked dread.
It was a nightmare to manage, you know, the anti spam,
the
uh all the stuff associated with running email manually by yourself nowadays.
And I realized no, like marketing,
you guys like mailchimp good. You're on mailchimp now,
right?
You've got all the mailchimp stuff,
all the A B testing and it sparks joy because literally all I had to do was log in,
create some accounts dump in a giant CS V of names and emails and,
and that's it,
right.
It, there's no more stress and dread and I got to turn off all those five servers.
It was lovely. So I was thinking about this in terms of it, right.
In terms of personal stuff, there's the stuff you need.
So, like you have clothes to wear outside
all the way down to that, you know,
stuff you don't want or need that was given to
you by somebody else you didn't even pay for it.
And in it terms, there's,
in theory, every single sort of it thing is necessary otherwise, why is it on?
Really? Right.
-- Like every it system in theory should be used to some degree
-- it should be.
-- And I think that's a really interesting point.
-- So I was thinking about this
of sort of from 0 to 1, like for example, at the CS A on on the one side
payroll, right? I think we can all agree payroll is important.
-- People need to get paid,
-- right? Or, or like email, right?
-- You can't exist without email.
-- Email was going to be next followed by the website.
Yeah.
So these are things we can clearly all agree that like
need to be kept up and running. So the CS A can just function,
right? That these are not at all optional and then all the way at sort of maybe zero.
Uh Well, perfect example,
we were using box.com back in the day because they had time expiring links which
Google and other people didn't have. Right.
And so that's actually quite a handy feature because you can share a link out and not
have to worry about it kind of biting you in the ass in five years from now.
And so
I think in terms of it, does it spark joy is essentially, does this service?
Well, step one is, do you need this service?
Right? Because there are sometimes just things that you can just get rid of.
I want to reframe this even more than that. And let's talk about security.
Well, and that's where I'm getting to. Stage two
is seven minutes in.
So, but stage two is, for example, do you need what this thing does?
And maybe not in its current incarnation.
So for example, with the mailing list stuff, we needed mailing list 100% to them.
But you know what, we don't need to run them ourselves.
That's, you know,
we can use mailchimp and so we outsourced it to mailchimp and life was better.
And then in security terms, there's, yeah,
there's all those security things around it.
For example,
I love Google because I can just enable
and force everybody to use two factor authentication.
Good luck breaking into accounts.
-- So,
-- you know what immediately comes to mind here when you, when you bring the
is in the world of security right now, I think we're at this
point of disruption where there's all these
automated tools starting to emerge and there are
a lot of them are comically bad to the point of like I'll use as an easy example, like,
let's say you have a SIM, which is, you know, a security, you know,
event manager basically where you bring in all this.
Yeah,
but you bring in all this, all this information, right?
And then you somehow process it and you have to deal
with it and there's always this talk of like alert fatigue
and, and I would bet you in a nontrivial number of organizations,
if you just literally turn the sim off,
it would make a lot of people's lives better and it would make no difference.
And if that's true of any of your security infrastructure, like holy cow,
what's the deal?
But conversely, there's like,
I'm going to pick on Home Depot here because I specifically remember remember Home
Depot was explicitly warned by their not their sin but their security firm saying,
look, you've got some bad stuff going on in here,
you need to deal with this.
And you know, of course it turns out and I was one of those, you know,
I got that notice saying, you know,
Home Depot got hacked and you bought stuff at Home Depot.
So like maybe think about getting a new credit card because we're
not really sure how much data went missing or whatever really happened.
And I think part of it too is again on that
0 to 1 scale,
-- I can't run a 24 7 knock.
-- Well, you can't,
but it depends what your environment or like I mean,
a SIM is my favorite example just because, like, there are SIMS that are really good
and it's partially good technology and it's partially good people.
-- And then there are SIMS that are just money fires that don't do anything.
-- It's worse.
-- It's not that they don't do anything. It's that they actively make your life
-- worse.
They're negative value. Right.
Yeah. There, there are too many false alerts
and, yeah, it's, it's actively making your life worse.
It's active eating up your time and money and attention
and taking you away from what you should be doing.
Right.
There was that tweet talking about to avoid solar winds, you know,
what would you tell your CEO or CISO or whatever the heck to do?
And I'm like basic inventory and software hygiene.
Like if you can't do that, everything else is the cart before the horse.
Well, but even even that I don't think is clearly defined in many instances.
This is one of the issues I think is there's a certain amount of missing
standardization and rigor in security where there's still
a lot of just made up crap.
Well, a perfect example at the CS A,
we just went through our annual exercise of who's all our vendors.
And we're lucky in that because we're 100% cloud based,
everything shows up on corporate credit cards.
And so we basically get corporate credit card
statements from accounting who actually has a spreadsheet
with all that data and we're able to go through and we're literally finding vendors.
Some, it's, you know, obviously somebody's signed up for like
some little lucid chart thing or whatever, for 30 bucks, whatever. No big deal.
But then there's other things where it's kind of like, whoa, you know,
we have this recurring monthly thing from this.
-- Who are these people?
-- Yeah.
But now at, at the same time, if you're a fortune 100 company,
your vendors are everyone else.
Well, and also it's not as clearly defined as to what they do, right?
With a cloud service, you go to their website, you can read what they do.
But when you have $100,000 bill from Dell,
like, what is that? Is that a, is that a cluster of windows 95
machine,
something fine, just pay the bill.
But I mean, you know, what's it running? Right? It's probably a pile of,
you know, or, or even worse.
You have a bill for 100,000 from Dell and 50,000 from Microsoft.
Like what's on your network?
Everything?
Yeah.
And so
this Marie Kondo Spark Joy Method. I,
it really, you know, I actually went through, you know, we,
we're currently going through the spreadsheet.
We're also updating from a GDPR perspective of what, you know,
do these vendors have any pi I from external people, blah, blah, blah, all that,
you know, is it self serve?
Do we have to remove it? You know, all this stuff and,
and it's really liberating because some of these, you know, we're like,
what is this?
Oh, you know what marketing uses that and really relies on it. Oh, ok. Cool.
Like they're on top of it. Good, you know.
But on the other hand, there's a few older things in here where it's just like,
what is this and why do we have it?
And
nobody seems to know what it is.
So let's figure out how to stop paying for that.
I,
I think that's the story and I see this in the security world all the time where people
have tools or infrastructure or something and you don't
even know why you still have it anymore.
And I mean,
it
honestly, in
my basement,
I have a closet that's full of boxes of stuff.
I literally could not tell you what's in them
and I have a suspicion that means I should probably just throw them all away.
I realized at one point I had boxes that I had packed for moving three houses ago.
I, I, yeah, I, I believe that.
And so I actually forced myself to go through all the
boxes and number one get rid of the obvious crap.
And you know,
and well, and for example, does it spark joy? Right? Like there's, I have this big,
you know, uh 2.5 inch cub
chunk of concrete here next to my desk, you know, it's a piece of the Berlin Wall?
-- Oh,
-- that's cool.
Is it a practical, useful thing? No, it's a chunk of concrete.
-- Does it have graffiti on it? No, no, no,
-- it's, it's just like an internal piece. It's,
it's one of the few times they actually spent money on making good concrete.
Sadly.
And so, you know, I force and that's,
I think that's part of step one is just forcing yourself to
go through these boxes or forcing yourself to go through these systems
and just
label and find out what you have
and, and some stuff will be just super easy to get rid of. Like
I had a box with like 20 bucks worth of change rattling around at the bottom of it.
-- So I scooped it up into a jar and took it to the
-- bank. That's cash money right there.
Yeah, exactly.
Like why, why was I keeping $20 and change in a box?
This is why I love when I'm traveling abroad and
I get to the airport and they have like a,
basically a bucket that's like, please put your change in here for, you know,
charity or whatever.
I'm like, oh, thank goodness. And I just like dump piles of it in.
-- So
-- I think doing that basic inventory and, and just labeling what you have and,
and you will get rid of some easy stuff that zero stuff, that stuff where you're like,
why do I have a moldy cup of coffee in a box,
-- right. That may or may not be a true story. I'm going
-- to complain. I need to just,
you know, whinge a little bit.
And so my Children are notorious for taking a drink into the basement
and then putting it in a weird place and then
we find it like a month later and it's like,
oh, my goodness,
you're going to clean this because I'm not touching it and it's
just like a science experiment and the grossest thing in the world.
Yeah, I have a rule. Only water bottles in the basement.
Like the kind that, like seal, like sports water bottles.
Yeah, nothing else is allowed food wise in the basement.
I, I try to have this rule but I'm disregarded. Obviously.
I've been viciously enforcing it since my Children were
born.
-- So,
-- no, like, look, ok, so this is, let's, I want to expand on this topic and use it.
Use it as a launching point because so here's the thing, right?
My kids take a glass of something into the basement.
They leave it there
and there's minimal repercussions.
I make them clean up after themselves, obviously.
But like, what am I really going to do now? As a security team?
You can tell people, oh, I would like you to keep your service updated.
And if they don't,
and if the payroll department says we can't update this because we can't pay people,
there's really nothing you can do and there aren't going to be any repercussions
I went more with, here's what you are allowed to do and encouraged to do.
You are allowed to have drinks on the kitchen slash dining room slash family level.
It's a four level split. You are allowed
to bring your drinks into the third level down here
into this work room because it is a concrete floor.
So I don't care what you spill on the floor because it'll be easy to clean.
It's that simple and you're not allowed to bring drinks downstairs
because we have those like two by 2 ft rubber,
uh, interlocking, you know,
mats that they have like gyms and if you spill a drink on them,
I have to peel up all the rubber mats and clean under them.
Sure.
But
they're not, that's not payroll.
Well, no, no, no.
But so I've encouraged, like, you want to have your drink,
put it at the top of the stairs, right.
So I've given them
ways to, to have their cake and eat it.
Your house sounds like an awesome place.
-- So, I tried, we have swings in the basement and all sorts of fun stuff.
-- That's
-- cool.
-- Yeah. Well, winters here are long and cold. That,
that is true. You're, you're
no more north than I am by a lot and I think winters here are pretty terrible.
I agree because, yeah, you can't,
oh, you know, payroll, you have to win all this patch.
And I don't care if it breaks payroll or not. Yes. Yes.
When I worked for that,
well, I worked for this electrical contractor company that, you know, had 5,
600 electricians on staff.
They did industrial stuff and came time to
upgrade the payroll machine and they're like,
Kurt, you know, can you build a cheap machine to host it?
And I'm like, no, because I don't want 500 angry electricians knowing where I park
on Friday at 6 p.m.
You know, I'm like, we,
the payroll company will sell us this vastly overpriced
5000 dollar machine and you'll pay for it because
-- payroll for 500 electricians,
-- I mean, so, so in all seriousness, you know,
kind of tying this all together now is there's this concept of things will say,
bring you joy,
but I think it's not even just bring you joy because in the world of security and it,
there's like things you actually need,
whether it gives you joy because we all have infrastructure that like we
freaking hate and we would burn it in fire if we could.
-- But replace it with what? Well, and
-- that's just it. You have to have it.
You can't get rid of it. You know what I mean?
It doesn't bring me joy, but it has to be there.
There's a lot of it stuff that yes, I would love to get rid of it,
but what it provides, we absolutely need to function so in that way that
the whole sparking joy isn't just sparking joy and happiness.
But it can also be, you know, from a practical standpoint.
Does this thing, for example, prevent you from being dead?
You know, I'm guessing a lot of people who are dependent on insulin injections
aren't
super happy fun times about jabbing themselves with a needle once or twice a day.
Probably not super fun. But does it prevent them from being dead?
Yeah. And
that's ok. But that's not the worst thing in the world. That's fair. That's fair.
And that's how I feel about a lot of it. Infrastructure like,
yeah, I,
no, I don't like maintaining X but, well, if we don't have X,
we don't have a company or whatever.
So I wanna,
I wanna kind of for the last little bit of time
we have here is so I think there's two extremes,
there's things you need and we'll say spark joy.
Right. There's the things you hate and can probably get rid of and probably should.
But there's this whole thing in the middle where there's this like sliding scale of,
we probably need this to.
Maybe we don't, but I'm not exactly sure. And turning it off might get me fired.
Can I give a perfect example?
Our Asia Pacific Office uses a little web hosting service.
It's like 23 bucks a month.
Toast uh website they do for, for having conferences and stuff.
And would I love to get rid of it and have one less thing to worry about.
Absolutely. But you know what, for 23 bucks a month
and they update the site and they use the site.
Sure.
You guys do.
You, I mean,
I think that's a no brainer then.
Like, but now let's say, let's say,
let's flip this around and say it was $23 a month.
It's riddled with security holes
and it's probably a liability to you as the
director of it at the Cloud Security Alliance.
Now, what do you do?
Well, then we would look at transitioning it off on to something else.
But your people are saying like, no got to do this. No questions asked. Go away. Nerd.
Well, then quite honestly,
I tweeted about this
would say you determine your risk appetite and that's what you eat for dinner.
And so in that case, I would do an email chain saying here's the downsides,
here's the upsides, here's the information about this.
Here are your major options.
If there's another clever option you can think of, please tell me.
But fundamentally if it boils down to,
you want to use this insecure thing with this potential downside.
Ok.
You know what organizations get to do that
except you're the one who has to clean up the mess.
-- It gets potent. Yeah.
-- And that's why I, that's part of my job,
-- I guess. I mean,
-- do you think that school janitor likes cleaning up vomit.
No,
I imagine that
that's part of the Cecil's job is to,
sometimes to eat that risk and maybe it doesn't turn out well,
and you're on the toilet at five AMI, guess that's part of the job.
And here's the thing that can happen,
even if you use the most secure thing in the world.
Oh,
well. Ok. No. No.
So, I think this is where though,
if you know it's insecure and you've kind of
attempted to remedy the situation and you've been unsuccessful.
-- Are
-- we going to put that scene from Fight Club in the, in the show notes?
Which scene, the cost of a recall of A Times B times C? Then
you know where he's telling this lady on the plane about what he does, right?
No. Well, essentially that's how business works.
We,
we make a series of risk management decisions and sometimes we make the decision of,
we will choose to allow this risky thing with a potential downside.
And that's,
-- that's it.
-- That's slightly different.
So you're talking about the business as an amorphous blob.
But I'm thinking about once you go down a layer, you have these different groups.
And an easy example is so you can have one group
that is like, oh,
I totally accept this risk except they're not on
the hook at all if something goes wrong.
So like from their perspective, it's zero risk.
But from my perspective, as a security guy,
I get all the risk.
See,
they're the problem you're talking about though is
that you have the responsibility but no accountability.
And when you have responsibility and accountability, mismatch,
no matter what happens, you're up the creek, it's going to end poorly.
No matter what. If people are responsible for something
-- that they cannot influence, they're
-- doomed.
I think accountability is a huge part of this, you know, joy or not joy.
I, I, I'd like this, this like number line in my head and on, on the left side is,
is joy and on the right side is not joy.
And I feel like if I'm responsible for something, but I, I'm,
there's no accountability from the people, you know, who own it.
I feel like that automatically slides it like as far to the right as it can go,
you know, you make your risk appetite,
you make what is acceptable and not acceptable and, and if you can't
force that, well, then you're up the creek like you don't,
this conversation doesn't matter because you have much more fundamental
problems to solve in your life and your work life,
if you're responsible for stuff that you can't exert any influence over,
well, you're gonna fail.
But anyways, if you can exert influence over, like I said, you know,
you do these email threads, you always put it down in writing,
in permanent writing,
you have this conversation and you ideally make a, a collaborative decision,
but it doesn't have to be collaborative.
You know, there's been cases where I'm like, honestly, I don't care, man,
like just tell me what you want and I will build that for you,
you know, and you'll be in charge of it all the way up to.
I do deeply care because I have to manage this and it's a huge high risk thing.
So for example, we're using Google
whatever it was called 10 years ago.
Now, it's I think Google Suite or something you keep renaming,
I can't keep track of it,
you know, and, and it's like we're, we're firmly ensconced in Google. Now.
I would consider switching to Microsoft 365. It's actually pretty decent,
but the cost of switching is oh God, no, we're never doing that.
It's really high for sure. Every single document link breaks. Kurt.
What's your solution for that? My solution for that is I quit and hide. That's
right. That's
right.
I,
I feel like this sparking joy because it not only
gives you a framework for sort of making a decision,
but a framework for being ok with that decision.
And I think,
you know, that's one of the things I love and hate about democracy.
Democracy gives you a way to make decisions.
But in theory,
it also gives you a way for the winners and
the losers to be OK with that decision because I've,
I've done so many tidying
attempts before
where I felt bad after tidying like that.
I had to get rid of stuff I sort of still want
or I didn't get rid of stuff that I don't want.
You know, and I didn't feel good about it whereas this sparking joy method, it's,
well, if I don't want it, I don't want it.
And if I do want it I keep it and if I'm not sure in the middle deal with it next time,
maybe that there's a ton of vendors with the CS A where I just want to, you know,
we've marked them in orange and it's kind of like we got to go deal with this, but,
you know, not right now, we can do it later.
-- And
-- that's fair. I think this is overly simplistic for a security team for sure.
But I do think the one, the one part of this conversation I'm walking away with is, is
accountability
is a huge part of everything.
-- And I feel like a lot of security teams are accountable but they can
-- responsible,
not accountable.
Right. They're responsible, but they're exactly. And so
-- that's backwards.
-- So they're set up for failure, right.
Failure is the only outcome of that because if the,
if the people you're working with don't have to care,
they just won't because it's not going to spark them joy.
Right.
It's like, screw it. It doesn't bother me any.
And that's, that's just human nature.
It's like making me responsible for my neighbor's backyard.
But I'm not allowed to enter his property.
Right. What am I supposed to do?
I don't even know how to process that.
-- Well,
-- and then that's what happens with security teams though.
Security team,
you are responsible for the security of the network and all systems on it.
Ok. Cool.
But you can't touch the payroll systems or hr systems. Right.
-- You can't even have a login,
-- oh, man, I love that so much when there's like a pen test.
And they're like, oh, all of this stuff is,
is off limits. It's out of scope.
And it's like, I don't, I don't think it works that or, you know what my favorite is.
So I've been, I was talking to a bug Bonnie Hunter the other day
and they said they, they submitted a bug to a company and the company like, oh,
that system is supposed to be out of scope and then they
marked it out of scope and then they marked the bug invalid.
That's
ridiculous. That's awesome.
And,
and then they were like, I will never report anything to these people again.
And I'm like, well, I mean, that's exactly what I would do
anyway. It's,
this is, oh, man, you know, so you,
you said we were going to talk about this and I was thinking about it
and this is not at all where the conversation went that I was expecting,
but it also really, oh, man, I'm really thinking about this now.
It's just that whole responsible and accountability piece and, and insecurity.
It's just, do you remember working at Red Hat?
-- I
-- mean,
there was a lot of,
there was a lot of responsibility
and accountability mismatches across the company.
Yeah. There, there was.
And I mean, I, even now that we're talking about it, I see it now,
even there's some things that I'm responsible for now that like there's, and, and,
and in fact, there's certain things I do that I feel like I fail
on a regular basis and it's because I can't do anything about it.
-- And, I mean, duh, now that you say it, it's so obvious.
-- Well, you know,
I want my house not to fall down but Josh,
I don't want you messing with my house or touching it.
-- Well,
-- that's fine because I live far away.
Yeah.
Right. But, you know, now your, your yearly bonus is tied to that statement. Right.
I mean, no, I mean, I mean, I get that right. It's kind of the same thing.
Like if, if someone, let's say builds a house and they have no accountability,
if it falls down, do they, why would they care?
Right. Like, whatever, just use the cheapest stuff. It doesn't matter.
The builder builds the house and if it does fall down they
just fold their company and reincorporate with a similar but different name.
-- And
-- I mean, that stuff like that does happen,
watch homes on homes. Right. That Canadian show where Holmes Holmes?
Wait, that guy is Canadian.
I didn't know that.
-- So,
-- he,
I've, I've watched it like, twice
and I just, it amuses me because he goes, and he's like, this is all terrible.
Everything sucks. And I'm like, this guy could be a security person.
I,
I was recently watching this H VAC guy who, you know, first person
records him fixing these commercial HVAC systems and
for example,
he just spent hours on one and it turned out to be
that the drain pan was pushed up because the drainage wasn't run,
right.
So the drainage not only sloped up,
but it was
pushing the drain pan up in the middle.
And if you push a drain pan up in the middle, guess what?
It doesn't do, it doesn't drain. Exactly.
So there was crazy ice build up that then
shorted out electronics and all this crazy stuff.
So literally he had to fix the drain pan pipe thing
and then he basically had to replace a pile of electronics and motors
and now it works and it's fine.
But it reminds me of this, you know, it's, we see this all the time.
You know,
people do work the some limited liability corporation is responsible for and
that LLC has no brand to protect and no assets to protect.
So if it goes south,
they just fold and rename.
You know,
this is why I'm considering buying Phillips hue bulbs because I bought single
and they were garbage. I bought Globe bulbs at Costco
and they, a bunch of them that are physically close like 20 ft or less away from the
hotspot.
Keep de synchronizing.
So you turn on the hall light and it like starts flashing
like an emergency signal and this is not a great experience.
So I'm looking at the Phillips U because Phillips is a
major electronics brand that has a brand name to protect.
And I've literally had zero problems with my extremely expensive light bulbs
which better not go over what I freak paid for these things. Like I'd be super mad.
-- I
-- know I'm looking at these things and it's there
are about three times as expensive as what I have.
Yeah, but now at the same time,
I've had them a long time and they literally never ever.
And actually one of them died once I think we have,
I talked about it on the podcast at some point, but like it died, I called them up.
They were like explain.
Yeah, this is what happened. They like we'll send you a new one. Like that was it,
it was
-- like, OK, that's
-- cool. So yeah, no, like I said, I always come back to this.
I want a framework not only for making decisions
but for helping me feel good or at least OK about those decisions.
I mean, yeah, I got, I got to think about this one man. I've got a lot to think about now.
And
I guess here's part of it as well and this is what I'll end on is you're mentioning.
So you've got an LLC builds a house, house collapses LLC dissolves.
-- But now at the same time in all this big mess, there's insurance,
-- a simpler example,
builder builds an entire subdivision.
Subdivision has one and well, technically two entrances and exits,
but one of those entrances and exits
has a rail line going through it
and the rail cars sometimes tie that up for 56 minutes.
And so the fire department is having trouble getting to the subdivision.
This is a real world thing like here in Edmonton. And,
and I quote, the homeowners are saying
the builder promised to build another entrance and exit that
wasn't cut off by the rail line and they haven't.
So now we want the city to do it. And it's like, well,
yeah, I bet the builder made a lot of promises that they didn't keep.
This is an example,
I would say where there's probably multiple failures because
like the city shouldn't have allowed the permits.
You know what I mean?
-- Like you've got to put this stuff in writing,
-- they met the minimum standard.
So there's nothing illegal. It has two entrances and exits.
So if the train is blocking the road and the fire department has to go around, it,
it takes about five minutes.
Ok. So it's, it meets, it meets all the legal standards. It's just not
nice because sometimes you have to wait a few
extra minutes for the fire department to show up,
which when your house or in this case, a car is on fire in a driveway,
people kind of want the fire department there. Now
again, this is that whole accountability versus responsibility thing
-- when you're the homeowner, I guess. Good luck. I don't have a good answer
-- for
that.
No,
there isn't because the homeowners aren't informed enough
and don't know how the system works.
And
also
they can't exert any control over builder, the builder built the house and sold it,
right. What are you going to do?
Well, apart from sue them, in which case, they're just going to fold and move on.
-- I don't know.
-- That's a good one anyway, I'm calling it.
So I guess
Kurt, thank you everyone for listening. Go to open source security podcast.com.
Hit up our show notes, use the Pound
Oss podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks everybody. Bye bye.