Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself.
-- Kurt Siefried and my partner in not crime. Josh Pressers.
-- Not crime.
-- Yeah. I don't wanna get
-- hacked. Do we
-- commit not crime? I don't
-- know.
Well, like you stop at stop signs,
uh,
generally stop at stop signs. I can't think of very many. I don't,
I'm a pretty boring person
to
be.
I'm, I'm not gonna pretend I'm like some outlaw.
Yeah, that's, that's the thing. Like
when I was young it was like, oh, I want an exciting life and now that I'm old, I'm like,
the more boring things are the happier I am.
Yeah. Like I have the first night free to myself in two months.
And so, like I'm doing this and then I'm gonna go do some work
and I had a sandwich earlier. It was
very
good.
Yeah.
No, I haven't changed.
I completely understand 100%.
I, I wanna say, I wanna say something though. So
if, if, if you have time, you know, uh, games done quick was like a week ago. Right?
That's a speed run marathon. I love,
there is a game for the Nintendo Switch.
That is about rolling a, a like moving a roll of toilet paper around on the screen
and to control the toilet paper on the screen,
you know, you take a real roll of toilet paper,
you put the Joy Con inside the tube and then you roll
it back and forth to move the thing on the screen.
I'm like, give me toilet paper. I was like, this can't be real. It's totally real.
And I'm like, oh my goodness, this is the best thing ever.
Like,
this is what I love about things like the connect or like Joycons in that
you can use them in ways that they weren't meant to be,
you can do some really clever cool stuff,
which actually kind of leads to what we want to talk about today,
which is this new proposed Dutch National Security Law?
Ok. So
when I interpret your words, I think it's, it's toilet paper,
but I don't think that's what you meant with that comment.
-- No,
-- just using things the way they ways that are maybe not supposed to be.
Ok.
So let's lay this one out.
I'll let you explain it because I don't like it and I know you don't hate it.
So you'll be a little more objective than I will.
Uh I wouldn't say that.
So there's basically this new proposed Dutch security
law and the biggest change is that so traditionally
you have a bad actor organization, so you do boring things like get a warrant
hack into them. Look at their emails,
build a court case, try to convict them and send them to prison. Ok. Fair.
You know,
that's typical.
Well, for the Dutch it is.
Well, for most of the world,
well, to summarize the Dutch government wants to automatically,
and administratively gain permission to target victims of hackers.
So essentially if they get a warrant to hack a hacking group. Right.
Right.
Then the victims of that hacking group,
the Dutch government would also be able to go into their stuff and look at it.
That's right.
So it's, it's a broad expansion of powers, essentially,
that's a bit of an understatement.
-- But
-- yes, I think broad should be underlined and maybe circled or something. But
-- yeah,
-- because some of
these ransomware groups are in a lot of systems.
Right. That's right. And now also if you read further, it also talks about
giving them the ability to like sniff traffic and
access emails and all that kind of stuff.
Like I basically,
if they're targeting a hacking group and the hacking group has hacked you,
they can automatically just like start rooting through your stuff basically
in a nutshell.
Yeah.
Now, now I
don't wanna dwell too much on the specifics of the Dutch
law just because obviously I'm not an expert in Dutch law
-- and
-- this is also a draft and blah, blah,
-- it's
-- a draft and the like lengthy bill is in Dutch, which I can't read
and so I've read the English summaries, which
I will assume are correct.
But I think the, the higher level discussion and this is what I'm interested in is,
should law enforcement have the ability to do something?
Like, if they know an attacker has hacked into somebody,
should they be able to basically also break in for the purposes of law enforcement?
And this would,
I think in the physical world you could compare this to
like AAA criminal runs into someone's house.
Can the police officer follow them into the house? Right. Sort of thing.
Exigent circumstances uh, in almost every jurisdiction on the planet. Yeah.
Right. And, and exactly,
and that
I've been thinking about this a lot and I feel like you
can think about it in the context of the physical world.
Well, it's where we have existing case law.
Right. Right. But, but, but now
if, if I am
say a bank
and a criminal is banking with me.
If the police have a warrant against the criminal,
they can't just show up and be like, hey, we already have this warrant.
So we're gonna, uh, we can look at your stuff. Right.
The banks would be like, no, you need a new warrant to come talk to me.
Yeah,
I was gonna say you would have to be banking with a
lot of criminals before they start rooting for your stuff and,
-- and that has happened,
-- right?
Like,
like
Deutsche
bank,
for example, what apparently was
-- the world's criminal banker. Uh
-- Right. Right.
Anyway,
but,
and, and I think
this is
truly unique because we can't compare this to
any physical like real world situation directly.
Well, there is, there's for example, America, the American government demands
banking information
for bank accounts held by American citizens in foreign countries like Canada.
And the penalty for us not giving that information over freely is they will cut us off
from their banking system which
like we can't do that like we would,
we would collapse.
And so for example, in a lot of countries like China, for example,
when
this law passed, you know, as soon as you basically walked into your Chinese bank
and they're like, oh, you're an American customer, right?
Here's all your money, go away
like they would just close your account boo you
up because they don't want to deal with it.
And there's a lot of Canadian banks,
you know, that don't want really want to deal with this.
But there's so many Americans up here banking and
stuff that we can't really get rid of it.
So
there are sort of some parallels but not nothing quite this.
We don't know what the intent of this law is,
right? And,
and, and for example, if the intent was like,
why do firemen get to kick down your door?
Well, because if your house burns down,
your neighbor's house might catch fire and we all agree that that's a bad thing.
-- Also, there might be like people in the building.
-- Right.
No, no, I think the intent is to empower law enforcement
to better operate
in
cyberspace. I think that's the simple explanation.
Now, intent and reality, especially legally speaking
often are the, the, the Venn diagram is two separate circles.
And
let's again, I want to,
we know a law like this is going to be
abused eventually, maybe not at first, but guaranteed 100%.
And I don't even wanna talk about that.
I just wanna say, like, let's say,
here's a question for you should law enforcement be allowed to hack
into a system they know has been compromised by an adversary.
The adversary is already in the system. Let's say we 100% know this
-- should law enforcement break into it.
-- What's the intention of breaking into it?
If the, is the, for example,
is the intention of breaking into it to patch it and fix it and kick the bad guys out
or is it
to gather information that might then be used to build a
case against the owner of that system for something completely unrelated?
It's going to be to build a case.
I guarantee it because like,
how many times have you heard of law enforcement
-- patching up the door, they knocked out
-- that's not really allowed and they would get,
you know, the,
the legal liability like we've talked about this before where you know,
part of me is like, if somebody ever writes a virus that actually goes out and, like,
forcibly updates all the windows installs that it compromises, I'd be like, yeah,
I'm ok with that,
you know. But at the same time I remember,
well,
some of those old window systems are running MRI machines and if you patch them,
the MRI machine will break and then people will die.
And that's part of the problem. You, you can't just like
upgrade windows to be its current patch set safely,
especially with like old industrial control systems.
But there's a reason
they don't want on
Windows
XP.
I don't want to even talk about this.
What I'm
saying is
the
i
the idea of upgrading the system or patching the system
or fixing the system or changing a config file.
We don't know that it's only gonna be a benefit there.
It could just make things massively
a rat's nest
car. It doesn't matter.
The question is,
should law enforcement be able to break into these
-- systems
-- with a warrant specific to that system?
Yes, but
that, that's the problem here is this gross
uh
broadening,
right? Of like, oh, you know, we we broke into this ransomware gangs systems
and now we have access to everything this ransomware gang has access to which,
you know, for some of those like, like not pia
is a good example
that was
so widespread
or uh code red
or whatever, right?
Well, code red is a bad example because that was like password list SQL which,
-- who knew that could be
-- a problem
20 some years ago now.
And it's still,
we're just still finally sort of getting over the
default password thing with like the eu saying,
uh what the, whatever the directive number is that you just can't like,
you, you can't make a default password of admin 123.
I keep coming back to what is the intent of this law.
And also the intent doesn't matter because once you have the law written,
you might have a new government in five or 10 years.
That's true.
Like,
but you, you still, you still haven't answered the question.
Should law enforcement be allowed to break into a system that
is secondary to the system they have the warrant for?
-- I think, no, I think the answer is absolutely not.
-- I think the answer is yes.
But with more guard rails and constraints
because I keep coming back to the, I don't want the fire to spread.
And so that, for example,
if law enforcement doesn't go into the system, how do they even know who to notify?
-- No,
-- no, no,
that's not the question
because
law enforcement
there, well, there's two, there's two parts of this.
I think law enforcement should be able to break into
a system if they have a warrant to do so
because I think it's no different than covertly installing a
bug in someone's house or their business or whatever,
with a warrant.
I think breaking into a second system should need a second warrant is what I think.
Well, and again,
the Real World analogs sort of fall apart because
if I get a warrant to go into your house
to look for a gun and I see like a pile of dead bodies on the coffee table.
Sorry, that's in play,
you know.
But on the other hand, yeah, I can't be like, oh,
I was searching for a gun and while we were like, excavating the foundation we found,
you know, a gold coin and you're not legally allowed to have gold or whatever,
like in a lot of countries you're not legally allowed to hold gold or whatever.
Um
Oh, really? I didn't know that actually
because they, they wanted the gold reserves to, you know,
have you read the terms of service on your safe deposit box?
You're actually not allowed to store money in it.
I, I know that
you can only store like money that has historical, like
historical value.
It can't be like modern money,
haven't you seen breaking bad? Like
they,
they use safe deposit boxes full of cash is their dead drop. Like
I get it.
But yeah, the list of stuff I'm not allowed to keep my safe deposit box.
I was like, wow, there's a lot of things like,
and basically it's all the things I would want to
keep in there because I want them to be safe.
Right. Anyway,
but back to this. So
I think the concern is we're entering an era where, ok, you have an IP address. Well,
great that like
20 years ago, given an IP address, you could figure out the ISP,
like in about a millisecond and then from the ISP and they could like,
figure out who owns that system.
Like, what's the billing contact for this IP.
It would be a computer with a person.
And now you have
like a bunch of stuff that's like
kind of on an IP address in the sense of it's
like behind that IP address from a net gateway and,
but like who's actually in charge of it or in control of it?
You know, you gotta kind of poke around the system maybe.
And some of it, like, I, I'm kind of wondering like, what,
like my Phillips Hugh light bulbs, like, for the sake of argument,
my Phillips hug light bulbs get hacked by a hacker.
The Dutch government goes into the hacker system and goes, hey,
they've compromised all these light bulbs.
Let's go into the light bulbs.
I guess they could pull the like, customer ID and then go to Phillips and be like,
you know, who's customer?
1234, like, let's go contact her or something.
We're stuck in a mindset of thinking of computers, but
everything's a computer. Now,
-- your oven, your toaster, your car.
-- I'm not saying they need to list Kurt as now.
II, I don't,
I'm not an expert in getting warrants,
but I believe today you have to actually like list a person or an address or
you don't.
-- Oh, well,
-- depending on the kind of warrant.
Well, because if you're looking for somebody, you don't know who it is. Like those
-- geofence warrants.
-- Ok. That's fair. That's a good point.
Like those
geofence warrants where we're like,
we just want every phone in this area at this time, the phone, this number
and, and look,
why can't, why can't you just get a warrant for an IP address then
be like this ransomware group infected this system. We want to go look at that.
-- You
-- might not know the IP
S
then what are you gonna attack?
Well, but for example,
what if it's under a tor network or something or it's
-- behind VPN even
-- then you still can't get to it,
right?
And I I,
you and your freaking, I hate your examples. Kurt.
Well, no, but for example,
you're forgetting things like I hack a hacking group
and I now control their command and control server.
So I can now tell all the hacked victims to like, tell me where they are,
-- send me an email and
-- I don't,
I don't know if that would apply. And, and so in my view,
I would not see that as breaking into a remote system. It's probably not.
Well, defined in any sense of the word.
Well, here's the problem.
Then by that definition, if I compromise Red Hat and compromise package updates,
then I'm not hacking you.
You're just installing malicious packages. Well, no, I'm absolutely hacking you.
Right.
And that's the thing. It's like part of the problem is this is all so poorly defined.
-- This is
-- very poorly defined
and
we're also stuck in this transition era of
everything's a computer
-- and we have in no way, shape or form come to terms with that.
-- It is true.
I did not think we would be arguing this particular detail
in this conversation.
Right. Well, but it's not a detail anymore.
It's people like, I know a guy that just bought a new stove and he's like,
it has an IP address and I'm like, you better make sure that you turn it on and like,
try to run it the day before Thanksgiving
so that when it wants to do a software update, you're not, you know,
up up the creek and not making dinner.
And he's like, oh,
it's true.
I hadn't thought of that. I'm like,
I love that. My car is just dumb. It's got a single color
screen thing that will let me pair to it with Bluetooth so I can play my music.
-- That's all I want. I don't want anything smarter than that.
-- I agree with you.
But my car has tons of computer.
I love the idea of Apple car play, like, I've used it in a rental car and it, oh,
it's nice.
But,
oh, man, like I've, hm.
So, but back to this,
I think problem is we're entering an era where everything is a computer and so it's,
and it's much more dangerous, like a,
like a desktop computer hooked up to an MRI machine. The MRI machine doesn't work.
Ok. That's sad. But like a Tesla,
uh, an oven, uh, a big industrial machine, uh a self driving forklift,
like forklifts are big and heavy.
I mean, ok,
so I wasn't thinking in this particular context and I have a suspicion that
the authors of that law were either they're probably thinking very system focused,
but you also raise another interesting point.
And I think this,
this is something that I think
or I, I rather, I feel
backs up my, my conclusion that we shouldn't just like Willy nilly do this stuff.
If some, if there is an MRI machine
and the authorities do break into it,
that's bad, right?
Like even if they know bad guys are in it,
having another person messing around with it probably isn't good.
Well,
I would say it's not ideal for sure.
But part of the problem is it also,
but it ignores the fact that there's already a bad guy in there.
Like we just had this happen with the
uh the Etr Certificate Authority.
Luckily a
good person took a poke at Etr
found them running some software
with the default admin credentials
in production.
And he went into the thing and was like, with default credentials and it was like, uh,
oh,
this is
a like, uh, and he like,
as far as we know, you know, he backed out and he posted publicly on the mailing list
and was like, you know,
blah, blah, blah, contacted them.
They said they fixed it, but I'm still a bit concerned
etr lied about it and said like, oh, it wasn't a big deal.
And the guy was like, uh, no,
actually I had access to like half a million records or some stupid number.
Oops. And
like, one of the things I pointed out to, it's like,
it's really nice that this guy who kind of went in through literally a
default administrative set of credentials was nice
enough to tell you and tell the community
that's not a high bar to hacking. Like, how do we know a bad
people weren't already in there
for real because that's such a low bar to hacking. But
I mean, it doesn't get much lower than that.
I mean, so actually,
so I was at a little conference literally yesterday,
which is, uh it was called Grassroots.
-- It's
-- ha I'm gonna bring up our listeners,
don't know when that was because this show comes out later.
-- Remember you say that every time to me? No,
-- I totally do.
But you also mentioned yesterday more than once and yesterday.
It is fine in this context because it's a meaningless ephemeral date. That is,
in fact,
this show isn't even gonna go out for probably
several weeks from the time we record it.
So I don't mind. But
so anyway, they had a panel on
cybersecurity insurance and they had a lawyer there who was talking about
kind of what, like what does it mean legally that you have to do in these situations?
And one of the things that was brought up,
how should you decide what was or wasn't leaked
during
an incident? Right?
And basically now like in in the context of what
you're talking about this registrar or not registrar C A,
right?
-- Yes,
-- certificate of authority, a root certificate of authority.
If,
if you can show compelling evidence that the data was not exfil traded in some way,
meaning like I have net flow logs,
this system,
I can show that no meaningful amount of data has exited this system.
We can say with confidence that the data
was not
exulted by the attacker, right? That totally makes sense.
Well, and a perfect example that's happened with revenue Canada in Hartley.
They actually said at one point it was
like 100 and 180 accounts were potentially compromised.
And it's like, wow, but here's the thing,
the kind of organization that has that technology
doesn't leave default user names and passwords in the software they deploy.
Probably not. But, but,
but, but here here's my point
when you don't know,
you legally have to default to assume the worst. So in the context of that C A,
they need to assume
that
a malicious attacker has accessed all of that data
like full stop.
Well, they're also lying about other stuff. So
anyways, I am completely confident
that the level of dirt baggery that's going on there is unspeakable.
But anyway, anyway, put, bringing this all back, right. Bringing it all back.
I, I feel like we have this discussion. There's this, like
there's the, the legal aspects, there's the technical aspects
and
I,
I am concerned
that law enforcement is trying to paint with too broad
of a brush just in general when it comes to
computers and tech
and the courts
have no freaking clue.
The lawmakers have no freaking clue.
I want to say the law, the, the, the,
the law enforcement have no freaking clue.
I think some of them know what they're going to be able to do,
but in general they probably don't really know what's going on either.
Well,
this is assuming law enforcement was driving this
and I'm not sure that's clear here.
I don't know. Like I've seen situations where
some enforcement organization, not, not just law enforcement but has been like,
that's bad legislation. Please don't do that.
It has happened before. Yeah.
And the lawmakers are like, oh, no, we think this is a good idea and they're like,
you really don't understand what you're talking about.
Like please for the love of God don't mandate that we all paint our houses green.
So that's
true. You know, and so,
and that's the problem.
Everything is so complicated here and then,
and then you start speaking about intent but you don't a we don't
know their intent and b their intent will change like society change,
governments change for sure.
So uh yeah, I don't know,
but I keep coming back to
we're in an era
where the potential for harm is much higher than in past.
Yeah.
And we need to find some way to deal with that because
fundamentally,
oh, perfect example. Did you read the thing about the uh
the flipper zero kerfuffle last week?
No, I have no idea what you're talking about.
Electronic meters uh like wireless electronic meters for your power
supply or for your power VTRL, right? And they,
they
report how much electricity you use and they have like a shut off thing.
Well, but they're also controlled wirelessly.
Now, do you think that they have very good,
strong security on that wireless interface?
Of course not.
Right. It's terrible.
So this guy basically had his flipper zero,
like basically tell the thing to like effectively
shut the power off and on a lot repeatedly
and guess, well, what do you think happens to a consumer level device
carrying 200 amps of power?
Uh 240 volts when you flick the switch off and on really fast for a while,
-- the magic smoke comes
-- out. There's many things that could happen. But yes, that's
-- it
-- died. It like,
did they only break the meter?
-- I would expect things in the house to also be broken after that.
-- But the point is
that they're,
they're sort of trying to put the blame on
flipper zero for being this dangerous device that enables this
attack to happen.
And of course, everybody on hacker news is like, no,
the phone
wise with this crappy
reader
and I'm like looking at my meter
thinking
it's probably just as insecure because like they're not gonna,
ok.
Actually, so there's a guy I had on the hacker History podcast some time ago,
he goes by hash, he has a youtube channel and I'll,
I'll post a link to one of his videos, the best one.
So he, he does a lot of smart meter hacking
and he found that there,
one of the security measures these smart meters
were using is they have like 256 channels.
I believe it is or maybe it's 100 and 28 it's a lot and they, they jump around, right.
And they have like predetermined.
Yeah, well, well, right, but no, the jumping around is part of their security
where the receiver and the sender know how to jump around.
And so anyway, he was trying to send a signal to this smart meter
and it was trying to jump around.
-- Yeah,
-- just send it on all 100 and 28 signals.
Well, that,
that's what he did is he used a AAA hack RF
and he just blasted the same thing over every single channel.
And so as it was jumping around listening, it was picking up exactly what it wanted.
I'm like,
that's so good because you figure, what,
10 years ago you couldn't have dreamed of that and now you could do it for like,
100 bucks.
Yeah, exactly. It's awesome.
I mean, so for example, I'm going to assume my,
like, even better when they were deploying these meters
app
Corp did so
not using electricians and all these electricians were like,
that's not good because that's a lot of electricity and angry electrons and
like, if everything goes smoothly and it's dry out and everything goes fine then,
yeah, you like, clip it, pop off the old one, pop in the new one, put the circuit, the,
the little ring on and put a little tag on it.
No problem.
But he's like, if anything is wrong,
are they gonna notice it? Like, are they competent enough to see that?
Like, oh, there's like a puddle in here or like a,
-- a raccoon or
-- how does this relate to our topic today?
So, the point is
that
again, like,
there's the real potential for harm with these things and these systems
are
always hackable and that's my other concern. Is that
there's no system that's basically un hackable outside of like
a few very limited number of crazy NSA whatever systems.
It,
it sounds to me like you're agreeing that
law enforcement shouldn't be allowed to do this.
No, quite the opposite.
Because the problem is though, like I said,
we've entered this era where everything is a computer, your electricity meter,
my water meter, they replace the water meter with this thing that
is like a Wi Fi and it's powered by the water going through.
It's got like a little turbine to power it. And I'm like, oh, that's clever.
Like that's cool that because I was like,
how does this get powered? And they're like little turbine. I'm like,
oh, well,
yeah,
that makes sense.
You know, it's got a little battery and a little
turbine thing or whatever magic. It, it apparently will,
the battery will never die. And I'm like,
that's not how batteries work.
And he's like, it is when they get recharged by the water. And I'm like, oh, ok, then,
you know,
and obviously your E meter is like, never gonna run out of juice.
And I'm
not,
I wonder when they're going to do the gas meter with wireless ones or did they
ever,
my gas meter has a battery in it because they put a wireless gas meter thing on.
I wonder if it has a turbine
for the floor, right? Because I don't know
-- you would. Well, you wouldn't need to, like, you don't
-- need to.
But gas is very low pressure.
Gas is only one or two P si, so it's gonna be tough to spin a turbine.
Well, or a little water wheel paddle thing anyways. The point is it doesn't matter.
II, I don't like this,
but here's the problem.
What's the alternative?
We just let hackers run rampant and when we compromise
or when you actually get into a hacker systems,
we're like, oh,
-- shoot, we can't go touch all those other systems.
-- That's not no, look,
there's always going to be bad people doing bad things like
that is not a question, right?
We're never going to get rid of crime.
I'm not saying law enforcement should just stand there and be like, well,
there's nothing we can do.
I'm saying
they need to operate in a, a, an environment that has checks and balances.
And I think telling them
if you get a warrant against this one group,
you can go whole hog on any system they have attacked.
Like, come on.
That's
so broad
and that sort of allows automation.
It allows them to just broadly collect everything and see
what's the problem and what's not
-- a problem.
-- I'm even comfortable with them collecting
1000 IP addresses and just going to a judge and being like this is, and look,
how often do you think judges deny warrants?
Probably never
under the FISA thing? I think that was three.
-- Like
-- never, but you know what I mean?
It's not even just the fact that they, they might get denied.
I'm comfortable with this. You just,
you need a process so that they can't, like, literally
just like, go straight down the hill as fast as they can.
They need to stop occasionally and be like, hey, judge,
we're doing this and the judge is almost certainly gonna be like,
ok, good job.
But when they do truly go off the rails, then the judge can be like, hold on a minute.
-- What's the problem with
-- that?
I was wrong.
It was four FISA warrants requests are rarely denied
during the 25 years from 1979 to 2004,
18,742 warrants were granted while only
were rejected and fewer than 200 requests had to be modified before being accepted.
Almost all of them in 2003, 2004.
So look,
I'm saying, basically
you're saying, let's add a check and balance. And I'm saying
it's just,
it's like
it's like those dialogue boxes in windows vista, they're just gonna hit.
-- Yes, they're just gonna hit. Yes.
-- FISA warrants are different.
Kurt
and these warrants are gonna be
-- always overseen.
-- I'm not saying they're gonna be drastically different. But
I think you get into situations where
if you're seeing abuse, obvious abuse,
you have an off ramp to start addressing that.
But if you get blanket permission past a certain point
that becomes a problem.
And that is the way I view this. I think as, as ridiculous as it sounds
having that extra step in there. Even if it's going to be rubber stamped.
99.9% of the time,
I think has value for the person who has to file the request
and for the person receiving the request. I think it changes the dynamic just enough
that it's going to help avoid like disgusting abuses of power.
So the one comment would be where I think that would actually
help with abuse of power is that it means there's now a
record with a different party of what was hacked and gotten into
that,
that I will grant you.
I would like to see as part of this law where they just,
if they are going to go into all these other systems,
they kind of maybe have to tell a third party some oversight that's external to them,
right?
Like
you don't have law like here in Alberta, we have uh what is it called? Um Aert,
what does it stand for?
Um Alberta serious incident response team?
And essentially they investigate when
bad things happen with the police, either to the police or from the police
because
as we've learned,
having the police investigate themselves, even if they do a good job,
people sometimes have a hard time believing like that's the thing.
It's like, yes, you cannot investigate yourself. It's like the
it's like when you have those, like, what, what is it, uh, regulation?
That's just no regulation.
-- No, I agree. I agree. There has to be
-- that appearance of fairness.
And so, ok, maybe that's part of the answer here is there has to be
some external sort of third party oversight
and,
and, and the paper trail. Right.
I think the paper trail helps because you can say, oh,
you're supposed to update the warrant with the new IP addresses and yada yada yada.
But the reality is
there that will, that will not happen, right?
I mean, we've all been there where it's like, oh,
I'll do this later and then you never do.
You know what I mean?
You start and mapping systems and you're like,
oh what's this weird IP address that leads
over here and then there's a VPN connection.
You're like bla bla bla
pretty soon you're somewhere in
Lord knows where West Germany
and, and I think the good guys need process and, and like
it takes time there. There's a person I love reading on Mastodon.
Her name is Terry Canfield and she's uh like a constitutional lawyer that,
that she teaches and she's been
analyzing just like literally everything happening
on the in the world for the last couple of years.
I'll put a link to her in the show notes.
But like one of the things she says is like, people are always like, oh,
this person needs to be in jail now.
And it's like, that's not how the law works.
-- Like, law takes time.
-- Yeah, that's one thing that always drives me nuts
when they're like, oh, this person allegedly did something bad.
They need to be fired or like, or whatever.
And it's like they're placed on administrative leave. That's not fair.
And it's like,
that's how justice works innocent until proven guilty.
Vigilante justice isn't justice. Right?
And, and I think that's one of the things, especially like in this context and again,
the lawmakers probably think, oh, this is great and,
but whatever,
all right, I think we need to land this plane.
It, it amuses me that we came to the same conclusion at the end. I love that.
I just,
I don't see any al alternative long term to dealing with this scale and level of stuff
other than to,
yeah,
I don't know,
but we do need some oversight. We do need to prevent abuse
a
100%.
-- And
-- so, yeah, but,
and we're clearly never gonna have secure systems. That's just not
a
-- reality.
-- That's right.
Right.
Like even Apple, like they pushed out that weird emergency, blah, blah dot B patch.
And I'm like, what on earth is this thing? Right.
-- Remember a few weeks ago,
-- did they ever, I, I haven't looked,
if they said what that was, we'll have to look that up at some point.
It was a security update. It was a really important security update.
That's why they,
no, I know that, but they said they were going to tell us what it was
later and I don't know if that's ever happened.
But anyway, while Kurt looks it up, he's distracted. So I'm gonna end the podcast.
So, thank you, Kurt. Thank you all for listening.
Go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up the show notes.
Suzie Pondo says podcast hashtag hit us up on social media.
-- Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day. You
-- too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone.
Bye bye.