Hello and welcome to the open source Security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
-- Josh Bresser. Uh,
-- good old Thought Crime. Ok. I have a, a complaint.
I, I want to register and this is something I not,
I've never really thought about before.
So I was at a small security conference last week called Grassroots.
It's a local show.
I did a talk about what is open source and that,
that's like a discussion we should probably have someday.
But anyway,
I,
I was giving some cards out to some people I'd met and I realized
like half my contact info was wrong on these business cards and I'm like,
I probably need to get new ones.
-- That's why
-- I only ever put my email address.
Well, so, so that's what I was thinking about.
I was like, you know what, I'm just gonna, like,
make my own cards with all of the contact info I want on it.
Like it just whatever work I'm gonna ignore like your fancy cards.
I know the CS A ones like we used to put Twitter on there and stuff and it's kind of like.
Right. Right.
But
I, I'm, I'm happy to do that.
I would like to put like Mastodon and stuff like that on there. Right.
But
so anyway,
I created SPG files for all the things I want on this and I go to like Vista Print and I
upload the SVG files and the things they show me
are not the things I put in the SVG file.
Right? And I'm like thinking, hm, is the SVG renderer they have bad.
So the thing I see on the, on the website is just wrong.
What, where is the disconnect here?
And if I get this card made, what am I going to get back?
And part of me is tempted to just do it to see what happens.
But anyway, I was like,
I'd always thought of svgs as like this magic universal file format.
Dude, we can't even render text safely. Like,
like people manage to mess up
Asy text. That's probably fair, right? Like there's slash ends in there.
Should that be a slash end or an actual break? No, I'm serious.
Like
I discovered, oh, favorite thing I discovered that in. Oh, what the heck.
So somebody at the CS A sent me a CS V file
and I'm like parsing it in Python and it's just like barfing all over the place.
And I'm like, what in the heck?
And it's saying some weird UTF eight sequence and I look at the file and it's like, no,
and what it was is Excel
can put in
uh character at the beginning of the line to basically specify that like, kind of, I,
I'm getting this slightly wrong but basically that,
like there's unicode or something in this line
and something like that.
So, like there's special encodings that Excel can drop into a CS V file.
That's exciting. And it was a specific CS V encoding character thing.
Yeah. Like there's all sorts of like even quote
unquote, air quotes, simple as
text CS V file with quotes and commas.
No,
like I totally messed that up and had to
spend an hour learning about this special command character.
Then
you there's probably a Python library that can do this correctly.
-- No, no, but
-- it's just I, I was expecting a CS V file that was asking and it wasn't
right. Like it's one of those, this is UTF eight and I'm like, but why?
-- But none of the data has UTF eight
-- anyway.
It's all exciting and fun
breaks.
Nothing works like this is why animated Jeeps are still used because
the only video format we can all render.
-- You don't
-- even notice though is now when I download a dot Web P file,
I can actually somewhat correctly interact with it on windows.
Whereas before it was just like,
you know, and I'm like
my web browser can do this. Why can't windows anyway,
right? Like I would just like to print this image or whatever you know,
I
know. So,
yeah. So, well, speaking of which, so open SSH is adding a feature.
If it had been added maybe 25 years ago, it would have been somewhat useful,
but nowadays it's kind of useless.
I disagree. I don't think it's useless at all. I'm glad they're doing this.
The, the title from Open BS D Journal
of the show notes says open SSH
introduces options to penalize undesirable behavior,
meaning things doing
like brute force attempts or crashing the open SSH process or whatever will they,
they, they looks like there's, they're not turning down by default
and there's a default of a 32nd time out. It sounds like
I, I love this. I think that I wish they'd done this a long time ago.
-- So
-- what is this? Explain to us what it is?
Well, my understanding is, it's kind of like, it's, it's similar to what,
what failed to ban was way back in the day, right?
Where essentially if you run an open SSH server on the internet,
regardless of support because I run one on a screwy port thinking, oh,
I'll escape all the BRT Marsha, Tamsa.
No, if you run open like an SSH server on the internet,
it's getting hammered all the time by random
log in attempts. And
the intent being
that what will happen is obviously, generally speaking,
open SSH doesn't have a concept of
like uh uh what do they call the, the time out
when you try to log in too many times, like rate limiting or rate limiting.
There you go. That's the word.
It doesn't really have that.
So Attackers will just like hammer the crap out of your machine
and try like a million passwords and when none of them work,
they move on to the next machine.
And so the intent
is that if it sees behavior like this from either one IP or a subnet block,
the subnet block being important, especially in like I PV six land.
So it can basically time out those IP spaces and say for 30 seconds,
you can't connect to me at all.
-- So
-- here's my question. What specific
threat
is it addressing?
I think there are two specific threat.
Number one,
the brute force
problem is real. Why? Why?
Because people put crap on the internet all the time that have,
-- shouldn't
-- people be using SSH keys?
A lot of people don't.
So I would point out there if you're using, for example, default passwords.
Well, this will get in actually eventually anyways.
-- No,
-- I don't think it, well, I mean,
potentially it depends on how complicated the password is,
let's say for the sake of argument using a top 1000 known like test,
test admin 1234 kind of thing
this will get in it won't stop it because the
attacker will just rotate IP S. See the I think part of the problem is
people a lot of people still think
-- IP addresses are hard to get and they're not,
-- no IP S are easy to get.
That's not, that's not the concern though, Kurt.
So the thing is I'm less concerned about brute forcing necessarily
because I think brute forcing, like you said, like if you're using a crap password,
someone's going to get in eventually whether you're banning IP S or not.
I, I like that. If it, something is correct.
Dashing the SSH service, it will also ban that.
That one feels better to me because there have been multiple
attacks against servers where in order to execute the attack,
you have to basically try something a million times.
-- That particular use case, I think is a big deal
-- until you're on a carrier grade. Nat,
like
when I use my cell phone, I am basically on the same IP address as
everybody in Canada on tell us network.
That's right. And so if it bans that IP
uh
-- oops,
-- well, too bad for you then, but that's
what I'm pointing out is
so turn it off.
That's the thing. Ok. No, no. Ok. Look, here's the thing.
You're taking the attitude too many security people take, which is,
this doesn't solve all the problems.
So it's stupid and useless and we don't need it.
And the thing is when people do this kind of stuff, it, it
infuriates me because there is so much that has been helped
back in the world of security for so long because,
and I used to be just like this a decade ago, I'll, I'll totally put, put my,
all the blame on me here.
But there's this prevailing attitude of, if it's not perfect, it's not worth doing.
-- And that is ridiculous, it is wrong and ridiculous to have that
-- attitude.
That's not what I'm trying to say.
-- What I'm trying to say is in this
-- case,
the cure
my soapbox,
then you have to learn to speak better
-- because that's what everyone hears from security
-- people.
What I was trying to say
is that this is a situation where
here is a cure and in some cases, the cure is worse than the disease.
And that is not really explicitly explained
here in the documentation and everything.
Like if you look at the commits and the documentation added with it, for example,
they don't mention
that, oh, you know, if you're on carrier grade net on a cell phone,
there is a high potential that if somebody else scans from that IP address.
And here's the fun thing.
There was a thread on hacker news about a year
ago talking about how do you download websites very reliably
because for example, like I can run a headless chrome and that will solve, you know,
because they're blocking curl and w get user agents.
So I run a headless chrome to get all the javascript running and everything. OK?
But they're banning my IP. What do I do.
And the number one answer is
you use carrier grade N
IP S because nobody wants to block like all of tell us in Western Canada, I mean, sure,
because like, as a website, I can't do that because like, uh for example,
when I use the VPN on my desktop here,
you know, Google gets very aggressive about like,
oh you need to log in again and like literally every a couple hours, Google's like,
who are you?
We're gonna double check because like the IP is so kind of mi
uh it's misbehaving badly. Google
block the IP address because then they would be blocking everybody on Nord VPN.
I, I'm not gonna disagree with you at all.
I think that's an extremely valid point and a good concern. So here's the thing.
There is probably a lot of people who don't understand this.
I don't have a total grasp on this either because quite frankly,
I just don't do anything valuable over my cell phone because it's a cell phone.
But the thing is
doing something like this, adding this sort of feature is step one and saying, oh,
it's worthless because of cell phones.
No, no, no,
no. This is like a learning experience.
There are going to be multiple steps along the path and if, if this is a problem,
we there there are going to be solutions.
-- I don't know what they are,
-- but we already have a better solution.
We have a much better solution for SSH and brute forcing. And that is
permit password login. No,
and only a lock key login.
I,
well, that's, no, that's not enough though, Kurt, because
the reality is you can have instances where keys get leaked.
You can have exploits.
-- Then
-- how is banning their IP address gonna work
-- because they're gonna log in with it
-- because,
no, no, what you're gonna see is, let's say there's a leaked key.
They're just gonna spray the internet with the leaked key.
I mean, that's what you see now where if you run an SSH server on,
on the public internet,
you see just like random keys being attempted against my server, like constantly.
-- Well,
-- because like open SSL that one time and Debian only generated 64,000 keys.
Oops.
Yeah. Yeah. Right. Right.
But, but anyway, my,
my point is there is nothing wrong with a feature like this had security.
Here's here is my honest opinion. Had security people been less like this
10 or 20 years ago,
we could have experimented more and learned more things because every
time you try to do something you're going to learn,
there is nothing wrong or bad with adding features like this.
It is a learning experience. Is it an end? All be all? Absolutely not.
No one should think of it that way. It
is a learning experience and by people coming out and saying, oh, it's stupid or bad.
Like if you read the hacker news comments.
The, it's just like this,
I think it is wrong to claim something is bad or dumb.
For one specific reason,
it is a learning experience and we need to use this stuff to learn.
-- So
-- I'm going to push back on that saying we've learned this, we have failed to ban.
People have run it for decades.
We know how this works and how it happens.
Do we?
Yeah, I, I ran,
fail to ban and then I stopped because I
realized the better solution was permit password login.
No, and only allow key access. Sure.
I, I agree.
So my, my problem with fail to ban was it was too jumpy or, or too,
I don't know what to call it.
It was a bit more Banny than it should have been.
-- Well,
-- this is going to have the exact same behavior if that's a problem.
This has a 30 second time out though, fail to ban would ban forever.
I don't know if fail to ban, could ban for 30 seconds. I honestly, I, I turned it on,
I managed to ban myself and then I just turned it off.
-- Instead of looking deeper into it. You
-- could configure it.
II,
I did have it either configured or custom mangled up to un ban after a while because,
yeah, that was one of my concerns.
Yeah.
And,
and like 30 seconds would be perfect because so here's
the thing and here's why I love the 32nd idea
when you have any sort of brute force going on, obviously,
people are going to try probably millions or thousands
of attempts a second to log into an account.
Right.
And even if you like, they try five times and then you give them 30 seconds to time out,
now you've gone from like
millions of attempts per second to like, maybe
100 an hour. Right. That's a huge difference.
And to be clear that 32nd is just an example given it's, I don't know what the actual
is.
-- That's 30 seconds is what they say. It sounds like it'll be the default. But
-- yes,
no, it said eg 30 seconds against the client
just as example.
So regardless. So,
but this leads to the thing. And what I was trying to get at is
this to me is not a good security feature and please hear me out
what this is a good feature is essentially slowing the Attackers down.
It's like the tar pitting with postfix where you have, for example, back in the day,
you have postfix set up to like,
no, you can't send me an email right now,
come back in four hours because spammers don't
like they, they don't come back. Remember that, right?
And now the annoying thing is, is, you know, when you got new email from people,
yeah, you'd have to wait four hours to get a reply from them the first time around.
I want it now right now.
-- But it was only for email addresses you've never seen before
-- so
I could set it, I think to the domain level, which I did some places because,
-- right, like,
-- that's fair,
you know,
like,
yeah,
at least once they sent you spam once, then they can.
But
again, it's like, it's like the tar pitting where, you know, somebody sends
connection to you and you, you send a really
slow
response
that, you know, that forces their scanning activity to go from like, yeah,
1000 scans an hour, 10 or 100 or, and, you know, and it,
it essentially breaks the economics because
Attackers have to be efficient because like, they're,
they're running on a shoestring budget.
There's two kinds of Attackers though. One of them has to be efficient.
That's the opportunistic attack. But the, the directed attack,
those are the people that will just get
a million IP addresses and do one attempt for IP against you.
And so I think the thing here is I wouldn't call this a security feature
because otherwise that's like calling,
oh, you know, those little, like concrete blocks at the front of the parking lot.
So you don't like park your car
where, like, you don't go past them.
That's like calling those a security feature.
No, it's like, so you feel a bump with your car and you stop going,
you hopefully don't run into the store or whatever.
Right? Whereas if you actually want security, you put giant honking boards
in front.
Well, ok,
I think the definition of security is broken.
-- I'll
-- agree with that because we have this obsession with like, it has to be a bank
or it's worthless. And
what we're talking about here is the concept we often call defense in depth
where there isn't like one thing that's going to solve the problem.
I have 700 little things
all meant to slow down or, or steer an attacker away from me
and it's going to give me time to react and detect, not necessarily stop the
attack.
Actually, I think you just said the important thing to steer the attacker away.
-- Right. And a lot of businesses do this where, I mean,
-- for opportunistic.
Yes.
Well, and a lot of businesses do this, you know,
where they have like giant security sign
labels all over everything so that hopefully the attacker goes,
oh, I'll just rob that other store that doesn't have those warning labels.
Yeah, I mean, that's right
when you're dealing with opportunistic Attackers. Absolutely.
And I think in this case, this is a good example of like putting up that, you know,
warning dog will bite you if you come on my property
kind of sign, right?
This is not going to stop a targeted attacker and that's ok because
the way you would do that is by having
key authentication, not passwords like sure, sure, simple.
But, and I think that's a big part of the prompt too is like, Show Dan, right.
Show Dan dot IO basically scans the internet.
-- Like, what, every couple of hours,
-- 7.5 minutes.
Right.
And you know, and then the thing is like, yeah, they fire off like,
there's like things like mass scan where you, you know,
if you have enough bandwidth and a laptop with more than about four gigabytes of ra M,
it just,
it can scan the entire internet in like eight hours or the entire
-- four internet in like a couple of hours.
-- V six. We haven't figured out yet.
Well, I don't think you really have to because you know DNS
but uh anyways back to this. So
I think the problem is this feature,
I personally would modify it more so that it is
safer to enable by default and essentially slows down attack
so that it can be enabled by default.
And for example, if you make SSH scanning by default,
let's do a round number 10 times more expensive computationally,
that's going to discourage and stop some people from doing it.
Yep. Yep. And ideally what we
see that the flip side of this is, is there's such a an economic
incentive to like showdown dot A O charges money for access to their database.
So they have a strong economic incentive to scan the entire internet.
And what I love then is, you know, as an attacker, I don't have to scan the internet.
I can just pay showdown, like,
100 bucks a year or whatever it is.
-- I
-- don't think it's even that much.
And, like, search for my, you know, I can search for like, all the SSH scanners in,
like the western side of Edmonton.
Yeah, it's got geographic search.
And so again, this kind of comes back to the,
I don't, I'm, I'm,
I want to get away from, like, I'm not trying to say that, oh, this isn't perfect.
So we shouldn't do it. But I'm saying is
the effort we invest in this.
We,
we already did it once with fail to ban and essentially everybody stopped doing it.
So unless this feature can actually be enabled
by default and work safely by default,
I would say, is it worth the effort
or should you put your effort somewhere else
like making sure you get key authentication only?
No,
I don't think that's a reasonable argument because I think
for number one open SSH is an open source project.
They're allowed to do what they want.
If you think they're wasting their time like f off, they don't care.
No, I'm not worried about them wasting their time.
I'm worried about them wasting my time
-- and everybody else's time,
-- they're not going to waste your time. It's not default.
Are there other things they could do? Absolutely. There, there definitely are.
I think the reason failed to ban
quite frankly. Just never caught on. It's because it wasn't included by default.
-- Uh
-- It was actually in some Linux distro, maybe
in a Linux distro.
But I think fundamentally this is a sort of behavior like if they make it optional,
I bet 1% of SSH users turn this on
less than that. Maybe. I mean, this is an example of we need to
make good security defaults because no one is going to turn it on,
It has to come out of the box with this stuff on.
So I think that is the advantage of putting
this kind of functionality into the open SSH server.
Like would it have been more effective 20 years ago?
Yes, 100%.
But I think there's value in doing things
like this now because lessons will be learned
and we can apply those lessons then in the future to even things beyond open SSH.
So perfect example here, why not just use zero trust import knocking,
boom done and you don't have to deal with Attackers even seeing your SSH?
Some people do that, but that's not default,
right? Again,
whatever the default is is what people are going to use.
I guess my fear here is people are going to get a false sense of
security that this actually somehow stops Attackers when
it's really only just slowing them down.
I don't know, maybe, I mean,
I think slowing down opportunistic attacks is almost
the same as stopping them because an opportunistic attack
hacker isn't going to stick around.
They're just going to leave.
Hopefully. No, not, hopefully that's
how they work.
Like that's opportunistic Attackers are looking for low hanging fruit.
All you have to be is a little higher than the apple below you. And you're good.
Well, that's back to that school of fish thought. Right.
Like,
you only have to swim a little faster than the rest
of the school of fish to get away from the shark.
You know, and the shark doesn't care who it eats.
No, because like, there's like, because it, I think people forget like 25 years ago,
you couldn't scan the internet,
you couldn't attack everybody in a country in an afternoon,
which like
you can do that now, computationally, like I have a gigabit of bandwidth at home.
That's more like I remember when internet backbones
were t like 45 megabits per second.
And now that's like
I would call my cell company to complain that my speed is broken if it was that slow.
Right.
That was only 20 years.
The whole universe of internet and technology has moved forward very quickly and
I think the way we secure things has moved too slowly.
And my other thought is anybody who actually cares
about this kind of stuff is already using,
fail to ban or port knocking or zero trust or has SSH on their
servers in a virtual private cloud or whatever the heck your vendor calls it.
Right.
So, but internally, like,
like I just internally stood up an application that has a bunch of,
it's like five docker containers and it's got like a
Mongo DB that's like totally unauthenticated and freaking wide open.
But it's only available on like that little internal docker network.
So, like, who cares?
Like, if you're into that network, I'm so far beyond up the creek.
It's not even funny.
Yes. And so
again, I come back to,
I want to see this feature done in a way
where it can just be enabled by default and like it
-- makes Attackers lives a little bit more miserable. I mean,
-- I think that's the plan
they, they mentioned in the announcement, like they want to turn it on someday.
Here's what they wrote.
We hope these options will make it significantly
more default difficult for Attackers to find accounts,
blah, blah, blah.
Like
this is HD itself. It says
per source penalties is off by default.
We expect to enable it automatically in the near future.
It's like that's the goal.
Yeah, I mean, and maybe it'll work and maybe it'll help.
I, it also depends on what like the values that they choose matter. Sure.
But that's the thing we get to learn by trying new things.
And again, this is, is the sin of security from the past
is perfect or nothing and nothing always won.
Well, I think part of it too was you got to remember we have very finite.
Like a lot of people have very finite resources.
They're like, by definition, if they had more resources,
they would update their software once in a while.
Like a lot of people want to update their software but can't,
because they don't have the time and,
you know, or things might break or will break.
-- But
-- again, that's an excuse for poor behavior. Kurt, there is no reason
-- but,
-- ok, but I'm saying that that's the reality.
That's not the reality.
There are two sides to this coin.
What you're talking about is the consumer side of this. What I'm talking about
is
in the past,
a project would suggest a thing like this and the whole security
community would come and take a big poop on top of them
and say that isn't going to solve all the problems.
So you're dumb and you're wasting your time and you're
an idiot and we would literally hound them so bad
they would give up
and they would never try it again.
That is what we used to do. You and I have done that to more than one project.
-- Well,
-- you
-- used to still do,
-- well, it's happening right now
in
freaking hacker news.
But that's the thing that behavior is inexcusable and should be not tolerated
in any instance because this is an example of let's try something.
Let's see what happens. The people who can't update their software,
they have other problems, but
in theory, if we can make software better when they can update their software,
they're going to get something more secure than what they have today.
Well, and that leads to something I've been thinking a lot about recently,
which is this
appeasement, like perfect example on Mastodon, somebody's like the L
journal is issuing all these bad CV S and I'm like,
are they bad, like then get them rejected?
Like there's a process for that and the person literally applied with
you should do that
and tell me how it goes and I'm like,
I'm blocking you.
-- Like, and, and the person even actually Greg
-- ended up blocking them as well.
They got even worse.
Oh,
-- wow! Ok. I'm so glad I didn't. Like, I'm so glad I'm not very
-- happy.
I didn't because I got to see the trade.
-- I might
-- want
to see that later.
But the point is this person even made like, like he said, if you to me, like, are you,
if you're making a good faith argument and then
proceeded to say I should do all the work.
And it's like,
no, that's not how this works at all. Even a little bit buddy.
Right.
I'm not even gonna like,
invoke an argument from authority where it's like I've done
a lot of rejected CV S my own and others.
Yeah, it's a thing that happens. It's fine.
Well, that's, that's another conversation I think.
But this boils down to, I think the open source world.
I'm very specifically not saying the security world,
I'm saying the open source world
needs to stop being so
appeasement.
Uh
Yeah. Oh, yeah. Yeah, they need to stop appeasing people.
Like I literally just grabbed a new chunk of software,
probably going to use them for the next 5 to 10 years heavily.
And I found a small,
technically a security flaw and it, it, I actually pointed out to them, like,
technically it's a security flaw, but it's,
I actually viewed it more as a compliance with
GDPR flaw because it can expose email addresses.
Right.
And I don't care about that from a security point of view,
but I do care about it from my GDP auditors yelling at me point of view.
And so like,
you know, and the solution is easy.
It's just when you do the forgot password reset thing,
don't tell them if the account exists or not.
Just say like, if the,
you know, if this exists, we sent them
and he's like,
he's like, yeah,
you're like, yes, from a, from an audit and compliance point of view. Absolutely.
This needs to be fixed.
And I'm like, yeah, I'm like, don't even bother getting a CV. Like, who cares?
This is so trivial, right? It does not matter.
-- Well, and it's gonna take like an hour of work to get that.
-- Uh
not even you change one config message.
No, I mean, to get a CV E,
-- it's
-- gonna take
and well, but what's funny is like I came to him with this and I came to him, like,
here's one way to fix it is like just edit this message to be the same as the other one.
But that's the thing I am now coming to him with. I really would like this.
Please fixed and here's like a good way to do it.
And here's blah, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah blah.
And that's
what you have to do.
Well, no, you don't have to because like
that guy went to see was a bully about it or this guy on Mastodon,
like do tell us like what did he get worse?
Like what did he just demand everybody do everything for him.
No,
he called out Greg for a particular description
but he purposely only copy and pasted half
the description and he left off the part that said it was a denial of service.
He was so good.
This person cherry picked text to try to prove his point,
but Greg obviously knew what he was going on.
So he called him out for it.
And that's a perfect example of like, I don't care if that person is,
I don't care if their intent is good or malicious, their behavior is bad,
but it's time to stop, it's time to start blocking them and just go on with life.
So like for the ssh people, if they're listening to the show, yeah,
feel free to ignore me.
I'm
-- quite possibly
-- wrong. They definitely ignore Kurt. Please ignore Kurt. But
in general, I think that
needs to solve. But at the same time
on a totally separate thing,
we do need to think about having solutions that are effective and useful because
remember when I used to think having more CV S was a good thing
and we'll have all the CV S for N PM and it'll be great.
And many, I've
talked to some high level people and they're like, yeah, we, we can't handle the CV S.
-- We got, we
-- need better data.
I agree. We were both in that boat. We were both wrong.
Very wrong.
We need better data. Not
because we need better data. We need better data
so that we can then enable
the possibility of automation.
Because right now,
like what I realized is everybody right now
reinvents every major CV E wheel by like having
to research it themselves and then can't publish
that anywhere sane to share it with people,
which is completely bonkers.
Right?
And I just did a test one. And it's funny because Miter is like, oh, that's in the NVD.
We can't fix it and go talk to the NVD. And I'm like, oh right. I,
I keep forgetting that the NVD and Miter are two separate CV databases.
Yes,
that's
right.
I keep forgetting that because in my brain,
they were supposed to be playing together.
-- That was one of the goals.
-- That's ok.
We have three now because sis is doing their own thing called bone enrichment.
So now we have Miter
NVD
github. That's true. Github
-- does their own thing too.
-- Github.
Count if you type in a CV E into like a read be dot MD on github
and publish
and then click on that CV. Where does it go?
-- Goes to the get up security advisory now
-- for what it's worth.
I, I almost exclusively send updates to
github just because it's so easy to do.
And I don't care if whatever, if miter falls behind, it doesn't matter.
They're the only people that respond.
Yeah,
you send Apr to
github
and usually it gets accepted in like an hour
and that's it. I'm done.
And if they have a question,
they ask a question and then we have a public conversation about it
and sometimes it'll be like we disagree with you and I'm like,
well, I think you're wrong but whatever, I can't really do anything about that,
that's fine
-- and it's ok, it's in
-- public.
That's where my container format was designed to have
conflicting opinions in the data and allow that,
but it's not gonna happen.
-- Well,
-- that,
that's too hard to unwind. Ok.
So anyway,
we're kind of running ourselves out of time here and I don't want to drag this on.
Ok.
So I want to end on this point and I think your appeasement
comment makes a lot of sense and I think that's a very,
very powerful and important thing.
I mean, this totally goes all the way back to Tama de Pierres. I am not a supplier,
I
think.
Well, also is it, is it your, is it a supplier or your supplier?
-- It was I am not your supplier.
-- I'm looking this up. I am not a supplier.
His blog post is titled I am not a supplier
success. I
thought it was,
you
know,
-- well,
-- he's also not my supplier but you know,
that's what it was.
Yeah, I remember now it's like, yeah,
because part of the argument was I am not a supplier at all.
So
I I
think
the appeasement story is important for a couple of reasons.
I think there's the angle of XZ of
like if you're an open source project, you do what you want to do,
you owe no one anything right?
There's the angle of for so long these
open source projects would like try something like this
open ssh thing like security people would show up and pile it on and they like,
well, I must be dumb because everyone's telling me I'm dumb.
So I just won't do this
when in reality,
like it could have been an experiment that we got valuable information out of
and and that's not how it works, right? And then I think on the other side,
there's the if you are a consumer of open source,
you can't just like show up making demands and requests.
You really like what you were saying, you have show up with a patch, you know,
-- try to help.
-- Ah perfect example,
this software I'm using
doesn't have any backup documentation.
And so I showed up saying I want to
write the backup documentation because regardless of this,
I need to back it up anyways.
And I'm like,
I think it's this thing in the Mongo TB and this
other thing and this other thing in these two critical files
is that all? And next question like, how do we go about writing this?
Like, do I submit apr do we talk about it? Do we like what, what's the culture here?
Because like, I've kind of looked through it and I'm not really 100% certain
and
the guy is talking to me
like, yeah, we're talking, you know, and it's, it's good
and that's, you know, if, if even 1% of people could behave like that,
it would push open source forward quite a bit
faster because I'm also beginning to realize like,
like that thing on Mastodon, I am now at the point where to put it bluntly,
I have the maturity to say, oh,
this person is throwing dog poo at people.
I'm going to put up a magical force field so they can't
throw dog poop at me and I'm going to ignore them completely.
-- I
-- ban people like un unmasked and actually there was someone the other day
that I posted one of my CV E graphs and they replied with,
you should never make graphs again and then explained what was wrong with my graph.
And I'm like, you know what ban?
Like I'm not even going to reply to this. It's not worth my time
like it. That's the beauty of, I think things like Mastodon is as,
as poor behavior emerges. It feels much easier to just get rid of it altogether.
Well, the other thing I'm realizing is there is
a statistical chance they might say something useful and helpful.
But in most cases, even if they do,
it's buried in so much other garbage and time
wasting stuff that it's just not worth it.
I agree. I agree.
And this goes back to like that whole classic trope of,
like the rockstar programmer that's like toxic and kills the team.
Like, ok, you killed your team but you had one productive programmer. Good job.
And the era of that is needs to end.
No, I think it, I think it's over. I don't think
there's a rock
star concept like there used to be.
I definitely feel like there was much worse behavior 20 years ago
than,
I mean, I think some of the things I did 20 years ago would get me fired today.
I have no doubt. And it, it, I'm glad. Right. That's the way it should be. All right.
I'm gonna call this one. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you for listening. Go,
go to open source security, podcast.com U
Podos S podcast. Hashtag on Mastodon. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye.