Hello and welcome to the open source Security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in
a Thought Crime.
Josh Pressers.
-- That was impressive.
-- It's been five weeks.
I know it's been a long time since we've talked. I used to talk a lot and
it's been busy,
but I'm, I'm back from the Open
Source Summit and I just want to say there
were an enormous number of people who asked about you
-- and that made me very happy.
-- So,
like, do I owe them money?
No. Yes, they were shaking me down for money. You owe them, Kurt.
No, they're worried about you. That's great.
So we're back. Hello. Thank you everyone for the love. It's appreciated.
I actually hadn't told Kurt that till just now. So,
-- so
-- just to clear the air. So basically my ex wife is sick.
So I'm now full time taking care of my kids and one of my kids is um special needs,
has autism
and needless to say
both of my kids are horrifically stressed out by this whole situation.
Gee, imagine that.
And so
the, the, yeah, there's just a lot of challenges but uh we're doing ok,
we're actually all losing weight, which is good because we're eating better.
We're eating as a family and yeah, it's good
and um actually my one son is going to school like in the morning and the afternoon
and he's asking to go.
-- Oh, that's
-- fantastic.
That hasn't happened in years.
So things are actually better in some ways, but I'm just very sleep deprived.
Very, very sleep deprived.
That's like the worst thing ever, man.
-- It is literal torture. Right.
-- Right. Yeah. Literally, literally.
Anyway. Alright,
-- I'm gonna, I'm gonna move straight along
-- now.
So the open source summer because yeah, I really,
that's something I would have loved to go to because it's only an hour flight for me.
So it was in Vancouver, Canada, which
is a lovely city for anyone who hasn't been. I've never been there before.
-- It's
-- like San Francisco but with healthcare
I, that's fair.
-- Yeah. Yeah, I mean it has that kind of feel to it, it
-- same climate,
it was similar, it was much warmer than San Francisco I think.
Well, that's true. We do have a heat wave across and like my province is on fire
like all of it.
That's true.
There was, there were no fires I could see while I was there but it was good
and,
and so I have kind of two big takeaways I thought we should talk about from the Open
Source Summit.
I Well, ok, let me kind of rephrase this for anyone who doesn't know because
I'm sure there's people listening that are like open source summit.
What the heck is that?
The Linux Foundation used to have a conference called Linux Con,
which was a lovely show.
Many years ago. I went to it a couple of times
and it was super nerdy.
What Linux Con was nerdy, obviously.
-- I mean, you fill a building full of Linux people and it gets nerdy. But no, no, no,
-- no.
I mean, like
if you look at a conference like Rs A or black hat,
I would say those are not nerdy conferences, those are marketing,
those are sales conferences.
-- Right.
-- Exactly. Whereas the open
source summit is still a very nerdy conference.
It is not a sales focus conference and that's great because I,
I enjoy that I enjoy the people there
and you have marvelous conversations and many of the talks are very good and you
see people that you've known forever because it's
just a bunch of old open source nerds
-- pretty much hanging out
-- at this point
people.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. And it's great.
But anyway,
there were kind of two themes I really latched on to from talking
to people and sitting through talks and I gave a couple of panels and
the first theme I think is
we are still focused on fear and security.
When,
when someone's trying to talk about like supply chain
security or build system security or application security,
they're all,
it's just about, oh, do you know who's building your packages?
-- Do you trust your developers? Can you trust your build system? And I'm
-- like,
how do you know there aren't peanuts in there?
It's never worked. Why do we keep doing this? That's what I keep thinking.
So
I'll tell you why
we keep doing this is because the alternative of
being empathic and patient and kind and listening to people
is really hard work. Like you have to fundamentally change who you are as a person.
That's it. No.
Like, and I say this like,
I have a special needs child who I literally drop him off school
in 20 minutes that I get a phone call from the school.
And she's like, I,
I'm having trouble understanding like what he's
saying because he's asking for a video.
She's like, and she's like, ok, can you say it again?
And he's like, blah, blah, I'm like, oh groceries,
he wants the grocery bag and it like you anyways,
the point is I've over the last 10 years have honestly fundamentally changed how I
listen to people because I've had to learn to listen to somebody very carefully,
very patiently, very kindly.
And that is a
really hard skill to develop. I won't disagree with that.
The majority of people don't understand my son.
And I'm like, it's clear he's saying this, he wants this like, duh, just listen to him
and I've actually got a document where I talk about like if he says this,
what he means is this, you know,
because he uses give and take, he doesn't say take,
just give like or like when he says,
I want to look at something that means also use or consume,
right? So he says, I want to look at your candy bar,
I'll be getting it back.
I mean, look, I say that all the time, I never give it back.
So
and that's the thing.
So learning to listen patiently and with empathy and with kindness and to,
and to really like that classic thing of like, OK,
what I'm hearing you say is this,
but maybe do you mean this or let's go level deeper, like essentially doing
therapy on the person of like, OK, you say you want an application that does X but
what you really do, you really want
maybe it to do this thing
and you're just kind of trapped in thinking it has to be done this other way.
And that's why you're asking for an accounting app.
I mean, OK, so I think
you are correct, but
I don't think
-- security
-- people, oh it's, this is not a solution. People won't do this.
Well, it's not even a matter of doing it. I don't think
we understand many of the problems enough.
And, and so I actually,
I have a marvelous example of this is I was sitting in a panel where people were
talking about like the salsa framework and the Fresca
framework and Microsoft's S two C two F,
it is Frescas like
a,
no, it's Fr CS A,
it's an open SSF thing. It is a,
what do you call it? The, it's like an example build system.
It has a fancy name that escapes me at the moment.
I'm still very tired from, from being gone for a week.
But anyway, I'm sitting through a panel and someone's going on and on and, and they,
they make the off color comment about, oh, if, if you have salsa,
you don't have to worry about
solar winds. I'm like, hold on, hold on, hold on. I'm, I'm in the audience.
I'm like, I'm like, hold on, hold on. I need to interrupt for just a moment here.
And I said, we love to hand wave
these
kind of attacks as, oh, if only you did this thing, this, this,
this thing I'm working on,
it would solve the problem. And it's like,
no,
and I did find out actually there,
there's a group in the open ssf called the end users working group.
They are doing work
on basically creating a li like, like taking these attacks, right?
Things like log for shell solar winds, whatever,
taking all these attacks
and kind of mapping them into. What part of infrastructure would this affect?
And then how could we change what we do
to have avoided that
in the past? Which I think is exactly
the right thing. To do.
Uh I feel like you should maybe tell them about the attack framework, which is,
that's the whole point of this,
right?
And, and the the the end user working group is kind of doing that, but that's just it,
Because
like salsa is a cool idea,
but I think we often back it into places trying to make it work instead of saying, OK,
we have this framework,
let's like actually do an analysis of attacks and what we're
suggesting and what will work and then modify as needed.
And I think that is something security people are very bad at.
-- I
-- think
-- it's worse than that because yeah, they're starting,
I have a solution for your problem and they
haven't actually listened to or understood the problem.
And the second big challenge and failure I often see here is
they assume that salsa is going to be applied correctly
in some magical version of correct,
right? Like a perfect example is we had a cryptographic signing of bio
stuff because
duh, right, if you don't sign it, Attackers will make fake biases and blah, blah,
blah.
Well,
how'd that work out for M si and Intel last week?
They might have accidentally leaked a bunch of keys
and like suspiciously Intel is doing a microcode update for
-- every single currently supported CPU like
-- I
didn't connect those two dots actually.
-- That's funny. Oh, yes.
-- How did you not connect those?
I'm
maybe
I,
I was like,
I'm like, dude, you know, like, OK, let's be real shipping. A kernel update is hard
like when we were
microcode is harder because if you mess up a microcode update,
remember when we did that thing and Intel did that thing
and then a whole bunch of Dell servers got bricked.
I mean, micro code won't break your server, just roll back the micro code. It's fine.
So assuming you can get back into the buy off,
you can, you know microcodes applied at boot time is fine,
right?
Well, I'm just saying like it's, if you make a mistake in microcode,
you're gonna have a lot of angry customers,
whatever they got that. Right.
And the point is they're doing a microcode update for
every single currently supported cu the only way they would actually
do that is that there is an end of the
world like an extinction level event meteor headed for them.
I mean, maybe I don't know,
-- it'll be interesting to see why I hope they publish details
-- anyways. But
like that's the thing is they also assume
that salsa will be somehow applied correctly.
And, and the other thing that kills me is all, most, all of these solutions
have like a real heavy operational component
and it's not like um well, seatbelts are a good example,
seatbelts have an operational component in the sense of you have to put them on
for them to work,
but putting a seatbelt on is very easy. And I love that.
I've got my kids trained to the point now where, like, we sat down in the car and,
uh,
I forget what it was.
We weren't going to leave for a few minutes and Felix, like,
put on his seatbelt right away.
And I'm like, don't worry, we're not leaving yet and he's like, have it.
And I'm like, it's a good habit. I'm not going to argue with you. I agree with that. And
so something like the seatbelt,
the operational component of putting it on is acceptable.
And also the cart dings at me if I don't put my seatbelt on and so on and so forth.
But if I don't run salsa correctly,
everything looks fine.
Ah, so, so there's actually a solution to this that I think is quite acceptable
and that is
github
is putting a ton of work into making a lot of this stuff, just the default state.
And I think that's the key is you need places like github
-- that
-- is literally just passing the operational
buck to somebody who's hopefully competent.
I mean,
this is like, what I've done with electricity, I don't generate my electricity.
-- I pay up
-- cor
I'm, I'm a ok with that. I think that's exactly the right way to do it.
-- Well,
-- this is how cloud won because
let's be real.
Do you want Amazon web services in charge of your
servers or the random people you hired off the street.
They're not,
they're not random. You hired them
well, but you get what I'm saying? Right.
Like most places this is industrialization and specialization.
That's right.
I mean, remember when people would complain about, oh,
Cloud is just someone else's computer.
That's the
point.
I mean,
-- that's
-- the
-- whole point.
-- That's the advantage. Like,
my water tap is just somebody else's sanitation plant.
Yeah, that's,
that's exactly what I want.
You know, you just reminded me of what
there was uh another discussion I was having and someone makes a comment.
Oh, do you know who wrote that open
source software?
And I said, do you know, do you know who grew your lunch?
And I think they, they might have gotten it.
-- But it's like, it's literally the same problem.
-- Asked them to name
10 kernel developers past Luna
Stoltz.
I couldn't name 10 and I know like five or six,
I'd be like Great Crow Hartman,
Lynes
Tods,
-- Sasha
-- Levin, who, who work with the G
SD?
Oh, yeah. Is,
is he still a developer?
I don't know actually because Ted did the file systems a long time ago.
-- I
-- think there's a several,
-- is it several 1000 active Linux internal developers now?
-- Oh,
I bet it's at least that.
And so, yeah, that whole, that whole fear based of like, yeah.
Do you know where this came from? No, I like it. It came off of github.
-- It's probably fine
-- even in your company.
Do you know, who wrote the software, like, where, what country were they in?
I mean, well, this, like, reminds me of my mother because she, like,
she came to Canada, you know, she's German originally and came to Canada, you know,
and she had all her paperwork and all her stuff and her phd
and she went to work for the government and, like,
nobody actually ever asked her to prove that she had her phd,
like they just sort of took it at face value
and she had all this paperwork prepared and the,
the properly printed and everything ready to go
and like, nobody ever checked or validated it.
And
that's something like
with your developers
do. They,
like,
beyond being able to write fizz buzz.
Have you actually validated that they know what they're doing?
I bet a lot of places haven't. I mean, you know, this reminds me as well.
I remember when I graduated from college,
I got like six copies of my transcript.
So I would have them ready for like job interviews and potential. You know,
I have literally never shown them to a single human being one time.
I just have them. I still have,
everybody assumes I have a degree in comp sci
because I work in this industry and I'm like,
uh
j
-- let's go with that.
-- I don't have a degree in comp sci.
I was an electrical engineer and then I was like, well, I don't want to do this,
let me rephrase, everybody assumes I have a degree and I'm like, sure.
Yeah, you just keep
-- assuming that
-- whatever, who cares anyway. All right. All right.
Before we run ourselves out of time,
I want to flip over to the other topic that I found most interesting.
A, I came up an enormous number of conversations. Weird, who knew. Right.
But here's the part that I think I found the most interesting is half of the people
are saying a I is stupid and worthless and half the people are like,
it's literally going to fire us all and take over.
Now, what's really funny though is someone I work with was like, why not both?
That's the thing. It's gonna be a mix of all of the above.
There's, there's gonna like Wendy's is replacing all their order takers with A I,
-- well,
-- I mean, we'll see if that works.
So, you know, here's the thing,
there's a video from Tom Scott that I suspect you've seen,
but he chose that little like s curve.
And the challenge is where on the S curve are we? We don't know yet.
We won't know for a couple of years.
And I think self driving cars are my favorite recent example
where like five years ago we were talking about how,
like we'll never have to drive again soon.
And unfortunately I'm still driving myself around and I hate it and I'm,
I'm even angry because I know
that I, I was hoping I wouldn't have to do this by now.
And I, I did test driving so I feel like I've had the future I want snatched from.
Well, see, with the A I, and, and let's speak,
I think we're mostly everybody's talking about is a generative.
A, I very specifically the large language models because that is the,
where all of a sudden it turns out, oh, this is actually not hard to do. You just need
some big honking cards, lots of memory and lots of cores.
And
I love that open A I is like,
and part of our data set was every comment on reddit that got three or more votes.
And I'm like, oh my God,
like
uh
I
didn't turn it off Twitter like that Microsoft bought.
know,
but the thing is ignoring A I is stupid or A I is gonna kill
everything A I two day is giving people useful results and getting work done.
And it's also,
it's not just doing work more efficiently. Like my favorite example is
one of the people at the CS A used it to rewrite a whole
bunch of paper abstracts to be about the same length and the same tone,
right?
Rather because you know, everybody that submits paper,
submits their own abstract obviously.
And so the abstracts are anywhere from like 10 words to like a book
like even, you know, longer than the presentation itself, however,
they achieve that.
And of course, the tone and the writing style is everywhere from like
an English major to, you know,
somebody who I think fed it through Google translate from like Korean.
And so she basically had
open A I chat
GP D just kind of rewrite them all to be like
50 words and roughly the same tone of voice and boom done
in, you know, an hour.
It's also going to enable things like one thing I would like
to see us do at the CS A is take your resume,
take the jobs that you want
and find the gaps
that
find the gaps.
And
that's step one, step two is then how do you most effectively address those gaps?
Some of those gaps might be like, ok, look you just
to address this gap, it's, it's so much work if you really want to do this, like,
go ahead.
But,
but maybe you wanna like change your sort of what you wanna do a bit, right?
Or versus like, oh, you know,
here's like the top three courses to address this gap or
here's a resource to learn and address this gap or whatever,
right?
And we could do that right now and I could look at a resume and I could look at the,
the jobs they want to take and I could figure that out in an hour or two,
but we'd have to charge way too much money for this.
Whereas if we build a system using chat GP T to do this.
It's going to cost about a dollar.
Like, no, that's it. It's just, it's like an API,
it's gonna cost operationally like a dollar. Now.
We obviously we have to build this thing that does
this and that will cost more than a dollar,
a few dollars. In fact,
EPT
is, but the thing is once we build it,
that's the beauty of software, right? You're
like 100% of the cost is the first copy
or 99.9% of the cost is the first copy and then running it then.
So then if we can offer this as a thing for,
you know,
at a very affordable price or,
you know, whatever
all of a sudden we're doing something new
and useful in helping people get better jobs.
I would love to do that.
That's what I keep thinking of is
it is easy to try to disregard this.
And there are some just chef's kiss examples of how stupid A I is.
I've noticed a lot of people poo pooing it and I'm like, oh,
have you tried it? And they're like, no or they're like, oh, I tried the free one.
I'm like, oh, have you tried? Well, and this is less applicable now.
But Chat GP T Four, you had to previously pay the $20 a month to get access to. Right.
And I, I don't think it's still available for free but whatever.
Not as good. So, I, I don't, I haven't paid them. I've used the chat GP T website stuff.
-- Yeah. Chat GP T three and 35 are garbage compared to four is
-- four. Not the one you use.
-- When you use the website.
-- When you use the website by default, you're in 3.5.
Unless you're paying for chat GP T plus and selecting it, you're not getting
four and chat GP T +41 of the biggest things is for example,
it can summarize chat GP T +335 cannot summarize worth a damn
chat GP T four is like this. That's the one you want.
The chat GT.
And this is part of the problem is people haven't
spent 20 bucks and even tried chat GP T four.
They tried the chat GP T three and 35 from last year and they're like, oh,
it kind of sucks.
And I'm like,
yeah,
like,
like official policy at the CS A is everybody
pays, you know, gets 20 bucks a month to buy cha
GP T plus access
and
use version four because version three and +35 are garbage compared to four.
I
thought it was impressive.
-- The things I asked
-- three and 35 are super impressive,
but four is like perfect example.
We have to generate exams
for like the CCS K and CCAK and stuff, right?
And so we have to generate a ton of multiple choice questions you know,
with like four or five answers.
And it's hard to do these because, you know, to get
yes, it's,
I've helped put these programs together and it sounds like it shouldn't be.
But the, the questions at the end are like 80% of the work
and so
nuts.
Even when we have humans do this,
that we have to do a lot of manual review and massaging of the questions they submit.
Basically a PDF page of text is about 500 tokens, about 400 ish English words.
A token is about three quarters of an English word
on average.
So like the has its own token,
whereas a word like pedantically would be split up into
three or four separate tokens because it's a less common.
OK. Sure.
Because with neural networks,
like we only have 26 letters that's not enough and words,
we have too many bad words in the English language.
So tokens are this kind of happy in between, right?
So anyways, the point is
I can feed it
about four or five pages of PDF text
and say, give me 100 multiple choice questions with 4 to 5 answers,
including sets with all of the above.
And it spits that out in like a minute
and it the API calls like a buck or two.
Wow, that's wild man. And that,
that would take a human being the better part of a week.
It takes more than a week
-- Yeah.
-- Right. I mean, it's
just like I'm using chat GP T to program just to save on my RSI,
like, straight up. I just don't have to type as much because it's just like,
you know, de download web file and it's like, what
is RSI?
We should
stress injury,
right.
Hands and wrists make all sorts of crunchy noises.
Yeah. I got reduced mobility in my right shoulder and everything.
But, so the thing is what's killing me is all, most of the people I've met that are pu
a, I either one haven't actually paid 20 bucks to try chat. GP. T four.
Number two haven't even tried Bing Chat, which is free.
You just have to install edge and, like, log in with your Microsoft account.
And again, Bing Bing is search, uh, chat is
like,
give me the episode of, um, Chucking t Where Wilson Flies
and it'll suggest like one or two things,
you know, and get it right.
What is chugging?
-- It's a kids show. Look, trains.
-- Oh, trains. Ah, ok. I get it.
So, like, think of revamp of Thomas the train with less like capitalism and fascism.
Dude. They break up one of the engines in a tunnel and leave it there to die.
I've never seen that. Is that a real thing? I've seen a meme about that.
-- They really, that's
-- a real episode.
-- Holy
-- cow. That's
pretty
real.
There's a,
somebody did a deconstruction of that universe and it's dark.
Um
So anyways like,
and then the other thing is people are holding
a i to this perfection standard of like,
oh a I will confidently hallucinate and give you the wrong answer.
I'm like,
yeah. Have you met a used car salesman?
Oh, perfect example. Go to RS A talk to a vendor about their product
and they might say things that are like,
you know,
-- does it really do that, that easily,
-- whatever your problem is we can solve it,
just give us money.
Yeah, exactly.
So, I love how, you know what it totally reminds me of is
uh when PHP came out and everybody was like, oh,
this is like the worst thing ever because you don't have to
know how to program to write PHP scripts and stuff and the quality
PHP script is going to be terrible and PHP apps are terrible.
They were, they were all a horrific train wreck because
like, no good programmer would write in PHP, right? Only the newbies wrote in PHP.
-- He wrote
-- Pearl back then.
Pearl
has like proper train handling and Red Jackson blah, blah, blah,
you know,
and, and yet here we are, you know, 20 years later with wordpress and Facebook and,
-- and
-- no one uses Pearl anymore,
you know.
And so II,
a lot of the same arguments and sort of cultural things I'm seeing around A I
are exactly what we saw with like things
like PHP or things like all these technologies that
made things easier and more accessible
and it's like that. No, only, like, I only want a skilled artisan to do X and it's like,
-- that's not how the world works, like
-- certain things. Sure. But like
the number of people buying artisanal furniture is much
smaller than the number of people buying IKEA furniture,
-- you know,
-- and like here in North America Home Depot,
Lowe's and all those places do a ton of business with, you know,
casuals trying to fix their houses.
Like, should I hire a professional to do my electrical stuff?
Probably?
-- I mean, it depends.
-- Do I do a lot of it myself because,
yeah,
you know, but that I,
regardless of all that,
the thing that gets me is that
right now today A I is doing useful things for people.
Yeah, it does things, it does certain things. Well, I agree 100 percent.
It's like PHP. Is it kind of ugly and messy?
And we still have like,
we don't understand edge cases or how to make it really do it kind of good and safe.
Yeah. Who cares? I got my web
and,
-- uh, well,
-- you care when your application has a huge security vulnerability.
That's
problem.
That is definitely future Kurt's problem.
-- I'm getting revenue right now from
-- X and, and that's, I mean,
like,
I remember when
we worked at Red Hat
and we made an acquisition and the code was really bad, like, really bad.
You'd have to be way more specific. But
-- no,
-- I'm not, I'm not getting the specifics,
but we went to the lawyers and we were like,
can we review the source code for security problems next time?
And they're like, we literally don't care.
It doesn't matter what you find that isn't going
to affect the deal in any meaningful way.
So, no, no, you can't.
And we're like, I mean, I felt like it was like they kicked our puppy but it's like, oh,
ok.
I guess,
yeah, code quality.
Yeah, revenue wins, man. That's the thing.
And, and that's, I guess that's the whole point, right?
With like the whole A I everything. Even if it's terrible.
If people find a way to save money or make money on it, it's going, that's it.
You
seriously
anybody doing content creation now is going to look at two columns.
Column A is hire people to write the content for 5,
1015 bucks an hour or article or whatever
or column B is get content, that's, let's say for the sake of argument really bad.
Like only 50% is good or maybe 80% is good.
What cost pennies?
And,
and here's the other thing that people keep forgetting about A i
latency, latency matters
when I can get 100 multiple choice questions out of chat GP T in a few minutes.
I can massage my query and massage the text.
I'm feeding it and feed it different text or change the text
and I get that iteration loop going and I can
do multiple sets in an hour versus if I have,
if I task you to go generate 100 questions
and you come back to me in a week or two and they're terrible.
It's like, well, that's a week or two of my life that's gone
anyway.
All right, I wanna, I don't wanna keep, keep going on and on about this one, but
I guess I'll,
I'll end it with this and this is my takeaway is today the text it generates
is not going to be like good. Right?
-- Some people need good text. Some people don't.
-- I've gotten some
really good.
No, it won't be novel though. Kurt. That's the thing, right.
It's, it's only going to actually
generate
nonsense.
That's not
true.
No, I disagree with you.
See you confusing, you're thinking of the data in the training set.
You're forgetting that you can feed it new data.
And that's true. A human can put it down the path of a novel idea.
I've been doing this and I've been getting novel answers out of it.
-- I've actually had chat GP t surprise me. And
-- that's fair.
Well, no, you're not getting novel answers out of it.
You're tricking it into giving you novel answers.
For example,
I chat GP T actually can read and understand an
output mermaid text diagrams and I fed it our threat model
and asked it, you know, what's the biggest threat
aspect of this model? And it got it correct. It was the personal accounts recovery
and then I fed it again and it, not only it, it actually in a way got it wrong.
It basically gave me more than one answer, which I didn't want,
I wanted the biggest threat, but it gave me a list of threats, but
without being prompted, it gave me a list of workarounds and I had not asked for that.
-- I mean,
-- that's interesting.
But I maintain no, the workarounds are, that's not, that's not a surprise
because the workarounds are
in the preceded Gigantor corpus of data that I think you have
to create the mermaid diagram to make it create a novel answer,
right?
That's the key
you need,
you need appropriate good human input to get appropriate good output.
I guarantee, I guarantee
here's a way to think of it, think of it like this.
If you or I gave chat G BT a prompt to write a story,
it would probably be acceptable on our level.
If someone like Charlie Strauss gave chat
GP T a prompt to write a story, it's probably going to be freaking epic
because he knows how to, he has the language and the capability
-- to start down that path.
-- I think that's what a lot of people are ignoring is.
It's just like power tools like you and me,
we could own the most expensive power saw in the world
and you still cannot cut, like,
you still cannot measure and cut a board to the exact right length on the first try.
And I've seen people on youtube that can, you know,
there's this Japanese master who does carpentry without speaking.
And he's just like, literally, what's those tape measures?
And then he just like cuts a board and he's like,
and it like slots in perfectly. And I'm just like,
oh, my mind is blown.
I think that's something people forget is that
these tools are only really been around for a few
months and people are already getting amazing results for them.
That's true.
Think about what happens when people actually
learn how to use these tools properly.
No, it's the Tom Scott S graph. It depends where we are in that graph.
If we're at the top of the graph in two years, it's literally going to be the same.
I don't, it depends. We don't know. That's part of the fun, I guess.
I think one of the most amazing aspects is all the places banning the usage of it.
And I also found, I felt like I was cheating at first, like,
am I really doing my job by getting this to do my job?
And then I was like, that's well, spell checks. The same thing.
-- I know the
-- banning the use is a risk conversation. We are not going
to have to.
No, no, but I'm just saying
what's interesting to me is some places are just outright banning the use of it.
And so there's a lot of people that won't even
get the chance or opportunity to really try it.
-- No,
-- I know again,
it's a risk conversation.
So I want to talk about one last thing
before we go. And that is the dot zip
top
level domain
from DNS.
There are a lot of security people going on and on
-- about how like the world will end because now dot
-- Zip.
So my,
ok,
the one new and novel thing it would result in is like
if I type a tweet with a file name F dot zip
and
that automatically haunt links
and that might also happen in email clients and other stuff. And I get that that's a
problem potentially. But
I mean, putting links and stuff is already kind of a known problem.
-- I
-- mean,
my suspicion is the the reason some of the people
are complaining is the terrible regular expression you're using to,
to sort through
content and emails and other things looks for dot zip and
now they're not gonna work because it might be a URL.
Well, I think part of the challenge is if enough places block dot zip,
then the domain doesn't become very useful.
That's true. That's true. That's like uh I know I have a friend who does,
he manages a hospital
and apparently.xyz is used by tons of scammers. So he just blocked that XYZ.
He's like, I don't know, I'm done.
Like I give up,
you win scammers blocked and maybe the same will happen to dot Zip if it's just
like a haven for malware and filth just block the whole fricking TLD and you're done.
Like, I just, I, I,
I'm trying to imagine like I get that it might
be useful for fishing or social engineering ish maybe.
But
fundamentally
like
it doesn't give you some new way to deliver a file to somebody short of it.
Hot linking,
they click the hot link and just accept the download
and that's totally uncontrolled which if that's the case,
then you've got big problems.
Yeah, it's my,
my suspicion is most of the whaling and gnashing of
teeth is just the usual like change is bad.
-- I have to, I have to learn new things and do more work
-- well. And also like.com
was a thing for a while.
-- I think in the, you know.com,
-- I've heard of that domain before.
The other thing I think that was interesting was file
extensions have been hidden from people for over a decade now
by default
in most os
to the point where like I exported a bunch of data and it
was in the form of the file names were like email addresses.
So like fu at bla.com
and they were CS V files.
And because I'm interacting with this and using command line tools to do this all
the time I never thought to even put a dot CS V extension on them.
Oh,
-- I see.
-- Right. Because I'm just always interesting files all
-- had like.com is
-- the
-- Org
-- or.net or whatever. Right.
I do this, especially when I'm doing work with DNS. Right. Like,
where do I put the results for the scan of
cre.org? Well, they go to a file called
creed.org.
I
can do
because then I can do things like for I in star do
and pipe it back into dollar sign I or whatever dollar sign
I 0.2 and then move, you know, whatever.
And
I shared some of these files with somebody and they were like, what is this?
And I'm like, they're CS V files and I had to just manually tack on dot CS V to all of them
because I realize like, yeah, this person
like I'd have to walk them through,
basically messing around with their computer system to show
extensions and change them and blah blah blah,
right? Because they're using the gooey
when they double click on it, they're operating system is like
or
file like what do you want to do with this
or.com? It's going to execute it.com.
So
I think that's part of the NASH is the security people are like, oh,
this is dots it blah blah blah, but it's like
everybody on the planet just sees an archive file and it better be a dot
zip because if it's not R it's gonna fail and they're gonna have to like,
what's
RR
or
does it have to support R by default? Now, I forget that. No,
because I just had to,
some stuff I had like some old archives.
I was digging through the other day and I had to install Winrar
or like when I ship somebody at dot Tar dot GZ and I'm like, oh, right,
you're not a Linux person.
Ok. Here's a,
here's a dot
zip.
So I kind of get that. But
fundamentally,
I feel like this is just exposing existing weaknesses
and bad security.
I agree with that because
the thing, they keep coming back to
compromising one user and getting them to open one file and
run one thing on their workstation causes this much trouble.
Like what happens if they're malicious
or paid or,
you know,
like I'm reminded of the L TT youtube channel hack where it's
like it was just a PDF file that stole a token and
Yonk like,
but now I will say they were very transparent and
they claim they fixed a bunch of the problems,
which is very cool.
Like that's the right way to handle that situation.
Well, and in fairness, like I've dealt with youtube channel permissions and Hoy
like it,
it does not add like when you do really high level admin stuff to a youtube channel,
it's just like, OK, click.
Whereas like in github,
you know, it's like, oh, you wanna change this setting or add this, it's like,
stick your security key in
or your other two fa because,
like, we want to really make sure it's you.
Yeah.
Well, I, I just, I did that the other day where I deleted a repo and you have made me,
like, type in the Yes, I promise.
-- I want to delete this thing, like the string. Well,
-- oh, no, that's a classic thing.
Just so that if anybody complains.
-- But no, no,
-- no, then I had to put in my V
key as well. It made me do both of those things. I was like, wow, that,
well, the typing thing is so nobody can accidentally delete the wrong thing.
And if they do,
-- go ahead and it
-- annoys me that I used to be
able to copy and paste that text and I can't anymore.
And I deleted like a really long repo name and it was, I was grumpy by the time I was done
on tying.
But here's the problem is
the cost of support calls for people who
want their repos back versus annoying everybody.
Absolutely.
Yeah. No, I, I get it 100%. I'm totally on board, but I'm still gonna complain.
Maybe there should be a switch for that.
Just like turn off, turn off all the safety settings.
No, I don't want that.
They don't want it either
because you know, someone's gonna turn it off and then they're gonna complain, man,
they they restored the, all the repos they accidentally deleted.
No, man, I get it. I get it. All right.
All right. I think we should call this one.
I only have one more note I guess is uh I switched my Mastodon
account to
Infosec dot Exchange. So that makes me happy. So, thank you Jerry Bell.
That's it. All right. All right. This is fun.
I missed you, man.
It's gonna be ok.
Just, it's stressful, but it's gonna be ok.
And, and I'm, I'm, I will say though,
the remastering work I've been doing on those episodes, I'm going to keep doing that
because I find it fascinating peering back in time
and getting
certain things we get really wrong and other things.
It's like, oh, my goodness, nothing has changed in five years.
I was about to say, I'm a little sad listening to some of those episodes. I'm like,
when did we record? Oh my God. It
five
years
ago.
Yeah. The, the, the two episodes I've done so
hitchhiker's got to do the Galaxy and left pad.
Those are both five years, more than five years.
And it's like there's a little more real in these than I like,
but I'm really hoping
pasy fixed passwords finally.
I don't, we'll see. We'll see. I don't know. Well,
-- that's another conversation,
-- I guess all I can say is it can't get much worse.
Don't never say that.
And I say that and it can, but
-- it
-- can always get worse.
All right, I'm ending it. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to opens social
security podcast.com. Head to the show.
It's easy. Pando
says podcast hashtag hit, hit us up on social media.
-- Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks
everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the.