Hello and welcome to the open source Security podcast episode 152 with myself,
Kurt Siegfried and my partner on Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
-- What's
-- new Kurt?
Well, uh, I guess apparently Tavis Ormandy hurt some people's feelings
now. He ruined the world again, didn't he? And Tavis?
Yeah, he's, uh, he tends to be the bearer of bad news for a lot of people.
-- Yes,
-- I would not look forward to an email from Tavis
or my all time favorite when Tavis tweets out on like a Friday.
Hey, can somebody from Company X, please contact me like now? Right.
-- You know, it's like, ah, crap,
-- fire up the coffee pot and cancel your weekend plans.
Something's up,
you know? And what drives me nuts is that everybody,
just everybody. It's better than it used to be 20 years ago.
But still so many people want to shoot the messenger and it's like, all right,
why don't, why don't we explain what happened first before we start
-- going into our meta stories about whatever?
-- So, Tavis Ormandy found a security bug.
Just the one. Right.
Well, and he's found lots of security bugs like on the order of over somewhere,
if it's probably somewhere between 100 and 1000 at this point that I'm aware of a
lot.
Yeah. Anyways. And so, uh, he works for Google Project Zero Day
and they have a 90 day disclosure policy, which to be fair is,
I think that's pretty reasonable.
I mean, 90 days either you can
to put it bluntly, either you can fix it in 90 days or you can't.
Right. Exactly.
It really, like 90 days is not nine minutes, nine hours or nine days, it's 90 days,
it's a quarter.
And if you can't get it fixed in 90 days, chances are,
well then, ok, it's just not going to happen any time soon.
And so their disclosure policy is 90 days firm.
Right. That's it.
So, you know, Tavis finds a security flaw in windows, tells Microsoft, you know,
and, and when we say Tavis finds a security flaw and tell somebody we're not like,
hey, I found this, like, weird behavior in your program and like,
I think it's a problem.
No, like Tavis is like,
here's like a nice big report with exploit code and like,
everything you need to know.
And I'll be blunt, Tavis probably understands that bit of code better than
pretty much everybody at Microsoft other than maybe the person who wrote it
anyway. So he told Microsoft and Microsoft took the report and then Microsoft
didn't fix it. And then Tavis released on day 91 as
well. He said he would. Yeah. And a whole bunch of people on Twitter got angry at him.
Uh Well,
so we should also clarify the security issue in
question lets you remotely crash windows is my understanding,
which is of course a non
ideal thing to be happening.
You know what it reminds me of is
this is kind of how we got in the responsible disclosure situation in the first place
where there's all these people that think I'm
special and I should get magic treatment and
I don't like what you're doing because I'm not in a situation to deal with this.
So I don't like you
about it and then sit on it until I'm ready to do something about
it.
Right. Right.
And now I would like to point out I
have not seen any negative anything coming from Microsoft.
I have a suspicion. They,
they, they're going to own this one the way they should.
It's been like whinging on Twitter from various
other like news organizations and people complaining that,
oh, Tavis broke the world again.
Well, here's the simple truth.
The majority of people complaining have never worked security response,
let alone security response at a vendor
because
you and I have worked security response at a vendor.
I still do. Well, yeah, you still do. But that world is only a few 1000 people. Really?
Yeah, probably. Right.
Like, realistically I'm talking about public facing products.
You know,
there's a lot of people doing software
security response for internal software services,
whatever.
But I'm talking about, you know, public facing products that are widely sold, like,
say windows or, you know,
a web browser or something.
There's only if I had to guess I'd say between
1000 and 10,000 people really doing that kind of work.
Probably. I think that seems fair.
-- So
-- to put it bluntly, those people also are too busy to complain on Twitter.
Uh Well, not exactly. I mean, you have to remember there was a day
when a 90 day disclosure policy was ridiculous.
And in fact, I just not long ago finished the cult of the dead cow book
and which I'll put a link in the show notes, everyone should read it.
It's very, very good.
And what it, it part of the book they talk about at stake
and that was the loft guys kind of
cashing in. I don't know what we want to call it.
No, I wouldn't say cashing in so much as going professional.
Uh that's for OK, going professional. I like that.
So basically this talks about
how the at stake guys
they,
they held firm to a 90 day disclosure period and that back then that was ridiculous.
Like nobody did that.
And you figure now, I mean,
that's how it works. Google Project Zero has adopted it.
They do 90 days and even when they started it, I remember it was
and it was almost slightly controversial with a lot of people.
And I feel like
-- we've reached a point, it's fairly acceptable, but
-- there aren't any
deadline
controversial,
realistically, any deadline would have been controversial.
You know, what this reminds me of is when you say
no to a child and then are firm about it.
And the first few times that child is not happy, especially
how do I put this nicely.
There's a lot of my experience, there's a lot of Children who have not been
given firm boundaries that are then enforced.
And I'll be blunt, I, I treat my Children,
you know, firm but fair and quite frankly, you know, if I,
if I make an agreement with them, like we're going for ice cream,
then we're going for ice cream or if you do this, then there will be consequent sex.
Then there's consequent sex,
end of story, even if
you know, and there's been times where I don't want to leave. I want to stay here.
-- But oh no, we did some behavior. So we're leaving man. This sucks.
-- I know.
And it's funny to you, you say that because
I, I'm, I'm very similar.
I would say we have, I would guess very similar parenting styles in that regard. And
we were,
we were somewhere and there was this parent
like playing on their phone and their kid was
doing something ridiculous and they're like yelling at
their kid without even looking up from the phone
and my daughter looks at me and goes, that boy isn't going to listen to her, is he?
I was like, no,
not even a little bit.
Yeah.
And
you're, you're absolutely correct.
There is, there's something to be said about that and I think
for disclosure,
it was very much an instance of the researchers
had to train the vendors back in the day
-- and it wasn't easy and they were demonized. I mean,
-- it's still a problem
with some people, but I think the major vendors for the most part understand this.
Well, the, the reality that always gets me is this shoot the messenger thing.
It's like
number one, Tavis Ormandy didn't create the flaw,
right. As far as I know, he didn't write new software for Microsoft Ever.
And number two,
it's not like Tavis Army
is some magic space alien with magic
-- alien technology to find security flaws.
-- You can't prove that.
And I think the evidence would suggest that's a very real possibility.
I've seen him eat a burrito. So I know he eats,
we,
we don't know, aliens probably have to eat
but
to put it bluntly, if Tavis can find it,
then it's not outside the realm of possibility, somebody else can find it. And
that's the reality. A lot of these security flaws when you, when you start looking
or you know what to look for.
Like, remember specter and meltdown and, oh my God,
it's the end of the world we found hardware flaws and then guess what happened?
A whole bunch of people found a whole bunch more hardware flaws
and they're, they're going to keep finding them till time ends.
I mean, that's the reality of it
-- because
-- they're looking now.
And
so
I
look at this and, and, yeah, my,
my experience of Microsoft is they're probably a little
bit annoyed but more in the sense of like,
uh, this again, not like, oh my God, it's the end of the world.
Well, look, they didn't fix it
well, and in fairness like this flaw while I would say highly annoying,
like it is a denial service in the crypto thing.
That
means it's actually quite exploitable, right?
Like I can send you basically mangled email and then your,
your email client like poops itself basically.
So, you know, most local denial services bluntly boil down to, ok,
don't open that file again, like stop doing that.
Right. Exactly.
Whereas this is a little different in that you can remotely trigger it reasonably
easily.
I'm going to say, you know, through email or some other,
some other well processing certificates from external
-- entities is a pretty normal thing to do on a, on a machine. It,
-- it, it is.
But so here's the way this is my guess of how this went down and this is me speculating,
just putting on my, I've been doing this a long time.
Hat
Tavis tells Microsoft Microsoft probably did the investigation
and it sounds like they told him kind of at the last minute we're not going to fix this.
And my guess is they looked at the resources they had
and the things that had to happen for the next patch.
Well, well, I guess the next couple because they do this once a month,
but at the same time I understand that
rolling a patch into windows is going to take more than 30 days.
And so they probably said we,
we this isn't important enough to juggle this other work.
So we're just going to push it off and oh, hey, Tavis,
it's going to take us longer than 90 days.
They knew what would happen, they knew this was going to happen. And if they were
considerably concerned with this, they would have done something
to either fix it or even ask politely for an extension or whatever. Right. So
now at the same time, I have a suspicion if this was like a remote code execution flaw,
they would have stopped the presses, right?
And you're going to basically wrangle up everyone you need
to and you're going to get this done right away.
And so
I think this is something else. People often forget in a lot of these situations is
the, the severity of the issue
has a lot of bearing on how,
how much resources you're going to put into it.
And in this case, I mean, let's face it it's not that bad.
It's actually a little more subtle than that too because you
could put in just enough resources to fix just that flaw or
you could say, look, this isn't super critical. It can wait a bit.
Let's actually free up a bunch of resources, not just to fix this flaw,
but to actually audit this code and give it a, you know, go over it because, ok,
no offense.
If there's one bug in the code,
there's probably more bugs.
And my suspicion as well is that a lot of this code is probably
old because I bet that's the kind of code you don't touch very often.
And this, I mean, this is something Microsoft talked about at length with their,
the beginning of the SDLC program they created many, many years ago
is when any time they found a flaw in a function,
they would typically rewrite the whole function with that exact assumption is
there's probably other problems in here. Let's rewrite it using
our, our new secure process with our reviews and everything else just to make sure
there's nothing else here because in many instances,
like looking for bugs is hard. Rewriting a function is easy.
Well, and not just that, but
I mean, you got to assume we've learned over the last 5, 1015, 20 years,
a lot about what these functions are doing.
There's performance improvements you can do,
you can make, you can maybe add some functionality you know,
you can just generally make it a whole lot better.
You know, like I'm always reminded of Python, right?
Python has a whole bunch of standard libraries
and for example, like if you want to do a web request, you've got, oh God,
what are they on now?
Like the fifth or sixth version of it? There's like URL lib http lib,
you know what I mean? Like they keep kind of writing a
new one and they tend to layer on top and then add a bunch of new functionality and
to put it bluntly, the latest one is generally the one you want to be using.
It's so much better.
Yeah. Yeah, because they take care of a lot of the nonsense for you.
Yeah.
And then the other thing too is like by going through this and either rewriting it or
going through it with a fine tooth comb and
actually putting some real resources into fixing it.
You don't have to keep doing this firefighting.
You know, it's the difference between putting out a little fire
and actually going, ok, maybe we should install the sprinkler system
and some fire exits.
Right. Right. Exactly. And I think in security we spend so much time
with our hair on fire just in, you know, constant panic mode
that we never stop long enough to say if I would spend a day doing this,
I would save myself, you know, two months of every year,
which is huge.
Well, perfect example of this,
uh hands up people, how many of you want to deploy and
enforce two factor authentication across your enterprise but haven't yet done.
So,
I mean, there's a lot of people that,
right,
basically everybody.
Right. No, no, there's some who have already done it,
you know, and, and that's a perfect example of all of a sudden all,
just the whole classes of like password sniffing, password phishing,
all that stuff just goes away,
you know,
with good two factor authentication, like UB keys or something. And
how many? Yeah, so,
you know, I get it. It's tough. We have finite resources and also to put it bluntly.
Yeah, it's annoying if my email client keeps crashing, but
I can just delete that email and then not look at it
probably.
I mean, there's, there's gonna be ways you can get around things like that. I think
it is. And that's what makes it not that bad.
And I feel like the other half of this
is any organization whinging about this and saying,
oh, I've got to work the weekend now or you've ruined my week or whatever.
You probably have terrible security controls in place
is my suspicion and I could be wrong and I'm welcome to
accept whatever hate mail or tweets or whatever you want to say.
I
have
a perfect example for you
remember specter and meltdown
and
how
some of the big players struggled with it. But got through it.
And then remember, for example,
a great example is uh some of the
docker vulnerabilities where some providers were like,
oh, sweet Jiminy.
We got to like, reboot everything. We, we're up the creek, it's going to be terrible.
And then other providers like Google
were like, yeah, cool. We run each docker container in its own VM. So like
neat.
Like,
yeah, you can break out of that darker container into the V, I'm sure you do that.
-- Right. Right.
-- Like
we, we just don't care like we architected our system. So
the vast majority of Docker flaws
-- just don't matter.
-- And that's the right way to do it,
right
is figure out where your threats lie and then
eliminate them if possible.
And so i it's clearly possible to architect things well, to build things better to,
you know,
there are software designs and techniques you
can do to make things more survivable.
I mean, and Microsoft is a great example of this things like a SLR and you know,
all the,
all the memory protection shenanigans they've been putting into windows so that,
you know, exploit code used to be really easy to write. And
I would say now it's not easy.
It's a little bit tricky, you know, you got to jump through some hoops.
It's very hard. I'm not gonna pretend it isn't,
it's,
it's not simple.
But anyway, we are, we're off on a tangent disclosure, right?
-- We're talking about disclosure.
-- I think it boils down to people
are arguing against reality
and reality doesn't really care about your feelings.
No, it does not.
And reality always wins, which is unfortunate but it, it does, it might lose
in the short term occasionally.
Which again, I, I think as I mentioned,
while we were discussing this prior to the show,
I feel like we're in a local minimum at the moment in the world.
-- But long term reality will win it, it cannot lose because it is reality,
-- you know,
well, to pivot, I mean,
this is a perfect example of this is this whole
French judicial analysis with A I and machine learning thing.
Yeah, no one knows what that is, you need to explain it.
So in France, um they don't have common law,
they have the sort of the Napoleonic code.
So the idea is that judges
don't
interpret the law, they apply the law, right? So in common law, like in,
you know, the UK uh Canada, outside of Quebec
and the US, right? Judges interpret the law and
their interpretation obviously has to be
kind of in line with how everybody else is
interpreting the law and what the law means.
And if it, if it's out of line, then you know,
you appeal and you go through that whole process.
But in France and, well, also Quebec here in Canada,
it's essentially the judges apply the law. They are not meant to interpret the law.
And so somebody,
well, I'm not going to say came up with a bright idea, but basically somebody is like,
hey, you know,
maybe we should analyze these judges decisions
and then we can say, you know, for law acts,
this judge is like 85% guilty. This judge is like,
you know, typically like 50% guilty, this judge finds people like 100% guilty.
Right? And you can look at how they're statistically applying these laws and,
and you know, whether or not
they're sort of within the what should be a statistical norm, right?
Because ideally a judge
in a perfect world,
you would give a court case to two different
judges and you'd come up with basically the same answer
in theory,
you know,
that would be ideal. Um
And obviously that's not always the case because people, right, you know,
whether or not you get the judge before or after lunch
and they eat something spicy probably has a significant statistical impact.
So
France
passed a law
banning,
applying analytics to judges decisions with,
with a penalty of up to five years in prison.
I'm sure this will totally work.
Right.
Well, I mean, it'll, well, here's my question.
I was talking with somebody else and they were like,
what happens when you have a machine learning or
an A I essentially that sort of idea of,
you know, fruits from the poison tree,
you come up with some idea or statement based on
data and analysis you're not supposed to have or do
and you come up with a statement, say, like, you know,
left handed people tend to buy their laundry detergents on Thursdays
and you get rid of the original data and
the original analysis that you used to get to that
uh statement or that decision.
Then what happens? Right. So somebody makes this statement,
somebody makes a statement, you know, this judge and this judge are applying the law
sort of outside of the statistical norm of all the other judges.
Well, you know, how do you,
do you, I guess you'd have to investigate and basically say, you know,
prove to me how you figured this out.
And if you figured it out using a computer, we're gonna put you in jail for five years.
I understand what you're saying. So you're suggesting
someone could acquire the end result of such analysis.
Whereas does now does possessing, I wonder if possessing the knowledge
is illegal.
This is a lot like an NP complete problem in that coming up with
the conclusion is the hard part but validating the conclusion once you have it,
isn't that hard?
That is true because you could just look at the court cases.
For example,
let's say you had a magical a IML system that identified the 1%
of judges that were statistically outside the norm of all the other judges.
OK.
Printed out that list.
Now, you know, where to look,
you know,
and that's the thing.
So now, you know, and, and the classic thing, you know, the US, um, talks,
I believe the phrase they use is parallel discovery where,
so they have the one stream of discovery that's, you know,
quote unquote illegal or not legal or not allowed.
And then they figure something out like, ok, Josh,
you know, he's been buying detergent on Thursdays. Ok. So we figured that out.
Now how do we sort of
construct a chain of evidence to come
to that conclusion without getting in trouble?
And we could be like, hey, I got a bright idea.
We'll just have like this FBI guy happened to be filming it
wherever you buy detergent on a Thursday and be like, oh look,
there's Josh buying detergent on a Thursday.
I
mean, I get it on the one hand, France is like,
we want to kind of protect judges identities and they sort of,
you know,
we don't want them being tarred and feathered with because the other thing
too is this also assumes that people
are doing correct and good statistical analysis
and statistical analysis, especially with machine learning and A I
-- it's hard and by heart, I mean, it's damn near impossible. It's
-- hugely problematic.
I mean,
my favorite example I always use is that if a
bunch of white dudes build like facial recognition systems,
surprise, surprise, it sucks for anyone who isn't a white dude.
I mean,
Yeah,
that's
ok. And I imagine in all seriousness,
judges are probably going to be
in, in a similar,
I guess bucket because let's face it.
Judges are mostly old white dudes,
I mean. Right. They're going to think a certain way.
They're going to act a certain way and a lot of them don't even know it.
You're going to run a statistical analysis and be like, oh, look, they act,
think and talk like old white dudes, right?
Be, be ashamed if you have some diversity here that,
that was cleaning things up for us a little bit.
And, and I my my suspicion as well,
most of the people who probably created these laws are also old white dudes
and unfortunately I have a a
in my soul.
I feel like this is old white dudes protecting old white
-- dudes for being old white dudes and it's like
-- yelling at the
-- dog,
-- don't do that. That is terrible.
Well, see what really drives me nuts is one of the key components.
As I understand, a fair judicial system is transparency,
right?
Like we're actually going through this locally where two years ago the
Edmonton police service decided to withhold the names of homicide victims.
Um basically making the argument that under privacy laws and under
sort of compassion to the family and the people around them,
you know, putting their names out in the public
unless it serves an investigative purpose, we're not going to do it.
And
I get that argument. I personally disagree with it.
And now two years later they're,
they're backs steping on it and going back to more of a transparent.
Yeah, we, we're going to name
the victims of homicide
and,
you know, any
legal system has to have a relative degree, if not a high degree of transparency
because otherwise all sorts of horrible shenanigans can happen.
You know, like in the US, there's those,
those court cases where they found judges were
selling Children to the to a prison system.
-- Seriously
-- that was super messed up.
This is,
you know, this to me is why we need
to
do these kind of analysis because there are some bad people out there.
I mean, government in general, I think needs
this sort of transparency and
-- I would say
-- yes and
that's exactly where I was going with. It is
so I, I have some stories I can tell about this around security.
And so I,
I work at Elastic and we're a very open organization and we have
all this like culture stuff on the website and it's a nice place.
I'm not going to say it isn't and security people by their nature are very secretive
and we hired a new ciso little over a year ago who basically
came in and is striving for radical transparency by the security groups.
And at
first everyone's freaking out, right?
Like, oh we can't tell people what we're doing. It's like yes, you can.
And you're gonna like, you know, it's not, it's not a choice.
I remember there were a lot of
customers that were quite shocked when I was really
honest with them. And I'm like, yes, I, I appreciate that.
You've reported this crosside scripting vulnerability and we're
not going to fix it anytime soon.
-- But, but here, here's a workaround,
-- right? And that's fair.
But the important thing that happens is when
you start having transparency into what you're doing,
people ask questions and they'll say, why are you doing that?
And then sometimes just someone asking that question of why,
why did you do it that way?
Why does this matter what is going on?
And if you, you know,
it's one of those situations where you
start explaining something and halfway through,
you're like,
why am I doing this? Like this is insane
and that's, and that's a big part of it is a lot of these large organizations,
they don't mean or want to be bad or
evil because like every large corporation that I hate,
most of the people I've met that work for it are nice people.
Of course, you know, like a great example being my phone company locally,
I hate my phone company locally.
I
mean, that's just how Canada works, right? Everybody uses the
phone.
Everybody I know that works for this company is actually a decent human being.
And I think that's one challenge is,
is there's a lot of organizations that impact people's lives
and they will start to have sort of those statistical biases or problems
that
basically won't show up.
I mean, you'll kind of have a gut feeling like, oh,
maybe we don't treat group of X people very well.
But, like, I can't really, uh, you know,
I don't have evidence one way or the other until
you do something like a big statistical analysis and go,
oh, yeah, like when it comes to group X, we're like 5%
meaner or we charge them more money or we give them less support or
we hang up on them more or I don't know, whatever. Right.
And I think that's a big part of this
is we need this transparency and we need this analysis
so that we can do better and be better, like you said.
So we can ask questions like, well, why,
why do we paint the computer read before we ship to customers?
Right. And, and we all have, it doesn't matter who you are, we all have certain
internal biases that a lot of them, we don't even know we have.
And
when you have the ability to look at the data,
it's like I forget there's some mathematician as you'll quote, if, you know,
if you can't measure something, you can't understand it.
And
in a lot of ways I agree with that.
And I feel like that's a lot of security where we just, we don't measure,
we make assumptions
when something fails. It's a secret. So we don't talk about it.
So, whatever, it doesn't matter, we never, we never improve and
that
it creates
-- a, it's worse
-- than we never improve.
-- We don't even learn, we don't even know we have a problem in many cases.
-- That's true.
Yeah,
-- that's completely true.
-- You know, that's something I've run into a lot where
as an outsider you look at an organization or something you're like, oh my God.
What, like what,
you know, and they're like, what do you mean? What?
-- Right.
-- Of course, we, of course, everybody keeps raccoons in their bathroom.
It's perfectly normal. Nothing to see here.
And, and more to the point though, you can't,
if the data is available.
Yeah, you can legislate that people aren't allowed to analyze it,
but you can't actually stop that from happening
-- intentionally or unintentionally.
-- Right?
Because there's people who don't live in France,
Google is going to crawl through the data and their machine learning will
stack and order the search results such that when you do certain searches,
-- you can extract information relatively easily
-- from sure.
Or, or there's people who don't live in France,
there's people who do live in France who don't care.
I mean,
this is, I, I assume a lot of this is public data.
You could probably download the data, crunch the numbers.
Well, that's, that's the challenge.
It is public data and that's why because they were saying, you know,
we don't want to take, for example,
the judges names off of the decisions to protect them.
Right.
Yeah. And
you definitely don't want that.
I mean, funny enough you just made me think of something from,
from the days of your is like, this is the old information wants to be free at it.
Right.
Where the point of that is obviously as, as young,
you know, wide eyed hacker types.
We were like, oh, we're going to make the world a better place and, well, we didn't,
but
the point is once information is out, you can't take it back.
If, if someone publishes this report, whether they're in France or not,
it doesn't matter because it's out.
You lose what now?
Right.
I imagine.
And I imagine there's a lot
of this kind of thing going on in the world because, I mean, let's face it,
stuff like this is actually really important.
Uh,
a fair and honest judicial system is like
one of the core things of western democracy.
Right.
-- I,
-- I know, I guess with that,
uh, I guess my thought is, you know,
why are we so afraid of being better and doing better?
Uh, no, no, II, I think, ok,
I'm gonna,
I'm gonna turn that on its head.
I don't think anyone's going to say I don't want to be better.
I don't want to do better. Right. I think there are
as humans.
We have certain things we want to see and obviously self improvement is one of them.
I don't know anyone who says I'm perfect the way I am.
Well, there might be a couple of people and
some of them might run countries, but
generally speaking, most people agree that,
that there's a certain amount of personal development they can take.
But I think at the same time
we have been,
I, I don't know if it's innate or it's just something that has been
kind of just pounded into our brains, but failure is bad,
right?
And so I think what happens is when you are a person in a
culture that sees failure as a negative thing and not a positive thing.
One of the ways you avoid failure is by hiding
and if you're successful, then you say, oh, look what I did. Isn't this neat?
But if you fail,
you just sweep that under the rug and you go
on to the next thing and everyone pretends it's cool.
And I think that's,
that's what we see a lot.
We see that in security, we see that in government, we see that in,
in almost everywhere.
You look,
well, you look at science, right?
The reproducibility crisis where there's really not a lot of
economic incentives for people to actually try and reproduce experiments.
And then when they do, they're like, wow, this is just
like,
and it's not that the science is bad or wrong. It's that like, OK, your lab notes suck.
And like, how did you go from step A to step Z?
Because there's like the instructions are like, and then you swish it.
Like,
-- why?
-- What?
No, I know. Exactly. Exactly. And this is the same thing with disclosure.
We feel like keeping things secret,
helps us avoid failure because now we have more time
and potentially infinite time if we do it right.
And then it's never a problem
and also less customers wanting to talk to you.
Issue X
-- and the press is calling.
-- Right. Yeah. Exactly. Exactly. And it's like,
like one of those situations where I love in that, you know, the comedies were like,
nothing to see here, folks.
Everything's fine and like the buildings exploding behind them. And
that's totally what it is.
Right. It's just it, and I think that's human nature and I think it is,
it's difficult to get past that. Right.
And,
and some of its culture and I think some of it's just kind of personal growth and I,
I don't have a good answer how to do it.
I mean,
it's,
then
that's probably a book. Someone could write a book about this one.
There's already many,
there probably are. And obviously they all work because it's the problem solved.
That's,
we could get into that some other day about the fact that, like,
none of those books work.
But that's another story.
Uh. Right.
All right, man. I think I'm calling it.
So, thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up the show
notes, you see Poundland Os S podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media.
Kurt, have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too, thanks
-- everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the.