Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast
with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in knowing what to set up and what not to set up.
Josh Presser.
What, what does that even mean?
Well, just that conversation,
we were having a few moments ago with sort of the whole
how operations have and have not changed in the last 20 years.
But
you have the perfect set up for a plumbing joke
and you, you blew it. We're talking about dirty pipe.
-- That is not something to joke about
-- dirty pipes.
Plumbing is not plumbing is serious business.
I mean, I'm a talented amateur plumber. I would say
any actual plumber just like shriek in terror.
Well, and in fairness, part of it though is like, for example,
my solder joints are god awful.
-- Like they are horrifically ugly but they don't leak. It's hard
-- to solder
pipe.
Well, it's hard to solder it properly and elegantly
-- but shark bite
-- man, I don't trust
shark bite. You know what?
There's a, I, I used to not trust them either
and then it's been 10 years and there's been, for example,
many youtube videos where they've, you know,
put a shark bite on and like tried to pull it
off or froze the water in it to see what happens.
And
mechanically, they are strong as
very strong
and
they don't leak.
-- I mean, II I know
-- that's kind of what you want in plumbing.
That's literally its only job
unless it's copper and you're using it for ground bonding.
-- In which case you need copper. I mean,
-- yeah, grounding is can be important,
I mean,
whatever,
-- whatever.
-- So,
no, so the dirty pipe vulnerability and this is the perfect example of
having an in depth knowledge of sort of how to do system
forensics and look at the Linux kernel doesn't matter until it does.
I read
the blog post from the person who discovered this.
Yeah,
that's
-- smarter than me.
-- I'm confident I couldn't have done this.
I mean, it is
an amazing recap of events and the bug is remarkably esoteric
and hilariously simple. I mean, it ticks so many boxes.
It's, it's even more than that.
It's, I, I love the fact where he's, well, it's kind of like Sherlock Holmes,
you know, once you've eliminated
everything possible, it must be the impossible,
right?
Because like if I had a situation like this, like, yeah, it's probably my fault.
That's just,
it's not the Linux Colonel's fault. Are you insane
like
20 years ago? Sure. My Linux
machine crashed every 15 minutes and then I got a
driver update once and it started crashing every 20 minutes.
And that was amazing. But that was 20 years ago.
-- Let's
-- explain this bug because it's so mind. But
IIII
I want to do it. I I
it is the most amazing bug I've read about in a long time. And so
I will put a link in the show notes to the actual blog post.
I would highly encourage you to go read it because it's so well written.
But
what it basically comes down to is so
in
the Linux kernel, there's this concept called a memory page, right?
You might have heard of this. It's four, it's a four K block of memory.
And basically everything the Linux kernel does happens in these four K blocks.
Like if you ask for a megabyte of memory,
you just get a whole bunch of four K blocks all squished together, right?
And when you're doing really any sort of file operation,
it maps a page of memory, a four K page of memory
to a file on disk.
And then the kernel will do things like watch
the page of memory for changes and then it
knows it has to copy the changes from the block of memory into the file on disk,
for example.
OK.
That seems pretty straightforward. And obviously there's
a bunch of weird permissions rules and stuff and those all get handled in the kernel.
But fundamentally at the end of the day, if it sees a change to the page,
it writes it to the file.
OK. Now what this person found was the, if you have the ability to modify
a page of memory that points to a say file, you don't have, right?
Access to your changes, get written to the file, which of course is like a that's like
that break the fundamental rule of file access, right? If a read only file,
you can't write to it,
you know what this reminds me of is direct memory access back in the day.
Remember when people found out about D MA and it's like,
wait a minute if I can plug it because you know, Max had D MA over hardware.
And so if you could physically plug something into
a,
yes, you could just do anything to memory.
And that's actually how some forensics products worked.
For example, you know, bypassing all the safeties and security controls.
It still works that way.
-- I mean, this is why like when you plug in a thunderbolt device,
-- yeah,
-- you better
-- trust it.
You have to like basically say like yes,
I trust this device because you could build a thunderbolt device that could
modify memory on the system because thunderbolt devices have access to D MA.
Yeah. And
it's kind of a, it's very similar in that regard.
And so anyway, the way this bug worked was
this person was doing some wild streaming of data using pipes. The the li
like you do like cat pipe to you know, sort or whatever
in the, in the,
on the shell.
And basically the way the pipe was working is it was managing to put some data in a page
that
the kernel incorrectly or no. How was it? No, no, it's, this is really complicated.
I'm probably gonna screw this up.
But it sounds like what happened was you filled the page with data,
you drained all the data out of the page
and then you managed to write in a read only file
into the page and then you could change some of it.
And when you changed it, that data ended up getting written back into the file,
right?
And so fundamentally, a normal user could modify
the a a read or, or a read only binary for example, or a script or whatever.
And so obviously, from the perspective of an attack,
you modify like a set U ID binary and now you can do crazy things.
I like how you go, you can modify a set I DB
and then you know,
yeah, like what? Right, exactly.
Now where, where this one gets even kind of more wild though is generally speaking,
a lot of people say, oh, it's just
local users, whatever. I trust my local users.
No, you don't because you have a web server that executes code.
-- We're
-- gonna
-- get to that.
I actually have a funny story too. I, I have a friend who got a hold of me who's a cis
edin and their security person was like,
you have to fix this on all your machines and they're like, we're gonna fix it.
But, uh, most of our machines, all the people who can log in already have root access,
so we don't consider it a high priority there.
And the security person, like, well, yes, it is.
And they're like, please explain why.
-- And of course, the security person couldn't, which I laughed at. But anyway,
-- the
funny thing is there is one minor reason which is
it breaks logging. You don't know who did what anymore?
Well, not only that look, I think the real sell to this is
you can modify container base image files with
this which are in the container world.
Like that's,
that, that's the holy grail like that's immutable.
You can't edit that, which means if you could modify a base image,
you can affect all of the containers
everywhere running on that system, which is terrifying.
It's not a direct container escape. Like you can't say,
you know, modify some set U ID outside the container or something,
but you can mess with
enough stuff in a container that I'm confident
a good attacker could leverage this to get out of your container environment
-- well, or just pivot to other stuff in the, you know. Right.
-- Right.
That's what I mean,
like find a container that's running privileged and then it's game over, you know.
And one lovely thing about the the Linux kernel patch for this,
his two lines are changed and it's literally buff flakes equals zero.
Like it's just,
yeah.
-- Oops. I mean,
-- that's what makes it such a, an amazing bug though.
It's hilariously simple. It's amazingly complicated. It's just, I love it.
It's one of those things that, where this is what I, this is,
I think one of the fundamental differences between security bugs and normal
bugs is normal bugs tend to bubble up and surface relatively quickly.
Like, oh,
you know, the, the color is wrong or the,
it just doesn't work like I type in an
email address with more than five characters and it
doesn't send the email.
Most security bugs
are almost never gonna be triggered accidentally.
And it's wild to me that this person actually
not only did this bug trigger accidentally
in the wild under like normal circumstances,
someone smart enough to notice it and understand it dealt with it because story time
I have been guilty of this
way back in the day I started using Amazon web services
with the Fedora images and I would fire one up.
-- Yes, I know this story
-- and there's no rude password and I'm like, well,
that's stupid, but also kind of makes sense because,
well, you could set a root password, but it would be the same on all the images.
So that's silly.
And you could sort of set one randomly at first run.
But how do I know what the password is.
So kind of the whole point is that you, you know,
Amazon shoves an SSH key in there and you SSH N
and I'm like, and then you log in and set a root password,
which is what I did for years and then somebody reports it and it becomes a huge,
you know,
massive security kerfuffle with like daily calls with
major vendors and it was just a disaster.
And I'm like, I kind of wish I'd spoken up sooner, but oops,
and that's the thing.
Like,
I just noticed it and kind of thought it was
intentional and more to the point I was like,
well, this is so trivial to fix and deal with why, why am I worried?
You know, like, even better story.
The first security vulnerability, the real one I ever found was the,
is
cuzzy.com file
was what
really kind of contains your password? And man, I'm gonna name names Cisco Law.
Their mind
when I went public with this.
And I was like, because I was like, what,
like you just ch mod minus R like you just make it not world readable,
change the password probably because it might have been read
and you're done.
That's it. And like Cisco lost their damn full mind. This is like 20 years ago.
Well, and that was back in the days when you just didn't talk about security issues,
like,
shoot the messenger. Well, exactly. And so,
yeah, I mean? And that's part of the problem is if you see something,
say something.
-- But then the second part of the problem is, but who do you say something to?
-- Well.
Right. Right.
And, and look,
I think what makes this bug so special is
it?
It only appears under a very certain set of circumstances that I,
I don't think are going to be very common.
You know what I mean? And it's, it's such a minor thing
that I, I think the odds of most people think
bring this out is nearly zero.
I bet you this bug has been exploit, not exploited but triggered many,
many times and no one noticed or they were just like, oh,
whatever the disc is corrupt.
Well, here's the other problem.
You don't need to just be technically savvy to do the forensics and, you know,
take this bug apart.
You have to have the curiosity and the time.
Right.
This is, I think this is one of the biggest problem with security people is security.
People forget that the majority of the mins have 17 printers to fix.
Yeah.
Right. They don't have time to, oh, this, like, one file keeps getting corrupt.
Like, three times a year. You should go spend 10 hours investigating that. 0,
-- 10
-- hours. I bet this took way longer.
Exactly. Right. Like multiple, you know. Yeah.
And, and my, like, my favorite part is in the write up. There's one point where
the author noticed
in the binary dump of the corrupted file at the end
there were the letters PK, A capital P, capital K and some other things.
And it was basically part of the zip file header that he was writing.
And how many, like, if I looked at that I wouldn't have put that together. No way.
-- So, yeah,
-- I mean, my take on this would have been, like,
-- files corrupted. That's weird moving along. Right. Like.
-- Right. Right.
Right. Files get corrupt.
Part of the problem too is you and I grew up in an era where files corrupted.
Yeah, that's normal. That's how computers work.
Like,
you turn off your windows machine improperly. Oh.
Or God forbid you eject a USB device without actually
ejecting it, like, in software and un mounting it and everything. Like it's gone.
Right. Like, even a floppy disk.
There's a reason people save their stuff to two or three floppies. Oh. Right. Right.
Part of it is modern computers. It's like ZFS. Right.
ZFS is this magical file system that essentially unless all your hard drives die,
you will never ever get mangled data out of it.
And God forbid a cosmic ray hits it. It'll tell you.
Right. Like, it's just technology has progressed where it used to be.
Like, if a file got mangled.
-- Well, yeah, that, that's Tuesday
-- it happened all the time. Yeah.
And, and now I think that's part of it is we've, it's, it's, well,
if you get something improved 5 10% a year.
-- But you do that for two decades.
-- That's not
entirely true because I have a Mac for work.
And as it turns out, remember Apple's cheating on the whole speed thing, right.
Like, uh, I've corrupted the disk on
many Macs will say. And now, granted, I do weird things.
-- So I get that
-- well, but also Apple's clearly cutting short,
like they're clearly cutting corners to get performance out of it right there.
Was that Twitter feed where the guy essentially is, like when you flush the SSD,
it doesn't actually flush.
And if you lose power, you're screwed
on a Macbook is actually not that bad.
Like it's probably not gonna happen. You have a big battery in there, right?
Put on a desktop,
you know, and, but so if I had to bet money,
Apple's willing to cut corners for performance,
that Linus would hit you with a hammer.
But
so, so
that's,
I think a good talking point that we should kind of
kind of take with it is when you have open source,
you can do things you can't necessarily do with a close system.
Like, let's say, for example,
you had a Mac or Windows and you were seeing this strange corruption,
there's nothing, there's no way you could have really done it.
And if you read the write up the, the discoverer,
he used get bisect to figure out exactly where the bug came from.
And now get bisect is this kind of amazing feature of G
where you basically, you see a bug, you do get bisect and it starts doing like,
basically randomly picking spots and it's not random.
-- Well, no, not
-- randomly. You just cut it in half.
Well,
yeah, I mean, basically you say, I know there's no bug in this commit.
I know there's a bug in this commit and get b
basically helps you sort out where the commit is
that introduce the bug. It's absolutely amazing.
And people forget powers of two and conversely, powers of half
are amazing because like, I love, you know, in the write up, he's like,
it was somewhere between these and it's like, oh what,
over 100,000 commits or a million commits or some stupid number.
And he's like in 17 steps. So like two to the 17th big number.
No. And you're right. It's, it's funny how that works. But still,
this is an example of
the openness of Linux.
It enabled all of this to happen.
-- Can
-- you imagine filing a support case with Microsoft
where you're like two or three times a year,
a file corrupt
and they'd be like,
-- buy a new hardware.
-- Right. Right. Yeah.
Right. They wouldn't take that seriously at all. Not in a million years.
And
you could potentially reproduce it. But even if you sent them a script
and you said, look at what I can do
the odds of them
figuring it out correctly are very, very low.
And so I don't generally approve of Linus's law that, you know, with,
with enough eyeballs, all bugs are shallow.
But I think in this particular instance, this is a shining example of it.
Well, I mean, there's a chance, right? Because here's the thing, uh
remember when we worked at Red Hat, did we ever say we would fix somebody's problem or
did we say we would make every commercially reasonable effort to fix your problem?
Right. And it's true though,
like,
you can't launch a support case with Microsoft of like
weird random file corruption and expect them to spend,
you know, $100,000 of developer time trying to track it down.
Like
that's not realistic, but at
least with open source, there's a chance,
like if somebody files a good bug in theory,
anybody on the planet can choose to work on it,
you know,
like, so there's at least the possibility, the chance there's the hope whereas,
yeah, with closed source, it's like,
yeah, unless you've got some massive, you know,
debugging binary skills like computer says, no.
Right. Right. Right.
And, and so anyway, anyway, bringing it all back together, I think you are correct
that
trickery and open source, I think would be frowned upon the Linux kernel community,
especially Linus would not approve of it in any way.
-- And I think that is part of the magic of all of this.
-- It would be an option.
It would be like hyphen hyphen fast and unsafe.
You know what I mean?
Like because there are,
there is literally software that has these options where it's like, you know,
you can do this thing, it will go faster.
But like God help you if you lose power halfway through
a transaction because it's gonna just like everything's going to be gone
and some people are like, yeah cool. I can live with that.
Uh
-- Yeah,
-- actually, you know,
you just reminded me is elastic search does this because like for example,
what happens is when you,
when you're like shoveling data into elastic search at an alarming rate it every,
every couple of seconds,
it basically stops to like flush everything out to disc and make sure it's cold
and you can basically tell elastic search like don't do any of this safety stuff.
You just like, I'm gonna,
I'm gonna hook this fire hose up to you and you're gonna take what I give you and you're
going to deal with it and then you just
obviously it it's not writing to disk very often.
So it it's really fast. But if you lose power like it's all toast.
And the thing is 20 years ago, I would have been like, oh that's dangerous.
Now, I be like, who cares? Just engineer it.
So you don't lose power,
get dual power supplies in every server have two
separate power grids with batteries and diesel generators done.
I mean,
or you just architect your data in such a way that you can
afford to lose power and just reload the last bit you didn't get,
you know, I mean, there's, there's ways to do this stuff and
I mean,
that's one of the things that some days I become infuriated
and some days I love it that there's so many modern
compute systems that they were like, just throw away all those hard problems.
We won't worry about those like
like database transactions, atomic like nested it.
Atomic transactions are one of my favorite back in the early sequel days,
like you needed nested atomic transactions,
right where you can have transactions
inside of transactions inside of transactions,
sort of set up.
And a lot of the modern databases were like, eh that's hard to do,
let's just not do that.
This is why my
QL won my SQL performance wise. Remember was amazing.
Yeah, because it didn't have any transactions.
It basically
it didn't have any safety seatbelts
or no,
it didn't have no, it had like no doors.
You hung out the side of the car while it was driving.
It was, you know what it did have that almost nobody else had.
It was
well, no, not just free post
high school was free but it why did it not win as much as my school?
And the reason is my school also had very cheap and easy multi-tenant.
So you could run one instance of my
and carve it up between 100 people.
I agree. And I found
poster
-- was much harder to set up as well because it
-- was correct. It was engineered.
-- Well, that's true. It was, it was done. Right.
-- Right. Like
SQL was the Mercedes and my SQL was, I don't know what I would actually compare it to.
That's a bad analogy. I would say posters.
QL was like the,
the properly built and functioning heavy machinery on the construction site.
And my sequel was like some guy rolled up in a
truck and told you not to ask too many questions.
He unloaded something.
We'll get it done. Just
make sure the OSHA guy is busy.
That's right. You Forman, you look away,
we're gonna do some stuff now.
Yeah,
pretty much. And there's a lot of stuff where that's entirely appropriate.
Like, if I'm running a little wordpress website or whatever,
I want fast and cheap and quick. Sure.
Anyway,
anyway, anyway,
but back to the security thing,
this is, this is, I think maybe one of the powers of open source. Is that also,
how many times have we seen something where some open source developer goes?
Hey, you know,
like, what if we do this?
And it's like,
what was the open BS D firewall fail over stuff
that was like real time fail over called again.
I have no idea. Uh Carp or whatever anyways.
So they basically uh you know, some clever open BS D admins were like, hey,
if we do this thing, we can basically have fail over and yeah, Carp and PF sync,
we can have real time fail over.
Like you can basically take a shotgun shoot one of the,
one of the two firewalls and no connections get lost.
Like
thanks,
like back then firewalls fail over in the sense of like this firewall died. Ok.
This firewall will now take over,
but all your existing connections are dead and have to be reestablished.
And
if it's web surfing, great, if it's like, you know,
an FTP session for a bank doing a batch transaction, not so great.
They came up with a really simple clever solution, you know,
and, and maybe commercial people can come up with that but maybe they can't.
And that's the thing I find with open source, right?
How many clever solutions have we seen?
And again, you know, you staple a couple 1000 clever solutions together.
And I mean, well, you have Linux,
I mean, I I think that's modern development environments.
I mean, look at the container world, look at open source in general, look at N PM,
look at everything.
It's, it's very much that kind of UNIX model of.
We're going to do a bunch of little tiny things and then turn them into one big thing.
And
I think even dealing with like security vulnerabilities
in open source is kind of a similar model where like this is a great example of,
there was some coordinations that had to be done.
All the right people came together in all the right ways and
it's getting fixed and that's great.
Now, I will say though one of the caveats to this one is it affects
certain modern Android phones and obviously, the the handset ecosystem
is legendary for not getting many updates.
Now, it only affects only a couple of phones.
I know it's like, I think some Google pixels and maybe some Samsung phones.
So it's not like it's a widespread problem, but you get the idea,
it's probably gonna be like months.
If you have an Android phone, you probably have a pile of vulnerabilities.
This is one of the reasons I will never buy an Android phone
outside of the one I have for testing,
especially with Canadian carriers being what they are.
It's
true.
I just
know anyway.
Yeah, pretty much so. I, the best part is that not only did Linux
fix this vulnerability but because it's so public
and because the write up is so public,
you know, I also suspect, for example, probably the BS D people,
even though there's like no shared code,
they've probably taken a quick look at their code
to make sure they didn't do anything similarly silly.
I
mean,
that's
part of the beauty of this.
Yeah, I, I,
man, the number of times I've done that
where something comes out, it's like, I know there's no way I'm vulnerable to this,
but I'm going to look for similar problems in what I'm doing
because I don't want to be caught with something similar.
Everybody makes the same assumptions.
Yeah. Actually, you know what's funny about that?
I remember, in fact, this is probably on the podcast. I remember when
some of the, like, specter and meltdown things came out for intel chips
and everyone was like, oh, by a MD, they're safe. I'm like, it's coming for them too
and it did eventually.
I'm kind of shocked arm never got nailed by all that.
Uh
I don't know if arm is quite as aggressive in the way they do that.
The caching inside the chip and the branch predictions.
You think Apple silicon based on arm is
not super duper duper aggressive on performance?
Yeah. It, well,
it is now
the new Apple stuff like as much as I want to hate Apple sometimes.
Like those, those chips are pretty sweet looking
what they're talking about. Being able to like real time decoder mangle 18
4 K video streams or something or
-- something
-- like
-- that. It's a
-- lot.
It's,
it's basically we're at the point where it's like how
many kilo quads it's just made up numbers and stuff
like that's what they
don't get. Why would you tell me how many transistors are in? Ac pu it's
like a lot.
I,
I can't fathom the numbers anymore and,
and computers have become so hilariously fast that I just nothing makes sense.
-- I have no idea what to do
-- or, you know, the solutions to
like
the sound on my motherboard died. And so I
currently have everything hooked up like through my monitor which has HDM I,
which does sound, I was like, oh yeah, my monitor has
a,
you know, has a microphone port on the side, cool sound.
And then I ordered a sound block
card online because I'm just like,
I'm not even going to try
a for
-- real sound blaster brand.
-- Like an actual sound blaster.
They still exist.
They actually some real nice gear USB and actual stuff.
Anyways, it's like 50 bucks, Canadian, so 40 well, 37 whatever us.
And so I'm basically just, I'm like, I'm not gonna just,
I'm gonna smack a sound card in there, disable it, the sound in the Bios,
plug it in, be done,
right? Because
the time to try and actually
confirm that it's like dead dead on the motherboard,
you know,
because it makes no sense that it would die because it really, how the heck did it die?
I don't know
-- who cares
-- exactly.
Ok. So
we're gonna end on this note because you have this attitude of who cares.
And I think the vast majority of us, if we saw some corrupted files occasionally,
we'd be like, who cares?
So the fact that someone had the wherewithal to go through this is amazing.
And I love it. I love it so much.
You know, what it kind of reminds me of is like crypto analysis back in, you know,
prior to the 19 fifties where it was, there were no computers, there was you a pencil,
some paper,
go figure out what this random stream of gibberish means.
That's right.
-- And these people did, which blows my mind.
-- It's amazing.
It's so, actually, if, if, for anyone listening,
there is a book by Neil Stevenson called Krypton
Naan.
And he kind of uh he novelizes a lot of this
and it's, it's very well done and it's a very good book. And if you have any
desire
to learn anything about cryptography or just kind of some of
the code breaking that happened during like early World War Two.
It is a phenomenal read. It's amazing.
All right. All right. I think we should call this one man. It's been,
I love it.
This is one of those issues that just makes me smile for all the right reasons.
And I love that so much now, of course,
I'm sure there's some people not smiling because they're working
ridiculous hours to get this fixed. So like,
you know, peace be with you all. I good luck. That's all I could say
so. All right, man. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you for listening.
Go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up our
show notes,
YZ Pound
do
podcast. Hashtag You hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.