It's December 25th. We made it,
actually, at this point, we finished recording,
I still have to edit 25 podcast episodes. So,
-- yeah,
-- it's like pie. If you cut it into small pieces, it doesn't, it's not as filling.
Obviously. That's right. Exactly. Anyway, Merry Christmas.
Merry Christmas to you and happy holidays I believe is the generic for everything.
Now,
whatever. I don't care.
I don't care if I, if I, if I
-- offend you send me, hate me. You know what? And
-- if you're working today, thank you.
-- Because
-- seriously, that sucks.
We need nurses, policemen, food,
food is good to people. I agree. And you are appreciated and seen.
-- So
-- why do we do some things? I'll be honest.
Most of the things I do is because I'm either tired or hungry,
but that doesn't even make sense what we've got to set this up.
-- Well, that's why I do things like, can't just start
-- talking.
I mean, ok, we'll say you were up late last night because it's Christmas day today.
-- So obviously you're tired.
-- But
so why
do some things?
Let me, let me, let me frame this
when many of us in North America and Europe celebrate Christmas.
We have a story that a man breaks into our house,
eats our cookies and leaves behind gifts if you have
behaved as a child over the course of the year,
even though most kids are rotten and deserve nothing.
Why do we do that?
Well, wait, is he also the man who folds our toilet paper into triangle points?
Does he? No one folds my toilet paper into triangle points.
You should demand a higher level of service.
Yeah,
I am the higher level of service in many instances.
-- So no,
-- the thing for me about the story of Santa Claus is
I like the idea of aspiring to be a good
person and to being well behaved and to being kind.
And I,
so I think stories that help people embrace these values
are probably not the worst thing in the world.
Yeah, I mean you can make that argument.
-- The actual mechanics of the story. Yeah, they're bonkers.
-- It's,
-- it's pretty nuts.
-- A perfect example.
Santa would have to travel at such a speed to get all the houses to be
covered
in
-- detail
-- because it would basically be worse than that
Pluto slam missile that they developed in the seventies,
right? And, and if you don't know what we're talking about, we'll put a link.
But this it was this horrifying nuclear weapon that essentially
did as much destruction by just flying around at mach
10 or something stupid as well as the nukes on board. And so
when you think about Santa,
it's like this stranger breaks into your house
and eat your food and leaves presents.
If you only if you've been good.
It, that, that's nuts.
Right? When people do that, we, we call the police.
So I want to tie this into security though, in the context of
there are certain
stories we tell in certain ways we behave
that
obviously have some bizarre historical context that has been forgotten.
And now we just do it.
And
I think this is like,
passwords are an easy example where we just did it the way we did it.
And now we literally have people saying don't do it that way because it doesn't work.
And the people who gave us the original advice are saying,
don't do it that way because it doesn't work.
And I still encounter people on a regular basis that are like, well,
I think we should still change passwords every month.
And it's like, well, I don't even know what to tell you.
-- You
-- want to hear the worst thing. Stupid tradition.
July 1st in Quebec is moving day.
That is to tradition, not a legal requirement, but by tradition,
that is the day when people move
-- one day a year is when you move.
-- Why? That doesn't make sense.
It began as a humanitarian measure of the French colonial government of New France.
So that's going pack a ways blah, blah blah, citing a 1750 bylaw, blah, blah, blah.
So the the point is, it's a 250 year old tradition that is just makes life horrible
because literally every moving company is busy for about two days of the year.
-- So
-- just move a different day. Won't that be easier?
Most landlords won't allow it.
Seriously.
Most people sign a one year lease.
-- Jeez
-- Louise,
you read up on it and it's just bonkers.
I just sign
like a third.
I actually, there was, I rented an apartment long ago where I signed a 13 month lease,
which was marvelous.
-- Actually, it was quite nice because I basically,
-- yeah,
because it gives you a month to move out.
Yeah, I had like a whole month to move. It was great. But anyway, brilliant. Anyway,
-- it was like, so the
-- point is, I mean,
we do things because we do things because our
ancestors did these things and they didn't die.
So obviously these are good things to do.
I mean,
like they were
like,
I think security is the perfect example of we are not a
species that has evolved to deal with the threats we have today.
Like, I'm really good at seeing a lion in the grass.
I'm really bad at seeing fishing, email, fishing. Right. Exactly.
And I mean, I don't know if we ever will evolve necessarily, but I feel like
it is a good idea,
especially on a day like today to remind everybody
that it is good and OK to literally question everything you do
every day to say, why am I doing this? If I don't do this, what happens?
You know what?
And that's,
that's a problem though because most people don't have that kind of energy.
They're too busy surviving.
-- And
-- that's a good point that, I mean, I feel that on a regular basis where I have, like,
when's the last time you optimized and reorganized your kitchen
-- cabinets? The answer is never,
-- I had a kitchen remodel last year. So.
Well, so you basically,
-- what you're saying is you burned it all down and started
-- fresh?
-- I did. And it was lovely.
-- Exactly.
So, how come you haven't optimized it and reorganized it since?
Because I'm happy with it.
Well, and that's part of what I love about human beings is the way we can post
decision, rationalize that this was the pair of shoes I wanted,
even though the pair I really wanted wasn't
in stock because otherwise we'd go insane.
-- I mean,
-- that's normal. Yeah,
I agree. We would, we would.
And
I, I, so I deal with this problem at, at work where I have
like a fire hose of stuff that comes in.
So, what you're saying is you have a white collar job.
I,
yeah.
Well, I've started trying to automate as much as I can, which is hard though because
spending time building robots to do my job means I if I'm busy doing my job,
I don't have time to build the robots to do my job.
-- And so it's like this crazy circular madness.
-- It's the red queen.
-- You have to run to stay in place. Yes.
-- Seriously.
So, anyway, anyway, we're out of time. It is Christmas.
We should get back to spending the day with
our families and I apologize to anyone listening to
-- us
-- or your friends or your loved ones or you know what if you want to be alone?
-- That's ok too.
-- That's true. I envy you.
I've had several Christmases where I spent them alone and it was quite ok.
-- And it
-- sounds lovely right
-- now. Others where it wasn't. But that's
-- life. Indeed.
Indeed. So let's, let's call it. Thank you.
Everyone who made it this far on this bizarre and ridiculous journey.
-- I'm sorry. There was no chocolates in the little
-- doors. There are no choc.
Well, it's not chocolate cart,
I
guess. Merry Christmas to all and to all a good night.
Have a good year. Everybody.