Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 100 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
-- Josh Bresser. We're
-- joined today with a friend of mine, Steve Mazak. Say hi, Steve.
Hey, everybody
and, and Steve tell us, tell us what you do.
Yeah.
So I'm the lead of the Solution architecture team for Elastic,
the company behind Elastic Search Cabana Log stash Beats and many other projects.
Uh Yes, Elastic. I think I've heard of them before.
Yeah, you may have.
Cool. So, so anyway, I know most people probably like uh sales guy.
What's up with that?
So,
actually I talked to Steve and it occurred to me
at some point we were talking about podcasts actually.
And
I realized that security people,
at least all the ones I've ever interacted with kind of suck at buying stuff.
They often don't know what to do or how it works.
And, and so I thought it could actually be really interesting
to kind of pick Steve's brain for a little bit about
what, what does it mean to purchase security products and, and how as a buyer can,
can we do things better So I guess why don't we kick this off,
Steve give us like the the five minute rundown
of how does a typical sales process work?
Right. And this is not, not too specific, of course, but just in general.
Yeah, it's good.
So typically it starts by somebody getting connected with somebody else, right?
And, and
the way that it can work is that
we send out
marketing emails or we do webinars and we have content that
we put out on the web for people to come and consume.
And if they consume that, typically there's like a registration form or something.
And that's one of the ways that we get in touch with people,
there's many different ways, but that's typically how it starts.
If somebody comes to us or we reach out to them through a mutual connection,
once that starts,
it really is then kind of a discovery
process where the prospect is discovering us at the
same time that we're discovering them and their business
and their problem that they're trying to solve.
And that takes many different forms. I mean, it can be
you just have an initial conversation on the phone with a uh account exec
and
they, you know, do their best to understand what the
customers trying to solve or the prospects trying to solve.
And then from there they determine how they decide they're going to buy. And
there's lots of different ways you can buy as you can imagine some
people know exactly what they want because they've done all the research upfront
and they just come to us and say, I just need a quote. I've already done
my research. I've already talked to customer references or,
you know, done my research in the community. I'm ready to go
uh other people, they want to see references or they want to do a,
they want to see a very,
you know, in depth demo. Sometimes they want to do
POC
do an rfirfp things like that.
-- All right, let's, let's,
-- I was just gonna say, what's an RF I?
There
we go.
Yeah. So it's request for information.
This is one of those things I love and hate as a solution architect.
The reason I love them is because
they're great to ramp a new solution architect onto the team.
You give them this spreadsheet that could be,
you know,
hundreds and hundreds, if not, maybe even thousands of rows long.
And you say, hey, go answer all these questions
and it gives the,
the essay a chance to really understand the
types of questions that they're going to be encountering
in the field as they learn their job and go out and talk to more customers.
The reason I don't like them
is because there's potentially 1000 rows or more on
these things and they take a long time.
And if you are not
engaged with the customer in the very beginning
of their buying process to help them define
what success looks like for the next piece of software.
They're trying to acquire your chances of winning that. That customer
is slim to none.
And I think there's probably statistics out there that say
eight out of 10 or nine out of 10,
you lose.
We have had pretty good success at elastic in my experience.
But I think part of that's because we're open source and there's
no barrier to entry when the customer wants to try our software.
Whereas you're probably familiar with a
lot of places where they say, hey, you want to try our stuff,
you got to get in touch with us first.
Right? Oh my goodness.
I hate that. That's not ideal.
Yeah. So, so as we go through
that process, eventually,
there's a point at which we start talking about timelines
and hopefully we know that early on in the process.
So we know what we're marching towards.
We validate budget, you know, how much do they have to spend on this project?
How much is going to hardware versus
software versus consulting and professional services?
And then we just work towards that,
that agreement or that, that deadline as we work together. And,
you know, I'm not naive enough to think that
most of the time we're the only vendor talking to a prospect,
they're probably talking to lots of different vendors.
And the idea is to try and understand as
much as you can about their problem and their preference
so that, you know, how to position your software to the things that they care about.
And this is where
honesty in the sales process becomes a really important thing.
You know,
that one of the reasons I love being in
open source is because there's already a presumption that
things are open and people are open and transparent.
And that's how I operate.
My goal is not to, to win based on, you know,
telling lies about all the other software vendors and what they can and can't do and
you know, say my, my software can wash cars.
It's much more about really understanding what they're trying to do,
seeing if there's a match and if there's a match doing the best
that we can to prove that we're the right solution for their,
their problem.
And then after that, it's all, if they agree to buy,
then it's about, you know,
going through the legal process to get papers signed and things like that
and then it, and then it becomes a thing.
And if you're like elastic, it's a subscription business. So it could be,
you know, a one year subscription,
it could be a two or three or even four or five year subscription.
And, you know, we, we believe the longer the better.
And I think the customers also agree based on my experience that
if you enter into a multiyear agreement with a vendor,
you typically get,
you know, maybe a
discount or at least some sort of price locked in for the long term.
Does that make sense?
Yes. That, that is awesome. I, I guess
we can pick that apart a little bit now where I
think you hit on something really important some time back.
We talked about professional services and I think that's,
that's one of the things people don't always think about is
it's not just a matter of buying a piece of software and, and
I think for, for many people,
at least in the beginning and this was something kind of I experienced long,
long ago in my career was, it's not like you go by a video game
and then you play it right where when you're enterprise software is,
it's a process and you generally need help from the vendor. Right.
That's exactly right. I mean,
I've seen a number of projects fail in my time where
the customer overestimates their ability to implement something successfully.
And,
you know, you've probably all seen this before.
I'm sure I've suffered from it myself too. It's very easy to think I can do it. I got it.
I don't need to buy professional services.
Early in my career, I worked for a large electrical,
like an industrial electrical contractor is their it guy
and they were replacing their accounting system and it ran on Sco
UNIX and I was like, oh, we can probably, just because back then,
Linux had a so compatibility
layer, whatever you want to call it. I was like, oh, we can probably do that.
And then I, I literally spent like half an hour
kind of looking at,
well,
basically do I want 500 angry electricians on a
Friday afternoon blaming me for not getting their paychecks.
And the answer was no, absolutely not.
And so the accounting software, you know,
it was this bespoke monstrosity because the, you know,
the construction industry has crazy billing
issues.
And uh yeah, no,
they provided a school box at like some horrendously inflated price.
But you know what not my problem.
And I think that was, that was sort of my first moment of it. Maturity
was where I literally was like, yeah, you know what,
I do not want to be responsible for this because
I cannot be in between 500 guys in their paycheck.
That's, that's not a good place to be.
-- Yes,
-- it's very forward thinking of you. I mean, I've been in situations where
people say, look, I have more money than time
and
sometimes it's the opposite. I have more time than money.
And, you know, they,
they think that because they have a team of engineers,
they can go and implement this stuff that it's almost like a sunk cost in their mind.
You know,
and I always try to help people understand that you're investing
with time and money no matter how you do this,
it's just a matter of what skill level and how fast you
want to move and how much you're willing to pay for that,
that
reduction in time to get something from inception to production.
Well, and the other thing I would add to that too is, is, you know,
is it a core competency?
So like I'm also the director of it for the CS A for the cloud security lines
to put it bluntly, the cloud security alliances are core competencies
are not running a bunch of servers, right? That's not what we want to be doing,
you know, um Netflix, apparently very good at that.
You know,
they have this monstrous cloud infrastructure and they
also happen to have a ton of content.
Um but, you know, in the CS A's and it's
my thing is always, you know, how much of this can I outsource because,
you know, I don't want the CS A to be like an it powerhouse. We're,
we're a standards and, you know, uh organization body, right? Not,
you know, we don't want to run servers for the sake of running servers.
And I see that with a lot of people, you know, where
um I've even had people, I don't know jokingly or not, but like, you know,
we should build our own white box
rack mount servers,
right? Like we can order the cases, we can order this, we can order that.
And in fairness that does make sense like when you're the size of Google.
Right. Then it makes sense to do that.
But like, you know, when you're doing a dozen servers or 100 servers, it's like, no,
please.
No.
And, and so that's one thing I've seen a lot of, especially technical people,
you know,
they've done it once successfully on their own. And that's cool.
But then, well,
like we keep saying this law of large numbers pops up
right when you want 100 of them or 1000 of them or
yeah, you want elastic search to be processing some, you know,
unimaginable amount of data quickly.
Well, you know,
it's interesting because the core competency thing is something I think
about a lot and we could use Netflix as an example,
is Netflix's business to
produce and provide entertainment content for the world or
is it to be really good at running infrastructure?
I think they would argue that it's both.
But
it makes me wonder,
could a could a competitor to Netflix pop up
and be great at producing content yet outsource all the
the the quote unquote non core competency activities like running that
-- infrastructure
-- there. It's a lot like it's a it's a core,
it's a strategic piece that not many people can do.
I mean a great example of that is like Walmart and Amazon with logistics,
right?
Almost nobody on the planet can get boxes to my house in two days, reliably,
right? I don't care how it happens.
But when I buy stuff online, you know, sometimes it takes weeks or months
and I think that's part of it, you know, is
people can adopt these things,
uh,
and use it as, you know, part of their moat to keep the competitors at bay. But,
yeah, to successfully execute that.
I mean, how many people tried doing what ebay or Netflix did and failed miserably,
or it's like, you know, back in the
late nineties, early two thousands. How many grocery delivery services?
Oh,
-- pets.com
-- was the
best because I was like,
they're going to deliver my 25 kg bags of kitty litter, like, for
-- free.
-- Yeah, like, sweet.
I know, we, we used to order Taco Bell from cosmo.com
just to see if it would work and it worked. But how are they going to make money?
-- So,
-- back to the sales because that's one thing I, I, because I've,
there's been a couple of companies where I, you know,
I looked at their product or their service or whatever and it was,
you know, it's too good to be true almost. Right.
And especially in the security world. Right.
I mean, that's a very common thing, like, oh, you know,
this product stops all network attacks and I'm like, really?
And so I'm kind of wondering is, well, a part of that would be, I mean, how do
you, how do you set, how do you sort of set,
like, realistic expectations about what your product actually?
Does for customers.
Yeah. It's a great question.
Basically how I think about it is
I'll go back to something my dad told me a long time ago is basically believe
none of what you hear and half of what you see
and what he was trying to tell me was validate everything for yourself.
And I take that philosophy to my customers.
You know, I don't want them to take my word for it.
I want them to try this software out. I want them to talk to people.
I want them to see it in action because I believe this seeing is believing.
And one of the ways that elastic is fortunate is that we have a
lot of people that are using our software and talking about it publicly.
So, you know, if someone's wondering if, if what I'm saying is true and accurate,
all they have to do is go look online, they'll find people,
they'll see stories of customers that are using our software and being successful.
And
for me, that's a really hard thing to get by when you're on the buying side
is how do I know this person is telling me
the truth?
Right? So, so let me ask you about that though, Steve is.
So, you know, this is kind of advice time, let's say I am a buyer
and I have a company
that, that sounds like they're selling me a pile of lies.
Like what's something I can do to try to, to figure this out, right?
Like what, what's appropriate for me to ask them in, in terms of, you know,
kind of let prove it, you know.
Yeah. So it's a good question.
I mean, when it comes to prove it, there's a number of ways you can do it,
you can get a demo and then have your technical
people in the room to ask all the hard questions
you can come, you know, go through that really long and complicated
and I think sometimes beneficial RF I process.
Um
you could even go talk to ask them for references,
like give me a customer name of someone that's implemented this successfully
with the same use case that I'm about to implement it with.
And we get those asks too.
-- So those are some things that you can do.
-- One thing I've always wondered.
I mean, because I get from the vendor side that
just the amazing
um
having reference customers, right? You know, especially good ones
that are like, yeah, this works great. We did this with it and solve world hunger.
It's awesome.
A stupid question. But why do reference customers? Why are they willing to do that?
Like because one thing I've encountered too is a lot of companies that, you know,
really want to keep their it and their sort
of special sauce secret as much as possible.
Yeah, it's a good point.
There's a lot of use cases that customers don't want to talk
about for exactly that reason because it is secret sauce and if they
let the cat out of the bag, then their competitors will be able to catch up.
But on the other side of that, you know,
why do people talk about their use and why do they become a reference for us?
And I think there's a lot of people out there that
become champions for a piece of software because they've built their career on it.
And they, it's almost like they owe a debt of gratitude or they feel they do
to that vendor or that technology because of
how successful it's made them in their career.
I'll give you a good example. We had a customer down in Texas that
had been working with a piece of technology for about 10 years.
He was a self proclaimed champion of that technology.
And after he encountered our, encountered our software,
he started using it and trying it out and he realized that he
could do so much more with our stuff than he was with the,
with the existing software.
And he
over the course of months and probably longer than that,
he started to become a champion for us
and leaving his software in the dust. And
it's the same thing he said to me that he's going to
build the next 10 years of his career on our software.
And so he's willing to talk about it and almost become an evangelist for us.
And I think if you think about this outside of the software world,
when you,
when you own something
that you really love and, and you cherish,
I think you want to talk to people about it. I mean, I'm a musician so I buy
synthesizers much to my wife's
chagrin
and there are certain synthesizers that I tell everybody
about because I love them like they are amazing
and I want everybody else to know partly because
I want that company to be successful and build more stuff like that.
Well, I mean, yeah, in fairness earlier in the convers, well,
before we actually got going and you were doing the setup,
you mentioned you had a Samsung Go
mic and my response was like, yeah, that's a good mic.
You know, that's actually what me and Josh started with.
-- We,
-- we did a long time ago,
you know, they're great.
You
know,
it's amazing how far that thing's got me for 30 bucks, I think.
Seriously, man, it's, I carry it everywhere with me.
It stays in my backpack all the time because it's super small and it's fantastic.
Yeah,
I have a yeti in the closet that I don't use, but I love it.
But I bought that. I bought that because of a recommendation from a friend.
Nice. Very cool.
And in fact, that's how we ended up with our mics is a fellow podcaster.
Told me to buy uh Road podcaster mics and so I told her,
-- like, go buy this mic, like we need new mic
-- also know,
as the microphone you can beat a man to death with.
It's true. It's like cast iron, it weighs a ton.
It's awesome.
You might need that on the subway once in a while.
So
I'm also curious.
So because I've actually, I was just thinking about this,
I've never actually bought expensive software.
Like I've
probably the most I've I've ever been responsible for is, you know, well,
it was basically Gmail for, you know, a pile of users
which adds up. But, you know, gmail is a very safe bet.
So it's not really that risky a thing to buy.
Um
So, you know, obviously for some of these projects, we're talking, you know,
hundreds of thousands or millions of dollars even.
And I'm just wondering like
from the customer's perspective kind of,
yeah, what, what can they do to protect themselves?
You know, because
there are definitely some less scrupulous vendors.
I would say, you know,
I've heard some horror stories about vendors that will just promise the moon or,
or my favorite example was a friend, worked for a company where
uh they were a technical person and, and the engineers are like, ok, well,
we sold this and here's the um
the uh the contract and the software engineer
response was our software doesn't do that.
And the sales guy response was, well, yeah,
but we told them it would soon,
you know.
So, yeah, I mean,
like with demos and stuff but, I mean, just, um,
yeah, how do you kind of tell the snake oil salesman? Because, like,
I look at some sectors like antivirus and it's clear
that there's like a lot of shenanigans going on,
like, really bad shenanigans.
It's interesting because, like, the antivirus stuff,
I think there's a lot of consumer, consumer based software that's really hard to
prevent the shenanigans. And, you know, I,
I send emails and text messages to my wife and daughter about things that I find out.
It's like, hey, if you're downloading this piece of software,
don't things like that.
So I do my best I can to protect them.
But on the enterprise side, I think the industry is changing this for us,
like all of us, not just the sales side, but the,
the customer side.
And part of the reason is because the cloud and the try before you buy mindset,
um open source is also changing this.
It's a little bit self serving because I work for elastic. But
all these opportunities that you have now to try before you buy. I
think that's one way that you can protect yourself really well because you get to
see if it's actually going to work for the use case that you need,
need to implement it for.
You know, we have a cloud trial for elastic that you can go on 14 day free trial.
If you like it, you swipe your credit card.
It's, it's, you know, a few dollars a month to get up and running and you start to build
trust on that platform
and it just kind of blossoms
like I, you know, I adopted this uh tool called a Sauna at Elastic.
And I started it because it was free.
I started to see if it would work for what I wanted to use it for.
And as I got more and more comfortable on it and, and realized that it would,
then I just kind of entered into a subscription agreement. Eyes wide open.
I tried it before I bought it.
So I think as the industry continues to go down the subscription path
and we, you know, we become consumers of that.
I think it's gonna get easier for us to protect ourselves
from predatory practices and sales.
But on the consumer side, that's a whole another thing I'm not exactly sure about.
And I think the consumer side is a little different because let's face it.
You're usually talking about a couple of bucks. Right. You're not writing
six and seven figure checks
-- for at least I hope you want.
-- And that's
part of the
challenge.
You know, when I'm, when I'm looking at products that cost 50 bucks,
it doesn't make sense to spend, you know, 50 hours
figuring out which one is absolutely correct. Right.
And that's, that's one of the challenges I see with this is,
you know, people ask me for recommendations and I'm like, uh
like that, that's usually my answer to most of their questions.
All right. So, so let's turn this question on its head though.
So let's say Steve, I am an enterprise buyer and I just wrote a giant freaking check
and it doesn't work.
What do I do now?
Well,
after you're in the unemployment line, you mean,
let's say I'm the second guy, right?
I'm the one who just, I was, I was just promoted to clean up the mess from the first guy.
So I've never been in that situation before. But if I were to speculate on it,
I think what I would do is
I'd probably do what I've seen done before, which is, you have to kind of pause
and re evaluate.
And I've,
I've been a part of sales processes where we get caught
in this cycle where someone made a decision about a technology,
it didn't work.
They
get exited out of the building, they bring in someone new and that new person,
their job is to
fix what's broken. And so what they end up doing is they,
they go through this re evaluation and it's really painful for everybody because
not only do you have to go back and see, ok,
what happened, what, what requirements are not fulfilled by the software,
you basically have to start over from
scratch to look at other technology solutions.
And hopefully there's some
prior art there from the ones that were evaluated before they made their decision
and then go down all the way through that process again. Now,
sometimes what I see is companies just kind of bite
the bullet and they customize the heck out of the software
to make it work for what they bought it for.
And they spend exorbitant amounts of money on this
and it, it, you know, sometimes it works
and
what ends up happening is no one likes the software upgrades become impossible.
And it's just kind of like you're, you're kicking the can down the road to failure.
Well, and, and to be honest, well, in Canada, right now we're going,
the federal government is going through this thing called the Phoenix Pay
project where they, they've now blown, yeah,
over a billion dollars Canadian on this federal pay system that's never worked.
And it sounds like they're finally going to pull the plug on it.
But the problem is they can't, because
you can't just pull the plug on a payroll system. Right.
You actually have to replace it with something like before you do that. And so
it seems like there's a lot of these, you know, just gigantic, it, disasters.
And part of me wonders if it's just part of the nature of the beast. Right?
Like building a large building seems to always be fraught with difficulty.
-- Um, and, yeah,
-- I mean,
I have my own theories about like why some of these big projects fail.
I think there's a lot of
nefarious things going on behind the scenes
quite honestly and relationships get complicated and
um we could probably talk for hours about this. But
there, there are, there is that kind of
human nature thing where I've already invested all this time and money
and I don't wanna
let go. Right. I just got to see it through to the end, even though, you know,
deep in your gut
that you're heading towards a cliff,
it's the most,
it's a cost fallacy. It's like
people just can't stop and take the emotion out of it.
Like most people identify with that type of thing
with the software project.
Like, you know, if I buy this software, it's now me, I'm on the line, like I've,
I've identified with
a
-- champion of software X
-- I think because you
mentioned several times now try before you buy.
And I think maybe that's one of the problems with some of these larger projects is,
you know, just either by their nature or by the type of organization it is,
they don't do that.
And, you know, they just,
they go through this like waterfall process,
create a 600 page document of requirements and then like,
OK, now we're going ahead with it, right?
Uh They don't do any like small scale testing or anything,
I think maybe that's because that's one thing I've
seen consistently where things start to break down is,
you know, where projects kind of try to go from 0 to 60 in one step rather than,
you know, like 10 smaller steps.
And so obviously, yeah,
with open source and with you like having a cloud service where I can like,
start trying it for free or for a few bucks a month based on usage.
You know, clearly those small steps I can start to
validate that.
Yeah,
this thing actually exists and works to some degree or it does
exactly what they claim it does and what I need it to.
Yeah,
it's almost like buyers should take the agile methodologies
and apply that to how they buy software.
Right?
I remember I did a project for a Blue Cross Blue Shield provider
in Oregon once and we were evaluating salesforce.com
to build the software on
and,
you know,
I was at a consulting company at the time and we organized a
team of architects that had done implementations in Java for a long time
and we were looking at the force.com platform at the time. And so
when we had these meetings with sales force and with the customer,
we had many,
many conversations about the requirements that we were trying to implement.
And because we had such a good experience, experience, team of architects
that knew
where the the
I guess bear traps were in implementation.
We were able to work through all those complicated issues beforehand.
And what we ended up with
was an architecture that was mostly on sales force.
But then we had to implement some things on the back end on Tomcat because
we couldn't do everything on sales force. But
we discovered that during the, the procurement or the sorry, the discovery phase.
And so it saved the project, I think.
And here we are years later,
I haven't worked there for years and that project is still up and running.
So I think that's a good thing. Like if you get good people and they can vet
the solution that you're trying to, to do,
you're trying to implement. And that's always a good thing.
Um
And, you know,
maybe there's unrealistic timelines out there and people just don't have the,
they don't think they have the time to do that. But,
you know, I think they're robbing Peter to pay Paul.
-- Quite honestly,
-- it sounds like you're in a catch 22 as a
organization often that, you know,
if you have the people with the expertise to do this, you would simply do it right.
And
clearly, if you haven't done it yet,
you probably don't have the people that can do that.
And I guess that's where bringing in the outside because, you know,
that's one thing I always struggled with was understanding, you know,
why would these companies that are huge and have tons of talent,
bring in outside consultants and contractors?
Right. Because
why would you need that, you know, you have 100,000 people
and,
well, yeah, I mean, obviously,
like very niche or specific knowledge about sales force and like, where
not to use sales force but build a custom back end.
Yeah, I'm guessing that's probably not very widely known or, you know,
that's a very niche skill for, you know, a small handful of people.
Well, it goes back to your point,
Kurt about the core competency thing, like we were building a, a
core business system for the
the healthcare provider.
And so they had all the domain knowledge.
So it was up to us as architects to go in and understand
the actual implementation details and the business
rules that we would need to implement.
And then
look at salesforce with a skeptical eye quite honestly to make sure that
it could do all the things that we needed to know that we were going to do. Now,
I think that the
provider was smart in saying we can't do this ourselves, we need some outside help.
And so they enlisted the help of our consulting company.
But
again, it,
I don't know,
I don't know how these people decide on whether or
not they're gonna bring outside vendors in versus inside because
you know, we could,
you can speculate on how often Netflix brings out
the experts, right? They fly in the the snipers basically to go implement some
system for them versus use their own internal engineers
that are on staff already to do it.
Well, it actually sounds kind of like we're in Dunning Kruger territory of,
you know, some people
know, so they,
they don't know enough about something to
know that they actually don't know enough about
it, you know.
And then there's the people that know enough about it to know that. Like,
like
that. Yeah, I should, I need to go find some experts and pay them money,
you know, like I, I just recently went through that.
I had some exterminators come to my house and do some stuff with poison
because, yeah, I know, I know enough about poison to know that.
Like, I, yeah, I don't want to die
or, like,
you know, melt half my brain.
Um,
and I, I guess that would be one of the, the catch 20 twos again of, you know,
some of these organizations,
yeah. How mature or how willing are they to bring in
help,
you know, to admit that they don't know.
Yeah.
I think it takes some self awareness and some, some ego checking quite honestly.
Like you just said, I,
sometimes I'm on the weekend,
the plumber at my house and most of the time I regret doing a project
that I did because it took three times as long as I expected it,
it costs twice as much and I'm left with cuts.
You know, my wife laughs because I cut myself with a hammer.
How do you cut yourself with a hammer.
That's so,
you know,
II, I do these things
because I overestimate my ability and I think it's simpler than it is.
And that's on a micro scale.
The same psychology applies at a macro scale.
It does actually. And, and you've really, you've hit upon something and
so I, I do the same thing, Steve where I,
I try to fix things on a regular basis and then I
usually end up wasting a weekend and then calling a plumber.
So I lose twice
and, and I guess this is,
this is what's going through my head right now is the fact that,
uh, we, I, I think especially in security,
we have a very negative view of sales people
and, and I don't think that's unearned from some organizations,
but I think at the same time
it is probably prudent
as a security person to at least talk to
a, a group that could potentially solve your problem and,
and see what they get because, like, I know from your perspective from,
from my dealings with you, you're obviously,
you know, you, you're brutally honest in, in these dealings.
And so, like, you're going to tell someone what's up when, when you call them and,
and I have a feeling that
if, if more security people found
sales organizations they could trust
it would be a very different world.
Yeah.
It, it would be
like, if, if I were a buyer today
I would do my darndest to go into every interaction
with an organization as skeptical as I can be.
And I would even plant questions in there that I know their software can't do
to see what they say.
Because one of the ways that one of the ways
that we earn trust actually in the field is by
being honest about what we can't do,
you know, a lot of people confuse
our software with things like hadoop and they just assume
that they can use it in a batch oriented way.
And it's like, well,
not really, it wasn't designed for that.
It was designed for speed scale and relevance,
not batch oriented back office processing.
We have a role to play there. But
if you're thinking about using us to replace a dupe, depending on the use case,
it's probably a bad idea.
And if you can
now that doesn't come up in every sales conversation, you know,
you can't go into a sales meeting and,
and try to expose everything you can't do like no one wants to do that.
But
as a buyer, you have to be able to ask these tough questions.
You, you need to put the vendor on their heels a little bit
and see what they say. And,
you know, it's funny because at, at,
at uh
elastic right now on my team anyway, we're, we're doing uh some sales training and
one of the trainings that we had was, it's called conscious selling,
which I loved the title and I love the, the content.
But the, the trainer was talking about
body language and tone of voice and how much that matters and how, how,
what you actually say matters so little.
I mean, the,
the diagram he put on the powerpoint was basically
your words are about 7% of what you're saying.
The rest is in your body language and your,
your uh tone of voice. So
as a salesperson,
you have to believe in what you're selling.
If you don't, the customer will pick up on it.
They may not know consciously that they're that you're
that you don't believe what you're saying,
-- but they will pick up on it.
-- Here's a question. You just mentioned that because I was,
you just mentioned you had sales training and I'm wondering
because I've never heard of this now that I think about it.
Is there such a thing as buyer training?
-- That's a great question. There should be.
-- Yeah.
No, I'm dead serious. Like I'm just thinking about this and I've literally
obviously marketing people and sales people have tons, you know,
they get together every year for their big thing and then they have like,
you know, like
there's always training and you know, all these things
and, and I literally, I can't think of ever having heard of buyer training.
It's funny, I just did a Google for buyer training and it looks like there are
well and I know there are for like specific, you know, for,
like when I worked for that electrical contractor, for example,
they had two people,
their whole job was estimating and buying.
That's it. Right.
They would look at a set of blueprints and they'd say it's going to cost you x,
you know, and if the contract went through they would then get on the phone and order,
like, you know, literally like $3 million worth of stuff.
But, you know, it's a very well defined, they had like binders,
they knew exactly what they were getting and I'm just looking for software
sort of buyer training. And
-- so
-- Kurt check this out on this course that I found,
there's a section of bullet that says, spotting,
handling and stopping scam artists, hustlers and
that's awesome.
Uh Send me the link Steve. I'll put it in the show notes.
I will, I will now that you got me thinking about this,
I should go through this training.
Wait, that's me.
So anyway, all right, let's, let's, let's take it home like this. So let's say
I'm, I'm a buyer
and
I'm in some high pressure sales situation and I'm looking for an escape hatch.
How do I get out?
So you
by escape hatch, you mean, I,
I no longer want to deal with? That's right.
Like I've got some pushy sales guy who's just, he's,
I'm feeling super pressured and vulnerable and like I need out, what do I do.
Well, there's a number of ways my preference is to be direct.
Says, look, I'm not going forward with your solution.
That's that.
And you, you have no obligation to reply to that sales rep after that, in my opinion,
uh the other one is to give him what we call tennis balls.
Now, like you can just say, oh, go fetch me a customer reference, go fetch me a TCO,
go fetch me an Roy and you just keep giving them errands until they,
they get tired of dealing with you.
This sounds exactly like how people break up.
Either that no means no or oh, I have to wash my cat that day.
Yes. Yes. They just make excuses. I I stop answering your emails.
I stop answering your phone calls and my wife and I joke
that this is basically the equivalent of unfriending someone in real life.
Like how do you do that?
That's hilarious. That's awesome. Alright, sweet. So I guess
any, any, any parting thoughts for us, Steve.
So I, I think right now on the security space especially,
I think there's a plethora of new providers and new vendors coming up every day.
I mean, Josh, you and I were at Rs A we saw this first
hand.
So
I just encourage people to be very skeptical and
you know, do your best to try before you buy,
ask questions of the of the seller that you know,
they can't do just to see if they're being honest with you
and really pay attention to body language and tone and see if they're
being,
you know, authentic versus just nice and, and
pushy and high pressure
and, you know, in the, again, in the security space,
the other thing I think I would say is make sure that when
you adopt a technology right now that it plays nicely with other technologies.
Like if you're,
if your technology does not have an API to integrate with other technologies,
something's wrong.
Is that even a thing anymore?
It is like a, a buddy of mine calls calls it a bag of doorknobs,
which I love this analogy
because you have this bag of doorknobs, none of them work with each other.
You gotta go to the door and try each of them out
and it's, it's a painful experience. So if you're evaluating software today,
there's a reason that the developers of the world are going api first and
you should be making sure that that software will integrate with other things.
Awesome.
And, and I must say Beador
Knobs sounds like a great band name.
But
all right. So anyway, thank you so much, Steve. It was, it was fascinating.
I'm, I'm really glad you came and, and I guess thank you, Kurt,
thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com,
hit up the show notes and you can use the Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag on social media to grab our attention. So yeah, nothing else you guys have.
Have a fantastic rest of your day.
Thanks.
Thank you.