Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siegfried and my partner and apparently
having the same youtube suggestion list.
Josh Pressers.
-- Do you mean because of the youtube link I put in there
-- and I was like, oh, and I'm like,
what is this?
And I click and I'm like, oh, yeah, I saw that yesterday.
So I, I have to talk about this because
I enjoy sharing
amazing videos I find in a good podcast and things like that.
So there's a video on youtube by
the channel is called Tech Tangents
and what this guy did.
I'm, I'm not even going to try to get all the, the model numbers, right and stuff.
-- So don't worry about that.
-- But no, we have to do it.
It's the Phillips CM 100 CD rom drive, whatever. Why is it special?
-- Well, it's the first CD rom drive ever bam,
-- right?
-- Like when he said that I'm like, what I checked and I'm like, oh, it is,
-- right.
And this is one of those youtube channels where they like work on and review
vintage computer equipment.
-- And I love
-- watching these, I think antique might be the word to use at this point.
Uh Maybe, I mean, sure. And like, I love watching repair videos.
Like, I love watching people, like Ben Heck,
and there's like the eight bit guy and Adrian's digital basement and there's like
this whole universe of people who work on and show off this old stuff.
And
the best part is I don't want to actually own any of
this because it's a lot of work to actually keep it alive.
And so I get to, well, it's not very useful either. Well, that too. Right.
I'd use it for five minutes and be like, well, this sucks.
And then I just have a pile of garbage in my basement.
And in fact,
I watched a panel with a bunch of these people
the other day at like a vintage computer conference.
It was on youtube
and they were basically talking about how they store stuff and they're all like, oh,
yeah, I have this, like, huge storage unit and I have a full of old stuff and I'm like,
I mean, that's really cool, but at the same time, like, what a waste anyway.
Ok.
So this video,
this person buys the first CD rom drive ever
made and unbeknownst to him when he bought it.
And I guess really it's not something you'd think about.
It doesn't plug into like ID E or anything. Right. It had a special port
-- for plugging it into a computer. Obviously it's
-- got, yeah. What was it?
-- Something, I forget that.
-- I don't know, it doesn't matter, watch a video,
a
video.
And so it's got this weird port and you need a special card because it's not like,
again, it's not a normal disc controller because why would it be?
It's the first CD ROM drive you've ever made.
And so this person is trying to find the card, he needs
to make the CD ROM drive work.
And they like,
don't exist obviously because we're probably like seven made or something,
you know, and they're all in a dumpster now
and he comes across another youtube channel where someone had
the same CD ROM drive and a card to make it work.
And this person showed it off, but the video was from like what five or six years ago,
right?
So this is in youtube days, that's
what like 700 normal person years.
-- So he emails the person and basically says,
-- no, no, he left a comment,
a comment.
What? Oh, whatever qui
this, right? And he's just like, it's a long shot, I'm going to leave a comment.
-- So
-- he leaves a comment on youtube basically saying like, you know,
can we talk about this?
And the person eventually takes a picture of the
front and back of the card and sends this guy
just a picture and all of the parts on the card are off the shelf stuff, right?
So this is like you can literally buy these chips.
Well, except for the ones that aren't labeled,
but they were able to make educated guesses on those.
No, those were just capacitors. Those are just,
-- that's easy. Capacitors are easy. The I CS are the hard part.
-- Yeah.
Well,
and the other thing too to remember is like these aren't multi layer circuit boards.
These are straight up, like the circuit board has a layer with, well,
they printed on both sides, right?
If, if it had an internal layer, there's no way they could have done what they did
-- unquestionably.
-- This is straight up.
Like if you take a picture of the front and the back,
that's all the traces except for the ones,
-- in fact, that are apparently covered by chips.
-- Oops, that's normal, that's normal.
But they could make educated guesses.
And the person who sent the pictures was kind enough to
do some continuity testing between traces to make sure that they,
the pins were in fact correct, which they were in any way.
So this guy creates a circuit board like in, in, I forget which tool he used.
But you know, like one of the the circuit layout programs and then he gets them made
and then he puts the chips in
and he plugs it in and eventually,
and there was like some twisting and winding and it doesn't work.
Of course, well, not at first, but that was a driver issue funnily enough.
It wasn't because the hardware is bad and it literally works.
This guy cloned a freaking isa card from
like what it was the eighties or nineties.
The story is just
unbelievable and it made me smile and I was just, it felt so cool watching this girl.
And I remember starting it out and thinking
there's no way someone would make this video if it didn't succeed at the end.
I was hoping because if, if it would have ended with a, like, oh, it doesn't work.
I would have been, like, so mad.
But
it was, it just, it's so cool and it's so amazing.
And the thing that really stuck with me and
it's vaguely related to the topic of the day,
30 years ago, cloning a card.
Like this would have been out of the question. There's, it's just not practical.
No, it would have been like a state level attack.
Right. Straight up.
Like, what, like when the Russians were trying to clone American computers, like,
I watched a youtube video about that as well just the other day
and like,
like straight up this would have been the kind of
attack where basically the Russians could do it well.
And the Americans,
-- but the Americans didn't have to do it because they had Silicon Valley
-- and now some
random guy on youtube
totally did it. It's amazing. I love it.
Well, and my favorite thing is, you know, what,
what really helped him out was he used, uh, KDE the window manager to make
the picture of the circuit board, sort of opaque
overlay on his tool.
So he could like literally draw the trace, like he literally was tracing traces,
having to
resize it constantly everything.
And I'm thinking like, man, that would be,
that would be an awesome plug in for that tool where you could like
staple a photo essentially to what you're working on.
It's not an awesome plug in how many people actually do this?
-- Very few people,
-- I bet.
No, but the people that do it are probably very passionate about it.
Oh, no doubt. And they all probably run KDE. So it's fine.
Yeah, this is one of those like,
just obscure features that I suspect the tool will
get because it also is kind of cool.
Yeah. Ok. So let's
as much as I could spend the next hour talking about this.
We won't, but this ties it nicely to the topic we want to talk about,
which is some of the, I guess
-- anti obscurity tools, I would say where
-- it's not so much anti obscurity.
It's just that there's a lot of security that works quite well
-- until it doesn't work well. And then it feels terribly and
-- hold on.
We got to explain this better. You're, you're
no one knows what you're thinking.
I, I sadly do, but
there aren't no, no potholes. Holy crap.
Kurt, for anyone who doesn't know Kurt has been banned by me.
For talking about potholes and he still does it.
And I cut those stories out of the show and I tell
him this while he's telling the story and he'll still say,
oh, let me finish it.
I'm like, no. Anyway. Ok. So there are tools like, for example, the flipper zero
and there's now a tool to take pictures of like the inside of life.
There's like software defined radio.
Well, the,
but the difference is that has always existed as a
technology but it's never been like an off the shelf.
That's
right.
And that's a big difference. Right.
-- And,
-- and so hang on, hang on.
And so what's happening now is these tools exist
and they're in many instances being used to,
we'll say circumvent traditional existing security,
like where you can obviously just take some pictures of a
lock and cut a key and the key works in the lock
and it's easy.
Yeah. Right. That's just it, it's for normal people. Exactly. And it's affordable.
It's like you're talking hundreds of dollars. Right. Not thousands.
-- Well,
-- a great example of this technology, Josh,
go make a fire out in the woods with no tools, go find some rocks, bash them together.
You know what I mean? But versus here's a bit lighter. Right?
Like that's,
that's,
yeah, like I'm sorry, but I can't make a fire in the woods without tools.
I need a,
I need a lighter and probably some lighter fuel and some like dry kindling from home.
But that's the point. Right?
Is
decoding a lock.
Sure. You just feel it out like the lock picking lawyer.
But that level of skill is really high.
And now there's those, like, it's a little USB camera with a little mirror and it on,
on certain kinds of locks, like cheaper locks and by cheaper,
-- I don't mean like cheap, cheap, I mean, like,
-- like the,
-- the stuff we have at our
-- house, you basically just push it in,
it looks at the pins where they're resting and then you can read off the
bidding like the the depth of each key cut and then just cut a key.
I actually ordered a pair of key cutter,
pliers and um the mechanical Lishi block decoder tool.
Oh
but uh yeah, so the thing is, well, like the flipper zero is a great example of it.
It's a little, basically, it's a little computer with radio software,
defined radio capabilities
and more importantly,
a nice little interface and you can just load arbitrary software on it.
So people have written, you know, like, well,
a simplistic example would be like Hyundai
and um a couple of manufacturers apparently implemented
rolling codes so badly that like they use the same code or it's so predictable,
whatever.
And like if you load this on the flipper zero, you could just record it, replay it,
boom, done.
That's right. Like there's no,
there's no skill anymore needed. It's like making a fire.
If I give you five gallons of gasoline in a bit lighter,
-- like you're gonna be able to set something on fire
-- there.
I mean, there are still instances. So I actually have a really good example of this.
I have another podcast called Hacker History where I just have people tell
me old stories and I just talked to a guy who goes by hash
and hash does hardware hacking of smart meters specifically as a youtube channel.
I'll put a link in the show notes.
He was telling a story and this a little bit of the story made it on the show.
But he told me uh uh quite a bit more once we hit stop.
And so when the smart meters were created,
they use like a rolling code for the the frequency they listen to.
So obviously, if you want to send the smart meter information,
there's like a pres shared key
and the sender will like jump between frequencies at a
set interval and then the meter obviously knows that frequency
jumping as well. And so it'll, it'll hop back and forth, right?
And that's one of that's basically their security mechanism,
right?
What this guy did is he was hacking on a smart meter and
he has like an SDR that's like 3 305 $100 something like that.
I think it, it's probably the hack RF is my suspicion.
And I think, I think this, this meter had like 200 possible frequencies.
And so his solution to get his data into it
was to just transmit on every single frequency at the same time.
And so as the meter was jumping around, it was still receiving.
And the thing is
when this meter was created like 15 years ago, 20 years ago,
this was a perfectly reasonable security mechanism.
Nobody's going to buy 200 radios and transmit
in sync.
That's right.
That would be like literally hundreds of thousands
-- of dollars
-- transmitting 200 radio signals in sync.
Right. Exactly. It probably couldn't have been done
without, again, like a, a nation state doing the work.
But now for $300 you can totally do this.
And like this is another one of those examples where
we had this security in the past
that was sufficient,
but it's not sufficient anymore.
You think IOT stuff sticks around for a long time,
like stuff in the power system and infrastructure,
like that's not gonna get replaced for 50 years.
Well, so he said,
hash told me, I,
I love, that's the one thing I love about hacker history. I learned so much.
But he said the, the life of a smart meter is 15 years.
So
basically
short,
maybe, I mean, 15 years is pretty solid, I think for any, any piece of equipment,
I would guess 20 or 30
maybe. But whatever, 15 years. But you think what was 15 years ago? We're in 2022.
So 15 years ago was the dark ages of computing,
I think by definition, 15 years ago is always going to be the dark ages of computing,
I mean.
Right. Absolutely.
And now, obviously in the, in the world of power,
you have equipment that is 100 years old in some cases.
What was that, that fire in California that they, they think was caused by that line
falling off the tower because the, the,
the piece of chain rubbed through
and it's so old, they don't have records for it.
Like they think it's from the early 19 hundreds.
Yeah, exactly. Like, that's very normal
in that world. So, 15 years for them is zero years, basically.
Well, and that's why I'm so shocked that, like, although I guess in fairness it's,
it's, well, you would know that this thing is going to be, like,
e waste garbage in five or 10 years and you're gonna want some new capability.
So, you might as well,
like, I'm kind of the same way with laptops now.
Like,
I would never keep a laptop more than about 56 years
because it's just so slow time to get a new one.
Yeah. Oh, absolutely. Well, and they fall apart now, like, they're built like crap.
I mean, I've got one here, the one I'm using now is like, what, two years old, I think.
And it's, it's definitely showing its age
but whatever, it doesn't matter.
Anyway, the point is when we're talking about security,
the technology moves ahead and, but what's, again,
what's really fascinating to me is
like, you can't Rekey
a large building without spending millions of dollars. You can't,
you know, like,
typically what you would end up doing is just installing a badge
reader system and like ripping out everything and a whole new technology.
No, no one cares is part of the problem and, and maybe the right not to, to some degree.
I mean, like, so keys are a good example.
How long have bump keys been easily available on the internet? 10 years.
-- They still require technique though a little
-- bit.
-- It's not like picking a
-- lock,
but it's not like just pressing a button on a flipper zero and the thing opens.
-- No,
-- absolutely.
I mean,
bump keys need a little bit but you get the idea
while it is easy to break a lot of the security.
Now it's still, I don't think common enough that anyone cares.
Well,
I know locally the big thing is you just jam a screwdriver in
the lock and turn hard enough and try to shear the pins off.
That works too because I,
I've had to now iii I know two people where I've
had to replace the lock to help them because that,
that's what happened to their lock.
Like somebody tried to jam it with a screwdriver.
I mean, it's a low tech attack but it works if you have a cheap enough lock,
it doesn't matter how good the lock is,
like an attacker that has a little bit
of determination can totally get through that lock.
Here's where I was thinking this is an interesting topic when we
look at kind of a lot of the world of security,
we harp about many things being too old.
I mean, you and I were just talking before I hit record about like the C language.
Why are we still using C? Right? Well, because it's, it's legacy and it will exist for
-- some cost
-- fallacy.
But in some cases when you have trillions of dollars of people,
years of effort in something.
Yeah. Don't just throw it away and replace it,
right?
I mean, look the Linux kernel just got rust right,
like literally days ago and it's I'm certain they will migrate many,
many things to rust.
But you're talking about measuring that in probably decades,
like C is not going away anytime soon, you know what I mean?
And I think it's similar with, we look at like the capabilities of smart meters,
we look at like what the flipper zero can do.
We look at these new ways to pick locks and make keys.
Smart meters are an interesting thing because there actually is an
incentive to replace them with newer technology that allows
them to have a more smart power grid.
And for example, cut your electricity
usage when there's like the possibility of a blackout, you know,
like all those people in Texas that signed up for that thing where
I'll get,
what is it?
Basically you'd get cheaper electricity if you let them kind
of cut you off when demand was really high,
they couldn't adjust their thermostats.
Right. Sorry. Yeah, they, yes, they got free smart thermostats
and in return for it they had to live, you know,
they had to be a bit sweaty when it got hot out.
And of course,
they all lost their mind when this actually happened because none of
them had actually read or understood what they were signing up for.
And, and so there is an incentive for this stuff,
especially with the power grid because even locally,
like our power grid, we've had,
I think three emergency alerts in the last two or three weeks where it's just
like something was offline,
something else was down for maintenance as planned.
But then also it got like stupid hot
in like September and,
you know, the power grid is kind of like uh whoops,
you know,
we're getting there, it was like stage two alert. So,
I mean, and that's the thing, right?
So with smart meters there is that there is a good incentive
to replace it with newer technology that probably will be more secure,
at least, hopefully, especially if it's now controlling what I can do.
So here's, I think that the point you hit on
much sooner than I was hoping to, but that's fine.
Security alone, I don't think is an incentive for any of this stuff. Right.
There needs to be some other reason, like replacing smart meters,
like, straight up unless you're a bank and it's money, who cares? Right.
Right.
And, and so I think when you look at, like, locks on houses,
even though they're trivial to generally get around,
I don't think you're going to see a major push to replacing
them because we have a technology that works basically for most people.
And it's not like you're seeing mass break ins or anything like that.
Well, actually we are seeing more break ins locally.
But one thing too is that it's not a
technology that's easy to really replace and improve significantly
because I also have windows.
But what I see,
for example is myself and everybody I know
is getting like ring doorbells and cameras,
you know, so that we can call the cops when somebody comes in or breaks in or whatever.
And that's the other thing is like a lot of security technology.
Like we're not going to replace seatbelts, you'll always have seatbelts,
but we also have air brakes and we also have
anti lock brakes and we also have collision avoidance.
-- So we, you
-- know,
I I don't like that example because I think
the point you hit on is with ring doorbells.
Security is often bad at prevention because prevention often requires 100%
Well, by definition,
to prevent something, you have to prevent it 100%. That's
what prevention means.
But once you have the ability to, like, monitor and observe an environment,
it changes some of what happens because let's say you do get broken into
-- with your house. That sucks.
-- Well, it happened to my neighbor,
my neighbor got broken into and my son noticed the next
day that his garage door was open and I'm like,
that's weird and it didn't even tweak to me that both
his cars were missing because they were away on their honeymoon.
So before we run ourselves out of time, I want to kind of tie this all together. Right.
So we know there's,
there's existing security technology that we'll say has never been
100%. We know that,
but it's always been good enough, right?
Be it, door locks, be it even our, our computer security is often the case.
Now we have all this tooling that helps you get around a lot of
just that we say
trivial security, maybe we'll call it.
And this is even true in the world of computers where there is
so much information. You've got things like metas
plait. Now you can buy exploits on, on various black markets like
the bar is lower than it's ever been.
Right? Well, and availability, right?
Like you were like, oh, you, you can't do that, Kurt like blah, blah, blah,
show me proof of this and I'm like,
here's a link to a commercial product with a how to video where they like.
-- No, no.
-- Ok. No, I want no, you can't do that to me. I'm not gonna let you.
So Kurt says he can pretend he's drunk and stumble up to a house and stick the
camera in and pull it out and then stumble away and then make a key later.
That's not how that works.
You have to,
no,
you have to pull,
you plug it in and it reads one pin and you pull it out and you have to twist the back and
push it back in and read the next pin and you have to do that for all five or six pins.
Depending upon the lock you're working with. That is not a practical attack
yet.
I accept that the day might come that you just stick it in.
It takes a picture of all of the pins and you pull it out and you've got what you need.
-- That isn't what exists today though.
-- Ok.
But, but I think part of it now is it's, that is clearly possible.
It is. It is well, within the realm of reason. Yes.
Honestly, I'm guessing you could probably just do it in software now.
Just whip up a little A I
probably that video
and,
and that's the thing, right is that
I think part of it too is it's not,
it's not just that these tools are available it's that we
know they're available and we can buy them online for like,
2, 300 bucks.
Right. Like Flipper Zero is, is doing that and like, literally they have that.
They have like, us customs seized a shipment of 15,000 Flipper Zeros
and it's holding on to them. Yeah, it was on their Twitter thing a week or two ago.
I don't know if it's been resolved yet and
I suspect they're kind of like this is naughty.
But is it illegal? Well, if it's not illegal? Well, poop, what do we do now?
Because,
you know, I,
I'm guessing law enforcement doesn't look at these and be like, oh, cute.
A little, like wireless hacking toy to learn. No, they're like this.
-- It
-- has a dolphin on it. How could it be dangerous,
-- dude?
-- Have you read about how horrifically evil dolphins are
just Google it. It's no, seriously, they are not a happy fun creature.
I refuse to believe this
are friendly.
They are friends.
The US Navy uses them anyways.
But, so
the thing is, it's like, I, you know, II, I see this like, lock decoder thing,
you know, from the lock picking lawyer and it's like, go on my website and buy it.
It's like they start at like 30 bucks depending on
like which key way and which key system it is.
Somebody like me, I'm gonna actually document, like, I want to see like,
after an hour of practice 10 hours of practice.
Like, how, what is my progression with this tool?
Right.
And I've only done really basic lock picking in pass,
which basically consists of like, I bought a master lock and a rake and I was like,
zip, zip click.
-- I'm like, oh, these really are garbage locks.
-- That's not, that's not lock picking
but ok. Ok. So anyway, anyway,
the incentive for
security I think is never going to be enough by itself. Right.
Unless you are a secured location which like things like banks,
obviously that's a different casinos.
They care,
you know, military installations, they care.
But you know what they all have in common people with
weapons willing to enforce the rules with violence
because that's
because that's the only thing that's going
to ultimately stop a determined attacker because,
you know, like if somebody breaking into my neighbor's house,
like I could be out there on my lawn yelling at them, they're,
what are they going to do?
-- Run away? They don't care, like, until the cops show up.
-- Exactly.
So, anyway, security for normal people, I think by itself and
there are, there's always going to be this progression of, we'll say antis
security
-- stuff. Be it flipper zero, be it lock picking equipment, be it, what,
-- whatever.
Right. The anti
anti
-- missile.
-- Right. Right.
It's always been a cat and mouse game throughout history. Right.
Like forever and it will always be a cat and
mouse game and I feel like we've reached a point
in
just the pervasiveness of technology, the simplicity of creating product
and
everything that exists
where
the, the ability to, I, I guess, obscure this,
this security because I would say a lot
of the security is security through obscurity fundamentally.
-- Oh, dude,
-- remember when locksmiths were like, well, like magicians, like,
we can't tell you how locks it worked.
Like people would post basic diagrams of how cylinder locks work
and people would argue with them that you can't do that. It's illegal.
You, you're like, dude, it's, it's simple mechanical diagram.
-- Like,
-- well, there, there's always been that though, if,
if your security relies on people not knowing how it works, you should
-- is terrible.
-- Like how many, how many computer security people railed about?
You can't tell people about these techniques or these, you know, secrets, you know,
like the magician's code.
I don't think there was a lot of that.
I think there was an attempt maybe for a short period of time.
I got death threats on some occasions from a vendor basically,
like, well, not death threats. No, I got death threats for that.
Ssh SSL tell like for Ssh, sniff when I wrote an article about it,
the end of SSH and SSL I got death threats from it.
Yeah.
And I also got threats.
I remember from a large company uh when I revealed a
security flaw in their product that I thought was super trivial.
And not a big deal, but they were under,
they were being acquired and so they wanted no bad news and they lost their minds.
Well, and, and there,
there have been many vendors that made a big deal
about security vulnerabilities and trying to keep them hidden and,
and there's still, that still exists.
I mean, bug bounties by a lot of companies aren't used to fix bugs.
They're used to silence researchers.
Right. Where if you don't shut up, we're not paying you money.
And that's, that's a whole another problem in itself.
But the point is right, we've got all this technology.
It's kind of caught up to a lot of our security and
now it's time for security to kind of make some of the,
we, we need another step.
Right? It's time for things like door locks to get better. It's time for things like,
you know, various RF ID
and infrared and whatever it is that the flipper zero can basically p now like
-- that stuff all needs to get that
-- flipper zero is in for it too.
Yeah, this infrared
when it was really cool actually. So when I was at uh Cipher
Con earlier in the year,
they had like this weird game with the badges and they used infrared to talk to each
other and people were like trying to capture the
data with their flipper zeros because Flipper zero,
like it was the,
the, the Kickstarter crew had just gotten them like,
literally days before this conference.
And it was funny because the,
the people, the, the people who built the badges,
they recognized this was going to happen.
And so
the, basically the badges were like, impossible to figure out.
They purposely made it, like, very, very difficult
that shipment gets released by us customs.
Right. Right. Anyway, anyway, but the point is right,
we, we need kind of need the next step now. But what, what is going to drive?
Right. Not just security like who is doing
new and novel research into door locks for residential areas, to
my knowledge
and part of it too though is to accept that maybe
door locks are kind of at an evolutionary dead end.
And for example, like
belts, a three point seatbelt,
people aren't going to accept five point or
eight point racing seatbelts in their car.
So
let's fill it with air bags.
I have quicks, set locks like I'm sure everybody in the audience is like, yeah,
I could pick those in five minutes like, yeah, you absolutely could,
you could also just kick in the front door,
but I also then have the, you know, the alarm system and the cameras and
I also don't leave my house much because I'm basically antisocial,
you know, so I'm always here, but that's the thing. Right.
So I,
I accept that locks are essentially unless I spend like 3
to 500 bucks per door to put like some you know,
RF ID badge system on it.
-- But I just get an alarm system.
-- Here's kind of the way I think about this.
Why do you have an alarm system?
Is the alarm system going to stop anyone?
No,
the alarm system is so that I know what's happening sooner and can call the police.
And more importantly, you can show it to your insurance company
and they can't claim
that your house wasn't broken into.
And I think that's part of it is you are actually correct and, and your,
your seatbelt analogy.
And I think like automobile safety and things like that are apt
is
you reach a point of just diminishing returns where for, for there's,
it might be money, it might be, people just want to accept it.
There, there's a million things hassle.
And then we, we kind of now we enter the realm of insurance
where you're acquiring insurance to basically fill that
gap where your protection or security or whatever stops
and reality kicks in. And this is why like,
you know, you're going to be safe enough in a car accident,
your car is gonna be trashed.
The insurance company is going to pay for the damage and take care of the problem.
-- Basically,
-- we, we talked about this many years ago, Tom, you know,
like should we build fireproof buildings or should
we just make everybody get smoke alarms?
Well,
the cost of making fireproof buildings is high like it's possible.
Like there are like no seriously like jails
and there are certain types of institutional buildings,
like I assume all concrete.
Yeah, I mean, so there are ways of building fireproof buildings, you know,
like a famous thing is most stables
are built now with steel, I beam supports and a steel roof.
So that if there's a fire, the whole thing doesn't collapse down because like shas
burn down
a lot because they're full of straw.
Like
no, like I just,
that's just how it is. Like
literally the best bettings for horses are like straw and shavings.
-- Interesting. I mean, that's fair.
-- Straight up.
We're talking multiple cubic yards of wood shavings in a building.
That's a fire hazard.
Yeah, like you end up with spontaneous combustion if you have a big pile of stuff,
I've seen that more than once,
you know.
And so the thing is like at some point you just don't like, you just accept that.
Yeah, it'll fail. So we ensure it,
you know, pull the risk.
-- That's literally what insurance is for.
-- On that note,
the insurance companies are generally very good about keeping track of what is
the acceptable and unacceptable products. I mean,
if you look at automobiles, that's a great example where
during the transition from
like, you know, no seatbelts to seatbelts and cars,
there was no doubt a point where insurance companies were like,
if you don't put seatbelts in your car, we're not insuring this car
and like,
that's a pretty good reason,
you know. And I imagine
it's probably very similar. I know when I got home insurance
they had me fill out this great big form, you know.
Well, you know, tell me about this, tell me about this. Like, who makes your locks?
Who does this?
-- And I get that,
-- I got a new furnace in ac and my parents and some other people
and as part of the standard thing now is they, they basically,
you're required to buy two carbon monoxide detectors as part of the package.
And that's the thing, right? They're like 30 or 40 bucks
and they absolutely 100% save lives.
Yeah. Oh, absolutely.
You know, we should link to that Reddit thread where that guy was, like,
I find these weird notes left around my apartment,
you know, and everybody's like, well, that's so,
and then it turns out to be carb monoxide poisoning,
right?
I will try to find that. It's, that's a really good story though. Ok.
So summing it all up.
I,
I think the interesting takeaway I have
from this conversation is that there's obviously
there's a point of diminishing returns on all security
and I think everyone can agree with that.
Right. Like perfect security obviously just can't exist.
It's like going the speed of light
and the closer you try to get to it, the harder it is.
Now we start entering places where we have to use other things,
-- be it like monitoring, be it insurance, be it whatever,
-- well, affordable things.
That's true. Things that, that have acceptable and under
return on investments
and especially insurance. So yeah, I I feel like
I feel like this makes sense.
When I, when I started this episode,
I kind of expected us to just spend a
lot of time bashing most of the existing industries.
Well, I mean, a perfect example of this is, you know,
we're finally starting to make the leap to hardware
two fa because we've discovered like we've reached the,
like we can't make S MS text two fa more secure.
It's, it's a dead end.
Yeah. Any
two factor authentication system that involves pushing something and
annoying a person is probably doomed to failure.
It has to be like a P system where they can't be annoyed so that they just send the code
-- to the attacker and make it stop
-- even though the
hardware two fa comes with its own set of challenges.
But the thing is, it's also going to take like a good decade or five for us to get rid of.
Totally. Like,
well, we're still stuck with password rotation
and we're gonna be stuck with like S MS text authentication for, yeah,
-- probably 50 years
-- forever.
Kirk. We'll be stuck with it forever. That's the answer.
All right, I'm going to call it. This is fun. This is good.
Uh And, and seriously, if you're listening,
go watch that youtube video of the guy who makes the ISA card.
It's like it's mind blowing and amazing.
Anyway, thank you, Kurt, thank you everyone for listening. Go to open
source security podcast.com. Hit up the show notes, Suzie Pound Os Ss Podcast.
Hashtag Do hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too and everybody get a carbon monoxide detector.
-- Seriously. You won't.
Yeah, definitely. All right. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.