Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast.
Probably one of the best well known security podcasts on the internet with myself,
Kurt Siefried
-- and my partner Josh Pressers.
-- Against my better judgment. I let Kurt talk me into
recording an episode where I have no knowledge of the topic.
-- And that intro does not spark joy.
-- I
just told you what the topic is, what you, what
we're going to talk about, well known security dot TXD.
-- That
-- thing. I heard the Dutch government is mandating it for all the websites. Now.
That's cool.
That's actually really cool. I think
here's the fundamental problem I have with security dot TXD by definition,
anyone competent enough to know about it
is also probably competent enough to just blindly fire
an email to security at your domain.com or whatever
or otherwise find how to contact you
people that don't use well known security dot TXD.
Keep emailing our, our data protection officer or sales or
whatever.
But one thing I will say where security dot TXD
is of benefit is places that have a bug bounty.
Cool, good. But which one like which provider? Right?
Because I've been in a situation where I, you know, somebody's like, oh,
they have a bug bounty.
I'm like a, huh? Like, do I get a hint?
Which one
you
got to find out?
Yeah. Uh,
look, there's
a reason these people email, like,
your legal department or your sales department or your DPO or whoever
-- the,
-- well, they're all the big bounties. Well, but
those places usually res
respond and that's why they do it because a lot of
times if you email a lot of companies at security at
it, it might be a black hole. There was somewhere with
-- Red Hat where security at went
-- to
Microsoft you're thinking of because it was
originally set up as like campus security.
And so that's why
they
had
Microsoft does it
actually at least
why was Red Hat secular, not security? I always wondered that, but
it was some bizarre old reason that apparent, well,
security went to the same place but
they always told people secular because apparently
in like 1997 or something, some security nerds decided it should be se
alert for alerting to vulnerabilities or something. I don't remember the details.
I just know
it was one of those bizarre historic decisions that
haunted everyone involved for decades to come
because I always found it super awkward.
Well, but the thing is though, if we actually get security dot TXT more widely known,
one nice thing is, well, for example, scraping websites
to find it as trivial
compared to trying to find a security contact.
Although honestly, with chat GP T and analyzing web pages and stuff,
it's getting easier to like, look at a random web page and say, like, you know,
tell me what color the product is or is, you know, there's security
reporting mechanism on this web page, right?
I mean, sure, I, I also feel like
I feel like putting this,
how do I put this nicely if you can't
get a security dot TXT on your website
and, or technically, or you can't, like, sell your management on doing it.
Well, there's your answer as far as report,
what will happen to reporting security bugs to that organization?
Right.
No, I mean, I,
I don't view security dot TXT necessarily as having value in the contents.
Just the fact that if you have one, it shows a certain level of maturity.
Oh, it's that signal that we're probably not gonna sue you for reporting a bug to us.
Right. Because how many places like, I will never email a bank a security flaw
because I've just heard too many horror stories
and I'm just like, not my monkey, not my circus.
Right. Right.
You know what I love is,
I'll talk to people and I'll say things like that and they're like,
but what if your money's at the bank?
I'm like,
bank has insurance.
Have you not heard of the FDIC?
We, we,
we literally just went through this whole thing with Silicon
Valley Bank where even if your money's not properly insured,
you'll still get it back.
-- Right.
And then I also love that then the conversation turns into,
but what if someone logs in as you and, and steals your money?
I'm like, that's called fraud also insured. Like we're still fine.
It's
ok.
It's funny, we actually just, uh, on Wednesday did a threat model for
essentially the scenario where
the attacker is able to run some code or get you
to do something like run a bookmark on your web browser.
So they have code running within your web browser, steal your security token.
And how
do you know what, what can we do to prevent that?
And actually we'll have to have a discussion
about step up authentication at some point later.
Yeah, not today.
But yeah, back to this. Like
I fundamentally feel like when I look for the security dot TXT,
especially a security related vendor and they don't have one.
I'm just like, oh,
you know, I'm
well, it's like email like you,
well, now you have to do SPF and DC M if you want your email to get anywhere.
I mean, basically, I don't know if security TXT will ever catch on
to that degree.
-- But
-- because, well, it was, the thing is like you have to do SPF and D Mark and DC
M on your email if you want it delivered.
Like it's just that simple, same thing. With http S
Google search engine optimization, like the HTTP S is part of your ranking.
So everybody's like, oh, well, I guess we have to finally turn it on,
you know,
and I get that it's complicated like the BBC had that excellent write up on
why it took them like two years to enable HTTP S across their websites.
You know,
because the third party includes in ads and
everything and obviously now it's a lot easier,
but back in the day it was not.
So anyway, that's the thing. Security dot TXT will never have that driver.
Ok.
I want us to back up a little bit because there are going
to be people listening who don't understand what security dot TXT is.
And so let's start at the very beginning and explain what it is and how it works.
I will start,
I just looked it up RFC 9116.
So this has been adopted by the I ETF.
Yes and Ashley, let's back it up. Even one more
well known U Ria, well known U I is a uniform resource identifier for
L path prefixes that start with slash dot well, dash known slash.
They are implemented in web servers.
So that request to the server for well
known services or information are available at U
L's consistent
well known locations across servers. And there's actually about
uh there's a couple dozen of these, for example, there's the
Acme challenge one, you know, for doing uh domain verification.
There's things like there's one for Apple account
based user enrollment for mobile device management anyways,
the point is there's a whole bunch of these and,
but what's interesting is the list at Wikipedia
only security dot TXT has its own page.
The rest of them are like, I have no idea how widely used they are.
If at all are the other ones. RFC. Si bet not.
Uh, some of them are and some of them are backed by vendors.
-- Let's
-- let's talk about security dot TXT.
I got the RFC pulled up, I'll put a link in the show
notes, right? So there's sections that are defined
for security dot TXD. Number one
Acknowledgments.
This is where you can acknowledge security researchers for their reports.
This used to be the only thing we did for security researchers who sent us reports.
Yeah.
Well, and again, we've talked about that on the show where, you know, I,
I would love to send you money but like legally I can't
or it's just too much work
and then they have next section canonical.
It's a field indicator, canonical URL S or security dot
te file is located whatever. Not exciting.
Well, no, that's important because for example,
you can have a lot of sub properties just point at your main security dot TXT
because also you got to remember subdomains.
So like, ideally,
ideally you serve a security dot TXT on every
the host name that
you have.
Right.
Reminds me I should probably set up a cloud flare rule for that anyway.
I just serve it off the route because
close enough. Right. I agree. I agree completely.
So, the canonical one is actually, it's quite good.
-- Uh, contact is obviously the next one. You can't. No,
-- don't just give ahead.
I'm reading the list. You don't read the list.
That's right.
That's right. Don't be, don't be getting out of your stay in your lane. All right.
-- So contact, right. Just remember
-- who has the six buttons.
I then no one, no one understands what that means. So anyway,
anyway,
I'm, I'm
getting a
contact contact field, uh, how researchers can contact you, right? Email address.
For example, it could be a URL, whatever makes sense, right?
In their example, they have a telephone number
part of me wants to do that now just because I think it would be awesome.
Well, and again though, it's, for example, if it's a bank, like, come on,
that's fair. That's fair.
Or,
and the thing to remember is that telephone number may not
be externally reachable or it may be going into IVR hell,
or it might just
-- get to a mailbox if
-- it's not externally reachable like it shouldn't be in this.
Anyway, we're going to keep going.
-- Does the
-- spec actually say that this stuff has to be publicly available?
Because I don't,
my understanding of security dot TXT is it doesn't have to be public.
-- Like this could be for internal resourcing too.
-- I'm not going to get into this.
Anyway. Encryption encryption key, you can use AC P GP key is the intended key. P GPS.
The funny thing here is uh the discussion on hacker news about this.
Everybody just basically says either one
nobody's ever sent us encrypted email and
I'm trying to think of red hat. Like how often do we get encrypted email to sec
alert?
We got it a couple times a month for sure because we had the
that banana signing server we had to use for decrypting things.
But for the majority of people,
they're never gonna see an encrypted email and more to the point now,
all emails pretty much encrypted on the wire.
-- So like close enough, right? Whatever,
-- whatever, it's fine.
-- I
-- think the encryption thing basically, if you're implementing this,
you can basically ignore it.
Uh expires. I love this field so much.
I
do it. It says
I'm just gonna read it because I'm gonna screw it up if I don't,
the expires field indicates the date and time after which the data contained in
the security dot TXD file is considered stale and should not be used.
I love this and it says that the value of the
field should be less than a year in the future.
This reminds me of the the the certificate problem where
people get certificates once a year and they forget.
So it take two weeks to remember how to request a certificate
and get it versus purposely expiring something on a regular basis.
So you're forced to deal with it constantly.
-- It's perfect.
-- It's, it's even better than that where
if you encounter uh uh security dot TXT with like a short time frame then you know that
it was probably put up not too long ago and it's sort of still active now in fairness.
like the one for the CS A I just said it to 2050 but also
cloud security alliance.org, like we're kind of known for doing security stuff.
-- You know what I mean?
-- You shouldn't set it to 2050. You lazy bum.
I just, I can't be bothered to automate updating it
-- anyway.
-- Moving on.
I like it looking, hiring security jobs.
That one is great.
-- I think that one is lovely. This reminds
-- me, was it, who was it? Was it
cloud flare? Someone who
who you like when you look at the HTML, it would say like if you're looking at this,
you should call us or no
Akamai I think did that.
Yeah, a couple of them have done it and like Nintendo had one for developers.
Yeah, they had like an actual like if you dug through the code,
there was like a side scroller anyways, it was pretty cool.
It was a Nintendo
maybe
anyway,
policy in the next field.
Uh It has a link to the vulnerability disclosure policy, which is great. I like that.
There are vulnerability disclosure policies.
I I get that it's one of those documents that will explain what is going to happen
when a researcher reports a vulnerability to you.
Part of it is some researchers have absolutely insane expectations.
Like I remember working at Red Hat
and somebody reported a cross site scripting vulnerability to us.
And I've used the story before and they wanted daily updates and I'm like, no,
we'll fix it when we fix it.
And I got them to,
I don't know, necessarily to calm down,
but I got them to stop bugging me by pointing out here's another
publicly logged XSS with the CV E in the product that like it,
they'll fix it.
Some,
I always felt bad and got annoyed when a researcher would report
something that was minor and it's like we acknowledge this report,
but
you're not gonna fix it for the foreseeable future. And it's like I,
-- I just called your baby ugly and kicked it. But I'm sorry, man. You
-- see.
And I think part of it is again when you do things at scale, you kind of get over that.
Like I love reporting stupid,
simple little vulnerabilities back in the day as a way of introducing myself.
I hated you so much courage. You
know, when
you, when I worked at Redhead and you didn't,
you would keep reporting these worthless temp file issues.
Oh, my goodness.
Well, part of it is, I was also trying to get some metrics to see what would happen.
We hated you. That's what happened. Ok. Fair.
I think what?
Well, but also what gets me is it's kind of like that whole and again,
this is another show but like I remember I was on a flight
and the thing that holds the curtain for the galley
was like broken and ripped out and I'm like,
oh, like that thing's broken.
He's like, oh, yeah, we have a zero defect tolerance policy.
We'll log it and I'm like,
well, clearly it's been broken for a while and your policy on zero defects is like,
like, hopefully they're triaging in like engines first,
you know, control surfaces and the, you know, the, the curtain for the galley,
-- whatever, you know, we'll fix it
-- later.
I'm sure they logged it.
Right. But anyway, all right, let's keep going. Preferred languages.
This makes sense what language we can contact you in.
Yeah. Right.
I,
and I think that matters a lot less now
that translation has become AAA very like Google translates
pretty decent and obviously the new chat GP T
and stuff like that is actually a lot better.
So,
and I mean, you and I both have as a skill probably on our resume, you know,
reading English as a third language,
poorly written security vulnerability reports.
Maybe because like some of the stuff that came into Red Hat was like,
you learn to parse weird stuff after a while.
Now. That's,
that's it.
Those are the fields.
It's very simple. It's,
it's one of those things anyone can do
and most of us don't, I don't have one at work and I should, I keep, it's on my list.
In fact, I have a, to do list it totally on there.
But it's one of those things that it's also minor
which makes it difficult to sometimes remember to do or to prioritize.
And I think that's one of the challenges this has.
So it's easy to say everyone should have one, have one and they should,
but they don't.
Well, again, that's, it's a good signal for like, do they do the details?
Do they take care of that little things? You know,
-- I agree.
-- How many people have an extra roll of toilet paper in their bathroom
versus
like what's on the wall is all you got?
I am confident that my Children have no idea how
toilet paper gets under the sink in my house.
I'm completely 100% certain of this fact.
I think they also don't understand that light
switches have an on and an off mechanism,
but that's another story.
I like it because it's short. It's simple.
It's, and it's a really good signal that this organization is probably not gonna
to
you
if you,
why did you want to talk about this?
Just because the Dutch government said everyone should use
these or was there some other nefarious reason,
mostly just because we've never talked about it officially on the show.
And it's been one of those things where it's been around kind of forever.
It's been a while. Yeah.
Like it was first done about what, uh five, I think the RFC is five years old now
according to,
-- but
-- it was before that,
according to Wikipedia,
the internet draft was first submitted in September of 2017.
Yeah.
And it was like one or two years before that where it was kind
of kicking around and some people did it or didn't do it or whatever.
But it's just
when I think about how much time I've spent trying to track down, like,
how do I report something to somebody?
Right.
Because if I, if, if this doesn't exist,
I go to the website and then I go to the contact and
there's almost never security contact. It is rare. Yes.
I randomly search maybe two or three of the
bigger bug bounties and maybe they show up,
maybe they don't.
Yep.
And then at that point it's kind of like, well,
yeah, I'm not gonna,
I'm just gonna
-- just forget about it.
-- Well, ok, look. So there's, I think
another piece to this story and
there's some history behind
the universe of disclosure. Mhm. Back in the early days
you either couldn't contact a company because they
just didn't have a mechanism or it was dangerous
and it was,
you just post things to full disclosure or to bug track or whatever and be like YOLO,
we're, we're gonna do this
and then of course, that created a mess for its own reasons.
And you had organizations like Microsoft,
Microsoft would specifically call people out for behaving what,
what they thought was poorly.
And this is where the term responsible disclosure came from, right?
Which responsible disclosure really meant
you better do what Microsoft says
or else and there was no or else you just were put on their naughty list.
But we're seeing the thing with A I now, you know, it's gone from, have you,
did you notice that Google for example,
has dropped all the ethical A I stuff and gone to
what is it safe A I or some meaningless term
that essentially means whatever we want it to mean.
Yeah, like don't be evil A I, oh wait, no, we're not doing that anymore.
-- And
-- now they're all calling for regulation because of course they,
I want to pull the ladder up behind them. So start ups and
the open anyways, that'll actually be another show, open source A I,
right.
The thing I think is sadly unlike say email security or http S
there's nothing to drive
adoption of security dot txt other than organizations that mandate it much like,
oh perfect example, DNS EC is, is in the same boat like I've done kind of
um scans to see who actually uses DN Ss SE
C.
And so, for example,
there's a couple of larger payment providers that do like paypal,
but the vast majority of payment providers, for example, don't.
-- Ok. TLS is good enough. Why would you do DNS X? She's gonna break stuff.
-- This is the
perfect example.
So I'm a payment provider. I'm not using DNS Sec.
How many times has my DNS been hijacked?
-- Exactly.
-- Zero.
Right. I'm not saying it's, it's completely zero for everyone.
But the reality is it's a very, very low number.
Well, and even if they hijack the DNS there, everything's TLS now.
Right. Well,
yeah, I mean, basically,
basically, well, you could potentially get it whatever.
No, no. Like, like Visa, for example, Visa, for example, actually has a, they don't,
basically,
they have a subset list of all the TLS providers as a developer you're allowed to use.
-- Ok.
-- Right. But if you control a domain, you could get a certificate for that domain.
Right. But like,
if you can hijack visa.com somehow
that, no, that's not happening.
-- Right.
-- I mean, anyway, anyway, the, the point is DNS Sec
doesn't solve the problem it was set out to solve
and I think it's been shoehorned into something similar.
I think the problem it's set out to solve doesn't really exist anymore.
-- Well,
-- because almost all of this security, let me put it this way.
What if we had to, let me put it this way? What if we had lets and crypt.org in 1995.
No, I'm serious. Right.
What would have happened to the security posture and all these security RFC S,
the vast majority of them,
like Dina SEK would have been stillborn. Like that would just be like,
we don't need this.
-- But
-- anyway, anyway, my comparison to security dot TXT,
I think it's kind of similar where security dot TXT
is solving a niche problem and the problem isn't contact information.
The problem is we need a way to signal we are not hostile to security researchers
and you could easily put a, put it just text and security dot Txt.
That's like we're not giant a hoes,
you can report stuff to us and that's basically the same thing
pretty much. Yeah.
Well,
-- you know what, that's a step forward.
-- It
is, it is,
I think you, at the very beginning of the show, you were like
anyone who has a security dot txt probably also has
a security reporting site or page that is findable by a person with moderate skill.
Right?
And it is, I'm ok with it.
I'm not saying you, I still think people should have a security dot Txt.
I think it's good to have one
and I think
it is,
it is unfortunate
that
today not having one doesn't mean
you
are inept at security.
It just means maybe the security team hasn't had time to do it yet.
You know what I mean?
Because there are definitely companies hostile towards security.
And then there are companies that aren't and, and maybe someday
not having a security dot Txt will be the signal of there'd be dragons here.
-- I don't know.
-- I did forget one thing, there is one thing security dot Txt is missing.
That is
a real pain in the butt nowadays.
But that, and that is scope of coverage.
You can put that in your disclosure policy. That's what a disclosure policy is for.
Well, yeah,
but it would be nice if it was machine readable because especially for giving URL S
right,
it'd be kind of nice
like because we actually a perfect example at the cloud security
lines we have if you go to clouds security lines.org/security,
um we do have a what is in scope for security
reports and it's a giant list of all our domains.
But then we also have a list of what is
out of scope for security reports because for example,
we use, we use off
zero.
So there's cloud security lines dot off
zero.com which they run it's and it's like a redirection
magic thing for the authentication
and everybody's constantly like, oh, it redirects URL.
So I'm like, yeah, that's how the Samal stuff like has to do that.
And they're like, oh and I'm like number one, it's not our site.
Number two, that's how it works. And number three, you go ask all
zero to fix.
I would kind of like it if they did
or same thing for github.
Like we're like,
you know, github.com/cloud security line slash star,
please fill out an issue in github for that thing.
And so it would be nice if,
if I could just put that in the security dot txt,
here's the deal.
You could do this if you wanted to. There's nothing stopping you.
It's a text file, put whatever you want in it, put a freaking poem in it.
It doesn't really matter when you work with bug bounties. The,
the list of things in scope and out of scope is generally just text on a website.
I, I don't think,
I don't think there's a convenient way to make that list, machine readable.
-- Even just having the urals are in or out of scope.
-- Maybe, maybe, I don't know. I'm not
fundamentally, I, it's, it's less about machine readable and more about, you know,
me redirecting users to like,
-- I'm sorry, we're just not gonna, it's here is out of scope
-- and, and,
and there's things you can't, I get that.
There's third party stuff you just can't. And it, it's, it's annoying and it sucks.
And because I remember when I ran the bug bar need elastic.
They were like, what's in scope? I said everything
they're like, what do you mean? I'm like,
everything's in scope.
If someone reports something we don't control,
I'm gonna give him a bounty and then I'll add it to the out of
scope list. Like that's the way it's going to work.
Well, that's, yeah,
that's why I added any best practices for SPFD Kim D Mark Betls http headers
and I just got tired of it.
So, all in all,
I mean, I think
I like it. Security dot TFT is cool. I don't have a lot else to say.
I feel like,
and I love that the Dutch government is sort of officially signaling now
we're not going to be jerks about you reporting stuff to us.
I mean, like this sets the tone from the top,
you know, it's like when uh was it.gov or whatever it is, like we're doing DNS SEC,
whether you like it or not and it sets the tone.
I think the government
having this file is less about maybe setting
a tone because the Dutch government has historically been
phenomenal in the context of cybersecurity.
Like they are ridiculously good and amazing.
They're like top five.
Yeah. If any of you are listening, like, come on the show, we'd love to talk to you.
But, but anyway, so
I
think for them,
it's probably more about legitimately making
the lives of security researchers easier.
Like they don't need to signal virtue,
virtue, signal, whatever the words are hard.
But you know what I mean?
They don't need to signal to anyone that they're the good guys.
I think in their context you just need to know. Ok, I'm a security researcher.
I found an issue in this Dutch website. Who the heck do I tell?
And in that context that is, I think the,
what security dot TXT is technically supposed to be for versus the
reality we see of virtue signaling of we're not giant a holes,
you know.
Well, to me it's, I mean, fundamentally it boils down to, I also,
when I'm testing providers look for signals and
actually a perfect example of something I'm really struggling with right now.
So 1015 years ago,
I was looking for providers that did HTTP S
and that was easy to check,
right?
You add an S to the URL and see if, if the little dinosaur pops up or not.
But nowadays, you know, one of the biggest challenges I'm looking for
two fa support for hardware tokens, number one and number two,
more importantly in a way support for more than one token, right?
Because like Google, Amazon, Microsoft github,
they all do this fine, they do it perfectly.
But for example,
slack.com just recently force is forcing all workspace owners and admins
to go to two fa and I'm like, oh, that's good. And then I go to the page and I'm like, oh,
I can give them my phone number for S MS or I can install an authenticator app.
It's not great but not bad, but I can only do one and my phone number I can't have,
for example, two authenticator apps,
I see.
-- Right.
-- So I if my phone breaks.
I
just use single sign on for that thing. It's way easier.
-- We
-- do and they're still forcing us to go to two fa,
oh, really?
Yeah,
I
have two, like
the cloud security lines,
we single sign on since like five minutes after I turned it on.
Hence the name,
right? Because I'm just like, this is,
this is easier, like anybody from cloud security lines.org.
Just how do I get into Slack? Well, you just go to Slack and click
but
the point is checking this stuff is hard and well, like well known security we need,
I think we need at least some public signals.
Otherwise people spend a lot of time,
waste a lot of time trying to figure out if it's safe for who to report to.
Well, they, they don't even have to be public. Look.
I have, I have a great example of this. So I complained to you, I think last night
that, that the cake was a CE A
IQ from stands for something.
-- Yeah, common assessment initiative questionnaire.
-- All right. There we go. Right.
It's just a gigantic questionnaire.
You can fill it out with details about your security posture.
I I filled it out for version 3.1.
I think internally for work version four just came out before.
It's like an incredibly
c service provider focused
which falls outside of the, the problem that I need this for
because I need to explain our internal security to external parties, right?
And so whatever, I'm just gonna keep 3.1 for the foreseeable future.
My answer
to that is like, well, unfortunately, the cloud security line,
so we do tend to be cloud security focused obviously,
but having said that I,
I am raising what you brought internally because I think
part of it too is cake is big enough now that
-- it's kind of one. It's
-- fantastic. But anyway, so here's the deal.
I have a customer that's like, hey,
I want to see all of your security policy documents and I was like,
-- we
-- get
-- those all the time,
but here's, here's what happens, right?
So I'm like,
absolutely not because they're obviously filled to the brim
with like pi I and internal system information,
like all kinds of stuff I'm not distributing.
So I say here's a cake, take this and then they come back like this isn't good enough,
send us your documents.
And I'm like, no,
I'm not sending you these documents. Let's have a call.
I want to understand your problem and it turned out
what they actually wanted was they wanted to understand our internal
security software development life cycle, our SDLC, right.
I'm like, oh, well, that's easy. Like I've got that filled out over here for you.
I'll just here take this, but it's like one of those things where
when you are dealing with, I think a lot of vendors, especially small vendors,
they don't know how to talk about this stuff or how to do this stuff.
And so sometimes it's probably easier to just make ridiculous requests, like,
send me all of your policies than it is to try to figure out what's going on.
So we get security questionnaires all the time
because technically speaking, when,
when a company or an organization becomes a CS A member,
we do have the pi I of the billing contact
and for some of them, that's enough to trigger this like giant process
of filling out. I've literally filled out spreadsheets with 20 tabs
and
yeah, it drives us nuts.
-- But we're like, we've tried teaching them and it's, this
-- is why the cake is so good.
There have been a ton of vendors that were like, here's my 7000 page questionnaire
and
I remember one time II, I was like, oh, I don't want to do this and I go to it.
And the first question was like, do you have a cake?
I
click upload
and then it grayed out every other question. It was like, thank you. I'm like, what?
It was so good. It was so amazing.
No, that makes me happy to hear because, well, obviously that, you know, like,
-- I think the cake has value and is
-- useful.
I love it. It's a great document anyway. All right. All right.
I think we've, we've kind of run ourselves out of time,
I guess
in closing,
this was a much less terror inducing topic than I was worried about when,
when Kurt tries to do this to me, I usually give him a hard, no.
But for some reason, my better judgment failed me today. But I think it worked out.
I think security dot Txt is cool. If you don't have one, it's a good idea.
But I get it if you don't like, it's, it's one of those things. So,
and I guess at the end of the day it's really about just be
nice to security researchers because they're usually
cool people and they get crap out
of them.
That's true.
-- There are some who aren't cool people but,
-- well, and it's, it's not that so much.
It's just, I get the bake bounty because money, like,
people got to pay the rent.
And actually, you know, it's weird.
I just realized we haven't had one come through in about six months,
-- but a bug bounty reporter
-- thing.
A big
bounty.
Yeah. I, I haven't had one either.
Now that you say that, I wonder, I wonder if something
did they,
was it just a small group of people doing it? And then they gave up because we
just kept telling them, no, I don't know.
Or maybe they, maybe Bug bounties official.
Bug bounties may become lucrative enough that it's
not worth trying to beg bounty yet.
-- But anyway, anyway, we say beg bounty. What we mean is people would send
-- you,
-- your SPF is not minus
-- all. Yeah.
Like, they'd send you these ridiculous things to emails, usually to legal a
or something like that.
And then they'd also beg for money at the end.
What they'd say is, I believe this bug report has value.
You should too, blah, blah, blah. Right. And I'd be like, uh huh. But our policy is no.
And my other favorite is when they'd be, like,
I found a very serious vulnerability in your website.
You should pay me and I'll tell you what it is. Like,
I don't think you did.
But
anyway. All right, I'm gonna call this one. This is fun. Thank you, Kurt.
I'm, I can, I can calm down now now that I, I know what the topic was.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you, everyone for listening. Go to, ok, before I end this.
Actually,
I just need to comment, Kurt is wearing a Waldo shirt
and, and I haven't made any jokes about it yet.
So I found you, Kurt. I see you right there.
No one else can but Kurt is wearing a Waldo shirt. I have a Waldo hat.
Maybe I should 10 to 2.
Anyway. All right. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you, everyone for listening.
Go to open social security podcast.com.
Hit up the show note, Susie Pound Os S podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media,
-- Kurt and have a marvelous rest of your day. You too.
-- Thanks everybody.
-- Thanks,
-- everyone. Bye bye.