Hello, listener,
Future Josh. Here
it turns out that we're almost certainly incorrect
in the basis of the Apple lawsuit being founded on copyright.
So everything you're going to listen to past this point
will say may be amusing but is factually incorrect.
I apologize for this heinous error.
Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself.
Kurt Siefried and my partner in probably not violating copyright doctrine.
-- Josh Pressers.
-- I mean, we violate copyright constantly every day. What is it?
The average person has over a million dollars
in copyright violations in a single day.
You know what?
There's actually a really good wired article a few weeks ago about
kind of what happened to all those people that got sued for ump
Kilian infinity dollars back in the day with Napster and stuff.
Remember there were all those law firms sending out, you know, just
mass
demand letters and suing them and, and
what I love is most of these law firms turned out to be totally like,
I think a couple of them actually ended up in jail.
I'm
shocked by this. They were so
uh let's say poorly run.
But yeah. No, it's it's interesting.
So today, uh well, not today, but like recently the Apple
Corporation
sued the NSO group to prevent them from using Apple products and services.
Yeah, I found that really wild
when I read this story.
OK. First of all,
disclaimers me and Josh are, are, you know,
I think we made it very clear in our previous show in the NFL
group that we're not in favor of companies that enable repressive regimes to,
you know, spy on journalists and human rights activists, not fans.
No, that's double plus on good. And at the same time
though, I, I suspect although I, I'm not certain, but I suspect like myself,
Josh feels very nervous
about a company
restricting who can use a physical product or a sort
of a common service that enables that physical product because
I, I'm not going to say Apple has a monopoly, but essentially you have a,
you have a choice, you have Android or Apple when it comes to mobile phones.
And so part of me is very, very nervous about a large company,
basically legally banning another organization because it next week
it could be journalists or human rights lawyers.
I mean,
maybe it's
the service aspect I can get behind because for example,
stores can trespass people who are problematic and say, you know,
this is private property.
You can't come on here,
done.
But Walmart, for example,
you know, they, they generally don't ban people from buying stuff from them,
say online or whatever. So
Walmart doesn't. But actually a good comparison here would be
the Walt Disney Corporation
where if you break certain rules at their parks,
-- you're banned for life.
-- Well, but again, you're on their physical space.
OK.
II, I feel like this has gone to a weird place.
Well, no, no, but I think actually, you know, no, there is a close parallel because,
ok, in the physical world you're in their physical space,
there's lots of laws around trespass and all that stuff.
And in the virtual world, like if I'm,
if I have an iphone that's not connected to the internet, it's kind of my device.
But if I, the moment I start using icloud,
I'm on Apple's turf, like I'm literally in their servers doing stuff. That is true.
So
the service aspect,
I guess I can sort of see the parallels with trespassing and saying, you know,
to put it bluntly if somebody is kind of very abusive of your online services, yeah,
you're probably going to boot them or restrict them.
I mean, yeah, so, so actually a great example is as part of the,
the now renamed Global Security Database
project with the cloud security Alliance,
which we'll talk about that another day.
But
I,
we get these requests from the Linux kernel people
to file a bunch of identifiers against the kernel.
And so I file generally anywhere between one and 300
things at, at a go
and it is very common for me to trip up the
github.
They're rate limiting
their anti rule.
And it's funny because it's very poorly documented.
I don't totally understand what's going on.
But, like, yeah, all the time, they're like, oh, you're using too much resources.
-- Ha ha. You're kicked out for a while.
-- Well, and that's an north
oral problem.
But one challenge is when you have abuse limiting systems you
can't tell the bad guys what those abuse limits are otherwise.
Well, it's like the old all the spam that scored 4.9 on spam assassin meant, you know,
the default cut off of five shockingly, right?
And so,
and, and again, that, that's another
set of separate set of arguments where, you know,
I hate these calf cask abuse systems where it's like you can't do that.
Why not? What am I doing wrong?
Well, we can't tell you because then you could abuse it more.
So let's back up a little bit and just say like, what is Apple actually doing?
So from what I can tell
Apple's goal is to cripple the nso group and not let them essentially find
security flaws in their products
and actively, you know, build products that actively exploit them,
which
-- when I say that out loud, I'm kind of like, I kind of
-- want that.
I mean, I, I don't think anyone would disagree with that necessarily.
And
so it, it sounds like from what I've read and I, I don't,
I am not a lawyer
and I don't totally understand the dynamics here,
but it sounds like Apple is using copyright
as the basis of this lawsuit where they're,
they're claiming that the NSO group is
violating their copyright on their software.
Yeah.
And I'm, I'm kind of surprised they didn't go with like end user license agreement.
But regardless,
I think the reason they're going with copyright is there's a very famous court case,
Costco Wholesale Group versus Omega S A.
So the deal is Omega makes fancy watches that cost a lot of money
and they price them differently globally, right?
They'll be more expensive in North America for
the exact same watch than say in Europe.
So Costco is kind of like cool,
that's what you call an arbitrage opportunity.
And so Costco, but you know, bought a big pile of watches in jurisdiction. A
shipped them in a container to jurisdiction B and sold them there at a profit.
And Omega
lost their minds and sued them because
you know,
this totally violates Omega's attempts to extract every last penny out of there and
consumers.
And so they sued Costco
successfully in uh what is this 2008
for
copyright violation?
Because obviously every Omega watch has, you know,
Omega stamped on the back or the front or whatever.
And of course, Costco fired back with for sale doctrine, you know, like
we bought these things, we, we can put them in the garbage, we can use them as plates,
we can,
I guess, really small cup holders for your, you know, Demita,
um, or,
you know, we could, we could sell them on.
Right.
And unfortunately, in my opinion, the court ruled against them,
uh, and said that
basically the first sale doctrine does not act as a defense to claims
of infringing distribution and importation for
unauthorized sale of authentic imported watches.
that board design registered in the copyright office.
I mean, yeah, there's,
there's some legal precedent here for using copyright law to restrict what a
person can do with your product that they legally purchased and legally owned.
Well, I mean,
this isn't comparable to that though because I legally purchased an iphone.
The NSO group didn't purchase my iphone.
No, no, no, but the, the NSO group bought their own iphone stuff
that
exploits
and you know.
-- Ok.
-- Yeah. Yeah. All right. I understand. I understand.
II, I don't know. I mean,
I, I guess this is where I sit on. This is, I feel like
in many instances copyright has become this strange hammer,
everyone uses to just pound every nail.
They see. And this is kind of an example of it. I, I feel like
what the NSO group does feels wrong.
It is,
is it illegal? I mean, I think the, the research isn't going to be illegal,
right?
But the attacking someone's device I suspect
is potentially illegal under certain contexts.
Yeah.
So a couple of comments here, I mean, there's,
there's a lot of activities that can or
cannot be illegal depending on intent mens rea
right?
So for example,
OK, perfect example, I see fire in your house.
So I run in, kick down the front door and go looking for people to take,
take out of there
versus I kick down your front door and take, you know, and I'm, you,
you find me in your living room, you know, uninstalling your TV, from the wall,
right?
The, the cops are gonna have, well,
hopefully the cops are gonna have two
very different reactions to those situationss.
I hope
so. I think part of it is intent because
clearly the nso group has the intent of, of,
well, you know,
doing things that let's ignore if it's illegal
or not because really that's not Apple's problem,
right?
If, if somebody does something illegal with one of your products,
that's something that the courts should deal with.
Not
you. You know what I'm saying?
Like there's a reason they're, they're felonies and they require prosecution and,
and
the justice system,
you know, it's not up to you to kind of handle that.
Um,
but I just,
and the other thing is copyright law. Yeah, it has become this monster
and I think part of the challenge is because
it has been successfully used like the Omega versus Costco um, court case.
But also if you lose your copyright if you use
copyright as an argument and you lose the case,
it's not like your copyright protections kind of go away.
It's just you fail to extend them.
Right. Right. Right. And so that makes it a much, sort of safer.
I,
I would assume it makes it sort of a
safer legal argument and that there's less downside.
It's like we can try this and if we fail cool, we can try something else.
-- I,
-- I think there's another angle to this
that
I, I haven't seen anyone talk about but
if Apple is successful in going after nso
in this way,
they could
not just them but
right. Any, any security research could fall under this umbrella and,
and while Apple might say, oh no, we're not going to bother security researchers.
Wink Wink. I mean, are you,
you know
that that specter is always there?
Yeah,
that's, I mean,
not
that, that's what I always say about these poorly written laws where they're like,
oh, well, we're not going to enforce it badly.
We're just,
you know, it's, it's not the greatest law,
but we'll enforce it selectively and do it properly.
No, if the law is bad, the law is bad and using selective enforcement of laws
-- is not the solution. The solution is to
-- patent trolls, right.
Patent trolls are like the perfect example of good intentions gone wrong.
Yeah. Well, and copyright trolls, right?
Suing people for listening, you know,
downloading music on Napster and suing them for empty ma jillion dollars.
Yeah.
Right. Right. So,
I,
I worry because if, if Apple wins this court case, then Apple can. Absolutely.
But the problem is not just Apple, then any company can shut down security research,
claiming copyright.
Oh, yes. Yes. Exactly.
And, and I might be slightly less concerned about Apple in some context,
although I know some security researchers that would disagree with me,
but
there are many companies that
say are hostile to security researchers and giving them this ammo
will just make things considerably worse. OK.
So I can't find a link to what I wanted to.
But basically there are documented cases of technical companies selling software
where the contracts expressly forbid you from
benchmarking the software and publishing those benchmark results.
So VM Ware did that back in the day
because
I, I remember
there was
it was it's around virtualization because
a long time ago,
virtualization didn't happen like in chip like it does where you
have like the magic ring negative one in the processor.
And so
VM Ware
built special technology to kind of
will say
inspect the pipeline
that's that's being sent to your CPU and then hijack some of
the operations because you couldn't do
virtualization and it wasn't very efficient,
but it was OK.
But when you had,
when you use VMWARE, they had an explicit cause in it.
They said you cannot use this to benchmark.
And there were obviously competitors coming out
that had some wicked fast technology,
Zen Xen, the which now does proper virtualization,
but it did what was called para virtualization back
in the day and para virtualization was very,
very fast.
Whereas actual virtualization was very, very slow,
except no one could show that because VM Ware said,
-- well, you're not allowed to benchmark our stuff.
-- It literally says
in the license, it's section 1.4. So it's right at the top after, you know,
-- is it still
-- there benchmarking?
You may use the software to conduct
internal performance testing and benchmarking studies.
You may only publish, distribute the results of the studies to third parties.
If we have reviewed and approved of the methodology, assumptions
and other parameters of the study prior to publication and distribution,
please contact us at benchmark and fwa.com to request review and approval.
Ouch.
This is I googled like VM Ware
Ya and
last updated may 3 2021.
So it's still there is a bit of an understatement.
It's,
yeah.
Wow.
I,
yeah, I thought anyways and, and that's my, my fear is,
I guess the good news is with open source licenses.
They're, they're unlikely to change the licenses to include these kind of clauses,
but they could.
No, no, no, you can't.
That's not open source.
Well, no, at that point, I would agree.
That's like a very fundamental limitation of your, your rights and freedoms that,
you know, Richard Stallman is gonna excuse me,
Richard Stallman is gonna pop out of your closet while you're sleeping and haunt you
-- levels of,
-- you know,
-- Stallman already haunts us all.
-- I know.
Um,
but, uh
yeah, I, uh
because we've already seen this with
cloud services where they just straight up in the term,
say you can't security test this because,
well, and in fairness, it might kind of mess up things for everybody.
I mean, I've been on both sides of this particular problem and
the, the challenge kind of becomes when you're,
when you're a service,
if you have people that want to test your, your actual production,
like
I've seen people do like, denial of service and they'll be like, oh,
your prod is broken.
It's like, no, you're an idiot, like, don't denial of service stuff like this is,
of course, now that's way harder to do if you have a proper infrastructure.
But, you know,
like 5, 10 years ago, it was, it was very different.
But now at the same time when I'm a customer of a cloud service
and I say, you know, show me your p test.
They're like, oh, we, we didn't run one and it's like, what now, I mean, come on.
Well, and here's something that all of this fundamentally
misses, uh when people discuss it is that, that really bad people,
they don't abide by the
es in court case like they will go and happily break the law.
And I mean, that's just it.
So like the thing is with the NSO group and this is,
this is one of the things I've been thinking about is
the NSO group is a legitimate company doing semi
illegitimate things is how I would describe it. It may be completely illegitimate.
You know what I mean?
I, I, whatever,
but now there's obviously plenty of,
we'll say sketchy organizations doing similar things.
And I think in the case of NSO group, I would just argue, they kind of got caught.
If they didn't get caught, we wouldn't know who they were,
we wouldn't be talking about them.
I mean,
they're legendary for not answering questions.
Well, I think part of the challenge too is they're doing it at scale, right?
It's, if an attacker finds a zero day
and uses it to try and, you know, put crypto mining software on people's devices,
yeah, that's bad.
But it's not that like nobody's going to die,
but
with what the NSO group is doing, they're doing it at scale and they're enabling
governments to do things that well, absolutely will result in people dying.
And I, so,
yeah, it's tough because
here's my view on this,
the end result of what Apple is trying to accomplish. I'm like, yeah,
yes. But the way they're doing it and the way that it will allow them
to then apply that to other people. And more importantly,
you know, because we have uh
well, essentially precedent setting cases matter,
this, this is going to, if this sets a precedent, that's,
that's a pretty big precedent.
I mean, it's going to set a precedent either way,
no matter how this ends. I think
humans lose.
Yeah.
Well, and I mean, apple,
I assume they have infinity million dollars to spend on this case,
they do have infinity dollars to spend on everything.
Like I'm assuming for them they've budgeted already several, you know, large
numbers
and
a rounding error for them. Exactly. You know,
17 minutes of iphone sales.
That's
right.
And so I do kind of worry because
also
I just, like I said, the, the, the concern I have is, is
even if Apple pledges not to be evil and even if Apple does a whole bunch of, you know,
legal protections to ensure that they can't use this for evil.
Other companies absolutely can.
And I worry about this unintended consequence
of, you know, are we going to see a situation where especially
all the commercial providers and,
you know, essentially go wow. Ok. Awesome.
We can just make the security researchers go away.
-- I
-- mean, maybe there will be some of that.
So let's, let's move this conversation a little bit because I think it's,
it's just becoming depressing.
So here's a better question.
So
Apple wants to stop N Ss O group. Let's say they do.
Is it going to fundamentally
change
the
vulnerability and attack landscape? Do you think?
-- I don't think
-- so?
It's basically going to make it much harder for
this one entity to do it and maybe others,
but fundamentally
right, they
apple needs to go fix software security
and, you know,
iMessage and they need to,
you know, keep improving their face recognition.
You know, it's my understanding is, for example, is it won't work if you're asleep,
you have to move a bit, which is awesome.
You know, that fundamentally,
well, the bad, bad people are going to keep looking for flaws because, well,
there's gold in those hills.
Well, and so that's just it. Right. So if Apple delegitimize,
I guess we'll say above the board security research,
some of those people will go do other things, some of them will just go underground.
There is a huge underground market for this kind of stuff.
And
if you, I'm,
I'm not suggesting NSO group is above the board by any means in doing this.
But
even without NSO, I mean, honestly,
this more feels like retribution against NSO than anything else.
Well, I,
yeah, it's, I'm assuming it's getting
at these levels, it kind of gets into political territory and all bets are off.
-- I
-- mean, maybe, but I mean, fundamentally at the end of the day,
let's say NSO group loses, they become
neutered to the point they can't function anymore
and they cease to exist like nothing changes.
Yeah, I mean, there, there's a clear,
there's a clear demand for that product and service
and there's much less, let's say,
ethically and morally bound people who will probably,
you know, there again, there's, there's money, there's gold in those hills,
let's go mine it.
Yeah. Yeah, there's tons of money
in the zero day market. And,
I mean,
here's where I think you can start making some strange arguments,
like you could say, apple should take this money
and harden their products.
My
thing is they're already doing, like, they're already doing quite a lot of that.
II, I agree. I agree. I, I suspect they're spending
far more than many of us can even comprehend.
They have their own CPU now with, you know, built in secure enclave. Like,
yeah. Yeah.
But I,
I mean, I mean. Right. Right. They still do some silly security things.
You could argue. Like, I know icloud backups aren't encrypted very well.
And obviously
iMessage still has far too much access to the system.
Well, some of that though is there,
you know,
remember when Cal
and all the wire
essentially when VoIP started taking off and all the phone, you know,
all the, the, the wiretapping laws were like, yeah, that's cool.
But you're still going to need to be able to provide us with wiretaps.
Right.
And I remember, you know,
back in the early two thousands when this was a huge deal and it's like,
I'm sorry, but like, if you're a legitimate phone company,
you can't not do this because then the men are going to show up and then the,
and with guns were going to show up and they're
going to shut you down for breaking the law.
So, as a company you kind of have to,
you kind of have to abide by the laws of the jurisdiction you're in.
Right.
-- That's sort of how this works. The shame
-- and the Clipper chip never caught out.
Right.
Oh, I know.
Yeah.
Anyone who doesn't know what the Clifford Chip is, just go look it up.
You'll, you'll love what you find.
-- It's a sad story.
-- Well, it was born of the time,
you know, that
we're not talking about Clipper
today, maybe some day, not today.
I do.
I feel like open source is generally safe in this because I, I cannot imagine
like every time an open source project changes their license, you know,
that the world collectively goes a bit bonkers for a while.
Well, I don't think it's comparable. I think Apple is using
a very odd and unique aspect of copyright to their advantage here.
And it's,
it's almost certainly not part of the intent
of copyright to exert this kind of control.
And I think when you look at things like open source licenses,
they explicitly shed
a lot of the copyright,
I guess intent.
I, I mean, funny enough.
So Apple is abusing copyright against NSO group,
whereas I would also argue open source licenses
abuse copyright in a completely different way.
Oh, absolutely. And and that's part of the legal hack. That, that was the clever bit.
Yeah.
Right.
Right. Right. Because, I mean, generally speaking, copyright is used
to restrict,
whereas in the case of open source copyright is used to unrestrict, which is
depending on that point of view, you know, BS D versus
GP L versus,
you know,
who's the end consumer or the company? There's a lot of arguments about that, but
I just,
I do worry that this,
ok, here's a question. So
Apple continues to build better silicon and to essentially try and, you know,
secure the technical insecurity debt of the past in
all the stuff that's jammed into an iphone.
Now,
is there anything really new and novel that they could do?
I mean, they run a bug bounty, they're apparently shipping, you know,
slightly modified phones to the, to the core security researchers that they like,
that gives them sort of debug abilities to,
to really get into the guts of the phone.
Like, is there really anything more that Apple could do
or significantly different? I mean, I guess they could
massively fuzz things, but
we don't know that they're not already doing that.
No, I, I think there's definitely some more they could do here in this space if,
if you
pay
-- attention to new novel things that we haven't heard of or
-- no. No, no,
I maybe, yes, I think that that's second, that's part two. So
part one of my answer. Is that if you know where to look,
there are a lot of researchers that will say have difficulty with apple.
Apple is notoriously difficult to work with their bug bounty
from what I've gathered is not particularly well run.
They,
they definitely take security seriously,
but they take it seriously in a very apple way.
Whereas I think in the context of their product
usage and just like the universe at large,
they could stand to be a little more open and co-operative.
And I mean, that comes with a cost of course, because like I've,
I've run many public vulnerability and bug bounty things and
there can be a lot of noise.
And so my suspicion is their difficulty is to cut down on their noise.
But I think they're also cutting down on a lot of good, good work from people,
which is a bit unfortunate.
Now, from the aspect of like,
what are the novel in new technologies that could be done here.
I think
there's probably a lot of space for them to utilize some existing models,
things like, you know, segmenting all your services,
-- running everything in
-- sandboxes.
And they're starting to do that with the
iMessage blast door.
And I understand this takes time and, and they're working on it.
But I think
we're reaching a point in kind of the defender space around
our devices and our laptops and in kind of everything where
II, I don't know if I would call it, the mindset needs to shift. But like,
I think historically, we've had this view of like my device, my stuff and
it's kind of turning into this is Apple's device. I'm borrowing it from them
and I, I have to trust Apple completely
and I think there's probably some space there
to make changes and I don't know exactly what that is necessarily.
I, I don't think anyone does yet because I think we need
new ways of doing things. I mean, a technology I'd point out to look at is
a MD has this thing they call sev, it's, I think secure encrypted virtualization.
Don't, don't quote me on that. What it stands for, but
basically what it comes down to is when you carve up a machine for virtualization,
A MD has the ability to basically like inject a key into your virtualized process
that all of your ra m all of your execution. Everything is encrypted in a way
that the operator of the,
the bare metal
has no insight into what that machine is doing.
And I think
something in that space maybe might be what we have to start thinking about more
where like what the machine is doing is so cut off from everything else.
Like let's say you break into
iMessage,
that's it.
You can't do anything else because it's just completely cut off from everything.
Two comments. One, I don't need to escape iMessage to gain a lot of value.
-- No
-- I agree in that case.
Yeah.
And the other thing,
I was just thinking you're talking about mindset and I was just thinking like
there's already big chunks of my life where
that stuff is very much strongly legally mine.
But for example, all my money is just a bunch of numbers on a screen that,
you know, off of like td.com.
And
there are obviously various legal protections.
But on the, and on the flip side, of course, there are, you know,
banks doing stupid things like accidentally giving control
of accounts to Attackers and saying like,
well, too bad,
you know,
they phoned up and we were really convincing and
where we think it might have been you anyway.
So too bad unless you can prove it wasn't you,
we're not getting your money back,
you know, until the media contacts them and they're like, oh whoops,
we made a whoopsy, we'll fix that,
right? So I, I do wonder if we, because,
well, for example, money is very integral, right?
You need money to pay for stuff so that you don't die,
right? Food, shelter, things like that.
And
a smartphone is no longer a nice to have thing
like a smartphone is how you access government services.
It's, it's how I prove my COVID vaccination, right?
It's how I, well, I, and I could print it out on a piece of paper.
It's QR Code, but for example,
it's how I validate other people's vaccination records.
That's kind of a big deal nowadays.
And so a smartphone is no longer a nice to have thing. It's,
it's like wearing pants in public. It's just something we all do basically.
Right.
And I think maybe do we need to look at some legislation around sort of
consumer protection or sort of setting standards of behavior
for
not just the phone companies but the phone device makers,
you know, uh, in the eu we've already seen things like was,
I think they require five years of security updates for phones now,
-- something like that.
-- Yeah.
So maybe, maybe we need sort of that level of thinking around smartphones and
-- smartphone services.
-- I, I think
you're right. I think
I've fallen into the trap
of assuming the solution to the problem is technology,
but it's really not. I think
uh a huge part of this is regulation
and
having kind of governments and making sure that when
there are attacks happening by a foreign government against
another government that there is diplomatic
retaliation to a degree. And, and I think,
I think as tech people, we often try to default to tech, but you're right.
This is, this is probably less of a tech problem and more of a,
a
go
like, like part of its law enforcement, part of its diplomatic relations,
part of its my government, I expect my government to, to protect me.
I mean,
if, if a foreign government
like wants to break into my house and steal my stuff. I totally expect
the United States government to be, got to have my back. You know what I mean?
And, and, yeah. Yeah, I think you're right. I think,
and what's fascinating here is Apple just recently again,
like within the last two weeks,
uh
Apple's created an alert system for basically,
if the company suspects state sponsored hackers
are targeting your Apple account or devices,
you'll receive a notification by iMessage and over email.
So obviously it's like Apple doesn't do this kind
of stuff because they're trying to be extra special.
Nice for Christmas like this is a problem
that they're trying to fix. This is some hypothetical
and, and I think it's not just Apple's job. I think there's also
there's a certain amount of,
of local government
that that needs to happen here.
I think one challenge though is, is
the level of expertise needed to just understand this problem,
let alone do something constructive about it.
I
I feel like this is like a federal government type of thing.
Definitely not provincial or municipal.
Yeah, sorry, not, not local. I mean
in, in
the country where you reside.
Yeah,
pretty sure this is outside the city of Edmonton's remit.
Right. No, a absolutely. Absolutely. Alright.
Yeah.
Yeah,
it's,
I think stuff like this is inevitable though
because again the the smartphones have become like,
I I cannot imagine a modern journalist
not having and using a smartphone
and I would extend that statement to
essentially anyone.
I mean,
yeah, I agree. And I think
as a citizen of a country,
I think having the ability to
live your life in this modern age,
if you don't feel like you can trust your technology,
-- that is a problem.
-- And the technology provider.
Yeah. Right. Right.
Yeah. Yeah. Ok.
I buy it. I
buy it.
Right. Man.
I don't
-- what a boring ending like,
-- well, I mean, it's,
I think part of it is framing, the problem is, is a, is a beginning
and that's framing like what do we want?
And I want to be able to securely live my digital life and,
and I guess you know what else?
Here's, here's how we'll end it
is I think Apple using
copyright in this instance
is
just proof that the existing legal frameworks and
regulations are incapable of handling the situation.
And so Apple's trying to hack the system,
but of course we think this hack could have it will, it will have
future ramifications that we don't even understand yet.
So really the problem is just the fact that
the rules and regulations have not kept up with the technology and it's reached
a flashpoint and this is, this is the result.
Yeah.
Well, yeah,
obviously if there was a good law that covered this Apple would be using that, not,
not so copyright, it is
an old copyright
can do for us.
Alright.
What can, what can copyright do for you.
Alright. I'm calling it.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening. Go to overs
social security podcast.com.
Shout
out to use
the Pound Os S podcast hashtag
on
social
media
the
rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks
-- everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.