Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 188 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Pressers.
All right. So here's the deal. This virus can go
off and eat a big bag of,
as far as I'm concerned, we're not going to talk about it.
We're going to talk about fun things because the thing,
the world needs more than anything right now is a beacon of hope.
And so talking about
the only thing anyone's talking about right now is
stupid and it's bullshit and we're not doing it.
We're going to talk about video games instead because everyone loves video games.
-- Yeah,
-- I was quite shocked.
I was reading about this and Activision has a league that
guarantees a minimum of $50,000 salary for about 100 players.
So not only does everybody love video games but like I had known that, you know,
like I'm into Starcraft Two and when I say I'm into Starcraft two,
what I mean is I used to play it 10 years ago
and then I got old and now I'm too slow and old,
so I just watch it on youtube.
-- Starcraft
-- Two is 10 years old now.
-- More than 10.
-- Oh, my goodness. I feel I'm old
if you would have asked me how old Starcraft Two was.
I would have been like, I don't know, three or four years, maybe.
Sorry, I lied. Nine years old. It's released July 27. 2010. Yeah.
So, wait, that is 10 years old now.
Well, almost 10. Anyway, point is,
you know, point is like when I say I play Starcraft two,
what I say what I mean by that is now I watch it on youtube.
You know, I watch the professionals play like, you know,
some of these professionals over the years have
earned in the hundreds of thousands of dollars.
Some of these professional video game players do really well now and
it's, and not only that watching them play is amazing.
And the thing I always remind my Children because my kids are like, oh,
I want to be a video game player.
Sometimes
this is how this works. You have to be really good.
You have to be well above average, which is step one. That's the easy step.
Step two is you have to be willing to basically practice nonstop over
and over and over again and never get sick of doing it.
And you have to like doing it
-- and that's the hard part
-- well and not only that,
but you have to do that against several 1000
other people that are doing the exact same thing
and probably
more than you.
And this is, I mean, this is the thing I always,
when I discuss Children playing professional sports with other parents,
-- this can get, be a touchy subject,
-- peoples
-- like physical sports.
-- You know, Little Bobby is great at baseball.
He's going to play in the major league
and
it's like
little Bobby
only plays on the weekends.
If Little Bobby was going to play in the professionals,
he literally needs to do nothing but practice baseball all week long and
he doesn't do that because he's playing with my kid on the swings.
-- Most of the time
-- I remember seeing a documentary about this about like those,
those quasi,
you know, amateur pro kids.
And when I say that I'm talking about like eight and nine year olds
that, you know, they were, for example,
going to like month long baseball camps in the summer.
And they showed this one farm kid and he had like
these targets set up that were like, basically twice the size of the ball,
like a little hoop or whatever.
And he's just throwing the ball through
these like hoops thousands and thousands of times
every day.
-- Yeah, basically
-- that's what you got to do.
And it's the same deal with these video games though.
So there are obviously there's people like to stream on,
I'm gonna pick on Twitch a lot,
but I know there's other streaming platforms so feel free to like, you know,
at Kurt on Twitter or whatever about it.
I mean,
and
you, you watch some of these people on Twitter and one of the things you'll see,
they'll say, oh, I'm grinding this out
and they will literally practice one trick for eight hours.
-- And I think who can do that? I can barely play
-- one of the Starcraft. Two guys.
I, I watch sometimes I forget his name but he was like,
he essentially decided on a strategy of only making.
Oh, what the heck was it like? It was, it was two particular units. It was like
widow mines and the science research vessels or whatever they're called.
-- Now,
-- I have no idea what any of those things are.
You have like 20 or so offensive units available
to you that have different strengths and weaknesses.
And he just basically was,
his plan was to get to Grand Masters just using
two units and like one variation on a strategy.
And, and so he wasn't grinding this for like a day.
-- He was grinding this for several weeks.
-- Oh, I have no doubt. I mean, no, no.
When I say grinding, I'm not talking about people grinding like a game.
They literally grind like one section of one game to learn one trick. Oh, yeah.
Yeah, there is no
way I could do that.
I mean, if I sit down to play video games,
I can play for maybe two or three hours and then I think I got to, you know, I'm done.
I can't do this anymore and these people obviously have
the talent but also the willpower to do it.
And I mean,
I'll tie this back to security a little bit is I kind of think
about this in security sometimes too where when you have a motivated attacker,
they will do things for days or weeks or months or even years,
sometimes that we can't imagine.
And so
it's very difficult to defend against an attacker like that.
And oh, you know what a great example.
So I was watching an interview with Teller from Penn and Teller,
the magician and he was talking about the fact that one of the
greatest strengths the magician has is that
normal people don't understand the links.
They will go to, to do a trick.
Like for example, they will pull out every two of clubs from 52 decks.
So they can build a deck with only two of like
normal people can't imagine that because we would never spend,
you know, three hours.
I remember I read a book called Scarring on Cards.
And he was like the world's best car cheat from World War Two.
He talked about things like the deck of cards
that has like the diamond pattern on the front.
What is it, bicycle or whatever? I have no idea.
Anyways, you buy several dozen, maybe 100 decks of this
and then you because the cuts are slightly off. And then you basically,
because you can see the diamond pattern on the edge of it and you basically just,
you make a deck where you know the pattern on the
edge from the diamond pattern on the front of the car,
it's bananas.
-- But then you have like a perfect cheating deck.
-- But again,
this is a thing that a normal person
would never do and wouldn't ever think of it as well.
And like, yeah, video games are, are the same deal. It's, oh man, it's,
but at the same time I love watching these people. It's so much fun.
Yeah.
-- And
-- see what's interesting to me is I was like,
I've tried playing video games and I'm too old.
I don't have the time to put into it, so I just get stomped. Right.
-- Let's be, let's be charitable.
-- Don't play online if
you know what we need.
Just if anyone listening works for a game company, like you literally need like,
I have a job and family servers
well,
and let the kids play on their own place and let us old people play somewhere else,
-- you know,
-- Starcraft two, for example, does that with matchmaking, you know?
Oh my God, I'm a reasonable mid-level bronze player.
I can actually beat certain cannon Russians and stuff.
There's a lot of games where that kind of thing doesn't work,
but also no offense if you're playing with all
the people at your level it kind of sucks.
Right.
It's kind of like, have you ever seen, like, 60 year olds playing, you know,
softball?
-- It doesn't look anything like 20 year olds playing softball.
-- No.
But when I'm 60 I don't want to play softball against 20 year olds because they're,
I'm going to break a hip, man.
-- I'm 40 I'm going to break a hip.
-- Well, this brings up cheating though. Right.
Like, if I could use an aim bo
or something.
And,
and actually one thing that was raised that I
thought was actually pretty legitimate was people with vision
disabilities or other disabilities that need kind of these cheating.
Help things to actually see what's going on or to, you know,
have a little more control aiming.
Sure.
So like using an aim bot for somebody maybe who, you know,
has not as much muscle control, which opened my eyes because I, you know,
I always thought of cheaters as well like cheaters like it was bad, right?
I didn't never thought of people say with
disabilities who want to play these games and
you know, not be completely
-- stomped even worse than I am
-- for what it's worth on consoles.
They do this, they call it a
mist because obviously let's say you're playing like Doom
on a
-- Nintendo
-- switch. But is this playing against the computer or against other people?
Well, it doesn't even matter, right? So I'll give you an example.
I Doom is 25 maybe this year it's old on the Nintendo Switch, which I have.
Well, we talked about the switch,
what a couple of episodes ago because I had to replace the fan.
So Doom went on super sale and I bought the Doom One. Doom Two and do
three for like
three or $4. Right? It was like, ridiculously cheap and
I've never played Doom Three. It's a, like a modern looking game
and you can like jump for example, unlike Doom one and two.
So I thought, oh, this will be fun. I'm gonna try this.
And you can imagine playing these games on a console is
really hard because without the mouse to kind of aim,
it's very, very different
-- to aim.
-- Oh, you're playing with a console controller like the whatever. Ok.
Yeah.
Yeah. Right. Right.
So they have this thing called aim assist,
which of course I turned down and I play on easy mode and I still die a lot.
But like basically a assist means as long as the gun is pointed,
kind of in the direction of an enemy,
it will basically like lock onto them and let me actually hit them with bullets.
By the way, Doom is 27 years old. Awesome.
It's still good.
You know, in all seriousness,
I bet I still play Doom Two is the one I really like the most.
I probably beat Doom Two once a year still where I'll just, I'll,
I'll spend like a week playing it.
I'll do, like, a level a day or something
and I'll just, like, tear well more than that. But, you know,
I tear through them and,
and I love it. I still love that game so much. You have no idea.
The other thing I found that was interesting is I didn't realize how much,
just how bad the whole anti
cheating situation is.
Like, there's, there's, you know, what is it va the valve,
anti cheat system and stuff like that.
But,
and what's interesting is a lot of this seems
to boil down to like voting systems where,
you know, essentially you're playing a game, you know, like,
say two teams of five or six people or whatever
and people can basically vote that you've cheated or otherwise
mispaved because obviously if somebody cheats like a lot,
it's going to become obvious, right?
Like if they, you know, consistently doing 360 no scope head shots,
which I'm not even sure what that means, but it's a term I read, you know,
they're probably cheating,
right?
Because even the best players can't do that consistently.
It's interesting because, you know,
there's these services you can pay 10 or 20 bucks
a month and they'll keep giving you updated cheats.
And what's really fascinating is at one point the va anti cheat stuff was kind of
because it was looking at people's DNS caches.
Oh, interesting.
Now,
the reason it was looking at DNS caches is
because some of this cheating software has DRM in
it and makes a call out to the mothership server to make sure you're still paid up.
-- And so they were looking for that activity to ban people. That's
-- wild.
I mean, it's clever.
Well, you know,
we talked about this on that episode about poker machine cheating where, you know,
they run the thing on their phone but the
data gets sent back to Eastern Europe or whatever,
for the processing.
-- Yeah, that's
-- right, man, that was a long time ago. Yeah.
So, I mean, it's, it's,
it, to me that, you know, even the cheating industry is like, well,
we have to do DRM and we have to, you know,
-- maintain control of these things
-- and think about your clientele.
You're working with a person who's interested in
breaking the rules to get themselves ahead.
So, why wouldn't they just pirate your software? Right.
Why are they going to pay you for it? So, you,
without
-- DRM, it's just going to get Pirated all over the place.
-- Yeah, it's, I had no idea.
Like I knew it was a big thing in certain games,
but one thing I still don't quite understand is how in, like,
the truly competitive games
that works because in Starcraft,
the preseason people play from home and stuff on
tournaments online and then as the season progresses they,
you know,
they go places to play on computers controlled by who's providing them Right.
Sure. That makes sense.
You know, and you don't get to sort of, like, load, like,
you don't get to bring your own PC.
It's like, no, everybody's playing on the same PC connected to the same land, blah,
blah, blah.
Yeah, that makes sense. Makes it fair, makes it easier. Whatever.
And now what's interesting is, I mean, there's enough money now in video games,
for example,
there was like a Starcraft two match fixing scandal a
few years ago where a guy was throwing matches,
like intentionally losing them
to get somebody else ahead and to basically, well,
essentially the online betting places if you know how
a match is going to turn out in advance
and intentionally losing a game is, well, it's super easy. It's harder to do,
you know, like, oh, whoops, I just deleted all my units or whatever.
I dropped the mouse on the floor. I'm, I'm trying to get the mouse. I can't reach it.
Oh, I knocked it under the table some more. Whoops.
You know, like I knew video games were big business but like match fixing and then,
you know, and people getting permanent bans for
not even just match fixing.
But this one guy who apparently was like
a professional Fortnite player was banned for life by
Epic Games because Epic Games straight up says
they have a zero tolerance policy for cheaters.
You have to have that though because if
you give people an opportunity for redemption.
They're going.
I mean, my favorite example of this is Pete Rose in baseball in the United States.
So there's this guy named Pete Rose who is actually a really good
baseball player and he would be in the baseball hall of fame.
Had he not been kicked out of baseball for basically
betting on games and being accused of purposely losing games.
I thought generally speaking,
professional sports players weren't allowed to bet on
their own
league, let alone their own team games.
And he did
and baseball kicked him out and he has a lifetime ban and now people are saying, oh,
well, Pete's old and he's a good guy and we should let him back in.
But in all seriousness, if you let him back in,
people know as long as I clean up my act a little bit after
the fact I'll be good and I'll get in the hall of fame.
Like, no, you got to kick him out and you gotta stick.
It's, it's like with your kids, right?
Where if you punish them, then they're like, oh, I promise not to do it again.
You're like, oh, ok.
You can have the candy after, like, no, you stick to that and like,
you make sure they know you're serious.
It's funny because,
so this guy is 17 and on the one hand, I'm like, ah,
17 year olds are generally not the smartest people on the planet, but ok,
but while he was using this aim bot on another account of his,
he was saying people should be careful to use
aim bots because he could get your account banned.
And I'm like, well, ok, at that point, he kind of understands, but then he's like,
I didn't realize they'd banned me.
I thought it was just my account,
which obviously that's why he was playing a different account.
-- Right. Not his main,
-- listen to you using gaming terms. His main.
Yeah. Well, it's a Starcraft thing.
So I know the star Trek
lingo,
you know, I mean, in an adult, you know, in the barcodes anyways.
Well, because that also boils down to like one of my,
my famous pieces of advice I have for most people which is, you know,
if you're going to commit a felony,
don't videotape it and if you're going to videotape it don't live stream it.
-- No,
-- just don't videotape it or
don't commit
fies
also.
That works too.
Yeah, if you're going to break the rules, especially when, if you're breaking rule,
don't let live stream it and acknowledge that you're breaking the rule
and that you understand what could happen and then complain later that,
you know, I love it because there's this like video of him crying saying, oh,
I didn't understand the consequences and I'm I
I take full accountability for my actions.
And my, my one thought is like, well, yeah,
and the accountability for your actions is you, you got banned.
That's the way it has to be because you need other people have to look at that and say,
I don't want to get manned. I don't want to be crying on youtube
to get my account back. Right.
It has to happen that way. I'm ok with it. It's harsh but it's necessary.
Well,
it's interesting too because then a lot of people and I can sort of buy into this,
this idea that he's a content creator and
helps kind of push the Fortnite community forwards,
you know, by making content and getting people into Fortnite.
But fundamentally at the same time cheating, generally,
especially cheating in multiplayer games kind of really makes the game suck.
-- Of course,
-- it does, it makes everything suck. Cheating in anything makes it worse.
Like I'm ok with people cheating against
a game they're playing against the computer
actually.
Yes, that's fair and watch speed runners, speed runners cheat constantly.
And it's awesome because, but they're not, it's obviously not multiplayer games.
There's no money involved.
It's just people are trying to beat the game really, really fast.
So they do insane, ridiculous things. And it's, it's lovely.
So, yeah, it seems to sort of boil down to, you know,
as long as you don't make the rest of the world the worst place for everybody else.
Cool. Like whatever you do in the privacy of your own home, so to speak. Great.
You do that,
you know. But, yeah, if you're playing against other people and cheating.
Like, I, I remember playing games against people who are clearly cheating and,
you know, it's not fun.
-- Like, it's just not, no,
-- it's, it's not fun playing any game against any.
Well, although I, I will,
I was having this exact discussion with my Children
not probably three days ago and I will say
there were, uh, some games I would play in college. We'll say while we were at the pub
that
revolved around cheating, the point of the game was actually to cheat.
It was, you know, dice games with cups and stuff. And those are marvelous games.
When everyone is cheating, everyone knows they're cheating.
-- Well,
-- but then, but then you're not cheating, that's part of the rules.
If you're caught, you lose.
But, you know,
it was so I was,
I loved those games. They were and I didn't even care that I lost a lot.
It was just,
it was amazing to cheat and to watch other people cheat because I loved it.
-- But anyway, anyway,
-- most people are comically terrible at cheating.
Most are, some are amazing.
And I knew some people who, it was like magician level cheating,
they could pull off and it was phenomenal.
But then I, I was saying to like, one of,
one of the favorite things is me and one of my friends,
we would stand apart and put like someone between us that we say was less experienced
it was beautiful because they didn't even know what was going on most of the time
and we were obviously cheating with each other against the unknowing mark.
-- I was, like,
-- every time I see video of three card Monty and it's just like, oh,
that guy that just won money.
Like, he's part of this, you know that. Right.
-- No, no, I can do it too.
-- Yeah, you can spot the red queen.
That's right.
That's,
I
was watching a street magician one time and my kids are like, oh,
we want to go watch a street magician and I literally took my wallet
out of my pocket and just clutched it in my hand the entire time.
The guy was doing his tricks.
Yeah.
Well, we should link to if, if we can find it this, like,
he's the world's best pickpocket and you can do things like,
uh, what was it?
He did this with Penn and Teller and he, like, removed the inside of their pen.
Like he basically took the pen away from Penn and Teller at some point unscrewed.
It took the inside out,
put the pen back together and gave it and
put it back in Penn and Teller's whatever pocket.
And then he's like, ok, well, can you write that down and they're like, click, click?
What? Like, oh, he's like, do you need this? And I'm just like,
like I get lifting somebody's wallet or heck
even removing their tie that's pretty impressive.
Like,
-- but like taking the inside of their pen out,
-- it is amazing.
And you think Penn and Teller are,
-- they know the craft
-- and that story could be wrong.
Well, some of the stuff on, you know, Penn and Teller fool us like they're like, yeah,
-- you fooled us
-- and, and they know that they know the art, they know what to look for.
They look for things we don't even understand and they still get fooled. And, and
I mean,
this again comes back to the beginning where
we were talking about like a motivated attacker.
It's very difficult to defend against them because they have motivation.
-- They have time and they have no. How? Well,
-- also what's interesting for Attackers
is in general,
they get to try and try again.
Right.
You know,
there's certain types of attacks where you don't get to try repeated times, like,
say robbing a bank.
Although
there are quite a few people,
dozens of banks before they got caught.
But, you know,
but when you're online and you're coming from a non extradition
country or a country that doesn't generally extradite to the US.
Yeah. So what right. Keep trying. What are they going to do? Phone the FBI.
We
were actually,
I was talking about this with someone this
morning is robbing the bank is easy spending.
The money is the problem.
Well, a lot of these people, you know,
don't have the best spending habits and their you know?
-- Yeah,
-- they're,
they're buying things that you can buy with cash
that you probably shouldn't be consuming at all.
Right. Right.
But, no, I mean, I, I hear you because they, yeah,
there's definitely countries in the world where they're not
going to send you to the United States so
you can hack anyone in the US you want and you're never going to get in trouble.
No,
this whole video game thing.
It really had me thinking because quite frankly I've, I've decided now I'm, I'm not,
I just,
I can't play multiplayer games unless I'm allowed to
cheat because I'm just that terrible at them.
Let's play Minecraft. Minecraft is nice and easy.
Yeah, I do. Yeah. Yeah, that's true.
Yeah, because, like I see my son playing Team Fortress Two and, I mean,
admittedly he's not good at it yet, but he's actually improving.
Right. He's, you know, he's slowly getting less terrible at it.
So I will play Fortnite with my kids every now and then
I consider it a success. If I'm not one of the 1st 20 people killed,
I'm so bad at it.
And it's funny because they,
at first they were like, oh, we'll be on a team together.
-- No, they don't even suggest that anymore
-- because, and now they're like,
-- we don't even,
-- yeah,
I'm dead.
Like they don't want me.
You're the tethered goat.
But here's the thing too. Here's the way I look at this is,
there's playing a game because you're good at it.
And so like,
I will play Mario Kart online and I played a lot of
Mario Kart when I was a kid so I can win.
I would say I usually place in the top three when I do an online
race and I'm obviously up against people of relatively similar skill levels to me.
But like, I don't suck at that game, but now Fortnite, I genuinely suck at it.
But when I play it, I also have attitude of, I'm bad at this game,
but I'm doing this to spend time with my
Children doing something they like to do and like,
-- that's
-- ok.
The biggest thing I've noticed, you know,
the biggest thing I've noticed the change in games from when you and I game to now
is how rapidly the games change, right? When we bought a copy of Duke, that was it.
And then, you know, we're lucky to get new maps
and now Minecraft has a full elemental table. They have
animals and bees
and you can,
I think the bees do pollination even
like
it's crazy.
Or you look at something like Fortnite and they just introduced helicopters.
Oh, did they?
Yeah, they just introduced helicopters.
-- Oh, man,
-- they had airplanes,
airplanes were awesome in that game and then they took them away and I'm like, oh,
man, I'd love the airplane.
Well, because they were broken. But apparently helicopters, they fixed a bit.
-- So for example, guess what happens if you jump off the helicopter at
-- height,
you can pull out your parachute thing and fly around.
No, you die.
What about your parachute thing though?
Uh, I think that doesn't count later in the game.
Like, it's sort of counts as packed away or gone. I'm not sure.
I don't, I don't know how that, but I, yeah,
because you jump out of the bus anyways point is like,
they're like, this is great because, you know, you can't just use the helicopter to,
like,
just kind of, you, you actually have to use it
with a plan and some sophistication. Right. And that's cool.
I'm ok with that, you know.
But, I mean,
do you think you and I could pull that off?
We could be like Thelma and Louise you get in the helicopter,
I'll fly the helicopter and then I'll crash and kill us both.
I'm in.
That
sounds fair.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
And I think that's probably the best outcome.
See, again, if Fortnite just had a server just for like, old people who suck.
It would be way more fun, I think, than,
than running into the game and having some kid shoot
me in the head in the 1st 2.5 minutes.
And it's like, well, that sucked. I mean,
there's actually, I,
I will try to dig it up but there's an old penny arcade cartoon about this.
And it's like, you think one of the guys basically said, like,
do these kids even know how to shoot you anywhere but the head anymore?
It's
like,
it's so funny
because they're obviously making fun of the fact that,
you know, the kids are really good and now that they're getting older,
like they're getting just destroyed playing these games.
Well, that's the thing too.
Like watching, it's not just that you have to be good at playing the game,
You have to understand the strategy and the meta because the games keep changing,
right? And that's the thing, right? You and I,
you learned how to play Mario Kart Cart. I learned how to play Tetris.
That's not how like a game like Fortnite or Starcraft
works now like Starcraft two has completely different units than
it did 10 years ago.
So actually, I, I must,
I will tell you now the Nintendo switch has something called Tetris 99
which is like Tetris Battle Royale.
And I thought I was good at Tetris till I played this.
And I'm like, I am really bad at Tetris like these people are ridiculous.
Yeah, I uh the whole slamming down thing. I never got super great at like I got
rotating.
Nothing like, yeah, so there's a way to like rotate you,
you create certain structures and then you can like rotate blocks into them.
You get like extra bonus points for rotating things like it's nuts.
And I, I have no idea these people are basically,
it might as well be magic because I have no idea how it works and I
can't possibly compete with them because they're operating
on a level that I don't even comprehend
well.
But that's true of a lot of things like you look at like wood carving or painting,
right? You give me all the same, you can give me a block of wood and the same knives
and I, I am not making you a sculpture. I'm making you a best an ashtray
and it's gonna be a little lumpy.
I am completely familiar with this problem.
Yes, I, you know though, OK,
so here's the way I will describe this and I'm going to do it in the context of
video games and this is true of security is the same way or a learning any skill,
right?
Where
like when I started playing minecraft,
I basically would just mine some things that
build these crappy little structures and be like,
wow, this is neat.
And then eventually
I got sick of that
and then I would do more things and do more things and I made more
tools and I made different blocks and I eventually reached a point where like,
and I, we, I think we just talked about this. I, I like literally built a machine
that would kill and cook chickens for me automatically because
I got sick of having to go and get food.
Like
what,
what just happened there right. It's,
and it was actually I had a lever on it because it would either just the way it worked,
the way chickens work is they lay eggs in Minecraft.
And there's a one in eight chance that an egg will hatch a chicken if it,
if you throw it.
And so basically, I have a machine that the chickens lay eggs.
The eggs are re hatched into chickens.
And so it, obviously it's, it's kind of like this repeating cycle and,
but, but the way,
the way I had it set up is I could flip a switch and stop making new chickens because
sometimes I'd get too many chickens because in the
game would start to lag because it'd be like,
you know, 7000 chickens in this machine.
But it was like,
I, I keep thinking about that and it's like, what the heck, I mean, I,
but it's like any skill, right?
I made a trampoline, you know, the trampoline is, um, it's piston blocks with the,
um, the, the, the slime.
So it's bouncy and
you put trip wires over it.
So that when you cross the tripwire, the, the piston fires the block up
and then down.
And so it's like this automated trampoline, you don't have to jump, you,
you bounce on it.
Oh,
yeah. Right. Right. And this is,
this is how any skill works, right?
Like when, when my other favorite example is elastic search where
like using elastic search is really complicated.
And when I started doing it, like,
I was proud if I could just make a little graph and like, now I,
I do all these wacky crazy things in it and it's like
some, you know, new people will say, how did you do that?
It's like, I don't like, I use it every day for the last three years.
It reminds me of the UNIX
landline, right? Like I had,
um what it was, yeah,
we wanted to essentially take a PDF and get all the most common words out of it.
And I'm like, OK,
tap, tap, tap, tap, tap, tap, tap, you know, uh PDF to text bunch of stuff, count,
sort unique.
Uh Still don't have a stop word list. I need to add that in.
But I'm like, I'm like, cut and paste, I'm like, yeah, here,
here this will work on like, you know, any Mac Os Linux, whatever,
right?
But I look at it and it's like, it's like basically a pile of line noise, you know,
with like tr you know, upper, lower, you know, and,
and it's funny because I actually documented what each of these commands do.
And I'm like, well, that kind of helps. But,
you know, it's funny because I'm looking and I'm like, well,
this is really obvious what this thing does and why you would do it this way.
But yeah, obviously to a normal person, they're like, what now?
-- Like, you can convert a PDF to text.
-- No. And, and that's fair. And I guess, right.
And you know what though,
just kind of thinking about this and especially
in the context of video games and cheating
is,
I think you could view it as two paths where you could either work really, really,
really hard, like many hours a day and become really,
really good or you could be like, screw it.
I'm just going to buy this cheating equipment and
go do something else with my free time.
Well, use a framework. Use an assist. I mean, that's why people buy elastic stuff.
Right. They could write that stuff themselves or
they
just,
you know.
-- Yeah,
-- that's fair.
Yeah, that's, that's exactly true. Actually, that's a very good point.
I'm not going to write my own web browser.
You know, I had to mirror website and I'm like, scrapy.
What are the config options for scrapy? Like scrapy literally scrapes websites.
-- I'm like, man, somebody wrote this amazing tool. I've
-- never heard of
this tool.
-- It's a Python library. That's
-- fantastic. Cool.
I should look at that because any time I need to mirror something I run W
get and it's ugly.
Yeah. And WG will work just fine. It's scrapy is a little bit more modern.
But yeah,
by and large W get is what I would use if
I didn't want to look up the options for Scrapey.
Because, yeah,
like many things I've used W get long enough to know what five options I need are
WG
dash
-- R that's all you need
-- and
no parent and mirror
whatever. Yeah, that's right. Mirror is the one you need, isn't it? Right. Right.
Yep. Yeah, that's true.
So,
I guess,
oh, my goodness.
I guess it's boiling down to learning how to use your tools and,
-- and even just knowing that these tools exist, I mean,
-- yeah, that's,
that's definitely part of the game.
Absolutely.
I think one advantage of open source is at this point,
I assume every problem I have that somebody else had that problem
-- and wrote an open source tool and released it on
-- github.
Or the answer is on stack overflow.
Yeah,
-- exactly. You know, and then the trick is just finding it.
-- No, I hear you.
And I mean, this is the whole point of open source, right?
Is the fact that if you need something,
it's there and you don't have to do it because if you're,
if you're writing a library that isn't
a core part of whatever it is you're doing, you're wasting your time
pretty much.
So, yeah.
And I suppose the same thing with you want to be a professional video game player,
right?
If you want to be the best of the best and you're not just practicing all the time,
you're probably basically wasting your time.
Right.
Well, you know, like when I look at these Starcraft two players, you know,
they live in these houses in Korea, they practice, you know, 8 to 10 hours a day.
They have coaches, you know,
I've watched some of their practicing and it's like the comment,
like they're talking at such a high metal level that like the stuff I need to
learn they don't even talk about or mention because it's just so taken for granted.
Right. Like they're like, oh, yeah.
And then when you did that and they're like, oh yeah, that, yeah, with the, yeah,
on the pass and the, yeah, and then the outer range.
Yeah. Ok. So don't do that. Ok.
And then, you know, onto the main, yeah, when you did that thing. Yeah.
Oh yeah, that, no, like put the t
like over to the left there on this map
and I'm just like,
what are they talking about? Like,
I thought they played a really good game,
-- you know,
-- it, it's probably like when I watch cricket,
I have no idea what's going on in a game of cricket.
Something I still don't understand is so in cricket you can
get a really high score and then they stop playing.
They
see that's why I don't get right.
Like, yeah, I don't even understand how the,
how the fundamental most point part of the game.
Where is like, when do you stop playing happens?
Because my understanding is that they can choose to stop playing at some point.
So I don't know if somebody wants to explain cricket. To me it's been tried before.
-- It didn't stick. Obviously
-- everything I know about cricket.
-- I learned from Hitchhiker's guide to the Galaxy. That's
-- pretty much,
yeah.
Anyway. All right, man, I think,
I think we should call this one. I don't, I don't want to spend too much time.
It's, this has been lovely. I must say. Thank you.
I needed to talk about something that wasn't that terrible virus.
So this is, this has been great and kind of for everyone listening.
This is my intention. We have enough crap news right now.
We have enough to worry about. I want us to try to keep this as fun as we can.
So if nothing else, we can be a beacon of hope.
And we also have like me and Josh are not experts on any
on anything. Literally nothing,
-- especially security. No
-- good Lord. No,
I can barely mow my lawn.
That's right. That's right. Wonderful. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you
for listening. You can go to open
source security podcast.com, hit up the show notes.
I'll try to put links to all the videos and other fun things we talked about today.
You can use the Pound Os S podcast hashtag to hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks
-- everyone. Stay safe out there. Bye bye
the