Hello and welcome to episode 86 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Pressers.
How you doing?
Excellent. I had a barbecue pork bun for breakfast.
That sounds like a very healthy breakfast. Well done.
They are delicious.
So
it has been uh there's some certificate crazy going on right now, isn't there?
Yeah,
I don't even know how to start this one. It's just like what?
Well, the thing is even.
Yeah.
So well to start at the,
I guess the beginning it would be that Symantec is one of the root cas.
And um
-- ok,
-- let, let's,
let's make sure we clarify all this because
some of this can get weird and complicated.
What is a root C A? Let's, let's see.
So a root.
Ok. So a certificate authority is
somebody who has a certificate
that they effectively then used to sign other certificates
like a certificate for www.example.com
and
the root certificate,
the public key part of that thing is,
is installed in your browser or your operating system.
So your operating system basically
you either your operating system vendor or your
web browser vendor has made a choice that,
hey, we're gonna, we're gonna trust Symantec, you know, they,
they seem like trustworthy guys.
And,
and we should also mention that that most modern browsers
-- have an insane number of root C
-- A s.
It's about 200 but the effective number is actually infinite,
which is another problem.
Uh But anyway, so basically, you know, a lot and,
and the thing is what browsers tend to basically have the same set of root cas, right?
Because having a root C A in one browser,
but not in the rest of them would be painful at best.
So anyway, Symantec runs a root C A
and they were caught
multiple times on just doing things that were not correct
to put it bluntly like and,
and not correct for very extreme values of not correct so much so that Google's like,
yeah.
No,
we've, we've told you to behave, we've told you to get better and you have not
so
effectively when it comes to certificate authorities,
the ultimate penalty is, is the death penalty effectively,
which is we're removing your root certificate from our web browser,
right? Which means
that
any certificate signed by that C A
now is effectively worthless.
Well,
it's worse than worthless because it generates a gigantic
warning with huge scary red words and letters and
it's just not like
I'm sure people have seen it. Right.
It's, it's, it's the same warning you're going to get with like,
a self signed certificate.
Well, true, but not from their bank.
See, that's the problem is
the people are going to websites that they
have trusted and, well, they still trust them
and had working certificates. And now all of a sudden those certificates won't work
once it's gone, you know, through the death penalty. So, anyways,
that's the Symantec portion of this. Now, what happened is there's a British
company called Trusco
and they don't have a root certificate.
But so what they basically do is they, they get,
they generate their own certificate which is
then signed by a root certificate authority
and they use their certificate to sign other people's certificates.
And this is the problem where we have like 200 root certificates,
but effectively an infinite number of actual certificate
authorities because there's all these companies like Trusco
that
and, and we don't even have a complete list of them,
nowhere near a complete list of them,
um, that can
sign certificates for anyone and anything.
So,
Chico apparently emailed their parent in
the certificate authority world effectively saying
we want to revoke these, uh, what was it? 23,000 certificates,
right.
-- And, and what does it mean to revoke a certificate,
-- a certificate or?
Well, like any encryption key can potentially be compromised? Right.
So a hacker breaks into your web server copies the
encryption certificate and the encryption key off your server.
They can now impersonate you, right. That's real. That's kind of bad.
So we have this concept of revocation where you can essentially
revoke the certificate and basically
create, you know,
this digital message saying this certificate has been compromised,
do not trust it.
And it's, you know, it can be distributed a variety of ways
uh traditionally, because none of those ways really work.
What we've done is when a certificate
is compromised,
we all the web browser vendors update their web browser with a
built in list of revoked certificates.
Right. Right.
And,
and there is a technology called CRL which
is certificate revocation lists and it's supposed to be
automated,
but it's such a train wreck.
It's too unreliable.
Well, it's, it was also built and designed for a time when we didn't have, you know,
hundreds of millions of secure websites.
Right.
Put up long
and then there's also um,
uh OS CP uh the online certificate
status protocol totally didn't have to look that up while I was saying it.
And uh
OS C
I, I think that's O CS P. It would be, right.
O
CS P Yeah, sorry. O
certificate status protocol. O CS P.
Essentially when you go to a website with certificate,
your browser then checks the status of that certificate to
make sure it's still valid and hasn't been revoked or whatever
the problem. There's, well, there's two prompts. One,
the services running these O CS P servers are typically not reliable enough.
So they're, they're not working. So what do you do
when the service doesn't work? Do you just fail and tell the user?
Well, too bad we couldn't check. So we're not going to let you go because
that could also be an attack or intercepting and blocking it.
And, and so I remember there was one time when II,
I told my web browser if it can't contact the O CS P server to fail for me.
And I think that that lasted for 15 minutes before I ended
it
half an hour.
But
it
was very sad.
And the other problem too is with O CS P is that
you're now leaking
which websites you're going to
to a third party.
So there's some really severe
privacy concerns here. So
to put it bluntly certificate, revocation doesn't work in the traditional sense,
um you basically have to get them revoked and then, you know,
whatever happens, the the browser update, whatever,
but more to the point
to actually revoke a certificate. There's like, uh there's a list of valid reasons.
You can revoke a certificate,
you know, the, the the certificate or the key was compromised or exposed.
And you know, there's a bunch of reasons that you can validly revoke a certificate.
You can't actually just go to the, to the provider and be like,
I just want to revoke them because, right, they, they actually can't do that.
And so basically what happened is that apparently the
CEO sent an email to this company saying,
you know,
we want to revoke to their parent C A
company saying we want to revoke all these certificates.
And the response from the parent C A company was, of course, you know, well,
like we can't do that.
There's no reason to revoke these certificates, right? Like,
like whatever, you know,
so
one of the quickest ways to get a certificate revoked is to
um,
basically show that the private key has been compromised.
One of the easiest ways to show that a private key has been compromised is
to simply email a copy of it
to the guy you're talking to.
And that's what happened apparently is they sent an email with 23,000
private certificate keys.
You know what I wonder about that? Was it one email? Like that's a lot of keys.
Honestly, they're only about a K each.
So it's like a 23 meg attachment and it would probably compress pretty decently.
I don't know. That's a good question
regardless. It's
a 1020
attachment. Who cares? But basically it's, it's, it's like, uh
you know, it's like saying,
it's like showing up in the emergency room and saying I hurt,
I want to see a doctor and they're like, yeah, no, take a seat please.
And so you take out a gun and shoot yourself in the knee and they're like, ok,
now we have to deal with you.
Like that's straight up. That is the closest analogy I think
that is sadly accurate, I think.
Um
So
yeah, by emailing the keys to this guy, of course,
now they have to revoke them because,
well, yeah, they're, they're compromised for sure.
-- Um
-- And there's also another side to this story that that is
making my brain hurt is why did these guys have the keys?
-- Like I know why they did but they shouldn't.
-- Yeah.
So a lot of certificate authorities,
um
we'll have like an online tool to generate
your key and certificate because let's face it.
A lot of people can't do this reliably.
I mean, I've even had like a fellow security expert generate a new key
and they forgot that on the GP G command line when it asks for like,
how long do you want your key to last?
And like, what's the expiry on it?
It's asking for you a number and it's the number of days and he forgot
that it was the number of days and thought it was the number of years.
So he plugged in 10
sweet.
And it was like,
so like a week later, I'm like, what dude, your keys expired? What the heck?
You just made it? And he's like, whoops, yeah,
you know,
10 day key.
Um So, you know, if people get this kind of stuff wrong all the time, you know, and
it also requires you to basically have a command line on a UNIX system, which OK,
is granted.
Not so hard now because, well, if you have a Mac,
you can do it easily and actually windows now can do it easily.
But back in the day it wasn't easy. It was very much, not easy.
Um, so anyways,
so I'm assuming
that they had an online tool to generate these keys
and
kind of kept a copy of those keys floating around. Which. Right.
And, and I read this story and they, they talked about,
-- well, clearly
-- they had a copy because they emailed it to them.
Right. Right. Exactly.
And they talked about cold storage, whatever that might happen to me.
I assume that would be like an offline.
You know,
we
can stick it in a locked filing cabinet
with a sign saying jaguar,
I, I would like that to be the case.
But I, I don't know.
I mean,
it's,
the whole story is just like,
it gets worse.
But wait, there's more. Right.
Oh, yeah. Wait, it gets worse. So, the Trusco
website had like a script on it to do, um, oh,
what the heck was the purpose of the script?
It was like to check the status of certificates or something
and it just basically fed stuff to a command line, running his route.
Yeah, that was really neat. I was, I was very impressed
by the results of that one.
I'm just wondering, did they take their website down or did somebody do it for them?
Like, did somebody issue like an RM hyphen RF space slash,
I think fundamentally you could say they took it down no matter who ran the command,
right?
I mean,
I know, I literally as security people were just like,
well, well, see, you know, you know what I've been,
I've been thinking about this a lot actually.
And I feel like this is a
learning event, we'll say as the PC term for, for what's going on the website
because
can you check your certificate still
anyway?
But here's one of the things that I've been thinking about here is
I feel like this is almost certainly an example of what happens when
you put people under intense pressure
and expect them to perform.
And especially when you're talking about security
failure is pretty much the only option
because you're going to cut corners,
you're going to make mistakes and you aren't going to make good decisions.
Yeah,
see what frustrates me about this is, is there's no real way
for me as a consumer, even a very
well, somewhat mostly savvy, you know, consumer of this type of stuff
to really make a truly informed decision
because you go to the Trusco
website,
it looks legit, you know, they have a ton of customers, they have a root certificate,
like they have a signing certificate, they have,
you know, they say all the right things.
And I mean, you know,
how am I supposed to know that they have
like some script running on their website that,
like allows you to run commands as route
there. There's no way you'd know. And it wouldn't surprise me if they're not.
The only C A
that has similar,
I mean, did you
not tar? Right. They had, like,
their signing server was a machine sitting directly
connected to the internet and it got,
like, infected by viruses because it had no antivirus scanner apparently.
And what really gets me is, you know, all again, I've said this before, but like,
all these firms have been audited and supposedly checked by
large, you know, auditing firms, some of them, you know,
the big five or is it big four accounting firms?
Now? I forget.
But, you know, I looked, I was looking up some of these auditors and like,
one was literally like a dude in Texas where Google
Maps put him in the middle of a field.
That's awesome.
You know, but like, if he's certified as an auditor,
why can't it be just a single person company?
Right. That's not
inherently wrong. And potentially it could be some hardcore guy who's, like,
actually stricter than maybe these big four accounting firms.
Like, again, I don't know.
I mean, we've talked about this before is the fact that
getting an audit or a pen test or a lot of this stuff done doesn't,
doesn't prove you're secure in any way.
-- It just shows you meet a very, very low standard of security
-- worse than that
at a specific point in time.
Yes, that too, because as soon as the auditor leaves,
you can screw everything up immediately.
And,
and in fact, that was, it's funny you say that is, is
I've been at Elastic
Con this week and I was talking to some people about compliance
and they kind of said I was talking to an old friend
and this is a story from long ago where they were saying,
you know, how did somebody get compliance with this particular setup?
And I said they set it up
and they got the compliance guy in there,
they got the approval and then the second he left,
they basically, like,
updated everything and changed all the configuration files to,
to make it work the way they needed it to work.
And, and it's like, I bet that is insanely common.
Well, it's just gonna happen organically regardless.
I mean, and this is also my argument for things like continuous scanning because I,
if you have automation
and you do your kind of compliance scan with automation and then if you know,
if the auditor leaves and then they start mucking things up, the,
the automated scanner is going to see it immediately.
Well, it's just that latency loop. Right. It can't be like a yearly audit.
It has to be like a daily audit.
Right. Right. Exactly. Exactly.
So, so anyway, anyway, kind of back to certificates
because this is so exciting.
I,
I, I look at this
and the security part of me wants to yell at people
because this was clearly a bunch of poor decisions.
But then the, the, I guess people side of me
thinks
this is probably really common because this stuff is really hard to get. Right.
Well, more to the point if, if, um, if a company,
if one person got it wrong, like it
obviously is not that difficult to get wrong.
Right. I mean,
yes.
And, and I think there's also
the other side of this, that's
the world continues to turn
even though this terrible event happened. And, and I guess
I, I always think about the, like the people who built the internet,
the amount of resiliency they actually built into this thing,
which was kind of on purpose, of course, but like, it is amazing
that we can have some crazy c a incident like this and,
and it's not super noticeable by most people.
No, it's,
well, part of it is we're in the law of large numbers and this is like
a
zero point, whole bunch of zeros, 1% of the internet is affected.
Right. Right.
Well, and not only that, like getting a new certificate is not different
to do it.
Let's encrypt. Right.
Let's encrypt. Exactly, man.
-- You
-- know, like, and, and actually there's some good news,
let's encrypt now is just in the process of getting support for the
Acme V two protocol.
So the Acme protocol is essentially long story short,
that's the protocol that lets you
automated,
you know, get your certificate and prove that you have ownership of the domain
um with its
automated certificate management environment,
just like it says on the camp
and
Acme V two supports wild card certificates.
And one of the reasons that is so fundamentally amazing
is, and I'm like, II I decided to do this a long time ago because for two reasons, one,
it was cheaper and one it was, and two, it was less hassle is.
So for the cloud security lines, right?
We had a, we have a pile of websites and they're all htps enabled.
They have to be because we're in the HSTS whitelist. So
I don't have a choice like all our stuff has to be encrypted.
Um
I did that to force myself. And anyways
so at some point, you know,
you're paying 2030 50 bucks a year per certificate per site.
It actually becomes cheaper just to buy a wild card certificate
like Star dot clouds security lines.org
and just slap that on all the machines. And from a management point of view,
you don't have one certificate to manage like it's
instead of like
20 or 30 right? And for a large enterprise, oh my God.
Like how many websites do these large enterprises have?
Well, like basically an infinite number.
It, it's huge. And
so, so this is something what, what people are going to say?
And I've had discussions like this is using one wild card
certificate is more dangerous than having one certificate for every.
Ok.
So there's that old timey security,
sort of least privileged compartmentalization argument.
Right.
So, like, yeah, if one server gets popped, blah, blah, blah, you know what,
who cares?
You just revoke and get new certs,
you're gonna have to do it anyways if it's one cert or a wild card, cert.
Well, and I guess my argument here is that
it's quite likely if you lose one cert,
you're probably going to lose them all
because there's probably some sort of systemic problem in your organization.
And so pretending you can protect 70 certs instead of one
I think is, is misguided thinking
and not only that you end up in a situation where
the,
the feeding care of 70 certificates has a
significantly higher burden of work than one office.
365. Remember they had that outage on a leap year day
because their certificates expired after 365 days.
Like most people have certificates that,
you know, you typically choose a one year term, which always drove me nuts.
I always wanted to pick like a year plus about two weeks. So that I had a,
you know,
because what I found is
I would buy like a one year
certificate, but then I'd renew it after like 11.5 months because,
you know, if something went wrong, I didn't want to get caught
with the site down basically.
And so I just,
instead of doing my certificate renewals at the same kind of time every year,
it just, it, every year it crept back like, two weeks,
you know, and you do that for six or seven years and it's like all of a sudden, you know,
you're like,
two months back and it's like you're doing
certificate renewals in the middle of summer now.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Well, and, and, and that's great.
I mean, that's a, that's a perfect example of doing something, you know,
changing things up in such a way that, that it forces you to make better decisions.
Right.
So,
yeah. Yeah.
So, so tell, let's, let's talk about,
let's encrypt for a minute because I know we've covered it on the show in the past,
but I think the way they work is super clever
and I love them.
So let's just why, why don't, why don't you give like the two minute rundown of,
of how let's encrypt works and, and why it's better?
Well, at least why we think it's better than the existing C A model.
Yeah, let's encrypt is essentially uh there, there are two sort of main
policy planks if you will
are frees
and automation
which dovetail quite nicely.
Um So obviously the nice thing is they give out certificates for free.
That's a, that's a very low cost point. I like free
uh big fan of free
um,
and with free, obviously you have to, as the C A,
you have to be very efficient.
Right.
Um, I know for a fact a lot of cas,
you still have humans in the loop if you
buy a certificate with the word security in it,
because I've run into that and had to wait a week for my certificate when
it was supposed.
Yes,
exactly. So, uh, the first, when we first signed up with cloud flare,
uh
you know,
Clower said automated certificate, blah, blah, blah, it should take minutes.
And, you know, I did my personal website and yeah, like took like 5, 10 minutes,
no biggie
and then I sign up the cloud security lines and
nope,
no certificate for me. Um And I emailed them like, what, what the hell you
and yeah,
because it's got like a keyword in the domain that it has to be reviewed by a human.
And it's like, well, this is awesome because I did this Friday evening.
So, you know, people don't work until Monday
in most of the world.
So essentially
they're 100% automated
as far as I know, right? Like I, and, and they would have to be,
and they use the ACME protocol,
the automated certificate management environment protocol,
which is basically a fancy way of saying you,
you have a script on your public facing web server.
Uh And that's another thing uh is lets
and crypt only works for public facing web servers
because those are the only ones they can automated the verify.
So you put this script on your web server. Uh Say, for example, www.c.org,
you run the script, you tell it your host name
and it basically does two things.
One, it creates the certificate, you know,
creates the keys and the request and all that
and sends it off to let's encrypt
and
then let's encrypt replies with OK,
go do this thing for me to prove that you own the domain.
Typically,
the, the most common ways are either
uh put like a text file on your web
server that has a specific name or specific contents
or uh set up a DNS record like some random, you know, string.c.org
and oh,
and then the classic third way of course is we're going to
email one of these well known email addresses at your domain like,
you know, what is it like host master
or admin or root
at c.org? And
you know, if they reply. Cool.
Um So they, they do just, you know the online methods, not the email one. I believe
you get the request saying go do this, the script goes and does that and
you know, like literally a minute or two later you have your certificate.
Um
And
well,
it's also worth noting that they hand
out certificates that have very short lifetimes.
Yes, I was just gonna say that I, I believe they're three months
uh roughly
I wanna say three months.
Right. Right. It's about 90 days, I think.
And, and that's a really good thing though. And I think it, it,
because
this is one of the, so, like we'll use the example where we've been talking about is
if you have certificates with a year or more of lifetime and they are compromised,
it's potential.
Now, the,
or the potential exists that you have certificates that
could be in the wild for years that have,
that are in the hands of, of nefarious actors.
Yeah, and I would say even more realistically and importantly,
operationally,
if you do something once every year or two years or three years,
chances are you might forget to do it.
But if you do something quarterly, you're just going to do it quarterly.
I don't do anything for let's encrypt. I have
automated on
my website.
I mean, that's kind of the point is that by, you know, making it run quarterly,
people run that script and, you know, have it in a Cron job or whatever.
So it just automatically,
you know, what's really cool.
Let's encrypt does also is if your certificate is
going to expire and you haven't updated it,
they will email you
because I like when I was figuring it all out,
I set up a test machine just so I didn't like hose anything real.
And yeah, like when my, when my test certificate expired,
it, it sent me an email that was like, hey, man, like,
see all the CAS do that because they want you to buy more certificates from them.
Like,
I'm getting
emails.
There's a whole bunch of certificates I bought years ago
are expiring and I haven't used them in years because,
well, cloud Flare and Amazon do free certificates now
and, and it's just, it's interesting reading between the lines.
Like, I think they're,
yeah, they're, they're definitely losing market share to the free stuff.
Um because
it's not just cloud,
for example, Amazon web services now has certificate manager.
And so
you basically typically when you're using Amazon web services, you,
you have some domain names kind of registered with it for
various things like say S MS like the simple mail service or
uh for elastic load balance or whatever stuff like that, right?
And effectively
you register your domains with certificate manager.
Uh It does the uh I think I opted for the classic, you know,
we send you an email with a link method
to host master route or whatever at your domain dot You know.
And um so now my
like my domains are registered with certificate manager and it's like, ok, what,
what certificate do you want?
And I just opt for a wild card because it's similar
and the nice thing is not only do they
reissue certificates on uh I believe it's 90 days roughly
they also revalidated you and poke you to make sure kind
of like you still control that domain name or whatever.
Right. Because
with a, with a party like Amazon, right, you could potentially
like sell the domain
to somebody and, you know, and then still be generating certificates for it.
-- Um, so they still. Right.
-- Right. Or, or I think it's more likely that people
stand up some infrastructure and then forget about it or stop caring.
And so it's in their best interest to make sure
this stuff kind of expires out instead of running.
So to put it bluntly, you know, Amazon web services
will now give me certificates for free.
Uh, Cloud flare will give me certificates for effectively free.
I mean, my personal bill with cloud flare is
up to a whopping $25 a month now.
Oh, man, cash or money.
I know. I know.
I know.
-- But
-- which actually funny you say that because the last time
I paid money for a certificate I paid more than $25.
It was like 70 bucks.
I paid quite a bit more than that because I needed a wild card certificate
and it was like 300 bucks.
Sure. Sure.
Which I guess is funny too because, because your traditional cas would charge me
for certain kinds of certificates when the reality is from their side.
It's all the same. Right. It's fundamentally the same.
Well,
yes and no, in, in theory,
and here's a classic one, there's,
there's multiple levels of validation for a certificate.
Nobody cares. Nobody knows. Right.
There's domain validated,
there's extended validation and there's a third one
that I can't even be bothered to remember.
-- And,
-- and we should. So, so the
EV is the big one that's when you go to certain websites and it's, it's green.
It used to be green. I don't know if it still is to, to kind of specify.
We did extra work to validate this website and you
get it with like Google and ebay and some banks and
well, they, they put the corporate name,
the officially registered corporate name,
which for example, for paypal works great because you go to paypal.com
and it says paypal
comma inc,
you know, bracket us.
Cool. But you go to some websites and like the, the incorporated name is like
nothing to do with the proper, like the website
domain name,
right? And I've literally ended up with some of them like, well,
it's probably legit like I just whatever.
Well, like, ok, if I click on paypal E
US
um,
certificate valid. Yeah.
And it, it's issued by Symantec class three V SSL cag three expires Wednesday,
October 30th 2019.
Uh, this certificate is valid details.
Uh, and then it gives me
a bunch of information about paypal.
Like I, I guess it's their corporate address in San Jose. I don't really know,
you know what this reminds me of.
Do you remember the XK CD comic where it says like how to verify GP G signatures,
like scroll to the bottom and look for this thing here
like
that.
I mean,
to
the point like all of this information in the subject name. So
us Delaware, private organization, serial number country,
you know, like street address, organization, organizational unit as CD N support.
Like that's all public record stuff.
Yeah, but nobody checks it. I mean,
right. Nothing. There's nothing you can do with it.
I mean, we just have to trust our web browsers to,
and, and again, I guess this comes back to the, the,
the message I keep beating like a dead horse is,
people are never the answer to these sort of problems.
Like expecting people to look at certificates and,
and make sure it's the right certificate is insane.
But making sure your web browser is doing the right thing is a totally, like Walmart
dot com and
amazon.com don't use extended validation
and those websites handle
a ridiculous amount of money.
Right. Right. And
I have a suspicion
-- they don't see the value in doing it.
-- I had to check.
I didn't even know if it had it or not.
No, I get it, man. I, I totally get it. It's,
I, I guess if the moral of the story here is probably
let's encrypt. Right? Just, just use it.
Yeah.
Just well and, and you are going to need to do everything
via htps pretty soon now. Uh, there's some major changes coming up so,
on April 30th of 2018
Google,
uh the Chrome web browser will,
if you, if it sees a certificate
and that certificate doesn't exist in the the certificate
transparency logs in at least two of them,
it will basically put up an error page.
Uh And what the transparency logs are is basically this goes back to kind
of the whole thing like with semantic behaving badly and issuing bad certificates.
So what Google and the rest of these browsers
want is essentially when AC A issues a certificate,
they have to then
uh not just send it to the person using it,
but they have to give that public certificate
to a certificate log.
It's essentially a public record, like, think of a,
like a corporate registry effectively, right?
And that way other people, security companies,
security researchers can look at these logs of like,
here's all the certificates being issued
and they can look for wonky and bad ones and alert people to it or, you know,
a large company
can look for their own name because for example, like there's the classic, you know,
like
walmart.com dot something, something, something dot something, right?
Or, or not even that, I mean,
how many instances in the past have there
been where people would manage to get a certificate
for like something.google.com from some random C A because
AC A didn't have proper checking built in.
Right.
Yeah. And so that's, that's one of the first big changes coming up this year.
Then there's another major change um that doesn't affect certificates so much.
But on
June 30th of 2018,
the PC I DS S standard and this has been pushed back a few times. Uh
will finally be deprecating TLS 1.0 and earlier, which means TLS 1.0 and all SSL
will be deprecated
uh with exceptions for things that aren't
web browsers like point of sale terminals,
obviously, because we're not like those things are never getting upgraded,
especially in the US
with your, what is it chip and signature?
Um
Yeah, and then
in July of 2018,
Google Chrome will start. So it used to be that when you go to HTTP.
Well, currently when you go to HTPS, you get a nice green secure with a lock and
the website
and when you go to HTTP, you just see whatever website, no biggie
that's gonna flip when you go to an HTTP website after July of 2018.
So what is it build? 68 of Chrome?
You, it's gonna label it insecure
in capital letters.
Yep. Yep.
And we, we did a whole show on this a couple episodes ago which is, yeah, it's,
I'm so excited.
I can't wait.
-- Oh,
-- it's gonna be awesome.
And so to put it bluntly,
um
everybody
who doesn't want to have to deal with grumpy users who are going like,
why is your website insecure?
You're probably gonna, well, I would suggest looking at let's encrypt and,
or if you really want to spend the money for some reason
going and buying certificates from, uh, uh,
a trustworthy certificate authority and what that
actually means and who those are.
I have no idea. No. Straight up. Like I'm not even going to pretend at this point.
Right.
II, I agree with you 100% is, is I think,
saying trustworthy certificate authority is quickly becoming an oxymoron.
Yeah. Well, and, and let's encrypt is a great example of one that isn't
necessarily trustworthy because they'll hand out
a certificate to anybody for anything.
Right.
And so, you know,
spammers and bad guys are getting certificates from let's encrypt.
And it's like, well, yeah, but that's
the
point of certificates was not to like, oh, only the good guys get them.
It was to simply, you know,
attach this domain name and this website are actually who they
claim to be and your communications with them are safe.
Right? And my view has always been, it's really about
cutting out everyone in the middle because now when I communicate to your website
and it's encrypted with http si have a certain amount of,
I guess,
expectation that nobody between me and you
can view any of that traffic. Right.
Well, or you know, replace the ads,
which is one of the main reasons Google is pushing all this
is
a
lot of I SPS globally are now,
you know, replacing ads because that's a revenue stream and it's incredibly, uh,
I'm not sure it's legal per se
because I'm pretty sure there were things about mucking
with other people's website content that make it somewhat,
not legal but who am I?
Um, and so more to the point, you know,
Google's interests in protecting their ad revenue very nicely
mesh pretty much 100% with my interest in,
you know, having the secure web and not having people snoop on what I'm looking at.
Yeah, totally, man. I, I agree 100%. So I guess let's, uh, let's bring it home.
What are, what are our final thoughts here?
Uh, well, go to let and crypt.org, uh, is it.org? I think it's dot org
and, um, you know,
just type, let's encrypt into your favorite search engine
and click the first link
pretty much. But don't go to like, let's
encrypt.something.ru. Don't go there.
Yeah.
Right. Yes. That's right. Let's encrypt.ru
to
lett
dot org and, you know, start using it.
Uh, and if you have internal sites that need certificates then, um, well,
you're gonna have to go deal with that by probably
standing up your own internal C A certificate of authority,
-- which
-- that's a much longer conversation than I want to have today.
Actually, the good news is IP A on Red Hat,
Linux and a bunch of others now actually works quite well in IP A
lets you stand up a nice light certificate of authority that works quite well.
That's right. That's right.
And, and that's, again, don't try to run your own certificate,
find
a
child
and use that because you will, you will screw it up. I guarantee you. I
like just, you know,
here's a bunch of recipes for using the openness as all command line to stand up.
C A just
I, I've done
it
and I, I definitely made a mess of it.
Of course you did.
It's super hard to get, right. So, anyway, all right, sweet, thanks, man.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
You can hit up open source security podcast.com for show notes
and,
and links to various social media things and you can use the
Pound Os S podcast hashtag to get our attention and yeah,
nothing else.
Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks.