What the way you're supposed to use?
Narrow press is brew your coffee at about 80 degrees.
Ok. That means I need the digital thermometer. I can't judge what 80 degrees is.
-- My kettle can be set to 80 degrees. Yeah,
-- I use a microwave.
-- I'm going
-- to leave that into the cold open because anyone
from the UK who just heard you say that died inside.
Oh, yeah, I know.
Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself.
Kurt Siefried who is essentially I'm a borderline
maniac when it comes to heating water for coffee
and my partner in the podcast who apparently heats water the proper way.
Josh Pressers.
I don't even know what to say to that like,
-- yeah, I know right.
-- The proper way.
But I'm too lazy to get a good kettle and I only want one cup of coffee.
So I only need 100 and 50 mils of hot water.
Look, you are a Costco fanatic.
I want you to go to Costco and buy the electric kettle that they sell there.
It's quite affordable,
but this way is faster because microwaving hot water is
the objectively fastest way to get the hot water.
I, anyway, we have two topics today.
I'm just going to move us right along because, like,
I
don't know what to say.
It's gonna be a bit of a rehash because we
just argued about this and Josh agreed with me.
It was, it was. But I don't want,
so it's a sovereign tech fund. We talked to
Piano crack
burger. Um, it's been, what, like, 456 episodes. maybe it's been a while.
I don't remember how long
-- that
-- two
-- month break I took.
-- That's true. There was that, that feels anyway.
Yeah.
-- But things are better now.
-- She sent us a link literally hours ago.
I master it on saying, oh, hey, take a look at this idea. We have and I am
smitten with it.
Well, especially because that idea has funding.
Like it's not just we had an idea.
No, it's, we had an idea and moved it through a process to actually get it funding.
Like this is not some random idea, not just funding like real funding,
funding that they're gonna give to people
-- that is like a whole other step of,
-- I just wanna,
I wanna cover this very briefly and, and once it
has more meat on the bones, we'll say in the future,
we'll talk about it more carefully and we can
probably just get Fiona to come talk to us,
which is better than us making crap up
once they actually have some experience in data. Yeah.
Right. Right.
Exactly.
Like
uh God bless the Germans.
So anyway, it,
it's called the contributing contribute back
challenge is what they're calling it.
I'll put a link in the show notes and
basically they've created these kind of three challenges.
The first one is improve uh developer, tooling,
securing software production
and infrastructure documentation. And basically
they, they've got all the details and I'm not gonna read them because I,
I don't think they're particularly important to the
aspect of this Kurt and I were discussing.
But basically, if you look down way at the bottom,
they basically say that the minimum amount
you're going to get is €65,000 for, it's like a, I think a three or six month effort
-- and the max is 300 €1000.
-- That's for round one.
There's also round two with, again the same thing.
-- So this is like real money.
-- Well, that's just it.
And that's the thing I thought when I saw this is
when you look at a lot of these open source funding proposals,
it's like we will give you $75 to write the Linux kernel in rust.
-- And it's like, wait, what
-- like
or fix this bug or
like we would like a feature added where,
you know, we can just import data from any source and
there's $100 bug bounty on it.
If, if, if my company did this,
it would cost $7 million but we're offering $75 and a gift card and it's like, wait,
what
-- I
-- mean? Or better yet, we'll give you recognition
-- because you can totally pay your rent with recognition.
-- That's right.
Exposure is the most valuable currency of all.
How do you think I pay the mortgage here?
I use podcast recognition to pay my mortgage.
You don't, have you been paying your mortgage with money?
-- Well, that's just silly. I know
-- what's wrong with me, right.
But, but look, this is the way right?
If we want people to work on this stuff and to make measurable, good progress,
you have to let them live their lives.
It's kind of like I know the Maslow hierarchy of needs has been debunked many,
-- many times, but it's kind of the concept of um
-- well, but
kind of can't live without food and, and that's just it like,
I don't mean to be argumentative, but
you can debunk them as little hierarchy of needs all you want. But like
if I put you in a box with no water
for a week, that's not gonna end well
-- for
-- you.
I'm not going to be fixing very much open
and I'll have a box to get rid of this heavy
if anybody wants a mystery box.
But anyways, but
so here's what's fascinating to me is I personally think that they are
solving the wrong problems, but
this is the correct way to do it because this is where we are.
And what I mean by that is
they are essentially like improve fast developer tooling.
And in my mind, it's more,
I think we need to take a step back and maybe look at sort
of the workflows and actually like what does the tooling need to do?
Because we sort of have this implicit assumption that like right code, check code in
C I CD pipeline
code slash binary pops out the other end
and I guess at a high level that's reasonably correct because what else would we do?
The challenge is we've had so much
new technology and new understandings of how to better build software.
You know, like we've literally in the last 20 years gone from
object oriented programming being like, oh,
that's kind of weird and strange to like
Python and stuff is the default now for a lot of people.
No one does object oriented programming. Kurt, we program with objects.
It's a long complicated technical
differentiation.
The point I'm trying to make is we've gone well, like, OK, 30 years ago,
we were happy to write assembler.
Now, we have Rust and Python
and web frameworks and
services.
And so I,
what's interesting to me though is when you look at
the workflow of most software that hasn't changed at all,
like the Linux kernel is a great example.
-- It, they literally a bunch of mailing list with patches flying around.
-- I
agree with that statement at
all.
Well, and I'm not saying that this is necessarily wrong. I'm saying we don't know.
And what I'm trying to say is we've had 20 or 30 years of progress in the technology,
maybe we need to look at.
So for example, car manufacturing,
car manufacturing has changed enormously over the
last 2030 years because of new technologies,
right?
-- Robots, Kurt,
-- the way we build software has changed drastically,
-- this has been turned into a shaggy dog story at a high level
-- write code,
check code in code passes, smoke, test
code C I CD code binary goes out the other end.
And the one thing that has significantly changed is
instead of code now people are writing service.
But
if you let me put it this way,
if you showed a colonel developer from 30 years ago what they're doing today,
you'd be like, yeah, that makes sense.
-- That's what we do.
-- Maybe, maybe here's, here's how I want to address that very long
rambling rant. It doesn't matter
that there are fundamental underlying
problems that aren't technically being addressed
by this because I think we can't address them right now.
We can't.
And we also end up in this situation on a regular basis
where we say
that doesn't solve whatever problem we think there really is underneath.
And in the case of open source, open source is a million different things.
It's not one thing we love to say, it's one thing but it's not, it's a million things.
Probably more than a million.
But the point is
you have to do something and you have to start somewhere.
And I think that's my biggest, I,
I guess compliment I can give to the Sovereign Tech Fund
is they're doing work. They're not just talking about work.
They have real money to do real work and some of it
won't be correct and they're going to learn lessons as they go.
And that is the key.
Whereas I've seen many groups that will spend months or years talking about
what correct is and I'll make air quotes when I say correct.
And then they don't actually do anything at the end.
And then,
like, why did you just spend a year talking about this? And
then
-- I,
-- because it's easy to talk about stuff and have meetings,
-- it's hard to build stuff,
-- it's hard to take action.
And actually I'm gonna, I, I
need to correct you.
There's something subtle. You said that's very wrong.
You said they are doing the work. No, it's better than that.
They are letting, they are actually funding other people to do the work.
And that is even more valuable because you get that,
that diversity and that just like,
-- well to put it simply from, I don't
-- want, I don't wanna say that
I think they're funding other people to do a lot of cool work.
But the things the Sovereign Tech Fund had to do to get this to happen.
I,
-- I can only imagine the mountains that have been moved.
-- Oh, the paperwork alone.
I,
I know what it's like working with government.
And this is incredible to me that they not just had their first
round of funding but now they're doing more stuff and it's like,
holy cow.
This is
amazing.
Anyway, I don't, I don't wanna,
-- I don't wanna dwell on this one too much and I also don't want,
-- well, just a quick note,
the first application deadline is July 6th.
So if you're interested in this, get moving,
that's true because this, this I'll, I'll make sure this episode goes out.
Uh What July June
7th 18, something like that.
I
forget
what, I don't know, I don't know how to add
but
yes, you will have some time. So by all means like go look at this. It's amazing.
So we have one other thing we want to talk about that.
That was the actual topic we were going to
discuss today because it amuses me to no end.
And then the Sovereign Tech Fund snuck in so well done Sovereign Tech Fund.
But there is a story.
Kurt sent me from the BBC that was titled
Why Millions of usable hard drives are being destroyed.
And I saw the title
and II, I immediately knew what was going to be inside of this story
and it did not disappoint.
And then I told Kurt, I said, didn't we talk about this watch
and I can't, I can't find the, what did you do? Did you just snap?
-- I just destroyed an M two SSD.
-- No, you didn't,
you broke
it in half. You made it so your computer can't read it.
-- The data is still on those chips.
-- Well, not,
did you crack the chip in half or did you only crack the PC B?
-- The chip
-- is cracked. The chip is, here's the other one
because I just upgraded the drives in my computer and the other computer.
-- Did you wipe it before you cracked it in half?
-- That's encrypted.
There we go.
That's an important point. And we'll get to that in a little bit. So
this is the demo you warned me of with you packing in SSDI, I,
I'll go take a hammer to it later.
So, here's the thing. Why do people throw out
quote
unquote perfectly good storage media,
like M two drives or hard drives instead of like resell
them?
And, well, a couple of things, there's actually, uh,
we'll put in the show notes but L tt just bought an old, what was it called?
Store. Uh, I forget the vendor of the
San
Ar.
Yeah.
Anyways. And they're like, it's like a 57 terabyte array which is essentially
two modern hard drives. Well, three if you want some redundancy.
Um,
and so here's the problem, right? If you want to sell used storage.
Well, number one,
you have to wipe it and especially wiping hard drives takes forever.
Not, not just that you can't wipe S sds
and that's I, yeah, that, that was gonna be my second finger point.
Yeah, you can't reliably wipe an SSD because of trim and stuff.
The next thing I would point out
by definition when storage is so old that a company is actually getting rid of it.
It's basically e waste.
Like it's 600 gigabyte hard drives in 2023.
Right?
Like that
angle. Yes.
And there's also the angle of these M two drives.
Well, I'm getting rid of them because one is at 80% and the other one is at,
at 87% health like they're dying.
I don't want to give that to somebody.
Uh Sure,
you know,
like I'm not like what,
I'm gonna sell a basically dying M two drive that will definitely K
out at some point in the near future for like 10 bucks.
And I'm gonna deal with kgg or Craigslist for 10 bucks.
No, I'm gonna smash it with a hammer and throw it in the garbage.
And then, and which kind of leads to my, one of my points is gonna be, is, for example,
uh, in most of North America and I think Western Europe probably too,
like you can't legally resell a car seat.
And
why is that?
Because helmets too
general
and stuff?
Yeah.
Uh,
why? Well, because it might have been in a crash and it might not be fit for purpose.
And you don't know, you can't.
Now with granted, with a hard drive and an M two drive,
like these M two drives very clearly.
Like I ran crystal disc and it was like, it's
80% health. And I'm like, 00, and the best part is on my son's machine.
The other machine,
it was at 87% health. I'm like, oh, that's not bad.
And then I tried to clone it to the new drive and
it failed and told me to run check disk and I'm like,
uh
NTFS needs check disk. I thought it was robust.
So I ran check disk rebooted. It took like almost an hour,
fixed a bunch of stuff, cloned it over
and like, I'm not,
I'm not giving somebody this drive.
I don't care if you run it in a ray to ray with a ton of redundancy.
Like it's, it's a half terabyte.
It's clearly unreliable.
And like, what I'm gonna put like
half an hour of effort into selling something worth 10 bucks,
right?
This is a
lot.
That's,
that's
by definition when this stuff is old enough to be sold off. It's,
-- it's basically e waste it.
-- It probably is. Now, let's, let's back this up.
And, and the,
I guess fundamental underlying point of this story
was around risk
where you've got, for example, let's say you're uh a data center,
you've got a ton of hard drives
and when it's time to yank the drives and replace them,
it's less about
kind of e waste or recycling things or, or whatever.
And it's really about you have customers who put data on those drives
and
generally speaking, as part of the,
like a sock two audit or, or any sort of compliance effort,
there's going to be data destruction requirements
and the easiest way to meet those requirements with something like a hard
drive is to just say we shred the drive when they're done.
Like we, when I say shred, I mean, literally like crushing the drives into dust,
well, not dust, like we'll say sharp pieces that you wouldn't want to eat.
And then of course, everybody's like, oh, but the data didn't.
So you could actually pull data off of it now. And it's like, yeah,
you could
know what
going
to that
point.
There's people who say things like, oh, you need to wipe a hard drive three times
or
you know, you, if you crush the platter, you could still get to off it.
I spent an enormous amount of time. Quit breaking that thing. Like put that down.
I feel like you're a child,
but Kurt's playing with the, the M two drive. Have you met me?
You're going to get like lead poisoning or something from that thing,
like quit playing with it.
-- No,
-- these are lead free now.
-- The solder they got the little,
-- there's, isn't there Arsenic and chips, whatever.
-- Anyway. Well,
-- I'm not licking it.
You're gonna touch your, your, I'm gonna, no. Anyway,
after the show,
we're like Children here.
But so, so I spent a ton of time looking for examples of like,
like academic papers saying like we took a hard drive, we
did a thing to it and then we extracted data off of
it using an electron microscope or whatever people are saying about.
I could find literally nothing. So I have a strong suspicion, you probably can't.
Well, and more to the point, it wouldn't matter because
everybody does
data encryption at rest,
like in
the
like
should be.
Well, do you think Amazon is not just encrypting all the discs anyway,
anybody competent is doing encryption at rest full stop at the OS base level
because,
well, it's just
the alternative is you don't.
And then if a hard drive ever does go missing or
doesn't get shredded or somehow goes walk about or oh,
remember that case where they,
they found the missing hard drive by a photocopier
at like uh Lawrence Livermore laboratories or something.
Remember they had that picture Kerle?
Well, here's the thing when that hard drive goes missing.
And I can say with 100% certainty it was encrypted at rest.
Everyone was like, oh, yeah, OK. Then
versus if I can't say it's encrypted there, now we have a problem.
Well, and look, this is a defense in depth measure where you're saying
they're encrypted
and they're crushed.
So if someone says, can you prove they were all crushed and you say,
I can't prove this truckload was all crushed with the beyond certainty or whatever.
But you can say, but
all of the hard drives were encrypted and the keys live
in this HSM over here and the keys were wiped.
So there's no keys anyone can get.
So even if they have the drive, there's nothing they can do.
And so this again comes back to the, why don't you just wipe it?
Why don't you just resell it like they're encrypted. Why do we care?
And it's because
there's inevitably going to be errors where something doesn't get crushed where
something doesn't get encrypted right where
there's something in the process fails.
And when you are a company like Amazon,
a one in a billion failure rate is going to be unacceptable to your Giants customers.
It's like every Tuesday. Well, and here's the other problem,
old hard drives,
use a lot of electricity. This isn't a car, this isn't something that is so
energy intensive to build,
but it is in almost every sense,
cheaper to run the car until it dies and then get a new one versus replacing it
old hard drives by and large,
especially in data centers because you don't just have to feed electricity,
you now have to feed electricity to a cooling system.
So it doesn't melt.
So basically for every watt in
you're gonna have to spend at least half a watt getting the heat out.
Probably.
Right. Plus it sits in a system.
So, but basically for like enterprise drives,
like these 15 K drives from about a decade ago, they average about 8 to 10 watts
power used. That's a lot compared to modern M two stuff, for example.
Well, and, and not just that, like, there's still hard drive,
like spinning disks in use today,
but I'm sure if you take the watt per gigabyte or whatever their rating is
that
it's one of those situations where
like keeping this old gear in service,
it's almost certainly worse for the environment than just buying new gear.
And it feels wrong to say that. But I have a strong suspicion. It's true.
-- No,
-- it's not a strong suspicion. It's so L tt spent $1000 on that
giant
San Array myth and it had 57 terabytes of data
storage. Basically
that is two
modern enterprise S
sds.
And so you'd want to buy a third one to raid five that sucker.
Sure.
The amount of electricity,
those three drives in a small server will use compared
to that half of a rack worth of gear.
-- That
-- thing's got to be like thousands of watts.
So it's gonna,
the RO I on replacing it just on electricity usage and cooling alone,
it'll pay for itself in
like a month or two.
And
uh so for example, the, the M two, drives.
I just, I got some western digital black ones for the computer.
They're rated at 1.2 million read
ops and 1.2 million. Right. Iops. No, that's it. Like they're, they're both over,
um,
they're over a million. Iops.
And what is a, what is an enterprise, hard drive from 10 years ago? Iops.
Well, in the hundreds to thousands
is it? I don't, I don't even know.
I have no idea.
-- So
-- the point is basically
there, there's just, there's no ex there's like,
literally you're gonna get pennies on the dollar for selling it.
Ok. Cost recovery, whatever pennies on the dollar.
But more to the point,
anybody buying it is insane. I mean,
well, it's probably security researchers looking for data. They can expunge.
Oh, here we go. A SAS 15 K drive.
Iops four kilobytes
block random, 100 and 88 to 203 typical
-- 50 to 60 megabytes per second data transfer.
-- What,
-- what kind of crap is this? This is. How old is that? This
-- is 10 years old.
Ok.
I'll buy that.
And that's what we're talking about, right.
We're not talking about modern,
like we're not selling off modern gear at pennies on the dollar.
We're selling off
-- 10 year old gear on pennies on the dollar.
-- All right. All right.
I'm tired of talking this soccer, but
I want to ask the question of you of why can't I
successfully erase
a SSD drive because I don't think this is always understood.
Oh God. Well, basically this goes back to the health of the drives.
Why is the drive saying 80% health? What does that mean?
I know this, I actually just watched a video about this.
So you and I were talking about it and unexpectedly,
a video about this appeared in my youtube feed, who know how
they're listening. So basically
the majority of flash drive technologies,
the cells wear out. It's just that simple.
Now, there are some technologies that don't wear out and they are
horrifically expensive,
but that's for an enterprise user and that's their problem, not ours.
And when I say wear out like both of these M two drives were
running in my son's system and my system for over three years nonstop.
And actually my system
has heavy IO workload because I do a lot of get stuff and a lot of multimedia.
And anyways, the point is I used the
snot out of this thing for over three years and it got down to 80 80% health.
And what that means is essentially
a
good chunk of the cells have literally just worn out and stopped working now.
-- No,
-- not a good chunk. OK.
-- OK.
-- Well, not a good chunk. But yeah.
So part of the beauty is
they anticipated this when they ship me my drive.
So my one terabyte drive
is actually a little bit more than one terabyte it's got basically a
tire of cells.
And so they,
it's,
well, uh, basically when a cell wears out and dies and stops responding,
they're like, yeah, that's normal.
That's ok. Go get a fresh one from the back.
Uh,
ok. Well, it's even more, it, it's even weirder than that.
Ok. So let's start at, at, let's start at, at, at magnetic media right
back in the day when Kurt and I were, but we lads
they
everything was magnetic media, right?
You had floppy disk,
you have hard drives and it's literally a spinning thing like a circle
-- like a record for anyone who knows. Oh,
-- well, actually my trash 80 had a set, right?
But sure, let's get all fancy with these hard
-- drives.
-- That's
true. You have tapes anyway, let's, let's just talk about round things, right?
Like for vinyls. Cool. So I can talk about records, right?
You got a big round thing spins around
and you have a magnetic head
that
reads
FM sound off of this media literally and then converts it into digital data, right?
Yeah.
And so what happens is,
you know where the head is? You can control what it's doing. And now
there would be times that a part of the disc would go bad, right?
And then the sector is marked bad,
-- a bad
-- block or sector, sorry sector.
-- Right. Right. Well, and there's blocks as
-- well.
-- Blocks or file system sectors are
-- no, there's,
there's bad blocks like that's the thing too.
There's sectors, like there
are parts of sectors I think, I don't remember.
It's, it's, it doesn't matter who cares. And so
-- now Kurt's going
-- to win. This is why we just
-- everything at rest now
-- basically.
-- But anyway,
-- oh, blocks are part of a sector.
OK? Sectors are made up of blocks. OK?
That, that sounds right.
And then a cluster is a bunch of blocks.
Sorry. A sector is like a pie shaped piece.
So a sector is like the pie shaped piece. The block is the actual like bit of the pie.
A cylinder is the circle. So like where the cylinder and sector intersect.
That's a block.
OK. Anyway, all right. I don't want to dwell on this. It doesn't matter.
It's not important. Anyway, so you,
you've got magnetic media, portions of magnet, magnetic media can go bad.
They're marked bad by file systems and other things underneath
and then you just don't use them, right? No big deal.
Then when it comes,
it's time to wipe the drive because you want to clean out all the data.
You can basically just say all right head, I want you to start on the edge
and I don't care what happens. Just like write zeros,
don't ask questions,
write zeros. Now, I want you to write the number seven over. You know what I mean?
And you could just totally control the head much like you
could control like a a record player's arm and needle and,
and stuff or like, put it wherever you want and make it do stuff.
Right. No big deal. So, wiping hard drives was really easy to do.
But then
flash media came about
and flash is special because it doesn't have to, like, read sequentially.
You don't know exactly what's going on. And so they built
these S sds
to hide all of the complexity of what's happening on the flash layer from us.
-- So we think it's a hard drive, but it's magic storage underneath.
-- Right?
Well, it's even more subtle than that is
20 years ago.
We didn't have massively powerful controller chips,
your hard drive and floppy drive.
Like, well, if you go back 30 years,
floppy drives were basically dumb and like the CPU literally had to drive
the arm back and forth and like you could overdrive it and break it
with.
And obviously over 20 years,
we've had a little bit of advancement in chip manufacturing and,
you know, design
drive is a computer now.
Well, and, and that's, and that's exactly it. So it's now cheaper,
you know,
to just
make a thing that has its own little computer in it so that it,
it basically presents an interface that says like you want data from X, here you go.
And it takes care of everything in the background.
And that's the other aspect of what happened is, is essentially a,
a very thick layer of abstraction was added
that you cannot penetrate. And that's
-- why you can't wipe a drive.
-- Well, you can,
you can, you can penetrate it, but it's really hard to do.
But, and that's the point when Kurt was saying there's like the,
his one terabyte drive is probably actually 1.2 terabytes.
And when it says it's 80% degraded, it means 80% of the unused 0.2 terabytes
has been
used
because he's burning out cells. Now.
It, it also you have to remember you, you don't, they don't just swap out the,
the magic extra cells.
You can move data all around. You can say like,
well and that's trim right to
do. Wear leveling.
Yeah, exactly because you can, you don't want to write to one specific spot.
And so they try to spread all this out to
maximize the amount of time this stuff can be used
with potholes
with heavy
traffic.
-- You did
-- get it
in. Oh
I,
I'll
let that one go.
But it's
true
-- like the wear leveling vastly increases the life of the drive because of
-- that.
If we say try to shred it and
SSD, we'll say all right, drive start at sector zero.
And I want you to write all zeros. It's gonna be like, wow, we sure are writing a lot.
Let's start moving this around.
And so you might think you might end up writing zeros to like basically
the same place on desk over and over again because it's probably like,
oh, more zeros.
I've got some zeros over here we could just reuse
and so
you can't wipe this stuff. And so if someone can, like,
take the magic software
and say,
like, SSD, I want you to show me what's actually written and,
and here's the craziest part.
You just physically extract the chip. Put it in a thing of a jigger. That's true.
I, there's videos of people doing that. It's, it's amazing.
-- Yeah.
-- And they're, I'm not gonna say they're, they're not cheap
-- but they're not expensive anymore.
-- It's pretty cheap to do this.
You
and I,
if we wanted to,
it's like without taking out a second loan,
-- it's
-- not,
it doesn't cost as much as a house. Right.
It's there,
there are probably hundreds to thousands of
dollars depending upon what you're doing.
But yes, very, very affordable.
You know, here's, here's the trickiest part though. So
when you have a, whatever they call the, I forget what they call.
The, the little grouping of bits on the SSD.
Is it a cluster?
It has a weird name. I forget it off the top of my head.
But what happens is like when it goes bad, it gets marked as read only
because you just can't write to it.
And so you can't,
you can't get rid of the data,
there's gonna be data on there and I'm sure there's some bizarre super low
level command. You could issue the controller that's like mess this up.
But fundamentally,
you've got data written
and that data is still there, right? Like hidden in these read only blocks.
The thing is my understanding is that the cells can
also wear out in a way where they are physically incapable
of being written to
like so it's there's no amount of low
level commands that are going to let you overcome the physics of the
properties of the material
being like, sorry, I can't do that.
And I,
I just keep coming back to the point of by the time
like this is a half terabyte drive that's basically wearing out.
It's not reliable. It's also slow.
Like, holy cow,
I swapped out because basically I bought like a one Terabyte Kingston,
like the cheapest kind of one terabyte drive I could buy four years ago
because I was like,
I'm gonna upgrade this right away and then
COVID hit and all the prices went bazonkers
and now they're back and now they
are really
cheap right
now. Like my computer boots in about half the time it used to. It is just
my
ops on this Western digital drive. Are that?
Oh, my favorite part was when I was cloning the drives,
the drives were reading at like 98% of their capacity.
So they were just going flat out
and it was writing to the Western digital drives at between five and 7%.
Yes, I, I had the same experience because I went from like an,
an SSD with, uh,
was it, uh, uh,
what is the, the drive cable? That's the
SAS
SA A
to PC invme?
Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah, that's what I did and I saw the same thing.
Oh, fun fact.
Um, I was, this also needs to be destroyed.
Um, yeah, good luck with that.
I'm gonna open up the case and
no one knows what this is. It's a,
it's a one terabyte, Western digital blue Sata SD.
And it's horrifically slow by modern standards.
Well, it's faster in a spinning disk,
which, I mean, and hard drives are faster than clay tablets.
-- Right.
-- Right. No, I know. I know.
I just, as much as I would love for there to, like, not be e waste.
I, I would also love for their, like,
like locally we have as part of our recycle program.
We have composting.
So, like, you have a,
you have a big green bin that you put all your yard clippings and food waste in and they
have a giant facility where they compost it. Which fun fact,
they built the roof wrong. They didn't account for the amount of humidity.
So it, like,
rotted out and almost broke. And I'm like,
the, my first thought of a composting facility is like, wow,
that's gonna be humid in there.
I, I
mean,
I can forgive that. I would not think of the humidity right away,
-- but
-- this is a $50 million facility,
I would think for $50 million someone would have asked that question,
especially in our environment with winter
anyway.
But the point is like, yes,
I would love to live in a world with basically as little to no food waste as possible,
as little to no e waste as possible.
But the, the thing is like
the,
the amount of time and effort somebody will spend driving
to my house to pick up a half terabyte SSD
is going to do more environmental damage than like reusing this thing.
Stop and like 10 year old hard drives just no, like they're, they're too slow,
they use too much electricity
and you can replace them with like two or three M two drives
that will be literally on the order of 100 to 1000 times more performant
use literally 100 to 1000 times less electricity.
Yeah,
I it's offensive and I hate to throw this stuff out that works like it works.
But yeah, I'm sorry. No, it's time to let go.
I mean, that's fair.
And so I think there's definitely the risk angle here and
then there's also just like the environmental impact and I think that's
-- just economically, it's not viable.
-- That's kind of the takeaway
is, is, it's not, it really isn't millions of usable hard drives.
It's
a lot of,
-- it's
-- millions,
it's millions of instances of like, I have 100 hard drives.
Like if it was a million hard drives that were all the exact same size and model. Yeah.
Chuck them in a
ra,
well, no, don't because they still, like, maybe, maybe chuck them in a radar
and use it to heat a pool. But no, don't do that.
But literally, that's the other thing is it's not a million homogenous,
working hard drives.
It's a million hard drives of, like,
-- well, some of these are about to die. We don't know which ones though.
-- That's right.
That's right.
And I can't wait for someone in the UK to pass
a law saying you can't throw away hard drives or something.
And then you'll just have warehouses and warehouses full of old hard drives.
No one can use
-- apart as maybe heaters. No, I guess you could use them
-- as
they're not use
for anything.
Nothing don't use old hard drives. Like, just, no, no, no, no, you can't do it.
-- I think I'll, I'll give you the last word on this one.
-- Kurt.
I would love to see a lot of people apply to that Sovereign tech Fund program
and I get that, it's kind of a big lift for a lot. Like it is a, it's
the, they're not doing small amounts of money, which was one complaint I saw online,
but the reality is kind of like the hard drives. They can't do 1000 projects.
That's right. That's right.
And maybe that's part of the thing to learn here. Is
we live in a very heterogeneous world and it's messy
and there are
no good overall solutions
-- for many problems. It's, it's complicated but we're
-- gonna learn.
It's ok. It's ok. It's not perfect. That, that's how I'm gonna end
it all.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you for listening. Go to
Security, podcast.com. Head up the show.
Not two
pound
says podcast hat
tag. Hit us up on social media. Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You
-- too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.