Hello and welcome to episode 59 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
-- What's new Kurt? Not a lot. It's been a quiet week. It has
-- been a really quiet week.
I was thinking that too.
There, there's not a ton of news which, which actually makes me happy
because as,
as you brilliantly suggested is this gives us an opportunity to
kind of talk about an idea instead of necessarily current events.
So
thanks to, thanks to Kurt, everybody we are going to spend,
I guess,
as much time as we can bear
talking about VPN S, which is actually a really interesting and fun topic.
Yeah. Yeah. No, it's, I mean,
well, for a whole pile of reasons, you know, people might want to have
a VPN either the traditional corporate, you know,
where they dial into their home network or their corporate network
or,
I mean,
or you dial into your home network so you can, like, check on the cat or whatever.
I basically do the same thing
in my house.
Right.
It's an easy way to get in
and of course, you know, for people surfing the web, they might want to, um,
not necessarily hide what they mean,
but at least, you know, not have it logged at their ISP or, you know?
Well, and there's a lot of countries now and I used to, well,
we would have joked about these countries but now they countries like the UK,
you know, where the stuff is logged.
Um, I believe they have to hold it for, like, 12 months or something ridiculous.
Why is it that long? That's crazy.
Yeah.
Well, I remember when it came out, there was a real concern about like,
seriously how much is this data storage going to cost?
Because
uh
yeah,
so anyway, so there's a whole bunch of good reasons for VPN S.
Um
And we're gonna discuss basically some of the technology behind VPN S and what you
might want to look for and then I think we'll kind of briefly go over
VPN services uh that are kind of more for home users.
You know, obviously, if you're running a corporate mothership, there's like,
really like what four or five major choices of VPN provider like Cisco and
I'm sure there's others
and you just go buy one of them,
right?
Yeah, nobody, nobody really sets this stuff up.
Um
But yeah, so, so speaking about VPN S and the sort of the technology behind it and, um
I mean, obviously one of the first big things,
uh but behind a virtual private network is,
you probably want to actually be private.
I suppose that's a reasonable assumption.
Yeah. I mean, but there are VPN technologies still out there and use that are, like,
really easily cracked or hacked, you know, ones that use like
really weak encryption, like, say DES or three des.
Yeah. Yeah. No, there are plenty. Well, not only that, I think
this is where I like to think about
Tor as well,
is Tor
is meant to be a very private system.
And, and the reality is that
if you're trying to escape the eyes of, let's say a nation state,
you're not going to do it with Tor
because these are adversaries that have the ability to
watch most of the traffic going in and coming out
and you can actually discern a lot of really
interesting data just by paying attention to what is coming
-- in and what is going out
-- or you simply run
an exit node block all the encrypted outgoing connections.
So like, you know, port 443 from secure web and stuff,
uh you know, only allow like port 8025 that kind of stuff and then just
uh well, log all the traffic,
you know, it literally can be that simple. I remember. I don't, I don't think
that is quite as effective now because there's, you know, a lot of,
a lot more websites are using HTTP S now.
Well, well, even with http si mean, if you're visiting,
you know, like, like buy guns
online.com, which they're gonna know
it, it's pretty obvious what you're doing. Right.
-- And, and
-- there's, there's been, uh,
studies and work done on actually analyzing the HTTP s like just the traffic flows
to see,
you can tell basically which web pages they're specifically visiting at
certain websites based on their sizes and their responses and,
you know, the calls to other domains, the calls to other,
you know, web,
um,
-- resources and whatnot.
-- Right.
Yeah, it's crazy, man. So, so anyway, we, uh we, we won't spend a ton of time on Tor
because
it's sort of a VPN. It's sort of not and it does some other stuff.
But, but anyway, on to the VPN.
Yeah.
So I guess, well, I mean, that would be one of the biggest things is, first of all,
you want to make sure it's using
a VPN technology that doesn't suck.
Like PPTP point to point tunneling protocol, which is the old windows based stuff.
I hope nobody uses it anymore.
Well, it comes by default in windows on both the server kind of side and client side.
So
I'm guessing a lot of people still use it because, you know, it's,
it's free and it's just built in and set up is pretty simple.
Uh But yeah, it's completely just broken.
-- There's no nice way to put it.
-- Right.
So, so let me ask you this, what is, what is your VPN client? Of choice.
Uh I typically, if it's a Linux
machine or UNIX
machine, I use open VPN.
-- Open VPN is pretty solid man. I like
-- it
well and it comes by default.
It does, it generally works, it supports modern protocols.
It's nice
and the majority of the VPN providers provide open VPN. Config
Yes.
In fact, all of the ones I have used in recent years, I have Open VPN has been
my client of choice,
which is, which is nice.
And in fact, my, my router,
I have an ASIS router. I think, I don't even remember now.
But it uh yeah, it, it, it,
it has a, a
button I can press to enable an open VPN server or I can set it up.
So my router becomes an open VPN client and VPN S me somewhere else,
which is really cool actually.
Well,
because then you can shove all your devices through easily and not have to set it up.
I mean, because quite honestly, you know, just even just
uh typing stuff into your phone, right?
I mean, I know you can import the config but yeah,
it's just sometimes it's easier to like
force the whole network through a VPN.
And I did that. Actually, I took a Hutu Nano. I think it is
and I put uh what is it open?
W
not open
RT
D
RT.
No, no, not that one.
Something on it,
maybe, maybe tomato. Um Anyway, I I forget off the top of my head.
But I, I basically put Linux on the thing.
I installed O
VPN
and it has a little switch on it and the switch is meant to be
used for when, when you have the, the
factory firmware to switch between wireless mode and the wired mode
and I, I set the switch up. So when I flip the switch, it turns the VPN on.
So that way I can like, turn it off.
Obviously, no VPN connect to the hotel wifi or whatever,
flip the switch and all of a sudden, pow, everything connected
to the, the hoochie Nano is now VPN, which is awesome.
Well,
that's a great example because my kids aren't kind of really using the internet yet.
You know,
they have ipads and they're locked down and they can basically
use like kids youtube and some apps and games and stuff.
But once they sort of start,
like, once they start surfing the web, for example, or, you know,
uh,
sending and receiving email, you know,
chances are I'm going to put them on their own wireless network
forced over a VPN so that if they do dumb crap,
it doesn't come back to me because, you know, kids are idiots and like,
that's not
a bad idea actually.
Well, I mean, I, I don't think they're stupid enough to, for example,
send in a bomb threat to their school, but kids do stuff like that.
You know,
um, or they get malware.
Right. Because they'll click anything.
Well, well, malware is going to happen with if you have a VPN or not. Right.
But at least this way it's like, away from all my stuff.
Yeah. All right. Anyway, let's do this.
You, you have a link to a site here. It's called VPN report.org.
We'll put it in the show notes
and it lists some, uh, important, nice to have and forbidden options.
I think it would be amusing. Yeah. Yeah. Let's, let's go through it.
Well, let's start with the forbidden because there's only two of them.
So PPTP based clearly. Yeah, if you, if you do a search for that in the CV database,
um, just know
like the protocol is broken, it's not the implement, well,
the implementations are also broken in some cases,
but
the protocol itself is just horrendously broken. And, um,
-- yeah, you just don't use it.
-- It's easy
to hack.
Right.
Yes.
Yeah.
And, and they also list data throttling is forbidden. But I,
I don't know, I, I can sort of like, you don't want somebody, you know,
paying $10 a month to a VPN provider and then
using like 10 gigabits per second of traffic consistently,
it would
probably
be a
situation, I think.
Right.
So, but, uh,
I mean, in general,
I wouldn't want to deal with a VPN
that does data throttling unless I'm being like abusive
and, and I mean, the reality is,
most of these VPN providers nowadays are 10 bucks a month or less.
-- I don't even know what I pay. It's not a lot though. I think
-- mine is eight or nine,
something like that.
Look into this at some point. I mean,
I just, just pay the bill every year and I don't, I don't think about it. So,
yeah.
And then, so the important things, uh,
the first one they list is DN le protection
and that's actually really critical because for example,
uh
you know, you're surfing the web, you make a link, uh you make a um
uh a request for a web page on Wikipedia talking about, say fascism or whatever.
Uh you know, you don't want your browser making DNS lookups outside of the VPN,
like not over the VPN but to the public.
And this is
a huge problem because what happens in many instances
and this is actually a huge problem with Tor
as well
is
you might have a secure link
to wherever you're going.
But your
computer is still set up to resolve to say your I SPS DNS servers.
So it'll basically send out your DNS traffic over the VPN
to the I SPS DNS.
And so now in their logs, they basically have your exit node
-- as well as what you're doing, right?
-- Like,
like I said back to the web pages based on DNS queries in the order of them. You can,
you can really quite easily tell what, uh, what web pages people are looking at.
Um,
and, and so one of the things I do with this is I have, um,
a system that's on a VPN
and it's firewalled so it can only talk to the VPN server
and that's it.
-- And
-- that's the right way to do it because not only that,
the thing that always scares me is how many times have you been doing something?
And the VPN drops
and obviously just given the way TCP works,
it naturally keeps going
and it's just not using the VPN anymore. Right?
And it's like, oh, crap, what have I done?
So, and then sort of the second one they talk about is the same thing IP address,
leak protection.
So,
um again, you know, if you're, well, if your computer is on the, the quote unquote,
like, you know,
real internet with like a real IP and you're
not behind like a net network address translation machine,
you know, you,
you could potentially leak your real IP address, which would be bad because, well,
yeah, then they know exactly who you are.
-- Uh And so again, what I do with my machines ideally is uh well,
-- but even,
even when you're inside of a net, this can be an issue.
And so the, the what what happens here is
you might connect somewhere through the VPN
and then you might say,
visit a malicious website that then has your web browser for example,
start like pinging internal hosts or non IP S for example, right?
And,
and in fact, this was there was an attack some years ago using javascript.
You
could,
you could essentially, right, like like scan a network
using javascript, like over the VPN,
essentially because it was still allowing internal access.
And so really the right way to do this is to make sure that once you connect to the VPN,
you cannot connect to any local hosts inside of
your network for the duration of that session.
Yeah.
-- Well, basically, depending on what you're doing.
-- Well. Right.
Yeah, I mean, we're, we're putting the tinfoil hat on here, right?
Like not that I take mine off. But
yeah.
Right. Right.
How they get you?
-- That's
-- right.
Every time I shower, man, like I, I know they're there.
Yeah.
So, and then the next one is the web RT C league product. And again, that's the same.
Like here's the horrible reality web browsers have
gone from being web browsers to being essentially application
operating systems, man. Come
on.
Yeah.
And so there's all sorts of things like web
sockets and just there's a whole plethora of technologies that
essentially your browser
can do all sorts of cool, crazy things,
but
maybe somebody doesn't know what web RT C is
and, and we should explain it.
-- So
-- web RT C is
the real
time
-- communication
-- stuff. Yeah. Here we go,
real time communication.
And I mean,
I
-- think we used to call it Ajax back in our Yeah,
-- basically.
Like, so the idea is that so javascript, not java, but javascript,
uh which has,
if I remember. Right. Nothing in common at all,
at
all.
Yeah. I, I've never understood that, but regardless.
Um Yeah, so, I mean, you can build really cool apps in
javascript.
-- I mean, well, like Google Docs is a great example,
-- like the whole internet now, man,
I mean, everything is all that like real time.
A magic things to websites, click things,
type things and it's not like the good old days where you
were like literally visiting a new page every time you did something.
Yeah. And so, I mean, you know, there's a million ways for this stuff to leak.
Um So, you know, ideally you want the client.
So ideally what happens is these clients are kind of smart
enough or configured to kind of prevent that leakage of traffic.
-- Um Right.
-- Well, then web RT C has the extra special bonus of
it.
You can do clever things with it when using the word clever
loosely where it can discover things that maybe shouldn't be able to.
But I think the other trick
that you need to be careful for is when you're using a VPN
is if you do some things
and then you connect to the VPN,
you've already left like a footprint in your web browser.
Uh
If we can find that link eff fingerprint,
browser fingerprint, I think it was.
And it's just things like based on your screen
size and your offering system and your plugins.
Exactly. Uh, pen
to click. We'll put a link in the show notes.
Um, but, yeah, like here we go. Test me. I am leaking.
I'm gonna guess probably about 20 bits of information
uh We'll see in one second. Oh, wow. It's taking a while.
They gotta,
they gotta test it all man.
Yeah. Well, and,
and there's also all sorts of new tracking
technologies like using the html canvas or using
um you can use HSTS headers. So the, the whole security transport security headers
because basically you can set these headers on a browser. And then the next time
if you want to test
you, you have them, you know, make a connection to this website and you'll see
uh
like basically you tell them to make a connection to port 80 on the website.
And if they've already got the HSTS header, they'll, they won't,
they'll just go straight to port 443.
And so you could quite easily just set a
unique serial number for like every web request with,
you know, a unique host name
and fingerprint.
Like, well, every single request to your website,
you can send out a fingerprint to that web client.
-- So
-- I, I think the lesson here is that you probably need a dedicated VM or something
you
need
something
you
do
like
proper tinfoil
hat. VPN.
Right.
Yeah. And so, yeah, I mean, there's, uh, there's a million ways for this to go wrong.
Um,
then they mentioned speed. Obviously you want speed, right? You don't want a VPN.
That's like
-- 10-K per second.
-- That's like the whole point, right?
Some things are ok.
You know, some applications that run in the background,
downloading stuff or whatever, right?
Doesn't have to be super fast,
but speed is always better than not speed.
You need it fast.
And, and one thing to remember too, again, back to the fingerprinting,
if you're up against a nation state, right?
They can just simply throttle your network traffic and look at other things.
You know,
that's true. It's, you're not going to escape a nation state.
I mean, let's just, let's just start there if that's your threat model like
this is the wrong podcast for you.
Yeah. You know what I mean?
And then they talk about using open VPN or uh IV two I PE
based. So internet key exchange version two or, you know IP security based.
I would generally agree.
There's, there's a bunch of other VPN technologies or implementations.
Ok? No, I'm gonna say that open VPN is basically the only reasonable decision.
Ike and IP SEC are a freaking nightmare to deal with.
Yeah.
Well, I mean, you really have to be, well, you have
your provider better send you a config
-- file. That's all I'm gonna say.
-- It's it's even worse than that, man.
It's just, it's such a nightmare to deal with them.
-- It don't, don't,
-- please.
I know I
was
supposed to make this easier, but I don't think it has.
I
PV six has its own set of problems.
Anyway.
Don't
they talk
about
no logging or tracking? Which is sort of self evident. Right.
You don't ideally want a VPN that logs or track stuff because, you know,
10 years from now those records could be
requested. And
well,
even though not even 10 years from now, didn't one of the,
the VPN S just get in trouble for selling user data to an advertiser.
That's awesome.
I, I gotta monetize those, uh, things
cost recovery.
Uh, the next criteria they put,
I'm not so sure it's three plus simultaneous devices,
I guess. I mean, if you have a mobile phone, a laptop and your tablet,
maybe I, I only have a service that allows one which is fine for my purposes.
I assume I get it for cheaper. I mean, whatever that's up to each person.
If, if you've got a lot of VPN
to do good for you.
Well, I think part of it is, I mean, here's the reality
operation security. So
OPSEC,
the real problem with
OPSEC is you basically have to do it right all the time everywhere.
End of story.
Yes,
that really, that's the problem with security in general, right?
Is, is the good guys need to get it right,
100% of the time and the bad guys only need to get it right once.
So the odds are not in our favor.
And then the next two things they list,
I would have just assumed for any company they say honest billing practices
and honest marketing and actually the honest marketing I get because
it was actually funny, there's this one VPN,
actually a VPN rating site that keeps spamming me asking
me to put a link on my website to that.
So I'm not even going to give them
uh
you could get some free VPN service here, man.
No, because they are a VPN rating site.
-- Just a
-- rating.
So terrible.
Yeah. So anyways and like,
I think they also have a service because they were talking about how they use like,
oh no, sorry, this was the, the, the VPN service we'll discuss next.
But they, they keep talking about how they use cutting edge crypto and it's like a
-- and all the other normal everybody else uses it
-- like military grade.
It's like we make our sandwiches with bread
-- like, yes,
-- that's tell me
you had me at bread.
-- We cut our bread
-- gone.
We use sliced bread.
I, I prefer potato bread myself but
it's fair
but still a bread.
It is.
Yes.
And what's interesting is the nice to have category they have on this rating site.
I would actually say this first one
outside of the US.
And UK servers is actually pretty damn important because
-- it
-- was the number one criteria for me.
I'm not gonna lie.
Now, the downside is I struggle to watch Netflix
VPN,
but definitely
they mentioned a free trial. Um,
sure
we can't, you can't just skip over outside of us and UK like that. Come on.
-- It's,
-- I mean, it's so, you know, it is really quite tragic. I mean, that we've,
what used to be these jurisdictions where, you know,
we made jokes about other countries lacking the freedoms that we have.
You know, now when you actually read the laws, like the UK Rip Act or,
uh, well, like us national security letters and they're like, oh, but it's ok, like
a judge resides over these and approves or disapproves them and it's like, well,
how many has the judge disapproved?
And it was like, three
or something?
You know, like, it, it basically never happened.
Here's the thing and, and let's not get, we won't get too much into the politics of it,
but
kind of the entire purpose of having a VPN service is
that you're not going to be tracked.
And, and even when, even though, like, let's face it,
I'm not doing anything even remotely illegal in my VPN.
It's just, I, when I'm on the road
and I'm connected to airport wi fi,
I'm turning on the VPN. Right. And in all seriousness,
that is what I use my VPN.
The
number
one reason Google's pushing HTTP S everywhere. It's,
it's
revenue.
Exactly.
Well, and so here's the thing,
my VPN gets used when I'm at the gym because
their networks screwed up and I can't connect to Google.
I
was,
I'm afraid to tell them what they've done wrong for fear.
They'll accuse me of hacking them.
So, I just, I just VPN, I'm like, whatever the song.
Right. I don't want to get involved
and then I also use it at the airport and that's literally all I use a VPN service for
and, but at the same time, like,
I'm not comfortable
using a service that can be easily subpoenaed by their, that's
fundamentally a technology like a VPN.
It's not completely hack proof.
Like if a nation state attacker wants to, they can put enough effort into
manipulating your traffic flows and monitoring everywhere to see, you know,
where you're going and what you're doing.
But it does significantly raise the bar.
And another thing to significantly raise the
bar is to involve other jurisdictions.
Like if they have to go to Sweden to get a subpoena,
that's a lot more work than like getting a federal judge in,
you know, Delaware or whatever
to sign off on something.
Well, well, right. And kind of my view of it is I would rather support
a VPN in one of these,
we'll say friendly countries in that
respect versus necessarily supporting an organization,
you know, in, in the US or the UK where I know that
they have to legally do certain things and I'm, I'm not bashing these VPN providers.
Like they, they certainly have purpose and, and they're good at what they do and,
yeah, go ahead. Get, get a US service.
If you're gonna, you know, be surfing from Starbucks or whatever.
That, that's totally up to you.
But from my perspective I just see value in making sure my money
is going to one of these other companies because I'm sure they,
they probably need it.
Yeah.
Well, I mean, the good news is now is if you look at the actual cost
of either colo a physical server or even VPs hosting,
it is crazy cheap. It's really cheap. I know.
And that's the thing about a VPN server too is like, it basically uses like,
almost,
no. Well, in theory, it really shouldn't be using any hard drive at all.
Just the operating system.
They should have disabled logging.
I've heard stories of VPN providers where their VPN hosts or their end points,
I guess,
literally don't have hard drives
where they use like a CD ROM.
That way, there's literally, there just is,
there's nowhere to store data even if the machines get hacked into.
And, uh, and I mean, bandwidth has gotten pretty cheap.
Like you go to some of these companies now and like a gigabit per second,
sustained traffic is like
tens of dollars.
And here's the other thing is in many instances.
Yeah, you can just go to, you know,
essentially a network provider and you can buy a port.
It's not like where you and I are buying, you know, maybe certain,
how many gigabytes in a month or whatever, up and down.
Like, no, no, you just, you buy a port and you can do whatever you want with it then.
Yeah, I remember looking, even back in the day, like years ago,
I think it was Hurricane Electric was what, 5000 bucks for a gigabit.
-- But I mean, this is like a decade ago now. It's no doubt, much
-- more
like two packs of gum and a sticker.
Yeah.
Right. No, it's, it's super cheap, man. It's crazy.
In fact, that's one of the things I think about all the time is
I don't need it,
but I'm like I could, I should host my Amazon data in, in Europe because I can,
you know,
that way if something happens in the United States.
-- No,
-- I mean, in both places, right?
That way, just,
just in case like for whatever reason society crumbles in the US then, then I,
you can easily just migrate to Europe and recover my data.
Right.
I'm pretty sure if you can't get your data in the US,
that Europe is probably not going to be taking a whole.
-- Yeah,
-- that's,
that's assuming I can get there.
Uh And that's, that's basically my assumption.
Uh Yeah, I could, I, I wonder if anyone's done that. Probably,
I believe the shortest,
I know the record for the shortest boat to make the Atlantic Crossing is, uh,
I think it's 4 ft or slightly less.
What? That's,
yeah,
some guy tried to set the record in a 3 ft boat and he had to turn around pretty quick
that it's
basically like a little,
like, think of a dishwasher with like a 3 ft
mast
-- on it.
-- Like, what is a 3 ft boat? I don't even know if I could kneel in a 3 ft boat.
Well, no, he had like the special bubble canopy so he could, like,
crouch in it basically
in
a
barrel at that point. Right.
She's getting a wooden barrel with a paddle
and that's what you're dealing with there.
Oh, my
goodness. People are crazy.
Well, you know, you got to set those, setting records is hard nowadays,
the
ones have been set.
-- No,
-- I know, I think about that sometimes is, is you think about, I remember like,
back in when I was a kid,
there were all these world records and things
and it was always a huge deal to see who is
going to break the next world record for whatever thing.
And now it's like, yeah, there's,
-- now you're basically gonna die if you try to break a record. Yeah. Right.
-- Right.
Don't, don't, don't do that
anyway. Anyway.
So next on the nice to have list is anonymous payment, which definitely,
if you are doing things that you're worried about getting in trouble about,
I mean, let's face it. Right.
One of the biggest things to deal with crime that most
-- law enforcement has learned is learn to trace
-- the money.
The money is a huge one.
And if you're, let's say, in, in a country that isn't very free in terms of speech,
this one's huge.
Well, more of the point too,
you got to remember a lot of the world
doesn't really have easy access to like credit cards.
Uh
So how are you going to pay them? Right. And that's
so
I think to some degree,
it's less about anonymous payment and more about
supporting forms of payment that are like nontraditional.
Like I know in Africa, um
uh you can recharge your cell phone like minutes,
like you can basically send credits to your friends and family
and those systems have become de facto currencies.
-- I can see that. Right?
-- Because it's way more convenient than carrying cash.
No bank is involved
and it's instant,
you know.
Um,
so, well,
Bitcoin is kind of a terrible example of an anonymous currency because a it's
not really anonymous and b it's just kind of a pain in the,
well, you can tell our listeners about your experience.
-- It's worth
-- a ton of money now though.
Well, show me the money.
I I Bitcoin Rich man. Right. That's what it's all about.
Send me a picture once you've converted it into Benjamin's and I'll believe you.
I,
yeah, I know. Anyway,
so I think the anonymous payment is sort of valid but even more valid for, like,
you know,
people just in weird parts of the world where you can't easily get a visa or an A E
or a mastercard.
Yeah, I think that's
a lot of these companies, you know,
use payment processors that look very suspiciously on, like, visas from
-- strange countries.
-- Uh, yes.
In fact,
I have this problem every time I pay my VPN bill because
it shows up as a foreign transaction taking place in their country.
And then my, my credit card fraud detection
goes crazy every time.
And I'm like, what? No, it's cool.
It's still, still me guys, like every year, same, same, same thing,
which is fine. I, I get it. It's, it's tough.
-- Well, it's definitely outside that statistical norm of behavior
-- and,
and it's actually funny too because when, when I pay them,
they always warn me that my payment is easily tracked.
And I'm like, yes, I'm, I'm ok with that guys. It's, it's cool like we're good
anyway. Anyway,
so the next one is uh P to P and torrenting, which, well,
obviously if you want to use peer to peer or torrenting you,
you better find a VPN that supports that.
I don't really know what else to say to that.
Yes, I don't know if
do VPN S not allow it. I mean,
some don't
or they don't,
well, they may not allow it or they don't support it properly.
Um,
and that's kind of back to that whole incoming connection thing because
the thing to remember about a lot of VPN S is they'll,
some of the cheaper ones, right.
They'll only have a single IP address with like 10 million people coming out of it.
That would be silly.
Well, yes and no, on the other hand,
it makes tracking the traffic very difficult because it's, you know,
it's very much aggregated.
You know what? No, I bet you
that
it would be trivial to take an added system like, like where you have,
let's say 100 users on one IP.
And I bet it would be
very simple to put those, that puzzle back together.
I,
I think it would depend because for example,
if those 100 users were all accessing Facebook
or
even then
even then I bet you it would not be hard to do.
And that would be a fascinating research project.
So someone smarter and less lazy than us, uh please go do this
or IV two or IP
A I know that they don't natively sort
of support traffic generation and padding to like,
you know, make it less kind of to normalize the traffic flows.
But do any VPN providers do that,
not where they have the client or they have the server sending
out traffic to kind of pad out the traffic to make it,
you know, harder to analyze.
I'd be amazed if any of them do.
I would assume they don't because I've never seen or heard of it happening.
-- Yeah,
-- that's there.
I remember research being done around this at some university some, some time ago.
And
it, it works though.
If you add random garbage to your encrypted streams, it can make a big difference.
Although on the, on the same side though, if you're a VPN provider,
you're burning cash,
right? You're wasting capacity if you're sending garbage packets back and forth.
Yeah.
Well, and that's the problem with here.
Well, this goes back to the whole NSA thing of,
you know, they don't really need to break the encryption because the metadata alone
is more than enough in most cases, like we know
Alice is talking to Bob at three in the morning
consistently and then banks are being robbed an hour later,
right? It's that kind of, you know,
that kind of metadata who's talking to who, how like,
you know, they phoned this person seven times hung up after 30 seconds and then,
you know, finally got a hold of them and talked for an hour,
you know, things like that.
You can, you can very strongly infer relationships and, you know,
kind of what's going on.
Um And I don't have enough data and traffic which, you know, if you're a nation state,
you do because let's face it right?
As we learned from my back of the envelope, Santa Claus exercise.
I mean,
you don't even have to like,
spend the money upfront.
You can just pay Amazon monthly to track everybody on the planet. Now.
That, that is true.
God bless the cloud.
Yeah. So,
yeah. No, I don't think any of them do traffic padding.
And of course,
the other thing is you can't really
do traffic subtraction without like breaking things.
Uh Yeah.
Well, not only that, if, if a VPN provider is preventing, say, like, uh, Bittorrent,
that means they're, they're messing with the traffic. Right? You don't want that.
Yeah.
Well, or they're possibly not allowing any incoming connections, for example,
you know, actually that's another good point.
And that's something people have to be really mindful of
here is when you connect to some VPN providers,
your computer suddenly has a public IP address
and if your firewall isn't configured to, like, keep things out,
you can find yourself in trouble.
If you're running some services you shouldn't be in your firewall,
lets them in because now you're essentially
a computer just sitting on the internet.
Well, like your classic Windows client with the SMB reporting the computer name
-- and the computer name is like Lisa's PC or whatever.
-- Right. Right.
Exactly. Or, or maybe you're running SMBV one on the internet.
Right.
Oh, wow. Nobody does that though.
So,
and then they finally list as a nice to have
and I love that this isn't an important requirement,
is I PV six?
Oh, my
goodness.
We could argue for hours about I PV six and, like,
yeah, it's neat. But
talk to me in two years and I've been saying that forever
and I wish
it wasn't true because I PV six in theory is a great,
-- one
-- of my I
SPS actually supports I PV six. Now. Tech savvy.
They're like one of those little scrappy upstarts that,
you know, buys access on the actual hardware lines.
Like they don't, like, tell us and Shaw
own like,
you know, the last mile.
But thank, thankfully in Canada they have to resell wholesale access to other I SPS.
-- Yeah,
-- I've been, I actually have one of the big ones.
It used to be Time Warner and I think Charter bought
them now or something like I've had I PV six for years
and I haven't enabled and it works and I connect to things with I PV six and whatever.
Like,
what's the difference?
You know what I mean?
It's not changing the world and, and in fact, there have been a handful of,
uh, uh, hosting providers. I've used that just didn't even support it.
So it's like this is
nuts.
You know what I mean?
Well,
I know cloud flare is making some inroads there because something like 30% of
the world's kind of internet traffic and web traffic goes through cloud flare now
and you can just turn I PV six on with them and then it'll talk IP
-- physics or I PV four to the actual
-- back end
they do magic kind of cloud fronting sort of thing
where if you don't have an I PV six server,
you can still connect to their I PV six service.
Yeah, just like with the HTTP S right.
The actual back end server can be HTTP,
it can be HTTP S with a cell sign certificate or it can be like strict where
actually has to be correctly set off.
See,
and like this is actually an instance where I PV six is gonna
be hugely awesome because I assume cloud flare just gives literally every single
host or whatever. It's, it's very own I PV six address. Right?
-- If they don't,
-- they're freaking small.
Well, everybody has like enormous blocks of I PV six addresses.
Like, it's just, you get them, that's how it works crazy.
They don't, I know they list their I PV four
blocks.
I don't see their I PV, hang on that cloud
last,
ah IP Rangers. Here we go.
Um,
I PV six they got slash 32 slash 32 slash ok. 123456 slash 32. So
that's basically six times the modern internet
and slash 29.
Good measure.
So I'm not even gonna bother to. Well,
it's a lot,
it's enormous, man.
-- That's, I think it's a
-- slash 29 again in I PV six. It's
what is it? Yeah. So it would be two to the 99th.
Is that correct?
I have no idea. That sounds
right.
Uh, it's a big number.
Yes.
You know what I think about sometimes with I PV six though is
I wonder if someday we're going to be like, oh, crap,
we're running out of I PV six addresses quick.
Everyone, you know,
we need, we need to get some back. Let's, let's renumber things.
I don't think we'll run out of addresses. I think we might run out of network blocks.
Uh Yeah. Ok. That's fair. That could be because
they're handing them out pretty, pretty willy nilly today.
Well, if you look at even I PV four, it's not like we've actually run out of I PV four.
It's just, we've run out of network blocks and a lot of them are not
well used. I mean, what was it like
mit had their own class? A
I
-- had a couple, I think back in the day,
-- you know. So like,
yeah, I mean, there's,
there's been a whole pile of classes that
are clearly not like remotely actually used.
Um,
I, to me the most exciting things are like,
if in theory we got things like mobile I PV six, that would be neat.
But more to the point it doesn't matter anymore because everything is web based.
Like who cares what your IP is and what it changes when you reconnect with the server,
I'll be like, I don't know who you are.
Reate. Oh, you're Bob. Cool. Yeah, I
was sending you video. Here you go. Here's your video,
right? Like who, who cares?
Well, really the only thing that cares is Google.
It gets touchy every time my IP address changes and it's like you have to log in again.
-- I'm like, uh, interesting,
-- you know, Google's pretty,
pretty kind to me about that when my IP address changes as I travel.
Although it knows I travel also. So maybe that's part of
I'm, I'm probably in some high risk pool of, of people not to care.
I know it varies because when I travel I'll kind
of get that initial one or two authentication logins.
But then I think it's smart enough to know, for example.
Oh, he's in like San Francisco. Cool.
That could be,
you
know,
I mean,
Google is not dumb.
I mean, this is not,
and this isn't exactly rocket science, right?
This is like your credit card company where you
warn them that I'm going to South America.
So please don't block my credit card.
You know,
because like I got a new credit card and then I
went to the cabin and it's like I can't spend any money
because I'm like a four hour drive from home,
which is kind of exactly what somebody who stole my credit card would be,
is try to gas up and hit the liquor store, which is
exactly what I do when I go to the cabin.
So you just have to stop exhibiting deviant behavior.
That's all I did. Anyways. I, yeah, it was just such a pain because, uh,
yeah,
-- so,
-- anyway,
as well as well, we, we've rattled again, which we tend to do,
uh, what about alternatives to, to VPN S?
I'm, I'm gonna tell you now that, you know what my favorite one is.
SSH.
Yeah.
And you know,
that's the SSH team has done some real good stuff around setting up SSH for VPN.
And
see this is my biggest annoyance with VPN.
And on the other hand, I get it that it's necessary.
It's like you have to have sort of administrative control of the machine.
Um But more to the point, like quite often, I don't want all of my machine to be VPN.
I just want like one or two high risk apps to be VPN
and that could be sometimes.
And so like a great example of that is when I'm traveling, right?
Like I wanna use my web browser
um
to surf the web, but I don't want, yeah, like the hotel network shenanigans
to go on or whatever, you know, somebody to inject malware or,
you know, put an ad server in with malware or whatever, right?
So what I'll quite often do is just set up a local SSH port, you know,
redirect like local port 80 to a remote server
and then, you know, point my web browser at that port 80 as the proxy.
Well, you know, you can ssh has,
it's like dash capital D or something that turns it into a sox proxy.
Yeah, that's the one I use, which is amazing.
Yeah.
No, it's, and it's because, well, I'm not going to say everything has a socks proxy.
Everything used to have a socks proxy, like 50
years ago.
It was
huge.
-- But Socks is basically, I think outside of web browsers, it's pretty
-- dead.
I can't think of anything outside of a web browser
that, that I would even use it with, to be honest with you.
Uh email client,
email client, my email clients, my web browser,
-- let's face
-- it.
Everything, web browser is everything.
Yeah, that's all it is. Everything else supports my web browser.
That's, that's life.
So
I mean part of me ascribes to that whole uh what is the Google
Man for all the times I mentioned this, you think I'm on
the
Corp
beyond Corp where, where,
where the assumption is essentially even your
internal network is like the public internet,
you have to just encrypt and authenticate everything.
You know.
Funny enough is I now have that kind of view of my home network
where I used to like have segments and stuff and I'm like screwed.
It's all flat now
because I view my Children as adversaries.
So I I cannot trust them,
not in the context of them like hacking me, but rather
I'm sure the devices they use will certainly have malware on them.
And so
I have to assume they're compromised in some way.
Yeah, that's, that's my problem. Exactly. Right.
My kids are getting old enough that they're going to
want to start browsing the web and it's like,
you know what?
At first I was like, oh, be careful doing this and this and this and now I'm like,
you know, what?
Screw it. I'm just going to wipe this computer probably a couple of times a year.
And that's, that's life. Now,
that's one of the reasons I like being with an Apple device is you can
-- wipe the device and reset it except
-- you probably have time machine backing it up.
-- So you've got all your malware safe and sound.
-- Not
the
ipad.
Those are all whatever.
Ok.
You know.
Uh, yeah, tablets. Well, and this other nice thing about tablets too, right?
Is it's really difficult to store files locally. Like you can't
kind of locally from your web browser easily. Save a file.
I mean, you can, like, save a, you know,
you can kind of send it to another app but you
can't just like locally dump stuff onto the file system.
Yeah.
Or if you do it's kind of more contained like
VLC media player, you can download files but it lives within the VLC app.
So if you blow that app away, it's gone.
It's,
I love that
I absolutely love that.
-- You know,
-- because,
you know,
it's something I just realized wasn't on this list
for VPN S but probably should have been,
is this guy didn't make any reference in any way to,
you could maybe claim open source.
But, but having, you know,
I guess verifiable clients
-- that you can be using to connect into a VPN service,
-- well, all of them,
if they're open VPN or IP
A
V two, they all have open source clients.
And that's true actually, because if you're using open
VP, I mean, open VPN by its nature, I guess, start as an open
source project, didn't it?
Yeah. Well, and for example, on my Macs, I use viscosity,
right? Which is a pretty nice client.
I am familiar with that because actually getting a VPN client on a Mac was a pain.
Basically, you use viscosity. That's how,
that's what I anything else is, doesn't
really
work.
I read some things and then I paid money for it,
which really bothered me because I haven't actually paid for software in like,
years
and I'm thinking what, who pays for stuff anymore.
But in this particular instance, it had to be done.
It could have been,
well, the reality is my Mac runs a whole pile of random stuff that, like,
I hope the guy is not a bad guy because I, you know, it, these things,
auto update once every month or two and like,
uh, how could I possibly know if they're evil or not like, well, Handbrake. Right.
It got
a mirror site got fiddled
with
-- and it didn't get caught with
-- that
Google chrome extension that got hacked.
-- We talked about that
-- last, last week, I think.
Just madness, man.
Yeah.
So, yeah, I definitely try to minimize what's on my computer.
I want to make one more plug as well in the VPN category.
Is there something, I mean, give me an eye on that.
That's kind of, I will call it an up and comer perhaps,
but it's something called wire guard
and I'll, I'll put a link in the show. No, it's,
I'm intrigued by it and I hope it does work out.
Yeah, it's super crazy.
And so so generally speaking, the we'll say historical VPN S had a very
right.
They're written by developers for people who know how to use
them and if you don't know how to use them,
that's too bad.
That's part of it. But it also has that kind of Ivory tower mindset of
you. You kind of have the
somebody is speaking truth out to the universe and you,
you have your trusted certificates and all of your credentials, trusted.
And
you know what I mean? You need some level of trust up front
before you can even really join that ecosystem. Uh with,
with like open VPN is a great example in, in IP SEC is a huge example of, of this.
Well, and the other ugly truth is the majority of current VPN S don't
like they work in a container, but they weren't like built with containers and mine,
they do.
And so
that's one thing that Wireguard really gets me is that
uh here it is Wireguard sends and receives encrypted packets using the
network name space in which the wireguard interface was originally created,
which basically means it understands containers
-- and will behave sanely and rationally inside of container,
-- which is super cool.
But then also importantly, on this point is
it's designed to be easy,
kind of like how SSH works when you connect to
a new host instead of having to find the certificates and
certificates and blah, blah, blah,
-- it's just
-- I set up a five node, fully interconnected IPs E
thing once and adding that sixth node meant, you know,
I had to update all the other five nodes.
You shouldn't, you screwed something up,
-- you shouldn't have to do that. But
-- no, this was like 20 years ago.
That could be,
-- but it
-- was
like,
and I wasn't using certificates was basically even more impossible.
So I was using like shared keys.
Terrible. I know
I wanted a full mesh so that, you know, it was more efficient and oh my God,
it, it was just like once I got it working,
it worked and they let it run for like three years, we never patched it,
we never touched it because, you know, if you touch it or look at it funny, it'll,
it'll,
you know, and that's actually a really good point is,
is a lot of these BPN providers in, in,
they don't touch it once it works and that's super destructive. Let's face it.
Right.
-- Like
-- you with your,
-- how long did your server stay up before a power outage hit
-- it.
It might have been, I think, like, 700 days or something
right
now.
In my defense, I did, uh,
I did yum update it on a regular basis but it was obviously running a multi
year old kernel.
Well,
-- Angie lipsy and
-- minor details. Yes.
-- Right.
-- Anyway,
see
here. Uh,
no, it was fine. It was running in my trusted home network.
Everything was ok.
Yeah.
No, I know. I know. That's something I thought about a lot.
It's, uh, but, but ironically, so here's,
here's the thing though and I'm sure people can relate to this is
I didn't want to shut it down because I knew
the disc probably went fsck cleanly on start up.
Right.
And so
you hit the, uh, the date count limit, which I've,
you know, you reboot once a year and it's just like, what?
Right.
And
it takes like, four hours to reboot.
I mean, it's totally like being sick,
not going to the doctor because you're afraid you're gonna tell you're dying.
That's exactly what it is. Stage
four
Melanoma. Right. Right. Exactly. Like I'm just, I'm happy you're not knowing.
And that's kind of the security model of many people
and, and it used to be mine.
We'll, we'll say I won't say I'm perfect, but I'm certainly better.
Uh, anyway, we're,
we're nearly out of time and there's one more thing I'd like to bring up is
we,
we will almost certainly not be recording an episode
next week because I'm going to see an eclipse
and
I am going to see the eclipse. But here's the crazy thing.
I'm going to a middle of nowhere city in Kentucky
and, and the population,
I guess is like 20,000 people or something and they're
expecting it to swell to 100 and 20,000 people.
I can't even imagine
you
up,
I'm going to get gas and toilet paper and I figure everything else is fine. Yep. Yep.
No, no, for real though. Are you taking your kids or just
the whole family's gone? We're, we're super excited to go see it. It's gonna be fun.
But yeah.
No, don't lie.
Don't laugh is we're,
we're making sure we have plenty of gas and we're bringing a
bunch of food and water with us just in case we're like,
-- you know, like stuck on
-- some,
there was an article on,
yeah, like the expected, like there were traffic jams in the one in the 19 seventies.
And honestly, this is interesting because this is one of those things where like,
how do you deal with the
sort of security slash safety side of this event when like, say
10% of the population all decides to stick a fork in their ear.
And like, what do you, what do you do?
Well, ignoring the safety aspect of it,
I just keep thinking from a security angle if I was like an evil doer or,
or a pickpocket or whatever.
Like this is, this is prime pickens here, man. Right?
-- Like 100,000 people descending on like some middle of nowhere city in Kentucky.
-- How
easy it is to fence a stolen telescope.
I, those things are not cheap to buy.
Not that I'm
to be
-- clear,
-- but I don't, I'm not bringing one with me.
Maybe I'll see there, there might be a guy behind the building selling telescopes,
I'll keep an eye out for that and I'll certainly take a picture if it happens.
But no, I mean, like this is something
I think many people don't consider,
but there are enormous security implications of,
of a population increasing by a factor of 10.
-- Yeah,
-- it's crazy.
Even a factor of two.
Like, I mean, even if law enforcement basically calls everybody out on duty,
you know, they only have like
most, maybe three or four times total capacity at a
single,
like this probably has what? Legitimately? 10 officers at best?
I mean, come on, 10 officers for 100,000 people.
No, I mean, it just, that's the thing, the traffic alone
I mean, not even considering traffic.
Right,
because that's one of the other things we're going
to get up really early and drive there,
hopefully before traffic gets too bad.
But it, and part of it too is my drive is in the path of the totality.
So worst case scenario, like park the car, look up, you know, that,
that's plan B
but
no, it's just, I, I keep thinking about this and, and yeah, there's
my brain can't handle
what
-- is going to happen.
-- The
sad thing, there was a person who specifically was going to travel to the US to
talk to all these small towns about kind of what
to expect with the eclipse and how to handle it.
Public safety, food toilets, the whole nine yards
and she couldn't get a work visa.
And so she only ended up visiting like 10 cities out of like 200 planned ones
or something ridiculous.
And so the majority of these cities are not really all that well prepared for this.
I don't see how a small town could even
remotely prepare for this because here's the thing,
this is like a one shot deal, right?
Like
it's coming once
and it's never coming back like you're never going to see this kind of traffic again.
And part of me also feels bad because I imagine there's going to be just
like a path of destruction behind all of the people who descend on this,
this like 70 mile wide.
Seriously.
That's what I feel like is you're going to be able to look at a map, you know,
like an aerial shot of the United States
and just see like the trample marks from all the people in this path. And it's just,
yeah, my, my brain is,
and part of me is super excited. I get to see it.
Well,
I imagine Google traffic is just a solid swath of red through the path of totality.
I guess
that's assuming any of the cell phones even work. Right.
Well, and there's a good example, right?
Like,
I know a lot of stadiums and stuff are set up for a sudden influx of 1020 50,000 people.
But I'm guessing most small towns aren't prepared for
like four times as many cell phone users.
Right? And, and
much less 10 times as many. Right.
I'm totally expecting to have zero cell coverage the entire time.
I'm, I'm down there.
Yeah, it's going to be crazy, man.
-- Well, I hope you stay safe and have fun. I hope
-- I have fun
and, and I guess mostly stay safe. It, it, I don't know.
It, it'll be fun to talk about that.
I'm sure I'll have many crazy stories to tell and, and nothing else.
I get to see a total eclipse.
I've never seen a total eclipse before, so I'm very excited
I've seen.
Well, I was in Germany for the total eclipse but I wasn't in the path of totality.
You weren't in totality.
No, we, well, because, um, we were pretty close,
I think it was about 90 something percent.
It was low nineties or whatever.
Um,
and it was
weird, I'm not gonna lie. It was just like, because,
like, you're not supposed to turn the lights off outside.
Right. Right. That's not how that works.
Like, my brain is like, no,
this isn't really happening and the rest of me is kind of like, yep, it is.
And the birds just got real wonky and confusing.
I heard that, that, that birds do crazy things.
-- All the animals apparently do crazy things
-- all of
a sudden it's nighttime except it's not nighttime.
And you know, this is actually a really, this is something we should spend some time.
Maybe we, we have two weeks to do it, we can do some reading. But uh
this is one of those great examples of just human nature
where as a human,
I am not programmed to accept the sun disappearing in the middle
of the day for two minutes and then coming back and,
and it, it's like fishing is a great, you know,
never
mind
-- is
-- the um
the tsunami,
the Southeast Asian tsunami where they show the video of the water drawing out to sea
and how many people know what that meant. Well, now
everybody
knows now.
Yeah, but back in the day, like I quite honestly, if I was you know,
standing next to the ocean and the water started receding suddenly I would be like,
what the, you know, I wouldn't
probably followed. It been, like, I wonder where it's going. Right.
Yeah. So, I mean, you know, that's the thing. Right.
We're just, yeah, there's, there's these freak events
but just, yeah, the, the physical world like earthquakes,
that's just not supposed to happen.
Right.
Well, but, and here's the thing, right? Is, is some of these events,
it, it doesn't matter
because as humans, we don't know what to do. It amuses us. Ha ha.
That's like roller coasters, right? Good example.
But, but there are other things,
especially around security where obviously the bad
guys take advantage of human nature.
And so
I don't know, it, it,
uh, you gotta love it. You know, it reminds me of it.
Well, I remember reading a story once that the, the astronauts on the moon,
the,
the horizon of the moon is obviously much different than the horizon of the earth
and it bothered them
when they looked at it. Right. Like they, they couldn't explain it
but they knew it wasn't. Right.
Which is just, yeah.
-- No,
-- I can definitely imagine that because, yeah, like we're just, well, it's like,
well, it's like being surrounded by air. We're just used to that.
Well, no, we kind of need that to live. Right? That
it's a different thing I think.
Yeah.
So, well, when you, when I see those deep sea things and it's just like, uh,
that doesn't seem right
under all that,
-- those
-- people. Yeah. I've, I've never going to space kind of.
I'm in the same boat. Like I, I don't, I don't want to do that.
I don't really like roller coasters. I can't imagine enjoying myself on a rocket.
No.
Yeah.
Yep.
So, anyway,
I
-- think that's it, folks, if we don't hear from Josh in two weeks, I guess it's
-- true.
This, you might be getting a new partner for the open
source security podcast.
I, I may be living although, although I must say I'm very upset
we planned our trip to go to Kentucky because we are like, what,
whatever they call it, like the length of totality.
I'm basically about as,
as close as you can get because I'll get like two extra
seconds of totality than the rest of the country or something.
Which right then, why not?
Which I'm sure was also a brilliant decision because
I'm sure no one else thought of that.
So, anyway,
so anyway,
I, I was reading and apparently, I think it's in South Carolina.
They have, uh,
many yeti and giant lizard man sightings and
they expect them to peak during the eclipse.
So I'm like, I could have seen a yeti or a giant lizard man and I, I totally did.
-- They have both. I
-- know totally
different, like ecosystems.
I'm not making this up. This is some other quack on the internet.
And I'm upset that I would have had an opportunity
to potentially see a yeti or giant lizard man.
-- Well, you better
-- photograph it.
I mean, because like I'm tired of everybody now carries phones
and we still don't have good footage of these things.
Like get your phones out of people and
for the love of God don't use portrait mode
or I
was
gonna
say mode. Sorry, that's what I meant to say. Not
uh Yes.
No, I know what you mean or, or even better
-- use
-- land,
not portrait. That's what I meant to say.
It's time to go.
Landscape is the
time to
use that.
-- It's
-- time to go.
Yeah. Thank. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for putting up with this.
Like it was fun. No, it was good. It was good. It was fun to talk about the VPN stuff.
So if you need any links to the show notes,
you can go to open source security podcast.com.
We have links there to Twitter
and a Facebook group and you can use the Pound Os s podcast hashtag to get a hold of us.
We love hearing feedback. So by all means, let us know
and yeah, I guess uh hopefully I'll, I'll see you in two weeks.
-- Yeah, I hope you enjoy the eclipse and everybody else as well.
-- Awesome.
Talk to you later guys. Bye bye.