Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 74 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
After our episode last week about Santa and
leaving out, we'll say offerings to him by the Children.
I had a friend contact me actually today
and said when he was a kid, they left uh whiskey out for Santa.
And I'm thinking these people Irish.
I know.
Is he? No, I'm not Irish.
No, doesn't matter like I've been,
I've been missing out on this for all these years.
And unfortunately, I suspect I,
I've reached a point where I can't change the rules now, but
I'm, I, I feel like
there's some grand conspiracy going on behind the scenes and I,
I've completely missed it and,
and I feel like a part of me is now empty and hollow because of it.
Yeah, I'm gonna agree with you.
Sweet.
Did you think I was going to say something helpful?
No, I, I have no idea.
So, so for those of you with either very young Children or no Children,
keep this in mind, it apparently is quite ok to leave booze for Santa.
So
do
you
know
the good stuff too, folks?
That's right. Santa doesn't like cheap booze.
So, anyway, I,
I do have one other bit of actually what I think is very exciting
news and I'm sure some people may or may not think it's exciting,
but
I have actually turned Bitcoin into money
-- like real,
-- you actually got it into your bank account.
It is not there yet.
It is very good.
So you haven't,
I'm comfortable saying it's going to get there.
And
so here's a crazy thing, right is I created an account on Coinbase.
I sold $50 worth of Bitcoin, which actually it's quite funny.
It took like six days for the transaction to go through because I, I submitted
my, my Bitcoin transfer
uh right before the Bitcoin price like went to the moon
and then the transaction cost like doubled from what I had submitted it as and
well, I could have done some trickery to maybe make it go through.
I was like, eh I'm lazy and I don't care.
I'm just going to sit on this and yeah, it did, it went through eventually.
Well, it's really fascinating to me that everybody's like,
oh Bitcoin decentralized, it's super fast and fun to use.
And it's like
I've been reading all these stories about how transactions are
taking longer and longer and longer in like six days.
Well, you just have to,
if I would have made my transaction fee,
the same amount of Bitcoin I transferred but
then it would have gone through right away.
I know. Anyway,
I
-- feel
-- like that's not the right answer.
It
is the only answer though because the Blockchain is too small.
So, so anyway, I, I moved the Bitcoin to Coinbase.
I sell $50 for the Bitcoin, which is probably worth like $200 now.
But whatever it doesn't matter, sell $50. Then on a Sunday
I managed to open a savings account with my bank because I,
the only way to move it out of Coinbase was with it with a
bank transfer
and I
give
them a real account number.
Right. Right. Exactly.
So, anyway, I opened a savings account on a Sunday with my bank
and then I, I initiate the transfer and it is
Coinbase takes like five days to transfer the money,
which I assume they're probably pulling like an 80 P style stunt where they take the
money and they throw it in an interest bearing account for a couple of days,
you know, and gain like a couple cents or whatever and then they,
then they move it along.
But so basically it was a $1
for the sale of the coin.
-- Now.
-- Is that a flat $1 or a percent?
I believe it is
-- my, my understanding
-- is it's a
2% fee. That's, oh, wow. I want to get into that business.
Right.
So, my understanding is the flat fee of $1
no matter how much coin you sell.
And,
and so another crazy thing though is you can only
sell $10,000 worth of Bitcoin with Coinbase without verifying yourself.
-- And so I, of course
-- that would be the financial reporting laws.
Uh,
yeah. Sure. I don't know. It doesn't matter,
like you can't bring $10,000 into the
US in financial instruments without declaring it and
all sorts of paperwork you got, basically,
you have to prove where that money came from and that it's ok
and, and that's kind of. Right. Right. Right.
And
what they had me do for that is I clicked a button and they,
my webcam took pictures of my driver's license and then like,
an hour later they told me of, of my driver's license, not of me.
-- I'm not, I'm on the driver's license, but I'm not actually. No,
-- no.
But I mean, if it was me,
I would make people submit a picture of
their driver's license and of themselves so that,
you know, you could maybe make sure that they
sort of look the same.
That, that might be a good idea. I don't know. My guess is it's not legally required.
So why would you go above
and beyond? Right.
-- Like, never, never.
-- Mostly
because it would discourage bad people from abusing me and giving me grief. Right.
If that's a cost I can external, if I can basically
reduce fraud by Externalizing some costs like you have to
take 17 pictures of yourself holding up random number,
digits printed out on cards, using baloney and bananas to scale.
Then I would do that because, you know, people will jump through those hoops
and it doesn't cost me money.
Maybe I, I don't know, whatever
doesn't matter anyway. In, in like an hour I was
so
now I can sell or buy as much Bitcoin as I want.
So there we go. I guess. Uh
now I will say my suspicion is if you have say a billion dollars worth of Bitcoin,
you're probably going to struggle to get rid of that.
But in my case, I don't have a billion dollars.
So I think we mentioned this last week, but
I was looking into the amount of Bitcoin being traded
and a major portion of the Bitcoin transactions are the washing.
I, I'm not even
like they're not even, it's,
it's not like legitimate transactions of people buying stuff online.
It's,
it's the people wanting to wash their bitcoins to,
you know, make them harder to trace.
Sure.
No, I, I have no doubt,
no doubt.
And, and that, that's fair. It's going to be,
it
was fascinating to me for abuse is,
-- is
-- people who want to launder money.
If you told them,
you could perfectly anonymously launder your money and it's like a 5% fee,
they would laugh and say how much can we put through,
right?
Whereas normal people,
if you say you want to buy stuff online with Bitcoin and by the way,
there's a 5% transaction fee
that's not gonna fly.
That is
very true.
And in fact, now that you say that, no, I, I had about a
half a percent
is what my,
a
dollar on 50 is 2%.
Uh, no, no, no, I'm saying when I moved the coin I moved like,
at the time it was like 500 bucks worth and
I paid like three bucks a little less than that.
So,
so,
yeah,
that's not
bad. How does that work?
But, but of course, had I had, I, I tried to move the Bitcoins like an hour after I did,
I would have paid more than double that transaction fee.
So
I guess in a way I lucked out because I didn't care and I was willing to wait 60 days.
-- So,
-- there you go. I'm actually really curious.
I'm assuming the money will show up because coin base is
-- somewhat legitimate
-- from what I see, they're pretty legit. I'm comfortable.
In fact, I've, I've dealt with them on a, on a business level.
Not, not in terms of me buying and selling coins,
but yeah, they're like a real company and I'm,
I'm quite comfortable expecting my funds to make it into my bank account.
So, yeah, and then what do I do?
Then the real adventure starts because when I do my taxes,
I get to figure out how to claim $50 in Bitcoin sales on my taxes
because I,
I probably could get away with not doing it and I doubt I would get in any trouble.
But the way I see it is
my guess is at some point the IRS is going to light up
-- users with a spotlight. I mean,
-- Revenue Canada already did that with paypal. Right.
Where they demanded records from paypal for the last three years
for any business account.
Right.
In fact, Coinbase has been really clear in their fact, like they're giving the IRS
everything,
-- there's no escape.
-- What choice do they have?
Spend $10 million on lawyers and then give them everything.
Right?
I don't blame them either if I was, this is one of the situations they be like, yeah,
it's cool.
You guys do whatever you need. Like you just tell us what to do and it'll get done,
you know,
I get it
and, and at the same time this,
this intrigues me how this whole process is going to work.
I'm actually really excited I did at the
end of the year because I don't have to wait like nine months to file my taxes now.
Well, I mean, it's like, it's like that aspect.
I don't know if you're aware, but so, um
all banks internationally are now required to report American account holders to
the IRS.
-- They were always supposed to, aren't they? It's just
-- they, they, now it's,
if you don't, they won't let you
trade,
like they won't let you talk to the US banks.
And so, for example, for Canada, that's just absolutely not an option.
Right? Because it's like,
it's like something like 30% of Canadian banks business
is with the US and through the US.
Right? I mean, 80%
some
of our GDP is,
-- uh, I see Canadian Banks down here,
-- even with
the reason for that is simple. We had very
uh much more conservative laws around, you know,
cash reserves and what they could do with those uh mortgage backed securities.
And so the banks like TD
were essentially sitting on large piles of cash when the financial
crash happened and a bunch of us banks were about to
not doing so great.
And so they went on a buying spree because, you know,
stuff was cheap and they had money
in, in fact, I used TD is, is one of the banks. Um I I use and then I see
-- BMO Bank of Montreal branches all over the place everywhere.
-- The rule is in Canada.
I mean, you basically have three banks, you have TD
CBC
C I BC. Sorry and uh BMO
Bank of Montreal
I
BC. I don't know if I've seen them around here at all.
This is wonky red and yellow thing anyways
-- doesn't matter.
-- Um
But yeah, so I mean, essentially, so what's happening in a lot of countries now,
especially in China, for example,
is when an American goes in to deal with
their account and they realize you're an American,
they're like, your account is closed now
and they hand you your money and they,
because they don't like, I mean,
in fairness,
nobody really likes these reporting requirements because they're such a pain,
you have to go through all your accounts,
figure out who's American send all that data to the, I mean, just uh no,
but you know, if you want to do business with the US, you got to do that.
So some banks strategy is to basically, um,
you know, we took care of the problem.
Right. Well,
if you have a huge wheelbarrow full of money at that bank, they'll work with you.
But if you're, if you're a small change, I'd get rid of them.
-- No,
-- they won't because it's,
the reporting requirements are so onerous for most of these banks that they,
the cost and the privacy implications,
um,
are
such,
yeah, it's, it's a real problem. I mean, because,
well, think about it, I mean,
there's one country in the world that charges you
income tax if you live outside the country.
Right. And that's the US.
You know, when I hear about that, I'm like, that's,
that's insane.
I know. But every now and then
I get tempted to try to maybe live outside the
country for a couple of years for work or something.
And then I remember
that I will lose all of my money to taxes
between
like us, taxes and foreign taxes and it's just
-- in
-- your
account.
Right.
But, uh,
well, and that sort of brings up a similar thing the whole, so
I think the biggest thing we're going to see in the next few years,
it's going to be amazing is the whole
facial recognition thing.
No, it's here now, man. Have
used,
yeah. But I mean, it's going to become ubiquitous and cheap. I mean,
we talked about Amazon web services, you know,
recognition with the mug shots and like
you can basically build an app to do like real time facial recognition
in like minutes,
you know.
Um
but I ran across a BBC
article from yesterday uh
about the Chinese facial recognition
stuff that they're doing with the government and the police.
And so the deal is they have something like 100 and 70 million cameras in the country.
Their plan is to deploy 400 million more over the next three years. That's crazy.
And
they basically did a demo where they took a
picture of the BBC journalist using like a smartphone,
the guy like crops it, you know, using like the little app on the phone
and essentially submits it to the system and flakes it like this is a, you know,
a person of interest like go arrest or talk to him or whatever.
And then the guy left the building and you know,
sees how long it takes for them to kind of track him down and deal with him and it was,
I think, seven minutes,
you know, and, and, but the thing is, it's completely automated, right?
Like there's all these cameras and
so, you know, it's every single person going through train stations,
every single person going through, you know, bus stations, all these,
you know, it always gets me, these privacy advocates are like, oh, you know,
just don't use a credit card, don't do this.
Great. But what about not using public transit or not using highways or not using
public streets?
You know, literally, you would have to go live in the woods under a tarp
so that the satellites can't see you.
So I remember when London deployed all their cameras because
the
ring of steel thing.
Yeah. Yeah.
And, and for those of you who don't know,
London has a lot of cameras in the city and basically,
if you are moving around London in any way
you're being watched. Well,
that's actually the common of all the British
towns now because it's cheaper than having cops.
You can have a central control room
and you can follow people using the cameras.
Well, but see, here's the point though is
I remember when this came out,
there was a website you could go to and
put in like where you're starting from and where
you were going and they would give you a
route that avoided the vast majority of cameras when,
you know, back in the day, my suspicion is today, you can't avoid them at all.
But I remember seeing this in the routes were as you can imagine, like the comical.
And I remember thinking that
nobody is going to do this.
And if you're doing this,
you're probably going to stick out more than if
you're just being recorded walking where you're going.
Right.
Well, and now, you know,
many western countries have passed laws like I know in Canada we
have a law that during protests you cannot obscure your face.
Like you can't wear a mask,
you can be arrested for that.
So, so in Canada, if I showed up with like the guy fox mask,
which seems to be the hip popular one,
they could arrest me for that.
Yeah,
that's crazy.
Well, not really. I mean, it's,
uh, Bill C 309. It was, it became law June 19th of 2013.
And, oh, yeah, it's up to 10 years in prison. So it's not like a little slap on the,
-- on the wrist. It's
-- like incredibly excessive.
Well,
it's one of those things where you kind of hope that they'll selectively enforce it.
Like, oh, you were wearing a mask and kicking in a window or something.
But realistically, I mean, if they decided to completely enforce it much,
like if they enforced speeding laws
across the board,
right? I mean, the first day would be a literal bloodbath.
They, they, that they may come in when,
well, it will, but the cars will be automated so they won't care. Just everybody
will be raging, going, ah, go faster and the car will be like, I'm sorry,
I can't do that.
Dave.
I, I won't care because I won't be driving.
I'll be reading a book in the backseat and it's going to be glorious.
That's what it will be.
-- So,
-- yeah, we'll, we'll put a link but it's,
it's actually now there's about a dozen countries with pretty,
some pretty serious laws against, you know,
obscuring your face
during protests or in general.
That is interesting. I
can
but the police have a history of, you know, videotaping who did,
what are these protests?
-- And then after the fact tracking them down dealing with it,
-- right.
Here's my take on this, right is this is one of those
tricky things. And
for example, let's say you and I go and protest net neutrality
and we decide to wear masks for whatever reason.
And
there are, I guess
noble efforts
you could say. And then there are
less wholesome like the KKK in the US comes to mind where these are
purposely obscured their face.
I misspoke. It's, it bans the Bill C
Bill C 309 in Canada bans the wearing of masks
during a riot or other unlawful assembly.
So if you're having
a
test and it's peaceful,
you're OK. But as soon as they do the riot act, you got to take it off.
I'm I'm comfortable with that.
I can, I
can live with that because I guess here's my,
here's my thinking on a lot of this stuff is
you can easily make the argument
that
this is for the good of society
and
in some of
this will make sense.
I'm going somewhere.
So you can say this is for the good of society. Ok?
But the problem is there is good and bad happening in, in situations like this,
right, where you can have peaceful protests.
Now, in this case, obviously, that's not illegal, but let's just pretend it is
OK,
you might have a peaceful protest and you can have kind of a violent opposition
and those are not the same thing,
right?
But
what what
what I'm always torn by is
it is better to
let the the right thing happen
even though you know, some of the bad guys are going to get away with it too.
-- And like my, my favorite
-- example, it's very American viewpoint, in my opinion
-- and
-- it might be, but that's kind of the way I look at this stuff and I see this,
for example, like in,
in uh court cases where
you can, you know, people are guilty and they get off on technicality sometimes,
but it is better to have a robust system
that is going to make sure the innocent don't also get incarcerated.
And I know that's not always true and there's a little back and forth there but,
you know what I'm saying?
Yeah, I read a simple explanation of that in that if,
if being innocent is not a defense then, then people have no
reason to be innocent.
Right.
We fundamentally have to believe and behave like
being innocent is the correct thing to do.
So that ideally, you know,
people don't go around murdering each other for a pack of gum
and
yeah, I, I agree.
I agree.
And, but on the flip side
of society,
I don't know if you remember, but in Austria they passed a law.
Um and then there was a guy dressed as a, I want to
say
it was a shark for a store or something and he
had to take off his face mask or risk being arrested.
So apparently mascots are now illegal in Austria.
That's hilarious.
Uh
oh, sorry. No, it was an anti
Berka law that they passed. Uh saying essentially
you can't cover your face like that. And so yeah, some guy in a shirt costume.
He, oh, he actually got fined
a
poor little shark. You got fined 100 and €50
for wearing a not burqa
well for wearing a shark outfit.
-- Uh
-- I don't know, it is sweet.
So, so anyway, back to facial recognition.
So China is going to capture photos of everybody and they're going to do
they have a database of all citizens. Yes,
that's true they have it. However, this is one of those things that
I would love to say. Thank goodness that can ever happen in America.
It's
already
happening in Arizona,
Nevada,
Nevada.
Sorry,
they're like the same place, I'm sure. Right.
I mean, that's ignoring the ones that also require. What is it, the thumbprint now?
I,
because most prisons,
well, because, you know,
like fingerprints or something, police and whatnot.
So, anyway,
why don't you tell this story first?
-- And then also
-- simply put, uh, when you get a driver's license in Nevada now
and for some time,
uh, they run your
face, your picture against a database of like
known criminals and stuff.
And so they caught somebody who'd been wanted for 25 years or whatever.
Well, it actually sounds like, so it's even crazier than that.
Apparently, this guy
went in to update his driver's license, they take the picture of him
and they just ran it across their,
their existing database of driver's license photos and basically said, hey,
we've got a match with this other guy here.
A different
and then, then they did some police work and then that's when they figured this out.
I remember when they started capturing the thumb prints,
I think it was somewhere in the northeast.
And that was part of the argument that would like,
that turns out that there are people with
like six or eight licenses with different names.
So, you know,
that's a problem
and now facial recognition has gotten good enough in the last few years. Right?
Because it used to be the thumbprints and stuff, you know,
that was kind of poor man's recognition nowadays, we don't need that.
We'll just walk into our office. We know who you are.
I remember
I used to live in Indiana, one of the US States and
when I was there, they, they started
tracking, not tracking but, but making, using like facial recognition software
and you couldn't, when you took your picture you couldn't smile,
you couldn't have your glasses on
and like you had to have very, you know, a very clear view of their face.
And of course, this was way back in the early two thousands.
So it was, the technology was terrible and they, like,
wasted millions of dollars on nothing.
But,
yeah, I mean, I, I remember when, when this kind of all
because they built a database
going back
and the thing is now, if you're trying to hide,
-- you've got data going back 20 years,
-- that's,
that's exactly it. Right.
Is, is that it's easy to nay, say this stuff when it first starts.
It's like, oh, facial recognition. It's terrible.
Yeah, it is. But it's going to get better.
I'm sure people said the same thing
about credit reporting bureaus in the beginning.
But every anything ever, Kurt,
everything ever has been, look at, look at the cloud. I remember the cloud came
out. I, I'll admit I was one of them. I was like, that looks kind of dumb, like it sucks.
Right. Who wants to use that? Now? It's like
-- everybody wants to use that.
-- That's
true.
Yeah, I, no, I fully agree. It's,
well, that's the thing. Like, I just got an Amazon, Alexa.
Alexa
wake up.
Oh, it
doesn't.
But the
little blue
light. So
buy
a doll
house.
Sorry.
Oh,
there you go. Hey, Alexa,
how are you doing, Alexa?
Awesome. Uh
Anyways and my son was asking Alexa
things and also going like Alexa
chicken butt and poor Alexa is like, I'm sorry, I don't understand.
But you know, and as comically terrible as Alexa is, I would point out that,
that that little $200 device is somehow magically doing voice recognition.
-- Uh
-- It's magically recording everything.
Yeah, I'm fine with that.
It's in a room where uh
it's, it's a, it's like the workroom
but um
uh what's really cool is I can now tie it into my terrible
sky. Oh, this is the best vendor ever Skylink net.
Uh Google. It, it's like the entire security system is like Tuer
Bucks. It's so cheap and terrible.
This is all I'm gonna say
Sky
-- link
-- net.
I know. Isn't that?
It
didn't even
pretend it
isn't sky.
Like come on
guys,
I
put a little more effort into it
and I mean, this stuff is terrible.
I'm afraid to even security test it because I kind
of almost bricked it twice already by just using it.
Um,
but like,
I mean, they are,
-- so who cares?
-- They, exactly. They make a camera that is pen and tilt.
Uh, and Zoom has the whole IR thing for night vision,
uh, does Wi Fi does Ethernet,
uh, it's like 720 P or something. Like, so it's pretty high quality camera.
It's like
90 bucks Canadian. So, like, what is that? Like, 70 bucks us?
-- So, how do you power this camera? Does it use? You
-- plug it into the wall?
Just, just an outlet and, and then I assume it's wireless to.
Exactly.
Yeah, it can be wired or wireless.
Um,
basically you get
a nice,
yeah, you can, but I don't want to wire my house up. It's such a pain.
Um, and this thing, you have, you get a little hub that, like,
talks to all the wireless devices,
like a motion sensor is 20 bucks and they're honestly,
they're good to about 40 or 50 ft.
Like, I put one in a room where there's kind of like a long haul and stuff.
It can, it's,
it's a pretty good motion sensor for something that
cost 20 bucks and runs on a AA battery and
wireless
into facial recognition
-- and you're gold, right?
-- Yeah,
pretty much. And, you know, it's, it's just on the one hand I'm like,
uh, so, you know, I made sure the camera is kind of, it's in a public area of the house.
So, like where we don't do private stuff really, because I, I'm not super keen now,
the one thing I do like about this camera is there's no cloud service behind it.
That's
so it's local only unless I like poke a hole in my firewall so that I can like,
remotely view what's on the camera and control it.
How, how secure is the wireless protocol?
Yeah.
So what's interesting to me though is that it kind
of comes back to the dumb TV security argument but
in some sense,
the more secure home system is the cheaper dumber one
that doesn't have a cloud service, for example, to get broken into,
-- uh,
-- maybe. Now, now does this, does, does your Skynet system,
does it have the ability to, like, open it up to your,
your iphone or something when you're away from home?
It can send notifications when I'm outside the house. Yes. So it can,
there is a bit of a service but it's mostly the notifications.
It's not like the video and stuff.
So for example, you wouldn't know when my doors are open and closed.
Yeah, I'm not super, I'm still waffling on it.
But here's the thing, like, if I, if I want to go with a professional security system,
it's going to cost me a minimum of 20 or 30 bucks a month for monitoring.
That's, that's like
the
set up is crazy expensive
also. No, because they basically like you sign up for two or three years or whatever.
Right.
It's like the way cell phones used to work,
but
the phone is free, just sign this 12 year contract.
Exactly.
So, yeah. No, I mean, I'm not super keen on this, but essentially this,
this is sort of the least evil
system that didn't cost an arm and a leg. Like, I could certainly buy a
pretty secure system, but then you have to go somewhat high end with like,
really name brand
and also like,
Equifax is a name brand.
Well, exactly. Equifax is a pretty good name brand. Turns out, whoops.
We just sort of let some bad guy have everything, minor detail,
you know,
iii I don't know how long until one of these
major security monitoring companies gets broken into and like,
everything gets hoovered up.
So, yeah, I basically went with the dumb TV argument, which is whenever I buy a TV.
Nowadays I find the dumbest TV,
I can buy that doesn't have a camera built in on the premise,
-- but essentially it's a stupid monitor and
-- hopefully
won't be too
happy
-- anymore. Kurt, there's no such thing as dumb TV. S anymore.
-- Really? Oh, dear.
You
know,
from
X TV. You know, there aren't,
although I have a Roku TV. It's very nice.
I love it.
I don't need to plug anything into it and I can watch Netflix.
I find my concern with those devices is more that the software never gets updates.
-- Uh, and I've seen those smart TV and they take forever to turn
-- on.
Uh, yes, it takes 12 seconds to turn on.
And I know that because I have a harmony remote and I
have it designed that when I push the watch TV button,
which I still have a myth TV machine.
I built like 12 years ago that's still running
basically the same hardware from 12 years ago.
Uh, I did upgrade it to Fedora 26 though. It took, I think four days,
I
will know I went from like Fedora 18 or something to like 26.
It was
starting at 18
and
run
up.
I kept doing this and part of me thought I should just reinstall and then I thought,
no, this is a challenge.
I'm going to do this
-- and it is surprisingly worked. Oh,
-- we got to put that video in the show notes.
But this guy upgraded from, I think it was D
OS one to whatever the
windows 1.0 to like windows seven or something. And it, it did work. Yes.
Uh Anyway, anyway,
it takes 12 seconds because I have a harmony remote and I, when the TV turns on,
I then want to tell it the like switch to this input.
And
I basically went, when I set up the remote, I had to do it right away.
It didn't work and I just kept adding a second until I got it. And it was 12 seconds,
which is
an eternity.
-- I want to watch my TV. Now, I don't want to wait 12
-- second.
Well, it's funny because you and I grew up with analog TV. S that you turn them on and
poop.
Like, it takes a 2nd
and 15 minutes later.
Well, when you change channels, especially on digital receiver boxes,
you change the channel.
It thinks for like, half, it thinks for a noticeable amount of time
and then starts displaying something, right?
Because it's got to buffer some stream and whatever, right?
Yeah, I can live with that because I have a guide, I have a guide card.
-- But
-- I, you know, I like that click, click, click, click, click, click, you know,
-- like the
-- knob
near. Yeah,
when you tell your little brother go change the channel like, yeah, pretty much
Sesame Streets on in 10 minutes.
-- You can't miss good
-- times.
And those were the crazy days.
But no, so I I,
one thing I'm beginning to realize is I think in some ways the
cheaper dumber products are probably just as insecure if not more insecure.
But because they don't have like this back end mothership service,
somebody would have to specifically target me to
break in versus I'm going to target the
backend service of some security monitoring company and
like get 5 million people on one go
uh sort of. So the your your your Skynet camera
is eventually going to develop a backend service.
It is going to happen someday
because
it'll become cheap enough
and there will be some demand in whatever.
And it
is, it is quite conceivable that
it's really only a threat today if someone targets you anyway. Because
let's say you're using a service, let's say you're uploading your camera to it.
-- Well, like Nest and
-- Google. Right.
Sure. Let's, let's say, and they say someone breaks in and steals it.
Now they have a 12 million hours of people's hallways
-- and, but
-- they also have Amazon facial recognition to run it.
But still,
I, I envision some level of targeting. I mean, don't get me wrong.
I don't want people stealing like my video camera footage by any means.
I'm not saying it's ok if this happens.
But I, I think there's still some level of herd immunity you can get away with
in, in some of these situations, right?
And, and let's face it. If you're, if you're being targeted,
you lose end of story. Right?
It doesn't matter what service you're using, it doesn't matter if it's cloud or not.
Like if you're a target, you lose,
you cannot beat them.
Generally. Yes. I mean, apart from living
in
the
woods under
teed, even if you live in the woods skit,
they're gonna just show up with a pickup truck, a tarp and a, and a crowbar and
they're gonna get you right. You,
if you are a target
of any sort of attacker with even modest resources you will lose, period
because they don't have to follow the rules
and they won't.
Well, see, in the second part of my thinking is,
is the cost to get a secure system is
like exponentially higher than this cheap junkie system,
like straight up.
Yes.
-- Well, is there a secure system on the market, like
-- whatever a bank uses or,
-- let's
-- say you had infinite money?
Oh, well,
then I would just hire some guys with
guns and give them really good medical benefits.
Ok. Let's dial it down to,
I've told you you can buy any security system off of Amazon with my credit card.
What do you,
uh,
one of everything?
You're, you're not helping.
-- Right. Like
-- this is no, I know what you mean.
-- Like there was, I mean, that we go
-- back to that
one. Right. I'm giving you my credit card and you can buy one, only one.
No stupid rules could stop being a monkey paw. Like, answer the question.
I'd buy the cheap one regardless.
Yeah. Right. Right. That's fair.
Well, you know, like I said, it also comes back to that, like,
paying 20 or 30 bucks a month for monitoring.
You know, that at, like, over the span of 10 years, that's thousands of dollars.
And that's hard to justify. Like, when I could spend 200 bucks
-- every two or three years.
-- Yeah. Well, not only that.
So, like, here's something to think about is,
let's say you're blowing 30 bucks
a month on monitoring, what are the odds
that whatever is stolen from your house will cost
less than the money you are going to spend,
assuming you even get broken into.
Right.
We also have insurance.
Exactly. And there's insurance.
It is
my suspicion is that if you did the Roia a
home security system, unless you live in a dodgy place,
which, in which case,
-- like your insurance is going to be sky high because
-- like they know
you are going to need bars on your windows.
Right?
Yes.
But I mean my my guess and this is kind of
one of those things I think this is like getting,
you know, device protection from Best Buy.
I am never going to
make as much money back in trading in broken garbage to
you people as I'm going to spend paying your extortion.
Well, that is one thing to remember for a lot of
alarm systems is that
the
they will lower your insurance premiums sufficiently to make it worth it.
However, when I was talking to my insurance company because we moved
and they're like,
you know, do you have an alarm system?
And I'm like uh yeah, we'll have like blah, blah, blah, you know, like door sensors,
motion sensors, blah, blah, blah.
And she's like, oh who monitors it?
I'm like, well, like, you know, we do a smartphone thing. She's like, ok, so like
subscriber monitor.
Like, they, they have that option in their soft point now to describe it because,
like, let's face it. Right. Anybody under the age of 30
they're not gonna spend like,
30 bucks a month on an alarm system when they can just
go drop 200 bucks on Amazon and be done with it.
And more to the point I want to go to my smartphone
anyways and I can even have it go to other people's smartphones,
you know, like
my parents or whatever. Um
Yeah, I mean, it's, it's clearly,
well, the future is here now folks and I'm sorry,
but it cost 200 bucks and it doesn't involve a third party company
charging a recurring monthly fee.
Not, not even that man, I mean, even even if you wanted a recurring fee,
the reason it costs so much is because humans generally deal with this
and I have a suspicion that A I is probably good enough
that you could,
-- you could be 80%. Ok?
-- You don't even need a I, I mean
like I'm looking at so it's ift tt and it's a
way to get devices and apps to talk to each other.
So for example,
I can have my skylink net system log everything to a Google spreadsheet,
-- just call it
-- Skynet,
right? Ok.
Um So I for example,
there's like a recipe to have this thing log everything to a Google spreadsheet.
So I have like an audit trail of like,
I know for a fact, for example,
like most police stations have that audit trail of like
every single door when it was open and closed,
who did it?
Which badge?
And I know back in the day,
what they used to do at the downtown location was have it go to a line printer.
So it was like a, a
right once read many unalterable copy and they basically just
fed this printer a box of paper every day.
So they had this unalterable log of, you know, door events.
So I, I have a friend who was in university way back in the day and,
and computing power was very expensive back then.
And this is like mainframe days, right?
And they had a, a printout log of the door.
And so, and you had it like everyone, a key cards and to get in to the mainframe room,
you had to scan your key card
and then it were printed off on the printer that was locked up in,
like the administrators room.
They figured out
that
the printer would go offline. Well, it would jam up right
on a pretty regular basis and they figured out how to make it happen.
And so
they would basically badge in
and then open and close the door like a whole bunch of times
and then badge out
and,
and generally if they did that a few times the
printer would then jam up and it would quit printing
things and so then they could come and go as
they pleased and use the computer all they want.
Because for some reason, apparently they didn't have like a log on the computer.
They only logged the door use, which
they literally build you by door time. I
think it was billing as much as like they wanted
to know who is around and who is doing stuff.
And these guys were obviously like, this was back in the day, right?
They, they were up to stuff
so they didn't.
But anyway,
it's like this is, this is crazy.
You got to love it
or, or wasn't it? I think Richard Stallman has a story of how they used to.
They, they kept like the computer was locked behind a door,
but there was a drop ceiling and you could just like climb over the wall. So
I've seen that before in multiple places with the wiring closets and
it's a new comp site building they built at the University of Alberta,
uh to future proof that they ran cable trays because you know,
whatever cable you run is going to be wrong in five years.
-- I know less than that.
-- Probably these cable trays though are exposed publicly.
And I'm like, what if somebody comes in here with cable cutters and they're like,
just please don't.
Uh But in all seriousness, I bet the threat there is very, very low.
I mean,
somebody tying into a cable No, it's not.
No.
What I'd be worried about is some drunk guy hanging off the cable train, breaking it.
Exactly. Exactly.
That's like when you're in college you don't need fire,
fire drills because the people take care of that,
you get one every Friday night.
-- But
-- there's this ift tt stuff that, like, lets me, you know, tie.
So for example, I can,
you know, set up like a sleepover mode for my alarm system so that, you know,
say between 10 p.m. and 5 a.m.
you can't open any of the external doors without the alarm going off or something,
but you know, movement in the house is allowed or you know, whatever.
Um
and but the beauty is you can tie multiple
systems like essentially if it talks ift tt
you can tie stuff together with a very simplistic
programming language and there's like these recipes floating around
do
stuff,
Alexa
will talk to my skylink net and that's I'm going
to be setting that up in the next few days.
Sweet
-- Alexa,
-- cancel.
What are you yelling at it for?
Because it's trying to talk every time I say that
words
pretty much.
Oh, see, that's funny. You can't talk about Alexa
without Alexa
flipping out.
-- At least
-- I think I can change the keyword. Yeah, I can change the keyword
just like with, hey Siri,
I've got it set up for the home link
button now because otherwise all my devices are like,
I'm going to be helpful,
exploded.
Oh man, I actually that would be really funny.
I wonder if you went into like a dense downtown area
and you were on a show
like, hey Siri or hey Alexa
Siri typically is somewhat tied to your voice.
Like you, you say it a few times recorded but my with the,
with the, with the, with the Amazon one,
um like my son could use it immediately and it was, you know,
talking and responsive to him, which, you know, for a home device makes sense,
right?
Because it's shared among multiple people
and you'd want guests to be able to ask what time it is or whatever.
Interesting.
I like it, it,
-- it
-- isn't, it is,
it is very much weird and the future in that,
you know, should I be polite to this thing, should I say? Thank you.
I,
I hear that all the time that people are saying their Children are being mean to Alexa
and they want to,
they want to add like a plug in to make them say please. And thank you.
Yeah.
You know, I kept having to remind Felix that it was not
a person
right
to him. It's a voice that answers
questions
on the
side.
You just open it up and they're in there. Right?
Yeah,
like the uh like in men in black, the first one.
Right.
Exactly.
So I, yeah, no, it's, it's part of it is I've decided to adopt some new technologies.
Uh I'm still holding off on VR and A R for
at least a few more years till my kids are bigger.
But uh no, I'm going to do some,
I've decided to bite the bullet and eat some of this home automation sandwich and,
you know, see how it works
because especially at this price point, like 200 bucks, it's just, it's so cheap.
I,
I looked into this probably five years ago and there was
like a bunch of Z wave gear and it was,
it was going to be super hacky and I bought some of it.
In fact, it's in a box on my shelf somewhere,
-- but like it was, it was more work than it was worth and I gave up.
-- Oh,
yeah, for sure.
Yeah.
No, the Skylink net stuff is pretty limited.
Um,
what I'm really looking forward to is so IKEA
has some really nice stuff around light bulbs and light
and I wanna see, uh, number one, will it play with
the Amazon thing? I'm gonna have to change that keyword. That is super annoying.
Now that you've made me do that
great. I'm gonna have to, like, print out and laminate a card with a list of words.
-- I'm not allowed to see in my, in front of my computers.
-- Just turn off your Alexa.
It's way over there. Uh, there's no off switch. I don't think you have to unplug it.
Really?
Or maybe, well, maybe that's what the microphone mute button does.
Yeah, that's what microphone
does.
Um
I haven't really read the manual or anything.
Why read manuals, open it up.
I can talk to it. That's right.
How did it work to make it sync with Amazon?
Did it, like, ask you to speak at it or did you use a computer or what you do?
Uh you uh smartphone app?
-- Uh OK.
-- And I it was very simple. Like, it took like 30 seconds.
Gotcha.
So it does like Bluetooth or something to your phone, I assume.
-- Uh,
-- but basically you hop it, it open, it's,
it's one of those classic things where it opens up an insecure Wi Fi.
Ah,
and you connect to that insecure Wi Fi and then
the app does pokes at it and configures it to,
I'm making air quotes here to be secure and set up.
I have no idea what it did.
Um, Magic. You know, I told it my Wi Fi password. Hopefully, nothing bad happened.
It's connected to your Wi Fi now. Right.
-- Well,
-- because it has, it doesn't have, well, as far as I know it doesn't have a plug in.
-- It's Wi Fi only.
-- Right. Right.
Sweet.
So,
uh, yeah.
No, it's, but, yeah, I've decided to bite the bullet on some of the stuff,
but one of my rules is I'm only going to buy the cheap stuff because
I'm probably going to be disappointed at some point.
-- So I don't want to spend a lot of money on this.
-- I don't, I don't blame you for that.
Uh All right, man. I, I think,
I think we've discussed Alexa
and, and your home security system enough.
I'm sure you'll have plenty of stories to tell us in the near future.
Any parting words of wisdom or advice,
be prepared for disappointment when buying technology.
How about just in general? Right. Be prepared for disappointment in general.
I, I think, I think that's good advice. All right,
anyway. All right, Kurt. Thank you, sir.
Thank you everyone for listening. You can go to open
source security podcast.com for the show notes and the
links to our Facebook group. You can hit us up on Twitter with the Pound Os S Podcast.
Hashtag
and yeah, I guess nothing else. Kurt. You have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks, Josh.
Thanks everybody. Bye bye.