Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 84 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
So, the question for you today, Kurt is, have you been pawned?
I checked and the answer is no,
-- sure it is.
-- I
also made my partner
the
answer is yes.
Unquestionably. Right.
-- Oh,
-- no, I've definitely,
I've had several notifications from them but nothing important.
Oh, that's right. You have, you signed up for their service, didn't you?
I think you signed me up too
-- if I remember correctly.
-- Right.
So,
the topic of the day, I guess is there's a website called, have I been Pawned?
And you can go to it? And basically there's a security researcher named Troy Hunt
who collects
lots of information from data leaks when someone gets hacked and it gets dumped
on paste spin or the dark web or whatever you want to call it.
He collects it and he puts it all together and he very
recently put out what we'll call version two of his password list
and it is 500 million passwords in this list. It's a 20 gigabyte list.
It's even better than that.
-- It's also how common they are.
-- Yeah.
-- Which is super
-- cool.
Actually, I, I remember I pulled it down and I took a peek at it quick with,
with human eyes because it's, it's a text file
and the number one password was like 20 million uses was 123456. And then it, it's
very parabolic after that where it drops to like 6 million after 20 million.
Well, I would assume a pert
of distribution, you know, like
a
state
and then obviously there's like, I think, I want to say,
I read some things from Troy and it's like, 16 million passwords are only used once,
which is,
-- that's lower than I would expect.
-- But
I'm not super surprised because people will,
especially people that have been taught, you know, swapping
e for a three, whatever like that. Right.
Um, and most people will do sort of what
the minimum is to get their password accepted. Right.
So, I've been to way too many sites where it's like they, they pick some random,
almost always even number.
Like your password must be at least eight characters long or
10 or 12 or whatever.
I don't think I've ever seen an odd number minimum.
And then they're like, and it must contain at least one of the following. Right.
Like, you know, uh, what is it, a number, a capital and a special character?
And that's really, yeah,
that's really pretty much all the utmost they ever ask for because beyond a letter,
a number and a special character.
Oh, I guess emojis.
But, yeah,
haven't seen that yet.
Oh, speaking of which are there any emojis in there or what,
what format is the password f just to ask you text or?
Ok. So what, what Troy has distributed is
he sha
one
all of the passwords. And so obviously the password field is of uniform length
and then there's a colon and then there is a number and the
number is the number of times that particular password has been seen.
And
I understand why he did this because you don't want.
-- Yeah. So he doesn't get sued.
-- Well, maybe I, that, that could be
and I think there's something to be said about not
handing out like the greatest rainbow table in history.
-- Right.
-- True. Yeah. Well, and realistically the bad guys have
already, I mean, no offense, but it's not like he
spent millions of dollars and time and effort assembling this list.
Like he definitely spent quite a bit of time and effort assembling this list,
but it's all
free stuff. Yes.
Right. Like he's not buying password list on the dark web.
He's just,
he's not,
I know he spends some of his own money and obviously his time.
Well,
more to the point if like government and
state actors don't have an intern doing this.
They do now.
Yes.
Yes, indeed.
Well, and I think there's some some additional interesting tidbits to this is so
it's a single sha one
and that means you can reverse this without tons of effort
in, in many instances, like to give you an example.
So I,
I've got the database and I'm currently loading it into
elastic search because that'll let me search it quickly.
And what I'm gonna do then is write an application to just like brute force, right?
Start with A,
then B and,
and just kind of see how long I can let it run till I get tired of it and see
how many passwords I get where all I have to do is generate a string and sha one it,
which is going to take milliseconds on a modern system.
Well, that's somebody already did that for, remember the, the NT land.
In fact, they have every NT Landman password has been crank.
We should, we should also specify for people who might not know a rainbow table is.
Well, ok, let's start over
you. You have
a, a password is typed into a box and most systems,
the good ones don't store the password,
they store a hash of the password where you take the password and
you do something to it to scramble it in an irreversible way.
And generally it's a very CPU intensive operation because let's face it.
You don't want the bad guys to be able to crack these passwords super fast,
which Troy did not do.
It's going to be easy to crack these essentially.
And that's what you're going to have to do is crack them. Right. There's no salt.
There's, well, brute force them. Yeah.
Well, brute force.
Yeah, that's probably more accurate,
which is fine because that's also not his intention.
Well, and the main thing is though, with,
well, and the other thing too is, is this is getting to the scale of, like,
the Yahoo breaches where,
when, you know, if you're just, like, basically
trawling, like, in fishing terms, you're just putting out a huge net and like, uh,
whatever we scoop up, we scoop up, right?
We're not picky about what we grab.
So if, you know, like with the Yahoo or, you know, with, with some place where,
let's say you get
1010 encrypted passwords, whatever.
But, you know,
if you get 100 million encrypted passwords and you don't really
care about which ones you do or do not crack,
then you can definitely get
a
percent of them because they'll have bad
questionably.
They'll have 123456.
And that's, I think part of the problem here is that we're, we're,
I think we're back into that problem of large numbers where
a lot of security is based
on systems and principles that don't deal well with large numbers, right? Like
what Google does for account security versus what your ISP does,
you know.
And, and this is a great example of this like,
given even a minimal amount of cracking effort you're gonna find
-- tens or, well, not tens, hundreds of thousands of millions,
-- I think,
I think millions is more accurate.
And, and so the thing I keep thinking of here is it's kind of two fold,
first of all,
with half a billion
passwords
there is,
I think it's safe to say any human generated password is probably on this list.
Right.
I, actually, there's a bunch of that
-- were not that I was surprised about.
-- What do you mean?
Well, like I, uh what was it, password hard to,
I think was not breached.
But that's, that's more of a passphrase at that point.
That's the other thing, right? Is that?
Yeah? Ok. Let's, let me, let me change my statement.
Let's say any human generated password of,
we'll say 10 characters or less is almost certainly on this list.
Right. And, and I'm sure there are
passwords that are not,
but I, I think it's safe to say human suck passwords.
And, and this is unquestionably proof of it,
especially when you see 123456 use 20 million times.
Hang on one second. I'm trying to math in my head. I can't math in my head. So good
-- math is
-- hard. It's fine. It's super hard. Ok. What's uh uh
no, wait. Yeah. Ok. Hang on a sec. 83. Where's, where's the power button there? It is
uh 1.5 E 19
that's actually not an insurmountable number with a bunch of GP US.
It, it is not.
So that is theoretically every
uh key on your keyboard on a standard.
Let me rephrase that every key on a standard like us,
one on one keyboard that like makes character.
So letters, numbers and symbols is uh I believe it's
about, yeah, 80
ish whatever.
Uh
52. Yeah, it's about 80 ish characters and 90 ish characters in total
10 to the, or to the power of 10.
Uh,
and actually,
it's funny because you actually reduce the search
base quite a lot by having password requirements.
Like, it must contain a letter, it must contain a pass or a symbol because
90% of those passwords that are going to have a bunch of letters with one of those.
Oh, exactly. And I wouldn't be surprised if you say a minimum of eight characters.
You've just made 75% of your passwords, eight characters.
Right? I mean, that's just how people are.
Well, I mean, I've dealt with sites where I, you know, I use a password,
like I use last pass which has a password generator and the sites like, nope,
too long.
And I'm like, really, like, 8 to 12 or 8 to 10.
And then I just assumed that they're actually
storing the raw password at that point.
It, it could be, it wouldn't surprise me if, if they put a limit.
Well, if you're hashing the password. You don't care what is given to you.
I mean, within reason if somebody gives you a gigabyte of text,
it's gonna take a while,
you know, anything under 1000 characters.
Yeah. But I think if you cap it
-- right, cap it at 1000
-- a
1000 characters should be enough for anybody.
I, I, yes, famous last words. Right.
I, I remember there was a service I used once a long time ago
where
they let me enter.
I put in like a 32 character password, obviously from a password manager.
And then it chopped off like five of the characters or something.
And I remember I couldn't log in and for some reason, I thought, I bet,
I bet those idiots chopped off characters and, yeah,
I just kept removing one character from the password and then it let me in
and I was like, this is insane
if you're gonna do this at least warn people.
I mean, you know,
one thing I've noticed too is a lot more modern
websites don't make me enter my password twice just once.
And, and personally I think that kind of makes sense because
they,
you can just password reset or recovery if it's a problem.
Yeah. Right.
Right. Yeah, I, I've seen that a fair bit as well
and,
and so here's kind of the second part of this conversation I think is
people are bad at passwords and passwords. Probably need to go away.
Well,
actually it's worse than that because I was thinking about this and by definition,
a good password is,
has a high degree of entropy, right? We'll, we'll put a link to the XK CD comic on this
because I guess it's the week of XK CD.
And so by definition, a good password is kind of a pain in the butt.
And the second problem is by definition,
you probably need more than one good password.
Like for myself. My sort of critical passwords are
my Google,
um,
you know, administrative account for my domain
and then my icloud,
uh,
and then my last pass and those are the three absolute,
like super duper hyper critical and they're like long and a pain in the butt.
And then I have two fa I
enabled on all of those things
as well. And, and that basically is the second point of this is
by definition, if you're doing passwords correctly, you can't,
it doesn't work for humans.
Like I, because I have a, like, I actually, I use last pass now,
but I still have a spreadsheet with over 1000 accounts and passwords in it that I'm,
like, steadily migrating into last pass as time goes on.
And, you know, a lot of them are dead, which is great, but
most people have dozens or hundreds of
accounts scattered all over God's green earth.
Yeah,
it's, it's terrible and it drives me crazy when I go to a site
and they make me create an account instead of just
having like a button to use Google or something.
I
know it's,
you know, you know, what is the worst of all though?
Is I went somewhere the other day and they had a button to log in with Twitter
and I thought
that
your tweets.
-- Yes.
-- They want to be able to tweet as me. And it's like,
no. And see that's,
I think that's going to be the next thing is it's kind
of like it'll be a sandbox thing where like you're like,
sure app, you can have access to that.
And then on the Twitter back end,
you'll actually have the list of accounts and what they can actually do.
This is what Twitter is like. Oh, sure. Yeah, here's a tweet. Go look at that Lam
Ipsum, blah, blah, blah.
Y
-- you know,
-- and
I, I, I've seen this with Facebook as well.
I remember there was, there was an app I installed.
I want to post on my wall, my phone, right? I remember the app said
we promise not to do this and I thought just, no, you don't, right.
-- If you don't need it but don't ask for it.
-- Yeah.
Well, exactly. We promise not to do something that we explicitly
setting ourselves up to be able to do, but we promise we'll never abuse that.
That's insane.
Exactly.
And this is where I love how permissions work like on Android and I don't know if I OS
can do this but I can go into an
app settings and selectively deny access to certain things.
So for example,
-- uh Facebook wants to access my microphone. Nope. Right. Turn that off.
-- Yeah.
No, I OS allows you to do that as
well. Like for microphone, for camera, photo store,
cellular data, a bunch of other things. Yeah.
And the list is enormous on Android and I love
it because basically I go in and just like,
you don't need access to this stuff.
Go away.
Right.
Yeah. And then the next step is it'll somehow check and like,
out if you don't do it
right. I've had apps that do that
or well, or it's like the classic, you know, news site,
you either have to log in or you use your three free views this month.
And my response is,
-- you know, control w bye
-- bye.
I
agree.
I agree completely.
But
I mean, if the Facebook app did that, probably enough people would be like, uh,
-- you know, they would choose to live
-- with
it. I think they would.
And, you know,
it's the most infuriating thing for me is when
you get to like a news article and you start
reading it and then about halfway down it pops up the login page and I still close it,
but it's like extra angry.
I hate that. It's
so anyway,
but going back to this, I mean, fundamentally,
I think it really boils down to two things. One, if you're only
authentication is passwords, then already you've done it wrong.
You need to support two fa in this modern world.
And the real kicker is 222 factor authentication is not that hard to do anymore.
There's, there's free stuff, both for the servers and the clients,
right stuff you can.
And because the other thing too is everybody's
carrying around a small computer in their pocket,
right?
So you don't need to require tokens and stuff, you know, you can use open.
So
here's the deal is we love to say how everyone should be using two factor A
and I have a suspicion. Many listeners to this podcast are using two factor off,
but I read a statistic the other day that with like gmail,
it's 10% of users which don't get me wrong.
That's a lot of people, but that's a terrible number.
Oh, yeah.
Well, and that's the second argument Ashley is that you shouldn't,
ideally you should avoid doing accounts as much
as possible and let people use their existing
accounts that they use and care about.
Like Google, Facebook, Twitter, linkedin,
I think are sort of four of the big ones here in North America
for identity providers.
Um And please, for the love of everything don't ask for like
access to my Google Drive because no,
that's, that's the answer.
That will always be the answer
two. I mean,
because like at the cloud security lines, we do this because
we don't want the responsibility of having to take care of this data.
And especially now with, with GDPR,
like now we're really happy that we made that
seriously. Right. It's not your problem.
Yeah, it's like go yell at Google.
That's, you know, for account
information. That's our response. Like we know their email address
and if they choose to give us their first and last name, cool, they can do that.
But we don't require it in some things and other things we do. But
fundamentally it's like account security. Yeah, it's not our problem. It's this
huge company over here,
but hopefully is doing it correctly.
And I say that,
but then there's companies like Yahoo where
apparently they weren't doing it correctly.
I think it's safe to say they weren't based on data breach results. I mean,
-- I, I lost track. It was how many 100 million? It's a
-- lot
but they didn't get passwords. I assume I have a suspicion. They only got hashes.
Not that that's necessarily better.
So there, there's,
anyway, before we go down the Yahoo rat hole because that's too easy to do.
There's another thing that Troy
-- hashed passwords.
-- They are hash passwords. Ok. But
it probably,
and, oh, no, no. Also,
well, it says, and passwords for about 200 million people.
I'm going to hope that they were,
-- but it doesn't explicitly say they were hashed passwords in the 2016
-- hack.
Who knows? And, and it, it doesn't matter. Right, because let's face it.
Most of those hash passwords are so bad.
You can probably crack them in a couple of hours.
So here's the other cool thing
that have been po
has done is they work with cloud flare
and
they have this thing,
this service now where you can check your password against because let's face it.
Most people can't download
20 gigs of data and do anything useful with it, right?
And so you have the ability to kind of query their server.
But here's the cool thing is you don't send the password and
you don't even send the hash to them of your password.
What you send five characters of the hash,
what they've done is they took the basically you
take the first five characters of your hash your pa
you take the password, you ha you sha one hash it,
you get your sha one hash,
then you take the first five characters and send that to the service and say,
give me all of the passwords that start with these five characters.
And apparently the average result is like my brain tells
me like 500 ish give or take 450 somewhere in there
is the average result that you're going to get back.
And then obviously locally you can check is my hash one of these.
And that has a nice advantage because obviously,
if you type your password in somewhere
and then a service queries this
and someone's paying attention to what's being queried
or even Troy himself knowing what's being queried.
He can say, I know what password that person has.
And that's, that's a good, that's bad. Right. And he's smart enough not to want that.
And, uh, well, actually it's just a nice little, uh, 15 or so line
script that does this
and we'll post that.
I,
it's like, yeah. No, I, that's how I was checking my password.
It's uh it's nice to know. And that's the thing too.
Also, if your password is not in the database
now,
they only have the first five letters of the shaw one
hash or the first five characters of the shaw one hash,
which is,
I'm not going to say it's
completely useless, but it's basically
really
doesn't.
Yeah. Which is, which is super cool. They call it K anonymity
-- because you're only giving up a bit of
-- data,
which is the K value is the five characters apparently.
Yeah.
Yeah, this is, this is something really cool and this is very clever, I think and,
and I give these guys a lot of credit because they could have definitely
done this the wrong way. And, and even though
I have a suspicion they're,
they're on the side of good and would not capture this data,
the,
the opportunity doesn't even exist, which is awesome.
So, here's a question that's probably gonna result in something? But
should websites
use this api
to check if the password you're putting in has been breached?
You know what I was thinking about this?
And
I think the answer is no,
I think what websites need to do
is
let you put it in,
potentially warn you and ask you to set up two factor off
because that's actually the right answer. Right.
I fear that the correct answer is also the answer where a lot of sites are not.
Here's the reality, right?
A lot of sites are built on older technologies where they just,
they can't easily retrofit two fa onto it without some serious effort.
Like apparently my bank,
most Canadian banks don't do two fa they,
they claim to do multi factor authentication in the form of like, oh, what's your
dog's name or whatever? And it's like
these have the exact same failure mode as my password. Thank you. Awesome.
Well, not only that, most of this information,
if you pay attention to someone's Twitter or Facebook profile,
you can probably figure it out.
Right.
Yeah.
And so I fear, I, I think you're right.
We should at a minimum, check their password and warn them
maybe with like a little infographic that explains
kind of what the heck's going on because,
you know, if they take their password into a site and says it's been breached,
they're gonna, you know,
it may not have been their instance of that password that was breached. Right.
They just picked a password that somebody already picked up.
The other part of it is if, if you're a normal person and you made that password up,
it's, it's on this list, I almost guarantee it.
I mean,
that's the reality of it.
If, if, if you're using a password manager and it's completely random,
it might not be on the list.
But I think anything a human can think of is almost certainly on this list.
500 million. That's crazy.
Well, as far as passwords go, as far as pass phrases go,
I was trying some simple ones wrapped around the word password and,
and quite a few of them were not in there.
And so I think that's interesting to me is
that people aren't even using simple pass phrases.
Like, uh, you know, this password is hard to,
most people don't use pass phrases because I have a
suspicion when you go to a website and it says
your password has to be a minimum of eight characters.
They don't think about pass phrase. They think about, I need eight characters.
What am I gonna use? 12345678, done. Right. Yeah,
still doesn't support it. Good Lord. Td still doesn't support it.
Yeah, for some reason, banks in Canada just do not do two factor authentication.
It drives me nuts. I have no idea why.
-- Maybe there's some banking regulation hidden somewhere.
-- It's possible.
It's,
it's more likely they have systems running on
Cobal and it will be too difficult to implement
for sure,
for sure. But, I mean, so do a lot of other banks.
Uh, yeah. Yeah, some of them, it's,
I'm not going to say it's easy because authentication can be difficult to do.
And, and not only that,
this is, uh, I was,
I was talking to a friend about this
the other day is authentication for most organizations.
Like, it's not, it's not their primary focus. It's not what makes them money. Right.
-- It's just a part of
-- the product. It's
-- a pain in the butt
-- for them. Right. And, and they probably let the intern write it.
And so, and, and more often than not, it's most of these places that do it wrong.
It's not that they're malicious or necessarily stupid.
They just, they don't know what can happen.
And most of the time if you explain this to people in about five minutes,
they're like, ah, I get it and now I understand why I shouldn't do that thing.
Right.
So, it's,
I, I wish there was an easy answer. Right.
-- I, it would be nice if there was,
-- well, I mean, one simple, easy answer would be,
uh,
well, I think kind of what Google is doing with their deprecating, well,
not deprecating, but they're going to be warning about http being insecure.
I'm pretty sure Chrome is smart enough to know when you're entering user name.
And password because actually the other day I saw the http insecure thing
because I went to my little, um,
I have a little machine that does torrent for
like these eight gig password files and stuff.
And it's got just basic HTTP authentication to log into the transmission client.
Right?
I haven't bothered putting a certificate on it
because it's internal to my whole network.
So I log in
and I get
that big insecure word in front of the URL.
So for example,
Chrome could choose to do this when you're
entering a user name and password and then not
entering like a
six digit number or you know, whatever other thing, then it could warn you like, hey,
you just entered a user name and password.
I'm not seeing any two factor authentication going on,
you know,
did something happen on your phone because it's so cool and more to the point,
it would be easy to whitelist the sites that
do this like you would very rapidly find out.
-- Right.
-- Maybe I, I don't think this is a terrible idea. I mean, I will admit there's
a lot of sites where
it either kind of brings you to another screen or it will,
it'll,
it'll pop up a thing on my phone sometimes and ask
me questions or it might send me a text message or,
or whatever.
But
in all seriousness,
I,
I think the power in doing something like that would be the
awareness factor because a lot of people don't know about this stuff.
I mean, like to give you an idea is
I, I was talking to someone the other day and, like,
they didn't even know what an ad blocker was and I thought, how do you not
know this?
They installed it immediately,
completely
different.
The
workers are easy to sell it. It's funny that way.
-- Right.
-- But it's like
in our world we've been using these things forever.
But in normal people, world, they don't even know this exists.
It's,
it's crazy to think about. And like,
if normal people don't know what an ad blocker is,
how on earth are they gonna even understand two factor authentication?
Right?
Or, or the fact that their passwords are terrible or to use a password manager or
it's awareness is
it, it is an
enormous part of this problem.
And, and there are so many people who just don't understand
the, the whole awareness aspect of these. And so
like this is where I give, give things like, have I been pulled a ton of credit?
Because
essentially this is an awareness program.
Oh, Lord. Can you imagine if Google changed it?
So every time you type in a password field, it checked this database and warned you
that could be fun.
That could be really fun.
Something.
-- I bet you. Is there a plug in that? Does that yet?
-- I bet we could write one.
It would be,
you could
write one. I mean, it's 15 lines of ash
and there's already stuff while you just look at the password,
probably two megabytes of plug in framework.
Two megs seems like it would be on the low end.
I, I do always love when you try to spin up like a simple web app these days or,
yeah, I've got two, like, hello World and then two megabytes of crap to make it run.
It's great.
But, uh, yeah.
No, I mean, something like that, you know, that's the thing that gets me right.
Is that what you put in front of people? Which is basically nowadays the web browser,
right. That's it. That's what's in front of people's faces.
There is so much potential there for good.
Yeah, seriously.
And I have a suspicion that's part of why Google
is doing this http S thing is because they,
they, they can't protect
well. Right.
I mean, there's,
there's other reasons behind it but the fact is like they have the faces of people
and so they can do amazing things
-- with that and, and thank goodness they're, they're doing good things
-- well.
And part of it too is like the,
the,
the power of a million people complaining.
That's something that companies will actually fix it just to
make the complaining stop because it's expensive to handle the.
Oh,
yeah.
Right.
Oh, man, there's, there's so many things I've done that with. Like,
I, I remember there, there have been security bugs
in various products and applications that, that, like, they,
they didn't really matter or you weren't vulnerable but
you just fix it to shut people up.
It's like I'm sick of people telling me my, my thing is vulnerable to this.
It's not because I don't use that, but I'm gonna fix it just so you go away.
Yeah.
Well, it's, and often times it's less effort to just fix it than it is to
keep explaining it for the next five years to customers and their auditors. Why?
-- It's not a problem.
-- Exactly. Exactly. And,
and I guess that's,
that's maybe the trick is we need people
complaining about wanting two factor off and,
and single sign on authentication to various websites and, and nobody is right.
In fact, there's, there's a handful of websites
that I use that.
I'll,
I'll shoot him an email every now and then and say something like
you should let me log in with Google or you should use two factor
author or whatever.
-- And if they reply, I would
-- say that to my
bank but they're
not,
they don't care.
But, but right, in the rare instance they reply,
it's clear they think I'm a crazy person and now they're not wrong,
but not for this reason.
Right.
Exactly.
But again, if, if they're only hearing from one dude,
that's
probably a crazy person. Right.
If you hear from half your user base now it's something you need to take seriously
and it's,
I don't envision this changing quickly.
I have a feeling what would drive change is if we can get someone like,
like web browsers to,
like you said,
maybe query this database and start telling people your password is on a list.
Hopefully you're using two factor off.
Yeah, I think that's about it. That's all we can really say.
Indeed.
II, I will say though,
I'm excited to get this list all sorted out so I can
see what kind of fun goodies are hidden away in it.
Yeah, I'm just, what also makes me wonder is this is the stuff that he found,
like, publicly as it were.
-- I mean, I'm just wondering how much stuff is out there actually
-- way more, way,
way more
and,
and not just that there's obviously illegal things
where people maybe hacked something or whatever.
Right. And, and it's there
and it's potentially very dangerous and, you know,
there's places that aren't hashing the passwords where, where,
you know,
essentially criminals have plain text of your user name
and password and if you're reusing that password,
like,
yeah, you lose, man.
Well, especially if it's the top million or whatever. Right. Right.
Well, man, I'll never forget, like some years ago it was, uh,
I think the full disclosure mailing list before it was the old
full disclosure because it died at one point and then came back,
uh, the guy who owned it, sent me an email one day and was like, hey,
someone's trying to log in as you with this password.
And I looked and like it was,
I used the same password for all my mailman subscriptions for the most part,
except full disclosure for some reason.
And I was like, oh man, I better, I gotta change all my mailman passwords now.
And, and
that's,
that's also when I started using a password manager because I thought
the only reason I was doing this because I was too lazy
to keep track of all my mailman accounts.
And
yeah, it's, it's crazy, man. I mean, that, that's the sort of thing, right? If,
if you never have an experience like that, it can be difficult to justify some of the,
the cost because let's face it.
Things like a password manager do come with a cost. It's pretty low these days.
It's, it's your time.
But, but it is there.
Well, more of the point you have to know they exist.
You have to know which one is good because there's a bunch of them out there.
They're terrible. Like straight up
-- here
-- now, here's a question is a,
is a bad password manager better than no password manager.
I'm, I'm leaning towards,
I'm going to be a jerk and I'm going to say it depends.
That's fair.
-- I'll accept that answer
-- because some of them will be
bad in a way that's subtle and difficult to exploit.
And some of them are just bad.
-- They're just,
-- that's true. That's true.
That's fair. That's fair. I guess. I guess it depends. This is where
picking on some of the, the bigger ones might be better. Just because
when, when a problem is found they will take it more seriously as they have
one of my number,
that's one of my number one
constraints for choosing software and services is not how secure are they,
but how do they respond to security incidents
and how quick that's fair
because the reality is no matter what I pick,
they will at some point have a problem, it might not be ever publicly known.
Like, like the fact that, you know, like Google,
they definitely get attacked and probably some of
those attacks get halfway in or more.
Oh, man,
I mean,
Google can't be un hackable. That's just,
that's not how reality works.
So,
you know, but from what I've seen of Google, they have like a massive,
uh,
internal security effort process people, everything,
you know, the, the fact that they pay for,
you know, project zero doing things like, like Tavis is, you know,
looking now at installer applications because let's face it.
Right. Like something like, what was it, Starcraft,
you know, they have an installer
that has like remote code execution, I think a flaw in it.
And, you know, that's a, hundreds of millions of machines
now.
Right.
And some of those, and those machines too are like gaming machines.
Which have like some real
do
not like that
iot like where it's, you know,
a three watt chip we're talking about things that are consuming, like, you know,
that's a 200 watt CPU with like four GF
or
-- some serious Cryptocurrency mining with that.
-- Right.
Well, 100 million of those.
Indeed. Indeed. All right, man, I think we should probably call it.
This is, I guess for what it's worth folks. Uh, check out, have I been pwned.com?
We'll put a link in the show notes and, and see if you've been ped and,
and even if your password doesn't show up there, you should, uh, be afraid.
Right. That's just living constant fear. That's, that's the easiest way.
All right, cool. Thanks. Kurt. Thanks everybody. Yeah. Hit up open
source security podcast.com for the show notes, UZ Pound Os S podcast.
Hashtag to get our attention and you have nothing else.
Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks.