Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Pressers.
Today's the day, I'm excited.
We have Toma De Pierre, the author of, I am not a supplier on the show. Toma.
Welcome to the show. I can't wait.
Hello, everyone. Thank you for having me.
We have been waiting for quite some time to talk with you about this
and we have been talking, you know, on social media and all that stuff.
So it will be interesting.
-- Oh, it's going
-- to
be so good. All right.
So let's just,
I will let you explain what you wrote and we will go from
there because you lit the world on fire with your blog post.
I'm in, I, I don't know if I lit the world on fire, but like that was kind of the point,
right?
I was getting pissed off.
Uh I've been getting pissed off about this whole discussion for quite some time.
So the blog post I wrote is basically basically what I write here
is I,
I wanted to talk about the whole discussion around the um software supply chain,
right?
Which is a tool, especially if you are around the infosec world.
It's a,
it's a term you have probably heard a lot in the past few
months or even a couple of years for a lot of reasons.
And,
and I have a lot of problem with it because,
and so what I wrote in that is that I think that the term is fundamentally
problematic to use because for open source software, at least
because as open source maintainers and as people that, that use open source,
we are not in a supply relationship, right?
We are not in a supplier
um relationship where you are,
we are providing you something even that is kind of a problematic word.
And so the whole discussion was around trying to explain
what the supply chain the software supply chain ID is because
I talk to people that may not have heard of the term
and then explain what a supply chain is usually
in the way we think of it
in manufacturing because I've spent some time manufacturing
and explaining why I don't think it apply here and why
it is kind of a problem to use it that way.
And something we may talk later is that I think it's
even counterproductive and that's something we may want to talk about.
It's funny because I actually thought when I read that title immediately,
my brain went to the, you know,
Sinon
pipe like this is not a pipe just because
you produce software and freely give it away. That does not make you a supplier.
Like in my mind, that supplier,
well, for there to even be a relationship, a relationship implies a two way street.
In my experience, the vast majority of open source programmers,
they have no idea who's using it software, let alone have ever spoken to them.
And so, yeah, like you, I, I looked at this and I'm like, well, yeah,
this sort of seems self evident but,
well, I guess it's not.
And I think there's another thing here, we, we, which we, we,
we tend to forget because it's so fundamental and really talked about
you were talking of the two way street.
It's not even a one way street because as the person that write the software,
I put it up.
But I have no
by definition in every single free open source license, I
disclaim all liability,
right? The software is provided as is
I at no point.
Is there even a one way, I don't know who you are,
but you don't need to know anything about me.
And I am explicitly getting rid of anything that could link this to me,
right?
So by making it 300
souls, I'm cutting this relationship.
I want to pick on you now because this is something you and I,
I think might have briefly argued about at Mastodon is it's easy to say
that you owe nothing and you will do nothing unless you feel like it.
But as you pointed out to me,
you need to sleep at night.
So if you have an open source project and it has,
let's say a critical vulnerability that, you know, is affecting,
say every Java application on earth, you're not going to just be like, screw it.
I'm out. You're going to do what needs to be done because you're a good person.
Yes.
But that's not based on the relationship that's based on me and my own
decision about how I do my life and why I did this thing,
right?
Where? But that's also we have a problem, right?
That's where we have a fundamental discussion around the
way we govern and handle this kind of work because
I don't have to do it.
But I think I, I will do it for all these things you talked about, right?
I need to sleep at night and there is more discussion we can have on this because I have
a few ideas and things I think can make
sense to bring here to explain to our listeners.
But at the same time,
we cannot as a society expect me to do it.
Maybe it's perhaps part of the problem here
is the framing of the discussion because I'm thinking
essentially both sides want the same thing.
But the open source person does it for intrinsic motivation, self motivation.
And the external party is saying, no, you have this obligation,
you have this extrinsic motivation to do it.
And I think maybe this is part of the problem because fundamentally the majority of
people want the same thing which is like bug fixes and security updates and,
you know, releases.
But
it's one of those subtle things where, so basically what you're saying,
what I'm hearing is that you're doing it for intrinsic motivation
and that you don't give a, you do not care about the extrinsic motivation of like, oh,
it's the right thing to do because it serves the world or blah, blah, blah.
Would, would that be correct?
No. Uh
I, I think there is a difference here
and I think because I think
we cannot say that people don't do that because it helps the world, right?
An example I would bring here is I have high doubt
that the people that on
all the time zone database,
right?
Which is basically two people doing it voluntarily.
And that's kind of an interesting discussion to have to do that
for fun.
I mean, they do it, I mean, it's complicated, we can get that
but I don't think they do it for fun, right?
I mean,
part of this is because they are interestingly they like this thing
and they like the whole complexity and expertise they have in this,
but they also do it because they know they have an impact and
that's something that is, I think
general for engineers, right? Is that a lot of engineers, I don't mean everyone.
Right.
But other engineers do this because even in the very small part, we do the thing,
right? Even if our job as engineers to work on
a coffee lid, right.
There are engineers that spend thousands of hours on engineering,
a better coffee lead.
We know that it's going to be useful and help people.
So I think that's not the inspiration.
I think you are. Right.
So,
in talking about the framing and I think the problem here is that
we frame it as an open source free and open source software problem.
And I think that's the wrong framing
because I think
yes, most of this case, we are caring a lot about for
security and all that stuff
are
free and
software
like not all of them but a lot of them.
But I think
the causality is not that we can the
security because there are performance or software,
they are free
software
because they are digital infrastructure because they are
the things that allow us to create things.
And so they end up everywhere
and
to enable them to be everywhere and have we, we can have a whole,
I have a whole idea explaining how we got that,
but
they are everywhere
and the fact they're everywhere
fools them to be free and open source.
Because if they were not,
we would have to manage so much commercial relationship
to just make a basic product
that we would not be able to create that product,
right?
And so we end up in the situation where all of
this as two governments also wind up with open source everywhere.
And then we have the discussion of how do we manage,
maintain and govern that body, that shared body of infrastructure.
And that's why I think the the that's kind of why I think the supplier relationship is
problematic is because
we can't get, we can't not have them,
right?
If you are a supply, if you supply crews, I worked for some time in car manufacturing.
If you supply crews to a scout
manufacturer
and they don't like what you produce,
they can go to a competitor,
they can change the through. It's relatively standard on
all
the
of software is that there is not really
any competitors for some of these bad infrastructure.
It's just the same everywhere
and there's a lot of reasons why, right. There's not that much variants
and there are a lot of good reasons why, mostly because it's really,
really hard to produce just one.
So producing two is nearly impossible for society
at the call that we accept right now.
And that's also can be a discussion can.
And so there is not really a supply chain relationship because quite realistically
like
everyone depend on, on the few people at open SSL everyone depend on open SSH,
everyone depend on bin for B GP and DNS and all that stuff, right? Like you
everyone depend on
um
we implement the NTP protocol and the GP sds that sync it with GPS data,
like all that stuff,
we all depend on a few people and a few specific library and there is not really any
competition you can have, right?
So
like when we frame it as a supply chain thing,
we are
missing that part because
I think II I finally found some data on this um in the Atlantic Council,
the city of few uh report that was published recently.
So they publish a few things
in
a random software product.
Any commercial software product you buy today,
80 to 90% of the code in it
will be free and open source software.
-- I think the number they said was 87%.
-- You see what I mean? Right? Like
you can't just say that this is a supply chain relationship at this point because
like this is all of it.
Like
it's a whole product. But uh we and
why we are in this mess
is because we cannot cut part of it.
Uh It's not like
like if you're in carf
touring, for example, the
infotainment system, right?
The systems that do your radio and your music and all that stuff in the middle, right?
This big piece machines that run in the middle come from a supplier.
It's really invented and, and created by
the cacs
themselves, they will tweak them a bit and all.
But there's a lot that come from the supplier
and so you can pick your supplier depending on what you want it to be able to do.
Sometimes
in software.
We don't forget that choice for nearly all the of three open source software we use,
we have to use it because otherwise we can't even create
the thing we need because there is so many fundamental basic capabilities
that are only realistically provided by these fronts
and Softwares that are shared by everyone.
-- Yeah.
-- No, I I remember paying money for the OS TCP/IP pack from IBM.
And,
and even there's a good example of like there, there was only the one option
like it's not like there was a market for two of these
and try to go in a market to buy a TCP/IP uh stock these days.
Yeah,
I mean, I'm,
I'm still actually kind of shocked that there are commercial TLS implementations.
There's a few floating around.
I just sure, I mean,
they are
infinitely
small on the market, right?
So in practice, like the end of the rating for nearly every part of the stack, right?
You can find
you, you can especially on servers, it's a bit different on desktop but,
but on servers which is a vast majority of what we deal with and even
on phones, which is a vast majority of the device these days,
you don't pay for the bugger.
Not anymore. No, no,
not anymore.
But partially this is because the
commercial one could not keep going because they were depending on so much.
Is there is so much we expect we, we take for granted.
Right. Like, could you imagine
having to pay for unicode handling?
-- No, I
-- think part of the challenge is,
and this came up with the, you know, when we talked with the lets encrypt
is that even if they charge a penny, that's such a huge barrier to entry.
And I'm just thinking like even a desktop.
So relatively quote unquote simple system, you know,
if I had to pay for, yeah, TLSATLS library, not just a server but
yeah, for all these core
like NTP, like you mentioned or, or a bind resolver.
Like I'm just thinking now when I bought the OS two TCP/IP pack,
I guess it was sort of implicit that they also gave
me DNS support because now that I say it out loud,
it's like, well, it's TCP/IP. Oh, you want a DNS as well? That's another one.
And I actually did, in fact have to pay for the NFS pack as well.
Like I bought the TCP/IP pack and the NFS pack. It's about 400 bucks.
And now my OS two machine could talk to my Linux machine and then
I eventually decided to just go with Linux because it all came for free.
Ok. I wanna, I wanna bring us back to, to something Tomas said
you compared open source to infrastructure,
which I think your description of you have to use it is reasonable
because like my favorite example is we'll say roads or the electric grid.
It's easy to say, oh, I could do it myself. But the reality is you can't,
you have to use the public infrastructure that exists.
But in the context of infrastructure,
infrastructure is
heavily regulated by the local government. Generally speaking.
Well,
the generally speaking, make a lot of heavy lifting
-- and, and I
-- think that's,
-- that's my weasel word
-- out.
And,
and I think so the first thing I want to point out is that not open sources like that,
right?
Like open
source.
And, and that's kind of why III I try to stop talking of open source security as a, as a,
as a old topic.
And I think that's, that's when we compare to party open source can be anything,
right?
If I write a small library that, uh,
change the color of a web page because that's
what I wanted to show to my daughter or something
that and I publish it. This is open source, right?
And basically no one care about that. And there's a lot of project like that. Sure,
I can do a small training project to explore something.
And so, and no one care about that.
And that's a lot of open source libraries out there, right?
But already that they also sell the ones that are not used that much,
but it doesn't matter.
Right.
So, and,
and that's kind of why I try to not talk
about open source as something that is so important.
II I emphasize the in fact
part because
I think the part we came about when we talk about security is that part,
right? It is that particular part that we use that is everywhere.
And that is now fundamental because you can build whatever you want.
If the libraries that on
your image
as a security so bad that you get rooted when you receive an
iMessage,
I am definitely not calling out a particular case here.
Um
Like
you can build all the sandbox you want if just receiving the
iMessage and discovering that there is an image in it is enough
to route the whole phone and give access to the attack.
Like the sandbox doesn't matter at this point, right?
So
and, and that's kind of why I think and so
so first that that's the first bit I would bring
the second one that bring us to a discussion I think about the comments,
right? Which is a sentence that people in open source we have heard before, right?
The so called tragedy of the comments. I I did hair
cut here for people listening at home.
Um And, and what that thing is that
the idea of the community itself has a lot of sense, right?
This idea is that as a group,
you have a shared resource or shared capabilities, right?
Something that benefit to everyone that need to be managed right and governed.
The tragedy of the country is a particular
discussion around that, that explains that if it's shared,
but anyone profit but no one you know, is responsible and everything,
then things do not get done.
Uh This tragedy of the commons has been
so thoroughly debunked by sociological research that does not really work that way
because what happened
is that when you have a, a group share the result that is important and they organize
to handle it.
And one of the way as we were talking about is go,
right.
That's one of the way we have found as a group to organize,
to manage a common and government tend to appeal
because we have something in common to manage.
Right? It's not a magical thing that come down and all it. And so
when you talk about, they tend to be regulated.
Yes.
That's because as a group,
we decided to regulate it because we needed them to be regulated.
We decided that was how we were going to govern and manage them.
Right.
But there's a lot of station when that's not the case,
right?
If you share, I don't know if you buy a lawn mower with your neighbor and you share it,
which is not something that never happened.
You probably don't need the government to regulate that.
You just work together on that. Right?
And, and there is a lot of situation like that.
-- Well,
-- but there would still be, for example,
civil law that would regulate that to some degree
at a high level.
I mean,
yes,
in practice,
if you just enter in an agreement with your neighbor to share the law more,
one of you will buy it and you will give you money and
basically you on civil laws that will not be really beyond it's yours.
But it's a use case. It's definitely,
if you want to
handle it properly through all kind of law,
you would have to create a corporation to deal with that
because that's the way we introducing. Right.
No,
what I'm saying is if I enter into a verbal agreement with Josh to share a lawn mower,
that
is a verbal agreement, it's a contract and now there would be civil law and stuff.
But I mean, and that's sort of at a meta level,
it always kind of reminds me of one of the roles
of government is to sort of be like parents and like,
ok, Children
try to work it out yourselves and if you can't work it out,
then we'll step in if we have to, but we would prefer not to.
It would be nicer if you two could just work it out and not bug us,
you know, just share the hot dog and be done with it. But I think you
see, and the other thing I,
I with respect to the whole tragedy of the
commons is the one thing I've always noted is that
you can't sort of overuse software. Like,
I mean, well, ok, in theory, if too many people downloaded it,
that could be a problem like the site crashes, but we'll ignore that.
And the one thing that does, I,
I keep coming back to is this sort of idea of responsible and sustainable use.
Because for example,
while if I just download the software and never bug the person again,
a million people can do that.
But if I download the software and then start making demands from that person,
well, that's not going to be fun for him if you know 100 people do that.
I guess what I'm saying is I don't think the tragedy of the commons works per se
but that it does maybe have some cautionary tales for us to consider.
I think the mistake here is to consider that it's a software that
is a resource and that we will need to make it sustainable.
I think the, because the comments is not about or
source by itself, it can be a
lot of things.
And I think in part, in this case, the the the mistake is to consider that, I mean,
the mistake, I don't know.
But the way we think of it
is that the software need constant work
and that's something that has not always been
appreciated and accepted, especially by free and open source communities.
But if you look at what we know about software engineering,
especially software engineering.
In the reality of today,
software
once produced,
we can copy it as much as you want, right? You can make copy for free.
That's the great thing about software
that does not mean that the way the software works
is good and will keep being good
and, and that sounds dumb because you think yes, the source code is the same,
the code is the same.
Why we bit rot, right?
It's not going to rot like a piece of, of, you know, food or something.
The problem is that software is fundamentally contextual software
only makes sense in a part when it's,
it's created
with a certain context in mind with a certain way to use it with a certain way
with a certain kind of hardware that will run
it with a certain kind of environment around it.
This environment is not static.
Quite the contrary, the more you use it,
the more this environment tend to change because another
character of software is that it changed its own environment
now that unicode is hand everywhere because a lot
of people spend a lot of time on this.
Well, now everyone expects unicode everywhere.
And if you don't have emojis, people will get hungry,
right?
And so, right?
Like and, and not only emojis,
but they will want custom emojis pretty fast
and that's not handled by the Unicode consortium.
So you better sit down and invent a new way
to do things otherwise you're going to have problems,
right?
And now all the F
ring that has done all this work for Unicode,
they have to deal with that and they are probably not ready for it, right?
And we get in this cycle because software fundamentally change the game,
right? It gives you new tools and that tool change what you can do. So now you need
the tools to change with you. And so we end up in the situation where
by definition of existing and being used
and the more it's used, the more it's true,
the more the software needs work and maintenance.
So we still have this kind of problem, right?
The other reason being that
usually and that's also something we can,
we, we, we, we are getting slightly better at
the software
as written when we talk about fixes,
right? We talk about fixing bugs,
usually fixing bugs is not going in and changing it and for
all
or doing a small obvious change,
right? That happens, right?
Sometimes something that should be superior or equal,
we just write to that superior and that's a problem.
But usually what we discover when we need to fix a bug, right
is that
you need to fundamentally change
how the software work.
-- I mean, worse, you have to actually define what the correct behavior is,
-- right.
Yeah.
Oh, maybe there is multiple and then you need to undergo multiple, right?
But the reality is that changing
this fundamental reality of what the software is, right?
Usually need a huge body of the knowledge of how it already works.
And also of all the techniques that you're going to need to get that.
And if you don't have that, then the time to get need also,
you need also to be able to acquire that, which is also a pretty long time.
Usually it's quite expensive.
And so you get in this situation where yes, technically we cannot overuse it,
but also
it does need a baseline of maintenance
and that baseline of maintenance if it's used tend to grow.
And that was, I mean,
right now, for a lot of front
or software does not exist.
And so that's where we get into the problem
of security. Like the, the look for shell case is visible lately, right?
Like log for J if you talk to the maintenance,
they would have loved to get three of the capabilities that was used for this escape
a long time ago.
But once they have a limited time,
two, they don't really know how people use it,
but also like they don't have time to deal with the
impact if they delete it and people can deal with it.
And they did not really know
how they could provide an equivalent use case,
right? They have done a lot of work and so they couldn't do it.
So they just kept it kept it around.
And so we get in these situations where as a society, we want all these things,
right?
We want this baseline of capabilities for tools,
we want encrypted communications, right?
Like this
definition, we want that
what we have not answered as society so far is how do we get that?
How do we maintain that and how do we
make sure that this level happen and is sustainable?
And so I, I, so that's why I try to walk down a bit from the
using,
right is using resources and consuming resources because I think at this point,
the same thing with a road, right?
I don't exactly consume a road when I use it.
I mean, I kind of do uh you know,
there is all kind of situation where I do have impact and that's managed.
But usually if I go walk on the road on a paved road,
I'm not going to do that much damage,
but it does need maintenance because there are
all kind of external parameters that impact it,
right?
And that's why I pay taxes and all that stuff,
despite the fact that I don't use it that much.
And
that's a discussion we have not have
for
digital infrastructure
and partial is because it's so new,
right? This is the description we have we are having right now,
but that's kind of why I got it.
So I like the way you split the difference between kind of using and maintenance.
And I think the Atlantic Council report does a nice job of this as well where they,
they kind of treat the using of open source like the,
the water system
in the context of like anyone can go and use it.
But obviously, if you pollute it and make a mess now no one can use it.
And the maintenance aspect, they,
they use infrastructure as a good example where something like
maintaining roads
isn't really a profit center.
And so it's one of those things that like, if a government doesn't do it,
there's really no way you're going to have economically viable roads. Right.
Well, I mean,
I've played simcity and that's the first thing you cut back
and then everything goes all to hell in a hand basket.
But the other thing I'm thinking of is is there's almost a,
there's this positive feedback loop as, as a project becomes better,
it becomes more used and it has to interoperate with more things.
So, a great example of this is like lip curl, lip curl handles, like
every
horrific corner case
that we know of.
And as a consequence, it is horrific,
like it is really complex and there's a lot of subtle stuff in there.
And so, yeah, for somebody to come in and maintain, you know, I'm always, uh,
Josh is gonna hate this, but like to quote unquote,
fix a pothole in the road is not just fill it with cold patch and walk away.
Right. Like it is to properly fix a road.
I love how people complain about roads when they're being properly fixed because it
takes like a week or two because you have to like tamp stuff down,
let it settle, tamp it again.
You know, we had a new overpass that was built and
a year later there's like these 1 ft,
like 30 centimeter, like
lumps in the road basically
that they're like, yeah, that's normal. That was expected.
And we're just gonna have to fix it because it takes time for all the soil to settle.
And I did actually some research on the soil settling and it turns out
like if you want to build something,
say 6 ft high and 100 m long and have it not settle and move.
It is just so complicated, it doesn't even bear discussion.
Um
And I mean, that's where all this good software like log for J is going.
But I also worry that sometimes these maintainers, for example, I'll pick on log
for J.
They were worried about the impact of removing this
dangerous feature in that people might be using it.
And my thought is
well, too bad like because if you are using this feature, maybe
need to step up
and support it
or pay for it.
Um Another great example, remember Open SSH had that remote key exposure thing
and it was in a feature that a company
could kind of asked for to support ssh roaming sessions
that it turns out.
Well,
nobody ever used and we know nobody ever used
it because we actually never had client support.
So it was just dead code on the server
that, you know, then they finally removed and the prom went away.
And so I can't help but think maybe people
have created this trap for themselves by being too nice by being too generous
and doing everything that these companies want and say,
OK,
that's exactly.
I think Josh,
you may remember I reacted to that same argument you had for the first time.
You talked about my blog post.
I think it was the ecology discussion, pollution discussion.
And you ended up in something quite like that and I reacted a
bit harsh and thats the thing where we discussed of guilt. I think
so I'm going to be really nice and try to use.
So I spend a lot of time in researching safety science
and with a lot of people that work in that field.
So we are talking field like, you know, uh airplanes, pilots, um ship railways,
nuclear power plant, chemical plants, all that stuff, right?
And
there have been a drive in a part of the committee, particularly in the
S and SRE software community uh to get some links to
these people because we feel that there is AAA Kindling here,
right?
One of the things we discovered from safety science
is that there is something true across every
single safety critical industry they have looked at,
which is that
when you ask for a report or an explanation or analysis
of a problem of an incident or something like that,
it always end up the story,
the narrative always end up
at
a human, took the wrong decision.
And usually this is explained in terms that we use could would or should.
And
there is a whole body of research on that kind of things.
And what this body of research says usually is that this
is really practical to find a reason for what something happened.
But it's really really rarely
achieve a change.
Like it is a great way to explain a cause of how something happened,
but it has really resulted in changes that make things better.
And so what happened is that the safety science researcher call this a first story,
right? It's the first story you get when you do your analysis
and then there is a whole body of research on what they call second story,
which is the stories that start
at this decision that was made by the people, right?
Usually what they call the sharp and the people that are the
forefront of the decision making. And
you start your story here and then you start here and you start asking questions like
how did that make sense at the time?
What was the constraint and pressures they were dealing with?
What were the way they were trained into doing their work?
What are the, because
usually when people take this kind of decision,
they take a rational decision for a good reason,
especially experts in this kind of important stuff,
right? Usually when you're an expert at that level and I, I
mean, if you maintain lip
girl, you're an expert, I'm sorry, like that's the reality of the whole thing,
right?
You,
you are an expert in that domain and so you take your decision,
you have a good understanding.
You have a
usually you understand the impact of your decisions.
Like the open
people are partially from
linked to open BS D like they know the impact of security, right? Like
to the point that a lot of people would say they are obnoxious about it, but they know,
right?
So
and so the question is how did we got the system,
this whole thing to the point where that was the right decision to take?
And
if you based on this second story, if you don't,
if every time you had a shoot could wood, right?
A counterfactual, the official term because it's a
fact that never happened, right? It's not the reality.
Then if, but if you study the reality,
then you can tease out what makes this happen and then
maybe you can start to find solution or place to look at
and more importantly,
you can at least convey that narrative and that story to other people
so that they can take the decisions that would impact that narrative and that story,
right?
So that they can change how they see things. Because as long as we say,
the
people, maybe there should be less noise or maybe they should,
the reality that what we're doing here
is that we are getting rid of the problem.
We are saying that this is not a problem of the environment.
This is not a problem of the constraints line.
This is not a problem of the work being unsustainable.
This is not a problem of us using this wrong. This is not a problem of anyone.
It's them having not taken the correct decision.
And so we just have to tell them to take the right
one or better one next time and we can move on,
right?
And
that does not to say that it's not something that makes us feel better, right?
Usually does. And it's really easy and we need that closure,
but it really end up
in positive change.
And so if people listeners are partly interested
into exploring that there is a good book,
I advise by Synet Decker
called The Field Guide To An Understanding Human Error,
which is um a, a staple of the field.
It's a book we give to everyone that come into this domain.
Like you remember quickly, I remember Netflix at some point,
bought them by the dozens to give them to some of the engineers.
So uh
so I advise uh it's a good start.
And, and so, so that's, that's the first thing I would say.
And so in that case,
I would bring the question,
what made them take that decision at the time
and more importantly,
what would we need to change for them to take a different decisions?
OK, I have a clarifying question for this story you're telling right now.
Are we applying this to the,
the like the companies consuming the open source? Are we applying this to the
-- creators of the open source?
-- So I apply that to the maintainers?
Because realistically Xia
-- is the only one that can do the change we need if you want security.
-- Sure.
OK. OK.
Then the next question I have is I feel like this is putting undue
burden on the open source maintainers or am I misunderstanding your your point?
No, I I think that the contrary,
I think the rate is that right now by
saying they should would or could have done differently,
we are putting on the burden on them.
And we're saying is if we want to progress as a society,
if we want to have more security in our digital infrastructure,
we need to stop doing that,
we need to stop putting this burden on them and we need to start looking at
what that burden is.
What do they deal with?
Why do they take the decision and take that burden in
and then we can start to talk about how we can support that or change that situation?
I
see.
So would an example of this be, for example,
like looking at the burden on the open source maintainers?
Obviously, if you make a breaking change, people yell at you. OK.
How do we get people to not yell at them about breaking changes or to notify
them in advance that this would be a breaking change and so on and so forth.
Yes, I would be even more direct.
Yeah.
Well, because the one thing I keep coming back to is also,
there is a big assumption here is that if they made a different decision,
it would be a more correct or better decision.
And
that may not be the case like we might have had a worse outcome, had they removed it.
And then the second thing is so let's ignore that for a moment.
We'll just, we'll pretend that we're making good decisions.
Fundamentally. I feel like it keeps coming back to all these economic incentives
of, you know, I as a maintainer,
do I want people yelling at me or do I just want this unknown?
But maybe zero,
maybe larger than zero risk of a security issue if I don't tidy up this code.
Yeah.
You know what,
I'll take it because nobody's yelling at me right now and if I remove it,
they will for sure.
Yell at me.
There is a
thing here which I think is kind of something I would tease out
and want to buy it is your use of want as a maintainer.
Usually it's not about what I want,
it's about what I can do.
And, and that's what I'm saying when I say about the constraints.
Right. It's not only because it's not like I'm just, uh, isolate
my decision in isolation. Right.
I maintain a few open source thing
up until really recently I had two hours every quarter
to spend on open source
for a lot of personal reasons. That's all the time.
I could actually, I could put it right.
And I don't think that's a particularly, like,
that's kind of an extreme case but not that extreme.
I think it's a reality of a lot of source maintenance.
Oh, no, we ran into it all the time at Red Hat, like the XML hash dogs and the guy,
like I can do this in three months.
Exactly. Right.
So, if we do that, then if we accept that, then the rating is not what I want.
It's what do I budget for.
Because if I have two hours every quarter
doing the work to get rid of something relatively complex that will impact my test,
my, my test shoot where I will have to get rid of some and maybe change some and all.
And that will take me 10 hours.
Well, if I do that, then I'm going to do nothing else for you?
Wow. Yeah. Yeah.
But that's the reality of it. Right.
And so if
we want to start having that discussion,
we need to start having the discussion about the reality of what it is
to be maintainers and what are the constraint and pressure that they deal with.
Right.
And that's something, and especially when I talk about time,
that's something where I am really critical of
the open source security action we see out there
and partly we are going to come back to it, the software supply chain
one, right?
Slcasls a come to mind and all the good stuff coming out of Google,
but also the open sec open SSO
SSL F
the open SSF
Thank you.
Like
I look at what they offer as solutions,
right?
And they come from a great place,
right? Like I'm not saying that they want to make things worse.
I don't think that's the case when I look at, what is that? Right?
Like II, I want to acknowledge that, right?
It's people that want to make something better.
But when I look at what is offered, it's all more burdens.
It's, you need to make your software reproducible.
Well, this point I know that can be really hard in some build system.
You need to add your signature on every come.
Well, that's an additional thing I need to maintain.
And if I change computer and I change my key and I losses,
that's a lot of work you need to have a well.
Ok, doable, not too hard.
Um You also need to
like if you receive a valle,
you need to disclose it
quickly if I have two hours every quarter and I just use
my two hours for this quarter and I receive a valr.
Do I take on something else to disclose it or do I wait a quarter?
Right.
You also have that.
There is and also we are going to audit,
you are going to do security audit on your code.
We are going to fuzz your code for you.
Great.
Now you are going to come back to me with the issues
I need to fix and I don't have time for that,
right?
And but that the real
of it, right? So
all of this come from a great place.
It's a, it's a place of care and of wanting the right thing,
but it comes also from a place I feel that does not
analyze the reality of what the maintenance as and their needs,
right?
And so we come with a solution we think will
work and would work probably better in commercial software,
but that may not fit the reality of what we deal with. And that's kind also why I'm
having problem with the supply generation discussion, right?
Because the you know, supply generation
you as a user
provide me with the needs
to fix the problem because you pay me, I make money from what you are using from me,
right?
As a not maintainer, I do not have resources except the free time I give
and my knowledge
and that is a highly competed for resource,
right?
And, and so, so we get into this discussion where I,
I feel like a lot of the discussion we have and that's why I love the Atlantic
Council uh report because I think they do talk
about that all Road and Bridget report by Nadia
Eba
right before that
from the
nation because they do talk about this, they have,
they went to talk with the maintenance to talk about the maintenance problem.
And when I see the openness, they say,
oh, I see a million millions dollars spent on security for open source, right?
I see the big like the Alpha and Omega program of all these big numbers next to them.
And then I go look at what the framework does
and there is basically no money in it,
no action in the framework, all of the action they will take that will be about
providing the resources to deal with the work they
they will create to the maintenance.
And
I'm not saying that because the main thing is I want to make a ton of money.
I mean, I would love to work more on open source, right? But
the reality is
at some point
if you need time and knowledge of particular specific
people and the rate is that for digital infrastructure,
we have a really small base of people that maintain it for everyone.
And when, I mean, really
small, I mean, really
small.
It's probably 10,000, it's probably already,
we probably have covered a lot of the bad
thing with 10,000 people.
You need to be able to give them the way to do their job.
And right now, a lot of them do not.
The example of lip curl come to my curl
for the first time
since the existence curl last year
was able to move
their website o
thing
from something paid by the maintenance with his own money.
Wow,
you make a whole blog post about it.
That was the first time since the beginning of our channel that
the curl project could pay for the sting of the website.
Like we are not talking here of paying people
millions per year to do that job, right?
Like we don't even have the point where we can own the website
and it's come right. It's not a small randomly
thing.
Like in my experience, that's the default is, you know,
pretty much every project is run at a loss like this podcast.
And uh and I do love the whole, oh, we need more maintainers.
And I'm like, how many maintainers do you think there are?
And they're like one per thing. I'm like, I got bad news for you.
It's actually less than one because there's a
whole bunch of maintainers with like 100 packages.
Oh, it's even better.
Have you ever heard of Auto?
Yep. Right. It, it's kind of,
you know, a small thing. Right.
And not used, it's definitely not critical for a lot of soft
that,
you know, legal thing. Right.
Right. How many maintainers?
Uh, I would guess maybe the guy gets his cat to do it once in a while.
Ok. The real
zero since 2012.
-- That
-- doesn't surprise me at all.
Ok.
For anyone listening auto
is used by
everything,
literally everything.
It managed a configuration and build compilation of
basically everything on the planet,
not everything but a large portion of the sea could be
on the planet.
It has no maintenance. It is 12
and it's not like it's complex, right?
Like it doesn't do anything complex, like nothing of the sense, it don't have bugs.
I'm sure it has no bugs, like no problem there. Right.
And there have been a release in 2020 or 21. I
remember there was a new version of
auto
come 3.14 if I
quickly,
the reason it was done
is because Bloomberg paid one guy for six months
to go through all the patches that were sent to the mailing list
and release a new version.
And after six months,
they realized that one person for six months will not be enough to do that.
And so they paid two people for a year and a half to do a new version.
But that was a one time contract
since then, there have been a bit of pick up in the auto
community trying to maintain it. But in practice, it's really hard.
Not a lot of people have the knowledge, not of people because it's really arcane.
Um not a lot of people have the knowledge all the time.
So in reality, it's probably going to end up in the same place,
but
we are taking a decade without any maintenance for
fundamental piece of infrastructure that is quite safety critical.
There actually is some activity starting late last year 2022.
But also a lot of it is literal like spell checks.
There, there is some kind of deeper level changes that are,
I'm looking at this one code, commit.
It's actually a little scary but I mean, it's one person, this one person from UCL A.
So yeah,
I know you're clearly correct though like there there
should be way more activity on this thing.
-- We need to include the video of this show.
-- No one can see the gestures Tama is making.
Ok.
I want, I want to realist all the way back now because we are,
we've talked a lot about the problem.
How are we going to fix this? What like make me feel better after this conversation?
Ok. So I have a bad news. My nickname in some of these c
call about safety science is a cynical meson
So, um I, I may not have a lot of good news otherwise I would not be called cynical.
I don't know.
I have I DS like a lot of people will have I DS.
Um
The reality is
I don't see a way out
in the current environment.
This is used everywhere
and this is fundamental like we cannot replace it easily.
Like despite the example, I give all the time is open SSL, right?
Despite everyone try to focus on everything and to create new ones,
performer and pros
IO and all that work, right?
We are still with Rus TLS and O like I looked recently into
uh I'm part of the airline committee and I've,
I have, it's a,
it's a virtual machine for the airline and Alex and all kind of languages.
And I, I have some of my code in there
and I was looking at can we get rid of open SSL because we linked to it?
And I wanted to get rid of it for, you know,
classic security reasons. And I looked at what we use
and the rating that we use in open SSL is also crypto
primitives as far as I can tell there is nothing out there
that even tried to solve that problem.
I mean, ring, ring
in brass kind of try but in practice, it's a mess
and we are not close to something that we
could use for something that's stable and that's used.
And So
I, right now when I look at the reality of the world that things are used everywhere
and it works good enough,
it work good enough for us to continue like that for a long time.
Probably
other solution we could get. Probably, I would say that if we want,
we could. So
I'm going to uh start with what we can do,
which I think we have an impact and then I can be a bit more, you know,
air brain and invent things.
The thing I think we need to do
is to tell the story of, of digital infrastructure maintenance.
We need to sit down and tell these stories.
We need to change away the narrative we have
around digital infrastructure
mostly because we don't have a narrative right now.
The only narrative we have is when Google say
you should put your name on things because we need to trust you.
Yeah,
I am literally quoting from a blog post with pretty
big names of social engineering at Google on it.
I can find for you if you don't remember it. But that was literally a thing.
-- Oh, I, I remember reading it and I was just like, what? Like I
-- literally
-- yell at my screen
-- like they want to identify
uh they wanted identification requirements for open source maintainers.
And I'm like,
oh
wow, that's,
that's a big ask.
I mean, it's not even a big ask. My my point is no, you don't have to trust us.
You have not trusted us for two decades and you have built everything on it.
You don't need to trust us like, oh, put us away.
What would us putting our name on it?
Bring you,
I,
I suspect it kind of boils back to that.
The first story of, well, now we'll know who to blame and ask for a better decision.
But you know what does not make people more secure liability.
It allows you to blame someone but you don't stop the problem from happening.
So I I don't, so I think we need to tell the stories.
We need to the Atlantic
Council did a good job as a as a story
oriented to um politicians like people that work in governments
and governance. And I think that was a good story and we need more of that.
The fact that I keep linking the Rod and Bridget
Bridges report that was done in 2016 to a lot of people in digital manufactures
that have never read it.
Despite the fact it was relatively big at the time, right? We talked about it.
It was a follow up to
bleed and all
tell me that we are not telling the story well,
and we need to tell this these stories better,
right? People keep being surprised when they talk of auto
com or curl all that stuff.
We need to tell these stories because right now they are not told
something we're also seeing with the CR A, right,
the Cyber Residency Act in Europe right now
is that it talks of open source and the way to open source is visible that
the people that wrote it do not know the reality of what we deal with.
And that's ok. Right. I'm not saying that they should have known it,
-- but I'm saying that we as a committee need to tell these stories.
-- Yeah, absolutely.
That would be the first step. And the hope is that if we tell
this story and if we are able to make this narrative,
how people think about this a bit more,
then solution would emerge. People, we do things to help.
And when I say people, I mean, organizationally, right,
I don't be independent people that pay for sponsorship on github
or stuff like that.
So that's the first one.
Now, if I want to go deeper, realistically,
we are going to need some kind of international governance on this. Sure,
that may mean government,
that may be not something else that may mean government.
Um There are a few interesting initiatives
right now, I can think of. Uh one of them is the German government
is doing a small pilot
of giving grants to open source projects
like fundamental one.
I think they call it the Sovereign Tech Fund or something like that.
I can find you the link uh if you want.
Um But
yeah, sovereign
Tech fans, that's the name they use and,
and the projects they are selected.
If you look at the projects that are selected,
they have an English page which shows that they understand something at least.
And, but what you see the project is elected.
It's bundler and Ruby gem
P GP kernel, wireguard, open ssh, open B GP D A
fortune packet manger.
Like these are sensible choice for this kind of gras that
when we want maintenance.
-- And I think something like this, this is a pilot. It's relatively small.
-- Sorry.
I there's also the FORTRAN package manager on
that list which I love because that like,
I'm sorry, folks, there's some boring stuff we need to fix.
Yes. Right.
And it's important like something I put out a few times we talk about all this
work we need to do to get uh green energy and all the climate general.
What language do you think all your simulation and
work run on for the impact of climate change?
Now,
imagine what happened if there is a massive floating point
handling error there that is creeping only one every 10
computation and we have no idea and no one knows how to handle this.
I think government impact some kind of taxation or something like
that will probably be part of the answer at some point.
Uh There is a
hard discussion we need to have in open source communities
around the fact that this goes contrary to the ethos,
we have talked about for a long time because we are not just
fighting
Microsoft to publish a noise
that some people can toy with and use a printer with.
We are running the world
and people life depend on us.
And so at some point, we may have to grow up and realize that this is
a way to what we deal with. The maintenance, knows that,
right, the local for
Jay people that dealt with all that time, know that.
But the ethos and the way we talk of it in the committee is
not there yet and that's something we probably need to talk to us.
So if you want to see change
and the final thing I would say,
and I will close on this is we could and that's me totally.
That's not what I would advise, but that's something I'm bringing up.
If we want this to be visible, we could just all decide to walk off.
So
all open source committee, uh maintenance committee decide, you know what for you.
We are not going to publish any update,
deal with it.
-- A
-- year. Society would collapse in a week.
But, you know,
deal with it.
Yeah, fork it and fix it.
I mean, no one can do that because for
it and fix it needs that you need to be able to
have the knowledge we talked about and you don't have that right?
So,
but, and,
and, and, and that we are not there yet and I doubt we will get there any time soon.
But at some point, if you want to make the problem visible, which is our prime here,
right?
Because the prime is not visible because it works nearly all the time.
We may have to try to organize these kind of actions.
Toma,
I feel like I've been drinking from the fire hose and holy cow.
You've given me so much to think about it. I thank you. Thank you so much for your time.
This has been
amazing.
I'm available, uh, any time and I get told that a lot
and I, I feel like we scratch a service. I want to Kurt and Tama.
Thank you so much.
Have
a, oh, wait, I have to do the, the exit of the show first. I, I forget that sometimes.
All right, so, so thank you, Kurt. Thank you, Tama.
Thank you for listening.
I will put all the show notes at open source security podcast.com. You can use the
Podos podcast hashtag
to find us on social media. Kurt and Tama
-- have a marvelous rest of your
-- day.
-- Thank you. Have a good day. Thank
-- you, everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.