Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Bresser.
So we did the memory safety episode was like two episodes ago,
maybe from the time of recording and we got
a generous amount of feedback we'll say on it.
But one of the people who got in touch was Carol Nichols,
the author of the Rust programming language book.
And I am so excited that she agreed to come on the show, Carol. Welcome to the show.
-- Thank you so much.
-- Hi.
Thank you for having me and thank you for letting me invite myself on.
I've actually been trying to get on this thinking about how I could get
on the show for a while because you two talk about Russ a lot.
I feel like um
you've actually talked about me back a little while ago
when there was the uh Russ decimal typo squatting attack.
Kurt was like,
yeah, yeah, the crates io admins took care of it, you know,
they deleted it right away and
I was the one who deleted that.
I was like, that's me. That's me. You're talking about me.
Yeah.
So, so just for your future reference and anyone else listening,
the easiest way to invite yourself on the show is to just say I want to come on your show
and be interesting.
And if you're interesting and we like what you're doing,
you'll totally get an invite.
It was very easy. Yes. Yes.
-- It's,
-- it's always amusing to me that every now and then someone will be like, oh,
how much is it?
Does it cost to be on the show? And I'm like,
you just have to be doing something interesting and then they never email me back.
So I like
that. I feel like is very telling.
Yes.
Anyway. Ok.
So we have Carol and we, we're going to try to talk about Rust as much as we can.
But I guess let's just start at the very beginning,
Carol because you obviously have written a book
and we'll get to the book in a little while, but just
like explain Rust to us, right?
Because you're, you're in a unique,
authoritative position to do this versus Kurt and I who are not.
Yeah. So Rust is a statically typed compiled
language that is aiming to be an alternative to C and C++ mainly one of
its main ideas is ownership and borrowing and lifetimes that kind of all related.
And that
is a big part of how Rust manages memory safely,
which eliminates at compile time.
A lot of the memory safety problems that other languages run into
and because this is happening at compile time,
you don't get the performance penalty of a garbage collector
or other uh reference counting that happens at run time.
So we think that rust is a great step forward.
Like I got involved because I was, I was doing Ruby
and doing a lot of performance treating of Ruby. And at some point
that's, that's a tough road.
Like I remember Aaron Patterson, some of the stuff he was working on.
It was just bonkers.
It's,
it's a lot.
And at some point if you want to get more performance out of Ruby,
you have to drop into C,
I'm terrified of C I should be nowhere near production C and that was about the
time that
Russ started
being like a viable thing.
It was before 10, but I was like, oh, hey, this looks pretty interesting.
And then Steve Clad
Nick wrote a book, an ebook called Russ for
Rubeus. I was like, oh, I can do this
and, and it's really great and I got
clearly super involved trying to help other people get into Rus.
And I just feel like it's the compiler keeping track of the tedium of,
of managing the memory for me so that I can, I can think about other things.
I don't have to become a master of, of
all the rules and, and pitfalls and foot guns.
Like computers are really great at keeping track of TDM. And people are not.
So let's let the computer
do that
and I get to write fast systems code
and think about my actual problem and not think about these memory safety problems.
So, so I think this is, is a big leap forward for the industry.
Of course, there's always more to do. There's there might be a next better language.
But
right now I feel really good about the state of us and
uh the industry does too. It's taking off and being used in more and more places.
And I think it's really going to help the industry overall become
safer and faster and
use for your resources, which is good for the environment,
improved security.
Holy cow. There's a lot to unpack in that,
that description.
Let's
let's start with the concept of borrowing because I
think that's the most unique and maybe different idea.
Rust has over other languages.
Explain to us what that means
because I don't think
it's something that we'll say traditional programmers will expect or understand.
Yes.
So this is actually the main reason I wanted to
come on the show because on the memory safety show,
Kurt was like, oh, Russ doesn't have a garbage collector
and it doesn't have a garbage collector.
Yeah, I honestly just assumed it did because like,
how else do you do it?
Well, let me tell you how.
So you also,
you also don't have to type alec and free all
over your code what the compiler does is when you,
when you create a variable and put some data in it.
And then at some point later that variable goes out of scope,
the compiler can analyze that and see. OK, it's that variables out of scope.
Now, at that point, I'm going to insert
it's called a drop called to the drop function.
And that's the cleanup code that will do the delo
and then you have the borrow checker which is
looking at where the variable is created and where it goes out of scope.
And the references you take to it, the borrowing
and make sure that you're not holding on to that borrow or trying to
use a borrow outside of where that value is going to be valid.
And there are additional rules on there.
You can have immutable borrows which means you just can read the data
and then,
and you can have as many of those as you want or you can have
one mutable reference mutable borrow to the value at a in a scope at a
time. And that is all checked at compile time.
So you don't get race conditions that way.
And the other neat thing is that this analysis works across threads as well.
There are additional
called send N sync and these are send, it means a type is
safe to send to another thread and that moves ownership to the other thread. So
the other, the next thread is responsible for cleaning it up.
And the first thread doesn't have access to it anymore.
Then sync is for types that are safe to share between threads.
So that's those are types like your mutex or um
an atomically reference counted variable where it only cleans up once
nothing is referring to it anymore. And that does happen at run time,
but
you'll get a compile error if you try to
share something across threads that you're not allowed to.
Again, like humans and especially me should not be writing multi threaded C and C++.
It has been proven to be impossible to get right.
Uh And it's really hard to debug like even if you can get it right.
Most of the time someone's going to mess up something somewhere and
you're gonna have to debug it at some point and it's terrible.
But in Rust, you get compiler errors,
which means you don't ever get it into production.
You don't ever have to get to the debugging part,
you have to deal with the compiler errors.
So this is this is kind of a mind mindset shift for a lot of programmers.
And another thing that I love about Russ is that
a lot of people have put a lot of work into making
the compiler errors useful and friendly and like specific to your code.
It points out exactly what your problem is.
So
one thing that a lot of programmers have to have
to learn and unlearn when they switch to rust.
Is that
the compiler error messages? You want, you want to
spend a minute and read those?
Like, I've seen programmers be like, oh, error. OK.
Let me go change some random thing and try it again and say, oh, it's still an error.
It's like, no, no, no,
no, seriously. Stop, go read. It'll tell you exactly what you need to change.
But in, you know, c you get, you get core dump,
it's like, what is this?
-- I don't know. Good luck.
-- Like even Python, I end up like reading. OK.
No, it's this module. No, it's not that it was called from here. OK. No, no, no,
no, no. OK. Oh, I forgot this on line 32. You know, eventually I get there.
Sometimes
a lot of, a lot of really smart people,
a lot of really great ideas are kind of coalescing in the Russ that just make it
a real pleasure to work with
it once you kind of get into the right mindset,
that's actually one thing I realize I've now never really given thought to.
So Rust is essentially sort of front loading the
errors by catching them in the compiler versus like,
well, my favorite recent thing is this Netflix Tech blog where they talked about it,
a Java function that
was supposed to be three times faster and it wasn't, and it turns out it was like a,
a cash miss hit thing.
And they literally just added a 64 byte
pad and then boom performance increased threefold,
right?
And it's this horrendously technical, you know, where they were doing like
the severely technical levels of investigation, you know, for
a simple fix as it were. And
so yeah, if Rust is catching these on the front end in the compiler and
not just catching them, but then essentially it forces you to fix them, right?
Because otherwise it won't compile.
Exactly. And there's no, just to confirm there's no way to override this.
Ah
There is OK.
Tiny catch. There is unsafe,
which is a key word in Rust.
And that lets you
opt out of a limited set of the checks.
The Rust does not all of them.
You can't just like turn off all the checks,
but it lets you do things like de reference a raw pointer.
And
because sometimes, especially when you're doing foreign function interface,
when you're,
when you're uh interfacing with an unsafe language like Sears C++ or something,
the Rust compiler can't check
or if you're doing hardware,
which is inherently unsafe, you
use the unsafe keyword, get direct access to it.
And the unsafe keyword is saying I as a human
have checked this and I promise you,
I've sat there and thought about it a long time and I promise
you it's valid because the compiler can't check it for some reason.
And the way that this is helpful is that when you do get a seg fault of some sort,
then if you've been limited in the amount of unsafe usages you've used, you know,
that the problem has to come from one of those
limited usages.
So it really cuts down the scope of what
you have to investigate when something goes wrong.
So,
yes, there is this escape hatch.
But as long as you're not putting your entire code base in an unsafe block,
it's, it's going to help. It's still going to help.
Well, and I think that's uh see, and this is, I think what I like about rust is rust is
there's the ideal and then there's, we actually have to talk to existing C code.
And the reality is every time I've seen this is the ideal this will replace.
Like,
remember when Java was going to replace CI I
literally remember that it was a long time ago.
But
yeah, it didn't
too much sunk cost.
And
that's what like the fact that the Linux kernel is like, hey,
we shoved rust in there and now like you can start
making parts of your driver in rust that are just a whole lot safer and simpler.
It's like, oh,
this might actually take off because we don't have to rebuild the world and,
and that's, I think
I just, it's not going to happen.
-- We're not going to rebuild every single piece of sea on the planet.
-- Yeah.
So I actually did a talk which
I know, I know this podcast kind of gets off on unrelated tangents a lot. And, uh,
a
little bit, I, I don't have room to talk because I,
I did a talk once that the first half of it was about railroad air air brakes.
Uh,
and it's actually related because, uh
George Westinghouse discovered that there,
there was a way to do automatic braking of the
entire train all at once with these air brakes.
And
before then they had to have guys up on each train, turning this wheel to,
to stop the train and just, people couldn't
stop the train fast enough. And so it was, it was wildly unsafe, but within 80 years,
they transitioned all the trains in the United States
from using the hand brakes to the air brakes.
And I'm looking at and looking at sea
and seeing the sea has been around for like 4050 years. Now.
Are we going to make it? Are we gonna, we know c is unsafe?
Now, we know this, we've had empirical evidence
across many code bases across many companies. We can't do this.
We have better tools available.
Are we going to as an industry as a country as a world?
Are we going to choose to not do the thing we know is not safe anymore?
And I don't know if we're going to beat the railroads in the 18 hundreds.
It's, there's just so much code out there,
but that doesn't mean, we shouldn't try.
-- I mean,
-- as far as I know, Canada is still mining and exporting asbestos.
Yeah, there's that
like,
it's not, you can't do it here. But
-- I
-- want to put this into context because I actually think that's a
very good analogy and I'm probably going to steal it at some point,
but
80 years
feels like a long time to us.
But
when you think about how much existing hardware
and infrastructure and everything is in place in,
in a large industry,
80 years is probably pretty fast. And I have a suspicion if we're going to measure
how long we're still gonna see, see development happening.
80 years is probably not an unrealistic timeline,
which also I, I felt I was uh Keys Cook wrote a
blog article, I'll try, I'll try to dig it up,
but I was talking about some of the security enhancements they put in Linux.
And when he said, you know, it's been
half a century of C use. I'm like, holy cow. I feel old like this is,
this is an old language now. But yeah,
I mean, that's where we're at, that's where we're at.
All right. All right. I want to,
I want to back us up one more time because I want to
tease out the borrow concept from Rust because I think it is if,
if let's
put ourselves in the shoes of ac programmer because
if you're programming in C you're passing pointers around,
like it's nobody's business
and anything can read or write to that pointer anytime it wants and nobody, you know,
the compiler doesn't care.
It does exactly what it's told.
Rust does not work this way. And as a I IC was one of the first languages I learned
and the brow concept
I think was the
single hardest thing for me to get. But once I understood it it was like, holy crap.
This is the way.
Yes.
And like,
so I took one c course in college and I
didn't like I could recite to you the academic definition,
you know, a pointer is an address that points to data on the heap.
But like as far as how to use that in my code and how to think about it,
like it just never clicked for me.
Well, or the stack, it can point at literally anything,
the best part and the worst part.
And I don't, I don't remember talking about any of that,
like safety and thinking about making sure that your pointers are val.
I don't remember that. I mean, granted,
you know, I was very confused at the time.
Um
So I would just, you know, throw amper sands and ask her so
on my coat and pray for it to work and be in the office hours all the time.
But yeah, something about rust calling it borrowing
and the compiler helping you really made it click that and it is very similar.
So you have a value
and then you can do AMP or sand value and that is borrowing that value
and then you can
use that borrow places, but it's still, it's still typed.
It's a borrow to a particular a value of a particular type.
So you don't have the problem of, of like
misinterpreting what you're pointing at
that.
You mightn't see another side effect of Rust's compile
time checks in the borrow checker is that,
you know, when you have a borrow,
when you have a reference in Rust,
you know, it's always valid,
there are no no pointers.
So there is a separate concept called an option that can be some or none.
And that is where the concept of having something or nothing can come in.
But again, because that's a type, it's an enum
that can have two possible values.
But whenever you try to use that value,
the compiler says,
uh can you make sure you handle the case of,
of when this is nothing as opposed to something and
do,
tell me exactly what you want me to do if in the case of this is nothing, it,
it has uh exhaustive case checking.
So it's impossible to use
nothing as if it were something in R
which is another huge,
I was so tired and ruby of getting undefined method on nil
in production all the time and it was just normal
and
it's just that problem is gone. And rust.
It's like a weight lifted. I don't have to worry about that problem anymore.
-- I can think about my other problems.
-- A lot of my javascript and Python code is.
Does this exist? Oh, it does? Ok. Ok. Let's do something.
Oh, it doesn't exist. Uh,
uh,
oh,
yeah,
undefined is not a function.
Uh, fun times.
I love that.
But, yeah, just thinking about, ok, something, something else is going to
be taking care of
whether this is valid or not.
And I, I just know that I have something here and I can read from it
or I'm allowed to write from it in this case.
And like knowing, knowing where mutability can happen or not, can uh
really help how you reason about your code.
Um And
oh like in the function signature, it'll say, am I,
am I getting a mutable reference or am I getting an immutable reference?
So you know,
is this function possibly going to change the value of what I'm passing to it or not?
And
that reasoning both on a human level and on a compiler
level can help you think about what your code is doing easier
and
also enable some optimizations on the in the compiler side.
So quick question, for example, if you pass an immutable value and then try to
like try to modify it, the compiler will catch that and
tell you
will borrow. Yeah.
And actually the
the variables when you declare them
you, you have to say let variable or let mute variable.
So you can just declare the value
to be. It's actually the binding is what it's variable binding
is the technical term for it.
But basically, if you pass it as immutable, then you never have to worry.
Yes.
Yeah.
If you pass it as immutable,
that function is not allowed to mutate it and you'll get a compiler error if you try
because this, I mean,
because my experience of programming has been consistently that we build tools
so that like, yeah, we use the programmer have kind of less
minutia to think about, you know, things like, well,
like you typed out a function name, does that function exist?
If it does exist, make it bold if it doesn't exist, make it like grayed out.
So that do I have to create it? Did I misspell it, you know,
vs code does this for example, like simple example but like I can't type
so I do this all the time
and I'm just thinking like especially with
the number of variables and the types of variables like,
yeah, I, I just can't hold that in my head anymore.
Like when I was like,
I read the C book once upon a time and tried to learn to program C and
you know, yeah,
I can make a toy program that like takes a name and plays Tic Tac toe with you
with like three variables. But
then I go look at like the bind code base and I'm like,
OK, there's a lot of variables here.
Like I, and where the hell are they coming from or going? And, you know,
and so
I'd never, again, I'd never really thought explicitly about something like Rust,
helping me
sort of manage my variables in the sense of
like, no, Kurt, you, you shouldn't do that, like, that's not safe.
Like, or if you do want to do that, you have to explicitly do it.
Yeah.
Like with Python, I mostly just, you know. Yeah, just kind of YOLO it
to be honest.
Yeah.
And this, this helps with reading code that you or other people have written before.
Like there are assumptions you can make
that
as long as it's compiling, you know,
the Rust compilers checked those things and you don't have to check them manually.
Yeah, because I literally like will grit my code to see.
Like, did I change this variable somewhere later on? Yes.
Yeah, especially in Python.
-- And I'm like,
-- oh, this is reminding me of for anyone who listens to the show.
I'm helping out a high school robotics team and I'm helping
out the programmers and they decided to use C++ which I
tried to
steer them to Java.
But they were dead set on C++ and the joke I
keep using with them is if it builds its ships,
if it builds, it's probably fine, it's OK.
And then of course, you run the code and it explodes, but
that's an entirely different story.
But with rust, I mean, literally, if it builds it,
it probably isn't going to explode when you run it.
Well, ok. So it's a little cave
out there, you know that it's not going to explode in specific ways.
You know, you know what the compiler has checked for you.
It is absolutely possible to write logic bugs and rust.
you still need to write tests for your log.
You can still like you can write a caching
structure and you have cash and validation problems and,
you know, you're,
you can write inefficient code because you're holding a new
text in a place that you really shouldn't be.
And
there's still plenty of mistakes you can make and rust, it's just,
there's a couple of classes of problems that don't exist anymore.
So
yeah,
it's not, it's not a silver bullet,
it's not the solution to all the world's problems, but it is a solution to some.
-- But
-- would it
be fair to say that Rust is actually making progress in adding more and new
capabilities and safeties? Right?
Because that's,
that's kind of the biggest thing I've seen with C is people keep trying to
like, yeah, we've made a lot of progress on compilers. They're better
but
C fundamentally is C like,
you know,
yeah,
there's lots of tools you can kind of bolt on after the fact
there are subsets of C you can use that are supposedly safer,
can spend 10 hours reviewing each line of code that I guess NASA does.
But at the end of the day, it's still c
and if you can just start from a different place, you're,
you're already leaps and bounds ahead of that
and you don't have to enforce everything
because that's just the way all the R code is.
Well, we should also be clear, this is the way
most languages except C and C++ are because like Java and Go and Python and
Ruby and all those like memory management is not an issue in those languages,
right?
But they solve it in different ways.
That's
right. And, and Rust is, is doing it as part of the compile time analysis.
And, and so OK, we're,
we're running ourselves out of time and we haven't even gotten to your book yet.
But I, I promise we're going to get to that in just a moment.
But before that, I want to touch on one other thing you brought up that I think is the,
the silver bullet Rust does have going for it,
which is Rust's ability to interface with C is
it, it is remarkably good.
And I think that is part of why we're seeing Rust catch on is there are many projects
that are,
instead of saying, oh, we have to rewrite the whole project.
They say we can rewrite this part of the project with Rust where you pick out,
say the most dangerous or most exposed code.
Right.
Yes, absolutely. Incremental rewrites are possible and you never have to finish.
You can just
rewrite parts of it and there's, there's stuff happening with us all the time
and, and that is definitely very exciting.
It gives us a path forward out of the legacy code that is not just
rewrite everything.
Yeah,
there's actually,
I, I
don't think you, you all have talked about this yet.
Consumer reports just put out a report on memory safety, which is actually yes,
it's, it's super interesting y'all Grau
wrote this great report and I, I love it.
I heartily endorse everything and it talks about how,
how can we as an industry be more transparent to consumers and to governments about
uh the memory safety
in the programs that they can choose to use
and
how can we uh she makes an analogy to um Ralph Nader's unsafe at any speed. How that did
a lot of uh advocacy to make,
make these problems more visible and more understandable to more people.
And I, I agree like
memory safety is not
something that your average, you know, politician or
consumer knows about
and maybe they shouldn't have to, but maybe we should help them
to make more informed choices
and to put pressure on the industry
to make better choices. And part of part of the report is
acknowledging that it's not
going to be
able, you're not going to be able to switch over overnight to a memory safe thing.
It's going to be instrumental, it's going to be
um
showing that you have a plan to address
memory safety and improve memory safety over time
that even just having that
actually having companies do that and not just saying they've done, it can make,
can make a difference
and,
and yeah, I, I fully believe um regulation is coming in regards to this,
whether it's gonna be good regulation and useful regulation is up to,
I don't know, I don't know that yet.
And actually that was one of my questions for, for you too.
If, if a government committee came to you
and said,
we're, we're writing regulations to improve security of software,
what's,
what's something you would want them to put it at?
I think for me, I,
I would be more worried about sort of the high level medicals than the, the,
like,
I'd be more worried about economic incentives than specific technical things.
My other concern would be, for example, we saw that right to repair bill in New York,
which looked amazing, like so good. And then, you know, it got
one that one minor tweak of like a sentence
and uh crap,
it's basically
useless now.
And that is my other fear is again, you know, because we had like,
that's one thing I learned is, you know, writing good regulation is hard
and it never occurred to me
because I mean, it happens all the time,
but they changed the bill or they add an addendum at the last moment
that, you know, 100% changes the meaning of whatever it was
was built into that legislation.
So I think for me,
I would kind of worry more about maybe
some sort of economic incentives slash insurance.
Like
if
simply put like in Europe, you have the,
it has to be fit for purpose so the consumer can return it in two years and get a refund
to the point of purchase.
Not through the manufacturer, not through, you know, oh,
you got to go to Sony for that, like good luck.
But I, you know,
like this is why I buy my electronics at Costco because one year money back.
So Costco generally doesn't sell terrible electronics.
So I suspect something along the lines of like uh a
con like fit for purpose with consumer rights
and making it really easy for the consumer to return the device and get a full refund.
That would be a good start.
But the flip side is, it's kind of like, you know,
I'm always reminded of roofing shingle warranties where they're like, oh, these sh
you know, shingles are warranted for 25 years.
Well, like the, the shingles, not the installation, not the removal,
like not the 90% of the cost,
just the darn shingles.
And it's like everybody, you know, that finds out the hard way is like, well,
this warranty sucks.
And I'm like, what do you think they're gonna, like, spend 10 grand fixing your roof?
Like, no.
So
I, I think I would go with sort of
honestly, like, making it possible for people to have two years to return devices.
And I think that
espe,
and especially accounting for like software problems or perfect example,
I've paid for ipad games that no longer work
or the sound doesn't work. Like
one of my son's favorite games.
The sound just doesn't work in modern versions of I OS and he's
not happy about this and neither am I because I paid for it
or they abandoned the game and went to a website
model because they didn't want to pay Apple 30%.
So
honestly,
I would go with some sort of version of like
if this thing stops working or doesn't work right,
for two years or three years,
you get a full refund from whoever you paid
and I think that would then force them. I think they would start asking a lot,
you know,
harder questions and having contracts that actually specify these
things have to work and be supported properly.
That's a very consumer focused answer.
And I'm not sure consumers know or care or ever will because how many
people have TV S that are like flaming piles of garbage and they don't care
and if they don't care,
then they don't,
I mean, this is this is
this, I think is related to the story of what Ralph Nader did, right?
When he did unsafe at any speed, it was,
I've told people many times in the past that
Ralph Nader was doing stunt hacking when he did that
right where he was purposely creating spectacle
that made the problem seem significantly worse than it was,
but that had to be done in order to raise the level of awareness needed.
And I think we have kind of similar situations sometimes.
I mean,
we've seen some stunt hacking against various products and every
now and then it gets attention and then the,
it inevitably dies down, which is just how it works.
You heard it here listeners, Josh wants you to do more stunt hacking.
-- I'm all for stunt hacking. It totally works the
-- car thing,
you know,
until they put a journalist in a car and made it go forwards and backwards with the
foot off the gas.
Everybody in tech, of course is like, well, yeah, of course,
you can hack a car and remotely control it like that,
like, duh.
But, you know, until you actually, I think, see it and feel it,
you're not gonna feel that pit of fear in your stomach.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
And, and look,
I think this is one of the challenges we have is when we try to talk about regulating
a lot of it
because
like,
what's the stunt that's actually going to move
the needle and you also need like repetitive,
a concerted effort towards the stunt and the message and we just,
we struggle with that, right?
And so my suspicion is what we're going to see
is we're going to see
places like, like the, the US government, you know, the,
the NSA released that report basically saying stop using C that's,
that's the TLDR of the whole report.
-- They don't say you should use rust, but it's, it's
-- highly uh inferred, right?
They don't say you should use rust, but that's basically what it says.
And so
I have a suspicion, we're going to see
the kind of the,
the power of the purse at work there where
they're going to tell organizations you shouldn't use C
but they won't mandate it,
but they aren't going to necessarily give you the money you want if you're doing it.
And that's
my guess of how we're going to see it because I don't,
I don't know if we can regulate something like the programming
languages people use because it's just such an esoteric and hard
to understand concept who would write that regulation and how would
you write it in a way that doesn't have loopholes,
the size of, you know, giant tunnels you can drive a truck through.
I don't know.
Yeah,
I feel like the consumer awareness kind of needs to
happen at a higher level than the end user.
Consumer like
enterprises
buying software from each other need to be need to say, ok, how much c do you have
that?
I want to compare, what's your, what's your plan for dealing with memory safety?
Like where are, where are your global security database filed issues?
That's right. That's right.
We're running ourselves out of time and I want
to talk about your book because the second edition
-- just came out. It's
-- available from No
Starch Press
noar.com right now
and it will be available on Amazon and Barnes and Noble February 28th,
which is funny because I had pre-ordered it from Amazon.
And then in the, in the presh show, Carol told me, oh,
you can buy it right now and no start.
So I'm like what?
And then I went and canceled my Amazon order and bought
it while we were waiting for Kurt to show up.
So
mine's in the mail.
Yes. Yes,
you can. You get it for free online at Doc dot Russ l.org/book.
But it's, you know, nice formatting paper version from No
Starch with a,
a nicely formatted ebook if that's how you like to read your books.
So I highly recommend ordering from nos
Starch if you can.
I know sometimes international shipping from nos
arch
is expensive. So
-- sorry about that if that's your situation
-- from a practical perspective.
So I know enough rust to be dangerous.
I'm certainly not an expert at it and I've only ever had the ebook.
I have your last edition ebook and I have struggled to learn rust
out of an ebook and I can't explain why that is necessarily,
but I am.
So now I have the paper copy coming and I,
I feel like I need to, it, it's,
it's different enough from anything I've done in the
past that I feel like I need to like
put the sticky note things on the pages and
I need to circle things and underline things to actually
learn rust properly.
Yes and like type in the code yourself, not copy,
paste it. Yeah,
anyone looking to travel down this path.
I just as a warning, I have failed with the ebook, but I'm
-- I'm optimistic that paper will, will save me
-- here.
One thing I've learned is you can't actively read electronic files,
you can't underline
put notes in the margin,
highlight stuff like and I I've gone through a couple of programs
that kind of let you do that but not like paper,
paper is different
highly recommend.
So say we work at the same company, you're in security. I'm a developer.
I come to you and say, hey, we're, we're working on this new application.
We decided to write it and rest
like, what, what is your reaction to that? What do you do differently?
What do you think about that?
Does it change what your plan is for securing that application?
-- Is it scary because it's new
-- Josh and I have generally
worked at more mature companies that already use multiple languages anyways.
So we're, we're kind of biased. Like
I recently built a project in a combination of javascript with, you know,
one file and uh PHP because it just worked so much better in PHP.
So I'm like, fine, like you want to use whatever, like I'm ok with that, but
I suspect for a lot of companies they would,
it would just be the, oh
the CC. Ok. What is this?
Right?
And I think fundamentally if you have mature process, like you have code reviews,
you have
like does it compile cleanly?
It has to compile cleanly before we ship it.
You can't just, like you said,
wrap like I wrapped it in a safe block and I fixed the compiler error,
right? Because that's happened like we had that openness C thing where,
oh, it's using an unitized thing. OK?
I made the air go away and it turns
out now it's only generating 64,000 different keys.
That's it.
You know.
So I think that would be as a security person, I'd be worried about those gas
that
might hit us,
you know, versus
the more kind of high level things like, yeah, we do code reviews. Yeah, we do.
But like what are the sort of,
what are those little gas
that might grab us?
I think that would probably be my biggest concern. But
I think for more normal uh
organizations, there would be a lot of that fear of the unknown,
I suspect would be the biggest thing.
-- Yeah,
-- I mean, I think one of the challenges would be
the
getting the people to use rust the way it's meant to be used. Right?
I mean, that's always a challenge where you have your, your culture,
you have the language you're using internally.
And like an example is like at work,
we have a lot of Python and so we obviously hire people who are good at Python.
And if we told them one day, hey, you have to start using rust,
there would definitely be a revolt.
Now, if someone came to me and said, we're going to build a new program in C,
I'd be like, no effing way.
Like I will die on this hill. It is not gonna be C
but if I was looking to build, say like an embedded device, you know, where I,
I need that compiled language and, and C is what I'm trying to do.
I think you could
definitely shepherd some of those people in the direction of rust for sure.
And of course, even then,
even then the security people can say
using C is a terrible idea and we're going
to have memory safety problems and all these issues.
And if you have a team of 100 people that only know c you're gonna lose that battle,
right?
I mean, that's just the sad reality of it.
But I think, yeah, if, if someone came to me and said,
what language like should we use?
Rust? My answer would obviously be yes.
Like I think it's great in, in many cases and,
and part of it too,
the beauty of modern languages is things like rust crates or you've got Ruby gems,
you've got PP,
you've got no J SNP M. Right. Like that ecosystem is
the power you get, I think and rust obviously has,
has crates which we haven't even talked about because
there's so much other stuff to talk about.
We have to have you come back and we can cover crates.
But I mean, we're, we're dragging out but thi this has been a treat, Carol,
I'll give you the last word and then we'll wrap this one up.
-- All
-- my, my other question,
maybe you can have this as you can have someone else on the show.
But because I,
you, you two are kind of blue team and this is more of a red team question.
My question would be if you're trying to pest a rost application and, you know,
you don't have
the memory safety problems to try and look for and
take advantage of is how would you approach that differently?
And I don't know if that's,
if there are many people doing that yet and, and what they would think about that.
And I don't know if you two have any,
-- any thoughts on that
-- from the pen testers. I know they
90. Well,
let's be real,
99% of applications have a known security flaw.
So that's what they typically start with is just
like I have a list of exploits, let's, you know, see, kind of what works.
The other thing obviously is
logic bugs,
but especially where systems interface.
Mhm. Mhm. So, I, I think for a lot of pent testers it would look about the same.
Maybe, I don't know. This is a great question and we'll assign it as homework
because
there is a project called Os S Fuzz that Google funds
and Os S Fuzz fuzzes all kinds of stuff.
They Fuzz Java, they Fuzz go, they Fuzz C and obviously if you fuzzing Java or go,
you're not going to see memory safety issues.
I am certain
they are fuzzing something written in rust somewhere in there.
And so we could go and look at those findings and see what kind of
bugs are turning up and they're obviously
going to be logic bugs because memory safety
is a non-issue.
Well,
that's not true because I bet you there is a nontrivial amount of rust
code that ends up in unsafe land calling into sea libraries or other things.
So I, I don't know.
Now, now I'm going to go and try to figure this out, I suspect,
but I'm interested to hear what the show you have on this.
And
yeah, this is, this is, this will be good. This is fun. It'll
-- I have too much work to do
-- already.
There is direct cargo support for Os S Fuzz and rust. Like there's a Google bucket.
-- There's
-- definitely people fuzzing.
There
-- we go.
-- It looks really simple to do
-- Os S Fuzz is fantastic.
-- OK. Last, last question,
last
question.
What's your favorite shop? Vac attachment?
The one that lets me get the water off my garage floor. It's kind of like um
it's like the scoop thing but with a bit of curve to
it so that you can get just like that one or two millimeters
to get all the water off the floor. Because that's like a six month problem here.
I like that little pointy one that can get in all the crevices.
Mine's brush.
That's true. The brush is nice because the brush lets you sweep away.
Do you have
pets?
I used to have a cat. Yeah.
Dust
and stuff. Yeah,
that's
true.
-- That's true. Without the brush you can't remove the dust, can
-- you?
That's
fair.
I knew I knew you would have opinions on this.
Of course. Who doesn't? Right.
Like,
it's funny too. Actually I own two shot backs because I have a really big heavy one.
And then up in my, like, workshop in the top of my garage,
I have a light one that I can carry around.
Yeah.
So,
anyway,
-- anyway,
-- I bought a small one for cleaning the car because I,
like,
wear it. Like,
no, I need the big one for the car because I need like the super ultra suction power.
But
they're better. They're much better now.
My small one is actually more powerful than my bigger one
because my smaller one is new and my old one is
mine.
Anyway, I'm calling. No, we're done. We're done now. Thank you, Carol.
This has been an absolute treat.
Thank you for bringing us into the weeds before the end. I appreciate that.
-- Thank
-- you so much for having
me.
It's been awesome.
I will put links to Carol and her book and all the other stuff from the show notes.
So. All right. Thank you, Carol. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you, everyone.
Go to open source security podcast.com. Hit up the show,
not, it's easy. Podos
says podcast hashtag hit us up on social media.
Have a great rest of your day. Everybody.
You beat me to it.
All right. All right. Awesome. Thanks, everyone. Bye bye. Thanks.