Hello and welcome to episode 45 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime.
Josh Bresser.
How are you? Kurt?
I'm doing better
better.
What? Oh, you're cold. Yes. But now you, you lack the deep sexy voice. You had just a
mere couple of days ago.
It's just, it's amazing to wake up and be able to breathe.
No. No. That's called being alive.
-- Well, I mean,
-- through my nose, yes. Life is amazing. That's right.
Everybody, you heard it here.
Um,
no, II, I know what you mean. There's nothing worse than being sick for a long time
and having the horrible pain of sniffling and coughing and,
and just being sick and tired of it.
Well, you know, it's kind of like, it reminds me, like, info
that we're, like, not sick enough to actually, like, you know,
turn it all off and fix it,
but we're like, just a little bit sick enough to be annoying.
Like, I wasn't sick enough to take a sick day for sure. Right.
I was nowhere near that sick.
So I'm, you know, but I'm also sick enough that I, you know,
enjoying life is kind of a chore.
I'm just a little bit tired and achy and, you know,
general malaise.
Oh, and I'm really sad because I found out these magic,
the gathering cards that I thought were counterfeit or real.
How are they real? They were
all jacked up, you said?
Well, uh, so a friend of ours who used to date a professional magic,
the gathering player.
So she
knows a lot about this stuff like
osmosis, right? Because she dated this guy for like seven years, I think. Anyways,
apparently those cards that are printed on both sides with a character is a new car.
It's a new game mechanic that they're doing.
That seems insane.
Yeah.
Um, and she ripped one or two cards and yeah,
they look legit and the printing looks good.
Like I, you know,
showed her the picture with the rosettes and stuff
and the rosettes seem to match up what's online.
So my next theory is that somewhere somebody is
shucking packs of magic cards to find the good ones
and then putting the garbage into these packs and
selling them on to the dollar store to like,
essentially monetize their garbage.
I can vaguely understand that.
Uh
Interesting.
Is that
apart from counterfeiting or like, you know,
monetizing your garbage cards? I, I
-- cannot imagine what other scenario these cheap cards fit into it
-- is.
I, what, what's the year on them? Are they, are they last year's cards?
Uh, they are.
I've seen, this is, I don't even know.
Oh, yeah, they are. Uh, well, they're copyright 2016.
So I, I wonder if they, last year's set because what, what magic has done actually.
And this is really clever of them.
It used to be. You just kept buying cards and buying, and buying and buying.
And obviously there were some really good cards from every set
that, that got released and then at some point they basically started saying,
all right, this is the 2016 set.
All the tournaments held in 2016 are going to be
done with 2016 cards to level the playing field.
Interesting note, here's one from
-- 2014. So
-- I wonder,
I wonder if those are just old cards that they
had like a warehouse and they're unloading them because,
because let's face it too.
If you're a like magic player,
you don't want last year's cards because you can't use them in tournaments,
right?
And in fact,
this is a great scam too because I bought magic
the gathering off of steam some time ago for,
I think it was like 2013 or something.
And then
they, they offered to let me buy the 2014 edition for a mere 10% off.
And I thought this is crazy.
I will admit, I'm kind of sad. These aren't counterfeit cards because
I, I had kept meaning to go to the,
the local dollar store and see if I would find the same thing.
And so I guess you, you've just saved me probably a bunch of money,
but I was also hoping that this was going to turn into like,
some sort of crazy detective story, which it clearly is not.
Yeah. No, it's,
uh,
what I really, well, hm.
Is there like an app where I can take a picture of the
card with my phone and it'll tell me what the card's worth.
I don't know. But I know there are websites you can go to that, that sell these cards
and you can obviously do it like on ebay,
but there's a certain amount of risk involved.
And so people are hesitant sometimes,
-- but there you heard
-- about that guy whose mom cleaned out his room at home in Japan.
What? Right now?
So there was this guy in Japan and his mom cleaned out,
like he's an adult and his mom was like,
cleaning out his room and she basically posted to some card
auctioning site. Like, hey, I found a bunch of old cards in my son's room. Oh, man.
And one of them was a black orchid,
black lotus,
black lotus. Sorry. Yeah.
And, uh, so that's apparently worth like upwards of 30 grand. Super
expensive. I, I do. I still, I used to know a guy that had one.
-- I don't know if he still does. I, I'd have sold it long ago if
-- I own it anyway.
So it's it's kind of sad because she,
she took down the auction with like some message that basically we stated,
like my son called and yelled at me for a while.
And so we've taken the auction down now.
-- But
-- you know what's really funny about that is this, this reminds me of,
of baseball cards
is
in the US people collect baseball cards. Well, they, they kind of used to, it's not
as popular,
it used to be.
And like when I was a kid,
you always heard these stories about these people with like, you know,
Mickey Mantle rookie card that's worth like a billion dollars or whatever.
And,
and so everybody has saved all their baseball cards
and they have almost no value anymore
because everyone has them, you know, if you have the really old ones, they,
they have value and
it's
right, exactly where everyone's keeping them now.
And the only reason the old stuff have value is because like everyone's
mom threw them away because they thought this is just junk under the bed
and,
and I suspect there's, there's kind of a security story in this for us,
we can tie this back to is
we often
like to think about things in the context of the past.
And in fact, I have a blog post, I'm working on about this, which
it's, I, I did not do this on purpose, not to plug myself. But,
you know, we think about things like five or 10 years ago.
Like my favorite example is run antivirus.
No,
you don't need it because your operating system comes
with various features that are vastly superior to antivirus.
And when you install antivirus,
a lot of times it turns this stuff off and it's basically just insecure crap anyway.
And so you're actually in worse shape today
if you're running antivirus than if you're just letting
you know your, your, your operating system kind of secure. You.
Well, what really gets me about antivirus is I, I mean,
I still sort of see the argument on P CS for a lot of people, but fundamentally,
I can't think of a single person. I know with a mobile phone that has antivirus on it,
it doesn't really work there.
But I think even in the context of the PC,
if you're running a modern version of Windows,
it comes with something called Windows Defender,
which is essentially antivirus built in.
Plus they have all of their
secure boot and you need signed binaries and all this stuff.
And so basically, if, if you don't mess with your machine,
you're in pretty good shape.
I mean, realistically speaking,
-- well,
-- I thought Windows Defender started life out as a,
basically an antivirus light.
Wasn't
it got additional features
-- I
-- pick some up, which I don't think is a surprise,
but I think it falls into the good enough camp and I know there's
probably a lot of people shaking their fist at their computer right now or,
or phone or whatever it is, you're, you're listening on.
But, I mean, let's face it, it, it's good enough.
It's not perfect, but it's certainly good enough.
Yeah.
Well, what I'm really impressed with was, you know, with both ecosystems.
Android and, uh, Apple.
Um, I know nothing of the Windows phone ecosystem.
I've actually only ever seen one in the wild twice now in, like, over 10 years.
And I've actually, in the last like probably five years,
only seen a blackberry device twice.
I haven't seen a blackberry since
I, I can't even remember.
But the only reason I see a Windows phone is because my brother in law owns one and I,
I mock him incessantly about this.
And
yeah, anyway,
anyway, but, but at the same time,
the Windows phone ecosystem is essentially dead at this point.
I mean, let's face it there, there's nothing there.
But, uh, but basically as far as I know both Android and Apple,
uh
you know,
don't really have a problem with viruses in the traditional
sense of like arriving via email or web pages,
you know, to your device.
It's, it's often malicious apps
which I mean, if you're going to download and run dancing hamster dot EFC, then,
you know. Yeah.
Right.
And, and even then my understanding is on I OS, this is not near the problem,
it is on Android for a couple of reasons is so on.
I Os, you can't install random
I OS apps off the internet. Right.
Uh, you can only get stuff off the Apple store as far as I know.
And the other way to do it is through the developer stuff.
But I mean, to do that, you got to jump through a bunch of
things.
You know, my mom's never gonna do it.
I've never done it and I probably never will.
Right. Right. And on Android
it's not
as easy as kind of one click. But you can get unsigned absence too.
Right.
And so you've got that,
but also the Android App store from what I understand is
slightly less curated than the I OS App store is.
But most importantly
is most of these Android phones haven't seen a security update ever.
And so it's easy to get root.
Yeah, that's, I mean, that's one of the reasons I, you know,
I keep saying I went with the Apple ecosystem is I know for sure.
I get 3 to 4 years of updates without a carrier in between me and those updates.
And,
-- and
-- this is why I bought a Nexus phone straight from Google
because I wouldn't dream of buying a phone off a carrier.
But, I mean,
the reality is how many people are going to have that as a
-- major or even a minor buying decision when they get
-- a phone.
Nobody,
-- nobody does
-- security
-- people.
-- And I,
I, I shudder when I see most people take their phones out of their pocket because it,
it's got like, you know, the, the local carrier branding all over it
and, you know, it hasn't seen a security update ever.
Well, it's like, what's funny is, uh, so at school on my kids' school,
obviously they have ipads with educational apps loaded on them.
Right.
And so I
went
into the, uh, settings
storage to basically just to take pictures of all the apps that are installed,
right? With the names. So I could hunt them down and put them on my kids' ipad at home.
Right. So they have the same stuff
because,
you know, he's like, I want to play this game and I'm like, what the heck is that right?
And it's like something that they have at school that they play.
That's educational. Ok, cool.
And this poor ipads, like I really want to update to I OS 10.3 please, please, please,
you know this
and I'm like, uh, I like, I really wanted to hit that button.
Oh, God, I wanted to hit that button so much, but I didn't because, you know,
uh, then that ipad is not available for like the next half hour, you know,
some kids gonna fri out.
But, um, you know, that's what got me is like, these are not super well cared
for devices oftentimes,
right? They're people's phones, they turn them on, they turn them off.
Apparently a lot of people don't even have a lock like a pin for their lock screen.
Uh They don't.
And this is actually one of the reasons I,
I love the fingerprint scanners they're adding because fingerprint scanners,
people like using those but people won't add a
password to their phone because it's too inconvenient.
So,
and that was actually only the only consistent reason
I've actually heard of people who bought uh like
apple smartwatches was so that they didn't have to
haul their phone out of their pocket to like,
check what a text or a message was.
-- You know
-- what I think about that sometimes is I see that as an advantage,
but you have to charge the stupid things every single day, which I see is
my
disadvantage.
I, my phone runs down to usually 20 30% by the end of the day, you know,
especially if I'm running a castle crush
or, you know, some 3d game like minecraft, you know, playing with my kids and
that just canes the battery. Like if it's just me using it
for boring stuff, then, you know, it's like 20 30%
for
a day.
So I charge my phone every night. So I, I don't see that as a problem because it's like
I put my gla
or when I used to wear glasses, right?
I would put my glasses down on the desk next to me
and go to sleep and then wake up and put them on
the
same keep my phone by my bed.
I purposely leave it in my office downstairs. And so I basically just plug it in.
Sometimes, not even at night, quite often,
I'll just set it on the desk and plug it in in the morning because, you know,
it takes like an hour to charge you things now.
And I,
I, I'm,
I understand what you're saying,
but for some reason,
my brain tells me that this is super inconvenient and you don't want one.
So, whatever,
like I agree partly.
But here's one thing I'm really looking forward to
is when things have induction chargers built into them,
it has an induction, it,
that's how it charges.
So
we should
just put it down on your night stand on the pad.
That's exactly how this works.
But there's also the issue of, I don't even want to do that. I want to just charge.
Right.
Yes, I know.
But here, right. Anyway, anyway, let's move on to another topic.
That makes me sound less crazy.
Well, you know, these little,
it's like those stupid stickers on fruit now that I hate.
Right, because,
you know, those are edible.
-- They are
-- obviously because people,
you know,
but uh,
what I love is when I get a piece of fruit that doesn't have one and
I'm turning this piece of fruit around and
around and around and around until I'm like,
oh, yeah,
sticker,
you've been doxed by fruit.
Uh, anyway, anyway, let's move on to Squirrel Mail,
which I think is one of the more interesting things that happened
-- over the last probably week or two. Do you want to explain the bizarre story?
-- So
-- Squirrel Mail actually is a program I used to use.
-- I, I think everybody did, man.
I remember when
came out. It was amazing.
Well, it's ok. So what Squirrel mail is, is it's a PHP application.
So, you know, it's good.
Yeah. Uh
it's been around forever and it basically provides
a nice interface to your email box.
Uh either pop
imap and then, you know, smt,
let's
face it
too late. This was, this was web mail back when like hotmail was just barely a thing.
And so it was huge that you could get your own web mail.
Yeah.
And so I actually set this up for myself and quite a number of people who have like,
you know, a
custom domain on a, you know, on a web host provider, right?
Because that's the other thing, right? Because it was PHP.
You literally just un tarred this package set like three variables, like the
IMAP server, the SMTP server and like the domain name.
And that's literally it. You were done. It just worked. It was awesome.
You could send and receive attachments, you could,
oh, it was a lovely package, right? And then of course Gmail came along and bloop
um
you know, nobody wants to run their own email anymore. That's just clearly insane.
Um,
so, yeah, I mean, so Squirrel Mail, I think part of it is, uh, it's a mature project.
Right. Because it's been around for going on 1015 years.
It's pretty old.
Yeah.
Or maybe even more than 15 years. It might have been pre 2000.
Well, no, it wouldn't have been because PHP anyways
point being is that it's pretty mature and stable and, you know,
what's interesting to me though is they still have nightly builds
of it and they do have like a little bit of,
you know, uh activity going on with it.
Um sort of maintenance, like make sure it works with current PHP.
Um But anyway,
there was a really bad flaw in squirrel mail uh that
basically allows remote code execution via like sending a wonky email
and um you know, like kudos to the developers, they actually fixed it
in the
uh in the source code.
Um They don't appear to have one of their emails said they cut a new release,
but I can't find that new release and they host off of Source Forge,
which is a nightmare to.
No, nobody should be using Source Forge anymore.
What I love is there's that one ad blocker
that just blocks like all of Source forge now
because if you go to Source Forge now,
like it literally looks like one of those casino websites
-- from like two 1000.
-- I know it's so bad,
-- you know, it's so sad because it was, you know, how the mighty have fallen.
-- Right.
-- Uh
-- It, it's the nature of everything. I mean, someday that will be
github and I know people don't like it when I say that, but it, it's going to happen.
I
mean, look at slash
talk.
Uh, slash
That is still mildly interesting, at least.
Yeah. But I mean,
-- I
-- don't know, I
have an ad blocker and I only ever look at
stories through the RSS reader and I won't lie.
Usually if it's on slash dot It was on Reddit yesterday.
So I don't usually look at them, but every now and then.
So, yeah, they still only have the 1.4 0.22 release on their Source Forge page,
which is from 2011.
-- Yes, that was that release.
-- That's
crazy.
Well, so here's, here's my take on this is
even if they updated the code
and they cut a new release to fix this one issue,
they haven't done a release in a very long time
and it's no secret that software doesn't age. Well, if you just
maintain your software and you, you're fixing minor issues
in reality, if, if you think of it as kind of a, a graph, your graph is going down
to the right, it is not going up, it is not staying the same.
You have to be constantly taking care of this because
as software gets older,
there are new ways to attack it.
There are new libraries that work better and let's face it,
scroll mail probably has some old scary libraries
in it from PHP that are just dangerous.
It doesn't work on a lot of modern PHP unless you're running a DEV version. Right.
Because PHP
for the last 10
years,
that's
what was that, that setting,
uh use global or something where it would
just magically take uh get and post parameters,
variables and, and automatically assign them in PHP with such a train wreck.
Well, but you know, it worked,
right. People built
apps with PHP that worked and they got stuff done and,
you know, as much as all,
all I do hate these languages sort of at a very
visceral level for making it so easy to be so bad.
-- People get stuff done in
-- them.
They, they do and working and wrong beats, correct and non-existent every time.
I mean,
there's been massive ecommerce platforms built on php.
I mean, wordpress, it's like a third of the websites
like doesn't, doesn't Facebook use PHP on the back end,
right. Yeah, they, and they built that whole um
not
z what was the other thing, the accelerator that precompiling stuff and
all sorts of crazy stuff for performance, right?
Um You know, same thing with like, you know, uh what was it, Ebay using Java,
right? I'm not a big fan of Java, but I think it was ebay
was using Java for the longest time and I mean, clearly it works.
No, they were,
were, they know who's node anyway, whatever it doesn't matter.
And, and I guess part of it too is
there is every language you can imagine in you somewhere no matter what it is.
And, and I guess the lesson here is
if, if you're consuming something, make sure it has updates in maybe the last,
let's say two years,
six years is too long.
This comes back to that argument of, you know,
kind of what does it mean when you see software with no CV S,
uh, that means it's terrible and nobody's looking at it.
-- That's what that means,
-- basically. Yeah. One of three things has happened.
One, nobody's looking at it.
Two people have looked at it but the upstream has fought those CV S and, like,
managed to get them not assigned.
It's worse than number one.
Yeah, exactly.
And then number three is, of course,
absolutely nobody's using it or even aware that this thing exists,
which is the same as number one, I think.
I, I think fundamentally it's, if, if there are no C DS for something, it, it's bad.
That's a bad thing.
Like, you know, run away.
So, anyway,
yeah, it's, uh, but I mean, what, what really
is interesting to me is, I mean,
I think a lot of people probably pick squirrel mail for the same reason I did,
which was set up is so simple
and I mean, there are clearly far better,
you know, solutions now like round cube.
Uh what is it
is round
still around even II, I remember that.
That was exciting because that was an Ajax mail reader similar to Gmail
and Squirrel mail was very HTML. At least the last time I read it, I, I suspect
here we go CV. From,
-- well, this year, last year,
-- see, that's a good sign.
Most of them exercise too, so not too severe. You know, that's also nice to see.
Right.
I would agree with that.
And so anyway, the lesson here is probably don't use squirrel mail
and more importantly is before you use something, take a look at it and make sure it,
it actually has somebody taking care of
it properly because I think even though squirrel
mail might have commits,
they aren't releasing updates so they clearly aren't taking care of things
on the back end the way they should be. And so don't use Squire Mail. Kids.
Part of me wonders are they able to release updates?
Because, I mean, I've seen projects where it's sold,
but the guy that has the access to do it is gone.
I've, I've heard of that before
and it,
it, I don't know, you know what, let's, let's move on to something happier.
How about because all of our stealing,
stealing all my mail. That's what was the site, uh,
-- that
-- bulk unsubscribe. Unroll me Unroll dot
unroll.me. That's it. Thank you. That
I,
I don't even know what to think about this.
And I have to admit at first I was really confused, but
so literally, all Unroll me.unroll.me does apparently is
helps unsubscribe you for mailing lists and junk newsletters, which I,
I thought that's what the spam button in gmail was for.
I guess,
you know, why would I need that third party?
So, and apparently unroll.me of course,
was you'd have to give it like access to all your stuff,
mail.
It wanted access to all of your mail because logically it has to read
all of your mail in order to decide what to unsubscribe you from.
And then the thing they don't tell you is they're also kind
-- of uh taking it all and storing it and selling it to
-- Uber
and other companies and apparently storing it not well secured as three buckets
and
why, why would they care? Right. I mean, let's face it.
It,
I, but here's, here's what I guess I think about this is this is clearly a service for,
we'll say technical ish people. I don't expect anyone to find this.
Like I would not expect my parents to come across this service, for example. Right.
They might if the word of mouth or targeted advertising because I,
-- I've seen one thing where like
-- I literally
confident my parents would never come across this
or it's one of those things I've seen,
I've seen similar things on Facebook like this stupid app that does blah, blah,
blah.
And I'm like, oh Lord, are people actually installing this and using it, you know.
Yeah, the answer is yes they are.
-- But
-- ok,
so people buy into multilevel marketing schemes.
Normal people probably wouldn't understand the context of this.
But I think anyone who even has a
remote technical background should honestly understand this,
this
how the permissions work of things linked against like your Google
and Facebook accounts and in whatever all of these kind of o
office
type accounts
is,
it's not a secret.
And if you don't understand it, like where have you been for the last five years?
I just went to unrolled on me and you know what?
It's really easy and clean, like it literally says,
clean up your inbox instantly see a list of all your subscription emails,
unsubscribe easily from whatever you don't want.
Get started.
Now you click get started now and then it literally says sign up,
it's got four buttons, sign up with Google, sign up with Yahoo,
sign up without looking, sign up with AOL.
And if I click sign up with Google, obviously, I'm not gonna do this.
Uh I get a uh terms and privacy policy,
it's gonna be a disaster.
Let me and nobody reads.
If I click continue, then
uh unroll.me would like to read, send, delete and manage your email,
view your email address,
view your basic profile info and manage your contacts
uh we're gonna click, deny.
Oh, oops. Looks like you declined access retry sign up.
No.
So
for a normal person, they wouldn't understand what that means. And I get that.
But I also suspect
this is,
I don't know,
I feel like this is targeting slightly more technical
people because normal people don't subscribe to mailing lists.
So part of it I've noticed is when I do sign up for stuff that wants me to sign up,
you know, with an all
off account
is I'll click on my options.
Like, usually it's like what Twitter, Google, Facebook,
linkedin are kind of the four,
right?
And what's really fascinating to me is quite often a lot of them,
very different
um
levels of access that they want or need.
And I suspect for some of them, like,
you know, I suspect some of them are pushing back a bit more, you know, um
than the other providers, right?
Like Facebook is basically quite happy to give quite a bit of access to
your stuff or a lot of these things almost always ask for access to like
send and receive tweets. And I'm like, you know, good Lord.
And it's weird to me that Twitter like allows that, you know,
-- a very narrow group of specific apps,
-- let's face it, they don't really care.
But I, I had an app on my phone once and I don't even remember what this was, but they had
a thing where they wanted to link it with Facebook.
And it said one of the permissions was post to my wall. And I was like, nope.
And they said in it they said post to your wall, we promise not to do this.
And I'm like, then you don't need it.
You just
come on guys, that's
how,
-- you know, it's like, oh, I just need to,
-- uh, you gotta love it.
But I guess at the same time how would a a normal person will say my parents
even remotely found them? Oh, they said they won't do it. It's probably fine.
It's like, don't please just don't do that
well and see traditionally companies had
a bit of, you know,
trust and brand that they worried about but like something like unroll me,
you know,
-- day
-- care,
you
know, they'll just fold up
shop.
So this is, this is a good, a good topic as well is
we
I I don't,
I guess it's still a thing but the obsession
with brand and brand image and what it means.
But let's face it man.
If you look at Target,
if you look at Yahoo,
-- if you look at all these companies that have just
-- targets a very bad example,
horribly pumped
in
Canada. Perhaps that that's another story.
But you get the idea right?
There's all these companies that have had terrible things done to their brand
and they like literally cause harm to people because their identities were stolen
and at the end of the day
it doesn't matter,
you know, the
-- phones to catch fire.
-- Right.
Exactly.
And I mean, I'll never forget it.
I was, I was at a, I was at an event one time talking to somebody about
Yahoo getting hacked. This was like the fourth or fifth story.
You're
gonna have
to come
out there were,
there have been a
lot.
It would. Right. And that's just it. Right.
-- That's part of it is,
-- it's like the old Sony
hacks, right?
We're talking about this
and he's saying, oh man, you know,
this is gonna be terrible for them and then
they need to get better at security and this.
And I said, all right, let me ask you a question,
what is happening to the Yahoo stock, right? This minute.
And this was literally like the day this kind of known.
So this was like as hot as news gets
and he says, oh, it's gotta be tanking. And I said, it's up, it's up, it's up two points
and he's like, no. And I pulled up my phone, it was actually up like 2.5 by then.
And,
and I said, look, man, people just don't care like that's the reality of it.
And which is also terrifying to me because as soon as some of these brand,
people figure out that like the brand is nearly untouchable
once you've built some a certain level of trust.
That's terrifying.
Look at what Nestle did in, like, was it India or Africa with pushing?
That was Africa.
Yeah. Pushing condensed milk for babies. And then they,
yeah,
well, no, it ended, they were pushing, uh, I think it was Coca
Cola as a better
healthier alternative than.
Right. But
that's not
something
-- but
-- whatever.
But
the point is these companies are doing things that are like horrendous.
Um, and then my favorite is somebody's like, oh, well, these companies have never,
like, killed a whole bunch of people.
And I was like, have you ever heard of Union Car Buy?
They might have, it's, it's happened,
right? But we don't need the EPA, it's fine.
So the reality is a part of it too is like, well, appliances are a great example.
There's what, four appliance manufacturers like globally now, basically.
Um, or like, you know, internet service in Canada, you know,
we were talking about that before the show and
Josh is apparently quite horrified about what I have to pay for, you know, uh,
-- internet access on my phone. You
-- know, it's really funny about that though.
And this is totally human nature. It makes me feel better about my
service.
But then at the same time I'm like, no,
this is not like I shouldn't feel good because Kurt has something worse than me.
Like we both want better.
Yeah, exactly.
So, you know, like a lot of it now is like, for a lot of these companies, you know,
I can't really
opt out because I need these services or products,
you know, a great example. Um,
how many major Canadian banks do you think support two factor authentication?
Uh
100. That's, I was close.
Yeah, true. You were close. But yeah, so I was,
I was trying to find a bank in like a major bank in Canada.
I don't, you know, so that when I travel, I, you know,
can find an ATM or a branch like in Vancouver or Toronto.
Uh,
no.
Uh, you know what I, I
think about this a lot and my bank does not offer two factor authentication either.
And, but here's the deal is
if somebody breaks into my bank account,
I
have
a
problem though.
I mean, they're gonna, granted I won't have money for a little while,
but at the end of the day I'm going to get it all back.
See, here's my, my current threat profile is my six year olds.
No, if your kids can log into your bank account and steal your money,
-- like they've earned it as far as I'm concerned,
-- keeps trying to pass
like the, the protocol now is ok,
Felix turn around and he has to turn around and cover his eyes.
-- I
-- thought you used last pass.
I do. But I mean, when I'm typing in my pin to my phone or, well, not my phone but my, I
read.
Yeah, I do.
And that's why that's why I upgraded to an iphone
se was to get the fingerprint reader so he can't
get into my phone.
You're solving your problem with technology.
But uh, you know, my kids could easily grab my credit card out of my wallet.
-- Register an Amazon account and like start buying all the candy.
-- Look.
All right, man. If your kids do that, like
you, you raise deviant
and
right, you, you, your, your, your problem is gonna be keeping them out of jail,
not like your credit card.
Let's face it
anyway. And I, I suspect that's not a practical threat model. But,
and so anyway, but here's the thing is I,
I've come to realize is I'm less concerned about my money in
my bank account than I am about like my gmail or Facebook accounts
because they're tied to lots of stuff.
And if I lose them, it becomes insanely difficult to get them back.
Well, there's also a very clear, well established legal and procedural framework,
-- dealing with your money getting ripped off. It's
-- regulated.
That's the, that's the word
here. It's,
you know, the challenge,
for example comes in when you have to deal with identity theft,
right? That's much more difficult.
And even then there is still ways you can
put credit freezes and you can alert your bank.
And
I was actually just reading on Reddit and
they were talking about um some threads on this
and um
you know, this person,
uh who in their state is a person with the exact same name born on the same day.
Oh,
man, that's brutal.
Well, and the problem is police checks,
right.
Whenever they do a police check,
they don't look up the picture or the signature or whatever description,
it's just like,
you know, name, like, what's your name and birthday?
Actually?
You know, it's really funny is I've, I've heard of these stories before where, yeah,
they use primarily name and birthday as not even birthday in some instances.
But I knew people with names of, we'll say, uh,
convicted felons
and
they would struggle in some instances to, to interact with, you know, certain,
like, banks and shops and things like that
name. Saddam Hussein in the UK, who can't get a bank account?
That's brutal. And it's kind of like,
well,
I would, I, I mean,
I can't speak for this individual but in my case I
would just change my name to almost anything else like.
Right.
I mean, let's face it,
change it to Donald Trump. Everything will be cool. Like,
well, I, I get that too. I mean, that would be like if your name was Adolf Hitler,
you've got,
you know.
Right.
Right. But you know what I mean? Well, it, it's tricky.
-- It's,
-- well, the problem is, for example, there's like, there's been cases where,
like the four year old has the same name as somebody on the watch list and they get,
uh, in fact a friend of mine, his dad gets, uh, pulled off to the, whatever they call,
like, the, the terrible inspection.
Right. Right.
Because he apparently has the same name as someone on the no fly list.
Even though this guy travels like hundreds of thousands of miles a year by air,
they keep pulling him out of the line because he has the wrong name.
Yeah. Well, and again, these systems are basically, you know, creaky
old ancient systems, like they run on like name and maybe birthday if you're lucky.
Right. You know, like,
yes,
I hate to say it, but this is one of the few arguments I have for a national,
you know, biometric database is
to sort of try and get rid of these false positives and make it, you know, a little bit.
I don't know.
I just, but knowing the government, well,
pretty much any government would make a bit of a hash of it.
It's, and we'd have a whole new set of problems, you know, because for example,
apparently fingerprints aren't as unique and individual as we thought they.
-- That is what it's looking like.
-- Yes.
You know,
so, ok. Well, I've read things like, you know, the, the blood vessels in your hands.
They, um,
apparently Japanese ATM S use that the advantage also being that
you don't have to touch anything just as a thermal camera,
you,
-- your hand above it.
-- That's
awesome.
That sounds
so Japanese, I
love
it.
Um You know, because quite honestly I know that these things aren't gonna like,
it's not like an old D and D trap where you, like, you know,
you put your head up and appear in the hole and a spike comes out and
you in the eye.
But at the same time, like every time I see like those movie Irish Readers,
that's like my first thought is like, oh D and D, you know that dungeon master,
he's a bit of a, you know, jerk and
you're gonna get a sharp spike in the eyeball.
Uh Where do you bank? Clearly? Not where I do.
But uh and also, you know, there's people without eyes and stuff,
-- right?
-- And that's the other problem with biometrics is that
somewhere, somebody's missing that piece of their body?
Yes.
Yes, they are. And,
and then, you know,
they're going to have to jump through a billion hoops to like get
into their ATM account every time they want to withdraw 20 bucks,
you know,
and that's what really gets me is my
fear of standardizing on a biometric system is that
the failure scenario will be really ugly because it'll be like, oh,
well a computer says
that's how it works.
Now, man, I mean, if you go to nearly any institution and you try to say,
get a loan or open an account or something and
if the computer pops up a window that tells them,
do not give this person help.
That's the end. They, they're not gonna help you.
Yeah.
But I mean,
when it's tied to your identity and it's maybe your basic form of proving identity,
then it really
becomes
a
-- problem
-- and
you can get replacement ID right now as long as you have an address to mail it to,
um, things like that, you know.
I know. I know.
Oh, it's madness. Uh, let's talk about
gr security.
-- Yeah.
-- What do you think of that one?
Well, I think it's like Nessus,
I mean, here is a guy and a small company, you know,
pouring a lot of work and time into a product
that then a whole bunch of other people, you know, free ride on.
Well, let's, let's talk about what GR security is.
First is there, is a fellow named, uh, Brad Spengler.
I
thought
Spender is his handle. Uh, and we'll refer to him as Spender from now on.
So,
Spender has a patch set for the Linux kernel called, well,
there's GR security and there's packs and he's involved with both
of them and I don't totally understand the relationship there,
but fundamentally brand is
scary, smart.
And he created these security patches for the Linux kernel
that add a significant amount of real security and like this stuff is the real deal,
right?
No, it actually does make it
-- right.
-- It's, it's very good.
And what's basically happened though is brand has a
company that kind of I guess supports these patches
because it, I mean, it's GP L two code. So you can't really,
you can say it's being sold but anyone who has the
source code can pretty much do whatever they want with it.
But kind of the trick here is there have been a
number of organizations that have just taken these patches and used them
without paying for support in any way and, and in the open source universe,
I'm not saying there's anything wrong with that necessarily.
But I think the thing I do have a problem with
is they were bragging about including gr security
in their product
and that's not really OK. But, and then at the same time, the upstream kernel
wasn't super receptive to working with these guys,
nor were they receptive to the upstream.
And so
none of their patches really ever made it anywhere. And so it, it,
it's just a strange, crazy story and I guess, well, it's,
it's happened before where you have this free rider problem.
And typically one of two things happens, you continue to have a free rider problem,
but whoever is doing the work, manages to figure out a way to deal with it.
Like
I, I have this already with CV CV has a huge free rider problem
in that.
Even companies who are like becoming CNAs and stuff don't want to do the work.
They're like literally like,
well, who writes the descriptions will you?
But we don't have the resources to do that.
-- Well, if you want to participate in CV, you kind of
-- maybe
this is why you just need to assign everything. A CS S score of 10.
You don't like it, give
us a better one.
But anyway, so that, that's kind of what makes the DWF really tricky to do is I'm,
I have to build a system that accounts for
basically 99.999% of users of DWF will never contribute a thing.
And in fact, we'll try and take our time and energy and be like, oh,
can you please explain XY or Z,
you know,
like not only do they not contribute, but they will try and suck our time and effort,
you know.
Um And
or alternatively,
you have like the N A situation or the GR security situation where they're like,
fine,
we're, we're gonna take our ball home,
-- right?
-- You know, end of story, right? Like
you want to play with our nice ball, then you've got to be.
-- So
-- here's the difference in your example though, is in the case of GR security,
you're not talking about something that's kind of widely used.
But CV E is like the fundamental standard
that, that all of our security is based upon.
So in that instance, like
Miter
just can't say we're taking our ball
and
has funding from DH S. So that's
basically they have a sustainable business model
and the government simply pays it
and that's, that's fine. That works.
I mean, if I could get funding from DH S to run the DW,
if I'd
probably not say no to it.
But
that
be
an American.
Yeah. The, the minor detail. Yeah. But
I mean, that's a perfect example.
That would be a potential business model for GR security. Right.
Where the DH S goes, you know what?
We really want the links kernel to be more
secure because that'll make life for America better.
We're going to fund these guys, right? As an example. And that's the problem, right?
It's hard business models around open source are not easy.
-- If they were, we'd have a lot more open source companies. It,
-- it's very true.
I, I totally get this as,
you know,
obviously I worked for Red Hat previously and I
work for Elastic and we have even in general
problems,
software models around soft or uh sorry
business models around software even in the,
in the close source world are, are still not easy, like look how many fail
-- or don't do well, you know, when they have a spectacular product,
-- right?
It,
it's very true and I think this is one of
the reasons we see as a service being so popular.
But I,
I, I guess
here's kind of my view on this is I don't blame Brad
for the actions he's taken,
ignoring all of the other kind of tertiary
issues around co-operation and working with upstream and,
and things like that because
I can understand how degrading it is when
you're doing good work and you see other people
essentially just taking your good work and not properly
crediting you or rewarding you for what you've done
well. Or in some, I know with
NUS, there were consultants making tons of money using this thing to scan networks,
produce a report,
charge lots of money and like not even contribute
a dollar or a minute of effort back to
NUS
and,
you
know, and just tricky,
uh you know, it's, it's, it's disheartening and it's, it's, well, like I said,
you know, it's the tragedy of the commons, except in this case, you know,
the people who run the commons can be like, well, we're, we're, you know,
we're putting a fence around it,
right? And now,
II I kind of view this in the light of security
where
security is like the ultimate thankless project
where you have people working on this stuff and they
often get no real benefit back from what they're doing.
They aren't appreciated by the people, they're trying to help
and in many cases, they're seen as the bad guy.
And so it is very difficult
to kind of work in an environment like that.
And we don't have a good answer to it today.
I mean, you and I both know that,
that trying to get security built into products is super difficult and it's crazy,
hard to do
I,
-- or
-- even get people to use CV S to
make it easier to identify the vulnerabilities when we're,
you know, talking about them.
-- Like, which one are you talking about?
-- Right. Yeah. Yeah. No, I, I agree completely.
It's,
this is a tricky one and I don't know what the answer is.
I don't know if there will ever be an answer
just because this, these are problems unlike any we've really, ever seen before.
I mean, historically speaking,
you had companies
or, or organizations or whatever,
that would make a thing and then people would buy the thing and that,
that's kind of how it worked and that's, that's not how it is anymore.
I mean,
it is weird.
Well, it kind of reminds me of like building codes, building codes are,
I think a good idea in general because when you see what people will do,
it's terrible.
But building, you know, but what gets me is when they say build to code, you know,
what they're actually saying is built to the legal minimum standards
so we could get away with.
In fact,
that's really funny actually because I
know some licensed plumbers and electricians
and
I was talking to them one day kind of about how they got their licenses
and what that meant and everything and basically the tests they have to take,
they have to know what the bare minimum is according to the code like that.
That's how they passed their test. It's not about doing something. That's right.
No, no, it's doing the absolute bare minimum to pass the inspection. It's like
that's great.
Well, to pass the inspection properly. Right.
Because if you do more than is needed that
it literally, I've seen cases where that might confuse the inspector and end up,
-- you know, with a whole pile of her.
-- That would not surprise me.
I, I would not doubt that at all. And
anyway,
it's heck in security. I take bare minimum at this point.
-- I mean, we don't even have,
-- we haven't even defined a bare minimum.
You know, we can't, like I said, we, well, we can't even
agree on antivirus.
Uh, actually, you know, this,
this is a great transition to kind of the next
story that came up and it sounds like a lot.
You remember all the baby monitor,
horrific stories from like a year ago where people
were hacking into the baby monitors and whatnot.
Well, it turns out that
it sounds like a number of these companies are kind of
cleaning up their act and they've added security to their products.
And so there, there might be hope
there might be. I'm not saying there is,
but
I think it's possible and, but then the question becomes
so there, there's people saying, oh, you know, customer demand made them do this,
which I'm sure it was part of that.
But I wonder how much of it was really they just didn't even know this was a problem.
I suspect there's a lot of that. I mean, what really blew me away many years ago.
Remember the huge Firestone tire recall?
Yes. And what was most interesting to me about it? Was that on the news?
They basically took a car, put like
two or three bad tires on it and like a couple of good tires
and then took it to like 10 or 20 different garages
to see, you know,
like
what, you know, like, oh, I heard about the Firestone tire recall.
Can you please check my tires and tell me if I like need to worry or not.
And of course the answers they got range from like, oh, all your tires are good to,
all your tires are bad too.
Like the good tires were identified as bad tires and
the bad tires were identified as good tires and like,
you know, every single possible combination they're in.
Right. And
yeah, you know, it's, it's
something as basic as here's a list of serial numbers. Please check them
people, you know, mess up right. And
the industry as a whole didn't realize like the tire industry didn't realize like,
oh, these garages, they're idiots
like they can identify these things, you know.
And so they went to, uh, my understanding now is that's why we have RF ID tags in tires
-- is so that we can at least get the damn serial number off of them.
-- But
even with that,
how many garages have the equipment and software
-- to read and interpret those RF ID
-- tags?
I don't know,
but
it's a step in the right direction.
It totally is. I agree with that. It totally,
you know, I just, well,
it's so funny story this weekend I was doing bicycle maintenance and on my bike,
I took photos again of the serial number on my bike
and on my girlfriend's bike, I couldn't find the bloody serial number.
-- There's no serial number stamped on her bike.
-- Is it like a cheap bike?
It's a cheap bike.
It's like,
I just bought my kids a new bike. 100 and 40 bucks, you know, little kids bike.
And it's got like a serial number.
A $140 little kid bike. It's not a cheap bike.
Like the cheap kids bikes are like 50 bucks.
-- Yeah, I, I need something that will survive.
-- Well, I agree with you. I'm, I'm
of paying lots of money for bicycles because you won't regret it.
I actually was really, so the bike I have now, I think I paid like 500 bucks for.
It wasn't, it wasn't cheap, it wasn't super expensive
and it replaced a bike that was bought for me.
That was one of those, like, like Walmart type bikes. Right. Really cheap.
Not, not very good.
And
it lasted me,
I think about a year and I just, like, destroyed it.
Well, it's like lawn mowers now.
-- Uh,
-- I
-- haven't
-- my lawn
100 and $50 lawn mower and it might last one or two seasons.
-- No,
-- no, I bought 100 I bought a lawn mower that cost $100 like, 10 years ago,
10 years ago.
I don't, I don't change the oil. Like, I don't do anything to this
and I've reached the point.
I'm like, some, it's just going to die and I'll accept that fate.
No, I, I've got like a 15 year old lawnmower.
My dad gave me his old lawnmower and it was a cheap lawn mower.
But, you know, back in the day they were built,
well,
maybe we were looking at lawn mowers now and
like a decent lawnmower is going to cost 3,
400 bucks and up.
-- I,
-- that could be, I don't know, I haven't bought one in a long time.
But, well, in this thing, even now, granted,
I've done a bunch of maintenance to keep it alive because cables fell off.
Spark plugs are broken.
I've had to replace all the wheels more than, I mean, it was a crappy lawn mower.
But anyway, it's,
yeah,
I'm waiting for it to die. I haven't started it yet this year.
We'll see if it still works pretty soon.
-- Yeah,
-- you
-- gotta
-- love it though.
But I also also,
I wonder with these baby monitors if part of
it is by adding security into the newer models,
that sort of helps them obsolete the older models
because when you think about it, right.
Baby monitors are something that people typically buy,
they only need them for like a year or two unless they're crazy people.
And then quite often, you know, they give them to a friend who has a kid.
So,
you know, I don't know if we gave ours away.
I had dumb baby monitors from back in the day
and
I
didn't even
-- bother with them.
-- Well, we had uh
why, why did we need one?
We, we would often the, the,
the room we were in to like watch TV in
the evening was very far away from the child's room.
And so it was handy for that or if we were like outside, whatever.
But
anyway, anyway,
I also wonder if it's because these things are recording audio and video.
Now we're starting to talk about wiretap laws and certain
legalities that are, you know, just previously weren't present.
I haven't heard of any of the legalities.
It sounds like from what I've read in this story in this story.
Granted, II,
I don't think I'm gonna trust it a ton and
I haven't found any kind of corroborating evidence behind it.
But the point is,
I think the fact that this is even being talked about
is a huge deal because even a year or two ago,
like the concept of secure baby monitors was what,
who, who are you talking about?
And now, at least people vaguely understand the problem.
Yeah.
Well, it's true of most devices. I mean, the number,
what really impressed me is when I bought that new router for my, uh,
friend's parents.
Um, it came with a sticker on the router and a sticker, the same sticker on the, uh,
the booklet.
And it had, I mean, what looks to me like a random password set.
Very cool. Although I
saw,
I saw 11 time this was on a picture on the internet
but the password was just the last eight characters of the Mac address.
You know what?
That's not reasonably terrible in that.
At least it can't be hacked over the internet.
It's
admin, admin. But still,
and the nice thing too is you can, you can automate that right.
You can have a script that reads the Mac address value
-- and then it is true to that when it
-- is true.
It's not completely terrible,
-- but
-- it's definitely better than a static password across the fleet,
you know.
Um, it's, it's so, it's a step in the right direction
for sure.
I mean, now you're, you're limiting it to local physical Attackers essentially,
which is a, we'll say it's less exciting
but
still, well, it's thousands of people instead of
all of the internet.
-- Yeah,
-- that's true. That's
true. You know.
So it's a definite improvement now, it's not ideal like this, you know, I, I,
hopefully they did a unique password for each one of these routers that
I bought and put the sticker on the router and on the,
uh,
-- on the pamphlet.
-- Totally. That, and nobody would know.
Exactly.
Yeah.
It's, I mean, part of me is, I mean,
I think we were talking about this a few episodes ago but there were
like $20 wireless routers at the store now and I'm so tempted to buy one
just to see how terrible it is.
You should,
you should get it and drop it on the internet and
do nothing and see how long it takes to get pumped.
Well, I love that.
I couldn't even trace down the Chinese manufacturer of this thing.
Like when I googled the make and model and stuff,
there's no result.
How is that even possible?
Like the only result was that, you know, on the website of the store it was on.
So,
anyway, anyway,
whatever. All right, man, we should, we should bring it home.
It's been, it's been fun.
Oh, well, I don't know. What's, what's the verdict?
Are we more or less doomed than we were before we started?
I think awareness is,
I do. I feel like things are starting to slightly move in the right direction.
I don't feel like any of the stories we had today were, were terrible.
This actually comes back to that comment I made to you earlier about the,
the White House correspondents dinner,
right?
So I was watching the White House correspondents dinner and the, uh,
the guy they had doing the main speech, uh,
from the Daily Show can't remember his name off hand and he gave the phrase,
uh, that I thought was really interesting talking about the media
and about how
trust is more important now than the truth.
And I suspect maybe we're sort of getting
to that point in information security and that
we've had a lot of smart people saying what is by and large the truth,
but nobody really trusts or understands them
and they haven't been super effective.
That is
probably reasonable.
And, you know, if we do want to talk to normal people and sea level people and,
you know, people making buying decisions,
-- we need to have their trust.
-- That's a good point. It's kind of,
otherwise we're just a bunch of crazy people
yelling about random stuff that makes no sense.
That is exactly true. And it's,
what is the quote from the big Lebowski, you know.
Yes, you're right, Walter, you're still an asshole, but you're right.
That's kind of what I feel like sometimes is we need to get over that and,
-- and we
-- need to make sure
the classic phrase you should have, you know,
somebody comes to you with a security problem or something
bad happened and you're like, well, you should have made backups.
That's not,
you know,
that's
not.
Yeah.
Ok.
I know. I know. All right. Anyway, anyway, let's take it home, man. Uh
Thank you everyone for listening. Thank you, Kurt. It was fun.
If you want any of our show notes, you can go to open source security podcast.com.
You can use the Hashtag Pound Os S podcast to gain our attention on Twitter.
We have a Facebook group. You can find
uh near the show notes beneath it as well as some links to Twitter and whatnot and
yeah, thank you everyone for listening. We certainly appreciate it.
And Kurt, you have a fabulous day.
You too. Hope the weather is warm there.
It's raining again. So I'll live anyway. That's better than snow.
I know. All right, man. Take care.