Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siegfried and my partner explaining what openness H and node IP have in common.
-- Josh
-- Bresser. Did you say node IP?
What is node IP?
Uh
Node IP is a
node library for IP, address manipulation, not really manipulation.
Um
More like getting the subnet mask or the given this IP with this subnet.
What's the first, what's the last IP or given this like hexadecimal strength?
What is that? And like
the correct dot quad format?
Yeah, it just, it does IP address magic
well, did.
It still does
and it will only ever do that and nothing else
I know
because it's now read only.
And so yeah, what does that have to do with this open SSH remote code
-- exploit bug?
-- I cannot wait for you to tie them together for us. So
OK.
So obviously the big news this week is open SSH
has a critical vulnerability in SSH D was present in.
No, it was rated important. Kurt, it's fine.
I'm reading literally from open ssh.com here.
They
called it.
-- I know it's critical
-- was present in portable open SSH versions. So and to be clear.
So there's two versions of Open SSH,
there is the Open BS D version which is open
SSH and there is the Open SSH portable version,
-- which is sort of there, the
-- one everyone uses,
the one that everyone on the planet not running open BS D uses. Yeah, exactly.
On Linux or whatever. And open SSH portable has
LAX.
Uh It doesn't really,
I don't want to say LAX capabilities but just
there's some integrations that open BS D and open sh
can do because obviously they're the same people and
they have like when they make a design decision,
they can just do it.
They don't have to convince 1000 Linux distro to.
Exactly.
So open SSH on open BS D does do some things
and have some protections that open SSH portable does not or
not widely available anyways.
So our critical vulnerability in opens in SSH D was present in
portable open SSH versions between 8.5 P one and 9.7 P one.
So basically every version on the planet
not on my de
in 11 system.
-- Really? Is it old enough that it's not affected?
-- It is old.
It just missed it by one version.
-- Well, ok, most things then
-- because it was funny I was actually riding my bike
on Monday morning. This came, this came up Monday morning.
I was, I took my morning bike ride,
I get back to my house and I like
happened to open Mastodon while I was like, cleaning up,
like putting the bike away and all that stuff.
And I saw that
and I was like, oh, crap.
But I literally like,
ran inside the house and sat out on my computer and disabled
at my open ssh instance that I had running in my network.
And then I read the advisory. I was like, oh, I don't need to turn that off.
Like I'm fine.
And so it
that may allow arbitrary code execution with root privileges.
And this is one of the things actually, this is a whole show for itself,
but it absolutely does allow arbitrary code execution with root privileges.
However,
the chances of you successfully exploiting this on an
X 64 system with stuff like address stack lay
randomization are very close to zero, not 00,
but very close to zero. It's small.
Yes.
Well, it's in the sense of like from a mathematical physics perspective, not zero.
-- From an insurance perspective. I'm not worried
-- here's the way I would address this.
And this is what I told the people I work
with about this particular vulnerability affecting certain things we are running
is that
I'm not concerned right now
about this particular issue like that.
I'm not saying we shouldn't fix and patch and block and
do things like that and add add mitigations because we should
because right now with what we know it is mathematically
infeasible to exploit this on a 64 bit system,
I would say unlikely.
I'm saying mathematically infeasible because I think
winning the lottery is mathematically infeasible.
Someone wins it,
not me.
OK. Then you're using the word
-- in a way. I didn't expect
-- that's fine. Now,
even though this is true today, it
is,
I think very likely that an version of this
exploit will exist at some point in the future.
That will not be mathematically infeasible.
Well, this is kind of the holy grail of exploits.
Exactly. Like every bug hunter, every exploit developer,
the eye of Saron has turned upon this one
and here's the thing,
it's easy to say, oh, whatever. Like it's never going to be exploited. Oh, whatever.
It's not a big deal. There are. What, what did they say?
Like 21 million open SSH versions on the internet exploitable to this.
So on. Show Dan, it shows 23,728,100
-- public facing open.
-- That's all versions, right.
They are old versions, new versions, something of it. It's probably a bell curve.
If I had to guess I'd say this, this feels like a 50 to 80% are affected.
-- Kind of versions,
-- right. It's, it's tens of millions for sure.
Which Kurt thinks is too low, but we'll talk about that too.
Oh, no, no, I don't think it's too low.
I think it's just absurdly small considering the size of the internet.
They're all in cloud services. Now behind gateways.
-- But
-- anyway, virtual private cloud,
there is enough meat here
and it's good
be there for a long time that I think
the potential to have like a weaponized exploit here is gonna be,
it's going to be valuable and people are going to figure out a way.
-- I think
-- the other problem is open a switch runs on a lot of devices that are not,
shall we say prone to
updates? I'm not even gonna say quick updates.
Well, and they're not 64 bits either. Right. So if you read the Q
this advisory on a 32 bit system,
they, it was what, 10,001,
but basically one in 10,000 attempts because it's a race condition.
And if you do one in 10,000 serially against a host,
you're talking about weeks of effort for that or
I could just do 10,000 attempts at the same time across the internet
and pop a shell somewhere.
Well, but the other thing to remember too is like, it's, it's the classic thing of,
you know, your 99 point, how many zeros is that?
99.999?
Yeah, that'd be the correct number of nines,
but 99 or 0.9999% to the power of 100 like 100 attempts.
It goes from almost zero to not like far away from zero pretty quickly.
And that's the thing of like
if it's a targeted attack Yeah,
they'd have to keep hammering away on this one portal IP address.
But most attacks are not
targeted, you know, they're not the NSA or whatever.
It's, I just want to grab a bunch of boxes.
Right.
What's really interesting to me is
like I said,
23 million out of four, well, not 4 billion, about 3.2
billion IP S that are valid. Like once you get rid of multi hat
and like 127 and 10 and all that, that seems like I just,
I just assumed there would have been a lot more public facing SSH instances.
-- I
-- don't know. I feel like 23 million is a lot.
Here's, here's kind of the way I look at it. I think,
I think in the internet of 20 years ago,
I would expect more things to be running. SSH.
But like we've reached a point where you don't SSH into stuff anymore.
You're, you're using
various orchestration tools and kubernetes and cloud services and,
you know, they don't, they don't use SSH.
Well, no, but many do like Puppet and Anz
for sure, for sure.
But, but even if you're using those things, Kurt and you're in like in Aws cloud,
you're not gonna open up SSH to the world, you're gonna
-- have cloud front in front of whatever it is you're hosting
-- because, well, no,
you'd have a virtual private cloud in the virtual
-- virtual network, connect and all that stuff.
-- Yeah.
And you're,
you're probably only serving an HTTP session in and
out of your environment because everything is freaking http.
Now,
honestly, in my mind, like if I'll be I
have web servers on the internet and their firewall to
talk to cloud flare and like my IP for SSH
because why else would I do it?
And that raises a good comment. You so this is a classic walk.
Don't run bug, like you don't have to run to fix it,
but you should walk maybe quickly to fix it and make sure.
Yeah, yeah, I agreed.
You mentioned mitigations.
And here's my always my thought on mitigations,
which is if there's something that mitigates
this attack and potentially other attacks,
shouldn't that just be sort of part of the baseline default convey?
No, not on this one. So this one's interesting actually.
So the way you,
the way this attack works and we haven't talked about any of the technical details.
-- But so
-- there's multiple mitigations to be clear here like firewall, like in my mind,
if you haven't already firewalled
your SSH,
there's one mitigation
that people are actually suggesting to change you can.
So the way this attack works is you connect to
an SSH server and then you send a bunch of
data and you basically wait on the last packet of data
to complete
the authentication, handshake.
You wait on the last packet and you want to
send that last packet as the SSH server is running
the time out handler and the time out is 100 and 20 seconds on new versions of open SSH.
And I think 600 seconds or 300 seconds on old versions. I can't remember the numbers.
-- I wrote it down. Let me
-- 10 minutes or something.
I, I wrote down 100 and 20 by default. Now, 600 on old versions.
This is why you should write things down kids.
But anyway, so you wait for this grace log in time out to land
and then you send that packet. OK?
So the mitigation being kicked around is to just turn off that timer.
So now though, the problem is
if I connect to your server
and I never complete that, that authentication handshake
-- the that TCP connection stays open forever.
-- Yeah. So basically the attacker can
hold open a lot of connections that essentially
wouldn't time out and they could trickle packets in like slow LS on a patch. Did
they don't need to trickle packets in?
-- No, but
-- wouldn't the TCP time out happen at some point if you don't send a packet.
Probably,
right.
So that's, but, but I mean, from an attacker's point of view, that's ideal,
like I said,
unpack it every 10 or 50 or 100 seconds and like hold open a million connections
-- and yeah, you can't log into your router anymore
-- and then you're stuck.
But, but again, the, the denial of service problem is magnitudes less bad
than
a root shell.
Well, it's uh you say that,
but remember in pastors in these open ssh issues where then
remember where
oftentimes people have devices running open
SSH and they don't have physical access
to them very easily and they don't have like we're talking of routers,
points of presence.
-- No, I get that. I get that.
-- And so this is definitely a thing where
hypothetical example, you know,
an attacker could prevent you from logging into
the device to update it and hold those,
you know, use that do not like if you implement this work,
quote unquote workaround or I don't want to call it a mitigation.
It's a workaround
because it actually works around the bug but also has harmful effects. Right?
To me, a mitigation is more of a like, oh, you know, there's a ditch here.
So we put up a sign saying ditch and that didn't work. So we put up a fence
but I'm not gonna argue
semantics.
Um But back to this. Yeah, I would say the log and grace time thing is, is,
yeah, be aware that somebody could denial of,
well,
they could prevent you from ever logging into that device again,
remotely basically,
right?
-- And depending on your threat profile that may or may not be an issue. Uh
-- Sure, sure.
But I, I don't know.
I mean, I guess here is the,
the things that the big ideas I have in my mind as I think about this one.
First of all, I feel like there hasn't been like a good
promote code execution bug in a long time.
And part of me wonders is that because we
are getting better at not making these mistakes in
things like open ssh or is it because people
who discover bugs like this are selling them to governments
not
releasing advisories to them? Like Wallace did,
I
suspect it's a bit of number two.
However, those attacks do then get discovered because people are like,
why did all my machines get popped or, you know, we traced an attack, right?
And that, that has happened.
But I think there's another factor that you're forgetting, which is
4 billion IP addresses of which about, you know,
3.2 are usable and only 23 million publicly exposed open SSH host.
I think the reality is there's less and less stuff exposed to the internet
publicly than they probably
past.
And what is exposed is port 443, that's
-- 80.
-- That's
and actually, so this also lends itself to.
So there's a podcast I was listening to the other day. It's called, um,
security cryptography, whatever.
Like actually security cryptography, whatever or you just forgot the third word.
-- Yeah,
-- that's the name of the podcast. I'll put, I'll put a link in the show.
It's actually really good show.
They have marked out on the top,
talk about zero day markets, right?
Like selling experts and things like that and,
and marks a security researcher from, like, way back in the day,
like us Geezers, we know the name.
And it was fascinating to me because, like,
the conversation was almost exclusively geared towards, like, phones.
But if you think about it, like, that's the marketplace today, right?
Where is all your pi I
-- the
-- phone?
Yeah, the phone is where it's at. For sure. Exactly.
The fascinating thing related to that is uh the market for KVM exploits.
Now, Google is paying $250,000 for KVM exploits.
-- What
-- is KVM for us nubs
kernel virtual machine?
So that's the Linux virtualization layer that essentially
-- all of the cloud runs on top of
-- and
everything, even,
even when you're running like container stuff now, like everything is,
-- is KVM magic
-- underneath.
And I, I was actually kind of surprised because if I had a KVM like exploit
escape, whatever
a quarter million dollars is actually not a lot of money for what that's worth.
I, I don't think that is unreasonable. So here's the deal.
If you are going to sell something like this,
you generally aren't selling an A bug,
you're selling
a kill chain
where you need to get from.
OK. Let's, let's assume you can log in, I'm going to get you from login to host.
Yeah. Right. And that's very different.
And you know, we've talked about that and passed on the mobile, you know,
with Pegasus and, uh, I forget the name of the evil company and everything.
I'm totally spacing out, what was the name of that evil company we talked about,
-- I, they talked about it a ton in that podcast.
-- Even the NSO
N
A group. Yes.
Yeah. Sorry.
And, and so what does this all have in common with? Node IP.
Well, node IP had somebody report a
air quotes security flaw
where it doesn't handle certain things correctly.
And the maintainer basically said, look in the context of node IP,
it's not a vulnerability
and he got fed up. But everybody else kind of pointed out.
Well, sort of technically true. But node IP doesn't
live on an island by itself. It's usually part of something else.
And in that context, it is absolutely vulnerable
and they basically,
some people argued with him and the end result was he marked the github
repo archives read only and has kind of
taken his ball and gone away.
Yes.
And, and that's similar to open SSH portable because the reality is at
least the open BS D developers,
they, you know, they're humans, they have flaws.
But one of the things they do actually practically get
is that open SSH on non open BS D systems
has problems that like pure open SSH does not because of like for example,
that integration with system D
or uh you know D bus and all that stuff
that came around last time.
And this, you know,
the login handling with this grace failure stuff doesn't happen on open
uh open BS D
but does happen everywhere else.
But they at least have the good sense to understand that. And then to, you know,
behave somewhat maturely and fix it properly
and not like, argue, it's not a bug because like in,
they could say, look, it's not a bug on open BS D like too bad,
right? We're not going to fix it.
That's not how open SSH portable has ever worked though.
No. And I'm saying that's a good thing, right?
Whereas there's other projects like this note IP
that went the opposite way of saying like,
yeah, no,
we're not going to fix it and we're gonna actually
like have a tantrum and take away our ball,
you know, Mark, mark the uh repos archived.
-- I don't
-- feel like calling it a tantrum is appropriate.
What is the upside of
-- marking it archived and not handing it off or not?
-- How do you hand this stuff off even?
I mean, is maybe JIA Tan is looking for a new project to work on?
Well, for example,
I'm pretty sure if he went to maybe either put a notice
on the front saying I want somebody to take over this and you'll
have to prove to me that you're valid by being a part of
the community or getting people in the community to vouch for you.
But there's ways to do this.
But
they're marking it. Here's the thing,
the node IP package gets 17.5 million downloads a week.
Yes. Actually, is this not archived anymore?
I think the github
repo is un archive now.
Uh It is, you are correct. Did somebody else who's the owner of it?
-- I don't
-- know if the owner changed or what's happened. But here's the thing,
if you own an open source project and you want to archive the repo because you're mad,
you get to do that.
But you have the
well,
but this is a classic case of just because you have the
right to do something doesn't mean it's the right thing to do.
I I'm not saying it was the right thing to do,
but I also don't think it
is acceptable to pile on blame on the developer.
These developers are under immense pressure
and when you are tired and angry and
overworked and burnt out,
you don't always make good choices.
One comment I would also have and I think people forget this a lot.
So on Matron,
perfect example,
I
will block anybody that is rude to me, which is fine.
I also realized I will block anybody that is not interesting.
Like if they kind of keep tooting at me
and they're not saying very interesting things.
I'm I'm also fine with that because you get those like link farmers who
just at a bunch of people hoping. So
this is a person who's like trying to be argumentative and clever,
but they're not actually that clever, they
kind of wrong.
And I realized like,
if you and I were having a conversation in public and somebody came up to us and said,
you know, I really like the old says podcast.
We'd be like, cool, thank you. Like, awesome.
And then if they kind of kept trying to talk about feral weasels, we'd be like, ok,
that's cool.
But like me and Josh were trying to have a conversation here,
-- you know, are
-- there un
-- feral weasels?
-- Probably.
But the point is like at some point socially,
like it's ok for us to turn their power back on them
and like have our conversation without them being a part of that.
And I realize
like that and that's, and I think that's part of it is there are
people go from like,
I think people need to start using these old timey social signals of like,
I'm just going to mute you or block you
instead of like
arguing with you and then marking my repos,
archived and running and just getting fed up.
I mean, maybe, but I don't think this is a reasonable comparison.
Kurt, I think you have to look at the issue though.
-- The issue is full of people saying please fix this.
-- But here's the thing.
If 1000 people are asking him to fix it, maybe
that's the
thing to do
and not doing it is, you know, I,
it's tough.
Like I look at open source and I say yes, the people doing open source, you know,
they wrote it, they gave it away.
They, they really shouldn't have things piled on them that they have to do.
But at the same time to, to go to a bad analogy in Holland in the olden days,
you know, if you lived next to the sea, you were responsible for a piece of dyke.
And the thing is if
100 people are responsible for 100 pieces of dyke
and one of them doesn't do their job,
all 100 people suffer,
right? Not just
the one with the bad dyke, but everybody gets flooded.
And so there was this expectation that if you
couldn't take care of that piece of dyke,
then,
well,
it's time for you to give up your farm because you're putting everybody else at risk.
And I think
the reality of the world is, is a bad open source package puts a,
a lot of people at risk.
But
I, I also had a heart. I have a hard time
reconciling that with.
So now this person who did all this free work and gave it away for free,
we're gonna make him do more work.
Like I, I don't think that's the solution,
but we still have this huge pile of risk and problem.
I have no idea what you're even talking about at this point.
I, I don't think you can clarify at this point.
What I'm saying is basically we
can't
realistically expect open source developers to always do the right thing.
-- That's not fair and it's not feasible.
-- No, we definitely can't.
I agree.
But at the same time then what do we do with this pile
of risk where they have a security flaw that they're refusing to fix?
Is it a security flaw?
Yeah,
when it's integrated with other software in dangerous ways
and there's been a ton of those where,
you know, CV E intersection flaws even more.
So where you have two pieces of soft, we're both doing the correct
thing in their own world. But when they talk together
-- they, something goes a bit sideways and it becomes a security flaw.
-- Ok.
I mean,
I don't think we can talk through this and I
think you're becoming dangerously close to sounding like a fool.
-- This is a hard problem.
-- No. What I'm saying is, it is a hard problem and I, I,
but we can't keep ignoring this risk and saying like, ok, you know,
he says it's not a flaw.
-- Ok.
-- This is
been a common
occurrence in software where a vendor says we don't think this is a bug.
We don't think this is a security issue.
I mean, there's the, the age old joke of it's not a bug, it's a feature, right?
It is easy for us to disagree with vendors.
It is easy for us to disagree with open source projects.
Well, I think part of it is by the nature of open source,
these disagreements happen in public and they're actually known.
Whereas for all we know there's a
million people emailing Microsoft every day asking them
to fix a security flaw and Microsoft's ignoring it and we would never know.
-- I'm
-- sure they get tens of thousands of emails like that a day is my suspicion.
And, and the other thing too is just to also load this.
There is the argument that says, look, if you're using a,
a library like node IP and it's insecure and you don't like that, it's insecure.
Go write your own use something different, like go deal with it.
But again,
that ignores the problem of the sort of the economic cost of fixing it
quickly in one place versus forcing a million people to do something different,
right?
11 of these is a more efficient solution, which is why open source one,
right, open source is by its nature, very efficient.
You know, Solaris used to make their own kernel in OS
and Linux murdered them on the efficiency of development cost scale.
Well, it also is because the Solaris computer cost $100,000 and a Linux
-- machine ran
-- on again, eco economics of scale.
I mean, look,
I
don't want to keep beating this dead horse because there, there isn't a good answer.
The,
the the reality is there isn't an answer and this is
related to something I've been thinking about a lot lately,
but it is also a topic very hard to get anyone to actually care
about is if you look at basically
any graph around vulnerabilities or software today,
it is all exponential growth.
Any way you look at it, you got exponential growth.
The Linux kernel is like, oh,
we're going to label
everything
that looks and smells like a security flaw
and that's 2000 so far this year with being on track for like 5000
-- and people are freaking out and like, but
-- the point is like they're,
they're noticing that, but it's everywhere you look, it's exponential growth.
And I think that exponential growth is finally catching up to us as an industry.
And there's a lot of people ignoring it though. Like
I have been trying to submit
this talk to a lot of conferences to be like, look,
this is a real problem and we need people to start understanding this.
It has been rejected literally everywhere.
And I've submitted this to places where the people should know
better and they should even understand this and they don't.
-- And
-- I think a quick summary of this is
all of Linux source code unpacked used to fit
on a like 100 megabyte hard drive.
And now when you com the compiled Linux kernel wouldn't even fit on that hard drive.
And I'd actually, I kind of wonder now how many lines of code
is an average web application
ultimately comprised of. And I'm gonna assume it's in the millions.
Probably it's
-- gigantic because of all the no J
-- S.
It's not even so much exponential growth of vulnerabilities.
It's that we had exponential growth of software
of everything. Yes. No, it's not just vulnerabilities.
It's of literally the world, right?
Everything you look at in technology, the number of devices that exist,
the number of things running the number of
apps, everything
take any data point
and it's exponential growth.
And I think the problem with exponential growth
is when you realize it's exponential growth,
it's too late.
You're
gonna double in a couple of months. So it, it hardly matters.
And I think this is all related to that.
I think
we don't know what to do with any of this because it's growing too fast.
Like my other favorite is when you have people
with N you know NVD collapsed and they're like,
oh,
it needs to go back to normal and it's like it
can't go back to normal because normal is a decade ago.
What you think normal is, has been gone for so long. It's not even funny.
It was funny to me when I, when I mentioned, you know,
I worked at Red Hat and I assigned six or 8000 CV S, you know,
Red Hat Hat was handling back when we left like 3000 CV S a year,
basically about 10 a day.
And it's funny when people talk about, oh,
I have to handle so many security vulnerability.
I'm like, yeah, Red Hat. We handled like, 3000 a year and they're like, what?
And I'm like, yeah,
across 100 products, like,
or sorry, 100 and 12 products when I was there.
And a lot of people,
when they start to learn about what, like making cookies. Oh, my God.
Every time, see, like a house it's made Cookie Factory. It's like
I can't, can does humanity need that many cookies? Apparently. Yes,
you can never have too many cookies.
-- And
-- that's the thing with software is now,
is people forget that we have how many
millions of people literally churning out code,
integrating code, deploying code. It's ridiculous.
It's like the road system when you start to think about
how much Edmonton spent on its road system over the years.
And you know, we've got
all we need to tie this all back up because we had open ssh,
we have node IP.
And yes, I think the scale is part of it.
-- I think that's a good explanation
-- and we live inside of it so
much so that we don't notice it until next people are going like,
yeah, I don't want to fix that. Go away.
But, but you,
you have to, what do we do? No, you can't, you can't not do that.
Well, yeah, that person absolutely can
-- just not do that.
-- Maybe,
I guess here's here's how I want to end it and here's a question.
So, what, what do, what do we do? I'm a person.
What do I do
the open ssh problem?
Ironically,
I would say update your package except Red Hat still hasn't released an update.
Yeah.
And they called it important.
-- So
-- there two things that you can do that are somewhat useful,
which is one except reality for what it is and stop trying to
argue that it's not real or it's not a problem
because I see a lot of that and number two
is,
is in general
having more mature and efficient processes.
Now, I didn't say anything about security.
I just said processes, be it, security business, whatever,
writing
code tests having. So for example, like once here's the thing I love is, you know,
does anybody actually
test software updates before they deploy them?
Why do you, I mean, actually really test them?
And the answer is like, not really
like we just all sort of assume when you type,
you know, whatever hyphen you open ssh
it'll update and just magically work because well, it does
in
most of the time. Well, it's different. Look, I think
there's also a different way to look at the problem because you back in the day.
Yeah, you had to test updates because you had a computer running software
and you'd install an update on that computer and there
was no really good way to roll that back.
But if you have a proper
system today,
you've got things like containers and virtual machines and
you can take snapshots and you can deploy an update
and then check if it worked.
And if it didn't work, you just roll back to the one that did work.
And so it's kind of a different world in that regard
and that perfectly speaks to that efficiency argument of use these tools,
use the power tools, use them efficiently.
And yeah, and then you can just deploy updates willy nilly.
And if they break, roll them back,
I mean, it's just,
I think this is the world we live in now.
Everything is wild.
You're gonna have critical vulnerabilities in applications and you're gonna
have people arguing about how exploitable it is or isn't
-- and
-- or just simply not tripping an update in a timely manner,
which is
weird.
But
whatever I guess
-- like does Red Hat even support 32 bits
-- still.
I hope not.
They might, there might be some architecture but,
but regardless the optics of the issue, right?
I think
the reality is you're fine, but the optics tell me
why have you released an update for this?
And, and I think open source is similar,
there's like optics versus reality and the optics of,
you know, rage quitting your project
sends a certain signal
and the optics of like using open source and demanding fixes from
people that you have no relationship with sends a certain signal,
I mean, and, and I, I think it all comes back to like,
this is exponential growth. This is the world we're in now.
And the reality is we have no idea what to do
in all of the various serious people.
They don't even understand the problem, which I think makes it even worse.
And I, I, something you just said, took the thought,
-- it's not just exponential growth, it's exponential
-- use, it's exponential,
everything
like everything.
Well, no, but when, when you say exponential growth,
I think a lot of people think of it from the supply side
and not the demand use side,
right?
-- I I view them as similar
-- and that's a big thing where a lot of people
get it wrong because like this node IP thing is a great example of like,
well, it's, it's just a stupid little library.
-- How much could it matter? Well, 17.5 million times a week
-- and it's also an N PM.
So everyone running node,
it, it, it's a mess.
I mean, even if half of those polls are like automated systems,
-- I
-- bet 90% are automated systems.
But even if it's a 90% like it's still 1.7 million a week,
that's a lot of potentially affected apps.
So like
in summary, I don't know,
like I said, accept reality and you know, try to be efficient,
which ironically is also part of what landed us here is by being efficient.
-- That is una actionable advice. Kurt
-- accepting reality is absolutely
-- stop arguing with reality. In
-- fact, I'm
arguing with you right now.
I mean, I, I get it, we couldn't,
we couldn't even get people to wash their hands like that email
we got that I posted on mast on where somebody's like,
I'm not going to say what he said. Exactly, because it's so gross.
But, you know,
the person basically was arguing against washing
their hands after using the washroom.
I
don't
-- remember this, but it's a
-- few days ago. Anyways,
I part of this.
Yeah, I think anyways, this person said, you know, I like the O SI podcast.
But regarding hand washing, I don't wash my hands because my dad taught me to,
you know, basically not wash my hands after using the bathroom.
I do not have any recollect. I don't think I've seen this.
-- I wonder if it went to my spam. It
-- might
-- have gotten blocked because of certain keywords.
-- Holy cow.
-- Anyway,
-- they
put it on Mastodon and it's like this is why I don't shake hands and
generally look at your master.
Although I don't look at social media very much like it's nothing like it used to be
on social media.
I don't know. Anyway.
All right, I'm going to call this one, I guess in summary, go update your SSH servers.
Everyone
wants to give you a package.
Hopefully, hopefully all the updates will be released by the time this show is out.
So,
whatever, you gotta love it, man. All right. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening. Go
up for social security podcast.com. Find the show not. It's
po
do I says podcast? Hashtag I
Mastodon Kurt, have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.