Hello and welcome to the episode 85 of the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime.
Josh Bresser.
I thought I was your partner in thought crime.
Whoops. Yes. Thought crime. Totally not real crime.
Totally not.
That's right.
So
I'm not even sure how to come up with a clever intro to this one.
So let's just say uh N PM. Done fed up.
Oh Yeah.
Yeah, this is uh
OK. Well, let's first let's ascertain the, the sort of the facts of the matter.
And what happened,
please
enlighten us. So N PM, the node package manager,
uh the node package manager is,
well, it's exactly that it's the node
package manager.
Um So like every other package manager currently on the planet, you know,
you have a program, it does a bunch of imports.
You have a dependency chain, white
chains
and uh node handles all the magic and can also do clever things like you
can use a certain specific version of a package or use the up to date one
uh
you know, all that good stuff, right?
And then on servers, when you deploy an application,
uh assuming you have N PM installed,
the application goes like I need this that and the other thing and N PM goes cool.
B DB
done. Here you go. And now you can work.
And so that way, you know, a developer can write an application
and
they
basically, well, they have like a Docker file that or whatever that says, you know,
go
do this and you know NBM does it all.
So N PM
released version 5.7 0.0
which contained a flaw.
Uh Essentially if a variable wasn't
OK,
backtrack of it. N PM
attempts to do some clever things. Uh
Typically,
how do I phrase this nicely?
You as a normal user
use pseudo sudo to run the N PM update as route, right?
Because it's gonna want to scribble in various parts of the
world and that normal users can't,
which, you know, that's fair. That's normal, right? That's how that works.
Uh But unfortunately N PM tries to do some clever stuff where it resets
permissions.
So instead of uh doing everything as root,
it does stuff as root and then reset some permissions to whatever user uh you are
that ran pseudo and did this
and there was a flaw in that. And so it basically ended up child
owning,
-- was it slash etc slash user and slash something else? Slash
-- boot? I think it was.
-- Oh yeah,
-- slash boot.
So,
-- right.
-- Basically,
basically the three most, well, I guess
it didn't touch slash bin. Thank goodness.
Uh,
but basically it touched pretty much three of the four most important
directories on the file system on a typical UNIX file system.
And,
you know,
by basically not having those directories owned by root and by having them,
I think it removes some set U ID bits and stuff.
If you reboot you,
you're gonna have a bad day.
And, well, of course that, that happened to a lot of people because a lot of people,
you know,
well, in fairness
5.7 0.0 not a major release and it looks like a stable release too.
So we'll get into that. But
basically the script ran his route challenge,
a whole pile of stuff slash boot slash E DC slash user uh to whatever user.
And of course, at that point, you have a very broken system and if you reboot,
you have a extremely broken system,
it sounds like things just don't come back if you reboot,
it depends on the cloud provider and the virtual machine and stuff.
But like, for example, in Amazon,
uh like with Amazon, if you have an EC2 uh elastic compute instance
that, well, basically if you end up with a, you know,
hit control D and type the root password for maintenance, you have a dead
box effectively.
Amazon doesn't really let you get in there to recover it.
You can look at the log files and it'll say, you know,
hit control D and type in your root password to, to fix this thing.
Um So if you, if you have like a physical machine that you can,
you know, get a console or you have like lights out management.
Uh Same thing, most V MS you'd be able to recover them because you know,
the VM lets you do this.
But yeah, most of the cloud or well containers,
it's dead,
it's just dead,
right?
And uh
so yeah, that happened and then so about 12 hours ish, about half a day ish
they clawed back the release and uh basically did a 5.7 0.1 that fixed
the stuff.
Um
It, well, here, no,
let me rephrase it,
it
fixed the problem. Uh but the,
it still does this silly stuff, in my opinion with the challenges and whatnot.
Uh does it a little bit safer
and yeah, and life goes on.
Uh except for those people who upgraded and well
life for those servers does not go on.
Yeah. Right. That's II I can't,
I, I guess I shouldn't say I can't imagine because I, I've been here before and it,
it sucks, it sucks hard.
So I was thinking le let's walk through sort of what happened and,
and dissect kind of what went wrong, I guess on the, on the top first level of depth.
So honestly, right off the bat
they released,
technically what they're classifying is a pre release,
but it's called 5.7 0.0.
Right. That 5.7 0.0 sounds to me like a very
like, oh, we're on 5.6 point whatever. Hey, cool. Bump to 5.7 0.0 nothing.
You know, they probably didn't change anything that major and it
sounds like it's safe to go. Right.
It's not 5.7 0.0 hyphen alpha or hyphen pre release.
It's just 5.7 0.0. And if you do look at the tags,
it does say pre release. But you know,
looking at the version number to me, 5.7 0.0 looks like it should be safe.
So, are they taking the old school Linux
way of odd numbers are testing?
They're,
but they're not doing semantic versioning like most people do, right? Where?
Yeah, I mean, in fact, Linux moved away from this because it was dumb,
right? It's
if you have a version,
well, it just, it doesn't make sense
with a rapid release cycle.
What does make sense with a rapid release cycle is like hyphen alpha hyphen beta
hyphen or
for the love of God don't use this in production.
We really, really don't want you to do that, but we do want you to test it,
right? I mean,
hyphen
RC,
I've never installed N PM
in this manner. I always just use a package that comes with my operating system,
but I would, I would not think twice about seeing 5.7 0.0. Right. I think
I'm going to install that in a way. I go,
yeah, they fixed a few things obviously from 5.6.
Although I must say also one of the, one of the old school lessons is if it ain't broke,
don't fix it.
So
I would,
once they have a running system, I do all I can to not touch it.
Yeah.
Uh, well, and you know, that's part of the thing with the Agile Devops
movement.
Uh,
part of it is also just kind of keeping everything
up to date and fixing it as the breaks.
So
do it now,
instead of later when you have to update and you're under a
time constraint because you have to update for some other reason.
Right. Well, this is the reason I always rebooted my servers
on a somewhat regular basis is because at some point I would have to reboot them,
like, say a kernel update
and then if they don't come back. Oh, God. Now, what? Right.
Versus doing it on a schedule when I have time to recover them.
And I'm, you know, I'm not stressed and I'm not pressed for time.
Right. Right.
And, well, and not only that I would not in a million years,
imagine updating N PM would hose the whole system.
I, maybe I
am,
but
I'm, I'm always a little nervous,
especially on a Mac when I run, like, things like brew or whatever,
like things that need to run his route.
I'm always a little bit.
So,
no, Brew doesn't run his route though. In fact, if,
if you run Pseudo Brew, actually, let's,
let's pick on Brew here for a minute is Brew does it right.
Yeah. Brew actually tells you don't ever do this. Yeah. Sorry. No.
Brew is the example of how to do correctly. There's the one that,
there's another thing I use where I just,
occasionally you have to run a singer's root and I'm like super,
it's pretty sketchy in some ways.
Um But yeah, no, brew.
If you try to run it as root, it explicitly tells you like that is a super bad idea.
-- Yeah. Right.
-- It is.
So don't do it. Yeah.
Yeah, pretty much.
So I, I would say that was the first failure, right?
They released a pre release version that wasn't labeled clearly as such.
I mean, they would claim it is because it's in the, you know,
there's a pre release tag if you look at the website and stuff, you know.
But uh
yeah.
Um
-- and also you get it if you just run N PM update. Right.
-- Right.
And I was just looking for the comment that talks about that.
But yeah, if you run update and it shows up
that's not pre
-- release guys. I, I'm sorry.
-- Right.
Well, unless you've got like some explicit, like we have a stable and we have a devel
that's fair two things
Right. And then, yeah,
but again,
if I'm on a stable version and I run update, I expect to get another stable version.
I think that as a
whatever
expectation.
Yeah, exactly.
Um
So OK, then the second thing is, well,
the fact that this exists at all that it's basically doing stuff as
root and then chowing a bunch of stuff as to back to a user
and a bunch of other junk.
Like I don't
understand,
I
let's let's
ignore that and assume it has its reasons because I'm not gonna,
-- I'm not an expert on the N PM internals
-- and I could do
something a bit easier like spawn a process as that user and then
just have that user do the stuff to their own stuff.
And I think this
comes
the
real stuff
and
stuff.
So this comes back to our discussion about authentication actually
and how a lot of people just don't understand this.
And actually
user I DS
is incredibly tricky on a unique system of how they work. You've got,
what is your actual U
I?
And there's effect, right? There's all these different kind of U I DS.
And in fact, I remember at one point this is many years ago,
there were, there were, there was an issue where
if you know, you can set like process limits for a user,
so user can only run 1000 processes.
And if it hits that
there was a bug in Pam I think it was that it would basically, if you ran,
tried to run as a user using like pseudo or something,
it would make you root
because that user couldn't do certain activities.
And, and I, I remember I spent like a week
just figuring all of this out. Like, what, what does it mean
with all these ideas? What does the transitions look like?
What is, what is all this and like,
nobody had done that before and it took a very long time and it wasn't
obvious at all how a lot of this stuff worked and then of course,
bugs were filed and we fixed it all.
But
it was crazy.
I remember that it was hard to do and I would not expect a node developer
to understand this in a billion years now at the same time.
That means like, don't mess with it guys, right? I'm not giving you a free pass here.
I'm just saying
I get why they screwed it up.
Oh, yeah, totally. Um
Yeah. No, it's
uh and then somebody else comment, I haven't verified this,
but apparently there's no unit tests with that code.
That is what is said and I, I poked around in the directory and I didn't see anything.
But again, I'm not an expert on this, this software,
but I think it's safe to say there are no unit tests, at least for this particular
edge case. Well, it's not really an edge case.
And part of the problem too is the unit test again,
like we've had flaws where like something has to return
some sort of error that typically almost never
happens except when it does happen and things.
And so, you know,
how do you build a unit test for this where it's like to trigger the failure?
Right?
No, no. Here's the thing though, man,
this isn't even about failure.
If they had like basic unit testing working where
you use pseudo as part of your unit test,
it would have found this because it would have trashed their test system.
Right.
Yeah,
I mean, that's the thing. They clearly weren't testing this now.
I would hope they start
and, and I can ignore certain edge cases because let's face it.
Unit tests are never complete and you're always going to find bugs.
The right answer is to add a test every time you find a bug.
But in this case it's clear there was no testing run as pseudo here.
And so, I mean, that would be sort of the, I think the next major.
Yeah.
Problem. Yeah. The, the just the whole lack of testing.
Well, and not even the lack of unit test,
but the fact did they actually try this on
any machines other than their own special DEV machine,
-- which magically somehow blessedly worked
-- well.
It probably worked because they didn't run it with pseudo.
I mean, that my suspicion here is that the testing that was done and let's face it.
We know they, they did some testing just because everybody does.
But my guess is the testing they did didn't involve pseudo because if they ran Sua,
they would have trashed their machines and they would have noticed. Right.
And then I would actually continuing on, I reading the comments here, like
so many people destroy production systems with this.
That doesn't surprise me at all.
Look, we all love to talk about microservices and DEV prod and all this stuff,
but let's face it, man.
Like
I bet 80 plus percent of everything is, is s
men's monkeying with prod.
See what's interesting to me is when I think about the failure case for this thing.
So for example, if I run some sort of package update or something as a non root user,
then rolling it back is relatively easy.
Uh worst case scenario, I can just restore the backups of the system.
And in this case, that's kind of where you are is you,
you've just trashed your system,
you need to restore the actual backups of the system.
And what's interesting to me is,
you know,
I, I hope these people have backups.
-- Um And or enough knowledge to fix the permission.
-- You
know, some of them didn't and I'm sure many of them don't know how to fix permissions.
It's,
this is something that I think you and I take for granted because of our background
where, where we come from some
-- trash
-- systems and
things were messed up back in the day and, and I think a lot of people today, I mean,
Linux basically works,
which I know that, that sounds crazy to some people. But
look, you install it and it runs and if you're using a cloud provider,
you don't even install it, right.
You, you have some sort of image you spin up
and then essentially when something goes wrong,
you probably just blow out the old image away and install a new one
and, and you sep the files before you do it, right?
And in this instance
that doesn't work.
Uh just for our listeners,
one trick I typically would use is uh R sync because you can R sync basically just the,
well, you can basically R sync one like a cloned machine to that one
like and by cloned, I mean, something that's running the same OS,
same version basically.
-- And you know that way you could restore your slash boot
-- and your slash that isn't
gonna work if you can't boot the machine though.
Right? Well, yeah, and that's why you hopefully do this before you reboot.
Hopefully. Yeah, I'm, I'm kind of wondering how many people notice.
Well, you would, if slash user goes missing,
then you're gonna notice that pretty quickly.
It sounds like a lot.
Here's the
thing from some of the things I read. It sounds like people ran this
and their systems stopped working, right?
They became unresponsive and what's the first thing you're gonna do?
I'll just reboot the system, right? No big deal.
-- And then, well,
-- especially with the cloud image, right?
Because that's how you fix cloud images,
you reboot them and then you kill them and run a new one,
right? So
it sounds like this was like
the perfect storm
of terrible.
Yeah. So
I,
I think basically a lot of that boils down to is a
lot of people are still using the cloud as a replacement for hardware
as a cloud.
I know I'm guilty of that too. I have like my little sync server for my OM
focus little poor little lights, sale machine.
Grunting away at web dab with like a gig of memory or whatever.
Yeah, I, I do the same. It's just so easy though.
It's so much easier to be lazy. Right.
Yeah. Well, and in this case to re re
covering the machine is super trivial because it made a back.
Yeah.
And then I think the other thing too is apparently there's only, well,
there's basically sort of
really fundamentally two people in charge of N PM releases. It sounds like.
-- So that's not a very big bus factor.
-- No, it's, it's not at all.
And it also, I suspect if it's two people,
they probably aren't doing a ton of testing because let's face it.
If, if you're trying to build software,
you have unit test.
Right. Right. Right. Well, there's
so no, no,
I think that's something important.
Unit testing is part of the game,
but you also need some sort of integration testing as well.
And, and here's the thing, they might have had unit tests for this,
but this is really an integration test failure more than a unit test failure, right?
Because like on windows, this won't happen. Maybe they tested it on windows, right.
Maybe they tested on Os X. I assume it doesn't trash Os X.
I don't know.
Right.
Here's the thing. I'm just looking at who commits to the project. We got
uh the top person with 4321 commits 445
446,000 lines added 288,000 lines removed next person.
1362 commits uh 560,000 lines or 570,000 lines added about 493,000 lines removed
next person. 781 commits 457,000 lines added 345,000 lines removed
next person. Now, 440 commits 385. Uh 386,000 lines removed. 224,000 removed.
And then the fifth one, it drops to 62 thousands. And so basically that,
that's what I'm saying, that distribution, there's basically
the,
yeah, it's like
out of the 483
483. Yeah. Uh,
Committers, there's like four that are like 90 something percent of us.
Everybody else is under a,
it's like one or 2000 lines changed
and then, oh, no, no, no, I lied. Sorry. There's
uh, 1234566 people with about a 1 to 2000 lines changed and then it's
16 commits with 100 and 97 lines and like negative 2021 lines.
-- So, yeah, it is a heck of a steep curve.
-- Yeah.
Yeah. And, and I think this,
this package manager runs a significant portion of the internet.
Yeah. So basically those like three or four, well, four or five people really can.
They have a lot of influence
and, and they have the ability to ruin many people's days.
Oh, yeah,
that's the other thing is always things like
this just when you think about how many hours
got blown away because of
people having to fix their systems. And it, and it kind of makes me wonder, you know,
so it's a negative externality, right?
They broke it, it broke a whole bunch of systems, those people in turn had a bad day.
And this is what frustrates me about.
The open source model is all these sort of free riders.
And I get that that's a fundamental benefit of the system
too is we have a whole pile of free riders,
right?
We have basically the whole internet now because
of all these free riders that can like,
oh, I want to spin up a super complicated web services
and like, you know, 20 minutes later of N PM or of Pearl back in the day or whatever.
And boom, you, you know, you've got something running. Right. That's awesome.
But
at the same time I can't help but wonder economically, you know, like,
probably hundreds of thousands of hours were spent fixing these systems.
Do you think those people are going to donate a few bucks to the project?
They probably won't be.
But that's
at the same time. So here's,
there's um and there's like so many layers of
stuff you just said. So. All right, let me start here. First of all,
you can use the term free rider to describe users of open source.
But I think that's just part of the nature of open source and open source developers.
Understand that is something that happens.
You make something people are going to use it.
I would bet you 95 plus percent of them
-- will never contact you or tell you anything.
-- The same thing with CV,
right? 99.9% of CV users are free riders and that's how it is. And that's,
I
don't,
I feel like free rider gives it a negative connotation.
Well, but ok, I don't mean free rider
as a negative thing. I'm just using it in the echo
-- and that's fair.
-- It's, it's not,
well,
I don't see it necessarily as a negative because for example,
standards don't work unless people adopt them.
-- Right. Right.
-- Right.
And, and I, I think there is also
the angle of
it's easy to call someone a free rider.
But like, I, I mean, we're great examples of, we consume,
say a Linux distribution that we may not get back to, but we're doing work on,
say CV E or something else.
And so
it's just part of an ecosystem. So anyway, I
OK, so good. I'm glad you were using Free Rider as a negative.
Yeah. No, no, no.
But my point more is that these people that were negatively impacted.
I,
I wonder if they're going to take action
to reduce the likelihood of that negative impact,
for example,
by maybe deploying on DEV next time or giving money to the project or giving,
you know, work and effort to the project.
Sending me the great example of giving effort to the project that would have helped
is like somebody running this like the minute it drops and then going well,
it totally mucked up my system, file an issue, contact the DEV,
let's fix this before it gets widespread.
That would have been a valuable thing, right?
And, and
it wouldn't surprise me if the person who filed the first issue,
I, I wonder if that was their first N PM issue they filed. Uh
But anyway, there's, there's also but here's the other half of it.
So you say, how many hours did these people lose?
Which is valid?
But at the same time, by using open source,
they also have saved probably millions of man
hours not building all this other stuff.
-- So
-- it's, oh, yeah. No, I mean, the, the number of times I've had open source dip
something and, and
kill something and just make my life miserable is vastly outweighed by the
extracted from open
source.
Like it's,
yeah,
but at the same time, you know, maybe we can do better,
we can always do better.
That's,
that
can be our new motto.
-- And I guess part of the question too is how do we do
-- better? That is the question.
And I think in this instance, there's some pretty low hanging fruit, right?
Like write some freaking tests. That's,
that's step one.
And in fact,
this is a great example though too of I can sit here and say write some freaking tests
and their response is probably patch is welcome
and they're not wrong, right?
Like in fact, I remember I I've done this on,
on more than one project I used to be involved with is
I was like, there's no test and they said write some and I said, OK, and I did
and
yeah, it it makes a huge difference.
So having, having unit tests for things like this and, and I,
I hope somebody steps up and, and helps out with this.
And in fact, funny enough, if you're ever looking to get involved in a project,
anybody listening,
like, writing unit tests is highly valuable.
Your patches will almost certainly be accepted and
you're going to learn the code base very,
very quickly if you do it.
So, yeah, like plus one there.
Yeah,
I think it's almost actually more valuable to
have external people write the unit test because
they're not
sort of blinded to
thinking that
-- you
-- write tests,
then you write the code. That is how you do it.
Yeah. Well, that, yeah, in a perfect world of spherical cows.
But what I'm trying to get it is the people who write the code
are often not the people you want writing the test after the fact,
right?
Because they're,
they're kind of blinded to how they wrote the code
and what they think reality should look like and like,
hey, reality doesn't run this on a Windows box except,
-- and
-- this is also integration testing and having like ac I
system makes all the difference in the world because you can,
you can do things like test it on Windows, tested on Fedora, tested on de
and tested on a
right. You test it on like everything you can get your hands on
just to see what happens.
I wonder if this Yeah, this would have happened even in a container.
Uh it, it would, well, it depends how your containers are configured though.
If you're doing containers correctly,
as soon as you shut down the container, it blows away all the changes. Right.
No, no, no.
But what I mean is if you, if you ran this, not in a VM, but actually you had a container
-- up
-- during, like the docker build, you
made
you, you know.
Yeah, like a docker.
And you did pseudo, then this probably actually would have been caught even.
So it's,
-- yeah, I guess the moral of the story is if you're using PSEUDO to run stuff
-- because
container builds happen as root, right?
It, it won't.
Well, so this problem only exhibits itself if you're using pseudo specifically.
If you were root,
it wouldn't happen.
Well, that was my second thing.
My, my point is if you're going, if you're going to support
or document and tell people to use PSEUDO to run certain commands,
then I, I think you kind of have an obligation to, to test that because pseudo isn't.
-- Well, it's root. It's
-- incredibly and
Pudo does some wonky stuff too.
It's,
it's one of those things like test it out because it does
some weird path things and it does some tt I tt Y things
between Mac and Linux
and uh
before I see it, is it
Yeah, on windows now. So yeah. Oh
wait, there is no,
-- you get pseudo if you install the Linux
-- subs
but it's in their command. I think it's in their command line. Uh Yep.
So, Windows has pseudo for real.
-- Well, the windows has a bash
-- shell. It's wonky. But, yeah, they have
one. I don't,
anyways, it doesn't seem, well,
I can't find for sure if it has Pseudo or not in their bath shell.
But regardless we have Pseudo on Mac Os and a K jillion different linuxes.
So, test at least like two of those, please.
Right.
That's fair.
And, you know,
it's, yeah, because, I mean,
I've interacted enough with Pseudo to know that
things can go really horribly wrong fast.
-- It's
-- better than it used to be. But I remember back in the day Pseudo was dicey.
Well, no, no, I'm not. No, this is not even stuff Pseudo does wrong.
This is like where, you know, oh, let's just remove a file and you leave a space
or, you know what I mean? Like
you, you, there's a trailing dot
or a slash gets separated at the front,
you know,
and I remember doing stuff like that before.
I remember the time I accidentally typed kill one.
Pseudo kill one. This isn't
hilarious. Which let you do that and then
things stopped working, we'll say
because it was hilarious back in like 1904 or something.
I mean, I get that,
I guess technically you should let the user do whatever the user does.
But
that's,
it was a learning experience.
-- Was it fun?
-- No.
Uh, in that one, I don't think
I'm trying to remember I think that the system came back,
it just took time to boot and it was a multi user system.
So people were, the phone started to ring
and,
yeah. Yeah. So that one, that one wasn't the end of the world. But I know
I've made mistakes before where,
where the system is coming back up and the file system wasn't clean.
And so it had to check it and it took like
a million years because this was way back in the day before
file systems.
And those file systems were terrible
because yeah, if you turn the power off to them,
they would like remember Windows back in the day, right?
You turn the power off and on a few times and
dude Windows, Windows was the worst. Although
yeah, anyway, I'll never forget. There was one time I was updating your computer
and I lost power during the update of Open SSL.
And it was, it,
I, I made it a point to bring the system back to life because I wanted to.
But it was uh it was challenging, we'll say because open SSL,
everything uses open SSL.
-- And
-- that kind of actually this whole update thing really brings up AAA good,
longer term point of using up to date software is good,
but using maybe not bleeding edge software is also good.
So for example, the people that are using um like vendor packages of N PM,
I don't think anybody was really affected by this
because they just don't package it fast enough for,
you know, this to have kind of escaped
-- and gotten into the wild.
-- This
wouldn't be a problem
when you're dealing with vendor packages. They aren't using pseudo,
they generally build this stuff as root or fake root. Right.
And then it does, it, it does things correctly.
And, um, the other thing is like, you know, it's on hacker news brought up, you know,
the the left pad debacle of two years ago, right,
where a similar sort of situation happened where
left pad was this widely used N PM library?
I think it was what, seven lines
literally padded text
to the left
and
the developer took it away long story
and, you know, it broke like half the internet, like straight up,
you know,
until somebody kind of hijacked the name space and
put something back up that was fortunately not malicious,
but a kind of a clone of left pad.
And
I've often wondered this, you know,
with the non vendor stuff where you're just grabbing, you know,
a bunch of bits from like Ruby gems.org or C
A or whatever. Because
I think people are under the impression that like to get code onto these sites,
there's like a big process and there really isn't
for
the bar is low.
You know,
it's not like somebody's going to review every line
of code and audit it for flaws because,
well, clearly if we did that we'd have really nice
archives or repositories of code that just works without bugs.
I mean, this is even true of Linux distributions. The bar isn't high to include code
and,
and this is a topic we can obviously discuss at some point in the future because I,
I think about it often
and I don't, I know we don't have time today to, to get into it. But
I guess
the, the thing I would, I would walk away with, of all this is
it, it's a good lesson
to build
resiliency into your systems
and knowing things like what if user slash us r you know, was blown away.
What, what does that mean for the system? You have?
I, I think it based, I mean, a lot of this boils down to just basic hygiene,
right? Have a test system or if not.
Exactly. That's kind of my point of, of resiliency, right is
have the ability to, to
test and recover from problems like this because here's the thing.
Look, the N PM guys screwed up and they don't have a very good track record right now.
And, and I do feel bad for them because
I know how thankless a lot of this work is and they're no doubt doing their best.
Right. I mean,
I,
I'm not going to call them malicious by any sense of the word.
They're, I'm sure they're good guys and they're trying their hardest.
Have we actually ever had an incident like this caused by
an actual malicious person because I can't think of anything offhand.
There hasn't been one yet and I'm not going to say there won't be, but,
but here's the thing is,
it's N PM today.
It could be Python tomorrow. Right.
There's,
there's always gonna be problems and people are
always gonna be making mistakes and so,
rather than
necessarily dwell on N PM,
like they have their own demons and they have their own things to work out now.
But at the same time, if, if you're,
if you're doing some sort of deployment or development,
these are the sort of things you need to keep
in mind because these are going to keep happening.
It is just the nature of the universe now. It is what it is.
-- Yeah.
-- If you drive a car, you'll end up with a flat tire someday.
Exactly. That's exactly right.
And, and you just have to decide,
I'm either going to plan for it and be prepared or I'm just going to say, screw it.
Hopefully it doesn't happen
until I quit. Right. And, and
that's the way it is.
-- Any parting thoughts, Kurt really
-- so much of this just comes back down to basic,
not even basic computer security, just basic system administration and, and
hygiene of computer use.
-- I have
-- a
backup.
I agree
completely.
I think this is one of those beautiful intersections
where
the, the same kind of process and tenants of security apply to
what is a nonsecurity issue?
So
there we have it
back your stuff up folks and um right. So I guess, yeah, thank you, Kurt.
Thank you everyone for listening.
You can go to open source security podcast.com to grab some show
notes. You can use the Pound Os S podcast hashtag to get a hold of us
and nothing else. Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks.