Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner at Thought Crime, Josh Pressers.
So you've heard the term
poor choices make good stories, right?
Uh
No,
-- you had never heard that.
-- I've actually never heard that expression.
Well, it, it does and I've got a doozy.
Well, assuming that the poor choice doesn't result in you dying then? Yes,
-- I did
-- not. I did not die.
I was mo mostly safe through the entirety of the
Kurtz aware some of it.
So I had bees in the wall of my, I should say bees. I, I use the word bees.
They were paper wasp or they were yellow jacket wasps.
They were not like honey bees. These were not friendly, nice bees.
See, honey bees are nice.
Honey bees are great.
And if I had honey bees in my garage,
I would call a beekeeper and have them like properly removed.
But these are not nice bees.
No,
I, I'll try to use the word wasp, but I'll probably say bee a lot like bees in my garage.
I just did it.
Yeah, I find that really weird that you have this like,
I, I don't know. I don't know. I call them bees, whatever. They're all bees.
-- Everything's bees.
-- Is that a thing you guys do? Like the bubblers?
I don't know. It might be. I live in a weird place. We have strange words for things.
I call everything bees anyway.
Bees
in my garage. Right. And,
-- well,
-- not in your garage, in the walls of your garage,
in the wall. Right.
And I could see them on the outside
and I have a two story garage. So they're like way up high, like really,
really high. We're talking like probably four or 5 m give or take right? Like 20 ft.
It's quite a ways up. And so I can see the bees coming in and out of a hole for reference.
How big was this hole? I don't really small, like the size of a bee. Like,
well, just sometimes it's a big hole. Some of the small hole, I don't know.
-- No,
-- it, it so funny enough,
it was a big hole because squirrels were getting in it and then I
made it a small hole and now bees were in it and I'm like,
I just traded squirrels for bees.
Like this is my nightmare also. People don't know this. I hate squirrels so much.
Like I,
my life is a constant battle against keeping squirrels from getting into my attic.
But so I, I do not, I don't like squirrels.
So I've got a hole in my garage, bees are in it and I spray them a couple of times.
-- The bees don't go away. And I'm
-- like, ok, you mean the wasps? Wasps?
Yeah. Sure.
And so I'm like, all right, I need to get rid of these things and I,
one time called an exterminator.
And he had this contraption where he put the powder in like a chamber and
then he applied air to it and there was like a small hose on the,
it's obviously like blew this dust
out into the cavity.
And obviously, when you're blowing dust,
it like gets around corners and goes everywhere, right?
So it obviously got and it killed the other wasp I had in my house a couple of years ago
and I'm like, I could totally build one of these things and
I can hear the bees in from, from the inside of the garage, right on the second story.
So I'm like, I'm not on a ladder. This isn't like scary.
I don't have to fear for my life.
And so I build a little contraption
and I looked at what the exterminator used and
it's literally the same like pesticide powder I already
have in the garage that my wife bought for
the garden like years and years and years ago,
I'm thinking, ok, I'm gonna drill a hole in the wall
and then I'm gonna stick my hose in and I'm gonna blow this powder in and I,
I built my contraption was a Gatorade bottle with a hole drilled in the side and the
top and the hose came out of the top and then I just poured in the powder,
right.
So
I do this, I drill my hole in the wall and like these
second, I remove the drill bit like bees start coming out.
-- I was about to say, yeah, I was gonna say you
-- immediately.
I thought I would have like maybe a second or two to put the tube in. No,
zero time.
If,
if you were sitting in your living room and like somebody smashed a hole in the wall,
you'd immediately stick your head through and be like, what the hell?
Right. Well,
-- so would a wasp.
-- Apparently.
So anyway, so the wasps are pouring out of the hole and I run away because I'm like,
I'm not gonna get stung and then I'm like, wait a minute,
I'm gonna have a garage full of wasps if I don't do something about this hole.
So, so I put on a hat and a coat and like, I cover up as much skin as I can.
And I, I got a pencil which was about the size of the hole and I like,
run up there and I shove the pencil in the hole and it fit nicely.
It was nice and snug and then I run away and I'm like, ok,
no more wasps can come out of the hole. But now I've got, like,
I probably have 100 wasps flying around the, the upstairs in my garage now.
Like, it was a lot. So, I'm like, what am I gonna do now?
And I thought, oh, I could wait for tonight and I'm like,
I don't want to wait for tonight because,
-- like, I, I, I've got 100 wasps but they're just
-- gonna, how does waiting help?
Well, at night they go, like, to the, they, they can't fly in the dark.
But, yeah, exactly. I'm like, how am I gonna find 100 wasp in the, in the dark? Right.
-- Sorry,
-- pause, pause, pause, pause. You think wasps can't fly in the dark?
They don't, no, they don't.
Most
flying bee type insects, wasps and bees and stuff they,
they can't see at night so they don't fly.
I'll be damned. Uh, no, it's because they become sluggish.
Usually with the, without the warm sunshine
-- that
-- could be so they will become sluggish and only
become alive one activity when there is warm sunshine around.
So you can safely sleep after the fact that they
will not fly around or sting people after dark.
-- Right. Right.
-- Today I learned.
So anyway,
I then took my shot back and started sucking bees out of the air with a shop
back which is a considerably harder task than I expected it to be for what it's worth.
But I did not get stung. I emerged from the end of that chain of events
with, with nothing to show for it except, um, a story, a
pencil in your wall labeled. Do not
look. And I, I sent a text to my family.
I'm like, do not take the pencil out of the wall in the garage. Like bees will come out
and then
I waited till dark.
I pulled the pencil out and it's like, I,
I definitely did like the Indiana Jones swapper.
Like there was, there was no clearance for anything to come out of that hole.
And then I sprayed my stuff in and
as best as I can tell the, the, the Wasps are dead,
I cannot hear them or see them anywhere.
I'm going to wait a couple of days before I declare like, complete victory.
But yes, my poor choice is made for a ridiculous story.
-- Well,
-- that kind of leads to this conversation, which is
sort of where is,
no, no, no.
But like, seriously where, where do people, like, where does a software vendors
sort of responsibility begin and end with respect to
end of life and taking care of stuff?
Right? Because you live in your house right now.
So you want to take care of it because you don't want to share your house with Wasps.
Yes.
But
in theory, if you were selling that house next week,
you might just put a piece of tape over the outside and be like,
we're not going to talk about this.
I would, that's illegal. That's fraud.
You can't not tell people about things, you know, wrong with your house.
That's a gray area. Because did you know,
you could say with a straight away
that would be a bad time to claim you
didn't know about it after recording this podcast.
Yes. After recording my story. Although at the end of the story, I was successful,
-- I
-- think, no, you think you were successful?
I, I'm 80% certain.
I'm 80%.
Yeah,
that's what I'll say. 80%.
By the time this podcast goes out, I'll be 100% certain or, or I succeeded
or
so. So there's a story about Google Chrome not working in an old version of Ubuntu.
-- It's an LTs from uh 2000
-- 18
Ubuntu 1804,
which is pretty damn old. Like we're on, we're now on to
Ubuntu
24.
Yeah, because the, the, the number is just a year. So 18, it's from 2018,
24 means it's from 2024
and Linux
has changed a lot in six years.
Well, and, and not just Linux,
but the user space, right? Which is kind of what this is really about,
-- right?
-- Because it was, I think a
glib c conflict or something that
it was like 4.1 and they,
they need a slightly newer
-- or something like that.
-- Yeah.
And, and this topic I like because especially our history,
I know we talk about red hat all the time on the show.
But like this was a huge thing at Red Hat because Red
Hat would say we support a Linux distribution for 10 years.
-- Uh
-- 13.
Is it 13? Now? It was 10, I think back in the day
it's, it's been 13 for a long time and it's actually a bit longer than 13.
That could be. And, and whatever
they're saying, we're support a thing for a really long time.
And now chrome is in a weird place because Chrome
is supporting
their thing on someone else's system.
At
-- least at Red Hat, it was our stuff.
-- Let's talk about why Chrome exists.
First of all, Chrome exists to protect
goals
uh to protect Google's ad revenue. Basically. Yes.
And also to Google has a history of trying to push the industry forwards,
like for example, with Google fiber.
Yeah,
trying to shame and, and
that did not work.
But basically everybody else got high speed internet for different reasons.
But Chrome originally remember when it came out
and the V eight javascript engine
-- blew the socks off of everything else to an absurd degree
-- and look at the sandbox,
they did, their security was top notch.
Yes.
And so so that people forget, but there was a time where Google docs ran pretty OK?
In Chrome. And
I, I cannot use words without you having a bleeper button
to describe how poorly they ran in Firefox and
Microsoft Internet Explorer and all those other things.
Yes, it was terrible for sure. No, it wasn't terrible. It was completely unusable.
Right. It was utterly unusable. It was so slow
and the web in general Google saw the future,
which was these javascript apps because like
the front page of CNN is like a megabyte.
So obviously delivering a big chunk of javascript
and some data is not a problem anymore.
Right. Right. And the future is these web apps as like I spend all day in web apps.
And I, I,
you know,
I know people who honestly prefer the web
apps to the native desktop versions of things.
There aren't many desktop apps I prefer anymore.
-- There is Microsoft Office and Slack.
-- The Slack app is just a web page
which infuriates me because if you change your
user agent to pretend you're the Slack app,
you get like the in the proper Slack experience
-- in the web page.
-- I know. Right. That's
why do I have to install your crappy stupid app to use your stupid service? Like it
-- drives me. I could complain for hours.
-- I
don't know.
I know because they want to track the crap out of us. That's why
so Chrome exists to basically protect Google's ad revenue streams and to
protect their like to make sure that their apps work like,
well, we'll say just to push Google's agenda,
their ad revenue is part of their agenda.
Security is part of their agenda.
-- Part of their, it's, it's 90% of their operating profits
-- to,
it's
a
big
part of their agenda,
but they also like their security work. They do, they have multiple agendas. It's,
yeah, and some of them align with what you and I want. So that's great.
Like they want better security because they're tired of doing, you know,
fixing people's accounts and dealing with cracked accounts and all that stuff.
And so challenges though,
sometimes their agenda doesn't line up with other people's agendas, which is,
for example, they want to keep Chrome kind of moving forwards, right?
Like they, they, they do a lot of releases like kind of every week or two and
they're constantly pushing out new
features.
And for example, they're, you know, they're,
they're putting in trust to death this fall by, you know,
removing their certificate from the root trust store,
which we talked about a couple of shows ago.
And so like a lot of things Chrome does some things they can just deploy like, hey,
we support this new web feature
and some things they have to kind of stage and deploy like, oh, you know, we're,
we're killing this.
So
you're gonna have six months or 12 months or whatever to deal with.
And the problem is
if you keep backwards compatibility,
that will utterly hobble your ability to move forwards for a lot of things,
it for sure does
-- supporting old things is very expensive.
-- Well, it's not just that it's expensive.
It's that supporting old things means some oftentimes you can't have the new thing.
-- It
-- can.
Yes, I've seen that before.
So a perfect example of this is a lot of people are like we need to support Python Two.
that thing needs to die
-- if
-- they choose that.
There's so much and, and they choose not to support Python three.
Their app is like there's so much that's just going
to be a horror show of compatibility and unicode support.
Yes,
it just, it's end of life like Python two is dead.
Well, and the Python project decided that and they can.
But the thing is the problem is Chrome runs on top of other stuff that Google
doesn't control or have any say that's correct.
Does Google have some sort of duty
to keep supporting platforms that they have supported? It's that simple.
-- So,
-- here's my take on this.
It's easy to dunk on Chrome right now
because obviously it's been doing some dumb stuff
like with the Manifest V three and just kind of some of the other attitudes.
But I think at the end of the day,
like, I don't blame someone like Google for end of life in something old.
It sucks maintaining it
and my suspicion, I don't know this for sure
because I don't run
ubuntu. But I, I'm pretty, I, I bet you can use a snap or something on
ubuntu 18 and,
and basically get Chrome to run and if you can't in all seriousness,
like upgrade freaking
Ubuntu, like there, there's, there is a path around this.
You can either run Firefox or upgrade
Ubuntu. So I, I don't think Google is out of now.
They should have given some warning, which my understanding is,
they just killed it one day and people were like, holy crap,
-- what's going on
-- more to the point?
Why is Google
the one in trouble here when it's a
btu's operating system?
And if people, if there's a package of software that is very popular,
should that kind of be a
Btu's job to
-- make sure it works.
-- Not anymore.
I mean, so this is something Google did with Chrome actually is
they took on the, the maintainer ship of that for nearly everything.
So like I, I run Fedora,
I uh the recording thing we use for podcasting is called Riverside and
it only runs in Chrome which drives me crazy and I hate that,
but I have to install chrome.
Do you know how much easier life is if you support one
web browser and it's chrome and you tell everybody install it?
Yes, I'm, I don't like it, but I understand.
And I, when I install Chrome, they gave me an R PM that then set up the app package
repository for fire for, for,
for Chrome.
That then every time I do ad NF upgrade,
I get the new chrome that Google has in their repository.
It's kind of clever now I could use like the flat pack, for example.
And that would, but I don't because I don't know,
I'm worried about the cameras and microphones and all the weird crap we
do like working correctly because flat packs have security on certain things.
And
so I just don't deal with it.
But,
but yeah, like Google did that and I suspect they did that to make sure
that the version of Chrome you were getting
when you were a user
was the experience they wanted you to have.
Because one of the things that happens is
when you have a distribution repackaging software,
they can make decisions, we'll say well,
or just the maintainer goes away on vacation.
That's true. You could, yes, someone could not upgrade it for sure.
That's I had to take over a PHP package in,
in uh Fedora because I needed an up to date version that actually worked.
And the person who was in charge
it previously, it just kind of abandoned it and walked away from Fedora.
Sure
it happens.
I mean,
I don't think for a major package you'd see an issue like that, but
it
could happen. Yes.
Anyway, Google controls their destiny, which I have no problem with.
Like there is absolutely nothing wrong with doing that
and it's not like you can't, I mean,
I know this is one of those classic like, well, you can,
technically it's open source and build it yourself and blah, blah, blah.
I mean, realistically, no God, no,
-- it's so
-- much work. You can't build. Chrome is not open source.
Chromium
is
open
two mixed up.
Yes, Chromium.
In fact,
you can install Chromium and it would not surprise me if Chromium still runs on
Ubuntu 18 because someone is building it there.
But Chrome which is based on Chromium is not open source.
It just uses a lot of open source.
So I always get those two mixed up. I forget that Chrome is like a binary only version.
And that's why everybody always, because I knew my brain.
I'm always like, why is everybody so sour about this thing?
-- It's open source but it's not,
-- not open source.
Right.
Well, and that's probably the other thing is a lot of the distributions, like,
especially Fedora,
you don't package binaries in Fedora. That's not how Fedora works.
You, you build source.
That is how it works. And I don't know if ubuntu is quite as strict.
I know they were a little looser back in the day. I'm not sure if they've changed, but
same idea.
Like, they don't want to take your binary blob of crap because in reality,
if you take a binary blob of crap from someone,
you, there's nothing you can do. Like, if there's
a,
or something doesn't work. It's like,
sorry, I,
I don't know what to do.
And that's an infamous problem with, like, a lot of hardware drivers.
-- Yeah. Yeah,
-- for sure. You know where the, the wind modems? Oh, God, the wind modems.
Yeah. Well, I remember the network.
I, I had this conversation yesterday with someone, I don't remember who it was now.
But,
yeah, like, so for, for, for all you young uns who have no idea.
Like, back in the day we're talking about 20 years ago, give or take. Probably
you would buy, like, a laptop
and it would have a wireless card in it
for Wi Fi, which was novel at the time, not everyone had it.
And in order for Wi Fi to work on Linux,
you usually needed some terrible binary only driver from the manufacturer.
And this was actually one of the places that ubuntu, they were like,
we are going to support all of these drivers.
And if you install
ubuntu,
like your computer is just going to work and that captured a lot of the
hearts and minds of people back in the day because like I could install Deb
or, or, or Fedora
and then I can spend a week trying to get this stupid Wi Fi card working or I can install
ubuntu and it just works.
See, it, it's interesting to me because I,
I just had basically a very parallel situation with my car, right.
My car has a Hyundai GD I engine from the years where
they
occasionally blow up or seize up or catch fire, even if you take care of them
I took care of it
and now Hyundai, well, uh Kia sorry is replacing the engine
on their nickel,
which is like five or seven grand.
That's a lot of money. The difference being with
chrome, for example is,
well, you still have a working version of chrome on Ubuntu 18. It's just
-- out of date.
-- No, I don't think that's, I would not say that. No.
What I'm about to say though is
software is different,
especially web browsers because you can't have an out of date browser.
-- I mean,
-- I would, I don't
think
-- like you can't, you can't browse the web safely.
-- I'd compare it to a gallon of milk.
Right?
You have a gallon of milk in your fridge
and you can do nothing
-- and it will still become unusable eventually.
-- Exactly.
Uh, well, not just unusable but like actively a biohazard. Probably.
Right. No, no. Like sir.
And that's the thing though is it's not like chrome,
just kind of degrades and stops working.
No, it becomes an active.
It's dangerous
if you actually like if you browse the web with a version of chrome from two years ago,
-- I hope you have some good antivirus on that system
-- that won't help you.
I mean, this is why people say softer ages like milk, not like cheese
because old cheese. Well, even that you'll say is iffy, but
yes, I've had very old cheese and it's quite, quite nice.
So, but that's the thing, right. Is this,
you can't just be like, oh well, you still have the working version, you're fine.
Keep using it. No abs like stop using it.
So actually you say that
that is not something I heard anyone say once and
all of the things I read about this particular thing.
I think it basically came down to
Google stopped supporting chrome on a really old version of ubuntu.
A bunch of people got angry, Google was like, all right, we goofed up,
we're going to make it work.
And then in, like, I think they said six months, they're gonna,
they're gonna kill it.
And, like,
I respect that. I think they handle it pretty well in all seriousness
or this was the plan all along
instead of giving six months warning and dealing with the blowback. Now they just,
they do this shenanigans. I doubt they're that Machiavellian. But whatever,
I'm skeptical, they, they're that with it, but that is a, that would be clever.
Well, it's just also, that's,
you know, Ockham's razor,
right. It's stupid. So, it's probably true.
My suspicion,
my guess having done a lot of this kind of work at some
point in the past is they were building the new version of chrome
and they were like, it fails on point
to 18 and they were like, ah, whatever. Barely anyone uses it there. Who cares.
And they were like, great. We're dead now and then it turned out
like,
yeah, people were using it
well, and that's the thing. It's possible it was like 100 people
-- but they were just really loud like,
-- well, and that's,
that's the case with a lot of things nowadays is you get
these like a small group can sound very loud online and,
and especially like dunking on chrome is cool right now.
So like,
I, I get it like it was easy to run with this one.
-- But
-- that's, that's one thing you mentioned. That's
is, yeah, we, we've, I think we've basically trained people in large part but
web browsers especially
also a lot of server software has to be up to date and patched or else it's toxic waste.
-- I mean,
-- just software, I think software in general is kind of viewed in that way now
the,
but especially software that interacts with other public
stuff that you don't control like the web
or, you know, like your mail server accepts in coming.
Like I always love when people are like, you know, hey,
can we like set up our email server?
So it only talks to trusted people. And I'm like,
not really like, unless,
unless there's like three companies you got to talk to and you,
they'll give you their IP ranges and then you'll never get email from anyone else.
Like
that sounds actually kind of lovely. Like I,
you know, somebody at the CS A was like, hey, Kurt, can you lock email out?
So only people we know, talk to us. I'd be like, oh yeah, yeah, we can do that.
So it's funny you say that because actually there's,
there's another story I'll link to in the show notes where
uh Linus Torvalds at some conference somewhere.
I don't know where he, he went on and on about a whole bunch of stuff.
And one of the things that came up was all of the
CD ES going to the Linux kernel because it's a lot.
-- It's what, like 60 a day, I think on average now.
-- No, no, no,
not 60 a day. It's,
um,
it'll
-- about
-- 60
-- a week.
Roughly it'll be about 4000 ish or something a year. Yeah. Give or take that.
That's the,
with about a 3% rejection rate, which is pretty damn good.
-- Yeah. Oh, they're doing, I think they're doing
-- a
good job.
Yeah, I think it was like 2.7 actually.
So, it's funny, uh, uh,
Daniel from Curl basically looked at number of lines of code in curl,
number of lines of code in the kernel and the ratios
pretty much line up from the number of CD ES.
Curl
has had a number of CV S A kernel has had based on lines of code,
which I found pretty interesting.
-- Well, the thing is if they're within an order of magnitude, they're
-- very close,
it's not even an order of magnitude apart.
-- I
-- have a suspicion. It's not so much about how many bugs there are.
It's about how many people are looking at the code and updating it
for. Exactly. Because curl
and the Linux kernel are both stupidly active projects
in ways that most other projects are not.
-- Yes.
-- And they're very receptive. But my,
I, I want, I would like to do some more work in this because if the,
it's, it's right now, I think like 13,000 lines of code per CV E per year,
like do the math.
If that is true,
that would be a super useful number that we could apply all over the place.
I have a suspicion that, that, well, that,
that number applies to C and that for other programming languages, like for Python,
it'll be a much,
that's a good point. It'll be a smaller number for Python because Python is denser.
Um because somebody did a really fast thing of for every line of code,
the developer writes essentially how many lines of
machine code gets spat out the end.
And of course, like c it's
a bunch and in Python, it's like a whole bunch because, you know,
people do like import pandas and then
that's like 10 megabytes of software right there.
And so I have a suspicion though that between
I'm going to use the word density,
the density of the language and the information it holds.
So Python is higher density than say C right? Because Python, you can,
I'm
willing to make this claim without any evidence.
But I, I have a suspicion for Python.
It'll be a lot less than 13,000 lines of Python per year per CV.
Oh, you think it'll be higher? I don't know.
Well, no, no, I think like Python will be like 1000 lines of code per CV per year.
Maybe. I don't know. It'll be interesting.
I need to find some good projects to do the research on anyway. Ok. back to line.
So Linus basically, like this was all pointed out and he said, like,
stop running old kernels
and that like this is the message coming out of the
kernel is like stop running these old kernels.
And then he also made a comment about like all the, the Chinese
4.9 hardware manufacturers still running like the 49 kernel.
This really goes to the fact of especially with open source
unless you're paying somebody like red hat a butt load
of money to back port stuff to keep it stable,
but no open source projects really gonna want to do that or care.
And we talked about that where, you know,
all these companies want people to take on this engineering,
you know,
um sustainment work.
And like, weirdly enough
that doesn't excite a lot of people.
It's pretty boring you have,
that's definitely one of those things you have to pay people if you want it done.
I mean, 100%. And I know like this is something tide lift is trying to do
where you pay tide lift money.
Then tide lift goes to open source and says, like,
please take care of this old stuff for money.
And I think 20 years ago, you absolutely could do this with the Lenox girl quite soon
mainly.
But now with the size of Len kernel and the change velocity or something like curl,
I it's going to become less and less possible in that.
It's just gonna become so much more expensive.
Well, and, and infrastructure is different now.
I mean, look, this is like the crowd strike. Delta story
of Delta obviously had
their infrastructure was not modernized to a point, they could roll things back or,
or fix problems remotely.
They were sending people, you know, people were schlepping USB drives around
to unlock computers and, and roll things back.
And
I think
back, you know, 1020 years ago
when something broke, you had to send someone out to fix it.
Whereas now a lot of infrastructure, like if something breaks,
you can roll it back without too much effort.
And I think this is part of what's helping drive this. Like let's just freaking
concurrent because it's a lot easier than trying to
maintain all this old crap and if it breaks,
we'll just roll it back.
Well,
something remember with an entity like Delta is
like they'll have their own network with Ilo,
you know, integrated Lights out management.
Oh man. Oh, I'm not blaming them. I'm just,
the thing to remember is, for example, they'll have a bunch of kiosks or signs
at the airport network
but where they can't maybe have long.
And so,
yeah, how do we fix it?
Well, Gary needs to go out there with a step ladder and, like, fix it.
Yeah, I, I, I'm not, I'm not, I'm not smashing on Delta here.
Like I, I get it, like, running an airline is hard. I don't know how it works. It's ok.
Uh,
so, but back to this, like, I think the reality is, is
there the cost
of maintaining a delta a change between you
and sort of upstream is getting to the point where it's no longer sustainable.
-- Not in very many things. I agree with that,
-- you know,
and
because the reality is, it's not just a delta of one thing,
it's a delta of multiple things that are interlinked.
And so I think it's,
you get this kind of network effect of complexity where if
something is 1% out and only one thing was 1% out,
then you're 1% out.
But when you have 100 things that are linked together and 1% out,
I feel like you're much more the one percent out of sort of the delta.
And I think that's
because I look at the complexity of software. Like I had,
uh the A, I write me a bunch of html,
five web pages to do some clever image manipulation for my son to make per
bead patterns.
And like when I kind of look at what's being called library wise, it's like
I'm literally doing
image
manipulation and recognition in like 200 lines of html code
and javascript
and it's just calling a bunch of magic libraries.
OK. You know,
and that's a simple thing compared to say, oh, I don't know a web browser like Chrome.
Where, Right? How many lines of code is Chrome?
Web browser in total with all the libraries it pulls in now
tens of millions. At least.
I bet it's, it's a lot. And, and so you bring this up.
Uh I remember I was at Red Hat when
we would back
for the security vulnerabilities in Firefox every
time there's a new Firefox that came out
and
we were part of, we helped fire Fox do security work.
So we usually, we knew what the patches were
that were security relevant and it was like a couple, it was like 10 or less, right?
And I remember when we hit the point where it was like, we can't do this anymore.
We have to just start taking Firefox and upgrading
it and that's the way it's going to be.
And it was like,
it was very contentious and there was a lot of
back and forth and stuff and it's like we,
we have no choice
and,
and I think the Linux kernel is the same story
like you have no choice anymore like you're taking it,
that's it.
-- Well. But
-- also if you want the new features,
ignoring new features, I don't even care about new features.
Just keeping the lights on
means you're going to have to upgrade same.
I mean this is the same deal like chrome is the same story like you upgrade chrome,
you don't, there is no plan B like you take what they give you
well and something to remember though
is with Chrome.
For example,
I have to be compatible with the website serving
the content I want to see and interact with.
I have to have those new features. Or else
my web browser becomes useless.
I mean to a degree
on this,
do you think an old version of Chrome is going to work with this riverside thing?
II, I don't know where they would put the cut off.
-- I I bet they know and they would tell me if I looked it up
-- but at some point, they,
they started using a feature in the video that
didn't exist in the previous version of Chrome,
right?
And I just looked,
the Chromium browser code base contains over 32 million source lines of code.
But is that just the browser or is that I bet that's not the dependencies?
-- I bet that's just the Chromium
-- browser
which is
I
bet if you add indep dependencies multiply that by a number
like
it's probably 100 million lines of stuff when it's all done. I bet.
Yeah. Which is like mind boggling.
Um, that's the world we live in now. That's how everything works.
And that's why I can have this, like,
image of you on a screen and talk to you and record it.
I know. And you're,
and I'm not
like, it's wild.
It
is, it always amusing to me, like all the things we can do now,
like we can we complain and, and
oh Zoom is broken like the world is ending. It's like
10 years ago. Like
I remember when like 480 video
was like, oh my God, this is amazing. And now,
so we were talking about that one day.
It was me and some friends and we were mentioning to the kids
about how like when the Star Wars episode one trailer came out,
we all watched it off dial up and it was like this itty bitty
video
running on like Real Player or something and it was just terrible.
I know. Right. Buffalo
that
everyone hated real player.
Yes.
Yes. Anyway. Anyway.
All right, we're kind of, we're, we're running out of steam on this one.
I think I just keep coming back to the world is so
much more big and complex in terms of scale and software abilities.
And
getting into that being in a delta, a change like out of sync with
reality with upstream.
It's just,
yeah, you can do it and and there might be some short term benefits where like, oh,
we don't have to do updates because we're doing this.
But it,
I just don't see a way forward that doesn't involve
keeping everything up to date all the time and,
and investing in testing frameworks and testing rigs and all
that stuff so that you can catch stuff right away
and work with upstream or with both upstream. Because
what I'm seeing a lot more is like, um
not a flaw per se, but like this thing now interacts with this thing in a weird way
where it doesn't work,
right?
And you know,
those two projects may not even know each other exist.
Let alone, there's a another thing that gloms them both together.
-- Well,
-- and look man again
to 18,
that's from 2018. We're in 2024 right now at the time of recording. So like
that's a long time ago. And,
and it kind of also,
I don't want to tell people what to do, but I feel like
if you're running a desktop based on technology from six years ago,
-- like your desktop is gonna suck
-- the thing to remember.
No, it's not about the desktops.
It's, it'll be about um like CNC milling machines that have a web interface,
-- things like that.
-- You think they're running a bunch of 18 on that crap stuff.
Remember that? A
web
browser?
Yeah, because it's a cheap way to write an interface.
I don't know you're
OK.
By definition,
if you're building something like AC NC milling
machine or a cell counting machine that runs Linux
and has a gooey interface,
building a web based interface versus trying to teach
these people how to use like GTK or something.
-- I
-- feel like running latest chrome on that system is not how it's working.
I just, I've seen a lot of stuff where web browsers get used and stuff that you,
you wouldn't like, think of being a desktop.
-- But
-- yes,
and I also suspect the developers who create
those particular systems cast that web browser in amber
and it's never updated ever because updating it might
break whatever fragile thing they've constructed beneath it.
If there's one thing I've learned from all of the,
we'll say like
industrial systems I've interacted with and it's not a lot
-- is they never change anything once they get it working, like it's set forever,
-- the,
the cost of an outage is significant.
Like I remember the story where somebody n map scanned uh a network and brought down
a production line for cookies and they had to throw a day's worth of cookies.
I believe it. I believe it. I, I know
like MRI machines at hospitals, everyone's like do not like they,
they tell the pent testers stay away from this IP
address because the MRI machines aren't running on that like
I get it. It's
and yeah, the MRI machines also running Windows 95 So
what,
how it works.
Uh It is what it is.
I mean, I don't know, I think all in all like, yeah,
it's easy to dunk on chrome right now but I, I don't, I don't blame him.
You know,
it
is.
At least now there is the possibility for software updates because for example,
stuff used to run hardware that was so limited that whatever code they gave you,
that's what you had
full stop.
And now, for example, you can just chuck a raspberry pie into something
and
there's a possibility of like upgrading Linux to
something reasonable even probably 10 years from now.
Maybe, I don't know. I'm not going to trust that once I get something running.
Actually my 3D printer in the basement,
it is a boron.
It runs a Raspberry pi as the
primary interface for the printer.
I've never upgraded it and I don't want to touch it because in fact,
my kid upgraded it once and it broke everything and it took us three days to fix it.
I'm like, never upgrade Linux again on this computer.
Like it will be whatever versions on it forever now.
And I'm literally a security guy.
I'm like, don't upgrade it.
But the thing is you probably have compensating controls like
it's sitting on a trusted network behind a net,
blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
I
don't trust my network,
but you know what I'm saying? Like it's not plugged into the
internet
-- and
-- the internet.
But it's definitely,
it's not like when you go to show
dot IO and look for like, remote desktops
software and it's like all there,
-- here's
-- my compensating control. I just realized we ended on this
is
there is no authentication to the system and you
can open a shell in the web interface.
So it doesn't matter how old it is because you
can already turn into root on the 3D printer.
So it's fine.
So there you go.
My compensating control is the complete and utter lack of compensating controls.
Yeah,
I guess if, if we give everyone root,
we don't have to worry about someone becoming root.
-- It's fine. Everybody,
-- it's not a bug, it's a feature.
-- It's intentional. We
-- solved security.
Well, it's like that whole CV thing. They don't do CV. S for intentional backdoor.
But if you make a mistake, they'll give it a CV. And it's like,
but when an attacker intentionally puts a back door into something,
shouldn't we want people to know about that?
We're gonna have a show all about this.
So, actually I was contacted, um, I don't know the guys, I forget his, his real name.
Um, he, he listened to the show, he goes by Grimm
on
Mastodon
and he is the paint maintainer of Pigeon
and he got a hold of me a couple of days ago. I was like, hey, I have a plug in.
That is a backdoor.
Well, I think it's a backdoor. Do you know anyone who can help me?
And I was like, let me, let me ask around, I can look for some people and I,
I contacted some folks, but it turned out uh Johnny
Xus,
who's a uh like a legendary gamer hacker guy. He's in the Chicago area.
He worked with them
and, and yes, it was in fact a keylogger
and now, but now pigeons like, OK, how do we try to, to bet some of these plugins stuff?
I'm like, we should talk about all of this, this whole story.
Like the whole saga would make a marvelous show.
So yes, we're going to talk about exactly this because I think it's gonna be amazing.
And yeah, it's like he also says, should I get a CV for this?
I'm like, you can try but it's against the rules, like, which is stupid.
Crowdstrike didn't get a CV. And it's like only the most important security related
thing that happened. It happened this year.
I love Xe did and it shouldn't have and people were complaining it got a CV.
And it's like, shut up, like, do not talk.
It is the best thing in the world that we can have automated scanners,
find this stupid thing and tell us if we're running it like
you're an idiot. Stop complaining anyway,
I'm
calling it.
I want to know if they lose criminal of security vulnerabilities. Ok. We'll do that.
I remember for the longest time people were like the, the
new
Scel refuses to do CV S and then L was
like, oh, ok. Well, we'll do them like, oh, not like that, right? Like,
because
like, like you said, like, it might be a milking machine.
-- It might be the Mars Lander, they
-- use the monkey paw,
like, don't use the monkey
and make wishes everybody, you get what you want.
All right.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to Pitzer Security podcast.com. Hit up the show to Susie Pondo says podcast.
Hashtag and thats done.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.