Hello and welcome to episode 97 of the Yoga
Source Security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime, Josh Reser.
All right.
So we were talking before the show and we decided that the,
the title is going to be Automation.
Humans Are Slow and Dumb.
And, and that made my day.
Well, it's provably true in most cases.
It probably is.
Uh,
so. Ok.
Well, yeah, why don't we explain to viewers what we're actually talking about?
Well, it's, it's
the topic is your idea. So, I'm gonna let you take this one.
So, um,
basically what I've noticed is there's been
a,
we're entering an era where there's
a lot more automation
of things that in past were not automated, like driving cars because
it's, you know, quite, actually, quite difficult to do that.
And so, you know, it's one thing to automate an airplane that cost over $100 million.
Right.
Because then you can, you can spend a bit of money on that and more to the point planes,
you know, they don't have to dodge stuff constantly,
maybe a goose or two. Right.
Well, it's, you know, even then Yeah,
even then you don't really dodge it so much as try
not to fall out of the sky when you hit it.
And, and what really piqued my interest was, you know, this whole thing with the,
the Tesla self, they call it self driving
and these things are killing people.
Tesla do they? Is it technically self driving or what do they call it autopilot?
Right.
And it's like human assisted or some crap like that because like the human
is supposed to have their hands on the wheel according to what I've read,
which of course I'm sure nobody does.
Uh, they call it
all Tesla vehicles produced in our factory, including model three,
have the hardware needed for full self driving capability at a safety level,
substantially greater than that of a human driver that is from tesla.com.
So, yeah, they call it self driving.
Ok. Well, that's cool.
Let's be clear.
Statistically on average is even a not great self driving car
probably going to be better than your average human driver.
And the answer is probably, yes.
Right. Humans are pretty terrible at this stuff.
Seriously, man, humans are awful drivers and as a human driver,
I will totally back this up.
Yeah,
but the problem is,
um,
ok. Well, obviously self Tesla self driving is not
perfect and, and quite far from it, right, because for example,
it slammed into the back of a fire engine and,
um,
there was that lane change thing with a barrier
ahead that a guy got slammed into and died
and,
you know, so Tesla's take on this and some people's take on this is, oh, well,
you know,
the human should have spotted that a problem was occurring and intervened and,
you know, saved the day.
And the problem is
that's basically impossible even at the best of times.
And here we have a situation where we've told the human, hey, chill out,
the car is gonna take care of this.
So now you see when you're driving, you're responsible for the vehicle and you know,
this, so you're,
you're kind of looking for problems and you're kind of ready to intervene, you know,
somebody swerves in front of you, you swerve out of their way, whatever, right?
-- I mean, that's the idea. But I think
-- um a good analogy is if you're a passenger in a car
under what circumstances do you lean over, grab the wheel and reef it over?
I've never had to do that.
And
have you ever had
a terrifies me?
Have you
done this
to
somebody?
No, I have not.
Um
And so, and that's essentially the analogy here is that, you know,
when you're in a self driving car that is in self-driving mode, you're,
you're effectively a passenger
and for you to deal with the problem part of the
problem is you first have to realize that there's a problem.
Secondly, you have to then realize that the car is not dealing with it
because that's literally the car's job at
this point. Right. It's self driving.
Right.
And so I think fundamentally, I, I,
because I've been looking at this self driving car
thing and I've been toying with the idea of,
you know, do I,
do I go with a,
a car that has some self driving features or do I wait for like the car with a button?
You know, and, and an app to tell it where to go.
I'm, I'm gonna run my current car into the ground with hopes.
By the time it stops running, I can get a real self driving car.
That's, that's my goal. I'm kind of really on the dice on this one. Yeah.
-- And,
-- and I would agree because from the research I've done now,
if the car is not 100% autonomous self driving,
then as the human being, you, you, you actually,
in some ways need to be more alert and more vigilant
than if you're just driving the damn thing yourself. Because
like I said, you have to not only spot that there's a problem,
but you have to spot that the car is not going to deal with the problem,
right?
-- So that's like two levels of, of reaction and decision making instead of one
-- is,
is that the intent of those?
I mean, so I
think the intent of
this statistically, it's better than people.
It's those corner cases where it will feel worse than a person.
But ideally those corner cases happen
less and less often,
right? I mean,
ok,
maybe
I, I feel like most of the the human augmentation technology I've seen
really
-- about
-- like
this
is
-- self
-- driving.
Some of it is, I mean, like, let me give you an example.
There's the, the things that will stop your car if you,
if you don't stop right where there's something in front of you
and let's face it.
We've all done this where we look at our phone, we look at the radio, we look at,
you know, like the, the weird cat off the side of the road, whatever.
And all of a sudden you look up and the guy in front of you stopped or there's
-- a tree there, whatever. Right? And,
-- and
that sort of technology,
right. As opposed to do you wait for the car to deal with it
by definition,
deal
-- with it. Right. No,
-- no, no.
What I mean is,
is you're in a self driving car and the car is in self driving
mode and you look up and you see there's a large stationary object,
say 200 m away from you.
What do you do? Do you trust that the car will swerve around it
or do you do it?
I don't know the answer to that.
I've never been in it.
Right.
And the answer is, well,
apparently Teslas end up running into a fire truck
at highway speeds when the fire truck is stopped.
-- Uh, that,
-- that did happen, didn't it?
Do you think the person could have
helped it
-- if
-- they'd spotted it soon enough and
not trusted their car?
Because the other prompt too is, you know, in theory with a self driving car,
it should be able to avoid an obstacle by very little.
Right.
So, you know, it's, it's a lot less dangerous to swerve a little than to swerve a lot,
right?
You swerve too much, you might lose control of the car and roll it.
You know. So
in a, in a theoretically perfect world, you know,
it's gonna swerve around the child and miss them by one inch,
right? And scare the bejesus out of that poor kid,
right? In an
imperfect world, right?
You,
you stand on the brakes and swerve and you end up
like rolling the car and rolling over the kid or something horrible
and, and that would be bad. See,
so that's, that's why I'm, you know, because here's the thing,
this is essentially history repeating itself.
Uh And as I mentioned before, you know, um airline
autopilots and automation,
this whole scenario effectively happened with Airbus back
in the day when Airbus introduced the flight,
not only the fly by wire,
but the,
the automation aspect of it and you know,
the joke at the time was uh Airbus planes will come with, you know, a dog
and the dog's job is to prevent, you know, a person from touching the controls.
And, um, so there were cases,
there were cases where, you know,
an Airbus plane got itself into a situation that was completely recoverable.
But because the human thought the computer was going to handle it,
it, it became unrecoverable.
Right. The, um,
the, the one being that slow speed pass where they just
gently descended into the forest and, you know, at
the Paris, was it the Paris Air Show?
I don't know, you pay more attention to this stuff than I do.
Um,
so, ok, so here's,
I'm gonna, I'm gonna unpack a bunch of this here. So
I, I feel like there are a couple of important topics
encased in this conversation there. There's, first of all, the fact that
a, a good
automated system
can outperform a human under most circumstances,
-- there are
-- always going.
Right. Exactly. That's, that's fair.
There are always going to be corner cases where
the automated system may fail or something could happen.
And
today we kind of have the attitude of the human should take over and fix
my comment on that corner case. I think part of the problem here
is that
even statistically if the self driving car is better than a human,
if the corner cases where it fails are ones where
human beings feel like they could have handled it,
then the perception will be probably that the self driving system is worse
because, you know, oh, every 10 million car trips, it makes a mistake.
Even a toddler could have spotted.
And, and I, I think this is where statistics become important and this is where
I, I want to take the conversation kind of to uh up up a level about automation is
there's always going to be corner cases and it's always going to be easy to say
a human could have done better.
But it's quite likely that most of these corner
cases represent a small percentage and given the,
the human error rate being astronomical,
that if you, if you kind of compare the two
in terms of overall safety,
the automation is going to win
every time.
The
problem
-- is in this one,
-- I think with the way we're doing automation,
especially with neural networks, there's no sort of
the neural network is confident in what it's doing.
It can't really signal that it's failing
because it doesn't think it's failing ever.
That's the whole point of it. Right.
Right. They, they never know they're failing. Exactly.
And, and this is where,
where I wanted to go in the context of security especially is
these days when you talk about security and artificial intelligence,
machine learning automation, things like that.
There's still very much the attitude of let the A
I tell the human when something weird is going on
and
you still get an astronomical number of alerts when something like that happens.
And, and I feel like we're,
we're kind of reaching a point where we need to start putting serious thought into
what is our autopilot look like and how can we trust it because it's going
to catch 95% of the actual cases and the 5% that are corner cases.
Those are the ones the humans should be dealing with
as one off, not the, not the 95
percent.
Those are the ones where it should be in a learning opportunity much like,
you know how the airline industry has become
much safer because in theory, every time there's a crash or an incident,
it's investigated, recommendations are made hopefully followed
and we solve that problem,
you know, be it mechanical or operational or some process
or in some cases, you know, it's,
it's like microburst and it's a completely new
set of radar technology and computers and some,
you know, some pretty amazing
and cool technology and process happens to,
yeah, we solve the problem,
-- you know, like, and,
-- and insecurity.
How many times do we do a proper triage of the incident and say
these are the things we should do to make sure this never happens again.
Well,
I think one of the challenges in security is
the majority of incidents are very low level.
Like
uh spam is a great example. How do we solve spam?
Well, we don't, we just statistically try and squish it down so that, you know,
you only get one or two spams.
A day.
-- I, I don't even get that anymore.
-- I still get one.
I, I, it's so weird to me that Google still lets through these.
Would you like to buy a list of blank,
you know, whatever
sap,
whatever technology
users. And it's,
of
course not
one of those in a while.
It's, I used to get them at least two or three a day and I haven't gotten one in a long,
I get about one or two a week and it's just, I don't understand because they're, yeah,
anyways back to the point is
the majority of quote, it's like every time some government or a company says, oh,
we get attacked a million times online every day.
Well, yeah, somebody port scans you and definitely somebody is running like,
you know, some,
like burp suite or,
you know, um,
whatever automated attack suite they are using. Yeah.
Oo, obviously they're doing that
against. Well, probably the whole internet basically.
Does that really count as an attack attack?
You know, it's like,
um,
oh,
apparently in this neighborhood of a few years ago
it was popular among the young kids to,
uh,
from a different neighborhood to come here on their BMX bikes and
try the door handles on cars and if it was unlocked,
you know,
swipe whatever they could from the car.
Now, that is crime,
you know, that's crime. But is that like an attack?
Is that like, no,
it's like people left their car doors open and people took stuff out of their cars.
You know, I, I
don't know what else to say
and, like a lot of quote unquote online attacks, you know,
I like the number of port scans and the number of just
web-based shenanigans.
You know, when I look at the log files, there's still people looking for front page,
you know, trying to exploit old front page instances
and, you know, technically do those count as attacks.
Well, it's, it's like so old and hokey that,
I mean, it's,
it's a tax against technology that I personally
haven't even used in about probably 1520 years.
You know,
this is an interesting point you bring up because in the context of automation,
you could compare this to every time you come to a red light
that you are taking corrective action by not blowing through it.
Be it a human or a, an A I?
And how many red lights have you sat out of humans where there's no people around,
it's like three in the afternoon, sunny day.
You have perfect visibility and there's not a single car you can see.
What do you do? You come up to that red light and you stop
and you wait.
Yes.
Right.
Right. Right.
You know,
because it's, it's illegal. Not exactly. And there's,
there's potentially negative consequences.
Well, and more to the point if people get in the habit of blowing through red lights,
they're gonna get lazy and they're going to start blowing through them when,
you know, they shouldn't be.
That is also very true.
Every time somebody says, you know,
they wanna set up a machine and actually monitor the firewall logs on it.
I'm like, no, you really don't
cause first of all, you're gonna have to sleep eight hours a day.
Ok. No, no, this is a great point though.
Somebody wants to monitor the firewall logs and we
know what those are going to look like.
They're going to be a train wreck.
But here's the thing is,
is this is where things like artificial intelligence and machine learning are,
this is what they were built for
is the fact that they can look at your
firewall logs and they can potentially find the,
the one bad thing
-- out of the 7 million benign things that are in those logs.
-- Right.
Well,
but the next problem this leads to and this
is actually related to that hack back thing is
what do you do? What's the actionable information?
Great. Somebody from China attacked me.
What do I do? Do I attack that? IP back? Well, it's probably some
poor little
camera that,
you know, doesn't have a, has a default user name and password online.
The poor little thing attacking everybody.
See, and that's, that's what honestly, I don't even,
there's so much stuff where I've intentionally stopped
paying attention to the logs because I,
I, even if somebody does do something bad.
II, I can't
do anything with it. It's,
well, I, I think it needs to be context aware.
So in the case of a firewall,
keeping the logs for forensic purposes is quite reasonable.
Right. And, and you can maybe look for certain things
and you could trigger
human response
if there's something that is quite obviously egregious.
But let's, let's, let's use your login server as a better example. Right.
If, if you have Bob from accounting, who only logs in
between the hours of 9 a.m. and 5 p.m. from Omaha Nebraska
and all of a sudden at 2 a.m. he's logging in from Russia, right? Something is wrong.
And ML would be really good at picking that up and then you could just say,
like kill his account, right?
Disable access right now
and then send an email to a human that says,
figure this out, right? This is not Bob
or if it is Bob, you should have told us he's going, you know,
my, uh, my partner has a problem every time we travel, her,
her bank is really aggressive about, you know, oh my God,
you're using your credit card literally outside of city limits.
Nope.
Yeah, like I had the, uh, I actually was
up at the cabin and my credit card wouldn't work in a small town,
but it would work in a big town.
It's like, you know, it's always so annoying, you know,
trying to buy a lot more but um
so it's actually really nice.
I found that the bank I use they send me text messages when I use my card
gets declined somewhere.
Ah yeah, they'll be like was this you text one for? Yes, two for no.
-- Yeah,
-- I've seen that
would love to have that
live in Canada.
It's, it's very nice.
It's always funny too
because you go somewhere.
They're like your card's been declined and I'd be like hang on, I take my phone out,
I texted back, I'm like, alright,
try it again and they look at me like I'm some sort of weirdo
I have magic powers or something. But
yeah, it's great.
So, but back to the, I think that's one of the biggest problems here is, you know,
when you tell a human being, hey, don't worry it's taken care of.
That's what human beings tend to do.
What
I don't understand
like a self driving car,
it's ok.
The car is doing the driving, just chill out, sit back, close your eyes, have a nap.
Uh You know that this guy in Britain just recently like last week got
banned from driving because apparently he was
on the motorway in his self-driving Tesla
and he was sitting in the passenger seat.
I,
I read that
that's hilarious
and yeah, so pretty sure there's that.
Well, I mean,
we're gonna need some really progressive motoring laws before that's legal.
I, I wonder sometimes how close we are to that.
And, and I guess so, here's the other half of it though.
And this is,
this is a problem we suffer from every day
is
humans suck at changing their minds and their attitudes.
And so, for example, a lot of people think, oh, self driving cars aren't safe.
It's always funny because every time someone says, oh, self driving cars,
you trust a computer to drive, I'm looking at him.
I'm like, do you trust me to drive?
They already do trust a computer to drive.
And, and I, I don't, I don't bring that up, but here's,
here's kind of the more important aspect of that is
a, like, especially in security.
There are certain things, people just won't, they don't want to change their minds.
Like passwords are my favorite example.
There are so many people who still think, you know, that,
that horrible password advice ned
handed out in the, in the two thousands is still valid
and it's like
I look here, Nist. Nist wrote down why their advice is terrible.
And there's people who look at that and be like, no, I don't believe them. And,
well,
especially the problem becomes when you have something where it's a statistical,
you need to,
you know, have a statistical model to really determine if it's good or bad.
And people of course, come up with anecdotal data
that disproves the whole model. Of course. Right.
And, and that's just something very human because,
you know, we're our threat model as Bruce Schneier
would say is, you know,
we're hardwired for the African Savannah rustling bushes in the distance.
Is that a lion or just the breeze?
You know,
and, and, but the beauty of it is
regardless of the answer to that,
you lose nothing by running away. Right.
Like if it is a line, you've run away. If it was nothing, you ran away,
potentially, there are long term consequences of, you know, you,
you spend a lot more energy running away
and you lose opportunities for other things.
But generally speaking,
statistically again, yeah, the, the, the,
the people with the genes that make them run away
a lot are probably gonna propagate more than the people.
Like, huh? I wonder what that is.
I should go investigate it or maybe apply a statistical model
to see how likely it is that that's a lion,
you know?
Yes. So
I think for me, what it,
yeah.
So I think what it boils down to really, for me is with, you know,
especially with self driving cars.
I hate to say this,
but I think in some ways we really need to wait for the completely self driving
capability
or, or where the car maker says, you know, at,
um, like highway driving, this will 100%
handle everything,
you know? You don't.
Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. And, and so I guess let's, let's think about that.
Now, now I think in the context of cars, you're right. But does
does that apply in other places as well?
If you have say
machine learning, looking at log
files, that's not a health and human safety issue, right?
But for example, what about a medical device
in what's the context,
for example, those pacemakers now that have sort of the adaptive
uh control and for example,
the pacemaker will see that you're straining and it will up your heart rate.
So you can like exercise,
like
old timey pacemakers literally were like a grandfather clock, like tick, tick,
tick tick, like they didn't have any intelligence.
You know, the newer ones can sense.
Oh, you're straining, I'm gonna up your heart rate.
So you don't like stroke out or, you know,
run out of blood oxygen.
Um And so there's been cases of uh where those things have gone a little haywire and,
you know, crank the guy, uh
uh heart rate way up,
you know, to the point of almost killing them.
And, and what's your point about that?
That's a case of, well, that's a system that has to be automated uh largely
and, you know, it, it is,
there's very much a health and human safety aspect of it.
And so it damn well better be 100%
or so close to 100% that we can barely tell,
you know, and that's the problem with these self driving cars right there.
There's that poor lady walking her bicycle across the
street that got run over by an Uber,
they, you know, self driving Uber,
you know, there's, there's all these cases where
I'm hoping we have like
an airline, you know, style safety investigation recommendations and a fix.
The problem being, these are like A I systems.
How, how do we even begin to prove that we've improved them,
you know, short of putting them back out on the road and seeing how they do.
I mean, I, I think that's true of everything and
I, I don't,
I don't think there is another way other than essentially real world testing,
right?
And this is true of any sort of automated
system,
the VR based testing of these self driving systems now
and, and for self driving,
OK, you might be able to get away with that.
I, I really don't know, I don't know enough about the technology
the,
because it's just data, right? How would the car know that that data isn't,
is a recording versus is live.
It, it, it wouldn't,
right.
But you also run into, I think some of the problems of,
if you keep feeding it the same things over and over again,
it's gonna be less effective than having it actually out doing real things.
And I guess like th
this is an example I would use, let's say you have, you know,
machine learning or A I monitoring your logs.
It, it would be trivial to have basically look at a human,
look at the A I see which is doing better.
Right? And, and so like that, in that, that case, you can kind of do it side by side.
And I guess even with self driving cars, you can do it side by side where you can say,
let's look at how the cars are doing, let's look at how the people are doing.
But the issue being, if the cars are doing worse,
you've now just like, unnecessarily killed a whole bunch of people, basically.
Right.
Uh,
well, I mean, weren't you looking into industrial disasters and safety and, and,
you know, essentially every single, like,
look at how many people were killed by horses, kicking them in the head or
being run over by
wagons or,
I mean,
just,
you know, how many people get maimed and mangled by farm machinery,
-- you know, like picking,
-- picking industry, like literally every one of them,
it doesn't matter.
And, yeah, I've, I've got a presentation
I put together some time ago. Right.
It basically looks at things like mine safety
and auto safety and industrial safety and every
company
in the US when they file their SCC paperwork has to put in a mine safety statement
or say we don't have any mines,
you know, when you file your, what is it, your
10-K or whatever with the sec?
Right? You know,
and like, because that's literally how bad mine safety was,
is it got so bad that they made all the companies report on it.
Like, that's gotta be pretty terrible.
It's, it's still bad.
In fact, even, even now there's, there's a lot of issues even though mining is,
is fairly regulated in the country.
But, but, I mean, this is where,
I don't know, this is one of the things I think about
is
generally speaking, nobody cares till it gets so bad. You can't ignore it.
But, but like, self driving cars are different,
right? I mean, I think you could argue it is so bad
that people can't ignore it because let's face it,
like thousands of people die a day in auto accidents
and, and even if self driving cars could drop that number in half,
that would be enormous.
-- Right. I have a feeling it's going to
-- be,
you know what I'm thinking is
also the number of people just hurt and mangled in car accidents.
You know how many people are in wheelchairs because of car accidents,
you know, like just the, the, the human suffering is, is, oh, it's astounding.
-- Right.
And
so I guess that's, oh,
man, this,
this makes the automation conversation tricky because
there is some automation
that if it, if it fails people die
and there is other automation that if it,
but I guess this is kind of true of security in general.
Right. And maybe this is one of the reasons security has never,
we, we've struggled to kind of bring the industry to the next level. Because,
I mean, historically speaking, if your company gets hacked,
nobody dies, right.
And that's becoming less true, I think in, in certain industries now. But
I mean, like practically speaking, your website got hacked. What happens?
Nothing. You know, you, you probably restore from backup.
Whereas with like cars in meds
now,
when, when things get hacked, people are literally going to die,
it's going to change some of the rules.
And so I wonder if that's going to make people care more,
but unfortunately they aren't going to care until a lot of people die.
Given historical precedent
of, you know, like rivers literally lighting on fire before people care.
Well, that, that's my favorite one because the people didn't care.
It was the rail company that cared because it was damaging their bridge.
Well, actually you, you, you say that a lot and, and there was that instance,
but there are many,
there are so many rivers that have lit on fire.
My tap water catches fire.
Well, that's still, that's true. That's in Virginia, right? A
couple of place anyway.
But here's the thing. So there have been
a disturbing number of rivers that lit on fire throughout history.
Right. Like you think one is when people should start caring. No, not one, like
more than 20. Right.
And those are the,
those are the incidents that were big enough to make it into the news.
You know,
there were probably hundreds of small rivers out in the
middle of nowhere that had been lit on fire.
But again, like humans suck at changing their minds.
It is, it is the human condition.
I think ultimately what's going to happen is self
driving cars will present especially for the trucking industry.
Uh An, an economically compelling enough case that it's gonna happen.
End of story
like industrialization, right? You had machines mangling people
left, right and center
and well, too bad productivity is way up. We can afford more orphans.
And that's just the brutal truth of it.
It, it, it was and then the, the in fact, the industrial safety on that scale
was, was particularly interesting because it was
in that particular case,
it was driven more so from kind of the unionization of employees than
it was from from government regulations where
then once the workers banded together,
they, they kind of cried to the government to, to change this stuff.
Whereas a lot of other things like environmental, for example,
has been very government driven.
And so it's, it's
more often than not. I think you end up with, uh
government starts to care for some reason or other with, with these things. And,
and I guess cars are also special because the government already cares about cars,
right?
So, I don't know, man, this one's different, it's very different
once
you get
essentially a car fleet, that's like a, let's assume,
uh you know, even 50 or 80% automated
things like I, that's gonna have a huge impact on things like crime,
right.
How do you, how do you get away if,
if you don't have access to a car that you can control?
-- You
-- just, you could probably make a ton of money with a getaway car service, right?
Like
no questions asked,
-- you
-- know,
but all the other cars are tracking you because they all have cameras. Now,
that's what the mask is for.
Right? So,
yeah.
No, I, I suspect that the, just from what I understand of the economics of cars,
the self driving aspect is just
personally, I want it,
but I only want it if it's 100% because I don't have to pay attention
completely.
II I don't like to drive and, and so the,
the concept of being able to just get in a car and not care, sounds amazing to me.
And it was funny too.
I, I was talking to somebody a couple of weeks ago about this and they basically said,
well, what if I just want to go for a drive?
And I said,
-- I don't, I don't
-- go
for,
-- if you just want to hook up your horse to the buggy and go for,
-- uh, or
take
your horse on the
-- state.
-- Well, no more of the point, people still do that but it's a hobby
and you go do it on private land.
Well, not only that man, you got to think, like,
if you want to drive and if you have a controlled enclosed environment to drive on,
you could drive really fast or, or
Kirby's drugs.
Right. Right.
Exactly.
Whereas today you have these idiots who think they're
racing on the road and they end up,
you know, crashing into people.
Yeah.
So, well, I think with that, I guess,
I guess the moral of the story is if, uh, is shoot for 100% automation because, yeah,
like you said,
people are slow and dumb.
Yeah. II, I think that's the key and this is, I think true of any sort of
automated environment.
Cars or airplanes or, well, airplanes are probably different but whatever.
But, but I, I think if you're, if you're deploying automation,
like
airplanes and trains have the exact same issues,
you got a human at the loop who may or may not be paying attention,
maybe
airplanes can't take off or land today, can they?
With automation?
They've been able to do that for years?
Ok. Never mind. Then. I don't know. Again, I don't know what I'm talking about.
Like, you obviously know this particular topic better than I do.
I basically know what I learned from.
-- You
-- know,
a thing called Auto Land.
It
-- sounds like a theme park.
-- Well, think about it.
You have like fog and zero visibility.
You either have a human doing an instrument based landing
or you have a computer doing the instrument based landing personally.
Me, I'm gonna go with the computer.
I, yeah, that's fair. I, I would agree with that.
I don't, I don't trust people, people out of the problem
anyway.
But, no, I, I think your,
your closing point is very true that if you're
going to deploy an automated system go all in because
anything else is going to be unacceptable,
I think.
And, you know, I guess
at the same time, let's, let's think about this for a second as well.
Imagine if you were, say, deploying
a fleet of tractors, do you think they did like half tractors,
half horses trying to work in tandem?
No.
Right.
Well, they
-- did as they, as they could afford tractors. Right. They would buy them.
-- And
my assumption is they do different jobs though. Right.
Where you wouldn't have like one tractor and one horse hooked up to one thing
that's dumb.
No, I suspect, I mean,
I think having the human assistive thing makes sense because you can make
those steps towards full automation and not have to make that giant leap.
You know, and you can actually bring something to market and sell it
and make money to fund your R and D.
But like you said, I think the goal should be not to be like, oh,
we're gonna build a car that's 80% automated.
No, you're, I think the goal needs to be 100%.
I, I agree. I, I think 100%. Automation should be the goal in any system.
And if that's not what you're shooting for,
you're probably just gonna make a bigger now.
Now you have two problems, right? Instead of one.
Well, yeah, you have to have humans figure out when it failed and then what to do.
Right.
Right. All right, man, I dig it.
So I guess. Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to open source security podcast.com.
Hit up the show notes, go to the pound or, or use a pound Os s podcast.
Hashtag to hit us up on social media.
If nothing else, Kurt have a fabulous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks.
Bye bye.