Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Siefried
and my partner in
-- Kvetching about stuff, Josh Pressers.
-- That's all we ever do. I mean,
anyone who listens to us is well aware that just complaining is our only skill.
-- Yeah.
-- Well, but complaining is a valuable skill in, in.
There's, I think there's two aspects to it is number one
complaining about the right thing
because a lot of people complain about the wrong thing,
right? They, they either
they complain about something and it's not the real problem.
There's like an underlying problem.
And number two complaining effectively,
I'm just gonna say no. If you have a complaint just be the change.
Well, I come back to see something, say something.
I mean,
maybe,
maybe
like Felix spotted a nail sticking out of the deck and he's like, dad,
there's a nail sticking out of the deck.
I'm like, awesome. And I pulled it and put a screw in.
That's when you teach him to get a hammer and
-- pound the nail down
-- the deck needs to be replaced.
It's the, you know, it's, it's, I think it's original to the house.
Like I've already replaced one third of the boards because, you know,
somebody sat in a chair and the chair went through the deck.
Epic. Right. And I'm just like, oh, yeah, that,
ok, I'm like, these boards are a bit more rotten than I thought.
So, I went around whacking them with a hammer, you know, and spray,
painting them orange and then
ripped out about a third of them. And then,
yeah,
so nobody falls to the deck anymore.
I mean, that seems like a feature of a deck you'd want to have.
Yes. Yeah. It's a good, it's a, it's a valuable feature.
Like, I think that's a valuable feature on most floors
don't fall off the floor right
through the floor
is falling through the floor the same as falling off the floor.
No, those are different
because generally when you fall off the floor, you're not gonna, like,
fall a story into, you know, whatever's under the deck,
-- which is probably leftover construction debris
-- anyway.
Anyway.
All right. What are we talking about today?
I'm always shocked at some of these big vendors
that have lots of money and still manage to,
you know,
instructions on clear house on fire. Right.
Like, they just managed to make such a hash of a problem that
shouldn't be that difficult.
And it's something, you know, in this case it's, it's bug bounties and bug, like
accepting bug reports
and then doing something with them
so that, well, we're going to, I thought we're going to focus on Apple.
But I mean, Microsoft recently had that where, you know,
a Microsoft VP went off on the guy who reported a bug
publicly went off on him and his linkedin and the guy's like,
look, you know, you were told about this bug five years ago.
-- There's like a US C certain number for it.
-- I have not seen that one.
It's, it's a credential exposure with Microsoft Exchange.
-- Ok.
-- Story of the creds leaking exchange. Auto Discover flaw.
The one Microsoft wouldn't fix even after five years.
So,
yeah, like last week the security firm called Guarico.
This, it's a,
there's an auto Discover protocol where you can basically
connect out to an exchange server and like,
give it your credentials and see if it has an email for you.
That sounds really safe.
I, I, yeah, I know. I'm like, what I'm like, don't you just
configure your, I don't know, whatever.
And apparently it, like, doesn't check the host certificates properly or,
and somebody pointed out even if it does check those certificates, you know,
like it is possible to get a certificate that's valid
easily. Like it's called getting a certificate
anyways.
Right. And so, you know, this guy goes off and it's like Microsoft, like
you were told,
I, I think what really gets me is ok. They were told about this issue five years ago.
They have never fixed it
and it's, it's been long enough that they've kind of forgotten about it.
So, when somebody kind of re reports it to them, they're like, oh, my God, this is new.
You know,
you have to, you have to behave in a certain way this, with this flaw.
And it's like, but it's been public for five years
and it's just
wait, is it, was, it, was it public? Public?
Yeah.
So it was public and then some research
company just wrote a report about a public flaw
and then someone from Microsoft got mad about that.
Basically. Yeah,
that's stupid.
-- So
-- here we go on August 10th, 2016,
Marco Van
Beek, managing director at UK based it consultancy supporting role,
emailed the Microsoft Security Response Center to disclose an auto
discover exploit that worked with
multiple email clients including Microsoft outlook
quote.
Basically,
I've discovered that it is extremely easy to
get access to exchange and therefore active directory,
user passwords in plain text unquote.
He said wrote quote,
it doesn't necessarily require any breach of corporate security.
I know it's most secure is only as secure
as file level access to the corporate website unquote.
His report received a case number from Microsoft and a reference number from us.
Cert,
so I don't know that it was public public,
but like us cert knew about it and gave it a number
-- but
-- still five years.
I mean, if you don't fix something in five years,
you clearly don't care about it it can go public.
Yeah.
Well, it either doesn't matter. It's like inconsequential or.
Well, I mean, if you, yeah, if you're not going to fix it after I would say five months,
let alone five years.
Yeah.
So Microsoft, some people at Microsoft, you know, had their tantrum and it's like,
yeah, I'm sorry, this isn't how this works.
No, I, I agree. I don't, this isn't a story even. This is like Microsoft.
Honestly, they're probably mad because they look dumb.
They're probably not mad because anything got disclosed.
I mean, the same thing is happening with Apple, right?
Like Apple's bug bounty people are reading between the lines.
It sounds like Apple. Bug bounty doesn't pay out a lot of money.
No. No, it doesn't.
I mean, Apple has historically been adversarial to security researchers.
This isn't new.
Even before they had a bug bounty.
It was very difficult to get them to take security reports seriously.
They've tried to,
or they've essentially tried to shut down that
company that makes the I OS emulator that,
you know, is really popular with security researchers.
-- Uh, they did, they, no, I don't think they did shut
-- them
down.
They tried to shut them down.
Tried very grossly.
The other thing is like Apple,
if there's a company that has no excuse for not paying high dollar bug bounties.
Apple now has 100 and 95.57 billion in cash on hand up 2% from last quarter.
Well, yeah, because they're not paying bug bounties with it.
I OK. So there's a couple of pieces to this,
all of this I think and including the new Microsoft story is there is
the concept of vulnerability disclosure
and this is when a researcher tells you about a thing
and then you have to do something with the thing.
Ok. Five years is unacceptable. Ok. So there's that
there's the angle of just the interactions between the researcher and the company
and then there's the bug bounty aspect, which is I would say the newest of the three,
but also hugely interesting.
And I guess there's kind of 1/4 which is the black market,
which is where a researcher can just be like screw apple.
I'm going to go sell this thing to zero DM or whoever
and make a crap ton of money.
Most security firms and researchers have actually become quite a
bit more professional over the last decade or two.
And
it's sort of like Apple and Microsoft
are, they're not consistent.
Maybe that's what it is is their lack of consistency because you think at this point,
like a company, the size of Apple or Microsoft would be applying six Sigma to their,
like when we worked at Red Hat, we handled how many thousands of bugs a year.
At that point, you have to industrialize, apply six Sigma best practices, you know,
and you, you reduce variance.
You, you try to improve the process because honestly,
if you squeak out a 1% improvement across a couple of 1000 bucks, that's a big deal.
I heard at one point and I don't remember where I heard this
but the micro, the security at microsoft.com account gets 500,000 males a year,
which I totally believe.
Think about that. How many people do you need to deal with 500,000 males in a year.
What is that per day? Let's check on the
14,
1300.
I don't know. Let's, let's, let's do the math.
500,000 divided by 365 equals 1369.8 emails per day
per day.
Yeah.
Also I'm a note that you're running, it's 1369.9
whatever 0.86
you're an engineer basically.
I don't care.
But uh yeah, I mean, and, and
well, and that's the thing that gets me is, yeah,
you're the size of Microsoft. That's a gnarly problem.
Too bad. Like you get to go deal with that.
Well, I mean, look when you become a, the larger your company becomes,
you obviously need certain infrastructure.
I mean,
you think about the toilet paper budget at Microsoft
probably exceeds the annual revenue of most companies.
-- You know,
-- even more to the point
most of the people Microsoft is dealing with.
It's let me put it this way when somebody
emails me claiming to be a security researcher.
It takes me about all of 10 seconds
to determine if they're like a legitimate security
researcher or not because they will have a
massive online footprint if they're truly legitimate.
And so that means then you have a lot of the potential for like diamonds in the rough.
Like a no coming in with something new.
-- And
-- I want, I have one complaint.
I want to interrupt you and interject here is I deal with
secure the security address at work
and there's nothing more annoying to me when they mail like legal at, with a,
I'm a security researcher and it's like,
maybe you could have freaking researched the security at email address.
Dude. I literally drive me crazy.
Yeah,
I generally speaking when somebody sends a
security report to not our security address,
like we have security at cloud security lines.org for security reports,
I, I cannot make it simpler than that.
Well, except I can,
we also have a security dot TXT that
says to email security at cloud security alliance.org
again.
I don't know how much simpler I can make it
except I think it's also on a web page somewhere.
But
yeah, like when a security researcher can't,
like when they email support with something, I'm just like
the chances of this being like something legitimate are so close to zero
and
so far it's, yeah,
so of that 500,000 emails, you know,
a couple 100 or 1000 of them are going to be from
people they know already who are on their top 20 bug bounty.
So you listen to those people, you know,
somebody like Tavio emails you and you Google Tavio
plus, you know, vulnerability. It's kind of like, oh,
we should probably brew a new pot of coffee
if you're accepting vulnerability reports and you don't know
who most of the Google project zero people are.
Like,
you should probably figure that out.
I'm actually kind of shocked only, oh, you know what I was gonna say,
there's only 16,000 results for him in vulnerability.
But the second one is his Wikipedia page.
So that's the thing.
If you're dealing with the security
vulnerability researcher who has a Wikipedia page
make two.
This is the thing, right? This is not hard to do for a large company.
Well, I, I think that's,
I, I think it is hard to do.
I think it's hard to do well and I think just because you're
a large company doesn't necessarily mean you should be good at it.
I think
this is very much a cultural thing.
And I think if you look at the, like if you look at the culture of Microsoft,
I think their security
gravitas has improved greatly.
But I mean, they still have a ways to go and everyone does for sure.
And, but I do think that when they deal with, with vulnerability researchers,
they do better than most
is my experience now we look at Apple. Apple has a long history of not
working well with anybody.
So I don't think it's clearly a cultural matter, right.
Where they don't want to pay researchers, they don't want to talk to researchers,
they don't want to do any of this stuff.
And historically, that was it. Right. You tell Apple something. Apple's like.
We don't care.
Now what? Right.
But now with the zero day market, I think this has been turned on its head and I,
I think Apple needs to do some serious soul searching in this space.
Well,
it's interesting because I was doing some worldly mapping around
the whole vulnerability thing and it boils down to.
There are two
user cases
for vulnerabilities. There are the people that want to fix it.
So they're like operationally responsible for a system that is vulnerable,
they want to fix it.
So it's not vulnerable and life goes on.
Right?
And then the second group
is the people who want to exploit those
vulnerabilities for typically bad reasons like ransomware.
That's, well,
there's actually an enormous amount
of state sponsored vulnerability purchasing.
-- Yes,
-- I would count them as the bad guys.
There's a book actually, I we should, we should read, I'm reading it now.
You should read it and we should talk about it someday.
But it's called, this is how they Tell me the World Ends by Nicole Plot.
I'll put a link in the show notes,
but like anyone interested in this topic needs to read this book.
It is frightening
for all the wrong reasons.
Basically,
it boils down to the people who want to fix it and the people who want to exploit it,
you know, and all the scanning and,
and all the pen testing companies are effectively in
support of the people who want to fix it.
Right.
The problem is, does that? Yeah, up until recently, there was
no path, no easy path to monetization
for vulnerabilities. Not really no.
-- And
-- now there is,
I mean, well, there's two, there's bug bounties
and they're selling the exploits
and the exploit market is probably 10 to 100 times the payout of a bug bounty,
plus they're probably less hassle to deal with.
Uh
It would not shock me if they are. I mean,
there is, I would say the bar is similar
for the burden of proof for each of them because I know, I mean, I, I work with
a
bug bunny like we have one at work. I talked to hacker one on a regular basis.
And there is definitely an expectation that when you are the hacker reporting a bug,
if you, for example, provide a weaponized exploit for the bug,
you're probably going to make a lot more money than if you say, hey, oh,
I found this bug in your stuff and you don't have a good reproducer, right?
The odds are high,
you're never going to see a dime from
that same thing obviously in an exploit market where
if you go to an exploit broker and you're like, oh, I found a buffer overflow.
They're gonna be like whatever nerd.
But if you're like, OK, I have like a functional exploit that gets me shell,
they're gonna be like, please come inside.
Let's talk.
Yeah.
Well, you know, it's the difference between saying, hey Edmonton,
there's a pothole in the road and hey Edmonton,
there's a very specific bad pothole causing problems at this exact location.
-- If a truck can fall in it, you know, there's a problem.
-- Exactly.
So,
and, well, the other thing I find really interesting is that
bug bounties will only exist if that company decides to pay for it,
right?
The odds of some other
entity funding a bug bounty for good.
It kind of happens, but it's more at the level of like, um,
eyesight or eye defense where they basically would pay a
bug bounty for vulnerabilities then go to the vendor.
But they would leverage that vulnerability as part of their, you know,
the service of reporting vulnerabilities to their clients.
Or uh there was that HP thing where they, they built a network product that, you know,
was a intrusion prevention
system. IP S
that they would buy zero days, create a signature to block it and then tell the vendor
and, you know, their whole thing was like, essentially, it kind of struck me as like
Hey, you know,
that's an awful nice window you've got there and
somebody over here found a pile of bricks.
Yeah, it'd be a real shame.
So,
so there is another, actually, there's another piece of this
that I didn't mention at the beginning is there's also the angle of like,
what do we do about open source?
And actually hacker one just announced the,
it's internet bug money two or something they called it.
I'll try to dig up a link to it,
but basically they're, they're funding.
Well, there's a bunch of companies that are dumping money into a bucket
and then they're using that bucket to fund
hackers finding flaws in critical open source packages,
which is really cool
the
whole eu
thing all over again. Right? Like, like we pointed out is
it doesn't matter how much these companies want to help. They can't
really, other than here's a like, oh,
we can write a check to this organization that'll then
eventually filter it down to bug reports that get fixed.
Ok.
That's better than nothing.
I mean, it, it's something this is,
I think this is going to be one of the challenges we see in open source is
there's so much
effort that's needed.
I think in a lot of these spaces and it's really hard to work with some of these people.
And I mean, I don't know what the answer is.
I'm not going to even speculate at this point,
but I I do think this is one of the next challenges we, we have to solve.
Well, we have to,
that's one thing I'm grateful for Red Hat.
But they taught me about sustainability and open source. Right.
That's a big mantra at Red Hat.
Yeah. Right. Don't strip mine it like
you got to cooper.
And so I think in general open source as such as generally sustainable and it's ok,
like it's, it's been pretty healthy for the last 20 years.
I think we're ok.
I do worry a bit about some of the cloud companies strip mining it, but whatever.
But,
but security is a little bit different and a little bit
harder because there's a whole bunch of different incentives and problems.
And I was saying,
well, to me it's a, it's a slightly more complicated subset of open source, right,
with its own
new set of problems
and,
yeah, I'm not, I'm not sure. I don't think there is one answer per se.
I think it will take probably dozens of different efforts.
And I, you know, note, I'm not saying education because, yeah,
because we'll just train our way out of this problem.
-- That'll work.
-- It's always worked before. Yeah,
exactly.
The last 50 years it's been awesome.
-- But no, I, I think part of it is, you know, things like bug bounties using rust
-- anyway.
All right. I, I think, I think we've gone off into the weeds in a direction.
I don't like I want to go back to
interacting with researchers from a like
vulnerability disclosure perspective because I've seen
every possible reaction to researchers. You can imagine
everything from companies being hostile to them, from companies welcoming them.
In one of my favorite is when you report something they're like, oh, this is great.
Thank you so much for the report and then you never hear from them again. And like
there's, there's so many pieces to this and, and this is one that's,
it is a difficult problem.
And in fact, we were just talking the other,
the Linux foundation just published like a vulnerability disclosure handbook,
which
is, it's ok. Like it's got a lot of weird stuff in it, but,
-- well,
-- it's like 20 years late.
Yeah, it is.
I mean, I think they,
they wrote a vulnerability disclosure handbook
for vulnerability disclosure in 2005.
But that's kind of another problem. But
like,
and this is one of the challenges I think is
the world changes so fast and so much and it,
it is difficult to keep track.
-- The
-- world is so inconsistent, especially in the open source world. Like
there's everything from the Apache foundation to a guy doing the
time zone file who got sued by that Crazy Astronomy Company.
-- Oh,
-- there's a new complaint I read about the time. This is really funny.
So apparently
I'll try to find the I this, I forget where I even found this.
It was on Reddit or something. But
so the time zone guy has a bunch of people mad at
him because I think it's the Belgian time zone before the A PC
in 1970 obviously, the names of time zones and time and everything is kind of a mess.
And apparently they decided
like the Belgian, no, Austria, Austria.
Um, um,
yeah, I think it's the Austrian time zone.
The time zone people decided was just Germany before 1970.
And now a bunch of people in Austria are really mad at them and
it's like,
it's apparently breaking certain things because of the way
it's returning the time zone name and it's just,
it's, I,
I laughed out loud when I read it because it,
I'm sure it's really important to these people.
-- But, well,
-- in fairness there, there is a bit of history there around, you know,
the
naming of parts of.
Yeah.
Yeah. Anyway, anyway, I'll, I'll try to dig it up and I'll put it in the show notes.
But, but anyway, so you are
now, I want to say the concept in the open source world,
especially of there being like companies dealing with an individual people,
you're dealing with or not companies, but like foundations and individual people
is nothing new.
In fact,
I think there are more individual people today than there have ever
been because if you look at like the node package manager ecosystem,
it has millions of packages that there are probably
hundreds of thousands of people who own node packages.
That's
amazing
-- and terrifying.
-- Well, I mean, part of it is
honestly, some of these software packages don't really need more than one person.
Some of them are pretty simple.
Like I remember looking at one,
it was called American Date and it took a perfectly normal fine
time stamp and mangled it into month, day, year.
-- And I stand by my words, which is the
-- worst format. I'm not.
Although I will say I also hate day, month, year, year, month, day is the only format.
-- Anything else is wrong.
-- That's how I'm bringing up my Children.
And it's funny because
that's
right sometimes. Yeah, I anyways,
that's right there. It's the only date format like at me on Twitter, I'll,
I
care about this enough. Like I will, I will ride this ship down.
But
I just
anyway, but no, you, you're absolutely right. I think
the,
a lot of things, it's ok. It's one person,
but at the same time now we have the challenge of if I'm a person working in my free time
and I get a security vulnerability report and I know
you're going now tell the story about what the XML D
thing with Red Hat and a guy worked on the weekend. But like
this is a legitimate issue of, if I'm busy,
I'm not gonna fix it right now.
But here's the other frustrating part is a lot of these security vulnerabilities.
I can literally count on one hand, the number of security vulnerabilities that
essentially an initial look at it. Oh OK. So the solution is X,
right? The vast majority of security vulnerabilities I've ever seen
have a very
generally simple solution.
And the, the examples,
the essentially the only two counter examples I
can really think of are bash shell shock
where that thing turned out to be a bit more complicated than we thought.
And the Linux stack guard stuff, right where, you know,
Wallace did amazing work and was like, I think we can, you know, one
megabyte uh guard pages and everybody was kind of like, yeah,
that sounds about right.
And then of course, Florian was like,
oh look at what I found and we're all like, damn it,
you know, OK. And it took, you know,
a lot of engineering effort to fix.
And I guess then the other example I can think of would be, you know,
some of the CPU based stuff like meltdown and stuff where,
and that was more and that was more a case of fixing. The problem is easy
fixing the problem. So you don't cripple the CPU with a 20% performance hit.
-- Oh,
-- that's tricky.
But basically
that's literally 20 or 30 vulnerabilities over the last two decades.
There aren't a lot. I agree. I think many of them are easy.
And so what I'm getting at though is for the majority of vulnerability
reports in general.
If a security researcher is competent enough to understand
a code base to find a vulnerability in it,
I would say probably nine times out of 10,
they should be competent enough to come up with a reasonable patch for it.
I mean, some of them do. Some of them don't though. I mean, I, I,
one of my pet peeves,
I remember when there would be researchers who would
mail the old vendor sech mailing list with a,
here's like 1000 font files.
I does that crash? True type
fix them? Like what? No, like this is ridiculous. And of course it was two bugs.
But, well, my favorite was when they,
they wanted me to triage and CV them and fix them and I'm like, no, come back and,
and the person would come back three days later with like,
oh, it's
one bug and it's a doss, it's not exploitable. And I'm like, thank you for playing.
-- Now.
-- Now I'm gonna, I also want to add
that if you're a security researcher
and you find a bug, like you don't owe anyone a patch.
I mean,
that's part of the challenge is like, yes,
it is extremely polite and helpful if you show up with a patch or,
or work with the project to get it fixed.
Now, I will say this is true for open source. If you go to Apple with a bug,
you can't give them a patch.
Uh You could give him a binary patch in theory.
-- But yeah, realistically, but
-- you can't know no one's going to use that.
That is not realistic.
But the point is as well.
When you see a company like Apple that has huge buckets of money,
I think the expectation is very different and I think it should be different.
And I think the story about the way Apple handled these bugs
like
this is
it is
it is negligence on the part of a company like Apple.
I think, I think the, the expectation from them should be higher and I think
they're not living up to it.
It kind of reminds me of, uh, remember all the tire recalls about, oh jeez,
this is over a decade ago and then that's why they started sticking RF ID
tags and tires because I remember specifically watching
the CBS evening news with Dan rather,
although I think it was Connie Chung at that point.
But anyways, they did that investigative report, they put like, what was it?
Like,
two out of the four tires were supposed to be
recalled and they took it to like six different tire shops
and, you know, they got answers from, they're all
bad to none are bad to like the two that are good
or bad and the two that are bad or good and like,
just
like this, this is stuff that can kill people,
you know.
Well, and it was killing people
and I I view software. You know, we're getting to a point.
Well,
my favorite story right now is that whole Tesla thing where Tesla is rolling
out the self driving feature to quote unquote drivers with a high safety score,
whatever that means,
so that they can start using this beta
feature of like self driving and crowd environments.
And it's kind of like, I've noticed that the whole, what is it,
the Batter Meinhof effect where you think of
something and you start noticing it all the time
and I've started noticing that there's actually quite a few Tesla cars in Edmonton,
-- there's just a lot of them everywhere
-- and I'm not really sure,
I'm comfortable being on the road with something that's beta testing,
self driving software.
So here's,
here's what I keep putting in my brain is
I think that is the normal expected reaction but
is
a Tesla beta car
safer than a human driver because human drivers are hilariously bad.
And that is the question I would like to know the answer to.
Well, and unfortunately, that data though, unless it's spectacularly awesome,
Tesla won't release it.
I, I don't think
anyone would ever release that particular data because I feel like
it is going to be full of dragons and monsters.
Well, I mean,
Google had that incident of why are our self driving cars getting rear ended so much?
And the answer is because you're actually reporting every crash,
whereas
there's a lot of rear ends where people don't report it because, like,
I literally got rear ended twice by a pregnant woman in space of 30 seconds.
Like, she kind of bumped me. I was stopped and she kind of just lurched into me
and then, like, lurched into me again
and, like,
basically left a dust imprint on the back of my car. I,
I own a very old pickup truck that is in terrible shape and I've been bumped into many,
many times.
I'm like, I don't even care like whatever.
But when I think about it, I know for sure there's two or three rear end collisions,
I could have reported that I
just never bothered to.
I suspect that it's, well,
my favorite is Canada's worst driver where they
had this one person who essentially had been in
something like 40 or 50 accidents and thought that
that was normal and then they're asking everybody,
you know, is this normal?
And they're like, no, I've only been in one accident or zero accidents
and this poor lady was working three jobs trying
to pay off all these debts from these collisions
and, but it was just insane like it was just
anyway, anyway, vulnerability disclosure.
Well, and that's the thing like vulnerability disclosure, these companies now,
I,
so we know how many vulnerabilities are sort of publicly reported,
how many vulnerabilities were privately reported and sat on or ignored
and how many vulnerabilities were found, but just sort of uh whatever.
-- I don't
-- care or how many have been reported
in private to a intelligent agency or something.
I mean, look at like the NSO group,
they were talking about this, how all of these groups,
like the NSO group try to maintain a 2 to 3 deep vulnerability pipeline,
I'm sure because,
yeah, they don't want to, you know, oh, our vulnerability got fixed. Ok.
Our product doesn't work for three months while we find a new vulnerability.
Exactly
what drives me nuts is, oh, this was on Twitter. But somebody basically said that
Safari on iphones had more zero days than say Firefox. How do we know that?
Because there's more zero days publicly reported.
And it's like, yeah,
because nobody's looking for zero days in Firefox as much because like, it's not
available on the iphone.
Like there's, there's no market for it.
-- I,
-- I think it is dangerous to claim one application is more secure than another.
I don't think there, there. That's true at all.
Especially based on highly biased public data.
Right. Right.
The thing is,
guess how many
CV ES there are for Firefox.
-- It's over 2000.
-- I, I believe that. I mean, I remember
so a long time ago
I worked with them on their releases because for whatever reason,
when I was at redhead, I got suckered into doing all the Firefox security updates.
And
I remember I assigned all their CV ES for a long
time and it would usually be 5 to 10 per release.
And that was,
I mean, one a month basically, I think back then
like
it's,
that's a lot.
That's a lot, man.
And so if a, if a, if a code base is large,
it has vulnerabilities and if a code base
is large and has 2000 plus known vulnerabilities,
there's more,
I mean, well, yeah, it's,
and look at parsing HTML is potentially one of
the most complicated things humans have ever done.
I mean, it's madness.
Yeah.
So it just drives me nuts when people look at these data sets and,
and extract meaning from.
No, no, there's half the data set isn't even there
or
to, to pretend that there's no or
to pretend somehow that there's not going to be as many zero days in something.
And yet there's 2000 plus security flaws in it
that we know of that have been fixed guaranteed.
Actually, I had a really funny conversation a couple of months ago where we were,
we were looking at two different open source libraries
and one of them had like 10 CV ES and one of them had zero
and the developer was like, oh, the one that is zero must be better. I'm like, no,
the one that is zero is significantly worse.
-- Nothing has zero security issues.
-- Nothing.
I was going to say they don't have a maturity, a mature security process.
No, it means they probably don't even have
a
process. That's right.
And no one's looking.
So it, yeah.
Right. Exactly.
-- Or
-- they just,
like,
I've run into a lot of major projects where they actually have
really good security change histories and zero CV S and they're just,
-- they lack that maturity
-- and that's a different problem.
But, yeah, that happens all the time. Absolutely.
I mean, look, one of my favorite examples I give people is if you go on github
and you put in, in the double quotes,
like search as a whole word or whatever prototype space pollution,
there are 3.9 million issues.
That is a ridiculous number.
And now granted, I'm not saying there's 3.9 million security issues, but I bet it's,
we'll say
a million
maybe.
-- You know what I mean? It's a lot.
-- Well, part of it is just the amount of code and github.
You know, it's, it's like every time they swab, what is it?
They swab buses or public transit for pathogens. And it's like
they find everything.
Well, yeah, when you, when you run a couple of 100 people through a bus,
yeah, I'm sorry. But some of them didn't wash their hands after using the bathroom.
That's right. That's why you wash your hands when you get off. Really. Anything
like anything at all, wash your hands
and I'm gonna have to go wash my hands after this.
But anyway, anyway. All right. All right, we're coming to the end.
I feel like
the bar. OK? So number one,
when you are a company,
you are going to receive security vulnerabilities from people. Researchers
have a way to receive them
that have a way to receive them. Be nice to them.
And, and I think one of the most important things,
a lot of people don't always grasp it is OK to say we aren't going to fix this,
you can publish your data.
The problem is most companies want to say we're not going to fix this now,
please never talk about this again.
-- And
-- that's not ok.
I don't agree with that at all. I think it is ok to say we're not going to fix it.
They can publish your data and if not fixing it is the right decision,
you should be able to add a quote to the data or just reply wherever that says,
this is why we made it this decision.
And if you made the right decision, no one is going to complain.
If you made the wrong decision, they might and then you can be like, all right,
maybe we screwed this up.
Let's let's think about it.
Well, and in line with this, I would say companies,
the security dot TXT standard is actually apparently now an
RFC draft like it's going to become an actual standard,
I would say at this point,
go do it.
Yeah, I mean, right, there's no reason not to or at least in github,
you can put your security dot MD, you know, same deal.
Well, to me, having,
if you don't have the maturity to put a simple text file
on your website that says here's how to report a security.
That's true.
Come on.
And I guess that not everybody can have security
at their domain name because apparently Microsoft has that since
the eighties for their campus security.
And so that's why they have that.
Yeah, that's apparently because everybody, well,
it's like the same thing with Red Hat.
It's sec
alert at Red hat.com, not security at Red hat.com.
And no, I actually don't even know why.
Actually, they both go to the same place, but Redhead always pushed se
alert instead of security at
probably because of Microsoft or something. I don't know.
Exactly. So, ok,
but you should be able to put a text file on your website
and more to the point if you can't get, buy in to do that,
then you don't have buy and to have a security program.
-- Uh,
-- yeah. Right. That's very true actually.
And, and that means without executive support, like you got nothing.
So there's the aspect of your company. Now, when you are a researcher,
there is
a certain amount, I think if you are working with the bug bounty, you, obviously the,
the transaction is a little different.
If you're reporting something essentially for free,
you can make some demands and you can have some expectations and I
don't think there's anything wrong with saying it's been 90 days like this.
I, I, I'm going public with this right
now. If you're getting paid by them as a bug bounty, they will use the money
as the stick of we paid you,
you will do what we say and there's a degree of truth in that I think.
And so that's a little different.
But if you're just reporting something and they wait 90 days and you're like,
I don't like this, I'm going public.
I don't think there's anything wrong with that.
Um,
well, two comments. One, I think it's like any negotiation.
It kind of depends on the size and power of the two entities, you know,
single researcher versus Apple versus like large
security company versus single open source person.
Right? Those are two very different equations.
And number two,
the vast majority of bugs aren't gonna matter that much and publishing them
publicly is not going to result in the power grid being shut down.
Let's hope
not.
Right.
The vast majority of bugs
can and should be public and not have, you know,
play secret security squirrel embargo games.
Yeah. No, I agree. I agree. I, I think,
I think if you are a properly functioning project or company,
you should be able to fix the fast enough that it doesn't matter if it's,
if it's essentially zero date,
you know.
Well,
and ideally you're architecting your stuff so that you don't have
world ending bugs popping up in it all the time,
right?
Like the whole
iMessage thing with apple where it's like, oh, oops.
Well, it's like, you know, Microsoft with their,
why is their font processing in the kernel?
Well, it's not anymore but, well, exactly.
But I mean if, if you do stuff like that then,
-- well, again you have deeper problems than just bug reports but
-- look how fast it is,
you know.
Anyway. Anyway. yeah, I agree. I think we're all on the same page here.
Alright, man, I'll let you get the last word on this one.
Um Try to be kind to each other,
you know, the whole iterated prisoners.
Dilema start with kindness and yeah, if they're a jerk,
then you can be a jerk but start by try being nice to start.
Agreed. Agreed. I like it. All right.
I'm calling it.
Thank you everyone for listening. Thank you, Kurt. Go to
open
source security podcast.com. Hit the shout out Susie Pound
says podcast hashtag hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You
-- too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye
the