So, Josh, I found 1000 security flaws in your product.
What day is it? I have no idea.
-- That's the day after yesterday.
-- It's, it's December 23rd.
We have to tell people because maybe people don't know.
-- Or you could be like, oh, it's door 20 three.
-- Wouldn't the episodes be labeled?
-- It's
-- labeled whatever. We don't know. We don't know.
Maybe future historians have found this and they're like,
we have no idea what's going on.
Oh, a different.
-- That's fair.
-- Right. Maybe aliens have, like, conquered humanity finally.
You know,
-- we were their example at
-- this point. I don't think it can get any worse.
I welcome my alien overloads anyway. Anyway. All right. What's the topic?
So, the topic is how to report, let's say, for the sake of argument.
1000 security flaws.
Good luck.
Yeah. I mean,
the reality is
number one, you would, obviously this would be generated by an automated system
probably because
each security flaw is going to take at least a few minutes by a human being.
And so that's weeks of work.
-- All right,
-- you can't look, I'm gonna,
I'm gonna say I've, I've talked to more than one person about this top,
like on more than one occasion.
-- And I will tell you now that if you're reporting 1000
-- do most projects will shoot
you in the face if you file 1000 bugs like or just create 1000 bucks,
regardless of what they are.
The point is when you find something this bad, you have to take
a, a heartbleed style disclosure policy where you just
say this is what I found and then
the community can get involved,
individual projects can get involved because the reality is if
you go to a special open source project and say,
oh here's a bug, it's going, it's not going to be taken.
Well by most projects, you actually need to show up with a patch in many instances.
And so just like crapping stuff into their
bug tracker and running away is not appreciated
and you're going to end up the bad guy even if you had good intentions.
Yeah,
I would say probably the best thing to do is
to make available the automated system that found these bugs,
which for example, Google did with their fuzzing,
right? Because fuzzing is infamous for this. I found a gazillion crash cases.
And more to the point, I'm not sure if it's one function or 100 functions ultimately,
you know, until we collapse it.
I remember this with the biggest example I remember is
the free type font processing libraries in open source.
Would they were notorious for,
like a fuzz would find it looked like hundreds of bugs and then, oh, no, just one.
Yeah.
And I agree. I think, think it is irresponsible to
say, have a fuzz or some other automated system
-- and claim you found something but then not show anyone what you did like
-- that is,
well, not allow them to reproduce it.
-- Yeah.
-- Exactly. That's, it's ridiculous.
And this is fundamentally, this is, I mean,
there's a reason the scientific method talks about reproducibility a lot.
Yeah.
Right.
We also need this in security because not only do I need to reproduce
it so I can then figure out what happened and try and fix it.
But I kind of also to know that I actually fixed
-- it.
-- That's, yeah, that's a very good
remember, I was going to say specific,
well say shelf but there's actually dozens where, oh, we fixed it.
No, you didn't.
You fixed a specific avenue of it or vendors that, you know,
fix a web bug by putting a single filter expression.
Right. That one field. Oh, wait, all the other fields are also vulnerable.
We'll just,
we'll keep whacking those moles because shell shock
ended up being four or was it six CV
S? Because we played the whack a mole? It was a nightmare.
-- It was a
-- lot
and it was very painful and unnecessarily painful.
-- But
-- now at the same time, this is a great example of a researcher basically
dumped the information to the world and the world came together and
worked on it instead of saying I'm just going to file a bug
-- in every application in every distribution and everything
-- to be fair. Yeah,
the shell shock problem wasn't with the bug reporter.
-- It was with the proposal solutions.
-- Yeah, it was upstream s fault. I blame upstream.
So that actually this is a bad example but also a good example.
It's a reasonable example.
I think, I mean,
there have been instances where now this is just one of
those problems that I don't think it happens very often.
It's a Black Swan event and there's no way to do it.
It's the problem of the law of large numbers
and the problem with the law of large numbers is every problem with
the law of large numbers becomes a logistics and strategy and policy problem.
It's no longer dinner.
It's how do we keep everybody from starving when you have to feed 10 million people?
-- Yeah,
-- it's, it's a very different problem for sure. And again, I think this is where
one person cannot solve this, but
the human race can.
And if you don't tell people all of the gory details,
they can't work together to solve this problem.
-- I
-- agree.
That seems very,
very hippy dippy, doesn't it?
Well, the reality is statistically speaking,
two people will beat one person every single time.
And generally speaking, if you especially want some sort of 24 7 capability.
You can't do that with one person. You need teams
and, and most importantly is if you
create a community around your, your security issue
and you bring everyone together,
you are the hero.
If you show up, poke them with a stick and run away,
you're the villain.
Yeah.
And I think that's the difficulty is I think a lot of people think, oh,
I'm going to report all these bugs
and they don't realize that you're actually the bad guy in this story.
How often do people show up thinking? I did one thing. I will be lauded as a victor.
No, it's, there's a lot more to it.
Yeah. Exactly. Exactly. That, all right.
See you tomorrow.
Thanks everybody.