Hello and welcome to the open
source security podcast with myself, Kurt
Seri and my partner are not making
exceedingly poor logistical supply chain decisions.
Josh Bresser.
-- I
-- mean,
I don't think I can back that up.
Well, so this, this morning,
I was actually looking at stuff in my bathroom because I was curious like,
where does all this stuff come from?
And
almost everything in my bathroom doesn't say where it's from,
but it does say imported by and then a large US firm, right?
And so for example, if we have sanctions, I'm not going to be able to wash myself.
I mean,
it's possible, I don't know,
I don't know where a lot of that stuff comes from.
Like even my hand lotion says made with Canadian oats but imported by, you know,
Johnson and Johnson us.
It would not shock me if Canadian oats are sent to the United States
and then sent back to Canada.
Yeah, it's,
I mean, look,
we live in a very global economy now where I
think cutting anything off from anywhere just causes utter chaos.
Yeah, pretty much. But also what gets me is sometimes decisions are made
that trickle out and it's like, how, how did that decision ever possibly get made?
So my, my current favorite massive fail is Microsoft straight up,
experimented with putting ads
in the file browser.
Yeah, that's great. Like I can't even fathom.
Like if you literally gave me a choice between,
we're going to put this puppy in a tree chipper
and we're gonna put ads in the browser or in the file explorer.
I'd be like, can we do the puppy? I think people will hate that less.
I mean,
-- like straight
-- up,
-- right.
-- So I, I uh let's give some context here.
I, I read this story and
apparently what's happening
is
a
in a preview build of Windows.
A we'll call it feature. I'm using air quotes here.
A feature accidentally leaked out to the public where there was an
ad in the file explorer and someone put it on Twitter.
And Microsoft is saying, oh, this was a mistake.
We didn't mean to do this where this is just an internal test.
They built the software that does it
and they
did,
but they didn't mean for us to find out about it.
Oh, wow. Oh, well, that makes it OK then.
Right?
And
I read this story and I'm like, I just stopped hating you. Microsoft like come on,
I,
-- I don't even know what to say.
-- See that's the thing, right? Microsoft didn't deny it.
They didn't say this is a shaft image.
They were like, no, that, that wasn't supposed to get made public. Right.
Right. You know, that's, that's literally what every
murderer and fraud person and, you know, criminal ever says.
It's like, oh, I didn't mean for you to find out
that,
like you caught me.
I mean,
especially in light of all that QR code, don't click. QR codes.
They're dangerous somehow.
It's like, ok,
so we've all established that drive by ads and ads are one
of the most dangerous things for web browsers on the internet.
Like that's how you do mass attacks.
And now we're going to put ads in a highly trusted user interface.
And when I say highly trusted user interface, I mean, as a user,
when I am looking at my file explorer
that is like
I, I trusted implicitly because it's my,
it's my file explorer for like since I've been using the computer,
it's basically been like what's on my desk?
Oh, that's what's on my desk. Cool.
Or on the network file share.
And it doesn't screw with me and make, it doesn't try and deceive me. And now it does
-- a
-- file explorer is one of those
just low levels of functionality
that you don't think about because it comes with the operating system.
You know what I mean?
It's not like when I run a game or something else I downloaded where I'm like,
I don't know about this.
I'm gonna check it out a little bit, but like
if it's packaged with Windows, I feel like I should be able to completely trust it.
Yeah, I do remember in fact having to install like MC or, you know,
command line file managers to be a little bit more friendly
-- than just a command line with, you know, CD and L si
-- mean, that was M sds, man.
Like
those were different days. There was no internet back then.
So I,
I just don't even know what to say to this one.
I feel like as a security person,
this is obviously ridiculous from the perspective of
you don't want something like your file manager loading
arbitrary resources from
some remote location
as a human.
I am appalled just because I am sick of
the ad fueled dystopian nightmare we all live in now
and the thing that irks me the absolute most is if you look at all of the ad economies,
you look at youtube is my favorite example.
You remember when youtube would show like one ad
youtube shows an obscene number of ads right now
and the revenue isn't going up to the moon.
-- So that tells you the value of ads is decreasing,
-- but that's always the case, right?
Same thing with cable TV. Oh, well, you'll pay for cable TV and it'll be ad free.
-- No, that that's actually what we were promised like 40 years ago.
-- Was it?
I don't even remember.
Yeah, literally the whole point was you pay for this TV. So there's no ads.
I like what Germany does. Germany has ads on TV.
But they're at the, there, there's like a block of them at the end of the show.
So you have time to go to the bathroom and get a coffee and stuff.
-- I
-- mean, that's kind of how, like public television and the BBC work.
I don't know what the CBC.
No, it's ads all the time. Just like America
and there's no limits on them now.
We changed that
-- good.
-- Good. That's,
yeah. So,
yeah, I just, uh,
I,
the fact that this got through committee and it got
implemented like this isn't some hypothetical like mock up.
This is
like, literally code that shipped.
I was supposed to only ship internally. Whoops.
So I just,
I uh like the number of attacks I can think of like where you put something in there
that the user is going to click because they think it's part of the U I because like,
well, it's not, you know, I, I can't even begin.
-- Yeah.
-- Yeah. Anyway, I, I think this story tells itself
and I imagine corporate people are going to love this even more than home users.
-- Oh,
-- I'm
sure you can opt out of this if you're one of their enterprise customers.
I mean, I, I think if you look at the world of windows, the whole version of windows,
it's very much marching.
I think in the direction of kind of,
I would say a chrome like experience where I
think Microsoft wants that control and they can like,
they get to decide what you look at and they get to decide what you do and
I hate that.
Well, I've already noticed that like with the family,
so I have the family sort of sharing or whatever stuff set up.
So I can limit, you know, my kids access to video games a bit by time
And it really, really wants me to enable location services
and
windows.
So, you know,
I can see where my kids are on their phones and stuff like
physically track them like the uh the iphone find my phone feature stuff.
But
yeah, no, it's very,
it's really clear that the mobile experience with the 30%
haircut for all transactions is what Apple and Microsoft want.
-- I don't blame them. 30% is a lot of money.
-- It is a lot of money they're doing all right.
Anyway, I hate ads. I'm sick of ads.
The only thing I hate more than ads is changing my clock,
which we had to do this week and I detest it and I'm tired and grumpy.
So
this is just like this is gas on the fire.
I'm just, I'm wound up as it is and now it's like dang it Microsoft
anyway.
-- Well,
-- and so in, in,
in news of like literally shooting yourself in the foot as much as you can.
So
as we all know, Russia invaded the Ukraine and we're now on to week, uh, almost four,
by the time this podcast comes out another week will have gone by
and of course, there's sanctions
and
I fully anticipated economic sanctions would hurt Russia because
that's the whole point of them.
But
for whatever reason,
myself and most people had never really
thought through the whole impact of sanctions.
So, a perfect example is apparently Russia is running out of storage.
They've got about two months left.
-- You mean, like computer storage, right?
-- Yeah. Like hard drive storage,
right? I mean, that's wild to think about.
Well, and, uh especially because we're,
we're getting into some very data driven
applications when you start talking about fascist
and authoritarian machines,
like things like facial recognition and surveillance,
like
that eats up a huge amount of storage
and you never delete anything, obviously.
Yeah. Well, you can't because you're afraid of everything and everybody.
And so,
uh, yeah,
I mean,
uh are, are we gonna have like national hard drive drives where you, like,
turn in your hard drives or?
Well, we won't. No, like, seriously. Right. What do you do? Because it's like,
that's, the thing is like building a hard drive. Now, how long would it take for, uh,
even
a, let's say, even a modern country like Canada
to actually build and start shipping a hard drives from
a hard drive factory with all Canadian stuff basically.
And I'm assuming it would be about one or two decades.
I bet you could do it in 10 years or less.
Assuming you just stole the IP from someone else.
I mean, how to do this is well understood.
-- Well, the problem
-- is, for example, where do we get the chips for the controllers?
Well, do we go steal a SM OS?
Ah, that's true.
Yeah, you can just, just start piracy, go take over some container ships and, and
claim them as your own. It's fine.
-- It's international waters. I'm sure that's
-- legal. And that's the thing. It's,
it's everything on the planet now has, for example, at a minimum,
has microchips built into it,
some pretty sophisticated stuff. Usually
we saw
with the,
the, the automobiles during the pandemic where
there was a, a, like a perfect storm of events that
hampered the chip factories and, like, you can't buy a car now.
It's like, wait, what a car?
Well, what happened is the automakers forecast lower demand.
So they basically canceled all their chip orders.
And of course COVID as a forcing function was like,
I don't want to get on a bus with other people if I can afford a car.
And so, like,
literally my used car is worth more now than when I bought it two years ago.
-- Yeah.
-- Except you can't buy another one.
Well, yeah, exactly. And so Ford, for example, their initial plan was to
build the cars,
shipped them in an undrivable state to dealers and then
I'm not sure what part two of the plan was.
They backed off that and now they're shipping Ford Explorers with no uh
rear. What is it?
The heating and air conditioning controls are, are disabled because there's,
well, there's no chips in them
and they'll be a little bit cheaper.
You can buy it and they sort of are promising within a year to fix it. Double promise.
Pinky squares.
Like I'm just looking at this. And so then the second problem becomes
ok. So supply chains are disrupted. That's bad.
But then Russia is now nationalizing stuff or talking about nationalizing stuff.
And
yeah, I, I'm not going to put assets in Russia
if they start taking them.
Like,
and somebody pointed out that Amazon Google all the big, you know, Microsoft,
all those big places, they don't have data centers in Russia.
They, they sort of weirdly foresaw this.
I mean, it, it doesn't totally surprise me.
I feel like when I look at a lot of the events happening around,
kind of just Russia in their behavior
is
when and this is very true of security. I re
I remember dealing with this many, many times is when you're
panicked
and you're under like obscene amounts of stress because
there's some sort of emergency happening around you,
whether it's your own creation or not.
Like, for example, if you get hacked, it's really hard to make good choices.
I mean, it's really hard like it's easy to say, oh, if I get hacked,
I'll do this and this and this, but it is nothing like that.
When you have an event, you have people breathing down your neck,
you have everything exploding, everyone's freaking out.
You don't know what to do.
And so you just start making dumb choices and,
and I have a suspicion that's part of this is like they're
panicked and they're freaking out and
they're making completely ridiculous choices.
Well, the other problem is you say they, but in this case, Russia is not a they,
it's Russia is Putin.
That's true.
And I think that's part of the other problem is that
traditionally you have sort of group decision making where ideally,
at least some of the more stupid stuff gets vetoed.
Uh
Although again,
that can go horribly wrong as we've seen
with Microsoft sticking ads in the file browser,
right?
But right, I mean, it,
it traditionally one of the reasons we use groups to
make decisions is so that Bob speaks up and says,
hey, guys,
did you know if we do that that it'll like
have this really bad consequence that we don't want.
I mean,
that's always easy to say in hindsight and I
think the conversation I want to bring this to is
so there's like all these supply chain things,
there's all this stuff happening in Russia.
Russia's making all these terrible decisions.
And I think sometimes if you think about kind of the greater security universe.
A lot of the supplies where they, like, we have a software supply chain
and there's an enormous number of interconnected
parts in ways we often don't understand.
And one of my favorite examples is when
you'll tell a software developer,
you have to upgrade this dependency and it's 36 layers deep
and they're like, I can't and you say you have to do it right now,
no questions asked and they do it and everything else explodes
somewhere else in the application that seems to be unrelated.
But you know, that's just kind of how supply chains work.
And we're seeing this literally in action
with real
the supply chain.
You know, I don't, I don't know what we call like the, the, the, the real stuff,
the global supply chain.
There you go.
Like it's just, it's like I'm at a point where do I just start hoarding soap
-- and toilet paper and literally everything just
-- hard lye and then you can make soap,
it's fine.
Well,
so that's what Toyota does as part of their
business continuity plan they now require or not.
Now they have for some time required
a their suppliers to maintain a 2 to 6 month stock level of whatever part it is,
they sell Toyota depending on how hard it is to kind of get a hold of.
Right.
So they essentially externalize the carry cost of
having all those backup bits and pieces,
right?
Right. And that's a really important part too.
So Toyota is famous for creating the just in time supply chain concept,
except most people here just in time supply chain.
And they interpret that as I will order what I need when I need it and it will be magic
and that works when the supply chain is firing in all cylinders.
What Toyota really does
is they have an enormous amount of insight into their supply chain
and they know that there are things they can get somewhere else if
they need to and there's things they can't and the things they can't,
they make sure they have some backup of
versus the things they know they can acquire elsewhere.
And like an easy example is microchips, right.
There's basically one place to get those.
But let's say, like you need a plastic knob,
you can probably get a plastic knob almost anywhere in a very short lead time.
So you don't need
-- six months of plastic knobs in a warehouse.
-- Yeah.
No, it's, and we discovered that, you know,
with the stupid truck protests here in Canada where, you know, they,
they basically shut down the auto industry.
Yeah. Yeah. Blocking that bridge
because the auto industry literally depends on a company in Canada making parts,
putting them in a truck,
getting them over the border in 3 to 4 hours and showing up at the factory,
you know, by 5 p.m. or whatever for the next trip.
And that's kind of why Shenzhen in places in China like that work so well.
Is they literally
I need, you know, this weirdly specific screw. Yeah, there's
the company that does, that is down the street,
you know, they have that critical mass of just everything is within a 23 hour drive.
But you need to understand that.
And I think again, if we want to talk about security which, and,
and I'd love to tie everything back to security whenever I can.
When you're talking about software and security.
Like
a lot of us fly blind where we don't know what's in our stuff.
We don't know where it's coming from.
We don't know how to get something new or different if we need it.
-- Well,
-- and that's one thing we don't have replacements.
Yeah. Yeah.
For example, back in the olden days I could very easily swap Apache for engine X
very easily. Right. I'm serving static content. I can swap them.
But nowadays with a fully integrated container web app,
the thought of swatching one web server for another is just a big, no,
that's a heavy lift
or like, I mean, switching cloud providers, right?
You don't just be like, oh,
I don't want to use AWS anymore, push a button and now we're using
no, like it doesn't work like that.
I mean, the whole, the theory of Kubernetes and multi cloud,
it's like I keep seeing it and I keep seeing people try and,
and,
and that's the reason a lot of companies use that is they
intentionally use that so they don't get locked into a provider.
Like,
I don't know its name, names Oracle. Right.
We can all agree if you get locked into Oracle, that's not a good,
you're not going to have a good time.
Right.
Well, back to that,
that security thing is what is the criticality of this piece of software?
Like how important is it?
You know, a great example being the, well remember, there's
the time zone guy who does the time zone file, but the whole world relies upon,
I
know,
you know, and one time he got sick and another time he got sued
and it's like
maybe,
maybe we should have a second person just to sub in for him in case he gets hit by a bus.
-- I
-- mean, this is kind of the story of log for Jay, right,
where you had this incredibly critical package
that was maintained by volunteers and everyone lost their mind.
-- So
-- one fascinating thing is, and I, I
sent this to you last night, but
I noticed on the most recent open SSL advisory,
they have premium support now with extended LTs support for software.
-- I'm pretty sure they've had that for a while.
-- Has that? Has it been for a while? Ok.
Because I literally just noticed it.
Yeah,
I remember the other thing they did too is they had like you
could pay them for uh a Phis version as well where I mean,
in a while,
like not like 20 years or anything like that.
But it's been, I think around five give or take that I,
that II I may be remembering something incorrectly.
So
like by all means, verify this,
I do remember open sl had a Phipps version that was not free,
like it was certified and it was tested and blah, blah, blah.
And that was for anybody that's ever done anything to do with government paperwork.
Just Phipps is worse.
It's better than common criteria.
But that's another story.
-- Anyway,
-- if you think a sock two audit is a pain in your butt, just wait till you try
fs
-- oh
-- man, getting those certifications and it takes years.
I mean, it was, it was always funny because
when you have in a modern, like DEV
ops style
universe, you could be releasing every couple of weeks
and getting some of these certifications is completely untenable
because you can't, like,
you'd have to do a release and then basically support it for
years while you're waiting for it to go through the machine.
And then by the time it comes out, you,
the two products you have the old and the new would look nothing alike.
-- It's, it's a hard problem. I mean, it totally is.
-- Well, that's the thing.
How do you certify something when that something is constantly changing?
Right. Right. You don't
in in possibly significant ways.
Like,
it's one thing to certify a car for safety and then add a
new radio to it that probably doesn't impact the safety all that much.
But as we've discovered with software
it's, you know, I'm making the hand wavy.
It's an ecosystem like in the it crowd, you know, you, you change one thing and boom,
the rain forest dies.
Right. Well, I mean, again, this, this harkens back to the supply chain. Topic of
everything is so interconnected that it's really hard
to untangle and it's really hard to understand.
And I mean, I think this is where some of the newer techno, I mean,
some of the topics we're talking about like we just talked about as
a
couple episodes ago, like
Essbaum
is a great example of I'm not saying it's a silver bullet by any means,
but it is a way you can gain insight into what you have, which is like step one, right?
-- There's like 300 more steps after that, but that is step one. Well, I
-- mean, to me SB
is what, what's the alternative?
Like we, we have to start doing stuff like that.
We have to start understanding what we're shipping and what we depend on
the alternative is doing nothing, which is basically what we've been doing.
How's that working out?
Yeah, I hope those soap companies keep shipping soap to Canada so I can be clean.
No, I literally, I'm like,
where does all my soap come from.
I was looking at like every single product I looked at doesn't say where it's made,
you know, it just says imported by,
-- there's
-- some old timey recipe you can probably find on the
internet to make soap from dead animals and ash or something.
I don't know.
Well, fun fact I learned that's why bleach makes your hands feel slippery.
Yep. Yep. I read that and read it also
because bleach combines with the oil to make soap on your finger.
I just learned this uh yesterday.
So I'm very proud of that fact because I always was wondering like,
is bleach slipper like what's the deal here?
But no, it makes soap on your hands. So I guess
uh but I'm not saying you should wash yourself down with bleach.
That is probably a bad idea.
I, I actually got some lye in my hands one time and I,
I experienced a similar thing and I was like, wow, lye is slippery.
No,
no, I just made soap
anyway.
Anyway.
So,
yeah, I, because that's like I'm looking at this and it's,
there's certain countries where it's clearly
dangerous to operate or there's certain,
you know, there's a lot of constraints like, say North Korea, Russia, you know,
Iraq where you're not just going to like, build a factory and be happy, you know,
like you would say, compared to
Canada or Germany or France or the US, right?
But
I guess part of my, what I'm looking at this now is like,
what about all these sort of in the
middle countries like that are having trouble but not
off the crazy and, like, say Brazil Argentina, you know. Right.
Like, I just,
I imagine right now for companies doing risk assessments of
where do they operate and put plants is complicated.
I don't think it's worse than it's ever been.
I mean, I think this is just part of doing business, especially in a global space.
I think historically,
we've gotten to ignore a lot of this, not because
it didn't exist,
but rather just we were living this kind
of carefree lifestyle because things just showed up.
And now we have, you know, we had the pandemic which had its own supply chain issues.
We have a global war going on essentially now
and that's creating its own set of issues.
There's just all this angst happening and I, I think
it is obvious to everyone now how just truly interconnected.
Absolutely everything is.
And, and I even,
I even see this in software where there's just more
and more talk of all the supply chain issues of how
everything is interconnected about where you're getting your software from
and starting to try to build some trust around that.
And I think it, it's all connected.
Everything we're seeing is all connected in every possible way. And it's,
I mean, what's the old curse? May you live in?
Interesting times like, holy crap, it couldn't be more interesting than this.
Well, like you said, I mean,
I think for now until now it just largely worked well enough that we ignored it
with the occasional, you know, ridiculous
developer tantrum where they, you know,
destroy their software and it breaks a whole bunch of an ecosystem or whatever,
you know. But by and large, yeah, things just sort of worked.
People behaved reasonably and now
people are behaving less reasonably and more to
the point systems are behaving less reasonably,
you know, because of like second order effects, you know, for want of a nail,
the horse is not working
and
yeah, it's, it's, well, it's like the classic,
like I'm always reminded of uh Fukushima, which was,
there was a nuclear power plant. The name is G
that was closer to the epicenter and actually got a bigger wave.
But the plant manager there basically said, I don't trust managers,
managers aligning weasels, we're building a 10 m sea wall
and he got so much flak for it.
And everybody was like, oh, you're wasting money, blah, blah, blah.
-- And of course, well that nuclear plant didn't have any problems,
-- right?
I didn't know that. I haven't heard this before.
It's,
we'll put it in the show notes. But yeah, like straight up, you know, the,
it was like Seaward's Folly, just Google Seward's Folly, right?
The Britain's first kind of major atomic power plant was literally
um
these little metal canisters with a giant chimney behind them.
And Seaward was like, we should probably put a filter on top of that.
And they're like, nah, this thing won't catch fire.
And he's like, no,
we should really probably put a filter on top of that
because if it does catch fire it's going to Irradiate,
like all of Britain and western Europe.
And we're screwed.
And so they're like, oh, fine, we'll put a, you know,
and it's like this horrendous cost and it's extremely expensive and painful and,
yeah, I guess what happened,
-- I assume it caught on fire. The pile
-- caught fire.
Right. Who knew?
Thank goodness for that filter. Or else, you know, I mean,
look, this is the classic story of security
is when you do your job correctly, nobody notices
when you don't do your job, everybody notices.
And it's always funny when I talk about this. I mean, I, I did a podcast.
It's been a couple of years now, but it was this thing called The Future of Tech.
And I just written an article somewhere basically saying, like, security is boring
and the point was like, if your security isn't boring, you're doing security wrong.
Right.
Security should be like accounting where it's just,
it is there and it does its job and you don't hear about it.
And like, that's the first thing the host just like, came out swinging,
like you're saying security is boring.
What's up with that. And I'm like, no, no, no, no, security should be boring. Right.
Like, if your security isn't boring, you're doing security wrong
and sorry, it was Croft Sea. I
don't know where I got Seaward from.
I don't know,
it wasn't Seward's Folly Alaska.
-- Was that
-- the guy
that was Alaska? Yeah, that's what I was thinking of. Yeah, you're right.
Sorry, I've got a lot of Russia on the brain because, yeah,
Russia was saying they want Alaska back
and apparently the Alaskan governor was like,
no,
-- wait,
-- what, when did they say this just recently?
Like yesterday?
Remember? Because they're talking about historical territorial claims?
Oh, I see.
-- Yeah. Right.
-- Anyway, and it's like, you know, that's not how this works
like you sold it.
It's not, you know, like buyer's remorse, I get it or seller's remorse.
But I think it works that way when you're three, when you're three years old
and I want the hot wheel you're playing with.
I can claim it as my own
until the parents find out and then I get yelled at anyway, whatever, whatever.
-- But
-- right.
So, no, this whole thing is just, yeah, if we do our jobs, right, it is boring
-- and
-- it should be,
I think that goes back to the people want the job to be kind of
sexy and exciting and movie plots and lots of typing on rapidly scrolling screens,
which I never understood because I just might, you know,
if you have two sets of texts scrolling one up and one down like in hackers.
It's just like
-- I feel like I'm just gonna get a migraine headache from that.
-- Whatever.
That looks cool.
I mean, look, man,
everyone wants their personal narrative to be something exciting.
Right? Especially when you're young.
When I was young, I was all about, oh,
security should be exciting and more people need to know about this and this
is a big deal now that I'm a bit on the older side,
we'll say
I'm like, I want the most boring job in the world.
Like I want to see no security events ever.
And that would make me the happiest person alive and it, of course,
doesn't exactly work that way.
But, you know, I, I mean, yeah, it's,
it is difficult,
especially in an industry that I think was built on the backs of a lot of,
uh exciting and rock star type things that happened.
I mean, you look back in history, you've got like the cult of the dead cow.
You had the loft, you had all these amazing hacker incidents.
You had these hacker conference says it was definitely a very look at me
sort of space. And now there's many reasons for that.
I would highly suggest reading the Joseph Mann, wrote a cult of the Dead Cow book.
And he kind of, he spent some time discussing like why
they had to do the stunts. They did
and it was to get the attention they needed. But it's like, kind of,
we have a lot of this attention now and I
think it's time to turn this into a maturing industry
and
that's going to be the next difficulty.
Just like car safety Ralph Nader had to write
unsafe at any speed and do some horrific demos.
And then now it's, you know, when you buy a car it's kind of, well,
how many airbags does it have not?
-- Does it have airbags?
-- I don't know. And I don't care,
like I know that any car I buy in the United States today is going to
a reasonable amount of safety. I don't know.
I don't, I could not tell you how many airbags are in my car right now. I have no idea.
And I don't, I'm not even gonna look now that we said this,
I don't care and I'm not gonna care, you know, and that's good.
That's what you want.
It's kind of like, how many times have you gone to the store and been like,
I wonder if there's mercury in this fish?
I'm eating
-- probably not very often. So
-- I used to not care. And then I, I learned things like
they'll put made in Canada on the package.
But what they meant is it was put in a box in Canada.
And it was actually like,
so for example, there's, um,
shrimp from Southeast Asia that actually has
worryingly high levels of mercury that I,
I won't buy shrimp and stuff from Southeast Asia anymore.
So actually, you know,
I do worry about that because there is shenanigans with that going on.
-- And
-- that's a bad example. Um
Well, no, it's actually a good example because
there's enough information in the supply chain despite the
cheating trying to go on. But I can still make safe decisions
and it's kind of an outlier but
fundamentally, I mean,
part of it too is when you have a lack of transparency and information,
like when you have information asymmetry.
Well, perfect example is you end up things like the housing market where it's like,
oh this house is on,
you know, for sale and it's really hot.
So like there's no time for an inspection, you have to buy it now.
And yeah, if you buy a house without an inspection, well, realistically,
either way you're going to have a whole bunch of issues that you need to fix.
Just kind of
how bad is it? Right.
-- No, II I agree. I agree.
-- At
least with open source, we have that information transparency is possible.
I'm not saying it's easy because you know, tracking down every bit of an S bomb is
let me put it this way.
If somebody came to me with a sufficiently complicated project and
said I have a 100% complete and correct s bomb,
I'd be like, no, you don't.
Yeah, I know you don't
I,
I think that's ok because I'm very happy to acknowledge that
this is very new territory and it's going to get better.
Right.
-- It, it progress is slow. Even
-- food may contain traces of.
And then it lists a bunch of weird stuff and it's like, oh,
I guess it's made it a big plant, cross contamination can happen.
Right.
And we accept that's ok because they kind of warn me,
I'm not sure quite how we warn people about that in the
su rule, you know, may contain traces of pearl. I would want to know.
One would think so. Like, II, I agree. I agree.
I think these are, I, I guess if I was going to sum it all up, I would say
it's starting to feel like the security industry
is, is growing up. I don't think it necessarily wants to.
I think there's a lot of being drug kicking and screaming into some of this.
There's still people going against cloud and automation.
-- Oh, I know there always will be
-- like,
there's still people I find who don't want to
remotely manage their fleet and it's kind of like,
why would you not want to do that?
I bet you there were people against automobiles for a very, very, very long time.
I mean,
I think there's always going to be laggards.
That's ok.
But I, I think at this point they're,
they're irrelevant to the conversation for the most part.
And that's great. That's great. Right.
And I think,
like, in the security world you don't hear very many people saying, oh,
like s bomb is a dumb idea.
I think we can all agree. It's a good idea.
I think what we're going to do with it is the next question where
there's obviously varying ideas about what do we actually do with the data?
But it,
it's going to get better. Right. Because that's just how,
that's how progress happens. Progress is slow
and that's OK.
It's, it's, I think sometimes it gets
frustrating where it's like I we should be doing this faster but like
sometimes
it's OK not to go too fast because sometimes when you go too fast, you make a big mess.
Well, part of it too is sometimes you can't, it's an ecosystem, right?
Because I, I talked about this many years ago, but why didn't Cloud happen sooner?
And part of it is, for example, we didn't have the bandwidth,
we didn't have the compute power to support it. We didn't have,
we just didn't have the software to operationally support it. You know, I
mean, for
example, 20 years ago, if I said Josh, I need you to stand up 20 web servers,
you know what you did?
Best case scenario,
you wrote a script to do it and then you hand checked your results, right?
That was the, that would have been the height of automation.
Yeah, it would have been Ss Hing
into machines,
but I still would have had to have installed the operating system probably by hand.
-- It would have been a lot of work for
-- sure. Yeah.
But what I'm saying is like, the height of automation would be, you wrote a script.
-- Yeah. Right. Right. Exactly.
-- There, there was no framework for this.
There was no ans
or salt
or puppet or whatever.
No. No, no, absolutely not. Yeah.
Yeah.
And
I mean,
it, it's getting better, you know, that's kind of the way I look at it.
I, I feel like we, we are improving.
I'd love it if it went faster, but I, I acknowledge that's not how it works. So
I'm, I'm hopeful,
I feel like
every time I look at some of the things happening,
I feel hopeful for where we're headed because I
feel like we're going in the right directions,
which is great.
I, I like that.
-- I
-- think the simple fact is we've got policymakers at the highest level,
like literally the White House is issuing executive orders on
this and it doesn't get any higher than that.
You know, you've got the German government,
you know.
Yeah, you've got the German government officially warning people that like, hey,
that Russian antivirus, you
might want to double think about it because
you know what if the government shows up at their offices and
tells them to ship an update with a thing in it?
I mean, look, the US government banned Kaspersky,
like a long time ago.
Well, and that's the thing.
So there's a difference between,
like the NSA tailored access operations where they intercept a few boxes,
stick a few chips in or do whatever.
There's sort of a level of plausible deniability and also of scale.
It's entirely different when, you know,
like an entire vendor gets subverted,
uh, willingly so well. Well, like the crypto a
thing and the CIA, right.
You know, it turns out that Swiss crypto company was owned by the US government.
Whoops,
you know, that's, that's, you can't really,
you can't really dance around that anymore.
It's like that's a problem. We, we can't ignore it. Is what I'm saying.
-- No, I agree. I agree
-- with
small stuff
anyway, I think it's time to go.
Alright, man, I'm gonna call it.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to open social security podcast.com. Head up the show note, Suzie
Pound to Ss Podcast. Hashtag Hit us up on social media.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks, everyone. Bye bye
the.