Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in identifying software
packages because they need to be fixed.
-- Josh
-- Pressers.
I mean, maybe they don't need to be fixed, but we need to know what they are.
All right. So I'll, I'm gonna set the stage for this one. We'll just jump right in.
There was a request for comment from SISA.
Uh
-- It's been, it'll be several weeks by the time this episode comes out,
-- but by the way,
I tried to leave a comment and their
site is broken for that regulations dot Whatever go
over now,
that's why it wouldn't work.
Oh, well,
it would have been helpful if it gave an
error because I could pull up other people's comments.
But it wouldn't. Anyways,
that website, it's good, but it needs work.
It's a government website, Kurt, like, come on.
It's shockingly decent, but it's just in this case,
it was not clear that the comment period is over.
Anyway,
I was part of a group at the open SSF that wrote a,
we'll say
reasonable response to sis's request for comment.
And the SISA paper is kind of long and disjointed and weird.
Well, I, I liked it because they did a thought experiment
and they had four outcomes and we're like,
here's kind of the upsides and downsides of these four different outcomes.
-- And,
-- I
-- mean,
-- maybe, ok, that's fair. Whatever, regardless
the purpose of this conversation is talking about how we,
you can identify software, which sounds boring.
But when you actually start talking about it,
it gets really interesting because it's funny,
Kurt sent me like walls of text over the since yesterday about this topic.
And I'm like, it's ok, like we know how to answer all of this stuff. We talked about it.
And so we're going to talk about identifying software because it's
actually really important and it's really freaking hard to do.
So
I will explain kind of what SISA talked about
and then we'll go from there, right. Fundamentally, they talked about
what is it four ways to identify software in their document?
Well, not so much, four ways to identify software but sort of four frameworks like,
is it gonna be centralized or decentralized?
That's
right.
So it's the same technology but the application
and the the business process is different.
-- Let's,
-- let's just explain the ones they talked about.
They are called PERL package URL. That's a very open source project.
Very cool, very interesting.
They talk about C Pe which is common platform enumeration that's run by Nist
C PE S are terrible.
Anyone who works with C pe is just like shuttered in faint fear and pain.
Then you've got something called Omni
Bore, which used to be called Git bomb.
And it's a very weird and unique way to identify this stuff.
It has its place, but probably not in this document.
And then there is, they talk about SW I very
-- sw is software ID.
-- I think Microsoft does it and
maybe
I think there was one other.
my understanding is it's used fairly heavily in the like IOT embedded device space.
It's, it's
sw I is considered an
EPA
format
but no one likes it. Well, I shouldn't say that
people in the like software space we exist in the very like high
level application. None of us like SW I, because it's very annoying to use.
So we're not going to talk about it very much.
This is something I want to raise is that the problem is
there are multiple software industries, there's the open source
and I don't even want to say industry because it's in some cases, it's just,
people are like, I wrote this thing and released it and if you like it great.
And if you don't, well go away all the way to like a thing like curl where, you know,
he's is a mature project with over 1200
contributors and it's like critical to the world
and then there's proprietary software, there's IOT software,
there's hardware stuff, there's
blah, blah, blah
and the
problem is, it's not just that they have different needs, they do,
but they have entirely different cultures.
Yes. That's right.
That's right.
So, and this is part of the challenge is that the reality is,
is you consume software at scale and by scale, I mean,
if your organization has more than 10 people, you are now consuming
software and services at scale.
Whether you like it or not,
like you're gonna run Windows or Mac Os or Linux plus everything it runs.
So right there,
-- boom is hundreds of things
-- and and this is one of the things we discussed with in the
SSF document is like
there is going to be one solution.
So let's not pretend there is because don't get me wrong.
If I was a dictator of the world,
I would love to be like everyone use pearl because I like it.
But I, I also recognize it doesn't work for everything and that's OK.
That's OK.
However,
there are things that don't work and can't work.
And this is like, for example, why C pe is I would say an abject failure because it is
Nist is in charge of C pe.
Nist is responsible for creating ac pe
identifier for every software version of anything.
And they make typos, they make tons of typos, they're inconsistent, they're slow,
it's awful. This is why C pe is terrible because it's a centralized database
-- and it's just a pain.
-- This is a perfect example.
Of, you can absolutely have a centralized database. But with more open access in
this case though, there is no open access. It is N
database and
N runs it.
And this is a perfect example of like this is where I tried to take
um CV and where I'm trying to take CWE is to have a central database. Sure.
But let's make it open, let's let people participate.
Yeah, it's not working out.
Maybe. I don't know if I agree with that. Let's talk about that.
So it would be better than just having
-- charge.
-- Maybe. OK. Yes, I, I won't disagree with that.
Now,
you're going to get arguments.
Like for example, CV E has their CN A program which they argue that's, oh,
we're a decentralized database which I don't think they
are because technically Miter is still driving the bus.
If it's a decentralized database, how come there's only one source for the data?
That's fair officially.
Now, unofficially, actually, we need to have that post CV era talk at some point.
I think we both need to think about it because I think it's actually
because I've been living in a post CV
era for about 15 years now.
I think we all are and we don't know it.
-- But that's
-- like the rest of you are just catching up.
-- We're not
-- talking about that today.
-- But
-- OK,
so I want to,
so there's now on the other side
of a centralized database,
you have functionally how pearl works every time I say pearl, I mean P URL,
-- not P er L the language just,
-- I don't think anybody cares about good old
pearl.
This happens all the time when I start talking about pearl, they're like,
does anyone run pearl anymore? I'm like, what? Oh the language.
No, we're not talking about that.
-- So
-- anyway, maybe just call pu LP
URL, P
URL. S. So pearls conversely, there's no like centralized repository,
there's no like central definition of, of things necessarily.
It's basically you look at a piece of software
and
using information about the software,
you can build the pearl.
It's not meant to be something that's necessarily like track somewhere.
It's meant to be something you can use evidence to create,
which is the complete opposite of the centralized database.
And there's also a very subtle thing to Pr L which is ideally
if two people look at the same piece of software using Pr L,
they will ideally create a, I mean, in a perfect world identical,
but a close enough pr L that you can reconcile them,
right?
And that is a major thing because all of these see and it's funny because the,
the CIA paper explicitly calls that out that
we in a perfect world, they want everything to have one identifier
and for one identifier to identify one thing,
that's it a 1 to 1 relationship. And unfortunately, that's not how the world works.
And
-- here's where
-- the girl gets even weirder. So here's what's wild.
So if I install a package with pie, pie, pie,
pie becomes part of the pearl definition because it's coming from pi pie.
If I
install the same package from
github,
now the pearl has github in its name because I've installed
it from GI even though they're literally the same package.
Now, if I download the package off the internet off of a random website,
now, I have the generic tag in my pearl,
meaning I could have more uh there's ways to do it even more.
But like in this example,
that is three different pearls for functionally the same thing.
And then ideally, you would also, for example,
have a hash of the original Tar Ball and be like, oh this thing from github
and this thing from Pipi and this thing from
Bob's
House
software are the exact same
in a perfect world. I exact same Tar Ball name, version and
file hash. It's just I got them in different ways. And that
to be clear really matters.
It does because also there will be times where that Tar Ball
or that archive is auto generated and it's not the same,
it is the same, but it's not like for example,
two files might be in a different order in the Tar Ball, which means now your file has
100% off.
But if you like unpack both of them and d them, they are bit for bit identical.
Not just that if you generate a Atgz right now
and then you do it one second later,
you're going it, it depending, I mean, not always but like conceivably
it could be different because the time stamps are different, right?
And so this is one of the challenges to
that whole like reproducible software universe and discussion.
Now,
this is where Omnivore is interesting because Omnivore kind of creates
these weird hash trees of the content in the archives.
So you still have some of the problems
around weird time stamping and things like that.
But when you're focusing kind of more on
you'd be able to reconcile it better. You know,
in theory, in theory, I mean,
there's a huge asterisk to this and Omni
Bore is very new and it's been evolving for a long time. So
like even some of the things we're going to talk about now
be different by the time this episode comes out, which is fine.
But now at the same time, it's very hash focused. Like if I gave you an omni
hash,
you'd be like,
-- what, what is, what is
-- this? I'd
shove it into Google and
-- hopefully,
-- if you're lucky,
that's it. Like.
And that leads to the biggest thing I wanna mention
is
these systems need
to aid in discoverability.
And this is one reason I like package URL is because, well, it's in the name URL.
See this is one of the beauties of using DNS is DNS is globally unique.
-- Oh no,
-- we haven't made it to DNS yet. We'll get there
-- in a minute.
-- But the point is
it aids in discoverability because if you say
food.
-- Ok, well, which food like the pie, pie food, the pearl
-- food in the world of S bombs.
This is a consistent problem because there are packages, for example,
in NP like N PM has consumed every English word as a package name at this point.
And so there are literally packages with the exact same name in like go and N PM,
which one am I looking at?
And even better, there are identically named
packages in the same language that are totally different things.
-- Well, that's not possible in packaging ecosystems
-- in an owned name space like N PM,
they are different and in github,
they are technically different because there's the, you know, the github
slash whatever slash
but there's a lot of PHP security like there's
a ton of stuff named security across all languages
and you know, whoever happens to own it in N PM, good for them. But
there's,
and it's actually if I remember right,
the N PM one is really bad because it's super
out of date but people keep using it because security.
But this is a good example of if I
have to go libraries written by different people called,
you know uh oh perfect example, like I need something to go talk,
let's say uh Google API.
So I have a Go Google Api,
I guarantee you if I search for that right now,
I'm going to find more than one in github
problem. And
in the go name space packaging managed system, there will be like a winner,
but that's not always clear because for example,
remember there's been N PM trademark issues where somebody's package
gets gank and it's
like
in some cases, it's kind of the same thing.
I think it was square did that once to a square API thing,
but in other cases,
the trademark holder has gained it and it's a completely different package
for sure, for sure.
And so the second thing I want to say is so number one,
we need discoverability and context as much as possible.
And number two, we need actually,
I think we need to have a lot more time stamping of like, OK, this
II I got this from this github
account at this time
because that github account might have changed hands or
it might be gone or it might be whatever.
Like what if Red Hat actually someday manages to get a hold of github.com/red hat.
Good luck Red
-- Hat. What happened in
-- theory like the guy,
I don't agree with you that time is an important factor in this.
I'm
in
context.
I agree with that because so this is actually where Pearl has a magic power
is pearl lets you at it because it looks like a URL and you know,
when you have a URL, you can do like question mark and, and all that other crap
string.
Query string. That's the name. Thank you.
I never remember what they're called,
but you can basically use query string. So you can add hashes, you can add
like upstream repositories, you can add what all kinds of stuff.
But the beauty is, they're also like Jason, they're kind of parcel by a human.
I can look at a Pearl URL and like basically understand 99% of it without even trying.
And that's really important. I know it's easy to say
all of this should be machine readable. Humans need not apply.
And I said that about many, many things and I agree with it,
which generally speaking, I do.
But I think like this is in a good instance where for example,
I I work with data like this all day, every day, right?
I work with our customers who are building bombs or scanning
for vulnerabilities or doing license compliance and all kinds of stuff.
And they'll be like, hey,
this package is showing up weird,
right? And then they like,
show me what they're getting.
I run my test. I see what I get.
I'm like, oh, I'm getting the same thing, our tool is broken or it's like,
I have no idea why you're getting that something weird is going on.
-- Let's figure it out.
-- And
that's one of the reasons very subtly why human readability is so important.
It's not,
I'm not even going to get into the humans versus machines doing the work because
the machine should be doing the work for
when it comes to
troubleshooting
and, and
human readable versus a giant binary blob that
has to be converted into something human.
Right? No, there's a big difference.
I can,
I can troubleshoot Jason by looking at
it
and be like,
it's also funny you mentioned this because I was having a
discussion literally yesterday for the time we're talking about this,
we're
I was talking to the at Anor,
we have a tool called
SIF that generates S bombs.
But part of generating S bombs is we have to identify stuff, right?
-- And that's kind of
-- the whole point of S bombs,
right? It's literally, it's, it's only job,
but we're,
we're trying to unwind like open JDK has some
incredibly gnarly versioning the way it works and,
and the way C pe defines it is even more ridiculous.
I'm not gonna get into it.
I would literally take me half an hour to explain something going to.
But I'm talking to the SIFT developers and one of them at one point is like
this whole project is just an edge case of edge cases.
Like it, it's edge cases all the way down. And it's like,
yes, it literally is, but that's also why we need that. Like
we need humans to look at the edge cases to unwind the edge cases which sucks.
Now, before we run out of time, I also want us to talk about DNS
because
of these suggestions the open SSF had
was that pearls are great,
but we should probably also lean on DNS more
for some of what we're doing because today,
like pearl doesn't require or necessitate DNS at all.
But DNS is magic and now it's your turn to tell us all why DNS is great.
I'm actually gonna make it worse.
Are we talking about DNS or are we talking about URL S
-- DNS, specifically
-- DNS?
So
I like using DNS because it gives me
two things.
It gives me a globally unique
thing
that
is really easy to discover and map control to who controls walmart.com.
Walmart.com controls walmart.com. It's a tautology but it works,
it does,
it's, it's the only global decentralized
-- thing we have on the planet to be honest. Perfect
-- example. I go to sun.com.
Oh, it's oracle.com. Now,
when did that
-- happen?
-- Exactly.
-- Living in a cave
-- for
-- sun
-- dot com is the perfect example.
And this is something we talked about a lot in our meetings at the open SSF
because Java uses name spaces that are DNS, right?
Like I, I don't know how many, I don't know how many people remember this,
but you used to when you would use a lot of the like built in Java classes,
it was com dot So
dot stuff, right?
And when you look at the way DNS is used like as a name space and programming,
it's usually backwards.
Right. Where you put the com first dot Domain.
-- Well,
-- it's, it's basically classical. Big Indian versus little Indian.
-- Yeah. Right. Right.
-- Right.
And it's really funny to me that A URL
is little Indian and then becomes Big Indian past
the request string. It's very strange
but it's kind of how people read things we read left to right. Generally. So
I agree
with that. But it's funny because phone numbers are big Indian
URL s are anyways
ignoring that little bit of silly.
But when you start to think about it, it's like, yeah, this really is kind of bizarre,
whatever.
But the point is the point is
DNS,
is that like, oddly unique and useful name space of the world.
And now I know, like we've talked about names,
there's one other thing you forget about DNS.
It's easy for me to get one.
I won't argue that that is a big deal because
I cannot get AC P unless N
degrees.
Uh. Right. But with DNS, even if I'm banned from.com, I can get.net or dot
Or dot C A or do
I just, oh, I recently got a dot IE for, because we have a presence in Ireland
and like, there's some legal requirements for it.
Like, you have to have a business number or VA number or whatever
and we do.
So, it, it was funny because you like literally have to send them the,
you have to send them paperwork for them to approve your domain name.
And so I didn't, it took like 24 hours,
but that's the thing is I can get a globally unique identifier,
you get the,
you know, curl.org
boom.
OK. OK.
Now,
I want to tie this kind of back to name spaces because
I know like we discussed name spaces in the past on this show
and name spaces can be a contentious issue because for example,
Russ doesn't use or want name spaces.
That's fine,
right? That's up to rust. They run cargo that, that's their own thing.
And so
the the kind of purpose of the DNS isn't even so much
to like create this weird name space universe where we're saying like,
absolutely yes, owner, not owner kind of stuff, right?
It's really just meant to be a way of creating a unique identifier.
There's like no reason
a packaging ecosystem would want to even use like a name space for a pack.
Here's the funny thing.
Why couldn't we have the best of both worlds where picking on rust?
For example, Russ says, hey, we do not do name spaces, but the package format will be
your DNS which you have to prove control of and then
whatever the heck you want, which suspiciously sounds like package urals.
But that's see we can have the best of both worlds.
Now where we can have name spaces that are unique
by using DNS as part of that name space.
And now you can have two or more
security packages because you'd have like bresser.net/security and
cre.org/security.
-- I,
-- I don't think Russ wants that though.
Well, and, and maybe they don't want that and that's fine. But I'm saying
it is, this is an example of where you can architect the centralized database
to sort of allow for more decentralized
-- central.
-- Ok. Let me, let me give you a better example.
Maybe to try to click because this is like this is really hard.
Imagine you have a package in rust called security.
You know, you do what is a crate install?
There's a cargo, I don't remember anymore right now.
But anyway, you installed the package security, right?
That's fine.
And that's how we'd want to,
we wouldn't want to have to make you type in some
super long package URL to do an install of a package,
whatever.
But the intent is then the
question, why not?
Because humans do this work and humans don't want to type in long things, they can
cut and
paste whatever. No,
let's say you install your package, right?
The idea isn't
that the human installing dependencies
is going to have to remember big long strings. The intent is that if I
generate a pearl from this thing,
I get the long pearl that includes like the
DNS and all of that other stuff because what I
want to make sure is I want to make sure that if I use cargo to install a crate
or I download the crate off of the internet,
I want the same
package identifier for both of those things because they are the same thing.
Now you can add additional information that says like I installed this with cargo.
I downloaded this off the internet. I found it under my rug, whatever.
But fundamentally, I want the ability to be like these three things are the same,
but I got them in different ways.
Well, and see, I think maybe this is part of the problem is
the traditional framing of this is
software and package identification. When what we're really saying is
we need software and package identification
and also
delivery life cycle identification.
Like
for example, if I buy something, if I buy a diamond ring,
there's a big difference between having it delivered by secure courier
and them saying like, you know, well,
actually mailing the post is actually really safe, so bad example.
But the point is
I want both,
what is this? But how did it come to be here?
Because for example, it might only be available through github
or maybe it's widely available through other things, right?
And that matters if it, if the github
thing goes away,
I need to find a new delivery method for it. I need to find a new way to get
it
right.
But I need
to
have that history of. I used to get it from github
and this is what it was.
-- I
-- think you have exited the space of package
identifiers now and you're on to a different problem.
Well, but the problem is they are sort of so tightly entwined
that you're saying that we need this. Well, that, but they're entwined because
there are people, for example, that are allowed to go run curve,
but they are definitely not allowed to download it from China and install it
perfectly fine.
Everything's fine, it's fine, you know,
and checks some doesn't match, it's fine,
don't
ignore it. And I think that's part of the problem though is we have to
acknowledge that it's not just about the software anymore.
It's there are other factors that some people have to consider. And I think they
common enough now
-- that we probably need to think about them as an industry.
-- Not yet. Not yet.
I think you're too far in the weeds.
And I think this is one of the challenges that comes with software identification.
And I'm glad we got here accidentally because I didn't even write
this on my list of things I wanted to talk about is
when we start
trying to do these identifications and because it's
literally corner cases all the way down,
we end up getting bogged down in all these weird details that
are important,
but we have to solve the hard.
Well, I shouldn't say hard, we have to solve the easier problems first
and then we can get to the corner cases.
But I think when we have discussions like this,
we only talk about the corner cases and then nothing gets done.
This is where I give Pearl a lot of credit because I think
Pearl has done a nice job of focusing on not the corner cases.
Granted there are many
but they, for the most part I think have have said let's not obsess over these.
See, my take on this is a lot like my take on the papers we produce at the CS A where
I want to at least acknowledge the corner cases and say, hey,
are you aware of this corner case because you might not
care or it might be like really central to what you do
and and that's fair and I may not be able to give
you an answer as to what to do about the corner case,
but at least consider it.
I
have considered it.
And then the second thing I would say is
I would like ideally for
these things like package URL S or whatever to have some like if nothing else,
at least have a notes field or have some sort of thing where I can jam in
some freeform data because
we did this with http headers where http headers are.
There's very few http headers that are actually RFC S
and the way http headers work is if enough clients and enough servers start
supporting them and treating them the same way it becomes a de facto,
not deo
but de facto standard because,
well, I mean, these other five web browsers support it, I guess we have to do
and I would like to see
that provides also a very
um sort of market driven consensus mechanism
where you can say looking at PR L data.
Oh, like 20% of them have this new field that you know, we're all using. OK, cool.
Let's maybe have an actual discussion about it or maybe not just start using it.
-- So
-- OK.
Yes, this is an excellent point. And I think it's an interesting topic because
I feel like this is something you see
in a more open environment. Like like
like sure Os V is another good example.
Like those are functionally open source projects is what they are,
they directly caused it to be extended.
Like I got four or five things in there that I wanted.
And here's the thing like something like
something like C pe or
sw I,
-- those are like committee standards documents, those
-- are cathedrals,
they, they are and it's very hard to see change. And
if you're not using it the way they say you have to use it,
you often get pushback that says you're doing it wrong,
right.
There's no discussion like you're just doing it wrong
because of what you're doing isn't written down here.
And I think like, you're talking about that organic growth,
that's a really powerful tool.
Any time you have some sort of like widely used feature because like,
hashtags are a great example, like Twitter didn't have hashtags at the beginning,
people just started using them and someone's like, oh, this is neat.
-- Let's do this, right.
-- And then the funny thing is, for example,
you know, anything with a dash and it's like, oh dang it,
that doesn't work with hashtags oh Well,
I
know
and I literally at one point proposed changing the,
the identification standards so that it would work with the Twitter hashtags
and
getting some very violent
push back on it. But I'm like
this.
Well, like hashtag log for J that's how we coordinate log
for
Jay. It is
and it's what makes the horrible like
like boutique identifiers so valuable now is because you can hashtag them.
-- But anyway, anyway, unless there's
-- a dash in them,
but you just take the dash out then it's fine. No,
and I've seen people do that. It
makes me happy.
But you know what I mean? Like, I think
the the organic growth of this stuff is really what I mean,
this is what made open source amazing, right?
-- Is the organic nature of it.
-- If you don't allow organic growth,
chances are somebody is going to do organic grow
and possibly
like metastasize and become huge really fast.
Like, like the proprietary software world versus the open source world, right?
Like we have the Halloween memos from uh Microsoft 20 some years ago now.
And now I'm, you know, running Linux on my windows desktop.
But that's the thing is like C pe and SW
I and things like CV E are
becoming less relevant because, well,
they are less relevant because people have moved on and created better,
more workable solutions for themselves that are
actually starting to become industry accepted,
right?
And because I don't have a choice because my choices are I can use CP or Swid
and kind of get half a solution
and get told I'm doing it wrong and not be allowed to extend it or change it
or I can,
you know, do package URL S and just, oh, we, we're done
like let's go have lunch,
I made it do what we wanted.
And I'm looking at like what your company
does and what all these asphalt companies are doing
and obviously some of them are doing things like sw because they, you know,
have to work with Microsoft or have to work.
They want to support the US government and that's fine.
But for basically everybody who's not the US government or
supporting the US
government as a customer.
So this is an interesting topic as well, which I won't dwell on because we're,
we're nearly out of time.
But like
the US government doesn't really care about C PE S for example, or
SW, I for the most part, like, even though SW I is technically a n
thing,
all of the government documents basically men,
Cyclone DX and SPDX vastly more, I mean,
occasionally SW I is thrown in but it's not very common, I don't think.
And C PE is the same story where like NVD publishes C PE is
and like
at, at
Acor, we've been working as, as, quite as hard to,
to get away from C PE s because they're just,
they're terrible and they're ineffective at what you need to do
in 25 years of consuming CV data at scale.
And by scale, I mean, I read every single CV up and through, I think about 2010
and then post 2010, I probably read or assigned about a quarter of them.
OK?
I almost never use C PE
like I use CP maybe 100 times in 25 years.
You
and what
like, so
it
like when I,
and when I worked for like eyesight and
I defense where we were consuming all the vulnerabilities
-- across everything. Well, and
-- you were building a bespoke, bespoke database.
Right.
Yeah. Back to this. I think the thing is to remember is it's, it's
the other thing is people tend to look at this from the supply side
and say, OK, the open source community wants this,
the close source community wants this, the, it people want this
and they ignore the demand side,
the consumers who also have different and unique needs.
So even though the open source world is like, OK, perfect example,
if the open source world tomorrow did
100% correct, perfect package URL
data,
there's still a bajillion companies that would be like, yeah,
but we need cyclone or uh sw
or whatever
and, and a company like yours would be like, OK,
let's meet that need and build a translation tool.
Uh Right.
Right.
And so that's the other problem is people forget that this
is a many to many problem with both suppliers and consumers.
And the worst thing of all is
and then that giant mix in the middle, that is both.
Well, there's, there's other unique aspect of this.
I'm not going to talk about today, but like
from your many to many angle,
when you're an open source project,
you probably don't care or want to care about generating pearls for your project.
Like who cares? Not my problem.
And so this comes back to that issue of I need the ability to look at a thing
-- and make a pearl from it because there isn't like an official pearl.
-- And this leads to
the last thing I want to say, which is
no matter how perfect or widely done this thing is
there will always be a relatively common case of I need to
assign my own identifier because either there is no identifier currently.
So I need to assign one
or the,
the identifier they assigned is wrong.
It's mapping into multiple things happens all the time.
And so again, the problem is no matter
what we do with these standards
and implementations,
there will always be the relatively common case of
I need to unpack this software using my own tools and
figure out what is actually in it because for example,
I gripped it and there is definitely a lock.
Oh for example XML hash dos,
I was gripping code and finding XML hash
dos
all over the place
because people put it in open source so that it compiles on windows
and
but they don't list that it's in there because they cut
and paste like uh it's a couple 100 lines of code.
That's
right.
And so no matter what happens,
there is always this common case of I need to do this myself,
either for myself or for my consumers, my downstream.
And
that can also be internal like a company like Sony or something.
They're so massive internally that they are definitely generating
software that they then internally consume and need SB
for.
And so no matter what we do with all of these standards and implementations,
there's always this common case of I have to do
it myself because it's either wrong or it's incomplete or
I tried to get it fixed and they refused or
and again, this goes back to this, well, this isn't really a corner case.
This is a pretty common case
and so regardless of what we do,
whatever we do needs to have this on ramp for people to do it themselves, for sure.
For sure. 100%. Yep. Yep. I agree.
All right, I'm gonna, I'm gonna call this one there. I think that's a good end.
Thank you, Kurt. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to open source security, podcast.com. Head up the show notes, UZ pound.
Oh, it says podcast. Hashtag Find us on Mastodon. Kurt.
Have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye.