Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself, Kurt Seefried
and my partner, not causing any harmful interference and accepting interference.
Josh Bresser.
Oh my goodness, whatever we are here with Alex
Cogan, the Chief operations officer and co-founder of Flipper devices,
which are the folks behind Flipper Zero,
which is like the greatest hacking device known to man by far.
So Alex, welcome to the show, man. We are so excited to have you here.
Thanks for such a great introduction guys and thanks for inviting.
All right, so let's just set the stage.
I'm going to assume not everyone listening knows what a flipper zero is.
So I will let you tell us all about the flipper zero.
Flipper zero is a fun looking device which is uh we call it in marketing like a Tama
goji for hackers.
But uh actually, it's like a serious multiple device we
packed with various uh access control system
like RFC NFC RF ID,
infrared and so on.
And it's used
for uh education purposes for cyber security research purposes,
for development purposes.
It's fully open source,
it's customisable, you can build models for it,
you can build your own firmware for it.
You can build uh apps for it
and just Tinker with these technologies as much as you want. It's uh
pretty popular nowadays, especially in a Tik Tok area
among
the
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Tik Tok,
we've got like, I think a billion views like totally
uh
uh with
a, with a hashtag flipper zero.
It's like, I guess it's the main marketing platform for us at the moment.
I'm too old for Tik Tok, so I don't know.
Yeah. Yeah,
people love it generally. It's
put it simply like a Swiss army knife when you have like a bottle opener, uh knife,
scissors, everything
but
in like small, small body,
it doesn't do anything of, of those things good. Right?
It's not a good knife, it's not a good bottle opener, but it's all packed together.
So Flipper Zero is pretty much the same.
That's actually one of the reasons I bought it is because
when I first saw it come out, it came out. I was like, oh, that's cute. And
I kind of quickly looked into like kind of what's the parts cost like,
what would it take to actually build one myself?
And the answer is it's actually quite cheap to buy the parts and build it yourself.
But then you have this like mess of wires crap that like
doesn't have a nice interface. No. Really? Right. Like it's like
a,
you know,
there's a reason people buy prebuilt P CS and stuff.
Like, just sometimes you want a thing that's in a plastic case that doesn't,
you know, constantly break because the wire gets snagged.
And I actually use mine mostly for like, diagnostics.
Like I love buying diagnostic tools, like multi meters, uh digital calipers,
all that stuff.
Like I like being able to measure things because it makes it
so much easier to troubleshoot them.
And one thing like that I'd never really thought about is like,
I had a software to find radio receiver for my laptop, right?
Which is great. It can like, listen to all the radio things,
but it can't transmit. And so
for certain types of troubleshooting, especially in radio, you have to transmit,
you have to interact with the device.
And that's one thing where the flipper where I'm like, oh,
it like sends or it receives and sends.
Like you said that, that
I think there's about five major technologies in it.
Like near fill contact infrared radio.
It's on the website,
I'll put it if you just go to the flipper zero
website and you scroll down maybe past what the top is.
It, it lists everything it does and it is ridiculous. And it's amazing
that does many things.
And the beautiful thing is too. It's like the Raspberry Pi in that
there's that ecosystem now of all the people writing code for it.
So I don't have to because I'm lazy.
I
hate writing code
and that's the other thing that sold me on it is I realized like I can buy the flipper
zero and then just kind of wait for everybody else to do the work and I download it.
No really.
That's like 90% of my it strategy is wait for somebody
else to build it and then buy it from them.
I guess it's a strategy
for most of the developers who just like
stack
overflow
c face.
Like you never stop doing this no matter how senior you are.
It's, it's actually was like our,
like the original original idea when it was
like just sitting having a beer with my partner
Paul discussing things. And uh we like
uh we're looking for like product ideas and stuff and uh like the original idea
was just about that you pack all the like cyber security uh technologies you,
you usually need in the field, right?
If you like a person who sets up a um access control system in an office
and you have like a F ID or NFC cards
and uh you
uh want to like penetration test it, right?
Like to understand how safe it is, how, how easy it is to hack
and usually like cyber security professionals who does
it like the physical kind of stuff,
they don't have the tools that they don't have ready tools,
they just build them using Arduinos,
Raspberry Pis, bunch of models, bunch of fires
and it just simply unreliable so you, like, you build this stuff,
you put it in your pocket or you put it in your backpack,
it gets, it gets messy and uh it just doesn't work like after 12 times.
So the original idea just was centre around this, like we need to do,
like we need to pack all of them.
Like it shouldn't be too complicated,
but it should be packed in one device
and it should be reliable, easy to use and with the screens with the buttons,
you know, like pro production quality.
And after that, it evolved with a like playfulness,
tama
goa cheese and everything else. Just you know,
it's a small thing, but I love that. It's not a box like it's got that kind of
kind of Star Trek,
whatever. I don't know what to call that shape like that kind of science fiction
angle shape.
No, I like it.
It's it's comfortable in the hand and it's not just like a little rectangle.
Alright. Alright. So
let's let's
you mentioned some of the history of this Alex. So I'm
I'm curious
like how long are we talking from, you know,
you and friends talking in a pub until a
flipper zero being released because I'm sure this,
this almost certainly took some time and I'm sure there's some crazy anecdotes
along the way.
Yeah, that's the show.
So I I think like our original conversation I mentioned it was like
October 2019.
Oh man, that's like
something was about to happen, I think in October.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, you see
where
it was going
and uh we published our first article about the device.
So the strategy was like we need to like idea
sounds cool to us, but when
there like a market for it and so it is like people who wants it
and there's enough people.
And so in December we prepared like the, you know, the first designs,
it was very far from what we have now, but
it uh showed like it's uh
uh showcase the idea and what we device looks like. And uh what can I do?
And we published it in uh December, I think,
and uh the reaction was like good enough for us to pursue this idea further.
But then of course COVID ca me and uh that's
messed with our plans a bit because like most of our
prototyping stuff and everything was in China.
All the logistics stop lockdowns, we cannot go out. But the like the situation was
not like in favor of us because like we had another businesses at
the point and uh all the businesses wasn't like performing good enough.
So that,
that's why we were like looking for product ideas
because we decided that like service business is like,
doesn't work for us anymore
or we are like, not good at it.
And we're like, ok, let's do products,
products sounds much more fun and more like suitable for um our ways of doing.
And so we like, we, we pushed like all, all the resources we had to it.
And by
July 30th, we launched a Kickstarter campaign. We uh
we raised uh around $5 million. It was like a huge success, very
unexpected. Like we, we had some numbers, right?
You can calculate depending on how much, like how many leads you have,
how like uh people react and
all,
but the numbers were like, not even close to what we've got after that.
Yeah. And um,
so the company was like 30 days
and then we,
we needed to actually like to finish developing
those stuff because we had the prototype,
right?
But like,
I don't know how much, you know about Kickstarter, but
when I actually saw it on Kickstarter, I was like, oh, I want this but then like,
it almost sounded too good to be true.
And I've like, I've seen a lot of hardware on Kickstarter just,
it doesn't work. Yeah.
And so I, I didn't actually fund the Kickstarter
and I waited for it to actually be released,
which then was very annoying because it was sold out in Canada for a
very long time and I had to wait quite a while to get one.
Ok? I just pulled up your Kickstarter.
It says 4.8 million pledged of $60,000 goal.
So you beat that a little bit, a little bit.
Well, 6060 60,000 was like optimistic.
You usually like you usually in Kickstarter you do like you go,
you lower your goal a little bit because just because of the
uh to, you know, to me
up is a Kickstarter algorithm.
Like, because like if you, if you reach your goal pretty fast,
it gets you up on a like main page, it gets you.
Uh
so more people see it. So we put like 60,000. It was like,
you know, the minimum, the bare minimum, like you just like make a few devices,
send it and you forget about it.
But you like basically did more like a few 100,000 for any serious enough device.
Serious enough consumer electronics.
That's what always gets me when I see when I see these so called quote un,
quote simple devices.
Yeah,
you have to make tens or hundreds of thousands
of them to actually make money doing it.
And it's like that, I'd find that terrifying.
-- Yeah. Yeah,
-- exactly.
So that's,
that's a plastic injection molds like tens of thousands of dollars depending on
the device can be hundreds of thousands of dollars depending on the device.
And the factory you work with plus chip shortage at the moment with the COVID and all.
It's like just terrible. It's the wild west because you cannot get any cheap.
-- Yeah,
-- because you're like the cars in the washing machine
guys where like one missing chip in the device
may not work at all or have really limited functionality.
Yeah. Yeah, exactly. So it's
-- like,
-- yeah, we'll just ship it without the screen. No big deal.
Yeah.
So,
so nowadays everybody design devices using like they
have this problem in mind right now,
right?
They remember it happened.
So you have like an alternative to pretty much everything, right?
Except maybe MC U or CPU, you have,
it's like an integral part but you just secure it as uh as uh as much as possible.
But everything else should be like hot
swappable with two or three alternatives.
That's what we were doing like in process like
just changing it and uh finding new ones.
But
like,
so this is what was crazy at some point.
We so we have the screen and it's like a sandwich produced by some factory,
but it's consists of like controller
unit, it consists of uh
uh other other parts and this controller,
it's like it, it's uh just in one day, they just canceled it,
they were producing it and they were like, OK, we have a shortage, we had a newer one.
We need to allocate this uh production uh production capabilities.
We have to the newer one. So the old one, we just cancel it right now.
And so uh we just lost the, the display
in one day and we had to finance the
development of the same display with this new chip.
But this just illustrates how, how crazy it was at the moment like everything
were like falling apart in process. You were developing it.
So it was crazy.
Unbelievable.
Ok. I, as much as I would love to dwell on, on how we got to where we are today.
The, the actual reason you're here
and this is where I'm completely blaming Kurt for all of these problems
is
the flipper Zero has been in the news a bit lately for things that can't do
that. It's being blamed.
Not, I would say hilariously, but I'm sure it's not hilarious for you at all.
Kurt trying to raise his finger and interrupt ha ha Kurt. It's your fault.
Technically, if you take it apart and rewire the whole thing, it can
potentially do what the Canadian government claimed. It does.
But this is also true of like
dishwasher.
Right.
Exactly.
I'm gonna rewire my dishwasher to steal cars very practical.
And just,
and so,
and
so the reason car theft is such a big problem in Canada
right now is it is a big problem in Canada right now.
But the justice minister had her car stolen now three times in three years.
And so now it's actually a problem affecting
the people who kind of run the country and the justice system.
And so now it's officially a problem that we have to, you know,
we must do something about, it's in the news and everything.
Right.
And so that's basically to put it bluntly,
that's why car theft and the flipper Zero thing all started blowing up in Canada
is,
yeah,
largely because the justice minister's car got stolen three times in three years.
Oops.
Ok, Alex, why don't you like, lay it all out there for us?
Tell us all the, all the silly things going on and all the, all the, I guess, blame
-- that flipper Zero seems to get here.
-- Yeah.
So the Minister of Science Innovation and Industry, I think
uh th they, they held this uh car
summit right? Because you guys got 100,000 cars stolen each year,
which is crazy.
And um
yeah, he ca me out and he said uh well, you know this f Flipper Zero device.
Well,
we're gonna ban it and they basically put a blame on us that like 600,000
cars got stolen because Flipper Zero ca me out like in uh t 2020 2021
or something.
And uh uh he uh blamed us on something that Flipper can't actually do cause like
uh Flipper can't
help you steal any car produced after 19 nineties
because like we cannot
do rolling oats which is like very ancient technology,
but
they accused us to visit and um
yeah, it was hilarious. It was insane. It was stupid. You can call it any anyhow. But
what we think is like very, it's very weird, you know,
because you say it's like the minister of justice get free cars,
cars stolen So like if you wanna address the problem, you should do it properly,
right?
But uh addressing
was like super populistic like let's plan this little toy
for $100 because it gets 100,000 cars to we we never
like sold enough units in Canada to get so much car stolen. You know.
-- Well,
-- and what really, to be blunt,
what really proves that it's not your fault is the, I forget what the name is,
is essentially the Canadian Insurance Institute or whatever.
It's the, you know,
the conglomeration of insurance companies here basically said,
yeah, no, that's not the problem.
The problem is the cars are too easy to steal and the carmakers need to,
you know, have the
microchips and the keys and you know, the lock codes and
that so that,
yeah, you can't steal them easily.
And so like even like to put it bluntly when
the insurance companies say the correct security solution is this,
they're usually they're the ones with the data.
Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah,
they,
and they're also the ones on the hook for paying for it. So
-- they tend to actually say what will work.
-- Yeah. Yeah,
I guess more problem is like the export procedures because all
these cars that get exported out to like uh Mina region,
North Africa,
Middle East. But if you can like actually steal a car and export it so easily,
it's like, it's like organized crime style.
Like you got some regulation problems.
It's like, not about the device.
It's kind of a public secret in Canada that the gangs,
the organized crime runs the ports in Montreal
and are exporting like CBC.
Literally a few weeks ago, did a,
an investigative thing where they went to Africa and they found
Canadian cars with like Canadian license plates still on them,
you know, like parking takes for like Toronto parking lots and stuff because yeah,
like, what are you going to do?
Like, phone the local cops and be like, hey, I found a stolen car from Canada. Like,
why, why are you bugging us?
Right.
And so, yeah, they found thousands of cars being shipped out of the port of Montreal,
for example.
Um, they just recently, you know, they ended up, uh,
seizing about 600 of them over a period of a while,
but no arrests were made.
Like,
and so it's kind of an open secret in Canada that we
have a very significant organized crime slash car theft problem because like,
well, there's money to be made there and it's nobody's getting arrested for it.
So it's like,
yeah,
it is what it is.
And yeah, it's definitely not the flipper. Zero's fault.
And what's really fascinating to me is they
then the Canadian government to save face.
I don't know if you saw, but they walked it back and said we're now going to target, uh,
you know, the unauthorized use or the illegal use of the flipper zero.
So kind of like burglary tools. Like I own a crowbar, I own a sledgehammer.
These are legal to own.
But like if I'm walking around at three in the morning with them and there's,
you know, cars being broken into,
I'm going to be arrested for possession of burglary tools.
You know, even though they are like, you buy them at Home Depot or Lowe's or whatever.
And I think that's still, I don't know, I, what I keep coming back to is like, they,
it's not even shooting the messenger.
It's like you basically,
well, and it's not like you even showed that it was insecure you're to, doesn't even
break into these systems
and yet, yeah, they're holding you responsible for it.
-- Yeah,
-- exactly.
I don't know.
We, we, we don't, we don't know exactly what, what they mean by, like,
not banning but restricting the use to legitimate actors.
Like, would it mean what you said it means or would it mean like a separate
licensing?
We don't know yet?
They don't respond to our questions so we like, can, can, can tell you right now.
Well,
and somebody pointed out like you can buy all the
components to essentially build your own flipper zero for like,
tens of dollars and solder it together.
It's right. There's,
there's the secret sauce of the flipper.
Zero is a very common secret sauce of you guys. Made it nice and easy
and it just works like you open up the box, you turn it on. No, that's it like you,
that's it.
I, that's, I loved it when I, you know, I literally opened up the box,
turned it on and I'm like
bloop. Oh, cool. And, you know, tried scanning the cat to find out what his number was
but he was too fat. I couldn't find it.
I, I want to
interrupt when all of this went down. Flipper Zero.
Put a, like animated GIF on Twitter where you used what AAA bit of wire and a head
jack to functionally show how to sniff car codes of the I, I'm curious,
like it's an amazing example.
Who did it?
I don't even know what to ask here other than like,
it was freaking awesome and good job.
Thank you. It's our team's work. Like we were brainstorming.
Like, how can we show them in most absurd way
that you can
use any
piece of electronics,
any piece of modern electronics right now and use it to actually catch a signal,
copy it and like hack it in the Canadian government's understanding.
Yeah. One of the ideas was like, what if we just cut it like piece of uh
with a 3.5 millimeter de and uh try to catch a,
like a red signal cause like basically it's an antenna, right?
It's like a, just a, just a normal antenna
and if you cut it like on a uh right lens,
you can catch a signal on the right frequency which we did.
And actually the sound card of the computer,
it catches it as a sound. So you can see the spikes if you like filter it
off,
you can actually decode the signal
inside.
Use some s uh software for radio signals which will trans
uh w which will transform it to like uh the code,
right?
Zeros and ones.
And that would be the same signal as Felipe zero
signals.
That, that's a great example. I loved it too.
Like, because it a big congrats to the team for Friday night. It was great.
It's so, I've no lie.
Watch that gif I bet more than 20 times because
it's just so utterly amusing every time I see it,
that actually brings up a good point.
I'm kind of wondering if,
maybe that's part of the problem is like
capturing and decoding and signals processing 2030 years ago
was like tens of thousands of dollars of equipment, you know,
like I had a friend who actually bought an oscilloscope that
cost as much as a car back in the day.
And now you can get those things for like 70 bucks and they plug into your ipad,
you know,
and I think maybe that's part of the problem is that like,
the radio technology went from, you know, tens or $50,000 to sure.
Here's like a little 100
-- thing that does all of them
-- I think you're on to something,
but I don't think you're barking up quite the right tree.
And, and this is kind of the question for Alex.
I think in terms of we'll say very next gen hacking devices. Flipper zero is
by far the most advanced and probably in the very front of the pack.
And we can look back in time. There were hacking things, you know, like you had meta,
you had various cult of the dead cow utilities, there was like back orifice.
There's been
any
an enormous number of technologies that have always taken blame
as being somehow bad and they're going to ruin
the world and they're going to corrupt our Children.
But the reality is
all of these things that happened in the past are
easily responsible for some of our,
we'll say improved security because it's always very cat and mouse,
right where Flipper Zero is now created an environment
where organizations with terrible security
have to fix it because it,
it's just like you a five year old can use this stuff to like hack, you know,
terrible RF ID usage or, or, or whatever NFC S and so
this I think is
the
amazing thing Flipper Zero is doing for society.
But I'm also curious on your thoughts on this because
I think we're going to look back in 10 or 20 years
and we're going to see that Flipper Zero was directly responsible for cleaning
up a whole bunch of lazy and terrible security we have today.
Yeah. Yeah, exactly.
That's what's, uh that's, that's uh how we formulate our like, you know,
um mission that we have kind of
that like to,
to increase the awareness of like the importance of cyber security around you.
Cause like all the, all these digital systems around you
everywhere you use them every day, you go to Metro, you use your card,
you open your office door, you open your car, you open your
front door. It's like everywhere.
But we, we never think how vulnerable or how secure it is, right?
So we think about that you need to change your uh door keys,
time to time because it's like, you know,
the security got better and stuff. People like lock picking.
So you, you buy a new one
but people like, especially like in Canada and us,
they like they have garage doors and stuff
and it's like installed in 2019.
And then you don't even think about it that it can be vulnerable.
It can be easily hackable and stuff. And it's like
if these things can be hacked with $100 device,
it doesn't mean that it's like, yeah,
the
the device is uh crazy good or crazy sophisticated.
It's $100 device with the off the shelf components. Nothing too crazy.
It just popular enough. So if you know about it now
and that brings me back to the
tt
point Right. We like it, it got so mainstream now.
Everybody, like, seen Flipper a t, some point
and it makes people think about it. Oh, ok. If there's so many flippers around,
like, shouldn't I get one and check my garage door or my,
uh, car or something? And
how, how safe it is. Can it hack it?
And you actually play with it?
You, you like it, it's fun to, it's just fun and cool to use, right?
You like catch a signal and go wow, what is this?
Like the signals are all around me
uh every day, all the time, but I never like thought about it.
I never catched one and now you can do it and you can think like, what is this?
Why is this? How does it work? Is it safe? Is it not safe?
And that's, that's uh and um
yeah, the the we we were really happy and surprised about the
uh support we got after the Canadian ban, right? Because like all the cyber security
uh community in Canada and not in Canada, they just raged about it. Like the thing is
not, cannot even do this. And plus you're just making our lives
uh much harder to get like the devices like this and
you get the awareness of people about cyber security much lower,
right? So like the bad actors are always there.
Bad actors use much more sophisticated devices they buy on
black market and Canada doesn't do anything about it,
basically
use them to steal your cars.
But you never would know about it. You never think about it.
And you,
if you buy also like popular small $100 toys
that helps you to understand how it works.
You will be more vulnerable than before. Right?
Because you will be like, oh my God, what is this black magic? How did it seal my car?
So, I think it's very, very important
that people actually think about it. Right?
It's like with the internet, we know that there's fishing,
we know that there's like http S and stuff, we know we, we need to
secure things.
Otherwise our data got stolen. Otherwise we get our bank accounts hacked.
But be because only because it gets,
it gets happened like people get the security better.
So this is the same thing with the access control system around us
and, and look, everyone knows what it is. I've got teenage kids and
so I'll, I'll, I'll tell you my story.
Actually, I bought a flipper zero, not for any of the, the radio magic. It did.
I was at a, a hacker conference called Cipher
Con and they have got these like overly complex badges
and people hack on them and all this stuff.
And I was sitting at a table with some people working on it and
this guy takes out his flipper zero and the badge did you art.
And so he was using the
UAR reader on the flipper zero. I'm like, oh, holy crap. That thing does you art.
But then it has, like, a little,
someone wrote an oscilloscope app for it and he was looking at signals.
I'm like, holy crap. The things got an oscilloscope in it.
Like I'm in and I ordered one, like, on the spot right there because I was like, this,
like this, that's what I want.
I don't care about the radio, stuff.
Like, I'm, I'm too dumb for radio but, like, you are an oscilloscope. I'm in
and, and, but anyway, I, I get it and, like,
my teenage kids and all their friends are like, oh, you have a flipper Zero?
That's amazing. I'm like, how do you, how do you even know what this thing is? Like?
-- Exactly.
It's, it's, yeah, it's, everyone knows that. It's awesome.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, young people love it a lot.
A lot of the times, like, people buy it, like, they see it on Tik Tok,
they buy it just because it looks cool.
They don't know what it is. Exactly.
And how to use it and they just, like, come to our Discord.
Hey, guys, I just, like, purchased. It just got the thing looks very cool.
I love the dolphin. But what I can actually do with it,
can you help me out?
And then people, like, uh, do you have any, any NFC cards on you or something?
And you know, people start exploring, start understanding how these things work.
So like it's, it's very, it's very,
it's very good for uh works great for education purposes
because it gets people really into it because it,
like, just looks cool.
It feels cool
and uh it helps to uh gather young people around it and uh make them educated.
That's, that's
what we
need that
because one thing I've been noticing is
young people nowadays don't have computers that they can take
apart or rather you can take an ipad apart once,
-- right?
-- And then it's just done,
right?
And part of it too is like, it's subtle things like they're all waterproof now,
which means they're all glued together to be waterproof.
Right? There's no screws
and, and the flipper zero.
No,
you're not pulling the old man on this cart because we
have raspberry pies and all this stuff like we never did
well. But, but technology by default used to be user serviceable
and now it's,
you have to look for user serviceable technologies.
You have to look for, you know, things that actually like the flipper zero or like,
like, because you guys published the Schematics,
right? Like,
as far as I know, like every single technical thing is available off your website.
I remember browsing it quick and I was like, oh, that's ok. They published
all the Schematics and everything neat. Like
there's the alternative firmware
you can
run.
Yeah, I'm pretty sure Samsung's never gonna do that for my TV.
No,
no. All right. All right. We're coming to the end,
Alex.
I'm gonna give you the last word on this one.
So, like,
is there anything you want the listeners to know about Flipper
devices or Flipper Zero or you kind of anything going on
and feel free to blame Canada as much as you want
for this part of it and it's completely Kurt's fault.
-- We
-- don't,
we don't want to blame anyone
here. Like, uh I just want to like this, it's not the first band we face, right?
Do we have another band from Brazil?
Which is also really
hilarious because like I talked with them and uh but
basically that likes the same government body like telecommunications agency.
And we had like a long conversation.
I had like a three hour call describing to them like what it actually can do,
how it can do it then
stuff.
And uh they were like, OK, we're like, we,
we're not ready to permit it for sales because we
think like the Brazilian people a re not educated enough to
know all the, all the dangers. And I was like,
uh
yeah.
Uh but we actually came to the conclusion that OK, let's try to like, certify it.
But then they
uh like in process of certification because they, they had this ban.
I was uh uh contacting
the certification labs like Kay guys, we need like Brazilian certification, blah,
blah blah.
And they were like, uh we have this band here online,
we cannot do any certification while it's there.
And I, and I'm going back to a telecommunication agency and saying, like,
can you please remove the paper or just tell
this uh is this particular labs that's like,
uh disregarded?
And they just ignore me,
they just ignore me. Like after 10
labs, I just,
I just gave up. So like we're still
in Brazil. Another stupid example is uh Amazon who thinks we card skimming device
for some reason? Oh my goodness.
I think it might be noticeable if you tape one to the top of a
card reader
one day like this.
I don't know, but it,
it gets crazier and crazier because like recently just I think a month ago
uh Amazon bans
prototype ports which is like just where P CBS,
which are branded, branded by Flipper, we sell them and they ban them as well. So
I guess that's how Amazon works.
They just have a,
a building of legal people who are not technically educated in any way.
They just
bad news and they're like, ok, we're going to ban it
and there's no person to talk to. It's like no one, you just, you just send
messages to a black hole and you go somewhere
and you get another answer which says no,
you're still banned, sorry,
you can try to appeal again
and
we're in this situation. So like any big company or government is not
doing enough due diligence and like technology stuff,
they eventually um put their attention to us and try to bind us.
We're really happy and we're really thankful for the Canadian community,
everyone who signed the petition
uh for uh uh helping us to fight it.
And that Felipe is not actually banned in Canada just because of all of you guys.
It's great to see
and we hope
it's gonna, it's gonna
change something in people's minds,
in government minds and think more about these things that's useful
and needed for society than dangerous.
-- Yes,
-- indeed. Think of all the free advertising you get right.
All the stupid
politics.
Yeah,
I think you raise a really important point because
I cannot think of any other way that, like,
ham radio licenses are on the decline in North America.
Like,
people are not getting into radio because it's
just not kind of interesting and fun anymore.
Like, if I want to talk to somebody across the world
that's easy. Like we all have signal whatsapp telegram
a
million options online.
And like when it comes to radio, like,
yeah,
radio is kind of complicated and I would not want to try and have
a child build one of these from scratch that seems cruel and unusual.
And so giving them a flip or zero where they can interact with it. Program it,
yeah, I can't imagine any other good on ramp to becoming
like to understanding radio
and you can take care of the dolphin.
Dolphin is cool.
All right, I'm calling this one
man, Alex. This has been lovely. I want to thank you so much for being here. So,
thank you.
Thank you, Alex. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to up for social security podcast.com. Head up the show notes, Easy Pound
to Podcast. Hashtag on Mastodon, Alex and Kurt have marvelous rest of your days.
-- You
-- too. Thanks everybody.
Thanks everyone. Bye bye.