Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast
with myself, Kurt Siefried
and I'm legally obliged to disclose that I'm a Canadian citizen
and my not Canadian citizen partner, Josh Bresser.
It concerns me when you open a show like this because I know
you and you had this smile on your face when I hit record.
So they're like, I know you're up to something and I don't know what it is.
Well, just I'm going to remind people that under 12 fam,
273 point or this is not a contact.
So you don't need to report
listening to this podcast as a foreign contact.
But if you, if you contact us or you give us feedback on the show and we reply to you,
then you will probably need to report this as a casual contact.
I
see, I see
unofficial foreign contact.
So I get that sometimes when I have meetings with Americans when they find out.
Yeah, over the last 25 years,
I've intentionally developed a pretty neutral mid Atlantic
accent when they find out I'm Canadian.
-- Well, we had this on product security all the time. Product
-- security at Red Hat
was
not all Americans, there was a bunch of Americans,
-- it was
-- mostly not Americans.
Well,
because it's a global company and that's kind of how the
-- math works out
-- before we delve into some rat hole.
I want to
explain like, so we talked about Red Hat
and then we talked about like is open source dying,
which was one of the conclusions of Red Hat's actions.
And I want to tie up this bow
with some observations and understandings of just open source in general.
And one of those things is
there are now organizations gene mostly us based
that are asking questions about what countries
are the developers from working on this software.
And sometimes they're legally required to do so under the Foreign Sanctions Act.
That's
right. That's
right.
And it's, and this is what I love is when people are like, oh,
these companies are being jerks and it's like,
it's like trademark law,
I'm required to protect my trademark. I don't want to be a jerk.
But if I don't do this, I lose my trademark. That's right. That's
right. And same thing with like, you can't just violate foreign sanctions. And
hopefully Uncle Sam
-- would be like, oh, we understand it's fine not
-- just sanctions,
the country of China comes up consistently in these conversations of,
are there any Chinese developers
that are contributing to this software?
-- Yeah,
-- I mean, we've banned their telecoms equipment from Canada
so much so, but Now,
the cell phone companies are saying that the deployment of high
speed internet and cell phones in rural areas is delayed because,
well, I guess we have to go buy the more expensive stuff from Europe.
Well, and I'm sure those companies ramping up production isn't a
two month effort. It probably takes 2 to 4 for years is my case.
Right. Exactly.
So, anyway, ok, there's a lot for us to cover in this one. And I want to start with
measuring open source because I think everything is,
-- is rooted there
-- by lines of code.
That's how you measure it.
That's how you measure source code by lines of code. Everybody knows this.
OK? So there is a project
that is at the open SSF
that is called
scorecard.
OK?
And scorecard is trying to put together
a an automated list of things you can look
at an open source project is doing or not doing
and then basically give a score
like zero bad 100 good type thing, right? That's not exactly how it works.
You get the idea.
Yeah.
And this feels like a good idea,
right?
Where I want to be able to look at an open source project and say how good or bad is this?
Well, like I can get blamed to find out who wrote the code.
-- Why can't I get blamed to find out what country it's from
-- the the country to my
knowledge at this moment is not taken into account. But there are questions like,
how many developers does it have,
do they have Binaries checked into their G
repo that aren't for tests?
Because obviously, like you can run tests on Binaries, things like that.
But there's questions like, are, are they using C I?
Do they have a repo?
-- That,
-- that is one of the questions. Yes.
And if you don't, I don't think you can score very much,
but you get the idea right?
There's all of these things they look at and then
they try to make it decision based on that.
This also then lends itself to a question.
You asked me a couple of weeks ago, which is,
is A I generated code any different than a single project maintainer.
-- Mhm.
-- And I think it's not,
but
-- that's kind of a different story and,
-- and just to be clear,
let's completely ignore the copyright issue around A
I code because obviously that just makes things
so much complicated. Let's just magically pretend
-- that A I code is somehow acceptable from a copyright perspective.
-- It probably is.
But that's another, it's complicated.
Well, it also depends on knowing that it came from an A I and II.
I have a suspicion,
small suspicion that some developers may have used
A I to generate code and checked it in
and not disclose that they did that.
I
think this might have happened.
-- It, it almost certainly has, of
-- course,
at some point somebody's gonna do
an analysis of get commits of the period from November 2022 to now.
And they're going to look at all the developers that went from like
a normal amount of work to suddenly checking in twice as much code
right around chat GP T four being released.
Ok?
I'm going to give you like a 32nd licensing kind of overview here in the,
the way it's currently viewed a project will be say licensed Apache two.
Ok. Now, mind you as well, I'm not a lawyer.
So like, please don't get your legal advice from me or Kurt or
ever.
-- But
-- I think we're qualified to give recommendations on sandwiches.
-- Maybe
-- I do like sandwiches. But anyway, so a project might be like Apache two, right?
And so if you include say a bit of software
that is public domain and this happens all the time,
that bit of software is still technically public domain,
but it is part part of an Apache two license project, let's say.
And so it's generally understood that the project as a whole is Apache two.
If you know, for certain a piece of software is covered by say public domain,
you could extract that code
and use it
because you don't have to give credit for public for un copyrighted stuff,
-- basically,
-- right?
An example might be there's like so many implementations
-- of GS that floating around or XML
-- parsers,
some of which are public domain like Z
Lib is functionally unlicensed if I remember correctly. But anyway,
now when you have A I generated stuff
to date.
The copyright office in the United States has said A I generated content is not co
-- writeable, meaning it is functionally public domain work. Yeah,
-- that may
change.
And that's another thing is we're just assuming
an implicit us centric view of this problem.
I have that because I live here
but
I have that because I live
in
Canada
-- of our foreign trade with
-- you.
You're changed to us whether you like it or not.
That's
right.
But here's the thing, here's where it gets weird.
Let's say you generate a bunch of A I art,
right? Let's say you make 100 images.
The
the pictures themselves
are not covered by copyright,
but now you put them into a collection of
works you're calling Kurt's awesome A I pictures,
right?
The collection of work, the book you just made is copyrightable,
but the individual pictures are not.
So for example, if I reproduced your book in the same order,
you could make a plausible argument that I am violating your copyright
even though
it is all copyright free images.
Now, if I put them in a different order, I'm probably fine.
And so this is where it gets really weird and complicated and the
law has not fully weighed in on all of this stuff yet.
Well, I mean, it goes back to the phone book argument, right?
Where the phone book is copyrighted,
but the phone numbers and names and addresses are simple facts.
-- That,
-- that's right.
You can't exactly copyright.
That's right. That's right. Facts can't be copyrighted.
But if you put the facts in a certain order now you can copyright that. Exactly. Ok.
Ok.
So now the, the other piece of that though I want to touch on is
the question becomes, I'm using A I generated code,
how is A I generated code better than an open source project with one maintainer?
And I think it's not.
And here's my explanation behind that.
When we think of open source, we generally think of the
kind of larger commons
community universe where you have like
herd immunity.
I
call it, well, let's just call it herd immunity, right?
You have multiple developers, lots of users.
So you end up in a situation where let's say there is a security issue,
there is a backdoor,
there is something
some of the people will get hit by it.
But then we will, it's kind of like the immune system, right?
Like the virus kills some of your cells before your body realizes. Oh, holy crap.
We gotta go take care of this thing, right? In, in,
in a pandemic type situation,
a bunch of people get sick and die first and then we're like, oh crap,
we have to figure this out.
So anyway, if you have one open source developer, you could,
you could make the plausible argument
that people aren't looking at this. Right. There's not
-- eyeballs
-- and it's actually more subtle than that.
Not only are people not looking at this and there's not enough eyeballs
for the sake of argument if that developer is away on vacation.
How do you update the source code? Right. Right. Well, that's just it.
So, even if somebody is willing to write a patch and submit it now, what?
And, and for example, we've seen this happen,
like youtube DL is going through this right now where they've refused to
ship an update for months because apparently their C I CD system is broken
and it's also,
there's been a change in youtube's back end that
breaks the software. And so there's a one line patch you need to do to make it all work.
-- Oh, that's
-- right. You, you talked about this a couple of weeks ago
and so like, do we? Well, OK, if I fork it now, how do I tell the community? Right.
We, we talked about this on a previous show.
So I'm just going to point out that it's not,
it's not just about getting the one developer who
understands the code base to write a code patch.
You could have the code patch,
but you still need to get it checked in, you need to get a release cut,
you need to get a change log and notification to people and all that stuff done.
And
that's
where having more than one developer.
Well, that's just, that's just one developer, multiple users, right?
When you have A I generated code, you probably have one developer,
the A I and one user you and so there's going to be bugs and you're not
going to find many of them because you're not going to do the crazy herd immunity,
flexing of this code. You're going to exercise kind of the one thing you need to do.
And so that's where I,
I think anyone claiming that one developer open source is somehow
dangerous but then is willing to use A I generated code.
-- You are a hypocrite is my comment
-- there. I would extend that to also then
anybody that writes their own code is by definition a one developer code shop,
you totally are 100%.
And the thing is that's fine for internal stuff.
Like I have a bunch of shell scripts that an attacker can attack
like technically speaking youtube,
I guess could have hack me because I'm interfacing with youtube to download stuff,
but that's not gonna happen.
Right. Right. And, and
that's just
-- not a concern.
-- I, I think the other part of this is when you are developing software,
a software team of one while it exists
often is
not common where you're going to have someone else
using or testing your product which changes the dynamic.
Right,
-- hopefully is key.
-- But this is I think where A I takes off is it's the same
paradigm
of spreadsheets
in the sense of I have a bunch of data
that I need to manipulate to,
to create a chart
uh once a month for a report.
Now, I can go talk to my devs and they're a bunch of surly weirdos
and it'll never get done.
Or I can kind of jam the data up in a spreadsheet and kind of make it work myself.
And that's what people ended up doing by and large
and to the point now where
to put it bluntly,
the world's economy runs on a bunch of Janky spreadsheets
that the numbers may or may not be right?
-- It
-- always has, it always has.
I don't think this is an apt comparison in this context. I'm not saying A I is bad.
I'm just saying it has to be viewed in the proper context.
-- But
-- what I'm trying to point out is some people forget as much as they want to disown
the quality of A I
and users given a choice between getting something Janky and done
and scratching their itch
versus having to wait or talk to the devs or get a budget.
This is the topic that we were going to get to eventually,
right? Where
I'm going to throw the scorecard project under the bus a little bit here in
this context
and
when you are a developer or you're an organization doing something,
building a product, building a service, providing a service, whatever, right?
There's every, every company has their, their thing they do.
If you look at something like open source open SSF scorecard,
and you might say, oh, this open source project has a score of, of negative 12.
And it's obviously terrible.
You can't use it if it's the only library that does what you need it to do.
Your developers literally don't care,
they're going to use it and here's the thing and here's how this works out.
If you're a security person and you tell your developers,
you can't use any project that has a score less than this,
right?
And now this, this used to happen back in the days when open source was brand new
companies would say no
open source in the product
developers don't say,
oh I just won't use this thing that exactly solves the problem I have
-- just cut and paste. That's
-- right.
They find a way like life finds a way is exactly what happens here.
And so this is where I find the whole concept of what country is someone from?
Did A I generate this code? Is this project scoring? Well, on open source,
those are secondary questions to the question of does this solve the problem?
I have?
Well, it it, I mean, this is exactly like public health.
There are some things that we should all be doing like washing
our hands with soap once in a while brushing our teeth,
at least once a day.
Flossing. No, I'm serious.
-- Like
-- this is just brush your teeth twice a day, twice a day and floss, floss, once,
brush twice.
But I mean, I think if we could get everybody to brush their teeth once a day,
well, that would be a lot or brushing them that's currently going on. Probably
same thing with hand washing with soap.
We don't live in that perfect world and we can't make people do things. So then
I think the difference is now what do
harm reduction strategies look like where we accept?
Because the other thing that always drove me nuts about
this is I use a thing that has a dependency chain
and I can't tweak that dependency chain without horrifically breaking it.
Yeah, 100%. That's right.
My question I'm always wondering about is what does harm reduction look like. And so
uh a great example is,
well,
what if you get your devs to ship the product once or
twice a week as part of the normal just getting features out?
And now that means you have the capability of getting a security fix
out a lot quicker than if you only ship once a quarter.
Not necessarily, that's not true at all. OK? So I've got a great example of this.
I have a project I created that uses React. OK?
And I did the end,
there's a tool called NPX which I don't even know what that stands for.
But it, it will like
I could type like I think it's NPX something.
React something and it creates the initial skeleton project for me. OK?
I create a React project.
This is using the, we'll say current latest accepted versions of
React stuff and
I build my project
and
it installs 1500 dependencies.
And there are warnings from some of the dependencies that say things like this
dependency is deprecated and it is going to stop working in the future.
Like those are literally warnings when I do this. Now.
If you are a project, it doesn't matter if you're deploying multiple times a day,
you need to be upgrading everything constantly,
but you can't upgrade everything because everything is hidden behind
the 12 react packages that and turn into 1500 reactions.
Think well, yeah, react to stuff.
And so even if you say we're going to deploy once a day that guarantees nothing.
No, no, that's
not the point I was trying to make
the point I'm trying to make is I'm trying to get
my devs to build capabilities that actually benefit us beyond security
so that
it potentially has a security benefit.
It could selling people. I want to spend a million dollars a year
to go from a quarterly deployment of the software
to a monthly deployment of the software for security.
You will not get that million dollars.
I want to spend a million dollars to get our quarterly deployments down
to monthly deployments so we can get features out to paying customers faster.
-- Oh, now we're having a discussion
-- maybe.
-- I mean, a million dollars is still a lot
-- but,
but they're not going to say no right off the bat.
Right. That's fair. That's fair. They might say no later on.
But
there's now the potential for a discussion and,
and that's the kind of thing I'm talking about is like, I, I think about
natural disasters and stuff and for example, the electrical system,
we no longer have all these extra repair crews
where when you have hurricanes down in the US,
you have repair crews from Canada going down,
right? You kind of have these mutual aid agreements.
And so the theory is, well, hopefully,
you know, in the,
in the summer we have hurricanes in the US and in winter we have ice storms in Canada.
So in winter when there's ice storms in Canada,
we literally had repair crews from like Texas.
But thank you. It's, it's a heck of a drive
and it's chilly. So bring some warm clothes and, you know, we got you some sandwiches
and, uh,
that's a more efficient way of doing it and
trying to get an electrical company to be like,
oh, we'll just have 10% more repair crews, you know,
just in case for hurricane season,
-- that's not gonna happen. No,
-- no, for sure.
But
you know what, let's build a mutual aid
pact society across North America
-- that has worked.
-- I want you to tie this to Open SSF scorecard.
-- It goes
-- back to harm reduction. Open SSF is that historical of this project? Score
seven or Flipper
Gibbet or green or blue? Like, I don't even know what these numbers mean.
Right. That's, yeah, that's, that's part of it. No one knows.
There are also some projects where it's like, oh, they don't have a test framework.
Well,
does that really matter if it's like a
thing called American date that converts a date to an American date format?
No, I right. Like it matters for G zip and Tar Absolutely.
You need to have a horrific set of tests to make
sure you don't get all these weird bypasses in theory.
I mean,
that's the thing.
What does the scorecard even mean the thing I've never seen with the Os SF
is they don't actually do they give concrete advice on if the score is this,
then you need to do this?
Yes.
Oh, they do.
No, not, not in the sense of what the project needs to do, but the user needs to,
-- there's nothing for users, there's nothing users can do.
-- That's what I'm saying.
Like,
like they don't say if it scores below 20 never use the software.
No, they just say this is a 20
here's what you can do to increase the score.
-- But, and that's the thing, you can't give that advice.
-- Here's the other part of it.
That's really funny is most of the major
security events of the last probably 20 years
were in
projects that would have scored relatively high at
scorecard because the reality is they're well used
project like Log for J was in everything.
-- Log for J didn't have an amazing score, but they did a lot of stuff.
-- Right.
Well, it's just a part of a basic maturity.
It's, and see that thing,
it's not even security so much as just basic maturity of using C I CD pipelines.
-- Having tests, having a bug reporter.
-- Here's what I really want to know and no one's
on this yet that I'm aware of, take all these scores
and then look at like how much effort have these projects created
or how many problems have these projects created based upon the score.
My suspicion is the higher scoring a project is
the more impactful security vulnerabilities in an RT organization.
And so I think it's the inverse of it's easy to
say projects with low scores are bad for me to run
when
they're probably not good for a variety of reasons.
But I have a suspicion the score is completely irrelevant
-- in the context we think it matters in.
-- Let's take it to its logical extreme.
How would Microsoft and their software development
practices generally score with an OS F
scorecard? Well, basically 100% because
do they have a security team? Oh, yeah,
they have blue team, red team. They, they have a,
they have their own conference.
Right. Like,
they have a leader board of all the people finding bugs in
their products and yet Windows is still cranking out Microsoft Tuesday.
Yeah.
Right.
And is it, you know, are, windows, are some of these windows bugs impactful? Yeah.
A little bit.
That's just it.
That's what, that's what amuses me over things like this is
what value do these scores bring?
Now, I see this all the time though, where you talk to a company,
you talk to someone that's
looking to use open source.
They want like source composition analysis and they've heard that
we should be rating our open source or we'll,
we'll tie this into, we should know what countries
the developers are from that that are writing this open source, right?
Like these are things we want to know
and
-- the question
-- kind of,
I want a pony that's house stream, but we don't get what you want.
No. Look, you can kind of OK,
-- we'll, we'll get to that in a second. Let's just
-- ignore the gross GDPR violation.
That would be knowing where your source code comes from.
Well, not exactly, it's complicated. OK.
Here's what they want,
here's what they actually want. OK?
OK. First of all, let's touch on the idea of like
there are these scores, do they matter?
We don't know, we think they might,
this is where we get into the issue of an enormous amount
of what we're calling security today is what I call crap,
a smart person thought was a good idea.
There is no foundational research or proof into an enormous
amount of what we do is scoring open source.
A good idea. I, I can't say it is or isn't, does it seem like a good idea?
It absolutely does. Is it?
I don't know.
So one comment you don't need foundational research to, to say if this is good or bad.
But what we should be doing is like you said,
taking all these scores and all these projects
lining them up against all the vulnerabilities and saying like, well,
did this help or not?
So some things I would argue are
like having a source code repo that is public is probably very good for security.
Can I prove it? Well, I would have to do a bunch of research
and
I can't be bothered
and,
but the thing is you don't need foundational research to figure out like, oh,
we're gonna, you know, here's the medicine we need to use.
What you can do is OK. Well, here's a population.
Half of them wash their hands with soap,
half of them don't who gets more sick on average.
Oh, the people who don't wash their hands with soap. Ok.
So washing hands with soap appears to
and there's the problem though, there's correlation.
-- You don't know that it's causative though.
-- That's right.
Like, oh the people who wash their hands live near the pump full of cholera,
washing your hands makes you more sick. Everyone,
the people washing their hands with soap, live in a
big enough city to have a soap store.
Right.
-- Exactly. Exactly.
-- And thus public sanitation.
Right. And that's the thing. Like
it's, I, I feel like it would be really tough to find correlation
between some of these things. And
I think so again, this is why I go back to the well, are there reasons I can sell this
that are not security?
So for example, having a testing framework so that not for security,
but just so we break stuff less often and more importantly.
So you can confidently make changes to the software
and and
not break stuff
because that thing, once you have a really good testing framework,
you can add features like a
chimpanzee on drugs
and know if it's gonna make it worse or better.
That's our new name for A I now, right? Chimpanzee on drugs.
Basically,
it's what it is
hard,
it just doesn't,
you
-- know.
-- OK. OK.
Hold on.
Yes, I think you are correct. And I think
the challenge you see with something like scorecard is today,
the value in it is viewed almost exclusively as security.
This harkens itself back to the I think I talked about this a
couple episodes ago when I went to the open source summit in Vancouver,
I went to a salsa talk where where people will make claims,
extraordinary claims about some of these frameworks and some of these projects
and the reality is you can't back that up at all. And I think these claims are
probably dangerous.
All right. All right.
I want to move us on to the last bit, which is the,
who is writing the software you're using?
-- And there's two pieces
-- to this. They're all signed off, commits. It's fine.
They declared that they wrote it. It's all
good.
Yeah.
No, for real. Ok.
So from the legal perspective, basically,
what's being asked is does anyone with a.cn email address
-- committed to this?
-- They all have qq.com email addresses.
This this actually comes up a lot on the certificate authority mailing list,
for example, basically, apparently nobody from China can email Google
Bliss and vice versa.
Yeah. So they all use like
Wonky gmail.com accounts. Oh,
so they're literally using Gmail.
So you basically have no good way to determine if this person is from.
That's the thing I keep bringing up and they're like, oh, ok, shut up. It's fine.
And I'm like,
this is some random like literally there are
gmail addresses on the certificate authority mailing list
that have zero occurrences in Google search.
So I didn't know this.
So this is why those cas aren't mailing that list with their email
address because their email address can't get to where it needs to go.
You're saying,
I guess the great firewall of China or something
interesting. So, so ironically,
-- there's probably a low
-- now they're not spoofing it because every time it comes up,
they've managed to prove like by either putting in their Bugzilla entry or
one of them even said a DNS record saying like straight up this gmail.com account.
If you dig txt the C A, it's like this Gmail address is allowed to speak for us. OK?
But, but
when we're talking about identifying country
of origin of open source contributions,
if many of the
contributors are using a gmail.com address,
it becomes significantly harder to I I mean, I had the assumption
that many of the Chinese
contributors were using.cn email.
The biggest, honestly, the biggest
Chinese email address provider you will generally see is the qq.com thing,
right? Where it's and it's their mobile number.
Ok,
qq.com, right?
Because when I first started seeing those I was
like these are clearly spam sign up and then I
it's like no, this is like a legit Chinese mobile provider,
-- email address thing of a jigger, blah,
-- blah, blah.
But no like that's an example where it
would be very easy to identify that contributor as
having China as their country of origin, right?
If they have a random gmail,
I can't do that right?
You can
you can maybe make,
I mean they might say I'm from China in their their email signature or something.
And then the question becomes like, ok, are we talking citizenship,
country of origin, country of residence?
Like these are all different things like,
one thing I remember asking at the beginning of GDPR was like, ok,
so GDPR applies to European citizens and they're like, correct.
I'm like, ok, what about European citizens
going on vacation overseas?
-- No,
-- it covers that stuff. It covers
anyone in Europe or European citizens.
-- Does it cover me as a tourist in Europe for a week?
-- Yes. Yes. You're covered by that
-- the week I'm there or afterwards as
-- well. I don't know the answer to that.
And that's where people like Kurt shut up. It's fine.
-- I
-- mean, I bet the lawyers in Europe know the answer to this.
My suspicion is it still covers you.
-- But the
-- point is that's a relatively clean and clear example. Whereas
what you actually want and this goes back to the show intro, 12 M 270
is
foreign agents
because you could be a foreign agent for China
and be born and bred in America
-- and
-- that happens all the time. And, and that's the point, right?
So here's the point of all of that.
If I am
a malicious actor and the intent fun functionally on all of this is
you have organizations wanting to identify,
where should we maybe look for malicious intent.
If I have malicious intent,
I am not going to make any
contribution
that makes it obvious. I am not like
an American in the middle of America
and I own a grill and I eat meat like I'm going to go out of my way to look like that.
-- You're saying malicious actors might lie.
-- Exactly.
I don't think that's allowed because all the
signed off thing,
-- you have to set the evil bit in TCP.
-- If
you,
this is the other thing that drives me nuts is essentially what they're saying is,
or what they're trying to say is this pool of contributors from,
for the sake of argument, Canada is statistically safe
and this pool of contributors from China is
somehow not safe because of government influence,
CCP whatever
and
more to the point,
the potential contribute.
The the potential value of the contributions from this pool of Chinese developers
is
not worth running the risk of having an evil contribution.
Whereas implicitly this Canadian pool,
the the value of contributions will be more than the potential of an evil actor.
And
this is just wrong on so many levels. I don't even know where to begin.
-- No, like I seriously don't know where to begin. We,
-- we can't begin.
I mean, we're, we're, we're running ourselves out of time.
And so I don't want to dwell on it too long. I just want to point out the
utter absurdity and nonsense
of this particular question.
-- The problem
-- is to somebody who says, well,
but this works for like military technologies where
we restrict crypto exports to these countries.
So they can't get a hold of this crypto, right?
That actually kind of did work for a few decades.
-- That
-- never worked.
-- No,
-- no, in the fifties and sixties I'm talking
about,
uh, when everything was hardware to a degree. Sure.
That's actually a really good statement when everything was hardware
and now it's software so I can just
make a copy of it and fire it off to China and they can run it on their own computer.
Yeah. I mean, I loved back in the,
in the early two thousands, in the late nineties
when
using Open SSL in the United States was illegal because of the RS A patent.
And so me downloading and compiling the Apache web
server using Open SSL was technically against patent law.
OK. This is old timey story. This is 25 years ago, but I got hired as a contract
to assemble a portfolio of open source software for a CD the one in the back of a book.
Yeah. Awesome. And I very explicitly
did not include anything with the RS, a patented algorithm. Yeah. And
oh my God, we spent two months arguing about that where I was like, no,
I look here's the list of stuff I, I can basically show you and it's all open.
And this is one of the few times where it's all open source.
I can actually prove to you that RS A algorithm is not in there.
And
the publisher,
it took a while for them to get over this
because II I included a couple of things that had crypto
but did not have the RS, a patented algorithm in there.
And so
the publisher was like, well crypto RS A obviously it,
-- I'm like, no, it's not in there again. Open source
-- here.
It was probably covered by some other patent. It's fine.
Yeah. But anyway, it's,
that's a, that's a good comment is like,
because with hardware,
I can't just make a copy of it by typing CP space blah, blah
work.
Yeah.
I mean, here's the thing though. It never stopped.
The other countries like Russia would get a
hold of everything and they would clone it,
I mean, guaranteed
and, and shave it down and like,
but the thing is you'd have to physically acquire one and you can do it harder,
you can do inventory management because some of the
stuff is just again going away from security,
some of this stuff is just really expensive,
you know. So,
like we might want to do inventory control in these $100 items and not be losing them.
Yeah.
But going back to this. Yeah. And
it's
with respect to the bad actor problem.
The bad actors are going to do things like
set up a Canadian persona.
Right. Oh, yeah, for sure. And setting up on a fake online persona is
easy
hijacking someone else's persona
is easy.
A perfect example on threads that Kurt
Siefried is not me. It's,
I'm pretty sure it's west coast Kurt
-- siefried. Yeah,
-- you were complained about this in the last episode.
And so,
-- you know, like
-- you're not better.
-- Ok. So I wanna, I wanna, I wanna finish this one up.
-- I am the true Kurt
siefried. That is my position.
Well,
the real Kurt siefried, please stand up.
Anyway. Anyway. Oh, my goodness.
-- So I want to tie this one all up.
-- I hope he doesn't listen to the podcast. No.
Yeah. Anyway, I want to tie this one all up. Ok.
So first we have Red Hat then is open source dying.
And now kind of, I wanna, I wanna tie this up with the,
the measuring and scoring and use of open source.
And I think at the end of the day,
none of this is going to matter for the foreseeable future because
the reality is open source is used by developers to solve problems
and they don't give two craps what the open
-- SSF scorecard is
-- because there's no alternative
in,
in many cases there isn't.
And so what's going to happen is if I'm running a
tool that's going to score the open source in my product,
I might run the tool and I might say you're using a package that scored very low
and the developers, here's what, here's what,
here's what the question is going to be.
Ok?
We can spend $250,000 to replace that with this
other package or we can ship the product tomorrow.
Guess what's going to win.
I mean, we did this a red hat,
right? They acquired a company for over $100 million
and I'm like, ok,
so we're shipping that software on the
date that you said we're shipping that software
and that's what happened regardless of any security concerns,
for sure, because I'm not stupid enough to say, like we're going to block this
and, and that's the thing.
And so here's my suggestion to all of this is,
I think the scorecard has value but not in the way we think of it today.
Yeah,
I think the value is in,
I I think of it as like observ ability where
you can look at like your infrastructure and say,
oh why is this machine running hot?
Is something wrong with that machine?
And I think it's the same thing with some of these scores is it's not
about like looking at an individual package and saying this package has a low score.
It's about connecting all the dots and saying this area of our application
doesn't look real good. Why is that?
And then you can ask more fundamental questions about, oh,
this particular
piece of our application
isn't well maintained.
No one's looking at it like are, are do we need these features?
Can we just yank all this stuff and be rid of it?
Like are we, are we cutting off a rotten branch?
And I think those are the questions and that's the stuff we need to
start using these tools for instead of saying like one of my favorites,
someone will scan an application and be like, I'm a, I like this CV E needs to be fixed.
I'm like,
what does that CBE mean in the big picture? Like what do you mean? I'm like,
how can I get to that code to exploit it? Like what does that look like?
And they're like, I don't, I don't know.
I'm like, maybe we should start asking bigger picture questions.
I had this constantly with Jackson Data bind and satellite
where they did not use those binary de serialization things.
And I literally had
a higher up at red hat say,
but you're saying the customer could modify the product to use that.
And I'm like, well,
they,
I mean,
the source goes there, they could do that. And he's like, then we have to fix that.
And I'm like,
-- I cried,
-- look, I have a product that ships out to customers
and I look at the open. So I look at the vulnerability scans every day
-- and I just tell the developers just fix this crap because it's easier than
-- argument.
And that's sometimes what I ended up with.
Let's let's fix this cross site scripting because
-- it's cheaper.
-- Well, that's just it. My art
isn't, this will make us more secure.
My argument is this will keep customers from bugging us.
-- It's cheaper than handling all the support requests.
-- Right. Exactly. Exactly.
That.
And so it's amusing to me that
the vulnerabilities we fix in the product.
I, I never make an argument about the security of it.
I make the argument of this will keep people.
Ironically,
it's one of the few times you can actually show a return on investment for that
effect.
But
no,
seriously, if it reduces support
by 20
that's
real
money.
100% 100%
anyway.
Well, and just to go sideways from it, this is one of the things
where I'm focusing on our A I usage policy working group is not,
what is it that you want to do to kind of be quote unquote, more secure.
It's what do you want to do from an A I usage policy
to sort of extract the maximum benefit from A I with sort of the least
number of problems and risks and, and gross
and potential issues that come from that
and also keep things in line with like your, your organization's core values,
right?
Because I straight up saying in the paper, like,
we're not going to talk about the ethics and moral of, of A I replacing jobs.
But for some things,
having a human do, the work is part of the value like a Rolex watch.
But Rolex watches are not mass produced because part
of their whole thing is these are Rolex watches.
They are made by craftsmen or craftswomen or people,
basically people with a high degree of skill
and they are,
yeah,
exactly.
And
it's funny because
people are like, ok, yeah, we, we want to have an A I usage policy now to, like,
extract the maximum benefit with and have as few problems as possible.
Culturally
-- and as a side effect, they'll have slightly better security and less risk.
-- Cool.
Maybe.
I mean, you know, well, you know, what's funny is,
I think if you have an open source
usage policy it'll probably accomplish the same thing.
Yep.
You know.
Well, and see, and then, and that actually goes to the second thing I said,
which is you have three policy choices.
Basically no policy or anything is allowed run.
And that's basically the open source policy at the CS A is like,
I just accept it like open sources here.
-- And I think most people have that
-- second major
-- choice is just ban it out of
-- the question.
You can't do that even A I or open source. I don't think that's going to happen.
You can do it.
But
unless you're in like some sort of regulated
industry or the government with no competition,
it's probably not going to end well for
you because your competitors are probably going to
-- use these tools even that
-- your employees are going to do it and hide it.
-- That's what's going to happen.
-- Exactly.
Yes.
And then of course, the third option is, is somewhere in that middle area
with nuance. And,
-- well,
-- you have to,
that becomes a risk management discussion then where you have to say,
what do I consider an acceptable amount of risk?
And I think this is true of A I, this is true of open source.
-- This is true of anything you do. This is true.
-- It's true of buying widgets,
-- Fred.
-- This is true of, of the food you stock in your cafeteria. Like
apparently the who is gonna declare Aspar
-- as a cancer causing chemical
-- as Kurt holds up a diet Pepsi.
Yeah, it was very tasty
as pertain.
I drink like five sodas a year.
Yeah.
-- So
-- I might have to just go strictly to coffee.
-- I don't
-- know that that's there you go, man.
So it's funny, you know why I switched to coffee when I was young
because
Mountain Dew was expensive.
Coffee was cheaper and that, no, that left me with more beer money to go to the pub.
Like my switch to coffee was strictly a cost
-- saving measure so I could buy more beer.
-- And that's,
that is literally what I'm talking about when I say make a harm reduction argument.
A,
an argument that your life will be better
because no,
seriously getting somebody telling somebody spend less money
on aspartame laced pops because you'll get cancer.
Nobody's going to care but spend less money on those pops. So you have more beer money
that's gonna work with a lot of
harm reduction.
Yeah.
-- Well, beer doesn't cause cancer cars. You
-- know,
cancer was the least of our concerns when, when you're 22 years old,
spending your evenings in the
pub.
Yeah, exactly. So,
and I think maybe that's part of what security, see,
here's the thing that always drives me nuts is
security exists in the world and we always,
a lot of security people pretend like we're somehow
so special and so unique that we exist separately
as we've learned from COVID.
Even the public health people are like, yeah, no, we can't make people back
like
we,
we tried
and the harder you push, the more push back you get,
-- sometimes we
-- can't even get people to cough into their, you know,
vampire cough into their arm.
Right?
The vampire
cough. That's a good name. You
cover your face, look, you're a vampire
-- and cough into your, the crook of your elbow
-- anyway. All right. All right.
I'm gonna call this one because we're dragging on. But,
yep, yep. OK. I think we're in a good place. Thank you, Kurt.
Thank you very much for listening. Go to
social security podcast.com. Head of our show.
It's Easy Podos
Podcast. Hashtag on Mastodon. I don't, I don't know how to end it now,
-- I
-- guess, you know what, for bonus points?
Can somebody tell us what NPX means because I
was googling it while the show was going on.
And as far as I can tell NPX doesn't
stand for anything other than NP executable,
but I'm not finding the acronym anywhere
N PM. Is N PM package manager. So I'm assuming NPX is the execution.
Ok.
Um
package named NPX. It says NPX execute N PM package binaries.
But what does does that? Is that all NPX means is N PM package execution?
So anyways for bonus points, tell us what the heck it means, please. Thank you
unmasked
on
-- and
-- then you'll have to report your foreign contact.
Kurt have a marvelous rest of your day.
-- You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks
-- everyone. Bye bye.
Oh, my goodness.