Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in Thought Crime.
Josh Bresser.
I've got a new one for you. I smashed my thumb working in my,
ah, no, no, no, no. My story is much better than yours.
I was working in my workshop
and
my wife wants like a blanket rack thing and I had some extra wood and I'm like,
what's a blanket rack?
One of those things. It's,
I'll put a picture in the show notes. It's basically a thing.
You hang blankets on, right.
And
you have a bunch of extra wood. She wants one and I'm thinking this is something to do.
I'm actually, I'm, I'm kind of between,
we'll say time wasting in the evenings right now because I
finished a bunch of video games and TV shows and like,
games done quick last week and that's done now.
So I'm like, I have nothing exciting to do. I'll go build this.
I'm, I'm tightening a clamp to hold some wood down to the workbench
and I, like, smash my thumb into something. I have no idea what I smashed it into it.
Like bled everywhere. I literally have no idea how I possibly did this.
There was blood all over the place. It's all bruised up now.
And I'm thinking this is the most ridiculous thing I've ever done in my life.
So, are you going to wear your work gloves from now on? No,
no, no.
Actually I don't,
I have never done like fine woodworking with work
gloves on and I don't think you could.
Well, fine woodworking is one thing, but I mean,
the other thing is I,
I was tightening a clamp. Like, what did I? There's nothing near my hand.
I don't, I literally, I have no idea what I even hit to do this.
Here's the thing I've discovered about work gloves
is work gloves by and large are terrible.
What you want is like a specialty glove.
And I discovered airs soft gloves, very comfortable. They
typically a pad on the thumb and index finger
that will also like allow you to work your phone, which is nice, right?
Because that's the other problem is you put work
gloves on and you can't use your phone.
I don't use my phone in the workshop anyway.
But the point is there was nothing to hit my hand on and I did.
So it's kind of like in full
se like, why are we hitting ourselves in the face that
I maybe I have no idea.
I'm like, honestly,
it felt like someone smashed my thumb with a hammer I obviously hit it on something.
I don't know what
and it's just like, I feel like I'm losing my mind.
So anyway, but I have the bruise to show it, this is kind of like the chromium thing.
So uh chromium sends out DNS probes
uh when you like fire it up.
So
you, you know, kind of figure out like, am I on a captive network?
Like is there a captive portal is that,
you
know,
the problem is the way they do it is they generate a random like domain name,
which is just like a random string of text.
It's like 7 to 15 characters long or something.
So of course,
that ends up going all the way down to the TLD servers because they want to like it.
They just look for like http
slash slash 1237 QXB 947
right? No.com
dot org.
So of course,
all these queries go to the root level name servers and something
like 50% of the traffic now to the root level name servers.
Is this crap? Seriously, I didn't know they did this.
I mean I'm familiar with captive portal.
So we should probably also clarify the reason this happens is
so if I wrote a web browser on my computer,
the web browser will say OK, computer look for this DNS record,
right? And then my computer will ask whatever name server is configured.
Usually your home router.
Hey,
go find this DNS record and then your home router
is usually configured to talk to another DNS server.
Like in my case,
it's talking to the Cloud flare 1.1 0.1 0.1 it will then ask cloud flare, hey,
give me this DNS record.
And if cloud flare doesn't know, then it will say, hey, root name servers,
And the thing too is like generally speaking, queries for like.com dot net.
You know, that stuff
you look that up and it gets cached. I was going to say there's not that many TL DS.
Well, there, there are like 2000 or something now, 1500 there's a
lot more to the point that stuff gets generally
cashed because even if you use 100 of them,
which I don't, well,
maybe somebody's browsing the web enough to see 100 different TL DS a day.
But the point is that stuff gets cashed for minutes or hours. So, you know,
there's not a lot of load on the,
on the root level name servers for actual legitimate traffic,
especially if you're using like 1.1 0.1 0.1
right? Because they'll do a query for like, where do I find.com?
And you know,
they hold that answer for a while.
But what's interesting is the chart has like
sort of chrome market share and you know,
this uh
this amount of traffic and of course, you know, it,
it basically as chrome usage goes up, this traffic goes up.
I mean, the good news is chrome market shares are like what,
60 something percent now.
So
I guess it can only get 50% worse. Why is that good news?
Well,
because basically it's not like chrome will
somehow keep linearly growing and you know,
this traffic will drive the top level name servers into the dirt.
Oh, you mean for this particular bug?
You just fix it in the next version,
you can't fix it,
right?
You have to use you, you can't, for example,
they could make a query for like random string.com
but that every once in a while that would actually
be legitimate and work or fail or nex don't,
you know,
something would go wrong and it would also be much
easier for Attackers to detect and do their shenanigans with,
right?
Because part of this probing
is to see if something is going wrong, right?
Because it's generating a DNS query that what's the longest TLD?
Basically, this will never accidentally hit a correct TLD.
Well, in theory and even then the TLD shouldn't be serving a record.
Like there should not be a record for.com like, oh yeah,
that's 1.2 0.3 0.4 go over there.
What's the point?
Well,
it's just remember back when those routers all
use some poor university NTP server and like,
hammered it into the ground.
That was neat. Well, it's, it's just, I'm kind of wondering like, at what point
does a company have, maybe
I don't want to say a duty but you
can't just like hammer away on public infrastructure.
Yeah, I agree with that. I think this feels like a silly thing
to be doing.
And there are probably
alternative methods.
II, I feel like Google could,
if they want this feature, they could support it themselves.
That would make sense to me. But that's just me.
Yeah, actually this just came up now that I think of it
yesterday. I think the
tu default ami
will the, the, the message of the day that Motd
curls to an
ubuntu
address.
So basically every time the system you log in
ubuntu gets
uh a website hit from you
and that the curl command
contains an enormous amount of information
in the user agent
that feels dirty.
And like
this is one of those situations of as soon as a company realizes what's happening,
you just, you know, it's easier than trying to fix all the AMI S
ban that freaking IP, you know what I mean?
And so my guess is Google by doing DNS nonsense, get skirts around the topic of oh,
we'll just be
and the stupid Google IP that everything's trying to hit.
Yeah, I don't know either way.
It's, it's because there's, there's a lot, there's increasingly more of this,
right?
Like all these essentially public good services
that are being like
to put it bluntly the TLD,
the purpose of the TLD servers is so that people can do DN SS lookups
and
sort of, I suspect the intent was
to do DNS lookups that are sort of correct or meaningful.
For example, I can't, can I just,
can I start using the root level servers as like a speed test?
Right? No, no. Like can I be like, hey, I wonder how many DN SS queries per second?
My system can handle and like start spamming.
Is that a reasonable use?
Well, not really, you know, but so where do you draw that line? I
do not know the answer to this. And
this is
always an interesting topic
because a great deal of internet infrastructure relies on nods and handshakes.
And this is another example of Google is potentially abusing
the not in handshake ecosystem that keeps everything running well,
more to the point.
This isn't something that you can actually block.
Like there's no way for the TLD to block that we know of.
Well, not, not reasonably,
you know, it just, yeah, I don't know. It, it kind of comes to me this whole
people used to, I don't want to say only do reasonable things,
but it was more that doing unreasonable things was that
difficult.
But when you have a web browser that's 60 some
percent of the market and you make a small change.
Well, that,
that has a very global effect. It does.
And you know what I would compare this to is we discussed B GP.
It feels like 100 years ago,
but it's a similar problem where when B GP was created for, you know,
internet routing,
it was, there were like six people that could use it so
great
each
other.
And right, exactly.
Like if something's wrong, just you pick up the phone and call Bob, you know,
two towns over and we'll sort this out
and now
everyone's using B JP and we're like, holy crap. This is ridiculous.
A great example of this is a most operating systems have
a host file because actually before we had DNS servers,
we actually had a host file.
So literally, like this is like an old timey phone book.
Like you literally had a printed phone book that
was inside your computer and the host file,
like people would publish host files for
their university or for their organization.
Well, yeah, but that's because there were like 10 IP addresses in use.
Yeah, exactly.
Yeah.
And so of course,
even though we have DNS and everything now,
we still have a host file and a host file can be really useful because if you want to,
for example,
do some development work locally on your laptop and maybe
like redirect something to a local port or whatever,
you can do that with a host file very easily.
Or, you know, if you want to have like sort of a site, local dns,
but not actually set up proper DNS.
You know,
it can be actually a lot easier to just edit a few
host files on a few servers and be done with it.
And so now Microsoft is now detecting host files that block the windows telemetry.
So
one way people try to turn off the windows telemetry is, I mean,
there's a bunch of magic registry editing keys that you can use,
which quite honestly like
I hate going into the registry editor.
It scares me because, like, you, you make one wrong move and you,
it's not even that your system is dead. It's like your system
is an introverted brick.
Yeah. Yeah. That's right.
That's right where there's some strange minor behavior
that pops up every three months and,
like, totally messes up your spreadsheet.
So, so what are they doing if I, if I zero out their telemetry servers, what happens?
Restores those files back to its default content?
Interesting. Yeah.
It basically they've decided that, like, for example,
if you want to put microsoft.com or, you know, stuff in there you're not allowed to
in, I have a lot of feelings about this. Well, my take on it, it's my computer. Don't.
I have some agency over this. It's totally not your computer.
It's, we are borrowing Windows from Microsoft.
So, at what point, how much of the configuration stack do they own?
And can they force upon me?
Can they force me to use their Ds server, they can probably, because I bet in that,
that phone book of the terms of
you didn't read,
I'm sure this is clearly laid out in there
in like section 307 subsection 400 paragraph eight.
Well, it really got me thinking like, I mean, because there's,
there's copyright protection so I can't really, you know,
there's certain ways I can and cannot modify the system,
but a configuration file is clearly meant to be
modified or else it wouldn't be a configuration file,
it would be a hard coded value.
It kind of is now
this is the future we deserve.
Yeah, I'm not going to disagree with you. That's what I feel like here.
I mean, we are, I think on a precipice in terms of things like privacy
and even
just, just consumer rights to a degree,
we've become lazy and complacent
and this is what happens.
I mean, this is,
this is one of the reasons the free software
movement in the nineties was picking it got so popular
because Microsoft was this wouldn't have even registered as
a blip on the things they used to do.
Well, I mean, I've had now had the experience of my one son had us on app.
He loved story bots.
Story bots took their apps offline and they only go through their website
now because I guess they don't want to give Apple their 30% cut.
But I'm kind of annoyed because I paid for the Story Bots app. Oh, so you paid for it?
And it disappeared.
Well, it didn't disappear if it's installed on your ipad,
you can keep it but it's out of the store.
So, like if you, if I buy him a new device, I can't install it on the new device.
Ah, interesting.
Or for example,
if I have to wipe his device or if we accidentally delete the app or something,
it's gone forever.
I paid for this thing. I paid for a license for this thing,
but
it's essentially effectively been taken away.
Well, it's not yours and it never was, I mean, this is
the whole Apple ecosystem.
Well, and so I was trying to explain to my other son that, you know, for example,
we don't buy software
and he said, oh, so we rent it and I'm like, well,
no, actually renters have more rights than us.
Like you can't just kick a renter out of
a house when they're paying their rent on time,
right?
Even if they don't pay their rent on time, you can't just kick them out.
But in this case, I paid for the app,
I didn't do a charge back or something like I paid for the
app in good faith and then it got yanked away from me.
This is the future we deserve.
I worry because, well, he's quite rightly,
he's quite upset about it because it was actually quite a good app.
And you know, you could personalize it with his picture and stuff like that and
now it's gone
and, and, I mean, gone forever unless I,
you know, the website experience is nowhere close.
And also I think a couple bucks a month that recurring revenue stream too. Right.
That's the other thing I'm noticing is a lot of children's apps are
getting pulled off the App store and being turned into recurring revenue websites.
This is very interesting.
I mean, you could tie this back to what, what Epic did with Fortnite
where they're, they're trying to stand up to Apple and, and you can argue this,
I'm not going to take a position necessarily because I can see there's, I think both
sides are wrong in this one. I think they're all terrible.
I mean, I agree, I don't like any of them, but I mean,
you've got the angle of Apple is providing an ecosystem, but then they're also,
it feels kind of like shakedown money from Epics perspective.
Well,
and then clearly like Apple with that whole wordpress thing where they tried to
sort of shake down the wordpress app and the Wordpress app is like,
but we don't have in app purchases and they, they had to cave on that one.
But I think that was,
is a little too where the bad guys. Yeah.
Well, as somebody pointed out though, this is not like
relying on public outrage to sort of police companies
behaviors is not sustainable or what we want.
It definitely isn't, but it's all we have right now.
Yeah.
Well, class
action lawsuits which, you know, the lawyers make out like bandits and we get,
what is it, $7 off on our next computer purchase?
And it takes 17 years for the case to go through. I mean, so,
yeah,
this is,
I mean, the, the obvious answer is
the government needs to
clean up some of this mess. But I think
they've got, uh, we'll say, but I'm not hopeful.
Well,
and the problem too is that the government passes
regulations and then the companies just engineer around them.
Like, what is it?
Uber and Lyft in California now have changed the pricing structure and model
so that we're back to, oh, you know,
these people are your employees because you pay them a certain amount of time,
you require them work these hours, blah, blah, blah, blah, blah.
And they're like, ok, well, we changed the system how it works.
So it no longer falls under that definition and they're back to being contractors,
guess maybe California
decides to do this dance again.
And in 23 years, we have another set of regulations that they, you know,
because literally they were like, we're shutting down by 1159 on this day because,
you know, the law takes effect at like midnight and they're like,
we're shutting down for a few days.
Like I think it was Lyft and Uber both shut down in California and
they're reengineering their systems so that,
well, the law doesn't apply to us as our lawyers understand it.
Well, in California walk some of this back, I mean,
and, and this is so this is an example of,
and this is what we just kind of make a broader topic because
the world is fundamentally different now than it was even say five years ago
and
things like what is work
and how we do it. And especially during a pandemic,
there is no comparison to the way things used to be.
And now, I mean, this is one of the challenges when, for example,
in the United States, most of our leadership is essentially, you know,
white men who should have retired a long time ago
and they're insanely out of touch and they don't know what's going on.
I'm going to, I'm going to tie this now kind of back to security because this is,
I see this
again and again and again where
you have leadership in a position of not
understanding what's actually happening on the ground.
But from their vantage point, everything looks great.
For example, in computer security, I have some knowledge of what's going on.
But I'll be blunt, even I
there are massive sea changes happening
and things are just totally different, you know.
And part of me though, I mean, previously on the show,
when we had Katherine Waldron from the R street institute.
She said something that I really never fully thought through before,
which is regulation has to be good regulation.
Right.
Well, but no, no, no, no,
but I'd always kind of operated under the premise that obviously
people who are making regulation are trying to make it good.
Well,
I can try to make a good wedding cake that I'm
pretty sure it's not going to be a good wedding cake.
II,
I suspect that is true when the regulators
have a highly adversarial relationship with those,
with the entities being regulated.
And I would go even farther to say that the, the entity is being regulated,
essentially have a highly adversary relationship with, like,
even their contractors slash employees, their customers.
Like,
like, honestly, I feel
kind of, you know, when I use Lyft or Uber, I feel kind of, you know, like it's,
it's not like my,
I have a barber. I like my barber. He's a good guy. Cuts my hair. Really?
Well, I like him. You don't have any hair?
Yeah, I get my head shaved every couple of weeks
anyways. But when I get in like a lift or an Uber, I'm basically like, you know, how
badly am I going to get ripped off by this company?
Here's the thing. They're cheaper than taxis.
And from my perspective I'm getting a deal.
But the, I always feel like the person driving is kind of getting ripped off too.
Yeah,
they're getting shafted and So I make sure I give them a generous cash tip.
I was about to say, yeah, because if you're tipping them through the app,
they may not be seeing that.
Right. I don't, I don't tip them through the app. They get a generous
bit of cash for me
when I exit the vehicle.
Right?
Like the fact that you have to like,
subvert the system to like make sure the driver can eat dinner.
Yeah.
Right. Right. And, and this is, this is what the modern world feels like, man.
From looking at the way Apple treats us to Microsoft's telemetry to Google.
Abusing the root name servers is just, I don't know if,
if history has always been like this, I think to a degree it has, but
it's just sometimes it feels super out of control
and like especially in the security universe,
everything is on fire all the time. We live in just constant panic
and at almost every turn, I mean, every time
I see an email come in from somewhere talking about, oh, you know, we,
there's an alert on this service or whatever and it's like,
holy cow, I need to go clean my pants again.
And it's just, it's, it's a lot, man.
And, and then you add the pressures of society on top of that and like it's
what a time, you know.
Yeah.
Well, I looking at investors like this,
somebody was pointing out on hacker news that it
feels like there's a whole bunch of ipos coming.
Well, yeah, because if the economy doesn't improve, good luck doing an IP next year.
Yeah. Seriously.
You know, I get it. These IP OS.
They want to make their money and grow their businesses. But at the same time it,
some of them feel a bit scammy, like some of them feel like they're rushing it out.
I mean, look at, look at most of your
icos, your initial coin offerings. Yeah, but those were scams.
Those were straight up all like that 2017 time frame of
all those Bitcoins that was very clearly
the make money fast era of the, the Cryptocurrency market.
Well, and that was before the SEC was involved as well.
And the SEC now, I mean, they have involvement but which coin was it that,
that raised like 2 billion and got what, like a $20 million fine
for doing it wrong?
Well, I mean, even more recently, there's the Yan coin which came up,
raised a couple 100 million I want to say.
And then there was a bug in the smart contracts.
So the whole thing came crashing down.
Oh, that's right. I read about that from what I read.
The idea was you,
you'd have the ability for humans to raise a consensus to say like we want to do this.
We don't want to do this.
Yeah, it was,
it was basically organized as a dow a distributed autonomous organization.
Yeah. Right. Right. But, but there was a,
so it was impossible to gain a consensus because there were too many, like,
magic coins that didn't exist, which is
good.
And that's, you know, that, yeah, here we go.
Uh, blah, blah, blah,
doubled from 200 million to 400 million
since the protocol collapsed on August 13th.
Yeah. Like the whole thing from, like, start to finish was done in a couple of days.
Like it was just a, you know, giant mess.
And I, well, but
those, how do I put it nicely? The, the Cryptocurrency market
is still at that gold rush stage.
The.com boom and the stock, you remember the.com era with
what some of those tech stocks did
and what was promised? I'm
so actually fun.
I don't, I, I imagine I brought this up before,
but actually my first job out of college, all of the office and the furniture we had,
it was the pets.com
office and furniture
that my company like basically got for a song because one day pets.com, like
the landlords just locked the doors because they didn't pay the bills.
Yeah, there was a lot of that.
I worked for one of those where they had, you know,
obscenely well appointed offices and then
three months later, the whole thing basically ended in tears,
right.
Anyway, anyway, this feels like a super depressing episode.
Well, what's interesting though is as bad as this is like things keep working and
I don't want to say this sort of abuse becomes normalized,
but we find better ways to deal with it.
You know, like I remember when spam was getting out of control and honestly, now
I get very little spam in my inbox, right? You know,
and I feel like honestly for these root level name servers, like OK, well,
if Chrome were to get 100% of the market share, well,
the problem would only be 50% worse.
So simple linear statement,
they would need 50% more hardware on the root level name servers.
Well, to be blunt,
just wait one year for an it refresh and Moore's law will take care of that.
Uh That, well, maybe, I mean, I don't, I don't know if that's true or not.
I don't have any data to back that up.
No, what I mean is like if you buy a bunch more servers in a year,
they're going to be at least 50% faster than the one
they will be.
But how many more Chrome running devices will be in the universe in a year?
I assume the number is increasing in
some manner, but it's kind of it's increasing,
not super fast because basically we've already got, what is it?
3 billion smartphones in the hands of people. Again, even if we get one
Chrome phone for everybody on the planet,
that would only be about two or three times as
many and that's not going to happen anytime soon.
And that's, that's probably fair.
And that's what I mean is like, we've, we've,
we're in the middle of that s curve where it's like, yeah,
we could definitely get more,
but we're off the exponential growth phase
of like getting smartphones into people's hands,
like half of everybody has them now.
I mean, yeah.
Yeah, I'll agree with that. That's ok. Ok. Like if IO
devices start doing this, yeah, we might be in a world of hurt.
Like, if every light bulb on the planet were to do this,
that would be bad. Yeah, that's probably a different problem though.
Let's hope it is. Yeah. Why is your light bulb running a web browser? Oh, Lord.
It's just a computer. Of course, it could run a web browser. I mean,
you have to think me,
most, most,
most light bulbs probably have more powerful
computers in them than our first computer were
20 years ago.
Absolutely. More than 20 years. The fact that it can talk TCP.
I, and it's not like a $200 add on piece of software from IBM for OS Two, which,
you know, I actually, I bought the TCP I pack for Os Two.
I know you tell us that a lot.
I was like, trying to explain to my kids what a phone book is.
Do I actually, you know,
now that you say that I have not received a phone book at my house in a, surprisingly,
it's been more than a year now, I think.
And I mean, in the past I, I'd get my phone book, you know,
thrown onto my porch by somebody and then I would pick it up and recycle it and that,
I don't remember the last time I did that, which is good for the environment.
I mean,
yeah,
fundamentally, the moral of the story is the more things change,
the more they stay the same.
But
I think part of it is the the
the pace of change and the rapidity of sort of, I hate to use the word innovation,
you know, especially when I applied to things like Lyft and Uber.
But the sort of the pace at which people try new business models
to kind of screw people out of their money is definitely speeding up.
It's the story of humanity.
I mean, if you look at and I need to finish this work, so I,
I talk about this all the time.
But if you look at say like worker safety at
the turn of the century,
I mean, it was basically you went to work, you worked 12 hours a day, seven days a week.
And if you got hurt, you were just basically fired and that was the end,
you probably were going to starve to death because there was no,
no anything or even worse,
read about what they did to Children in the form of chimney sweeps.
Yeah. Right. Exactly. That's, that's horrifying also.
But anyway,
the point is what happens is there's horrifying conditions and the
only reason they changed is because people wanted them to change.
But at the same time
it was so horrifically bad
that it couldn't be ignored anymore.
And, I mean, that's one of the, this is the perpetual problem we have.
Especially insecurity
is until we start killing people by the millions with technology.
Is anyone really going to care?
And I mean, if you look at the history of humanity, the answer is no,
no one is going to care.
Well, the thing is we have enough other quote
unquote like we have existential real problems that we're busy ignoring.
Yeah. Right. I mean, climate change is one of the easiest to pick on, right?
Like climate change.
We, there's literally as we're recording this, there are two hurricanes
in the Gulf of Mexico. Has that ever happened before? No,
that's completely bananas and humanity is like, oh, whatever, it's probably fine.
Like it's not fine at, oh,
I just, I remember this summer we've had
multiple heat warning advisories and I'm like, I,
that is not a thing when I was a child and that's the thing, right?
Like the climate
is not in a happy place, but as humans, we're like, whatever, it's fine
and unfortunately
it is going to have to get even worse than it already is before we care.
I mean, like this is a story of humans.
And see that's,
I think it's part of the problem with some of these
technological things is like by the time we figure out,
hey, we should have a secure iot world and how that actually looks.
Well, I've already got, you know what,
I don't even actually know how many IOT devices I have in my
life anymore. Like I'd have to go count light bulbs and a bunch of other random stuff.
But now, now here's the flip side of that coin
and this is for all you market forces folks out there,
we literally have security,
the market demands.
And is it, here's,
here's a question and I'm not going to answer
this because this is kind of the topic for,
for everybody is, is the security we have today good enough.
And
I don't, I don't think we should even necessarily answer that. Like this is,
this is, this is the question
like, how many people have we killed because of the bad security?
It's, the number is pretty low for sure. I mean, I guarantee it's not zero.
Well, part of the challenge too is,
is information security is one of those classic things where it's not going to
quite often, it's not going to kill anybody out, right.
But it might add to stress levels or, you know,
do something that statistically shortens life a bit for a bunch of people.
So, you know, like, are we killing anybody directly. No.
But are we making everybody miserable? Yes. Even ignoring,
we make lots of people miserable. I mean,
anyone listening to this podcast.
Uh, but so, so, but like, here's the other side of it. Right.
So, ok, so my credit card gets stolen
and I have to deal with it,
which actually like that hasn't happened in a while for me either.
But like my credit card get stolen, I had to deal with the outcome of that.
And, but
on the, on the flip side,
my ability to easily use my credit card for all kinds of
things has probably given me a net positive in my life.
Ignoring the fact that I have to deal with some of the aftermath of it getting stolen.
So as much as we want to harp on security sometimes, maybe,
maybe we have the right amount.
I don't know. That's the question that we have the security, the market demands.
Well, I would say we have the security that we deserve at this point.
It
is the future we deserve. Kurt.
Uh All right, cool. I'm gonna, I'm gonna call this one.
I feel like I'm going to end it on one happy note before I do in Washington DC
in the United States.
There is a panda who gave birth to a baby panda
and there is nothing more fun in Boston to watch.
I don't know,
whatever, shut up
but
go, I will put a link in the show notes. Go look at the panda. They have a panda. Cam.
Pandas are awesome and you can't not love pandas. That is,
that is the happy note we will end on.
So I do enjoy a good zoo webcam like in pandas man, like pandas, pandas,
pandas are our hope for the future.
That's all I can say because like that is an animal,
by all accounts should not exist in nature
yet it somehow persevered and as humans helping
keep them alive because they're so cool.
So there we go. Pandas. Like when you get depressed, think of pandas.
Thank you, Kurt, that you all for listening. You can go to open
social security podcast.com. Hit up the panda links.
You see Pound says podcast hashtag do hit us on social media.
Kurt have a fantastic rest of your day.
You too. Thanks everybody. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.