Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 22 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime, Josh Bresser.
-- Hey, Kurt,
-- how are you doing?
-- I am doing
-- excellent.
-- So,
-- fresh coffee, fresh
coffee that it doesn't get much better than that. Right.
Can you imagine
being the guy that
discovered, you could grind these beans up, roast them,
run hot water through them and then drink it.
So I read a story about that once about a,
I guess there was a farmer in the Middle
East or something and he noticed his goats would
act particularly odd after they were eating a bean
off of a tree or a bush or something.
And, and that's right.
And then obviously he did some investigation into
this because obviously these goats were getting,
you know, like hopped up on caffeine
and apparently that's how coffee was discovered, which
love altering their brain state with chemicals.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
And,
and funny enough, I mean,
I've, I've heard it suggested,
I don't know how true this is and I've never done a ton of research into it, but
they believe that a significant amount of the,
um, I guess cultural progression
that happened kind of in the, the 17
1800 ish time period
was
attributed to coffee because
to that
people would drink beer
or alcohol was
right. That's also a depressant. So if you're all sitting around drinking alcohol,
you probably aren't having the live well, you're gonna have a lively conversation,
but it's about ridiculous things like, you know,
I bet I can jump out of that window and land in that bucket of water underneath it.
Right. As opposed to when you're drinking coffee, which stimulates the mind
and creates these obviously very, I guess intellectual discussions, we'll say
-- I can buy that.
-- I,
that I can't say one way or the other.
It's something I should probably read about at some point.
Speaking of lively conversations that are gonna stimulate people,
I think we have an awesome topic.
Right?
Do you wanna, do you wanna tell
people
-- about this?
-- Well, this is, this is related to, was it episode 20?
I think we discussed the idea of planned
obsolescence with IOT devices because the issue was,
you know, so, so some organizations, some manufacturers know
that a certain device they've created
is going to end of life.
And
a handful of organizations have done this like Google did this with a
uh what was it, was a nest
gateway or something like that?
And they basically bricked them all and people lost it,
right? People were, were very upset
that their devices were destroyed.
And so what this really got us thinking about is the fact that
manufacturers have a concept called Planned Obsolescence where they know
how long one of their products is going to last
when you buy a washing machine,
they know how long it will sit in your basement and work because
it has certain parts on it
that have certain lifetimes. And so
that also got me thinking then is
if, if a manufacturer of a, a
physical good
knows how long something is gonna last.
Now, granted, they don't know, to the day they know kind of like,
well, some might,
some might,
but
we'll say they generally speaking, don't,
-- but they know about, you know, this will last four years or
-- more or less
once they build it, they can't
change it
in,
in many
instances we'll say yes. Right.
But then they got me thinking. So, is that any different than an organization
bricking all of their
un, I guess, end of life. Gateways
one day.
See, and this gets into that. Do you actually own the device or are you licensing it?
That's a whole, you know, legal thing right there. Right.
-- So
-- let's ignore that for the time being because
when we think about say a toaster,
you own your toaster, no one's going to argue about that.
But at the same time, the manufacturer knows after two years of use
or
your toaster is going to stop working or maybe
a better example here is is light bulbs.
Because as part of my research into this, I found out that
a
long time ago, this was back in the early 19 hundreds, basically,
light bulb manufacturers were doing an amazing job
and these bulbs were lasting like forever,
literally forever.
And basically, all of the light bulb manufacturers came together.
They created a cartel and they decided light bulbs will have a 1000 hour lifetime.
That is a spec we will build them to.
And so practically speaking,
they could build light bulbs that last forever,
but they don't because they want them to burn
out because they want to sell more light bulbs.
And I mean,
that was totally the intent and I don't know if
they were sneaky about it when they did it,
but it's very clear
that's how it works today.
So why aren't we all losing our minds over
the fact that our light bulbs are artificially constrained?
Is that the case of led ones? Because the ones I'm buying are like, I think $30,000.
Well, well, this is obviously old light bulbs. I'm sure the led s
they claim they're
having
to
change.
Are they going to actually be 30,000 hours or is that just
something they put on the box to make you feel special?
Well,
one thing I've noticed is I remember as a kid and
a young adult changing light bulbs was something you just,
you at least once a month you had to go change dead light bulb
right in your house. It's just,
that's just something that you did. Right. Like taking out the trash.
And what I've really noticed is when I went to CFC si, went to CF CS early on and,
yeah, they weren't very good.
Some of them were a little bit brown and hard when I pulled them out. And,
uh, yeah, I got rid of those ones.
Um, but I've gone to Led Lights now, um,
through my entire house
and
I don't think I've ever had to rep. No, that's not true. I've had to replace one,
one bulb. I've had to replace in
23 years.
I admit I don't have any led s but the,
the compact fluorescence these days are pretty solid.
I have quite a few in my house that have been here for many, many years.
I found one thing I found especially nice with Led s
they work really well at cold temperatures. So, my unheated garage,
you know, because like we had about what, three weeks of minus 20 °C weather
and CF CS
would take several seconds to
come
in
the cold.
In fact, it's been,
it's been very cold here for the last couple of days and I have automatic lights
on my garage that when it gets dark they turn on and they're compact fluorescence and
they look sad.
I use, I still use the halogens for my outdoor lights because out here, you know,
well, uh
Friday night, we had a cold weather advisor, you know, minus 40 plus a wind chill.
And, yeah. So anyways,
yeah, so this, this idea what, what's interesting to me is
this kind of incentivizes manufacturers to actually build a working
update system that can push updates out to their devices
because it gives them now the option. Should they choose
to brick these devices or to downgrade them simply maybe
not even brick them but to downgrade their functionality.
And then say, like, look, you want that new functionality, go get a newer device.
Is that an incentive? I mean, what's the incentive there?
Well, from the manufacturer's perspective, they can now
-- forcibly make you replace your device.
-- That is true.
But people will lose their minds if the manufacturers are
-- purposely bricking their devices, right? For
-- now.
I mean, this is already happening with the Samsung seven.
So we've uh the galaxy, what is it?
-- Sorry, the Galaxy Note Seven,
-- the Galaxy Note Seven.
And in fact, when we recorded our episode,
I said Verizon wasn't going to brick them and
like the next day
they changed their mind. So,
so apparently yes,
all of the Galaxy Note Sevens on the planet should stop working very soon.
See, and there's a good example, I'm guessing Verizon was, you know,
did their lawyers, for example, tell them, look,
you've been made specifically aware of a problem that can cause
lost to our customers even, you know,
kill them
and we could have taken action to prevent it and we didn't.
And if this happens,
you know, I'm guessing some lawyers probably talked and
I'm, I'm guessing that was part of the decision.
-- Well,
-- here's the deal too with, with the Galaxy Note Seven, though,
this is a device that is actually causing harm, people can get hurt from this.
It's one thing when it's, that, it's another thing when it's,
let's say I've got a, a media player plugged into my TV, that,
that Roku one day decides it's time for this to die.
Well, see,
and there's a good example is can I prove harm while I lost the function of the device?
So
instead of just breaking it, for example, um the Pebble watch is a good example,
right?
Pebble got bought out and they sent out an email saying essentially, you know,
we're gonna be turning servers off.
So your Pebble watch is going to lose functionality.
It'll like, for example, I'm assuming it'll still tell time at a minimum,
but for example,
maybe it won't show the weather or do your text messages or whatever stuff it does,
right?
And as a consumer, you know, depending on what you signed or what you bought,
what the user license agreement was and so on and so forth, you know,
because there's a part of the challenge is when you
buy a toaster going back to your early example,
when you buy a toaster, it, it just does toast.
Right? And that's not,
it's simple to understand and it's not something you need like a cloud service for.
But let's say I buy a smart watch.
Well, it'll tell time on its own. Sure. But
for example, displaying the weather, well, obviously to display the weather,
it needs to have a backend service.
So what if the company is providing that,
you know, so that line between
that line of functionality that's kind of based on the
device and based on back end services really gets blurred.
Yes. But now we come to the point of
if there's a device just like this Pebble watch,
I is
it, is it ok for the manufacturer to brick it on purpose?
-- And
-- I would say it depends on the circumstances if these things are catching fire
like the seven, you know, then yeah, there's a,
there's a strong compelling case for it.
What about your IOT camera?
That's now part of a botnet is, should the manufacturer be bricking? Those?
I would say it also depends on what is the remediation after bricking, you know.
So in theory with the Galaxy Note seven,
they brick these things, then you bring them in and you get a new phone,
right?
You're made whole like your, your loss is the phone and you're made whole, in theory,
by getting a new phone.
I'm guessing most of these IOT manufacturers won't break
these devices and offer you a new one.
-- But I don't
-- get a new toaster when my toaster quits working
well, but it quit working due to, you know,
um, planned obsolescence or whatever not.
There's, it's, you know, we're basically going into the trolley problem area.
Right. Is it better to take an overt action that does less harm
or to
be passive? You,
-- you
-- have
the
problem, I mean, there's a million variations on it, but fundamentally, the
only
problem is, is a, is a, is a,
what's the English expression?
It's a, it's a mind exercise to explore morals and ethics and
you know, these uh issues
and the problem basically states you have a train
track that uh splits into two different train tracks.
Uh And it's currently for the sake of argument, the,
the switch setting is set to go to the right and on the right track there is a
group of say five people
on the tracks that are gonna get run over by the trolley. Now you can throw the switch
to the left
and it's only gonna run over one guy.
So what do you do? Right?
Do you take, do you take an overt action of making this choice,
switching the track and you know,
being
directly leading to the death of a person or
do you take a passive action and not get involved
and allow five people to die?
But legally,
you're probably not in as much trouble because you didn't take an overt action.
You know, because
let's face it, most legal jurisdictions have the concept of,
if you take a direct action that causes somebody to die, you know.
Um, depending on what the circumstances are, you could be charged with murder,
you could be
charged with manslaughter.
You could be charged with reckless endangerment, you know, things like that.
But very few legal jurisdictions have a very strong framework for a passive action,
you know, outside of certain circumstances, right?
Like certain people have a duty of care like doctors and police
where they have to take an action or do something.
But, you know, as a normal bystander you and I,
we're not required to run into a burning building to save a baby.
We are not.
And I don't know if this is necessarily correct though because
this is closer to maybe an automobile recall where if they don't take action,
they're actually more liable than taking an action.
Right. True.
But what if they're, they're breaking the devices because
either there is no specific harm,
but there's the potential for harm because this device is known to be flawed and
Attackers can get into it and use it for a botnet,
-- but your device is not yet part of a botnet,
-- right?
And so here's,
here's my thought on this and I see this as having two parts
is there is if I buy a toaster
and it breaks in a week,
I'm gonna get a new one because of the warranty.
And so I think there's a certain amount of implied
life to every product
in many jurisdictions.
-- It's
-- quite, it is, it's very explicit in many
places. Exactly. And so
I think
there's that aspect of it and I think even if you buy an IOT device and it
stops working or even if they would break it in the short span of a warranty period,
it would be expected you get a new one.
But now when my one,
these things are also reliant on back end services, so I could give you all the,
all the toasters you want.
It's still not gonna display the weather.
I wonder if I can buy a toaster that displays the weather
probably we should look into, if not, I'm going to build one.
But anyway, so
the weather toaster.
Uh anyway, anyway,
so what happens though when we reach the effective end of the life of a product?
And this is where like you're talking about, backends, stop working or, or even
even less direct than that because obviously,
if the backend service stops working, you've effectively bricked a product.
Ok.
When you reduce the functionality or in some cases, like with the nest thermostats,
yeah, you've,
let's just,
let's assume, let's, let's keep it simple. Right? Let's not worry about edge cases.
Let's just say backend service goes away. Product is bricked. Ok.
So that's an easy case. But what happens when I have a product that
doesn't necessarily rely on a back end.
It may be like a video camera is a great example here where it records video
and then I connect to it and I can see the video. Right.
But now it's, it's five years old, it's 10 years old at some age.
It's still technically working,
but it has become a threat because it's joining botnets
and it hasn't had security updates in forever and whatnot.
And,
and in this instance, this is kind of where
a typical manufacturer would have their planned obsolescence kick in
and a gear in the thing that's made of plastic
would have broken and now the camera is broke,
but in this case,
it's all electronic and this stuff is gonna last for 50 years if you just let it run.
But at the same time,
it needs to die because it is harming society. Right.
Well,
there's definitely the potential harm society and I would say we'd probably
have to look at what happened to the auto industry because they,
they went through the exact same problem, you know, with, for example,
tire recalls,
not all of these tires are going to burst and cause a roll over and kill people.
A certain percentage will.
And I think that's part of the problem is
we don't have, you know what percentage of these devices are now part of a botnet.
Is it like 100% of the internet connected ones
without a firewall or is it, you know, some subset like 1%
I, it is conceivable that 100% of a certain device without a firewall is part of a bo,
I mean, I think you could make that assumption and be pretty darn spot on.
However, however,
here's the problem comparing it to the auto industry is when cars fail,
people die and people get hurt when your IOT camera fails, nothing happens.
Well, I mean, if it's part of a botnet, it could cause harm.
-- It does
-- cause harm but not to you, you don't see it.
-- That's the economic problem.
-- Right.
-- Exactly.
-- It's a network externality.
Exactly.
And so this is, I mean, so this is kind of the trolley problem of,
you don't know what the trolley is going to hit, but if you pull the switch it hits you.
Right.
I mean,
that's basically what this trolley problem is and
no one is going to flip that switch.
It's a, obviously,
you know, people are very
well, even basic it security. Like applying patches.
Most sites still don't do that very well.
You know, we're not asking them to buy all new
it every five years. We're just asking them to apply vendor
supplied patches on a regular basis, like Microsoft Tuesday
and how many sites don't even do that because that costs time and money.
Right.
That's,
you know, so we, we,
we provably have a situation where a lot
of people won't do the right thing either because
they don't want to or they don't even know what the right thing is.
You know, and this is, I hate to say this is one of the,
I think this is the biggest argument for
automatic updates is because the,
the vast majority of people don't
honestly know that they should be updated
-- to update.
-- Here's what,
this is such a weird problem. We've already wandered off the reservation
into planned updates. Let's make the assumption.
Let's just make sure we're very clear. Let's say you have a device,
it gets automatic updates.
The vendor provides automatic updates and five years from now,
the vendor says we're sick of updating this device and
now we reach the point where if they brick it,
they are the bad guy and the villain and
everyone will hate them if they don't break it.
Now,
there are insecure devices on the internet that will say
join botnets and make the world a better place.
And so here's our trolley problem.
They flip the switch, they,
their customers hate them because they've just run over all the customers.
They don't flip the switch and now the trolley
goes off and ruins the internet for everybody.
Right.
My take on this would be
ideally there would be some sort of redress for
losing your device or it would be made very explicitly
clear at the start, this device will be supported by the manufacturer for five years
and then we'll say give you a six month or a one year grace period
and then it will be disabled at this date at midnight.
I think that is
a
-- right thing to do. But now
-- the problem is the companies that don't do this,
we have an advantage,
but hey, our stuff lasts forever because we never updated
it
right. Because I'm gonna go
in,
I'm gonna go to the store and now we have the,
the we'll say responsible company brand Iot Camera that
says it's going to quit working in five years.
And then I look and there's, you know, shady company incorporated
that has no such thing. And I'm like, well, I'm gonna buy the one that's $20 less
and will last longer because it's, you know, the buying, that's not my problem.
And this goes back exactly to what I said
last episode with around the used cars and consumers
knowing or not knowing that they have a good
quality product and being able to differentiate them.
You know,
the problem is the things that you
can typically actually see and differentiate are not
sort of the security properties or not those sort of fundamental low level things,
right?
It's more of the feature set. Hey, this camera is black and white.
This camera is color, right? Very clear differentiation, very easy to understand.
You know, this camera has more storage or less storage. This camera
uh
has an app that I can use on my phone to remotely view it.
Well, you know what that now means,
your camera is probably attached directly to the internet
-- and you know that that app is totally secure, right?
-- Yeah.
You know, so that's the thing. I mean,
um,
do we possibly need some form of, uh,
I don't wanna say warning label but like a basic information label that says,
you know,
this device uses a backend service and loses x amount of functionality without it.
Or this device requires, you know,
not to not be firewalled from the internet needs raw internet access for whatever
that reminds me of Kurt is, this is totally like
one of those instances where when you watch an adult themed TV show,
it tells you like what all the naughty bits are that you're about to see.
Right.
That's exactly it.
And, but again,
it comes back to the companies that do this initially
will be sort of at a disadvantage because they'll have to
spend money and time on doing this.
And then, you know, they'll, their competitors will be like our product is perfect.
-- Ok.
-- So
until
we get
regulation,
-- let's
-- explore that
is
without any sort of mandated regulation and rules.
Do we think anyone would actually do this voluntarily?
It's tough because it's hard. I, I just,
I can't see there being enough of a market for a quote
unquote premium product with good security for that to actually be enough
of a business differentiator
for it to be worth doing. I would agree completely.
I would say
that this could be part of a brand,
for example, like the Google Nest brand or the Apple brand or whoever, you know,
these guys that are making hardware now and have, you know,
brands that are recognizable versus
brands that are not recognizable because I've, you know, they're,
they're new to America or the US or whatever.
Um,
what I would like to see is more, you know, consumer reports, crash test ratings,
right?
But is that something that, you know,
can realistically be done because even when you think about it, right,
the cost of taking a car and crashing it.
Yeah, it's expensive 4050 grand.
But the cost of paying somebody to audit a product
-- for security properties is easily that much
-- or more.
It's even more than that though. I mean,
even if consumer reports conducted a security audit on a product,
what happens in five years
when the manufacturer decides to shut down the back end?
I mean, let's use your, your nest smoke alarms are a great example of this.
Do you know,
are those going to self destruct some day because the
hardware inside is deemed unworthy of detecting a fire?
Well,
Google could definitely break them but there you actually have a device
where losing its functionality does put me at actual significant risk.
It does.
And do you know what happens because like they always say, you know,
you should have replaced your smoke detector
every five years or every 10 years or whatever.
And
there's a reason for that. Right. Because it has actual radioactive material in it
that decays and it becomes less effective after a certain period of time.
Yeah.
Yeah. No. Um,
one thing they could do, I, well, I mean,
and the thing is there's ways to break a device without actually breaking it.
Right. You could, for example, have an alarm every five minutes
and it's gonna be so annoying. People are gonna, no, but, you know,
so people replace it because it gets so annoying.
Um, you know, it starts, for example,
you just have the product send out an alert and speak every five minutes saying,
you know, beep, beep, beep.
This product is now obsolete. Please replace me.
And
in, in, in the case of a smoke alarm, I would totally do that in a second.
But now
if we have an IOT camera
it, we come back to that argument where product A
will, will annoy you until you replace it.
And product B just continues running forever as part of.
Exactly.
I think it's gonna be a lot like the car industry and pollution and that these are
the, the, the problems are largely externalities in that.
Yeah, it costs me a little bit of maybe time and hassle, but really not that much.
But being part of a botnet causes somebody else a huge amount of pain,
but I don't care like much like pollution
and I think we're going to need regulation and,
you know, part of me wishes that, you know,
these large companies would actually kind of lobby for some of these, you know,
sort of product labeling laws and stuff.
But I also fear then that by adding all this legislation and requirements that,
you know, are we going to lose
the new stuff?
You know, the cutting edge stuff that maybe isn't, you know,
funded by a company that can guarantee that they're back end will run for
more than a year or five years or whatever the legally mandated minimum is.
Right.
Yes, I think the answer to that is yes, it
regulation
-- rarely encourages innovation.
-- Well, on the flip side back to, again, to Steven, uh
you know, he's, he's talking about these fa uh what is it called in America?
The, uh the, the medical FDA.
-- Is it the FDA, the Food and Drug Administration that does the medical
-- devices?
He handled medical devices.
Um, you know, and, and that is a super heavy regulated environment
with really high entry costs and, you know,
but, but, and there's a lot of innovation
for what it's worth and this is something we should,
we should get Steve Christie on this show someday to talk about this
because I thought the medical device industry was very much an established player,
huge company sort of thing.
And it turns out that
the vast majority of medical device manufacturers have, like,
less than 30 employees and are super tiny.
Yeah. Right. Exactly. And so
how are these, how are these companies operating in? What?
Well, I, I guess what, what is, or should be
a heavily regulated environment?
Well,
you can have a lot of regulations and they don't necessarily incur a lot of costs
and, and in this case, they must not because,
you know, I, I'm familiar with things like common criteria and fis and those are,
those are, those are standards that incur massive cost to get through them.
I mean,
ignoring just the, the financial cost of getting it done in the first place,
there's all the development and everything else going on around it
that is significant.
Yeah. No, I think fundamentally things will have to get worse before they get
bad enough that people take notice because quite honestly,
you know, those, those denial of service attacks,
there's been a couple more that haven't even made the news.
-- Yeah, they just does it really matter.
-- Well, and that might be
the, the long term answer to this is rather than trying to fix the devices,
they just denial of service is,
is not a problem because there's enough bandwidth and
the infrastructure is built in such a way that
too bad, you know, you're not attacking the infrastructure in this way anymore.
Yeah, I also can't help but wonder, you know,
people breaking into these devices uh currently
are monetizing them by for example,
using them as part of botnets to do denial of service, right?
That's a relatively easy way to monetize things.
You don't have to be technologically sophisticated. You literally can go to github
and download
the, how do you pronounce it?
Mirror
botnet code and just like start using it,
you know, plug and play.
Um even even better than that man,
you can go on the dark web and rent a freaking botnet.
Exactly. So it's a very clear, simple path to monetization and
part of me can help but wonder and this is a show
we'll have to do is this whole cyber deterrence piece with,
you know, strike back capabilities.
So for example, if, if I'm getting denial of service and they're not spoofing the IP S
and I realize like say
80% of the attack is coming from this one brand of IP camera
that has an own flaw that I can use to break the camera,
you know, can I do that? Yes. Should I do it? I don't know ethically
legally.
No,
we I'm not getting into that
today though. It's the answer is
-- no,
-- can't hack back, hack back is
not OK.
I'm not talking so much about hack back,
but a very limited target engagement of this device.
And I'm just gonna say, for example,
turn it off or maybe break it or something along those lines, you know, I don't know.
Justice,
isn't
it?
It's
a,
well, but, ah, do we need justice or do I just want the problem to go away?
Isn't that the same thing?
No, this is
I,
if I can, if I can say, for example, like with
a
Mi,
how did you pronounce
it?
So, with the
Mira
Botnet, for example,
if I could say break into 80% of these devices and turn them off or whatever
and stop the
DDOS for an hour or a day or permanently by breaking them.
I'm, you know, I'm now happy because the D
-- OS stopped,
-- but you just broke into a 10,000.
Consult
-- someone else owns,
-- but these people obviously aren't taking care of them.
If, if, if your neighbor doesn't feed his dog,
should you break into your neighbor's house to feed his dog?
Uh
You, you'd
be in less trouble. Well, but the point is that
the reality is breaking into these uncared for devices
is very unlikely to result in harm to you,
right.
It's already been done. They've already been broken into
running an insecure device is gonna result in no harm to me as well.
So it's
the
ethical, I think part
of the challenge is, but it's, it's chances are it's going,
I think it's going to have to start happening at some
point because somebody in some country is going to get do
and they're going to be in a country that
doesn't really care about American law or whatever,
you know,
some Russian dude gets, you know, de
dosed from America
by another Russian dude.
You know, he's not going to be worried about working all these devices.
What happens when you hack some Russian guy's IOT camera and he calls his friend in,
in New York who drives up to Edmonton to sh
you.
Right.
Well, I would use, you know,
the reality though is I think a lot of these things, you know,
they're,
it's that sort of industrialized petty crime, right?
Even if a device gets bricked, you know, how many,
how many wireless routers have you had to throw it off over the
years because they just die after one or two or three years.
Well, that's just what they do.
I mean, that's part of the plan.
-- If you
-- brick these devices would people even,
and, and some of them they wouldn't. And that's actually where I think
some of these device manufacturers should just put like
a counter on the inside that says after,
after two years and random days between zero and 100 just
don't work. Right. Just stop working.
Blink, blink the red light that says something's wrong
and just never work again.
And,
and I mean, that
here's the thing though is if you tell people it does this, they lose their mind.
But if it just stops working because it broke,
that's fine. And in reality it's
the
-- same
-- thing,
printer cartridges
that's why I bought a laser jet printer.
Yeah,
me
too.
I'm just thinking about it. Wasn't there a printer manufacturer?
A big one that basically had cartridges that
expired
expiry date? All
of them do this. Well, no, but that was enforced by the cryptographic chips in them.
I, I'm pretty sure they all do that.
Yeah. So we've already crossed that limit and people,
and people hate them for it. I bought a freaking
laser
jet just because of this.
Well, the people who know, hate it and the people who don't know whatever,
they just keep buying the crappy printers.
Well, why wouldn't that work for this situation?
You're
maybe right.
It is.
See, the problem with,
is with these economic based issues is kind of whatever works for
a lot of people is what is going to end up happening,
whether we like it or not, unless we, like, regulate the heck out of it.
And I don't see regulations for this coming any time soon.
Part of it being is that any regulations for this would be so, you know,
good intentions
and any, you know,
loopholes or whatever that can be exploited are going to be exploited.
-- So,
-- here's the reality of it is un,
unless IOT cameras become sentient in certain murders,
people,
they're never going to get regulated and that's just the reality of it because from,
from everything I've looked at in the history of humans and giving a
crap about what's going on until a lot of people start to die.
Nobody can.
-- I mean, cigarettes still aren't even illegal.
-- That's true.
And even when a lot of people die, sometimes nobody cares.
You know, uh, cars kill how many people every year in America in Canada.
-- Uh,
-- almost as many as mosquitoes do.
Seriously.
Um, I believe mosquitoes are still the single largest killer of humans throughout.
I, I would, I would bet cars are a close second
and
in reality
-- reasons.
-- Right. Right.
In reality, we should be losing our minds over how, like,
just grossly unsafe cars are to society.
But instead we're worried about, you know, like sharks.
Yeah.
But it, it's humans are weird.
It is,
this is why this is why we need the machines
to take over because they will be a logical,
reasonable creatures unlike us.
Yeah.
So I think what we should do is at some point
discuss all the hack backing cyber deterrents that whole issue and,
and just to put it clearly, I'm not 100% in favor.
We should
realistically, I
think,
but I think realistically part of it is it's going, it's already happening. Right.
We're already having people hack each other. So,
you know,
should that be part of the stance? Should that be part of what we legislate?
I don't know. You know, and,
but the reality is it's already going on whether we like it or not. I feel. How do we
-- deal with
-- hacking back is vigilante justice and I'm going to draw a hard line. Right.
Like,
if my neighbor
takes my garden hose, I can't go break into his house and take his TV.
Like, it's just that doesn't work. You cannot have vigil anti justice,
period. Ok.
Ok. So then part of the concern I would have is,
you know, we're kind of,
the internet really is sort of the wild west in many ways
and that we don't have very good legal frameworks for dealing with some
dude's equipment in China, attacking me or denial of servicing me or whatever,
you know, and quite frankly,
I don't think we ever will because the cost of it is so low,
it's fixing, it is not worth it,
which I think the right solution here
and this is me just making crap up on the spot is I
view this as the kind of security flaw versus sandbox application universe where
we will never fix all the security flaws. So the answer is to sandbox application.
So security flaws don't matter,
just as we're never going to fix all of this internet gear.
So the answer is making sure we have an internet
and an infrastructure that is resilient enough that it
doesn't matter if it's full of rogue devices,
it just, it still works.
I would tend to agree, you know, much like the real world.
We, it's illegal to break into people's houses and we all have deadbolts
Right.
Exactly.
Uh, so, yeah.
No, it's, it's a, it's, I, what I'm really curious too is, uh,
over the next week and a half.
How much is the IOT going to grow
with Christmas?
You know, it's gonna grow a ton. I'm trying to think. Did I get my kids any IOT crap?
I don't think I did.
I'm not sure I'm comfortable.
Well, I'm trying to think, I mean, I'm pretty sure none of it is iot
enabled. Did I buy anything for anyone?
I don't believe so.
Yeah, I'm, I'm comfortable saying I did not purchase any,
any internet enabled devices for Christmas
that you're aware of.
You heard about those passive Wi Fi chips that are powered from the Wi Fi
radio signals themselves.
I did not hear of this, but that sounds
interesting.
Well, essentially it's, it's a Wi Fi chip set that is low power enough
that it, it can be powered by other wifi signals.
It's got a little antenna to pick up the signals, convert them to electricity and,
and then it's,
well, and then so it can power itself so it doesn't need batteries or anything.
It's a Wi Fi chip set.
So essentially what we're getting to the
point where we can passively harvest enough energy
from Wi
Fi signals, you know,
-- to actually power a device that can do something that's not
-- new man.
-- You got, you remember the old school AM Crystal
-- radios? Well, yeah, exactly.
Um Except now that it's running, you know,
software, maybe a microphone, maybe a camera, maybe internet capability,
you know.
So in theory, you could have, for example, hardware bugs, you know,
video and sound that are passively powered,
you know, by and just by virtue of being there. So
you Sprinkle these on people
when they're out at lunch, you know, they walk back to their office,
have a board meeting.
There was uh
you know, I remember I read about this,
I was reading an espionage book once and there were these, these bugs that I,
I wanna say the Russians use them,
but they'd, they'd implant the bug into a location.
-- Obviously, the one in the US embassy in the Eagle
-- is, is that,
is that the one that was the passive where, where it,
it, it, it, it didn't,
well, how am I, what am I saying? Here? Words are hard,
right?
So essentially this thing didn't give off any radio signals until
someone basically focused a radio signal at it to power it.
And so they do their bug sweeps come up clean
and then the,
the, the spies would essentially power this remotely and then it would, you know,
send across the signals and whatnot and, and that kind of stuff is,
-- it's fascinating and horrifying at the same time. And
-- I think I,
one of my best childhood memories was when they had to
build three stories on top of the US Embassy in Russia.
In Moscow
because the thing was so full of bugs, they couldn't,
they couldn't fix it, they couldn't remediate it. And so they brought in
American workers and they brought in American materials,
like steel and concrete and rebar and everything
and they had, they added three stories to it that were now, like, secure and bug free.
Right.
And it was funny because I remember very specifically
on CBS evening news because they were using,
they were having meetings and instead of talking or writing anything down,
they remember those old wax pads with the saran wrap on the front
and you would write on it and then peel it up and put it back down and write on it again.
-- They were using those meetings to communicate.
-- That's hilarious.
-- You know, I've not heard that there's got to be a book about it from the
-- eighties.
It's, I remember when I was a little kid, I mean,
but yeah, it was just, it was, it was so bad that they, yeah, they had to, you know,
to do it securely, they had to import all the materials, workers, everything,
add three stories to the top of this building
and just, you know,
have everybody agree not to talk about anything interesting on the,
in the rest of the building. Right.
Oh, man.
But here, so here's the thing. Right. Here's the thing too.
There's
that stories like this
are when you have an active adversary.
But
from the iot angle where we're talking
about these cameras and toasters and whatever
else like this is purely passive badness and it's already out of control.
What happens if there were like active Attackers in this space, it would be
a total disaster.
It certainly wouldn't be pretty,
we're
doomed.
It's, well,
the economics are such that we're in a new area and we haven't figured this out yet,
you know, and,
and quite frankly, so far we've been willing to eat the cost just like, you know,
car desks have come down, especially when you look over all, like,
per passenger model, they've really come down
and we've deemed that they're acceptable.
Yeah,
I, I guess so. That and, and maybe that's exactly what this is. We are going to decide
that
in iot Wild West on the internet is acceptable.
I
do
have
a
choice.
-- No,
-- we don't. We really don't because, I mean, this is
unfixable.
I mean, we've, we, we talked about this,
this is the trolley problem where you don't throw the switch and
the trolley rolls away. You do throw the switch, it runs you over. Right.
Like, that's a pretty clear option.
There is nobody on the planet who would be like,
I'm going to throw the switch and murder myself instead of the
trolley just careening off down the street and maybe hitting someone,
maybe not.
Who knows. It doesn't matter to me.
Yeah. Yeah.
No, it's, um, and I mean, I SPS especially don't want to get involved in this because,
you know, common carrier status and all that and whatever.
I mean, there's no such thing as common carrier status anymore
that annoys me to no end.
Well. True.
But it's at the point where they don't have to actually spend money fixing it,
which is what they want.
Oh, my goodness. Whatever this is,
uh,
I know,
that's why I don't buy home automation equipment and I will not
-- for the foreseeable future.
-- I know what you mean, man, I,
every now and then
I'll walk through the store and I see some of this clever stuff where
you've got these like magic doorbells or these crazy lights with the apps or,
or what not.
I'm like, wow, that'd be fun to have them. No, don't do that.
You know what's gonna happen.
Yeah. And I,
it's not, you know, you know,
what's gonna end up happening is someday I'm probably gonna get some
and I'm gonna end up building like a secondary internet with,
with its own dedicated connection
from another provider or something. Completely ridiculous.
And I'm gonna be spending hundreds of dollars a
month to secure like a $4 light bulb I bought
totally justified.
Yeah. No, it's, I, I don't know. I mean,
the reality is it's happening and
so
we started out talking about planned obsolescence and
I guess let's bring it back there
to, to kind of wrap it all up is I think
maybe that's going to be the answer is
we have a sort of forced obsolescence in the iot universe where
this stuff self destructs on purpose after a set amount of time.
But
I,
I guess initially you're going to have to trick people into not
thinking that's real because they will lose their minds if they do.
But I imagine this would be like almost anything else where eventually
in time it will be an expected reality where you
will buy devices and they will have a very specific
lifespan.
And when that's done it's done
well. And part of it too is, I mean, I look at TV.
S and they've come down in price ridiculously, you know, a $500 TV now is
60 or 70 inches.
You know, they're ridiculously huge and cheap
and, and part of it is like,
you know, well, light bulbs back to light bulbs.
Did I get angry whenever I had to swap out an incandescent light bulb? Not really.
It was just, that was how life was,
but
it's right.
It, it, it is what it was, but they also didn't say this light bulb will stop,
stop working on December 27th
print.
It's not, I'm sure it's not in any print. I mean, the light bulbs are pretty clear.
1000 hour lifespan.
Right.
Well, no, but what I mean is if they do have to announce it,
they'll put in the fine print, people won't read it,
it'll break and some people may complain, lose their minds.
But by and large, I think
when I look at all these, you know, products that have,
uh,
pieces that, you know, intentionally or, well,
they intentionally fail at a certain time.
Uh, you know, people have largely accepted that. Um,
yeah. Yes.
It, well, but there's the illusion of control
where if it's breaking
you don't know the day or the hour and you think that
maybe I'll get lucky and it'll last extra long or maybe
I'll take really good care of this thing or whatever.
But if it's in a purely electronic device
-- there is, but
-- people throw their wi fi routers out all the time.
I've probably been through over two dozen in the last two decades.
I only throw them away when they die.
Well, my, I kill mine a lot though too. It's for, for whatever reason. I, I don't know.
-- I have bad luck with
-- routers.
Well, for example, I, you know,
I've thrown out all but one or two of my 2.4
gigahertz one because quite frankly five gigahertz works so much better,
you know, things like that.
And, you know, and, and part of it too, is that a
device that costs five or $10
-- versus something that costs $500?
-- Right.
Well, and I mean, I don't know about you, but I'm buying routers in the,
like 1 to $200 range typically.
So
I,
if I paid $200 for something
and
I knew the day it was going to die,
I might be hesitant to purchase it, even if I knew it wasn't the right thing to do.
Right.
I
would agree.
Whereas if it, if it's $5 I'd probably be like, yeah, whatever. I don't care.
Oh,
I think what will happen to you is there's other
ways to give the illusion of control or to ideally,
you know,
make your product so sexy that people want to upgrade to the new shiny version.
And there's always, I mean, cell phones are kind of like that
but
it's certain things, I mean, a light, a light bulb just gives off light.
How are you gonna make that?
-- They
-- also play music now and they do different colors.
Who wants a light bulb?
Plays music?
The senha are
ones, they actually look pretty cool.
I almost bought some but then again, I was like, no bad.
Don't buy these, but
you should get them and tell me how they work. I'm super interested in this.
They have a blue,
I want like a demo
go buy
expensive. How much?
Like I, when I looked they were over 100 bucks each. That's a
lot. But that was like two years ago.
You should
play
music. It
-- has, it plays music and does mood lighting.
-- You know, you want
one. You should go look again.
Do you know you do?
Yeah. So
-- we should set up a Kickstarter campaign to uh get Kurt some IOT
-- devices.
Lord. No.
Oh, my kids would probably love it.
Yeah. Yeah, they would. But you would hate it
and you'd still do it because it's free IOT devices.
So,
in summary,
we have no idea.
-- Yeah, I doubt the industry does either.
-- Everything is terrible.
Uh Yeah, let's just end it there and acknowledge that this is,
this is a crazy problem that clearly has no
good solution today and we'll keep thinking about it.
I'm certain we'll discuss it again.
So in the meantime,
if you have thoughts or questions or wanna tell us how ridiculous we are,
it's the Twitter Os S podcast. Hashtag
You can also go to open source security podcast.com
for the show notes and various other bits and pieces
and
you have nothing else.
Thanks for listening folks, Kurt,
you have a fantastic day and I will speak with you soon.
Thanks. You too.