Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner are not really understanding how the web works.
Josh Bresser.
That's right. But luckily we have an expert with us today, Daniel Stenberg, the,
I guess the, the creator of curl. Would that be accurate?
I would say that is correct. Yeah.
All right. That's fair. Daniel. Welcome, man. We're so excited to have you here.
-- It's good to be here. Good to meet
-- you. All right.
So I'm just gonna start with the one question everyone has on their minds.
Why don't you just rewrite Curl and Rust in a weekend
in three days?
So I get this question a lot about rewriting curl. Of course.
And, and for some reason, it's always rust.
But, but
that's such a big question.
But, but of course, first,
we created Curl a very long time before rust even existed or
there weren't really any
good options for the first few decades.
And
by now then it's,
it's a pretty big vehicle and everything works and it's quite
a big job to just consider a rewrite into anything.
And I also consider that one of the
one of the big good things with curly is that it runs and exists everywhere.
It sort of,
it sells it to the next platform and the next platform
so you can use the same API on pretty much anything.
And that's, I think that's a
-- good pitch for,
-- for. No, you're right. It's kind of like V I in that.
-- It's always there and it works.
-- Yeah. And even the library is like that.
So even if you write your application today on with the API in one platform, right?
And you can switch to another tomorrow and it's the same API is there big systems,
small systems?
So it's having that
you, so that it's
actually exists everywhere has been a huge benefit for all users.
And that
has been a pretty big factories that is written in c
the most portable thing.
So it has been a sort of a success factor but of course in the backside and yeah,
it's not memory safe.
So there is we have this bus load of unfortunate problems coming with it.
So sure, I, so the
I could imagine introducing more memory safe languages going forward,
but I'm not going to do that as one single rewrite take.
But
I could possibly consider, you know, replacing components and
using more third party libraries that are written in
rust rather than written in C if they exist.
And if they're good enough and if that is sort of what the
uh
the user community wants to go.
Uh A lot of people are sort of begging asking
saying we should all go to those libraries and,
but
um looking where the users are going today, they are not going with those choices,
right?
They exist and they're out there, they've been here now for years,
but that's not why I see where I see users going,
even if they, even when they exist as sort of
at least semi
decent alternatives like the TLS libraries and other things,
I want to, I want to pull that thread
because you have one of the most widely used applications on the
planet and off the planet for that matter because I mean,
curl is running literally everywhere
in space.
And
you mentioned about the users aren't going there with these various
memory safe libraries and languages in, in all this stuff. And
I think if you look at curl,
the
kind of user experience of it
has
it, it's phenomenal, right?
I mean, there's a command line application but it works very well.
The library is very easy to use
and I'm, I'm curious your thoughts on,
on how did you end up in a place where you
basically built an extremely user friendly command line application and library.
Suddenly
I've never considered myself sort of user friendly in that
I don't sort of work very much with users.
So it's,
I wouldn't say that it's by accident maybe. But
I think I had
a little bit of a fortunate or luck when I decided that
it would be oriented around URL S the way it is so that
you could sort of put different URL S and it doesn't really matter.
So you don't have to think about it. And
-- sorry,
-- stupid question.
But if you're writing a web library that gets stuff from the web,
how would you do it any other way than oriented around URL
S?
So
it just, it seems
to me
that that's a very good question. But um
uh
originally when I started making libraries, right,
the other libraries that existed, they were not really oriented around URL S,
they were more, you do an HTP oriented thing.
So you would sort of create it around the, the more
mechanics to the components within the HTP.
I'm just trying to remember having a flashback to like 25 years ago.
-- It was FTP. Kurt, it was all
-- FTP. No, but no, you're, you're, you're right in thought.
It was
essentially, yeah,
-- you had to construct the request yourself.
-- Exactly.
So they were more low level and more you would have to
understand or sort of at least work with the protocol more.
And I wanted to
avoid the use of having to know a lot about the protocol, but more talk about
uh well,
the end point and then sort of magically fix things for you
so that you could do different protocols pretty much without understanding the.
So then you could do an FTP URL and an HTP URL and it would get the data the same way,
even though you, the protocols are completely different underneath.
That's fair.
That's a good point.
So then, and then, and then my pretty early,
very early on realized that people really do not want things to change, right?
If you write a script today, you
don't want Carl to sort of, no, we changed a few options or change things.
So everything would break down the road, right? So we very quickly figured out
-- we should just stick with everything, whatever we ship, keep it like that
-- forever.
I think it boils down to like Linna says, do not break user space.
Exactly.
Yeah. No, I, I really respect that.
One thing that drives me nuts is I wish
there was like more of a standard dash
I dash hole for input output files and stuff. But I get like once you pick something
that's it like it's, it has to stay that way.
-- Yeah.
-- Exactly.
Because then you get a trade off,
you sure you want to be compatible with other tools that also use the same kind of,
but you want to be compatible with yourself from the past as well.
So you have that weird situation. So
sure you want to be like the others, but you also don't want to break your other users.
So
mm and I,
when you've been around for a long time.
I decided all those early options very early.
That was, you know, basically 1997 times. So,
maybe a few of them were not very cleverly
chosen and maybe I should have done it differently.
But
-- that's long gone now. Right. So, it's too late.
-- The
thing is, I mean, in reality though,
you can't optimize a problem until you've solved it and used it for a while.
Like that's one thing I keep running into with
kind of, a lot of these tools is and their options is just, oh, we didn't, we,
it's not that we didn't know any better.
We could not have known any better.
Like, for example,
you're going to have options you're gonna need in five years with H TB version.
What is it now? Three or two, no, three quick.
Like, there's gonna be new stuff that you can even predict 10 years ago.
Exactly.
And a lot of those we did add back in
the days we don't need anymore because that's sort of,
that's how we did the internet 20 years ago.
Right. So now we have short options for things.
No one ever is going to use totally wasted. But we,
but yeah, that's exactly how it just turns out that way.
All right, I'm gonna steer this bus into the security lane because that's,
that's why we're here after all.
So, I'm curious, your thoughts,
Daniel on all of the security people complain nonstop.
How curl pipe to bash is like the most insecure thing ever in the history of the world
yet. It is probably the most popular way to install software ever. Yeah,
I would, I would, I mean, it amuses me to no end that everyone complains.
Everyone still uses it.
I'm, I'm curious your thoughts on this, just like,
when you hear security people complaining and whining that it's a horrible thing.
-- Yes.
-- I, in my view it's not that horrible.
I mean, it, it's not the best thing because it's sure
trusting something and you're just piping it to your,
to your shell.
I mean,
in the worst case as a pseudo and your shell like that,
but in most cases people are actually, I mean, there's some kind of trust to the site.
You're, you're downloading that content from anyway, like,
when you're installing,
I don't know, I know
Homebrew or r they have that as documented ways to install it,
but you're downloading it from their official websites.
Right. You're,
you're there already. You're viewing the site, you trust it.
So
the difference from downloading that script and
running it or running it immediately,
it's a very subtle difference. Sure, you can do it in better ways. I agree. But
I often think that people actually are overreacting to that thing.
But of course, if you go with just a random site somewhere on the internet,
you can just run it then, yes, that's totally insecure.
But
that's rarely what people are doing when they do this.
That's also true of all those old shareware sites that were like, not two cows,
right?
Like,
you know, we download dot exes from
wherever.
Like I,
I literally bought a web camera and it said to get the
drivers go to this IP address slash something slash dot exe.
And I'm like,
I, I put it through virus total and it scanned clean and I'm like, ok,
but I, my only complaint about curl pipe to bash would be
you might get an error so it might not work. Right.
I, I can't like easily download it and keep it.
And number two is like, there's no versioning or what am I getting? Right?
And it's almost always the latest.
And I, so for me, I personally don't like it from a reliability perspective.
I don't, honestly, from a security perspective, I mean,
I'm downloading software from
repositories and II, I don't inspect it like
I don't have time for that.
Yeah.
So, yeah.
As long as it's http si mean, if it's not http S then obviously
that's bad.
That's
exactly as long as it's htps
and you're downloading it from, from a place that you actually trust.
I mean,
it's one of those sites you actually want to not
just a random thing with a lot of digits somewhere.
Someone told you to download
it always amuses me when I see like the,
the, the old retro computer enthusiasts that are, like,
I found this executable on this website and it had the drivers for the thing.
And I'm like, oh, my goodness, like, this is my nightmare.
-- That
-- guy that wrote that made that USB card for TRS eighties
and got some drivers off of an old B BS mirror from,
like,
and it's just like that,
that's actually how we used to do this. Like, you'd go to a,
-- yeah, you just download stuff and make it work and security
-- for a very long time.
Exactly. We did that for a very long time.
I mean, I guess a lot of people are still doing it. So, yes,
-- I would
-- assume if I buy a smart fridge, that's what it's doing.
Yeah. Right. Right.
Oh, my goodness.
Ok. Let's talk about memory safety for a little bit because
you mentioned a little while ago how Curl isn't written in a memory safe language.
But I do want to comment for as widely used as Curl is
and no doubt as much attention as it receives from security researchers.
I feel like there are not very many security vulnerabilities
in
Curl. Like, is this
an accident? Is it on purpose? Are you mindful of the, the way it's written?
I
it is not, it's,
we're, we're doing a lot of work and making sure that we,
that we limit and, and limit down and,
and reduce the amount of security problems that we suffer from.
But sure we have our share of it.
Uh So yeah, we do everything we can to make sure that we, we do it as good as possible.
You know, all the tools and all the analyzers and fuzzing and
uh nonstop and we have a bag bounty.
So we pay researchers cash for the report security problems.
So that's um,
yeah, so I think we're doing pretty much as from an engineering
point of view. we're doing everything that we can.
There, there are really no silver bullets on how to do it, right.
You just have to do everything and, and then
do everything
slightly better all the time and maybe learn from your mistakes and do
-- it a little better next time when you've done a mistake once
-- so.
Well, my one suspicion was always and maybe this is wrong or right, but
curl talks to everything straight up everything, right? So
for it to work,
you have to basically support every corner case
and every bit of weirdness and every little strangeness
and I can't help but think that that essentially
forces you to write very robust code because you,
you can't make, basically you cannot make assumptions,
any assumption would be unsafe because there's
definitely a web developer out there.
That was like, no, I think that's a bad idea. I'm going to do it this way,
you know, and I,
is that the case?
Uh
um
Yes and no, I think,
I mean, yeah, that goes as far as you get all those corner cases from the valid,
uh, situations. Right. That could happen. I think
that's the tricky part is still when there's a malicious intent somewhere,
that sort of, you know,
finds that weird thing that nobody actually ever implemented
it this way because it would be crazy.
But, but when you do it, but someone can figure that out and, oh,
you could also have this really strange value into a
field somewhere and then we would treat it badly,
right?
Uh
So,
so yeah, sure it gets pretty good when we, we're,
we're working with all the edge cases, but
then we still have to
just apply a lot of common sense, read code review. And
of course, um
I would say just try to write code in a sensible way. That's
easy to understand, easy to debug and easy to spot those problems, you know,
the memory
overflows, the how to handle buffers and everything.
And over over there,
I would say maybe four or five
last year. So we've
also made an effort in a while ago. II, I guess it was maybe 566 years ago.
I,
I spotted that we had several security problems in a sort of related kind of code and I
figure out that I should really reduce this kind of thing so
that we don't accidentally slip in more of these kinds of problems.
So I sort of try to
introduce more helper functions into curl that we could use than to
reduce the sort of the risk that we would introduce this problem.
Again,
one of those things and one of those
I would say theoretical problems is that it's an integer overflow,
which is very common in like in C when you,
you do, for,
for example, you have a length of data and you add a number and then you malo
that size to get the data, right?
And then
we had several of those problems when someone figured out.
Oh, well, on a 32 bit system,
if you have this huge buffer and you enter that and we take,
you know the buffer multiply it by four and add something sure it could wrap
uh in memory and you would get a mao
of three bytes and copy four gigabytes and that would be bad, right?
So, but
OK, really, really, really hard to actually execute in in, in real world.
But maybe in some cases you could. So it was a security problem. But
like that, we make sure that we basically everywhere.
Nowadays we limit the maximum string size you can pass into the library.
Why be why accept half a gigabyte when maybe eight megabytes? It's crazy big anyway.
So just limit it to that and things like that sort of put some artificial, well,
not artificial but some limits here and there to limit
the the the risk of us doing those mistakes.
Again, totally.
So that way, I think we slowly gradually actually improve or,
or we reduce the risk of introducing those same things trying
to learn from past mistakes and and not do them again.
Uh 11 question, do you like, do you share test cases with other web clients? Like
I was just looking at your test suite director and there's
like a bunch of profiles and a bunch of micro servers,
blah, blah blah.
But for example, do you and w get for the sake of argument, like say, you know,
here's a test case, here's a new one
and share them or is that a thing in the industry at all?
It's not.
Um I mean, it, it would be good. I mean, I think we could all benefit from that.
I, there are some
other projects that are reusing our test suites and,
and I know a proxy that is testing their stuff with our test suites.
So I think it's good.
Otherwise I think our test suite is very, very much crafted for,
for curl for our purposes and, and for our use, it's
might be a bit bit of work to, to generalize it, to be useful for others.
Of course, it,
it would have been good if we would have been
even more people to sort of help out and contribute to
um a common test suite. But that, that's not the case here.
Totally. All right. All right, let's, let's keep going down this road
you recently
got, I'll say a bit of attention for some CV E incidents
that you're quite vocal about. I'm,
and in fact, we did a whole show on this. I mean,
it was,
you, you're here, like, tell us your story.
Oh, yeah, there's been so much CBE recently, so, yeah. So,
yeah.
Yeah. Yeah.
Where to start.
Of course.
Yeah, I started the venture, of course, by complaining, uh,
the NVD always sort of inflating our, uh CV ES whenever they can
or, and, and they think that's a good thing.
So they tend to sort of
host our CV with a very high scores.
When, when I think that's completely wrong, I think it doesn't help anyone.
I think they're
scaremongering and,
and, and the effect of that since they sort of inflate everything
nowadays,
a lot of people seem to be using these scanners or
scanning for software and they use those scores for CBS.
So now suddenly I get a lot of feedback from users saying,
hey, I found these CV s in,
there's always on windows nowadays so they found a
curl on windows. It's vulnerable for this CB, you know, scored high as
a whatever,
what should I do?
And I tried to argue that, no, no, it's not that bad.
It's just, you know, it's just a medium or a low security problem because blah, blah,
blah,
but that's not what their scanners say.
And a lot of people now have these contracts when they say they're
obligated to fix their uh scanning warnings within these number of days.
So, what do they do?
-- Well, they, they email me and cry about it, but I can't do much about it so
-- well.
Ok. So first comment because this is something that comes up a lot. Uh So
just so viewers know the NVD is the
national vulnerability database and it is funded by
and run by the US government for the US government.
And what a lot of people forget is that these CV SS scores
are for the US government.
Now,
the problem is everybody else uses them because there's
no other freely available source of CV SS scores,
right?
And so the US government makes this like worst case assumption of like, well,
somebody could be using this curl thing in a stupid, crazy way
as root,
root, like grabbing random stuff from God knows where.
So that's the first comment is that the CV S scoring is wrong in the
sense of people are using it wrong because they're not the US government probably.
But the second thing I don't understand is
they're scanning their software,
they're finding a curl version that is out of date with a vulnerability.
Why are they talking to you? Like you already released the patch? No, I, I like I'm
serious. Like, what are you supposed to do?
It's like, well, here's the patch, like here's the new version we,
-- we did.
-- Yeah, exactly. Yeah.
But then there's this huge disconnect from the world who is using, they're using
but they have no idea how to actually get that
fix into their machines. So, yeah, why are they emailing me?
Because they find out that I'm behind curl.
Do you just send them the latest tar ball of curl and be like, here you go.
No, because what else are you like?
Yeah.
Well, yeah, what else can I do? I,
I really can't do anything.
And in, in the case of windows,
I can't do anything at all because you have to fix it with windows itself,
you have to do it with windows update.
Otherwise you break windows update.
So,
so what I can just say you,
you need to contact Microsoft about that or just wait until they fix it.
Um,
and that's not a really good message. No one likes that.
-- Ah,
-- this is so amusing and, and I don't,
do you still get the emails from people complaining about their cars?
I recall because your email was in like the back of car manuals.
-- People were emailing you about their cars. Yeah,
-- I get car questions every now
and then
I
actually get questions about pretty much everything
because people find my email address in,
in everything.
I sort of get that because by definition, these people, like,
they're flailing around and they find a name and an email address and so they hit it,
right.
Like,
we used to run an answer column
at the, at the, uh, security portal.com. This is like pre 2000.
And,
yeah, we would get people
with like crazy stories saying I need help.
My computer's been hacked, blah, blah, blah. And we're like, yeah, we can't help.
We're not gonna help, like, take it to a computer store.
Yeah.
And I'm pretty sure that in many times my
email sticks out because it's the current license.
So, so
do these open source collections.
That's my, my,
and I think in many other cases they don't have the email and the licenses.
So, you know,
we have to scroll through that list of 100 and 50
licenses and then somewhere in there that's an email address.
I'm gonna mail that guy and ask about my GPS problem and he's going to fix it for me.
Oh, my goodness.
Ok. How much, like random, weird email like that do you get?
It's got to be ridiculous.
Well,
how much? Yeah, I, suddenly, every week I get some kind of email about,
there's,
they're often also about games because it seems to be fairly popular in games.
So I get a lot of games questions, you know, fixing
people's problems in how to solve games and game accounts and stuff like that.
Yeah, I get a lot of V PM questions.
It goes in waves suddenly sometimes, you know, when some app
in particular has a problem doing a particular phase or some bugs or whatever.
I can get a huge amount of emails for some particular product,
you know, out of the blues.
I have no idea what they're talking about,
but suddenly I get a sort of a flood of emails
and then they might go away or come back and,
yeah,
it's funny because it's not me.
I actually find it kind of curious in many times because it sort of reveals, oh,
curl is used by this little thing that they were emailing me about.
Oh, in that kitchen thing in that car, in that fridge, in that printer, you know,
but, but what else would they use? Like if I have to go get something from the web,
I'm
everybody knows curl like
yeah,
like literally there's curl and w get, what else would there be
like? I can't even think of anything off the top of my head,
right?
But if you would write an application on, on a, on a device somewhere,
there are alternatives and in particularly if you would do it on a mobile phone,
for example,
there are Android solutions that would do it or
I OS solutions that would do it differently.
So there are
definitely competitors and alternatives to use
because just back to the Microsoft thing, I've just actually ran curl and so yeah,
curls installed by default on windows since whatever version some long time ago.
But what's interesting is the hyphen version hyphen hyphen version.
None of that stuff works.
Like I'm trying to figure out what version of Curl do I actually have installed?
And I'm like,
I'll tell you why because you're not running Curl. When you type that,
it's an alias thing.
Yeah,
that's another sore point here. So you,
you stepped right into it.
Sorry. What, so what am I when I run Curl in powershell? What is it?
-- What is it actually
-- running? That's an alias for another powershell command.
So yeah, they did that before. They had the real curl.
They introduced an alias for another thing that's totally not curl at all.
Oh Invoke web request. OK.
Yeah, because I was like this does not look at all like curl or behave like curl.
-- So
-- if you, if you invoke it as curl dot xe, you get the
curl,
the real curl.
So I'm hearing Microsoft rewrote curl in a weekend. That's what I just heard.
Yeah. No, it just, it, it runs something called invoke web request,
which is a Powershell thing I'm assuming.
Lovely. I'm sure that doesn't break everything. Right.
-- Yeah,
-- exactly. So
-- we get questions about that too.
-- Yeah.
Yeah. Like because yeah, because when I ran it, I was like, what
some weird,
yeah, I've actually never
on windows before I realized
like never in my life.
Well, I have Linux
like
I'm not gonna run this on windows
until now. All right. All right. So let's back to the CV. E topic.
So you had all these difficulties with CV E and
your solution was to become AC N A
and I'm curious your thoughts on that whole
thing.
-- So,
-- ok, so,
so when I got this most recent bogus CV E that
someone filed against Carl 2020 19 909 or whatever it is,
which was clearly not a
security problem at all, whatever might recess about it.
Um,
because they, of course says that it is
-- well,
-- and again, I mean, I was on a CV board,
they don't
validate anything. They can't, right.
Like there's close source CV S like, I don't have a copy of
-- Hai's nuclear power plant controls
-- often.
But in this case, I, I submitted a rejection to them with a full motivation,
including all my information
about it, you know, source code links to the patches, everything and said
this is not a security problem.
Look at the patches, here's the explanation, but they,
but they still insist that now it could have a security impact
without, you know, without going into how or why or anything. And it's just some
group email saying that
end of discussion.
So, ok, so they think it's a security problem but it's not.
And because they think it, it's a security problem,
it remains a CV E and then it remains.
And by uh NV DS
keeps it hosted and they,
but it's OK. My secondary thing was then to complain to NVD and say,
how can you score this as
whatever they scored it? Um
And you should just, yeah, they scored it 9.8 and then I,
I complained to them and it ended up as a 3.3 after my complaint
and again, back to NVD. Sure they, they do a worst case scenario.
But when the, the only information they have says, integrate overflow,
what is the worst case?
Probably pretty bad
because what kind of input do you do in integra overflow?
That could be really, really bad or it could be nothing. But anyway, so since II, I
don't like the situation, I think there's so many
bad steps along this way,
I think one of the ways I can limit the damage here is to
actually register as AC N A because then I can get a better say about
uh future CV S that concerns products that I am sort of
in my scope as AC N A which then becomes curl products, curl and lib
-- pretty much
-- well and again to history for the viewers. So
how do I put this nicely? The CV program was a great thing 25 years ago.
And unfortunately, it's still basically the same thing and
the world has changed.
And number two is even as a board member,
like I kind of tried to find out how CV E actually works within Miter
and I was unable to
like for example, who is doing that work,
like the actual names of the human beings doing that work.
II, I don't know.
Right. And I was a board member for what, like, 67 years, something like that.
Um, so
-- that's all I got.
-- So,
I guess your frustration is totally expected
-- and, and no one knows what to do
-- and,
and the solution of you have to become
a CV numbering authority and jump through those hoops
so that you can have that sort of first rate of refusal is in my opinion,
utterly, utterly ridiculous because
like I get that
it just doesn't scale.
No, it's totally ridiculous.
And I also feel a little bit selfish for doing this because
we can, everyone can't do this. It's not, it doesn't scale. It's a crazy thing.
So I, I understand that it's really not a long term solution for anyone.
It's rather a short term solution for me,
but that's also
sure.
So, but yeah, I'm doing it anyway and it seems to,
I'm actually not accepted there yet.
So sort of we're in the process. So we,
we're a few weeks off here because I've had all the interviews.
I've done all the things.
So it's just a few more steps in the dance to become accepted there.
But it seems to be a rather low administration for us.
So I think it's not going to be a big hurdle for us. It's very limited to only our CV ES.
Yeah.
Well, I mean, and the dirty, the dirty secret is, there's a lot of CNAs that have, uh,
one of my favorite ones.
They've done six CV ES over the course of their
entire career and they all point at marketing pages now.
Right. So, there's like, there's a lot of CNAs that shouldn't be CNAs and there's,
well, I mean, I think we can all agree if, like,
something like curl should be somehow involved in this process better.
You know, there's a lot of software like that, like,
yeah.
Yeah. I don't know.
I don't know what to say.
That's one of the reasons I quit the board.
Exactly.
I don't know what to say. That's a sort of a comment.
All right. All right.
So, I wanna, I wanna bring this one home with the kind of community angle to curl.
I, I just looked on Mastodon and a couple of days ago you had
you, every time you have a new committer to curl you, like, put a little blur.
But, which I think is phenomenal. Like, that's amazing. And it was number what, 1209
1000, 209 contributors to Curl, which is
bananas and, and I'm sure it's more than that by now, probably.
And by the time this comes out it'll be far more.
-- It's actually,
-- exactly by the time this comes out, but it's actually 1209. Exactly.
Right now.
Well, you said that two days ago. So,
so, so
I think it cannot be understated
that the community of people you have constructed around this tool
is phenomenal and gigantic and without question,
contributes to part of that success.
And so the question I have is obviously on one hand,
there's like managing a community and building a community.
But then also I feel like
how do you get all this done in a day?
You, I mean, you're, you're all over the place, right?
You're managing a community, you're building an application, you're,
you're doing security work with,
with CV E and miter and every and it's just like
I look at you and I feel like I am pathetic.
Well, what can I say? Iii I do my best.
I try to, to, to be effective at doing the things I do and I need to do and of course,
when it comes to the sort of the community and a lot of contributors around it,
it's
I try to just keep,
uh treat everyone fair in the same way and just make
sure that I thank everyone and accept their contributions and I,
you know, put the feedback cycle back
the way I would have wanted it to be. And I think the way it,
the more curl is used and the better it has succeeded and the more it's used,
it sort of it feeds back.
So more people are actually interested in fixing
things because more people are using it.
So it's a positive spin in that regard
and
then how to do it.
I, I have a lot of people helping out uh I mean,
more and then just providing uh pull request as well.
So we're, we're a whole team these days
and we
just try to do the best we can to make sure things are
progressing as it as they should.
Now you work for wolf SSL. Right.
Yes.
So
how many like staff do they have? Like essentially maintaining curl?
-- That's basically me.
-- OK. OK.
Which is, I mean, that's amazing.
Still like the fact that they're willing to invest in that I think is phenomenal.
I think that's actually healthier in some ways because it's
more sustainable to have the community actually supporting it.
And
I think this is one of the cases like the
kernel where like
the community should be able to do this because this is a slightly,
somewhat widely used piece of software.
Like, no, really. Like
this isn't some niche thing,
you know, and I, that, yeah,
that was always my concern with Red Hat when
Red Hat had all the developers working on it,
paying them and if Red Hat decides not to do it anymore.
-- Poof.
-- Yeah.
Right.
-- So that's the, that's the question I always get then what happens when I stop?
-- Yeah.
-- Like I would be sad if curl stopped working. Like,
-- yeah,
very,
very sad.
Well, I, I, even if I would stop. I don't think it would stop working. You know,
I don't plan to
and I don't plan to stop at working at curl anytime soon anyway.
So I, I plan on continuing this.
But I also,
I get this question quite a lot, so I'm not alone here and I also always make a really
strong effort to make sure that everything
we do is completely open.
You know, all the processes, all the code, everything is there.
So even if I would go on an extended vacation tomorrow, um,
it wouldn't really stop anything.
It wouldn't possibly make a little dent in the speed on
how to do things because I do quite a lot.
But
it's, it wouldn't be a,
it wouldn't stop anything. It wouldn't be that big of a
problem
over time.
Awesome. Awesome. I mean, that's the dream, right?
You've, you've got,
you build your community and then the community becomes its own thing.
Oh, yeah. It's, it's certainly the dream. I mean,
I, I'm already living the dream here.
I'm, I'm working with my spare time project full time. Yeah. So.
Oh man.
So, ok. So let's end on that note.
Then you said working on my spare time project full time.
Obviously, you started doing curl part time in the nineties, obviously.
At what point did you realize? Like this is it, I'm, this is my job now.
This is what I'm doing.
Well, it took forever. I, I, um,
I started working with curl full time in 2019.
So, the 1st
21 years or so I did it on my spare time.
-- So, yeah, it took a long time until I actually got it to become my job.
-- Holy cow.
I didn't realize it was. That,
that, that's like, I guess late. Oh, my goodness. 2019.
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah, exactly. I'm soon celebrating my fifth year as full time curl.
Yeah. Wow.
-- Amazing. Holy cow.
-- It was also partly because it's, it's a difficult step.
How do you actually sort of
how do you, how do you make money from something like this?
And how do you do that from day one or? It's hard to ramp up and it's
me. Right. And where's the money? And blah, blah, blah.
There's a lot of things that have to sort of,
I have a lot of ducks that have to be in a row to this to work. So
it was a sort of, yeah, and that particular moment in time I just had the opportunity.
I took it and then I
worked with Wolf as
Os and they sort of believed in this and signed me up for this. So,
yeah,
just worked out fine.
That's fantastic.
Awesome. Awesome. Alright.
Alright, we come to the end, Daniel, I'll give you the last word on this one.
What do you want everyone to know
reduce Carl Moore?
You know what
I agree because I've seen people write their own Janky or use weird niche
web clients and it does not end well and well, no
ignoring security that just stuff breaks.
That's a good point. Exactly.
They don't have the expertise to be like, oh, this
niche server that now is 6 million servers or,
or like Yahoo picks it and all of a sudden, like, 30% of the web is using this thing.
Like, that's the thing I keep running into with all these web clients is like,
yeah, like just stuff breaks.
You mentioned, you mentioned what else you would use instead of curl.
And I think exactly what you're mentioning, that's some often my main
biggest competitor, especially when I talked to uh companies who are you
smaller systems?
Because from a lot of uh development board providers, they might ship their own.
Here's a Sa Mle HDP client and, you know,
that's 45 lines and you don't, it's very small and you can just, you know,
you don't need that big old curl. It's too big and, you know, complicated.
Here's a little tiny thing and it also works. But then, then I have to have it.
Yeah, sure.
It might work for that particular use case for a short while while you try this out,
but it's not really, you know.
Yeah.
So you don't work in the lab.
Yeah, for a while maybe. Yeah.
And as much as I hate to see a software monoculture,
at least I'd rather see a well maintained healthy monoculture versus like,
yeah, a 45 line.
Yeah, like in my head, I'm just like, thinking, like,
can I even fit all the status code handling in 45 lines?
Usually not.
And usually you have to do a lot of weird assumptions or Presumptions or, you know,
crazy things for that to work.
-- You only need
-- two of those. It's fine.
-- 200 everything else.
-- That's right
that you happened to see just now when you tried it out. Yeah.
Oh my goodness. This has been, this has been an absolute treat, Daniel.
I want to thank you so much for joining us today.
Thanks for inviting me. Well, this was fun.
-- Fantastic.
-- All right. Thank you everyone for listening.
Go to open source security, podcast.com. Head up the show. Not Suzy Pound
O says podcast. Hashtag on Mastodon,
-- Kurt and Daniel have marvelous rest of your days. You too.
-- Thanks everybody.
Thank you. Awesome. Thanks everyone. Bye bye.