Hello and welcome to the open source security podcast episode 31 with myself,
Kurt Siefried and my partner in crime, Josh Bresser.
-- Do you know what is interesting about the number 31?
-- Kurt? Is it prime?
It is.
It's a merc
prime, in fact, which makes it a special prime
right now. Remind me. Well, no, don't
tell me what that is because I've completely forgotten.
Math is hard that no.
So
-- to do
-- with rulers, it
has nothing to do with rulers. It might, I don't know.
Anyway, it's basically two to the power of N minus one.
And there are a handful of primes that
fall into that category which are known as Merce
primes and
in the universe of prime numbers,
they are considered special for, well, for obvious reasons, right?
Because when you're dealing with
kind of the, the magic of computers, you've got powers of two.
And so basically in the case of a 32 bit integer, true to the power of, well,
it's not 32 bits in this case, but you get the idea, right?
True to the power of whatever bits minus one would basically be
a very large prime number you could represent on certain architectures,
which is, is less important today than it used to be
long.
But regardless, prime 31 how exciting,
you know, well, what really amuses me is um on my iphone when uh I go to search,
you know,
you swipe down to search for something and it does the helpful web search when you,
when you start with the letter E it immediately,
you know, e the irrational number
it like, defines it for you and pulls it up on the screen
and that just amuses me every time.
That is hilarious. Why would it, do you use E a lot or
no?
But it's just, I guess as far as letters go, that's one of the few that has like a very,
you know, like
a solid search result.
I mean,
can you imagine how many people Google for the letter E
because like their math class covered it and they're lost?
Maybe, I don't know.
I guess I never thought about it when, when I was a, we didn't have Google. So
I had to go to the library to find information.
-- This is true.
-- Right.
Interesting.
So, speaking of mathematical constants,
there's been an amusing bit of news from a hotel in Austria, I believe.
How is that related to a mathematical constant?
Well, things that should behave in certain, predictable ways, but then they don't,
uh, you mean the door locks when everybody got locked into their rooms.
Well, and it's not so much that, but it's the,
apparently the reason why the door locks failed.
This is interesting to me.
Apparently. Ransomware is what I'm reading in this story.
Yeah, I don't, now folks to be clear,
I don't know if this is fake news or not
because apparently it's been hard to confirm this story.
But fundamentally, I'm, I'm going to pause it. It's believable. Right.
Well, I'm going to say globally speaking,
we for sure have a lot of electronic door locks which, you know,
there's been different brands that have various terrible security flaws,
like those ones with the little hole that you stick a
paper clip in and you can unlock them or whatever.
So I'm going to posit that somewhere on the planet,
somebody made a door lock that does not fail open
properly when the power goes out for whatever reason.
Right. And I think that's a believable thing.
You know, I, I would love to be proven wrong.
I really would because I, I, you know, with fire code being what fire code is,
I love the fact that if the,
you know, the power goes out,
I can get out of my burning hotel room and escape.
And that's kind of the idea behind failing open, right?
Is, is for events such as that.
Yeah, but the challenge being,
see,
my understanding of most electromagnetic locks is that
they're either active in the sense of the
power needs to be on for the electromagnet to work to hold the door locked,
right? And if the power fails, the electromagnetic disengages
and click the door opens
and you can all flee in an orderly manner.
-- Yeah,
-- and there's a lot that do work in their distance.
So in this instance,
I doubt that's the case because hotel door locks run on a small battery,
right?
And so, you know, realistically, well, you want to reduce power consumption.
-- So,
-- so actually I have a story about this is I was in a hotel, this happened recently,
maybe in November, I think it was and
the hotel room,
the door lock was acting up.
And so I go to the front desk and I say, you know that this lock is acting funny.
What's the deal help me out?
And they sent a maintenance guy to the room and I basically hung out and watched
him work on it and it took aa batteries like that's what powered the door lock.
It was crazy.
He took the whole thing apart and he was poking around at it and looking at it and yeah,
it was, I was surprised by the simplicity of how it all worked together.
Well, realistically, it's, it shouldn't be that complicated.
You know, it's a door
with Wi Fi that talks to the network that,
oh wait, no, that does sound like it gets kind of complicated
name
his last words.
But uh no, so I'm assuming these locks, obviously, you know,
you don't want to drain the batteries like every day.
So, yeah, like I, I'm, I'm pretty certain that there is a case where, you know,
that these will fail closed and it brings
to mind some interesting thoughts because for example,
like
if you do, you have a failure scenario where let's say the door lock,
you know, loses, um,
communications with sort of the master control. Do you want it to fail open?
-- Well, probably not because you could just be having a network outage,
-- right.
Well, ok, so we should also clarify though, that there are
kind of two big ifs
that, that I would say are part of this is
if you lose power or if you lose access
and if
you,
I, I guess fail closed,
you still want people on the inside to be able to open
the door and it sounds like that was not the case.
Yeah.
Yeah, I've seen, um, I mean, typically, you know, these hotel doors have like a knot,
a handle on the inside that you can turn and I'm assuming,
you know, that just mechanically opens the door, whether it's locked or not,
right? You know, much like a crash bar on a fire door, right?
You want to be able to mechanically like, because that's the other thought, right?
And I guess we should make a distinction here
losing power at the lock like the batteries run down
versus like you know, the hotel loses power,
but obviously the doors are running on batteries so they're fine.
And so obviously, you know, if the batteries run out, I don't want to be, like,
locked in my room until maintenance comes by to,
-- you know, change the lock.
-- Right. And
to my, I don't think I've seen a hotel door
that works in that way
in the past.
I, I believe all the ones I've ever experienced have some sort of manual override.
Yeah, every door I've seen, I mean, it's fire code, right.
The,
the fire code basically pretty much everywhere on the planet states
that you have to be able to open the door to egress
without special tools
or keys or anything. Right.
Like, so basically the idea is like,
anybody over the age of eight can figure this out in less than 10 seconds.
No, seriously. Right. Because, you know, the little kids
exist as a thing, you know,
and, um, you know, you don't want to have like some like mechanical puzzle lock.
You know, here's, here's part of this story is
that can be true, assuming the software is working correctly.
But I could also see an instance where you
could conceivably forcibly lock the door with the,
the, essentially the software and you now iot lock
that says
it's locked and you will not open no matter what anyone does.
True, which is why there should be a mechanical override,
right? Like when you turn the knob on the inside, it should override any
electronic system even.
And I've seen cases where it physically,
like, for example, there's a motor to lock the lock, which can be, you know,
it's not very strong.
So you can physically,
like, if it was trying to lock the lock, you could physically, unless you're like,
really weak, you could physically open,
you know, turn the knob enough to like, you know, push it and get it open.
And, but one thing that occurs to me is like, how do you test these things?
What do you mean, how do you test them? You lock it and then you open the door?
But how do you test highly complicated systems
to ensure that they always fail open?
You can't, right? You can't, you can't test every possible
scenario with something like this.
-- Now, now that said this is where
-- a mechanical override would,
-- right?
-- Yes, there's a mechanical,
but who's testing the mechanical override,
right?
This is where having labs,
independent labs that test this stuff and do the research
make a huge difference in my opinion because they can,
they can basically verify
that. Yes, no matter what is happening on the device, it will still open.
If a human being touches the inside handle and and let's face it when,
when you deal with some of these groups
like underwriters labs is a great example where
they literally like they do crazy things to this year to test it
because I, I, I've known a handful of people that,
that have gone to work there as they were.
Uh, I went to, to college not far from underwriter labs.
So, every now and then, and they, they'd hire somebody and, yeah, like, for example,
when they have to test a light switch,
they build a little machine that turns the light switch on and off till it breaks.
That's crazy.
I love IKEA has those, you know, those sitting machines
that just,
and they've had this, the IKEA, I go to,
they've had the same chair and the same sitting
machine and the counter is up until like,
well into the six digits.
Now,
I don't know what this is. So you must educate me.
It's basically, it's one of those IKEA, you know,
the Swedish chairs that have like the sweeping kind of that,
that one piece of wood on the side.
It's kind of like a lounger.
And anyway, so it's got these two kind of pads, one to simulate,
I guess your butt and one to simulate you like
your back on these pneumatic arms that basically go.
Like here you go.
And it like pushes down on the seat first and then
pushes down on the back of the chair and then,
and it releases them and pulls them back to seem like somebody
is sitting down in the chair and getting back out of it.
And like I said, it's been there for, like, since,
well, and the IKEA has moved three times. It started out in West Ham Mall.
Then it moved to near South Commons or to, um,
near to white mud and then now to South Commons or South of South Commons.
And
I swear to God, the same chair, the same machine.
And like I said, it's, it's well into the six digits now, you know, and it's,
and the chair hasn't failed. So, like, cool. You know,
I actually bought one of these chairs
and my five year old was able to use it as a trampoline without breaking it.
It's nice to know that of all the constants in the world.
The IKEA sitting machine is one of them.
Yeah.
And so, yeah. But no, I agree. And, but the problem is,
you know, testing costs money and
our, you know, I buy electronics and I'll be honest,
I don't think I've consciously ever checked for a UL or in Canada's case, a
CS, a Canada safety agency, Canada.
It's on the back of my phone. What does it say?
I never check either.
However, when I am replacing, say switches and outlets in my house,
I
assume
that the hardware store is only selling UL approved gear and I'm pretty sure
they do because I suspect it's illegal for them to sell anything else.
Right.
You
know,
and
just common casual people that don't.
Right. Right.
Right.
And now I did buy some Z wave gear at
one point to start looking into like some home automation
and I was very particular to make sure that was UL approved because I knew that dodgy
Z wave gear
would almost certainly burn my house down. Right.
I mean, like,
-- just
-- turn the heater off in winter.
-- Uh,
-- these were switches like light switches.
Right. Right. And,
yeah, you know how that's gonna end? Right.
We all know how that's gonna end,
like fire in the wall. That's, that's what's going to happen.
And see, that's what I love.
So dirty secret. I actually bought a copy of the Alberta
Provincial electrical code and read it from cover to
cover and then talked to an electrician friend about it
because I had to do some simple rewiring in my house
and I wanted to make sure I did it right.
And it's fascinating to read the code and to see at every stage, like, literally,
you can just reading between the lines,
somebody died and here's what we did to
prevent that from happening again in the future.
You know. So things like,
and like, literally if your house is co
is up to electrical codes,
you can make like five or six mistakes and wreck
five or six things before you actually electrocute yourself.
Oh, yeah.
It's,
it's remarkably difficult to burn your house down with electricity these days.
It's
assuming it's done correctly.
And I would note that in many cases of electrical fires,
it is because somebody did something they shouldn't have done.
He said, well, I remember when I was a kid, like electrical fires.
You heard about them on the news all the time?
And I can't remember the last time I read about an electrical fire happening
anywhere near where I live.
Just
in general,
the majority in the western world, I should say, especially in North America.
The majority of what fire departments spend their
time doing is responding to medical calls.
I believe that I have no doubt,
you know, I, I actually know some firemen and they're like, yeah, no, the,
the vast majority of our calls now are medical in nature. And
the, like, all I know is when stuff like when health
and condos do burn down, it actually makes the news
and it's, you know, it's rare enough that it's like a big deal. Like there was a two
house fire.
It's,
it is not common anymore and I feel like it was very common when I was a youngster,
-- smoking
-- in beds had something to do with it too
seriously.
Yeah,
that's fair. The smoking rate was much higher. And additionally,
a significant number of products that are produced now
have all this crazy fire retardant built into it.
In fact, do you ever see the, there's like a video of, of the,
the terrorist trying to light a,
an eu flag on fire and he couldn't,
it had the fire retardant material in in it
and it was like that is, that is hilarious.
-- Well, it's
-- like kids pajamas. Right.
You know, and those, uh, those Halloween costumes remember back in the eighties?
Oh, no, maybe.
Well, for those listeners just go, we'll put maybe a link in the show notes.
But Google, you know, Halloween costume fire hazard.
And it, like, it was a big deal for a year or two. I remember this.
Oh, man, those masks had that terrible smell.
Yeah.
-- Yeah, I remember that
-- kid, kids, you don't know how good you have it.
And I think this is actually a great example of where the system mostly worked.
I mean, the reality is
there, the number of doors I've encountered that, like,
don't work as expected,
like, when I need to exit in an emergency is like, basically zero.
I can't say I can think of a single instance of having to exit in an emergency and
outside of when I was in college and,
and we had routine fire drills at three in the morning.
But other than that, I, I can't think of an instance of that.
Yeah.
And I mean, in fairness, if you go on, like, Reddit on our OSHA or whatever,
you'll see people who've, like, stacked, you know,
pallets in front of fire doors and like,
or chained them shut in schools to keep students from, like, coming in and out,
you know,
and, and that's no granted that is, you know, that's a problem, but it's not,
you know, an inherent problem, you know, within that specific fire door.
Right. It's some idiot parked a forklift in front of it.
Right.
Right. Right.
And, um,
that's never gonna change. Right.
That's just like that's human nature is we make poor decisions. That is
terrible at operational safety and security.
And this will be the beauty of
robots taking over is the robot
forklift in front of the fire door, right? They're
more than happy to pull it 10 ft forward more,
which will take three extra seconds before going on coffee break.
Yeah.
And so like I said though, especially, I mean, with something like a door,
it's relatively easy to determine, you know,
this door has a mechanical mechanism that allows me to override it and get out now.
But what happens when we're talking about something more complicated,
like say the power grid or,
you know, hospital equipment or, you know, where you have failure modes.
And, and one of my questions commonly for these is like, what is the fail safe mode
like? Is it to turn it all off? Well, you know, if it's a pacemaker
that might not be the fail safe mode,
I am completely unqualified to answer this question.
And I would bet you that there are people who sort of know the answer,
but we probably don't know it all today and
it comes back to you talking about that fire code
that you can kind of guess why that rule
was added because somebody almost certainly died from it.
And this is how regulation of medical devices is going
to work is people are going to get killed or maimed
by these devices.
And every time it happens there will be
an investigation and they will add another rule.
Yeah. Well, because I know with pacemakers there's been cases.
So they now have pacemakers that are sort of adaptive. Like they basically
essentially they can sense your physical activity and then up your heart rate for it
so that you can go and exercise and you know,
your heart will pump faster and you get more blood to your system.
And there's been cases where this has failed and the pacemaker essentially gone to a
like a safe heart rate level of say 60.
But when you're having to physically exert yourself,
that's a problem and
you don't die in that case, right?
-- That sounds like a reasonable
-- safeguard
because then on the flip side,
there's been cases where people are like sitting at their desk or
whatever and their heart rate jacks up to like 100 and 50
that would be bad. Clearly,
it probably doesn't feel great, you know, and that's the problem, right?
Is, is especially when you have a system where the failure,
like the safe failure scenario
is constantly changing.
Like, like that's what gets me about safe self driving cars. What is the safest
fail safe in a self driving car. Do you pull over to the side of the road and stop?
Do you continue at speed?
Do you?
I would assume pulling over is safer than anything else?
Assuming there's some level of failure
probably.
But for example, uh I had the experience once when I was younger of um,
I was being driven, not driving.
Thank goodness it was in Britain,
which I hate driving there because I always feel like we're, you know,
-- in the wrong lane
-- because you are in the wrong lane
anyways, we hit heavy, heavy fog,
like 100 ft visibility, fog on the,
-- on the motorway or whatever they call
-- the
-- typical British
-- weather.
So, the question is, do you slow down or keep speed?
And the problem is if not everybody makes the same decision,
I can tell you what most people do is they do nothing.
-- They drive like it's a bright sunny day. Yeah,
-- exactly.
And so my friend kept going at the same speed.
His reasoning being is that cars are better designed
to handle a frontal impact than a rear impact.
That sounds like the most terrifying reason
I've ever heard.
I mean, you're,
you're basically playing chicken with everyone in front of you at that point,
as opposed to everybody behind you playing chicken with.
You
see, that's the thing, right? There's no,
there's, it's like a lot of things until we agree on a behavior.
It, it's, it's really quite unsafe.
You know, this is why stop signs work so well because everybody stops.
-- Well, no, let me rephrase, almost everybody stops.
-- You've never been to Boston.
Yeah.
But, um,
you know,
this is why traffic generally works is because everybody
agrees to the same rules and the same behaviors
in
theory.
So this is where actually this is,
this is the argument I always come back to in self driving cars is
you can have
kind of the, the expected norms of self driving vehicles.
And if one person is able to essentially hack their car and say,
don't stop ever again at stop signs
and all the other cars will accommodate that road car.
You have a problem.
Right.
Well,
yes and no, in that we already have that situation with emergency vehicles, right?
-- They're allowed to blow, but
-- that's
ok because they have lights and if I put blinking lights on my car,
they're going to arrest me.
I mean,
and if you, and if you start blowing,
if you start,
see, here's the thing, we already have laws against that, like driving unsafely.
But how are you going to? Because
let's face it
because
the
record
it and send it in
maybe,
and that could be a plausible solution to this, which I, I assume
privacy
implications would prevent that though.
Well,
I think that privacy implications make an assumption that people will actually the
majority of people will own their self driving car versus the majority,
I suspect the majority of people will use a self driving car service like Uber,
which already exists.
I tend to agree.
I think that is the future because first of all,
your car sits in your garage like literally 90% of the time and is not used.
So that's wasted time.
But also, I think this instance of people messing with their cars,
of the firmware or whatever you wanna call,
it is going to be the bigger danger and there's,
-- it's going to be really difficult to stop people from doing.
-- We already have that.
There's, there's been cases, um, I'll have to look it up,
but there was essentially a case where somebody
was driving way too fast in a residential area and killed one or more people.
And I believe part of the problem was they had monkeyed with their firmware in
their car to make it go faster and they put bigger wheels on the car
so that they,
um,
you know,
essentially their speedometer didn't report what they were
actually doing because the wheels were bigger.
Right. So,
you know,
uh, most speedometers in modern cars are basically, um,
you have an output speed sensor from the engine
and you have, uh, the sensor on sort of how often the wheel is turning.
But I mean, that sensor doesn't know how big your tire is.
So if you put a bigger tire on, you're,
you know, you're gonna go faster if you turn the wheel the same
speed. Right. You know, just basic physics,
math,
um, bigger circles. That's how they work.
And so, you know, he was found guilty of a variety of things.
So, you know, laws for this, like, we already have these generic blanket laws of,
like, don't be a jerk in public, don't, you know, drive dangerously in public,
don't spit on the ground,
but enforcement becomes an issue.
But I, I suspect it won't be as much of a problem because
even if, think about this for a moment, even if 1% of cars on the road
were belonging to a service that sold
data,
uh, to insurance companies or maybe made it publicly available on youtube for,
you know, the best of round up fail videos
or flat out, sent it to the police.
You know, like right now you can already dial 911 to report a drunk driver. Right.
So if 1% of cars are on the road enforcing laws, essentially,
I suspect
that's enough to give us pretty much blanket enforcement.
-- That could be, that's a really interesting way to think of it.
-- You know,
when you talk about these unintended consequences, I really keep coming back to
if,
if
we'll essentially live in a ubiquitous surveillance society,
if like 1% or more of cars are constantly watching everything.
That's,
yeah, that's very true. That's,
well, I mean, I think we,
you could argue we already live in a surveillance society.
I mean, every everything that takes bad
today, records data in some capacity,
but there's no economic incentive in most cases to upload and analyze this data.
Now, there are, is, for example, cell phones,
your your movement data is sold quote unquote anonymized
-- for, you know, traffic stuff,
-- huge incentive.
Now look at all the ad companies, I mean,
you think that free app you got isn't tracking where you go at, like, all times.
True. But
there's a bit of a, I mean, even a free app is only going to get so much penetration.
Let's face it. Self driving, cars are going to get,
I'm, if I had to put money on it,
I'd say about 100% penetration within 30 years at the most.
You know, I bet it's less than that.
Well, and I'm guessing we'll get like, 80% adoption within
-- a decade
-- or it'll come fast, I think. And it'll be, I,
I was, I was talking to somebody about this but they were,
they were complaining that they like to drive and it's like, yeah,
and I like to ride horses.
Right.
My horse isn't allowed on the interstate for some reason. Right.
Well, I think a lot of people forget too that
there's a huge class or there's classes rather of people
who
can't drive or want to drive
shouldn't,
or shouldn't drive.
You know, too old, can't afford a car,
can't afford insurance,
you know. Paraplegic quadriplegic blind,
you know, it sucks to be a blind person to wait on the bus
and hopefully the bus drops you off at the right spot.
Right.
You know, with smartphones now it's a bit better, I'm assuming.
But fundamentally, you know,
like here in winter, every time I see somebody in a wheelchair on the sidewalk,
I feel bad.
Right. Because I feel like I should go help them.
But at the same time it's like, I, you know,
I can't spend all day pushing this person in a wheelchair around.
Like, it sucks to watch them struggle.
Even, you know, a three inch curb with ice is like,
it's literally insurmountable in some cases and I've had to help them over the curb.
You know?
So you think about that, those people, they're,
they're gonna love them some self driving cars.
Yeah. Well, I'm gonna love it. I, I hate to drive
or more to the point being able to send my kids somewhere without
having to worry about the cabbie or the Uber driver doing something silly.
And I don't mean like
touching my kids or keeping them because actually they're welcome to that.
They can keep my kids, they can't touch them.
But, you know,
just getting my kid from point A to point B with
no stress and hassle without myself being involved would be awesome.
-- Like sending your kids to, you know, swim class or karate.
-- Right.
Right. Right.
Yeah, exactly.
And Well, so
I,
I think about this a lot actually is my kids are reaching the
age where they can start kind of doing some things on their own
and I would never like,
dump them in an Uber or something like that without an adult present.
And it's not even that I, I miss, I mistrust the Uber drivers.
It's that I don't need my kids being like, hey, let's stop off at the candy store on the
way,
you know, like, no, just freaking bring them where they need to be
and
just because they're buying you a candy bar doesn't mean it's ok to bring them there,
you know, something like that.
Yeah.
No, it's, uh, I remember when we were doing uncle at large once and, uh,
we went to an event and
the one guy stopped to gas his car and two of the kids basically got out
of his car and really quickly went inside
the grocery store and bought monster energy drinks.
What is uncle's at large?
It's big brothers, big sisters, basically. It's a Canadian version of it.
We also have big brothers, big sisters, but we have uncles at large and aunts at large
anyway.
So, yeah, so these like eight year olds or whatever got each,
got themselves a can of monster energy drink.
Needless to say that
-- that was a bit of a tough day.
-- I can imagine that.
That is awesome.
Yeah,
I'm tempted to do with my guys someday.
But, um,
no, I, I think that with the self driving cars and with the data reporting, I mean,
I hate to say this but, you know, I'm not
averse to the thought of like everybody who doesn't use
their blinkers getting a $10 fine on the spot.
I would love to see those people be punished in the most gruesome
way possible because people who don't use
their blinkers are terrible humans beings.
Yeah.
So, or what I love especially is when they indicate one way and then go the other way.
That's my favorite.
Yeah.
No, I, I,
man,
people are terrible drivers.
-- Like that's what it comes down to
-- and people are terrible in general.
-- Not
-- everything, not everything. We're good at certain things. But driving
one of them,
I bet someone will create a robot that can tie shoes better than we can.
We've actually, there's a better solution.
There's laces now there's laces,
they're like elastic size and they have like a hook on the end.
So you just, like, pull it tight and put the, the hook on
-- those.
-- I, I rarely tie my shoes. Actually, this is kind of one of my secrets and
I just despise the action of doing it because it seems so pointless to me.
And I don't know, it's just one of those things. I don't know. I can't explain it.
And
I've, I've seen those. I've never tried them though. I, I should someday
Yeah,
but uh no going back to how do we test these fail safe systems,
especially when the failure condition.
What is safe changes constantly?
I think a lot of it would go to actually identifying
like what are the fail safe conditions like the power grid,
for example, is a fail safe condition, we shut it down or is a fail safe condition
like just keep putting energy into it.
Uh No, the the power grid, this is, this is well known is when crazy things happen,
it turns itself off.
And, and I mean,
that happened with there was a huge blackout on the
east coast which I think even affected parts of Canada
Toronto, my uh they were doing blackout beer because all the fridges were off.
Oh nice. But yeah. Right. And, and that makes sense because
if you keep adding power to the grid, very bad things can start to happen.
And anyways, but I mean,
and then you get into medical devices and cars and all these things.
And
I think part of what would help is
to understand
how do we want to use these devices?
Like what, what is the actual use cases we want these devices to fill
and conversely what use case like what sort of behaviors do we want to avoid?
Uh I think killing,
killing people is bad
and not killing them is good.
Right? I think we could probably start
and then everything kind of falls together.
Yeah,
but things like property damage would, would we, for example,
accept property damage to trade off?
Say, if, you know, just there's, there's lots of, you know,
like that whole trolley problem with self driving cars, you know, does this,
does the self driving car swerve into the pack
of school kids or the pack of old people?
You know, that's not a valid argument in my honest opinion.
I don't think the car is going to make the conscious decision,
who should I kill,
right.
It's going to somehow have some level of avoidance.
And practically speaking, I think
a a properly constructed self driving car is never going to have
that issue because it's going to detect the problem so long before
it became an issue that it's going to have dealt with it. I mean,
that's the thing, that's the thing people don't understand
when you think about cars as we think about cars with our skeleton
covered meat bag perspective of where it takes us seconds to process events.
Did you see the video from the Tesla car where it
essentially detected an accident like three seconds before it happened,
right?
Like that is what these computers will do is they work on a level we can't comprehend.
And so
our attempts at kind of using our constraints
of the world to build these scenarios is totally
inaccurate because we can't even fathom this is
like saying explain the fourth dimension to me,
right?
You can't do it because you don't know what it is
and we can look at what's, what's the crazy shape called
the, the tesseract, which I find.
No, it was a hyper cube.
It's also known as the tesseract which they use in, in the uh uh the Marvel World.
And what is it, the Avengers movie?
That's what the bad guys steal, they call the tesseract.
And I'm like, well, crap, we can't say that anymore.
But like, like, right, that's a,
a three dimensional shadow of a four dimensional object.
And our brains don't know what to do with that. Right.
And that's exactly what this is with,
like self driving cars in our brains cannot comprehend the self-driving
universe because it's going to be so fast and so accurate
that
we just don't even know what it is.
Well, I'll give you that because we,
we've already crossed that boundary with planes, right.
We've gotten to the point where,
um, not so much with commercial planes, but with uh fighter planes,
fighter planes are now designed specifically to be
unstable so that they can turn fast.
Right?
You don't want a slow and stable platform.
You want something that like wants to turn 180 degrees in like less than a second.
And the reality is humans can't fly vehicles like that.
They will crash and die.
So the computers do it and,
and that's been the case now for something like 20 or 30 years, at least,
possibly more.
Um, so I will give you that.
Um, yeah, I mean,
definitely when computers are reacting in tens of milliseconds and by reacting,
I mean, like,
actually completely processing the event and determining what should be done
versus like, oh,
car in the wrong lane, huh?
You know,
there's a
flower over there. Oh, crap. The car is still in the wrong
people.
I'm getting a text.
Um,
so I'll definitely give you that.
So I think, and, and this, because when I see this, you know, I also see a lot of, um,
you know, I see a lot of systems where people are like, well,
we've identified this part of the system as being critical but
this other part of the system we don't think is critical.
And then, of course, you know, when something bad happens,
it turns out that that other part of the system does turn out to be critical or,
you know, somehow involved in things
-- in a way
-- that
it's like when the bad guys come in through the H VAC system, right?
And then, then like, hack your entire infrastructure,
stuff like that
or coming through the door locks,
right?
Oh, man.
You know, there's a thought, does such a thing exist as a AA battery with
a
Wi Fi enabled AA battery that I can remotely turn off
because here's a thought I stay in a hotel, swap the batteries in the lock
and then come back, say a week or two later, turn the batteries off the lock fails open
-- and I ransacked the room swapped the batteries back and leave.
-- Ok.
Well, we should probably clarify that as well. When, when I say fail open,
I really mean, people inside can get out but
you don't want people outside to get in.
I think the, the fail open mode where people on the outside can get in is pretty
-- sure
-- the paramedics
would like to get in that room
and maybe they do. But you know what? Here's the deal though.
If a paramedic needs to get in,
they probably, right.
They probably have one of those rams and they're just going to knock the door down.
They
-- call
-- the fire
or right. That too. Right. Whatever or main
and
true. No, that's a good point.
Yes. It, it's complicated now, a, a Wi Fi enabled battery,
if they don't exist, they almost certainly will at some point.
And it sounds like the dumbest thing ever,
which means you'll totally be able to buy them in a couple of years.
Uh, for those of you that can't hear me. That was me typing and, oh, look at that. 2015,
they exist
Roost Wifi battery for smoke and seal alarms. It's a nine volt
battery.
Uh,
uh, what now,
I think the premise is that it warns you if the battery is dying.
No,
no, it's a smoke alarm.
It's not a, it's a smoke alarm,
not an actual battery.
It's, I'm so confused.
We'll put something in the show notes if this actually exists.
It's
a, oh God.
Yep.
Yep. Oh, Jesus.
-- It's a $35.09 volt battery with Wi Fi
-- I'm interested.
This sounds awesome. Is
it rechargeable at least?
Oh, bloody well, better
for $35.
Uh, it's got a family friendly.
But have you seen that they have those Wi Fi enabled SD cards? Right? I mean,
-- this is totally believable
-- but for like cameras and stuff that makes sense, right?
Because you want to, you know, get the data off the
being. You can like literally cram wi Fi into anything, right?
It's small enough, you can put it into a battery.
You
well, but
-- like my Nintendo wii your
-- Nintendo wii uses nine volt batteries.
No, no, it uses SD cards. But
you know
-- what about it? I
-- mean,
there's devices that you can stick an SD card in that are
not capable of retrofitting and cameras are a good example of that,
right?
Because people have some pretty expensive, you know,
digital DS LRS from prior to the Wi Fi and everything revolution.
And why do I want to put a Wi
Fi SD card in my
-- wi so
-- you can transfer the data to your laptop wirelessly while you're shooting.
I'm shooting my wii
or
no, no, no, sorry the camera when you're shooting with the cameras.
I understand that purpose
and then you mentioned the Nintendo wii and now you've confused me.
Sorry, I apologize.
It's all right.
You know, I'm not opposed to the idea of a nine volt battery being able to signal that.
Hey, I'm like dying,
you know, please replace me.
But, um, 35 bucks for a nine volt battery seems a bit pricey, especially, like,
as you said, you know.
Yeah, pretty much every smoke alarm I've ever owned.
Like, goes absolutely bonkers when the, when the battery starts to die,
whatever, man, $35 for an IOT battery. That sounds like awesome
right there.
Yeah.
Yeah. Awesome.
You should get some and then tell me how cool they are,
you know, you want to.
Oh, I, so don't,
-- I was at Best Buy the other day and looking at some of the IOT stuff and, oh,
-- man,
just don't look, don't look because it is nightmare fuel and we all know
what it actually means for humanity.
Yeah.
Right. Just don't do it.
So, speaking of all these, uh,
sort of health and safety and emergency exits that work safely, you know,
one problem I've run into a couple of times related to this is
how do we handle credentials safely in a way that is sort of more fail closed so that,
you know, bad guys can't get a hold of them.
I think the answer is to not use encryption or authentication
and just make them wide open so anybody can connect to the device
and that's fine
that
-- more in the case
-- the mir about
it, right.
Yeah, I mean more in the case of where you have um a service needs a password,
for example, to access a remote other service like a database.
So you have, you know,
and, and this is a common problem I'm seeing in the IOT space is that, you know,
essentially by definition, every IOT device needs to go talk to some, you know,
mothership to send data to get updates to blah, blah, blah, blah, blah things.
Right.
Um,
and with IOT, it's generally a bit less of a concern but, you know, with,
with more traditional applications where, you know, I got to talk to a database
and, you know, you, you don't want somebody breaking into the application,
stealing the password and then going and hosing
your database at a later date or whatever.
And so, yeah, how do we kind of have these systems
where you have the credentials available to the system?
But, you know, in a safe and secure manner?
Yeah, I mean, this is,
this is a really hard problem actually is I remember a long time ago,
the answer was to just hard code credentials into everything
and
that totally doesn't work. Especially not at scale.
-- Well, yeah, especially if you want to be able to change those credentials.
-- Right.
Right. Exactly.
And so there's kind of two things that I see happening around this
now is if you're talking about client authentication to like a mothership,
like you were saying,
that's where using certificates
is fantastic. And ideally, certificate pinning is the option you want to use.
But even just using like general TLS certificates
with the existing C A infrastructure is
that's probably good enough for most instances, right?
I mean,
you can do like some self signed certificates
with pinning and some other things like that,
but generally speaking, uh whatever you don't really need that.
But then there's the issue of how do you store,
say passwords to unlock hard drives in your data center, right?
You've got literally thousands of machines and
your options when it's time to reboot them
all is to pay the intern on Friday night to type password 75,000 times or
you come up with some way to safely store the secrets
somewhere
and then obviously get them back and, and that's hard to do.
That's, that's what really what this boils down to is we, we want
it to be automated,
right? So, yeah, like you said, we can reboot systems or restart them
without having to have somebody like physically log in and type a password in.
And so I, I know one thing you've advocated is you sort of split the secret,
right? You have say the secret and you have it encrypted
and then you have a key for that elsewhere that and you
just make sure you don't back them up onto the same system
or, you know, you, you essentially split it a little bit to, you know,
so the attacker would have to get two systems or two things now.
Right. I've, I've seen that as
the way it works.
I've seen instances where you just make like a,
you know, an HTTP request to some sort of secret server.
It's,
there's a number of solutions that exist around this or like
the T PM in a machine T PM consume passwords.
There's
many ways to do it. But the bigger problem isn't so much how you do it.
It's the fact that
you have to make sure this is a resilient
system because if you lose your secret store,
now your data center doesn't work.
That's a huge problem.
Yeah,
and I'm, I've, I've seen cloud,
this has actually become a bit less of a problem in the sense of if you sort of embrace,
embrace that cloud ideal of, you know, we don't reboot or restart,
we just deploy new infrastructure and turn the old stuff off.
You know, as part of your cloud infrastructure,
you have it obviously sending configuration details and you know,
that can include secrets like passwords and whatnot.
But ultimately, you know, then your cloud control system has to have some, you know,
you, you really don't want that being attacked and compromised.
So,
you know, at some point somewhere you either have to,
you have like the ultimate secret
the ultimate password that, you know, you then, you know, like,
like using last pass where you
have that ultimate password that controls everything
and, you know, encrypts everything within your last pass,
you know, and if you lose control or access to that, you are.
Yeah, totally up the creek.
And so I'm,
I'm wondering if part of me thinks that centralizing this actually
makes sense because then you only have one thing to defend.
I won't, I won't disagree. And not only that you can log every request.
And the thing is when you're dealing with something like a secret store,
what I think a lot of people forget is
the intent isn't necessarily to stop. Absolutely.
Every bad guy that's trying to get at this, it's to maintain control.
So
like, for example,
you might have a machine that goes rogue and starts requesting passwords,
it's not supposed to have and you will know
exactly what was requested and when it was requested,
if you have a centralized secret store,
whereas if you have a bunch of these passwords on disk or whatever
and, and even if they're confiscated on disk, for example,
which I know is sometimes lets you pass your controller on this
is
even, then you won't necessarily know who accessed what and how,
which is a huge problem because you ha you lack that auditability.
Is that a word auditability?
Uh Pretty sure,
not,
that's one thing I've I've encountered now, you know, for example,
with using Amazon web services and enabling cloud trail, right,
which is their auditing service.
And now every single interaction with Amazon web services is locked
and even better yet,
they have a way to set the logging so that it'll show evidence of tampering, right?
I assume they just signed the entry.
And if you know you delete entries, then the chain of entries is broken.
So the beauty is even if I or one of the other super admins goes around, at
least we'll know somebody monkeyed with the log,
which of course would be a huge red flag, right.
Right there. Right.
And so, you know, I think that and, and the reality is data storage is so cheap now,
there's no excuse not to log everything.
I
agree,
you know,
-- inexpensive storing data is
-- now, I remember doing an article about TCB dump and,
and I,
and this was a few years ago, crunching the numbers on essentially,
what would it take to keep, like, say a 30 day buffer of gigabit of network traffic?
Like to literally have a system that just keeps a ring buffer of
the last 30 days of network traffic coming over your gigabit link.
And the answer is it's affordable, you know,
and from a security perspective, like
it's kind of useless now because everything's encrypted.
Right. Right. Which is
the beauty of it, to be honest with you, because
we've reached a point where you can't necessarily trust anything on your network,
which is at zero trust networking model.
But even then, you know, even if everything is still encrypted,
you'd still have the metadata, you know,
they went out to these Russian IP S at three in the morning
every day,
you know, for two weeks,
right.
Um So there's still value in that.
But I mean, that's,
uh I remember when heartbleed came out and it was a big deal in Canada because the,
you know, the revenue Canada had to shut down
the tax filing site.
And what was really amazing to me is they came out on
the news and I think it was the number was 181.
Um
But basically revenue Canada was able to come out and say we shut the
site down and there were 181 people affected by this and we're informing them
and my response was what like, wait, they,
so like they keep enough logs and auditing that they were able to go
to everybody that had accessed their site and like mail them a thing saying,
-- you know, you may have been affected by this
-- or did they make it up?
I revenue Canada doesn't, they're generally very boring and they, you know, it's,
yeah,
II I generally trust them, like when they say I owe them X amount, they,
they've never been wrong.
That's fair, you know.
Um but you know, when you think about it from, like,
being the tax people that level of auditing makes sense.
You know, because no doubt they're also dealing with people who are, like,
doing all sorts of financial shenanigans or, or claiming, oh, you know,
I logged into your website but then, like, it ain't my payment.
I
totally,
yeah, I totally,
I totally clicked that button but nothing happened,
you know.
So, just from that, you know, like these people have a history of, like, you know,
records mean we can catch you.
Yeah, that's, that is true. That's a very good,
that's how they got Al Capone, right.
They got him on tax fraud.
Yeah. So, is he an insurance salesman or something, I think?
Yeah. Right. So,
exactly.
Yeah. No. But, um,
so going back to this, I mean, it's, it's,
I,
that's one thing I would like to see is a better, you know, because for example,
I have my, um,
the hard drives on my file server are encrypted
and so, like, every time I reboot
I,
you know, have to log in and enter this huge long password and, like, you know,
if I ever forget
it
here. So here's the question is, what is your threat model
in this instance?
My threat model is me forgetting to wipe the hard drives or
the hard drives failing so much so that I cannot wipe them,
but I
-- have to throw them out.
-- So here's what you actually can do in that instance.
And this is, you know, fun tips to Josh is
you can encrypt the drive
and then either use no password
which should unlock it automatically with locks, assuming you're using Linux
or just, you know, hard code the password into your boot options.
And what happens then is all you have to do is wipe like the first one K of dis
-- and that's where the key
-- crypto
shredding thing
you, right.
As long as you can get rid of that first one K of disk,
the rest of the disk is essentially random data at that point.
Yeah.
No, I've thought about that, but to be honest,
I reboot my file server so rarely that it's just a non
-- issue. I don't
-- even want to think about how long mine's been out.
It's every time I reboot it, it's, it's horrible because I, I've not disabled
checking the
on
and I hate to say that's one of the reasons I went to um ZFS is FCK on 20 plus terabytes.
-- I just don't, I literally don't have time for that.
-- Oh man, 535 days.
So uh
yeah. Well, hopefully there's no local Attackers executing Colonel.
I had
no
important data on that system
and I do that on purpose because I have a very zero trust sort of model.
And so even if an attacker got in intalled all of that data, they would
really, other than like kids DVD S, there's not a lot there.
My concern would be more an attacker,
inserting data than my other systems than process and get compromised.
I'm not gonna say that's impossible.
But generally speaking again, we've got watching videos which is pretty, in fact,
we don't even do that anymore because now Netflix has so much content on it.
We don't, we haven't even
used my file store of DVD S and
probably years I should,
I should actually start logging access to those files and I bet I would.
I
be
right.
That's
true.
This
is
a problem I'm having with the,
this is one of the issues I'm looking at for the CV E database is we're going to allow
uh more CNAs
and, you know,
currently the majority of CNAs are
relatively high trust individuals and organizations.
But as we expand it, you know, we, we get into the more dodgy parts of the world,
which is good because we want those people to report security flaws.
But you know what happened? And we have, we're going to be using a
Json format and it's one of, it's funny, one of the miter guys is like, why,
why did you pick
JSON over XML? I'm like
XML and I send him back.
Well, I send him back the link, you know,
cv.miter.org/what. Is it like search blah, blah, blah, question mark equals XML.
And I'm like,
there's just too many flaws in XML parsers for
me to safely handle XML data for random people.
So, regardless of the security flaws, like parsing XML is a pain in the butt. Parsing
Json
is painfully simple.
Yeah. Well, and more to the point is human readable.
Right.
Even if you don't have a processing system, a human being can sit down and, like,
look at the data.
Um, but anyways, and, you know, so that was the, the first part was just, yeah, XML.
Very complex. Lots of security flaws just wow, you know, so much, not fun.
And, but then the second thing is as well with, you know, this the CV stuff,
one of my concerns is I want people to be able to provide artifacts like say,
you know, here's a sample of the,
the
the affected source code or here is a test case or here is,
well, for example,
there's been kernel exploits where you need a kernel module to
help make the exploit more reliable because it's a race condition,
you know.
So instead of it happening one in a billion times, it happens one in 100 times.
Well, and then the question becomes, you know, like, well, websites go up,
they go down, who knows?
So we're, you know, I'm gonna have a way for people to embed these files within the
JSON data, right?
So that we don't have to worry about their websites being up or down,
you know, and then it becomes like PDF S oh Lord,
I hate opening PDF S from random people nowadays.
You know, because
seriously,
you know, my my response is to open them in Google docs
and have Google docs render them for me, you know, on their website back end thing,
which I assume is sandboxed all the heck because you know,
no doubt people are trying to attack it all the time.
You would think so.
And, but this raises the question of how do I safely provide data?
And you know, I've had to ask questions of like back to this fail safe, fail open.
Do I want to have the case where all the data can be
scanned by an antivirus scanner or do we specifically want to have,
for example,
a password protected zip file with the password included in the
JSON file
because we'll have samples that trigger antivirus and get blocked
and people need this CV data,
you know.
And then,
so what I've decided is we're going to go with some
data formats that unless you sort of explicitly process them,
they, they don't get processed,
right? Like it'll be a string of text in the
JSON
which well, I'm sure some
Json parser can puke on that.
But,
you know, realistically we'll put them essentially through a transform,
like say you, you encode them
so that they should be safe
and then when you explicitly start processing them, then you would have to worry,
you know, it's kind of like that old thing where you would take a file, save it as word,
save it into text and then save it back to word
and you, you're for sure you've gotten rid of the virus,
you know,
but you know,
these are questions now that we're going to be sharing
lots more data and lots more potentially dangerous data.
You know, how do we do this? Because we actually want to share unsafe data, right?
That, that by its nature is what security stuff can be.
Um You know,
there's a famous case where one of the CV descriptions
had the example of the regular expression code in it
that triggered the flaw and it actually broke somebody's CV E processing system.
I remember
that we talked about that a couple
of weeks ago, you know,
um
and so at that point, I mean, you know,
-- the reality is any, any type of data will break some system somewhere,
-- no doubt,
no doubt.
And I guess this is why we kind of plan for failure
because if you don't,
you, you're going, I guess ironically you fail if you don't plan for failure.
Yeah. Well, and there's a perfect example, I've decided for leap seconds. CV E
like uh your system should accept leap seconds
and then round them down.
And so essentially, if you're taking the data in and then sending it onwards,
you should get rid of leap seconds because we, we honestly, there's,
we don't need luckily that level of granularity and
accuracy in CV data, like if we're off by one or two seconds, typically,
that just won't matter at all,
you should just stop using seconds. Seconds are silly.
And
I've thought about that, but there are cases where we, we actually sort of need that
uh, granularity to some degree. But
I think it's safer to assume, like to essentially
make that decision of, you know, because here's the point.
If we don't accept seconds, then I can't say use
is
0 86 01 time stamps.
Then we have to do, I have to define some wonky time stamp format, which
I'm not qualified to do that.
-- Right.
-- And even if it's
quote
unquote as simple as just drop seconds.
I know,
I
know, I understand.
So I'd rather be as standards compliant as I can be.
And with, you know, like what Google and Amazon do where they just,
they, they sort of,
um, I think what is it,
Amazon does it over a period of a week where they increase
the length of a second or decrease the length of a second by
uh one over what 86,400? That's how many seconds are in the week
slid the clocks,
they skew the clock slightly. And so at most, you're only ever a half second out,
which is pretty clever, in my opinion.
It is. It is. And I think this is a beautiful place
to say that these poor people listening are nearly an hour out of their lives.
So why don't,
why don't, why don't we wrap it up here
and say thanks folks for listening. We certainly appreciate it.
If you want to check the show notes, you can go to open source security podcast.com
and all the fun things we talked about. We listed there.
There is also links to comment on Twitter. We love your comments. Please let us know
there is a Facebook group you can join and, and comment and we may well not, may we?
We almost certainly will reply
if you see something there and
if nothing else. Thank you everyone for listening.
Kurt, you have a wonderful rest of your day.
You too. Stay warm,
stay warm. It's coming, man. Spring is spring is coming. I can feel it.